<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[在诺奖得主古尔纳的故乡，大海不再只有伤痛 | 月是故乡明②]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257356]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/ 11/07/b840996666c29ba0936ba0ac8e934fd8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;578&quot; height=&quot;386&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/ b840996666c29ba0936ba0ac8e934fd8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Zanzibar, a woman picks up seaweed at low tide. /ICphoto&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the occasion of the New Year in 2016, I came to Zanzibar for the first time - &quot;Unguja Island&quot; from the southern big island&lt;/span>;&lt;span style =&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(also known as &quot;Zanzibar Island&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, the northern island &quot;Pemba Island&quot; and other small islands, hereinafter referred to as &quot;Zanzibar Island&quot;—— The capital of Stone Town&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(&quot;StoneTown&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, on a hazy morning at sunrise, I walked to the edge of the Indian Ocean with jagged reefs. Fishermen returning from the sea came ashore. They were shirtless, laughing and yelling in Swahili with tired faces. They pulled the not-full nets ashore, picked out lobsters, large octopus and tuna, and threw aside the remaining inferior goods. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A few hours later, these high-quality and fresh seafood will be delivered to a number of high-end Western, Indian, Arabic or Swahili restaurants. Then it is placed on the plates of tourists from all over the world. Those of poor quality will be transported to the local fish market and sold to countless people wearing bamboo baskets on their heads and wearing colorful kanga at a price of less than one-twentieth.&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #888888;&quot;>;(Traditional costumes of Swahili women)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, local women chattering enthusiastically. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I think that if I read the novels of Abdul Razak Gourna, at that moment, I might not be able to help but think of those in his different stories. A long paragraph about Mulberry Island, and empathize with it, such as: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url=&quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8 -length=&quot;113&quot; data-source-title=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;...the water plants were washed endlessly by the waves, lying on the beach It’s like a sunburned dream. There’s also the smell of sea salt, floating in every corner, in the nostrils and in the cochlea, just like the monsoon wind blowing from the sea and the port.&quot; (&quot;Farewell&quot; &quot;Memory of Departure&quot;, 1987)&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Unfortunately, although I have lived in Tanzania for six years and visited San Island three times, on October 7, 2021 Before the Nobel Prize for Literature was awarded to Gurna, I knew nothing about this author who grew up on Sand Island until he was 18 years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;1955, Stone Town&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the East African Islands, the dominant position has always been the sea, and the ocean further offshore. Every November, the southwest monsoon and ocean currents blow through southern India, southern Arabia and the coast of Somalia, to San Island, and then further south to the Comoros Islands and Madagascar. Before tourism became the main industry of Sand Island, the vast majority of people in Stone Town relied on the sea for their livelihood, including fishermen, sailors and merchants who came and went with the wind. At one time, there were dangerous merchants who sold ivory, spices and slaves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In today&#39;s Stone City, various houses of different sizes are dotted along the entire coastline. Many are Islamic-style buildings, and a few are decorated with complicated European patterns. It has been converted into post offices, office buildings, cafes, restaurants and private residences, among which there are many simple shabby iron shacks owned by local fishermen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of 2019, I came to Stone City for the third time. Taking advantage of the New Year holiday, I wandered around for nearly a week, looking at the remains of the ancient shell city wall seven or eight centuries ago. See the dungeons and chains at the former site of the slave trading market, and the monument to the 1964 Zan Island Uprising&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(Zanzibar uprising to overthrow the Sudanese rule, 4 years later, Gurna left Sang to go to England)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;See how the lovely blue water licks the rocks of history little by little. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/0f29c1a85781d77f84cf6340ecd8f7ba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/0f29c1a85781d77f84cf6340ecd8f7ba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;Writer Abdul-Razzak Gurnatou/Visual China&lt;/span >;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;One evening, I was walking in the old city and came to a square old house. It was hidden, but it was empty inside. It is not clear whether the house is for private or public use. Walking around the alley next to the house to the backyard, you can see a group of little boys wearing robes and square hats. They are squatting and playing with marbles and soda bottle caps. On the other side of the yard, there were several men leaning against the wall. They crossed their arms and talked about the rainy season, the wind direction and the lowest price for buying lilacs. Behind them were several women who set up small stalls selling fruits and vegetables. They seemed to be selling scattered dried fish, cherry tomatoes and onions. In fact, they were more interested in chatting. It didn&#39;t matter whether the things could be sold or not. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The sun was setting at that time, and the light shone just right in the yard and on the roof, and finally briefly settled on the sweaty brows and cheeks of men, women, old and young. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After walking out of the yard, I went to a cafe across the street, ordered a cup of Americano with clove flavor, and pulled out an old book from the bookshelf. The book is called &quot;Eye of Cloves&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(&quot;Eye of Cloves&quot;, F.D. Omani)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, published in 1955. When I opened it, I didn&#39;t have any expectations, it was just to kill time. Sand Island is called the &quot;Lilac Island&quot;, so judging from this title, it is not much different from most travel books about Sand Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I flipped through the pages of the book until I saw an old black and white photo. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Isn’t that square house and yard in the photo the same place I just passed by? More than fifty years have passed, and nothing seems to have changed. It seems that even people&#39;s status and clothing have been frozen at that moment. The adults sit or stand bored, and the children run or jump carefree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The caption of the photo reads: Arab residential area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This description can be used to summarize almost any neighborhood I passed through today, but to put it more accurately, most of the neighborhoods can be called &quot;Indian Arab Swahili&quot; Xili Mixed Residential Area&quot;. Because in today&#39;s Stone City, the vast majority of locals are accustomed to interracial trade, mixing, and intermarriage. It is difficult to accurately identify whether a person is of Arab, Indian, Southeast Asian, or Sri Lankan descent just by looking at his skin color and dress. With Vasili ancestry or a mixture of two or even three of them, almost everyone became a &quot;Zanzibar&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/b916a255dac148c595805f20cc1d0b79.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/b916a255dac148c595805f20cc1d0b79.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;Overlooking Stone City/Visual China&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;In 2015, Gurner mentioned this residential area in a lecture at the University of Kent where he teaches. He was born and grew up in Stone Town, an area generally known as the &quot;Arab residential area.&quot; He projected a related black-and-white photo in class. The photo showed a small square house with a simple two-story building standing on the left. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url=&quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8-length=&quot;98&quot; data-source-title=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;p>;&quot;I was born in the small building on the left. When I was a child, we always stood on the terrace on the second floor and watched the sailing ships leaving the port or returning from the sea, one after another, loaded with various goods. If you go downstairs and pass through the courtyard downstairs, you will see a workplace, a warehouse, and a vegetable market behind it.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url= &quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8-length=&quot;244&quot; data-source-title=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;p>;But what you can’t see from the photo is what kind of person he is. Live in this place. If you could see them, you might feel helpless like me. Why? Because when the outside world talks about us and this place, they will always savagely describe it as The complexity and richness are summed up in these seven colorless words (referring to the &quot;Arab residential area&quot;)... But in fact, in the house at the back, there lived an Indian family; next to them, lived The president of the Lilac Planting Association is an Englishman; the house on the far side is the local police station, and the chief is a San Island native of Somali descent; behind the police station is a cafe run by a Yemeni businessman... But According to convention, this is only an Arab residential area.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Gulna described all this calmly to the thoughtful college students in the audience, except for the slightly wrinkled Meifeng, no emotion can be seen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I think of that photo taken in 1955. Gurna was only about 7 years old that year. Maybe he was among the group of children playing in the background of the photo. From that time until he left home at the age of 18, it was a decade of great change in the history of Sang Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/5da0c2c9b6ad5aaebca8654dfef6c27c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/5da0c2c9b6ad5aaebca8654dfef6c27c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A man draws characteristic tingatinga paintings and sells them to tourists/ICphoto&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;1964, Mulberry Island Revolution&lt;/h3>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Lilac Eyes&quot;, I also turned to another dated black and white photo. Its caption read: European residential area - although the large Arab-style flat-roofed building in the photo looks There is nothing &quot;European&quot; about it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The next day, I found out the specific location of the building. After arriving, I discovered that the building complex was built one after another by Arab merchants two to three centuries ago. In the 19th century, the British became more and more active on Sand Island. Until the end of the 19th century, Sand Island became a British protectorate and this area was officially occupied by the British. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1872, Richard Belden published two issues of his travel diary about Zan Island, &quot;Zanzibar: City, Island and Seaside&quot;, and many subsequent comments They all thought that he might want to use this to hint that European readers had begun to explore the source of the Nile in 1856, much earlier than Livingston. But surprisingly, the influence of this diary is more evident in his inadvertent description of the slave trading system on Sand Island, which reminds people that the slave trade in East Africa is no less rampant than in West Africa. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a meeting place for Arabs, Indians, Europeans and Africans, San Island is like a corridor connecting various rooms and halls, and at the same time provides sweet dates from the Arab region. Plantations, the tea fields of India, and the sugar industry of Southeast Asia&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(even the Americas)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; provided labor. The most miserable ones were the male slaves who were selected as eunuchs by the Ottoman Empire. Because of the unhygienic conditions of castration, usually only one in ten could survive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Belden mentioned: Investigations show that before 1897, when the British used both carrot and stick to ask the Sultan who was in power at that time to abolish slavery, two-thirds of the people on Sand Island were of the population belonged to the slave class. Still, Belden wrote, it was difficult for him to differentiate between black and brown people and what their ancestry was. &quot;Swahili, Persian&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(later developed into the &quot;Shiraz ethnic group&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, Arabia and India...all mixed together , I feel that the people here&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(referring to Sang Island)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are simply like a brand new race.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1890, the British officially took over Sand Island, but did not provide any effective and constructive mechanism for sustainable development. Land, wealth and power are still highly concentrated in Asia&lt;/span>;&lt;span style =&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(Including Arabia)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the hands of the merchant class. At the same time, as was the practice in many other colonial powers, the rulers adopted a rigid management method in Sand Island by classifying all civilians according to their ethnicity and forcing them into a certain ethnic identity group. This made the tension inherent in the complex and subtle multi-racial mixture of Mulberry Island suddenly become tense. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Until the 1950s, a political storm against colonial rule swept across Africa. In 1963, Sand Island declared independence from the United Kingdom, the new Sudan succeeded to the throne, and British forces hurriedly withdrew from Sand Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Two days after leaving the &quot;European residential area&quot;, I came to the outskirts of Stone City and stayed at a B&amp;B recommended by a friend. &quot;Chat with the boss, you I&#39;ll be interested.&quot; My friend told me with a wink. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wilson, the owner of the B&amp;B, is a Tanzanian, British-Indian, 70-year-old man. He was born and raised on Sand Island until he was 6 years old, and then moved to Sang Island with his parents. Dar es Salaam&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(Tanzania&#39;s largest city)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;until the age of 20, then went to Edinburgh to attend university for four years. anthropology. After graduation, he changed three or four teaching jobs. &quot;I felt like I couldn&#39;t find a sense of belonging no matter how much I stayed in Europe,&quot; so he returned to East Africa. At first he wanted to take root on San Island again, but before he could settle down, he encountered the 1964 revolution. He had to take his Indian wife and three children and flee to Nairobi and Mombasa on the coast of Kenya, where he lived for more than ten years. Then we moved to the evergreen town of Mosh at the foot of Mount Kilimanjaro in Tanzania. It was not until 2005 that he returned to Sang Island and has settled there ever since. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I found Wilson and sat with him among the coconut trees in the evening breeze, drinking ice-cold ginger ale. His eyes were as low as his voice, and like most people on Mulberry Island, it was difficult to tell where he came from just by looking at his appearance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Although I am not a real Sandao person, when I talked about the revolution with many Sandao people, I found that their memories of it and their The definition of it - whether it is good or bad, good or bad, depends largely on who they consider their best friend, who they often share a pot of coffee with, or who they often invite into their home. Relatives and friends for dinner, in general, are extremely personal. For example, if your best friend is an Indian or a Shiraz, your evaluation of the revolution may be completely different. , because the Indians may be robbed and killed, but Shiraz can escape unscathed...&quot; Wilson said slowly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“But in fact, the revolution had already begun to take shape before 1964,” Wilson continued, “because it had only been more than half a century since slavery was abolished. , the old skeleton of society was basically shattered, and a reasonable new skeleton had not yet taken shape. It was full of loopholes. In addition, the British implemented many policies and regulations on clear class divisions. The Arabs still occupied a large number of people in San Island at that time. Absolutely outstanding status. So when the British withdrew, the undercurrent of conflict between the majority of landless African laborers and the minority of Arab landowners immediately transformed into a revolution.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Wilson still remembers that in 1963, in Stone Town after independence, the iron gates of the police station were opened one after another, and all the imprisoned and beaten Africans poured into the streets and alleys, with eyes full of resentment and rage, as if they were gathering strength. , volcanic lava ready to erupt at any time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 3 a.m. on January 12, 1964, the &quot;African-Shirazi Party&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (ASP, Afro-Shirazi Party&quot; member and Ugandan John Okello led 600-800 &quot;revolutionaries&quot; with extremely simple equipment to launch a surprise attack on the police headquarters and radio station. They had no guns and ammunition, only spears, machetes, iron rods and daggers. However, because of their surprise and desperate determination, they won comprehensively in just a few hours. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this regard, the leader of the revolution, Oklo, always insisted that the actions of himself and other insurrectionists were &quot;pilgrimage acts&quot; in order to do justice for heaven and liberate the people who were persecuted. The people of San Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/a73eb2ebf13993d40816f628301beeb7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/a73eb2ebf13993d40816f628301beeb7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Citizens chatting on the street/ICphoto&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;2005, at the seaside&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Pilgrimage&quot; &quot;Pilgrims Way&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(PilgrimsWay, 1988)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In &quot;PilgrimsWay, 1988&quot;, Gulner set the protagonist Dauda as a man who lived on the island of Mulberry in 1964. After the revolution, he fled to Canterbury&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(British city)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and became a nurse in a hospital. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After living in England for many years, Dauda returned to Stone City. At the seaside, I remembered that I and my friend Bosie once sat on the pier like this, &quot;watching the sea foaming with hands and feet and gnashing teeth.&quot; I remembered that on the same day, they paddled out to sea in a small boat and enjoyed that moment &quot;like &quot;Freedom without borders&quot;, watch how the Stone City gradually becomes smaller and smaller behind you, until &quot;it seems to have turned into a beautiful mirage&quot;. At that moment, they fantasized about escaping from the narrow and twisted streets of this small town and going to the distance to find opportunities as colorful as soap bubbles. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/3f125a9a5679eec53025d346922a999f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/3f125a9a5679eec53025d346922a999f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Picture of a boy diving near Stone City Pier/ICphoto&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Suddenly, the wind direction and ocean current seemed to be disturbed, and the boat started to stumble. Dauda became wary, but Bossi told him with a smile that this was just a sign that the northeast monsoon &quot;musim&quot; was blowing from the coast of India and Arabia to East Africa, while rowing the boat steadily steadily. When the sea seemed to have calmed down, Bosie explained why he could not leave his mother and daughter and go to England with Dauda, ​​and then come back to take care of them after he had established a foothold:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style &quot;One day, these people who we have regarded and used as slaves for centuries will unite and cut the throats of those who enslaved them. To At that time, the Indians will go back to India and the Arabs will flee back to their Arabia. What about you and me? What will we do... We will be slaughtered like animals... Who will care about us? They just They will tell us that this is Africa, their Africa, even though we have lived on this land for more years than they have.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Bosi then handed the boat over to Dao As a challenge, he was asked to row the boat back to the shore and jump into the sea to swim back by himself. But the sea suddenly changed its face, and fierce hurricanes filled the entire ocean. &quot;I was struggling and beating the wooden paddle randomly,&quot; Daoda recalled, &quot;but when the storm finally calmed down, I looked around, but No more Bosie.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url=&quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8-length=&quot;132&quot; data-source-title=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;&quot;I can&#39;t find him... Bo Xi, I miss you. Even at this moment, I am still crying for you. What else can I say? The wind and tide pushed me to the north headland and pulled me ashore. I didn’t even know who I was. How did I finally get back to the shore after I tried everything possible... But Bosie, you missed the worst part. The moment I landed, I was beaten with sticks and stones.&quot;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Gurner set the two endpoints of the timeline in &quot;a certain November when the northeast monsoon is about to begin as usual and merchants are about to visit East Africa again, and the slave trade is about to begin. It will be between November, when the trade of Sang Island once again reached a climax, and January 12, when the revolution of Sang Island broke out in 1964. Drag the scale back and forth between these two points, discrete and aggregate, and start over and over again. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Later, Wilson took me to a beach 40 kilometers away from the B&amp;B, where he and his family had sat and waited for hundreds of hours under the scorching sun. Beaches expecting British rescue signals and ships from Kenya. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 10 a.m., this unnamed beach not close to Stone City and unknown to tourists is empty and quiet, with no one and no wind, and only the bright sunshine shines warmly Staring at the milky white sand made me feel dizzy after just looking at it for a little while. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;About the beach, in &quot;Farewell Memories&quot;, Gurner wrote: In the past, those slaves who refused to be slaves would come to the beach next to Stone City. , and died there. Their corpses will float on the sea together with dead branches, leaves, debris and garbage, showing the fatigue after the struggle, just like their wrinkled black skin and the broken hearts under the skin. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, I wonder if the beach where Daoda frantically searched for Bosi and was beaten crazily was similar to this one? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2005, Gurna published &quot;Escape&quot;. Like almost all his novels, it is also about &quot;wanting to escape from a foreign land that cannot be escaped, and wanting to return to a foreign land that cannot be escaped.&quot; The story of immigrants who cannot return to their hometown. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the same year, after years of struggling with his inner alter ego, Wilson finally plucked up the courage to return to Mulberry Island alone. Not long after he settled down, he met his current wife, Khadija, a girl who was almost 30 years younger than him and born and raised in Sang Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The afternoon after returning from the beach with Wilson, Khadija and I sat on a wicker chair by the sea, picking fresh wild spinach and preparing dinner together. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Hadija was born in the 1970s and grew up in a fisherman&#39;s home. She only had general concepts about the slave trade, colonization and revolution, and did not have many specific feelings. Wilson almost never mentioned to her those bitter memories that had been sealed for a long time and seemed to have happened yesterday. &quot;I fell in love with her simplicity, carefreeness, and no need to be entangled in the past... In short, I fell in love with her.&quot; , experiencing too much is not a good thing. Fortunately, the current generation of Sang Island has revived because of tourism. After many years, the sea is no longer just a symbol for most people. With the pain and shadow, it once again became their hope.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wilson&#39;s emotion is still in my mind yesterday, reminding me of a passage in Gurner&#39;s book Words: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url=&quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8-length=&quot;129&quot; data-source-title= &quot;&quot;>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;&quot;Going back to the beach feels like returning home. How can I put it? It&#39;s like I can realize that this place once belonged to me... No matter where you go here, you will be treated like one of your own family... I can still feel the generosity in her bones from this place. Nobility and palpable passion.&quot; (&quot;By the Sea&quot;, 2001) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[呼伦贝尔：一抹秋颜，油画里的童话 | 眼睛在旅游①]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257596]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[篁岭“晒秋”丨指尖华夏①]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257580]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province, during the harvest season of fruits and vegetables, Huangling Village Villagers used bamboo plaques to hold harvested red peppers, corns, pumpkins, beans and other crops, and placed them on wooden racks in Hui-style houses for drying, outlining pictures of &quot;autumn sun-bathing&quot; in mountain villages with a bumper harvest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/JJ8Fw9wkQc612fkckK0w8E2Vj5dxVfj8qgbwibKJ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;801&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/JJ8Fw9wkQc612fkckK0w8E2Vj5dxVfj8qgbwibKJ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251994&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Huangling Village, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province, villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/djIu7O6bSFec6lMrEFlsBfFS6faaIXyzgP0HqZem.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;756&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/djIu7O6bSFec6lMrEFlsBfFS6faaIXyzgP0HqZem.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251993&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/hy2QJB2VLUg8vjvzoIfahKqRVAAeNRGiuKPNR5wp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/hy2QJB2VLUg8vjvzoIfahKqRVAAeNRGiuKPNR5wp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251991&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/y5pMPP9HGJVGpBAWK55N1xtlg65nzgsqbxnmJnAd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/y5pMPP9HGJVGpBAWK55N1xtlg65nzgsqbxnmJnAd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251990&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/gwwGmmz7mu1OZTfMcA7JZlAzUwOoWfPmFvcVa9pE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/gwwGmmz7mu1OZTfMcA7JZlAzUwOoWfPmFvcVa9pE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251989&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/ofIyLJjx6z174cq6PIVNTZpltMilcx1WeSbuAqNU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/ofIyLJjx6z174cq6PIVNTZpltMilcx1WeSbuAqNU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251988&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一身都是月 | 中秋国庆“悦”读专题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257720]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 21:23:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;This is Southern Weekend’s “Joy” reading special topic, and I’ll see you again. At this moment, maybe you are already on the road. go home? Visiting friends? Or run all the way to poetry and the distance. The meaning of reading is to make time more valuable and make the journey no longer long and lonely. So, please keep these selected contents, take an 8-day long vacation, blow out the reading lamp, and be covered with moon. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 21:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在故乡普洱茶山，醉茶]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257357]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;The temptation of spring tea is greater than the virus&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;On the sixth day of the first lunar month of 2020, because Due to the novel coronavirus pneumonia, the county has been closed down. I sent a message to my older cousin in the countryside early in the morning to ask how my relatives in my hometown were doing. My cousin said everything was fine. He has asked his family not to wander around outside unless they have nothing to do; and for his uncle who likes to hunt wild animals in the mountains, he has been strictly forbidden to go hunting in the mountains again. &quot;My uncle is quite honest,&quot; my cousin said. This makes me a little bit unbelievable. My uncle has always been fiery, but now he is willing to listen to his cousin. It seems that his dignity as the head of the family has already been established. My cousin is very busy. He leaves early and comes home late every day. He is the barefoot doctor in the village. He has to go to the monitoring point at the entrance of the village to measure the body temperature of outsiders every day. He has a heavy responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a special period, there are still outsiders coming, for no other reason than that my hometown is one of the best producing areas of Pu&#39;er tea in Yunnan, and March and April are the time to start picking spring tea. In previous years, before the spring tea was picked, many foreign merchants would come to the village early to reserve tea trees and tea farmers, so that the first crop of spring tea could be purchased, packaged, and transported as soon as it was roasted. Although there are not so many people coming this year, for some people, the temptation of spring tea is still greater than the virus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/GKBNpqDRxP4vc2LgiCeJsYZbFjwjbkfejw1kFD3f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/GKBNpqDRxP4vc2LgiCeJsYZbFjwjbkfejw1kFD3f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Spring in Pu&#39;er Tea Mountain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Information/Pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pu&#39;erbanna area belongs to the middle and low mountains and hilly areas, with interspersed large and small mountain basins and The valley flats pushed out by the Lancang River and its tributary water systems in the area are the main human settlements. Because it is located inland, surrounded by mountains, and has a high quiet wind rate, the cold lake effect is prone to occur in winter. This is especially noticeable when driving on a winding mountain road. It will become hot and cold as the terrain changes, and you will also see the cold lake effect in the winter. There is thick fog at the bottom of the basin and white clouds lingering in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xishuangbanna-Menghai-Huimin line is one of the main producing areas of Pu&#39;er tea. Mangzhi, Manzhuan, Mansa and Youle produce Pu&#39;er tea with excellent quality, and Yiwu tea is produced in Mansa. Menghai Huimin belongs to the six new tea mountains outside the Yangtze River (on the west bank of the Lancang River) - Nannuo, Hekai, Mengsong, Jingmai, Brown and Bada. The well-known Pu&#39;er tea brands &quot;Brown Mountain&quot; and &quot;Lao Banzhang&quot; are Produced in Brown Mountain, Menghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/xyqcOrWkZO0vTxXGzd88RbCkCplOnBnTIPhwKkFp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;549&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/xyqcOrWkZO0vTxXGzd88RbCkCplOnBnTIPhwKkFp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Schematic diagram of the distribution of ancient Pu&#39;er tea mountains. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Information/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Pu&#39;er is known as the source of tea in the world and is a famous Pu&#39;er tea town. The good Pu&#39;er tea is in Lancang, and the Jingmai-Mangjing-Manghong area in Huimin Township is one of the important producing areas of Lancang good tea. The largest ancient tea garden of 10,000 acres among the twelve major tea mountains is here here. The ancient tea garden was planted in 696 AD and has a history of more than 1,300 years. There are also many semi-wild ancient tea trees in the area. The age of the trees is unknown, but according to locals, the oldest tea tree is 1,600 years old. These ancient tea trees still produce a certain amount of output every year and are a cash cow for local villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;My hometown is in a village of the Blang ethnic group&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;In the spring of about three years ago, I went back to my hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My hometown is in Manghong, a village inhabited by the Bulang people. According to the tea mountain classification, it belongs to Jingmai Mountain. The Bulang people living here are good at planting, picking and making tea. Since ancient times, Tea is not only their daily necessities, but also an important commodity in exchange for supplies. Bags of Pu&#39;er tea carried on horseback are transported from Jingmai Mountain to Pu&#39;er Prefecture, Myanmar, and Thailand. Ma Gudao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I rarely go back to my hometown.小时候是因为交通不方便——老家隐匿在山里，过去道路难行，从寨子到县城，须翻山越岭走大半天到乡上搭班车，再坐上四五个小时才能到。长大后则因为在外读书工作，连回家的时间都少，更不用说回老家了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那年春节假期，听说我回来，小叔和大表弟捎信让我回去看看。布朗族过的是傣历年泼水节，对春节并不重视，所以我没有在春节回去，而是过完破五才和哥嫂一起回老家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从惠民乡进芒景的时候，发现路况比几年前好太多，这都是因为普洱茶的缘故。做茶叶买卖的人都知道这一带普洱茶好，每到采茶季节，外地客商全都跑来收茶，为方便运货车辆来往进出，政府出资修建了一条公路，大大提升了物流运输效率，当地种茶的布朗族因此致富，这里也成为远近闻名的富裕乡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在进茶山必经的桥头，设有一座关卡，对出去的车基本不看，对进入的车却查得极严。据说是为了防止有人把其他地方品质一般的普洱茶叶偷运进来冒充本地普洱再卖出去。虽然身处边地，这里的人早已有了品牌意识，对自己的茶叶和品牌格外爱惜，不允许有人坏了自己茶叶的名声。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/VMXuGJSIQJZcZ6Q0kYQ3VdEXyn7U0RzVk326YbW7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/VMXuGJSIQJZcZ6Q0kYQ3VdEXyn7U0RzVk326YbW7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;普洱风光。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然路况与过去相比是天壤之别，但也走了四个小时，到芒洪老宅的时候已经是中午11点多了。小叔从吊脚楼里迎出来，招呼我们进屋。老宅是传统的布朗族木板楼，已经有几十年历史了。上次我回来，爷爷和奶奶还在世，现在他们已经过世几年了，而老宅还是保持着过去的布置和格局：灶间依然有火塘，尽管现在寨子里早就开始用电和沼气，但火塘里仍旧日夜跳动着火焰。老家人用这火塘的火烤制他们最爱喝的罐烤茶，在冬夜里围坐在火塘边烤火，喝茶，吸水烟筒，聊天。火塘是家的灵魂，任何时候也不能丢掉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然时近中午，家里只有小叔在。堂弟上学，中午在学校吃饭，要下午才回来；小婶上山摘茶，也要下午才回家。眼下虽然古树茶还没到采摘的最好时候，但第一茬的台地茶已经开始采摘了，从此时开始，一直到整个四月结束，是寨子最忙的时候。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;台地茶指的是近几十年栽种的普洱茶，虽然口感没有经过漫长历史沉淀下来的醇厚，但也属茶中精品，不施任何人工肥，靠土壤自身，茶地林木的落叶以及阳光、雨露滋养，也称为生态茶。我的一位台湾朋友曾告诉我，台湾对于茶叶进口要求很严格，一定要完全生态的茶才允许进口。老家的茶叶很受台商青睐，每年都有相当一部分茶被台商买走，足见品质之优越。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;用红牛解茶醉&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;虽然老宅的格局没变，但我还是发现多了两样东西，一个是巨大的茶台——小叔自己做的，看那体积估计树龄也不小。随着外地茶商的进入，也给寨子带来了不一样的生活方式，喝茶就是一例。过去喝茶，一般是趁火塘上坐着铜壶烧开水的时候，往小土陶罐里抓一把茶，放在塘火边煨烤，待水滚了，茶也烤出香味，将滚滚的水往罐里一注，就是一罐酽酽香茶，香得浓烈而富有野性。这罐茶极香，却也极苦，苦过以后却又回甘绵长。茶力也十分霸道，初喝的人一不当心就会醉茶——气短心慌，很像低血糖症状。本地人的土办法是抓把生米嚼食，据说很灵。罐烤茶初喝易醉，久喝却容易上瘾。过去寨子里的人很少去山外，交通固然是一个原因，另外他们嫌外面的茶水淡。非要外出，一定要带上自家预先烤好的茶叶，待茶喝完，不管事情办得如何，那是一定得往回走了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今老家人喝茶也讲究茶道了，茶海、茶洗、茶壶、茶则、闻香杯、主人杯、品茗杯等等，一个不少，讲究水温，讲究水质，讲究开汤。一招一式，有板有眼，古老的寨子同样在时代的变化中吸收新知并改变着。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老宅的另一个变化是多了一人高的消毒柜。布朗族本身就是特别爱干净的民族，以我家老宅来说，虽然老旧，但收拾得非常整洁干净，露天的掌子（当地对吊脚楼露台的称呼）一尘不染，让人觉得质朴而亲切。如今寨子制作普洱生茶，对于卫生越发讲究，不仅人家，就连寨子里，虽然依旧是土路，但却收拾得十分干净。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;把我们迎入老宅后，小叔不忙别的，先张罗我们喝茶——采茶时节，几乎家家都是在茶山忙碌一整天，根本没有午饭概念。茶是刚刚摘下新焙好的春茶，虽然不是古树茶，但也属上品。小叔将滚水注入茶壶，盖上盖略闷了五六秒时间，然后将茶倒入茶海，再分给我们。为了观看茶色，小叔特意买了透明的玻璃小盏，茶水注入后只见茶汤清澈，色泽新绿，入口是一种清新的苦涩，两杯之后回甘姗姗而来，才一瞬间甘甜便溢满唇齿间，更一波波在口腔里放大开，仿佛一位初识时含羞带怯、熟识后热情活泼的青涩少女——我想她必定是一位布朗族少女。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据说喝生普刮油水很厉害。中午才到老家，胃里的早餐已经消化得差不多了，而小叔又在左一杯右一杯的让喝茶，很快我就有点低血糖症状了，瘫在沙发嚷着要吃饭。小叔这才恍然大悟般拍拍脑袋说，你醉茶了！然后慢悠悠地安排做饭。他先用电饭煲煮上饭，再往火塘上支起一口大锅，倒进水，扯下一条腊肉剁成几块扔进锅里，在等水开的当口，他一阵风似的出门了。片刻，小叔又一阵风般回来，捧回一堆红牛放到我面前说，先喝点，喝了就不醉茶了。我开了一罐喝，果然感觉好了点——看来如今醉茶也不再嚼生米，而是改喝红牛了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小叔把红牛往我手上一塞，又奔出去张罗午饭。他从鸡圈里抓了只鸡现杀了，乒乒乓乓地剁成块，等锅里的水一滚就悉数下到锅里，加入佐料盐巴，搅和几下盖上锅盖继续焖煮；又从腌菜坛子里掏出一大碗水腌菜，一部分加酱油辣椒凉拌，一部分切碎了与斑鸠肉同炒。下午两点钟，我们终于吃上了迟来的午饭——走地鸡煮腊肉，拌水腌菜，水腌菜炒斑鸠，柴火烧出来的菜格外香，我吃得津津有味，足足送下去两碗饭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;咱家的古树茶&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;吃罢饭，大表弟也正好从村医务所下班回来。他跟小叔打过招呼，对我说，姐，要不要去看看咱们家的茶地？我说好。表弟便和小叔下楼去发动摩托。芒洪村建在山间，村内道路不宽，而且坡度起伏很大，骑不了自行车，平日里的交通工具就是摩托，各家各户都至少备着一两辆摩托车。表弟载着我，沿着一条细黄蜿蜒的土路向山里开去，后面是小叔带着哥哥。行驶到半山腰稍平一点的位置，表弟停下摩托车，引我来到路边，指着山下不远处对我说：“姐，你看，那是咱们寨子！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时是下午四点半的初春，阳光已经微微泛黄，天空晴朗，光线柔和，蓝天下带着四面坡屋顶的吊脚楼错落有致地分布着，在烟雾般的竹蓬和芭蕉树的掩映下断断续续起伏着，延伸到对面的山间，显出一派恬静的乡村风貌。表弟说，这是他最喜欢的地方，平时去茶地路过的时候都会停下来看一看；什么事也没有的时候，也会来这里站一会。 “这是我从小生长的寨子，我们的祖辈都生在这，埋在这，再没有比这里更好的地方了。”表弟说。我们看了一会，表弟招呼我上车，继续向上驶去。又转了几道弯，表弟再次停下车，说，“到了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/H3lU50w9mcJSHm6oFrojMJPnRP6mf3ZfyfGJVc6B.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/H3lU50w9mcJSHm6oFrojMJPnRP6mf3ZfyfGJVc6B.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;山中村寨。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一面山坡，看上去像一片未经人工扰动的山林，错综地长着粗细高低不一的乔木、灌木和一些藤草。在高大的乔木和低矮的灌木之间，是一棵棵约2米高的茶树，深绿的成叶中间，新绿尖长的嫩叶正剑般刺出来，再过几天就可以采摘了；虬曲的枝干上覆盖着斑驳的层层苔藓，仿佛是沉淀下来的时间残骸；苔藓一季季地生长枯萎，在茶树枝干上堆积起一层薄薄的苔藓土，成为寄生植物安身立命的地方。在这里，只要长到一定树龄的普洱茶树上，都会寄生着一种叫“螃蟹脚”的植物。螃蟹脚学名枫香槲寄生，对于风湿关节痛、腰肌劳损和急性膀胱炎疗效显著。茶叶发芽的时候，也正是螃蟹脚的花果期，一丛一丛的簇生在茶树枝丫间，常常导致茶芽无法生发。云南古树普洱茶属于大叶乔木茶，植株高大，想要清除螃蟹脚很不容易，所以过去对于茶农而言，这是一种可恼的寄生植物。如今螃蟹脚被人广为追捧，价格卖得比普通普洱茶叶还贵，动辄便是千元一斤，茶农往往把螃蟹脚当作茶叶的副产品，又是一笔可观的收入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;表弟自豪地指着这些茶树说：“姐，这些都是咱家的宝贝，古树茶！你看这几棵枝干特别粗壮的茶树，这个有300多岁了，那个500岁，那边那一棵是这块茶地的“茶魂树”，寨子里的老人说至少800岁，他们说茶地才开的时候就种下的……这几棵茶树我都做了编号，每年都单独采摘，单独炒制，可以卖出很好的价钱。”所谓的“茶魂树”，就是每片茶地种下的第一棵茶树，茶园有多老，树就有多老，茶园消失了，也许树还在……茶魂树是茶园的灵魂所在，它化身为神明，保佑着这片茶园，因而每年4月都要举行茶祭、“叫茶魂”，不仅每家要祭祀自家的茶魂树，寨子里还要请来大佛爷和德高望重的老人主持盛大的仪式，祭祀茶魂，呼唤茶神。除了这几棵被表弟誉为“宝贝”的古茶树，这块茶地的“主力”由树龄约在200年上下的茶树组成，间杂的细小茶树由古树的枝条扦插而成，它们继承了母本茶树的性状，有着一致的风味，所欠缺的只是岁月的历练。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“姐，你知道这座山叫什么名字吗？”我摇摇头。 “这是哎冷山，用帕哎冷的名字命名的！”表弟骄傲地说。帕哎冷是一千八百多年前布朗族杰出的首领，传说为了寻找理想的栖居之地，他带着布朗族跋山涉水，历尽千辛万苦，终于找到了一片长满野生茶树的地方，这里土壤肥沃，溪流潺潺，植被葱茏茂密，鸟兽出没其间，四周群山环绕，正是建立村寨的理想之地。于是帕哎冷便带领族人在此定居，并指导族人驯化茶树，开辟茶园，这就是芒景芒洪一带布朗山寨和茶园的由来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“哎冷山的水土是最好的水土，哎冷山的茶也是最好的茶！”表弟以不容置疑的坚定态度对我说。布朗族相信首领帕哎冷为他们找到了最美好的家园，最肥沃的土地，更崇尚人与自然和谐相处的道理，所以布朗族种茶除了必要的护理之外，从不进行人工施肥，更不用说使用化学药品。山中的茶树吸吮着雾气和露水，自泥土和杂草枯叶中提取养分，一点点转化为茶叶物质，形成了景迈山茶叶苦涩重、回甘生津强，汤色桔黄剔透的特点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这时，表弟突然转过身正对着我，认真地说：“姐，我总在想，祖先留给我这么珍贵的茶地，我一定要守护好，不管是茶树还是茶叶品质，决不能在我手中毁了。”我明白表弟的意思。他的主业是乡村医生，但他的业余时间几乎全部放在了茶叶上。布朗族本来就是一个特别爱干净的民族，到表弟这里，他把医生的职业习惯也带了进来。家里人采茶炒茶，他要求做到“三不落地”，即采茶不落地、委凋不落地、炒茶不落地，至于最后压茶饼，则完全是他亲自来，不假人手。 “我一定会好好把茶叶做下去，帕哎冷会保佑我们的。”表弟把视线投向远处的天空。在那里，快要下沉的太阳被一片云遮住，光线从云后透出来，给云彩镶上一道明亮的金边，像是某种来自自然的暗示和赞同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[名字最有梗的小城，凭什么又翻红了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257896]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[墨西哥公布“外星人”遗骸，网友：长得太符合刻板印象]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257926]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;当地时间9月12日，墨西哥议会首次召开与“不明异常现象”相关的公开听证会。会上，两名科学家在播放了几段显示“不明飞行物和不明异常现象”的视频后不久，展出了两具疑似“外星生物”的遗骸，相关话题很快冲上“热搜”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/30ce9c40e8e1e64679e83b2f04cf4218.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/30ce9c40e8e1e64679e83b2f04cf4218.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252807&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年9月13日，墨西哥首都墨西哥城，听证会上展示了疑似“外星生物”遗骸。图源/视觉中国&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据当地媒体报道，墨西哥方面计划通过听证会推动相关立法工作，该国可能因此成为全球首个承认“外星生物”的国家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你相信有外星人存在吗？相信不相信说不清提交&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;网友：太像人了，所以不信&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;根据公开信息，这两具遗骸于2017年在秘鲁被发现，距今分别有1800年和700年。从现场公布的画面看，遗骸外观与人类相似，头部细长，每只手有3根手指。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究者在会上称，这些标本已经由墨西哥国立自治大学（UNAM）的科学家研究过，在与其他DNA样本进行比较后，发现超过30%的标本DNA是“未知”的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/b5a0c6003422e9e8d534e44897417238.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/b5a0c6003422e9e8d534e44897417238.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252809&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年9月13日，墨西哥首都墨西哥城，疑似“外星生物”遗骸的手指。图源/视觉中国&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;听证会上还展示了标本的X 光片，其中一具身体内有“卵”，而两具都有由非常稀有的金属制成的植入物，如锇（Osmium）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;消息一出便引发热议，大多数网友持质疑的态度：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“太像人了，所以我不信！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“很符合人类对外星人的刻板印象！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这个和科幻片里看到的有啥区别？长得非常&#39;意料之中&#39;啊。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“宇宙那么大，有外星人真的不出奇。只是这个外星人样子也太符合之前幻想的了吧……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/0aaadec694c7f26b6a3753bf0b6f547d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1052&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/0aaadec694c7f26b6a3753bf0b6f547d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252810&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国科学院国家空间科学中心研究员、航天科普大使刘勇在接受南方+记者采访时说，外星人的存在是一个“概率事件”。 “仅仅银河系便有大约3000亿颗恒星，更别提宇宙有超过2万亿个银河系这样的星系，所以外星生物即便概率很小也会存在。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但对于此次墨西哥公布遗骸事件，刘勇认为并不可信，甚至有些“无厘头”。在他看来，一方面，外星人的形态有许多种可能，但像人的可能性非常低；另一方面，他认为由于技术等原因，目前人类寻找到外星人的可能性非常小，要从“独木舟时代”发展到“航海时代”，才有可能发现更远的文明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;外星人、UFO为何热度不减？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;抛开此事真假不谈，最近，国内外关于外星人、UFO的消息不断“刷屏”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此次墨西哥公布遗骸之前，8月初，哈佛大学一名教授也曾宣称他“可能发现了存在外星生命的证据”。据称，该团队正在对2014年不明物体坠落地球时的残存碎片展开分析，这名教授认为碎片上存在外星技术残留物，可能经过改造。他和团队正在将发现的结果整理成一篇论文，希望在一个月左右公开发布。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在国内，9月7日晚，济南七星天文台发布了一段视频，显示9月6日的监测画面中出现“发光下坠”的不明飞行物。 9月1日和5日，七星天文台也两次拍下了不明飞行物的痕迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山东天文学会副理事长、济南天文学会秘书长牛桂华认为，由于有疑似动力的存在，目前只能得知不明飞行物并非流星之类的坠落物，但无法明确正体是什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/e46802e8b3061256fb33217f3b0175d4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;437&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/e46802e8b3061256fb33217f3b0175d4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252808&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;左图：当地时间2023年9月13日，墨西哥首都墨西哥城，听证会上展示的“外星生物”遗骸，右图：电影《ET外星人》里的外星人形象。图源视觉中国&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大约一周后的9月13日晚，“UFO”又冲上微博“热搜”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微博网友“小禧遇”发视频称：“有谁知道曹县往西北方向天空上两道光是什么吗？UFO？录视频的时候光柱消失了，就剩下这些烟雾。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不少网友在评论区说也看到了同款不明飞行物，坐标涉及北京、江苏、山东、天津等多地，并晒出照片。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为何人类对UFO、外星人如此着迷？刘勇认为，“寻找地外文明”已经超出了简单的科学问题范畴，成为一个哲学问题。探索宇宙的奥秘和生命的起源，或许也是在探索人自身，探索人在世界上、在宇宙中的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，人类正不断加快推进对宇宙的探索。从1977年发射的两艘“旅行者号”探测器到建在贵州的“中国天眼”等，各种探测手段更加完善。以“中国天眼”为例，其实验目标就包括接收地外文明、脉冲星、快速电暴等信号。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在刘勇看来，人类距离寻找地外文明仍有很长的路要走，“或许要在千年、万年的时间尺度上才有可能”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[音乐家李海鹰：月光流淌在珠江上]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257914]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021849850177&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;人物周刊李海鹰稿件视频.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/G8hfqzJQv3VepINkT0VCcndx1kDzyd2fW3QrQgrz.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/e6988e555576678021849850177/HVmbvbHXk6EA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/e6988e555576678021849850177/HVmbvbHXk6EA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月末，珠江中的沙洲二沙岛上，李海鹰正在排练由他创作的交响曲《中国1921》，这位作曲家在近几年转向大型音乐作品的创作。除了正在排练的交响乐，他还在制作一部大型电视剧的音乐。当我们走进广州交响乐团的排练厅时，恰逢乐团鸣奏，像踏入了流淌的溪水中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你们走进来的时候，正好到关于广州的那段。”李海鹰说，排练厅外十几米远就是往东流的珠江，江水再往下流，就是他小时候长大的地方。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为在珠江边长大的人，李海鹰的音乐里有着强烈的流动感。30年前，他写《弯弯的月亮》，请“声音很飘”的刘欢来唱，他觉得这首歌是“整个被雨水淋出来的感觉”，尽管当时“寻根热”正引领着文化界，《信天游》《一无所有》等正把西北的风和沙吹遍大陆乐坛。他也为《七子之歌》谱曲，在关于澳门的曲子里，他用旋律模拟着海浪对石岸的拍击，这首歌跟着中国的首颗探月卫星“嫦娥一号”去了太空。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“虽然我住在北京，但是我的很多创作的委约都是广州的。”69岁的李海鹰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/eomOXOcVnf0VzkC2W51Rkyk8QpJWDriwbjOltSud.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/eomOXOcVnf0VzkC2W51Rkyk8QpJWDriwbjOltSud.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;李海鹰&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（李乐为/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1970年，16岁的李海鹰进入广州粤剧团，成为了小提琴手兼创作员。5年后，他成为中国海军南海舰队政治部文工团的小提琴手兼创作员。1982年底到1997年3月，他在广东音乐曲艺团当创作员，写下《弯弯的月亮》《七子之歌》《我不想说》等作品。他善长将民歌元素融入流行乐曲的旋律之中，因此作品带着鲜活的地方感，比如广东调的《弯弯的月亮》、东北二人转风格的《过河》、有山东音乐特征的《走四方》。他也写了不少流行乐，如陈奕迅的《从何说起》、孙俪的《爱如空气》，也为《亮剑》《鬼子来了》等影视作品配乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;交响乐始终是他的梦想。49岁那年，李海鹰开始跟从指挥家、音乐教育家徐新教授学习指挥。54岁时，他在中央音乐学院的教室里重新学习作曲课。五十多岁的他重新学习和练习指挥与谱曲，他坐在教室里和本科生们一起上课。“其实都是很基础的课程，就是本科课程。”他乐于学习，也乐于当新人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年，李海鹰才成为交响乐新人，写作并指挥了大型交响乐作品《我们的孙中山》，加上后来的《六祖颂》、《第一交响曲（珠江）》和《中国1921》，他一共创作了四个交响乐作品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;恢弘的历史题材，在李海鹰的音乐里呈现得很具体，他用不同的音乐风格去对应不同的城市，用京剧去描摹北京，用龙船调刻画武昌，长沙则用花鼓戏……他的音乐始终保持着在地性，这或许来自他对民歌的熟悉、在创作中对相关内容的调研。在儿童音乐剧《猫神在故宫》中，李海鹰为了充分把握北京的气息做了大量调研，希望用音乐去描画一个城市的历史与现代的鲜活气息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/yGLXcpFrWdn0r6AKhKQ47kltM4JIkXqYfqNHV6Va.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/yGLXcpFrWdn0r6AKhKQ47kltM4JIkXqYfqNHV6Va.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年5月，李海鹰与广州交响乐团演奏《中国1921》&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（李乐为/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以下是李海鹰的口述：&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;交响乐与流行：鲜活的地方感&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在这场演出之前，我其实有过一两天焦虑。《中国1921》是2021年首演，光是今年都已经演到第七次了，是不是我还能做些什么，我能不能让乐团这次表演再好一点？如果我要做一个没有新意的操作，那我干脆不做，所以这次排练时我还在改曲子、删小节，当然这些是我在家里想好的，不是现场灵机一动。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;排练的时候，我有两个角色，一个是作曲家，另一个是指挥家，等于演奏者。跟乐团一起演奏时，我会从另外一个角度来考虑音乐、重新演绎作品。而且做交响乐还得有一个能力，记忆力要强，就跟下盲棋一样，整个棋盘要全记得住，这也是做音乐不断锻炼出的一种能力。曲子基本上要背下来，而且还要想怎么演奏，是活泼一点，还是柔软一点？我做指挥的时候，我就修改一些表达的方式，而且还得听演奏，一边演一边改，还调整了不少。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2019年广州交响乐团委约我这个作品的时候，原本没想到我写这么大篇幅的作品，当时余隆总监和我说，首先要写出动听的旋律，其次是内容集中在1921年。我根据这个思路搜集资料，发现从1920年8月到1921年春,上海、北京、武汉、长沙、广州、济南6个城市成立了中国共产党的早期组织。与此同时,在旅日、旅法的华人中,也成立了由留学生中的先进分子组成的中国共产党早期组织。所以，我最早的设计是9个乐章，用9种音乐风格，描述十月革命，以及1920年至1921年间中国共产党成立前夕发生在中国北京、武汉、长沙、济南、广州、上海和日本、法国的历史片段。根据音乐的结构缩成了5个，但依旧是9个段落构成。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;第一乐章是热烈的快板，描述十月革命的爆发，名为《石破天惊》。第二乐章开始是安静的行板，包括两个乐段：《北平飞絮》和《武昌秋水》。第三乐章是圆舞曲，《东瀛密巷》和《巴黎晨光》。第四乐章是中国舞曲，主要讲长沙、济南和广州。最后的乐章就来到了“一大”的召开。到了北京我就使用京剧，武汉我就改编龙船调，长沙用花鼓戏，济南部分我就创作了一个山东的调子，广州的部分也能听出很多广东音乐的元素。到了最后，我用了交响乐经常用的方法——赋格，把不同的主题全部叠在一起，这象征着滚滚洪流汇在一起，形成一种巨大的力量，冲向结束。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这是我的第四部大型音乐作品，目前我和中国儿童艺术剧院合作一部音乐剧叫《猫神在故宫》，故宫过去的主人已经不在了，现在故宫里的猫咪“多尔衮（猫的名字）”在网上很受欢迎。我对这个题材充满期待，也在全力创作中。故宫是中华文化的一个聚集地，我们想要推广中华文化，所以就创造一个故宫的“猫神”出来。我希望写得新潮一点，有很多现代元素，但又内含北京的文化，比如有北京童谣、北京琴书、评剧等等。我觉得这个很重要。什么样的作品能够得到公众的认可？首先，它必须得有根，同时要学习全球的优秀文化。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;创作还是需要不断学习，我觉得自己现在正在冲刺期里，但也有惰性。我跟那些学生讲，人人都沿着惰性往下走，你知道这是人性弱点，不如尝试一下反过来走走。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;只有不断地创作，才能让社会接受我。起码对我音乐上的合作者来说，所有人的期望都是我在不断进步，如果哪天发现李海鹰已经停了，合作基本上也就到头了。只有不停地让别人惊讶，我才可以继续做我想做的音乐。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/SHhPiGzjsaDFAYdtAiphLrdCCBKLJqGQKX9fX112.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/SHhPiGzjsaDFAYdtAiphLrdCCBKLJqGQKX9fX112.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252763&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;李海鹰&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;时代变迁中，永远的音乐新人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;其实我从小的理想就是想做交响乐。上世纪80 年代，我到流行音乐行业里去了。滚了几圈出来，又做了影视配乐，《亮剑》《外来妹》《幸福像花儿一样》等等，《鬼子来了》也参加了。最后觉得还是要回到我的童年梦想，去实现它。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;小时候，有次我家里放了圣桑的《引子与回旋随想曲》，那是我第一次被交响乐打动。我爸爸以前是广州黄埔造船厂的副厂长，厂里很多工程师都是留学苏联的，很多人都喜欢音乐。所以我家在1950年代就有电唱机，它播《蓝色的多瑙河》，也播很多广东音乐和粤剧。我的音乐启蒙就是这部唱机和另一台波罗的海收音机。大概14 岁时，我逼着我妈给我买了一把秦琴，琴一拿回家，我就立刻把我听过的所有广东音乐都弹了一遍。后来收音机在播红色娘子军的音乐，我就拿着小提琴跟着拉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;16岁的时候，广州粤剧团来我们学校招生，我被选进去了，因为我是学校里唯一会五线谱和会拉一点小提琴的学生，后来我又进到广州星海音乐学院作曲进修班学了一年半。到1980年代，有一些唱片公司来找我做配曲，相当于约稿，我也从那时开始成了自由音乐人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我第一次写歌词是《弯弯的月亮》，先有了几个音符，接着曲子和词交叠着写，半小时很快写完了。当时乐坛流行的是高亢、硬气的“西北风”，《弯弯的月亮》是典型的广东调，我说它是“整个被雨水淋出来的感觉”。好些年后我才意识到这首歌记下了珠江上以船为生的疍家人的生活，不仅仅是词本身的描述，就连曲的节奏也是疍家人摇橹的节奏。这个灵感来源于我小时候就住在珠江边，坐疍家人划的船过江，疍家人还背着一个襁褓划船，船只能坐四个人。我坐在船上听见他们在喊阿娇，阿娇是最常见的疍家人女孩的名字。只是现在在珠江上已经见不到疍家人了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;写这首歌时，没有音乐公司的委约，我也没有很确定想哪个歌手来唱。我第一个找到的是陈汝佳，陈汝佳来录之后，我一听就觉得不合适，于是就给刘欢打电话，问他在不在北京，让他明天录歌。刘欢也没听歌，电话里就答应了。我第二天就去北京，他下午就来录了。那时还没形成明星制的商业市场，所以和歌手之间的互动就是这么简单。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1980-90年代的广东，某种程度上说也是黄金年代，因为样样都是新的，而且日新月异。也许所有人都在怀旧，觉得过去的年代才是黄金年代。实际上那时整个经济基础并没有很高水平，但是浪潮中的人所展现的冲力和激情还是挺难得的。这个浪潮起了很大的推动作用，当时的广州不仅仅在音乐，包括媒体，比如电视台、电台、报业、广告，还包括影视剧，都走在前面。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/STJftJIqxtidMsGROGhEagOpstYMzv7sJHSJEd9e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/STJftJIqxtidMsGROGhEagOpstYMzv7sJHSJEd9e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252761&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘欢《弯弯的月亮》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《弯弯的月亮》创作于1980年代末，那时音乐界是西北风刮的正猛的时候，所以大家一听，觉得这首歌怎么这么特别、这么南方、这么柔软。当然，绝大部分人是很快接受的，只有行内很少的一些人觉得不合适，觉得跟整个时代的潮流不一样，那时候都是《我的故乡并不美》之类的东西。这个潮流背后都指向了1980年代的“寻根热”，比如油画《父亲》、电影《红高粱》，这一切都属于寻根文化，大家都往土里扎。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;因为姜文的电影《鬼子来了》，我从广州去北京做配乐，电影当时已经拍完开始剪辑，配乐有我和崔健、刘星三个人。那次到北京后我就没走了，开始把比较多的精力投入到影视配乐。从《背叛》《黑冰》到《亮剑》，有人说，怎么你把所有剧的配乐都给写了，我没有，只是正好那几部剧火了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;写完《七子之歌》之后，也有几年，我一直写来写去都写不好。有朋友跟我说李海鹰你已经好久没出过歌了，他这句话让我意识到这是个问题了，几年没有传唱度很高的歌，人家就觉得你的歌出不来了。一直到《爱如空气》这首歌，我光旋律就写了一个半月，后面效果不错，成了电视剧《幸福像花儿一样》的主题曲。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我还是一直想做交响乐，因为一些工作的契机，2003年我开始跟指挥家徐新老师学指挥。等到2007年，我又重新系统学习作曲。2008年我和一群本科学生到中央音乐学院上课。有次中央音乐学院的作曲系主任叫住我说，李海鹰你跑到这里干嘛？我说上课。他说，你跟谁上课？你别学坏了，学坏了就完了。我还是老老实实上课。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从粤剧，广东音乐，流行乐，到影视配乐，再到交响乐，我对音乐永远有新鲜感，永远当新人。时代大浪淘沙，我往往是没等这个浪潮退去我就去干别的了。比如说我做影视配乐，后来去做古典音乐，没有等到浪潮结束把我搞得走投无路，我早走了。我做古典乐算新人，到2016年才开始写大型作品。就保持这样的学习和谦逊、投入的状态，包括现在写音乐剧、歌剧，我也希望有创新。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;音乐是直接为人写的，是一种对话。还有一点，我并不主张自己的想法。我就写你的想法、你的感受。大家觉得艺术家总强调自己，但为什么要把“我”和“你”分开？我认为我不重要，我早就知道自己是有限的。这种观念也许会让我在表面上显得很没个性，但越往后我越觉得，我的音乐不是写我的，我的音乐想表达的是这个时代，表达的是你们和他们。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[铜绿山，大地深处的楚国秘密]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257334]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Climb up the steep steps. At the top of the mountain, there is a flat area. On the flat side, I saw that long-known plant. It is not eye-catching, slightly similar to the common broom grass in Sichuan, but shorter; it is also a bit like orchid grass, but with thinner leaves. It has not yet reached the flowering period, and there is no purple-red color like the clouds in the picture. If you look closely, it does look like a toothbrush. No wonder it is called toothbrush grass among the people. In fact, its scientific name is Haizhou Xiangnuo, and its other name is more widely known: Copper Grass Flower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to imagine how excited the ancestors who were looking for it were when they saw the coppergrass flowers all over the mountains and plains on this gentle hillside three thousand years ago. They were even ecstatic with excitement. Because the copper grass flower is a symbol of an important metal - wherever it grows, deep in the earth, there must be copper mines...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/5ofLItqyHH0Tl7WRalCsMJW6VkUfNdzcaSj4GY5C.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/22/10/28/5ofLItqyHH0Tl7WRalCsMJW6VkUfNdzcaSj4GY5C.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213168&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tonglushan ancient copper mine site is located in Three kilometers west of Daye City, Hubei Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Gifts&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The banquet was over, and King Chu Cheng gave it to those who came to see him Zheng Wengong gave a generous gift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This generous gift is estimated to be worth about 20,000 to 30,000 yuan based on today&#39;s market price. However, in the distant Spring and Autumn Period, its value could not be measured in terms of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is copper. When Zheng Wengong returned to Zheng State with a thousand kilograms of copper, King Chu Cheng regretted it more and more. He sent an envoy to catch up with Zheng Wengong - he must have wanted to take back the copper, but doing so would not only offend Zheng State, but also make people in the world joke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Chu Cheng’s regret had very clear practical considerations. In the pre-Qin period, the ancients classified the major affairs of the country into two things, namely &quot;the major affairs of the country are sacrifice and military affairs&quot; as stated in &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;. Although the original meaning of &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; refers to sacrificial rituals and military rituals, later generations further extended it and believed that the most important things in the country were sacrifices and wars. Both sacrifices and wars are inseparable from copper - sacrifices require a large number of bronze vessels to be cast; as for wars, copper is a necessity for making weapons. Compared with the stone, bone and wooden weapons of the Stone Age, copper weapons are invincible and have unparalleled superiority. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bronze originated in the Longshan Culture period. The Xia Dynasty began to enter the Bronze Age, while the Shang Dynasty and Zhou Dynasty reached the peak of bronze civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called bronze is an alloy of copper and tin or lead. It was called gold and lucky gold in ancient China. Among the chemical elements that make up bronze, the most important is copper, which accounts for more than 80%. Without copper, there would be no bronze; without bronze, there would be no bronze civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For King Chu Cheng, his regret was not about the thousand catties of copper. Copper, he had plenty of it. He was worried that Zheng Guo would take the copper back to make weapons. Therefore, he asked Zheng Wengong to promise that the copper donated by the Chu State could only be used for ritual vessels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tracing back to the origins of Chu State, it was once so humble that it could be ignored. In terms of level, among male princes, Bozi belongs to the fourth level: Zi. Regarding the initial land enfeoffment, it was only fifty miles away. There is a story that illustrates the weakness of the Chu people when they founded the country: After Xiong Yi was named the son of Chu, he built a temple. After the temple was completed and the first sacrifice was about to be held, it was discovered that they were so poor that they didn&#39;t even have a sacrificial cow. This &quot;country&quot; is so big, but it can&#39;t even produce a single cow, which shows how small and shabby this &quot;country&quot; is. Out of poverty, Xiong Yi took people to the neighboring country of Bo to steal a calf. After the calf was stolen back, Xiong Yi was afraid that the owner would come to visit him, so he had to kill the calf overnight to sacrifice it - and the rules at that time were that sacrifices were held during the day. Since then, the Chu people have formed a unique custom: all sacrifices are held at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like a trickle of water can gather into a mighty river, as long as enough time is given, a miracle may be born. For the Chu State, if it was like an unobtrusive flame in the wind when it was founded, then, after hundreds of years of continuous development, by the time of Xiong Tong, the son of Chu in the early Spring and Autumn Period, the Chu State had risen. Become an important presence among the princes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 704 BC, which was the thirty-seventh year of Xiong Tong&#39;s reign, he sent his followers to ask the Emperor of Zhou to promote him to a noble title. However, Emperor Zhou flatly refused. Xiong Tong was furious and proclaimed himself king, calling him King Wu of Chu. Although the Emperor of Zhou has lost his former authority since King Ping of Zhou moved eastward, the princes who dared to brag against the disapproval of the world and claim the title of king began with Xiong Tong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiong Tong dared to fight against the Emperor Zhou. On the one hand, due to the hard work of more than ten generations, the Chu State was no longer the small country with a lot of obstacles; on the other hand, after many years of hard work, the Chu people gradually controlled One of the most important strategic materials has the material basis to challenge Emperor Zhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is copper, copper from the Coppergreen Mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/HnrOGxJiZOSdrgXR10zG7Zpr8MN4jXcLRwGTIToa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/HnrOGxJiZOSdrgXR10zG7Zpr8MN4jXcLRwGTIToa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213165&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Azurite mine in Tonglu Mountain&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the northeast To the southwest, after crossing the Yangtze River via the Qijia Expressway, it enters Huangshi City, Hubei Province. To the north of the highway, there is a lake of tens of square kilometers, which is Daye Lake connected to the Yangtze River. The westernmost end of Daye Lake is Daye under the jurisdiction of Huangshi. Heading west out of Daye, the road twists and turns, passing through undulating low mountainous areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tonglu Mountain is hidden deep in this low mountainous area. The &quot;Daye County Chronicle&quot; published by Tongzhi in the Qing Dynasty explained the origin of the name Tonglu Mountain: &quot;The top of the mountain is high and flat, with huge rocks facing each other. Every time it rains, there are bronze greens like snowflakes and adzuki beans dotted on the earth and rocks. Hence the name. It stretches for several years. Zhang, the soil color is purple and red, and they are all Guanshan. It may be the place where copper was produced in ancient times.&quot; This green snowflake adzuki bean is actually malachite, which is a copper-containing carbonate mineral that is often associated with copper. The large amount of malachite washed out of the surface after a shower shows that the copper mine in Tonglushan is shallowly buried and of high grade, making it a rare rich mine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as China is concerned, copper resources are widely distributed and relatively concentrated. In general, the main copper mines are in the south. There is a rich copper ore belt in the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River - from Tonglu Mountain to Ruichang, more than 100 kilometers away, and to Tongling, more than 300 kilometers away, there are dots of large copper mines, with reserves accounting for one-third of the country. Two or more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rise of Chu State was also invincible due to the blessing of Tonglu Mountain. As the first metal mastered by human beings, a steady stream of high-grade copper ore is put into burning furnaces to smelt out massive amounts of copper, which is then combined with tin or lead to be upgraded to bronze - ritual vessels cast in bronze, lingering in the smoke. The temples made of bronze became a bridge between the Chu people and their ancestors and gods; the agricultural tools made of bronze allowed the vast land in the south to be reclaimed, and more food was enough to feed a larger population; the weapons made of bronze accompanied the Chu people who were brave and good at fighting. Charge into battle, expand territory...&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conquest&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Starting from Tonglu Mountain, a three-hour drive, nearly 300 kilometers away to the northwest is Suizhou City, Hubei Province. In Suizhou, the sensational tomb of Zeng Houyi was discovered. The most important cultural relic unearthed from the tomb of Zeng Houyi is now stored in the Hubei Provincial Museum, which is the bronze chime that can still play beautiful music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Hou is the king of Zeng State; and Zeng State is another name for Sui State, which was enfeoffed by Zhou Dynasty. Thousands of cultural relics were unearthed from the tomb of Marquis Yi of Zeng, among which the total weight of bronze products exceeds ten tons - the bronze chime alone weighs four tons. So much copper, where does it come from? In the past few years, professionals used chemical and spectral analysis on Zeng Houyi&#39;s chime bell, and compared it with the copper mine data unearthed from the Tonglushan archeology, and concluded that the copper material of Zenghou Yi&#39;s chime bell came from Tonglushan. ——Using the same method, it was also proved that the raw materials of the bronzes unearthed from Fuhao&#39;s tomb in Yinxu, Anyang, also came from Tonglu Mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/BUDkuuqJntNhn6I4gZ4OhMcUTYdeKFDanhoC1Wnb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/BUDkuuqJntNhn6I4gZ4OhMcUTYdeKFDanhoC1Wnb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213167&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zeng Houyi Bronze Chime Bell&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These conclusions are actually Within reason. Not only did the large amount of copper material in the tomb of Zeng Hou Yi come from the Tonglu Mountain, but even when the Emperor of Zhou was enfeoffed to follow the country, a very important reason was for copper. During the Shang and Zhou dynasties, there was a busy and important copper-tin road in the hinterland of China. That is what the bronze inscriptions call &quot;the path of gold and tin&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the National Museum of China, there is a bronze vessel named Zeng Boyun. The 簠 is a utensil used to serve rice during sacrifices or banquets. It is also called the 簋, the square one is called 簠 and the round one is called 簋. Zeng Boyun was used by the king of Zeng (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sui&lt;/span>;). The inscription on it contains the following sentences: &quot;...Kedi Huaiyi, suppress the Xiefan Tang, move the golden road and tin, and use all the tools to prepare the way.&quot; It means: (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zeng Bo&lt;/span>;) punish the Huaiyi , the transportation hub Fantang and the copper and tin channels have been stabilized and have returned to normal. This is the origin of Jindaoxixing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shang Dynasty moved its capital many times, but generally speaking, they were all in today&#39;s Central Plains region; the Western Zhou Dynasty made its capital Haojing, now Xi&#39;an; the Eastern Zhou Dynasty moved its capital to Luoyi, now Luoyang. During the heyday of the Bronze Age, the demand for copper and supporting tin for thousands of years during the Shang and Zhou dynasties was undoubtedly astronomical. In the vast north or the Yellow River Basin, only Zhongtiao Mountain and other places had copper mines, but the output was small. . The copper and tin needed by the Shang and Zhou Dynasties could only be transported thousands of miles from the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The general route of the Jindao Tin Line, which mainly transports copper and tin, is as follows: Hunan&#39;s tin and Tonglu Mountains and northern Jiangxi&#39;s copper, after being collected in the present-day Wuhan area, arrive in Suizhou via Xiaogan, along the Suizao Corridor. It entered the Nanyang Basin, then passed through present-day Fangcheng and Ye County to Luoyang, or continued westward to Guanzhong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is an extremely difficult transportation line. Two or three thousand years ago, when roads and railways were scarce and there were only rugged trails, the ancients could only rely on animals and manpower in addition to ships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long transportation lines mean more risks and more uncertainties. Especially when the transported items are copper that determines the fate of the country, the risks increase sharply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to ensure the smooth transportation of copper and tin from Tonglu Mountain and other places to the capital, Emperor Zhou enfeoffed more than a dozen small countries in important areas north of the Han River and south of the upper reaches of the Huai River. Most of these small countries have the surname Ji, or are related to the surname Ji, so they are called the Ji of Hanyang. The concubines of Hanyang had two tasks. One was to guard against Huaiyi in the south; the other was to ensure the smooth flow of the copper and tin road. After the decline of Huaiyi and the rise of Chu, the first task of Zhu Ji changed from guarding against Huaiyi to guarding against Chu. However, things are unpredictable. Not only did the concubines of Hanyang fail to curb Chu&#39;s northward and eastward advance, but even the copper-tin road they guaranteed and even the Tonglu Mountain that produced copper mines fell into the hands of the Chu people. In the end, &quot;Hanyang&quot; All concubines, the state of Chu is complete.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The countries established by the concubines of Hanyang are dotted in the intersection of north and south China, including Tang, Cai, Ying, Xi, Shen, Sui, etc. Among the concubines, Sui Guo is the most powerful and is the leader of them all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanyang Basin and Jianghan Plain are separated by a series of low and gentle mountains. Among them, there is a long and narrow plain between Dahong Mountain and Tongbai Mountain, both running northwest to southeast, which becomes the link between Nanyang Basin and Jianghan Plain. traffic channels between. This tunnel is bounded by Suizhou in the south and Zaoyang in the north, so it is called the Suizao Corridor. As the eldest among the concubines in Hanyang, Sui Guo follows the gateway of the Zao Corridor and connects to the Yangtze River through the Jianshui River. Copper from Tonglu Mountain and more distant places such as Ruichang and Tongling can be traced up the river, passing through the Sui Zao Corridor and then north. Transport to the Central Plains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/27/0db5OdAetgUKAOX0yDkVnWKje30RWBDgAHTMIkrd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1331&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/27/0db5OdAetgUKAOX0yDkVnWKje30RWBDgAHTMIkrd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The war between the Chu State and the Chu State for the Tonglu Mountain was The era of King Wu kicked off; the main target of the war was Sui Guo - before this, King Wu of Chu annexed Quan State and established counties on Quan State&#39;s territory, which was the beginning of China&#39;s county system. At this time, the power of the Chu State penetrated deep into the Jianghan Plain, and the fertile Jianghan Plain was being eroded bit by bit by the Chu people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the set goal, King Chu Wu showed great patience - he has been waiting, looking for opportunities while waiting - King Chu Wu waited from his middle age until his twilight years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 706 BC, Sui suffered from a drought, resulting in a massive reduction in grain production and a lack of food for the soldiers and civilians. King Wu of Chu took the opportunity to attack Sui. The Chu army came to the city, and the princes knew that they were no match, so they had to send people to King Wu of Chu to ask for peace. King Wu of Chu accepted the peace talks, and one of the conditions was that he would ask the Emperor of Zhou to be promoted to the title of Chu Kingdom. The first expedition against Sui and the establishment of an alliance under the city with the country meant that the Chu people had already gotten involved in the road of copper and tin, and from then on they could obtain a steady stream of high-quality copper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years later, Sui, who had an alliance with Chu, refused to attend the alliance led by Chu. King Chu Wu used this as an excuse to attack Sui for the second time. This time, the Chu army was defeated and the Sui army fled. Even the chariot was captured by the Chu army. Also in this year, Suihou informed King Wu of Chu that the Emperor of Zhou refused to promote him to the title. Therefore, King Wu of Chu became angry and proclaimed himself king. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next three years, Chu defeated a series of countries including Yun, Jiu, Zhou, Deng and Liao. These countries either became vassals of Chu or had to fight with Chu. Make an alliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in 699 BC, when attacking Luo State, Chu State general Qu Xia was conceited and underestimated the enemy. He was defeated by the coalition forces of Luo State and Lu State. Qu Xia committed suicide. ——Since then, the Chu State has formed an unwritten rule: any commander who leads troops to fight must commit suicide to apologize once he is defeated. This determination, soaked in the bones and blood of Chu people, was passed down to the last commander-in-chief, Xiang Yu, the overlord of Western Chu who would rather commit suicide than return to Jiangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Wu of Chu had to slow down the pace of his campaign. For the next eight years, King Wu of Chu did not raise any more troops to attack his followers. He concentrated his efforts and swept away Luo, Lu, Yan, Zhou and Liao, and firmly controlled the Jianghan Plain. It should be during this period that the Tonglu Mountain also belonged to the Chu State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When everything came to pass, King Wu of Chu attacked him for the third time. Because Suiguo is not only an important stronghold on the copper-tin road, but also a springboard for Chu to fight for hegemony northward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the eve of the expedition, he felt heart discomfort during the sacrifice and knew that his days were numbered. Sure enough, when the Chu army crossed the Han River and King Wu of Chu was sitting under a sycamore tree by the roadside to rest, he could never stand up again - this king who advocated force and was determined to expand his territory died like this. On the journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the death of King Chu Wu, the Chu army continued to advance towards the capital of Sui without announcing the funeral. When Suihou saw the army approaching the border, he was frightened and sent people to sue for peace. From then on, Suiguo, who was originally loyal to the Emperor of Zhou and monitored the south for the Emperor of Zhou and guarded the copper and tin road, became a vassal of Chu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the death of King Chu Wu, King Chu Wen came to the throne. The first thing King Wen of Chu did when he came to power was to move the capital from the remote Danyang to Ying. The Chu State had moved its capital many times. After the first move to Ying, the subsequent capitals were all called Ying or Yingdu. The place where King Wen of Chu moved to Ying is said to be Jingzhou or Yicheng. No matter who is right, the indisputable fact is that the power of Chu State has crossed the Han River from west to east. During the reign of King Chu Wen, he successively destroyed the State of Shen, Xi and Deng, repeatedly defeated the State of Cai, and made a northern expedition to the State of Zheng - this was also the beginning of the Chu State&#39;s quest to dominate the Central Plains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After King Chu Wen, King Chu Cheng went to a higher level and successively annexed more than ten small countries such as Er, Gu, Huang, Ying, Jiang, and Fang. The State of Zheng, which borders the State of Chu, was on the fence between Jin and Chu. This is how Zheng Wengong went to see King Chu Cheng, and King Chu Cheng gave him a thousand catties of copper. However, King Chu Cheng was born at the wrong time - he met Duke Huan of Qi, the most powerful of the Five Hegemons of the Spring and Autumn Period. In order to teach the Chu State a lesson, Qi Huangong led the coalition forces deep into the Chu territory. Although the two sides did not decide the winner, the Chu State had to admit its mistake to the coalition forces and recognize Qi State&#39;s dominance. By the time of King Chuzhuang, the grandson of King Chu Cheng, this soaring and blockbuster King of Chu defeated the northern superpower Jin, thus becoming one of the five hegemons of the Spring and Autumn Period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The history of the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period is a history of princes fighting against each other. In the merger of big fish eating small fish and small fish eating shrimps, small countries continued to disappear and big countries grew bigger like a snowball. Among the princes, the Chu State destroyed the most, with more than fifty people. At its peak, Chu State ranked first in territory, equivalent to the sum of other princes. It can be said that if it were not for the incompetence of several generations of Chu kings in the late Warring States Period, it would have been more likely to be the Chu State that wiped out the heroes, rather than the Qin State located in the northwest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the Chu people’s illustrious military exploits, Tonglu Mountain was the silent and lasting first driving force, creating the miracles of the Bronze Age. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Ruins&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Tonglushan Ancient Copper Mine Ruins Museum is located on the hill where coppergrass flowers sway. There are few tourists, and the copper grass flowers are looking at themselves in the wind. On the other side of the hill, I saw a huge pit like a funnel embedded between the peaks. The pit sank hundreds of meters below the surface and was hundreds of meters in diameter. A road winding like a snake passed by a factory with thick smoke. Reaching into the pit, trucks crawled like beetles. This is the open-pit copper mine that is still being mined today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/9uJBUw2mJkQOkjCfGS5hm1oryhTPWo0UgpL6g2iZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1441&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/9uJBUw2mJkQOkjCfGS5hm1oryhTPWo0UgpL6g2iZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;213166&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tonglushan Open-pit Copper Mine&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1973, the It was while working in this open-pit mine that the miners of the Nonferrous Metallurgical Company dug out thirteen rusty copper axes from the ground. Later, using thirteen copper axes that had been dormant for thousands of years as clues, archaeologists followed the clues and unearthed seven open-pit mines, 18 underground mining areas, more than 50 ancient smelting sites and More than ten smelting shaft furnaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reappearance of ancient copper mines under the earth not only reveals the secret of the rise of Chu State, but also proves that Chinese bronze culture is not foreign, but originated from the mainland. Archaeological evidence shows that the mining of Tonglushan copper mines began in the late Shang Dynasty, and continued through the Western Zhou Dynasty, the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period to the Han Dynasty, which lasted for thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the museum, large and small copper slags are displayed in glass cabinets - things that look either slightly yellow or slightly green. Archaeologists estimate that there are as many as 400,000 tons of copper slag in the entire Tonglushan site. Based on rough calculations based on copper slag, Tonglushan produces about 120,000 tons of copper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The figure of 120,000 tons is a bit empty. If you convert it, you will know how huge it is: the Shang Dynasty Stepmother Wu Ding unearthed in Anyang (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Simuwu Dafang Ding&lt;/span>;) is the heaviest bronze in China so far, weighing more than 800 kilograms. 120,000 tons can be used to cast 140,000 statues. Some people have made another calculation: the main equipment of soldiers in the Spring and Autumn Period was copper ge, each weighing about half a kilogram and 120,000 tons, enough to make 240 million pieces. Of course, not all of the 120,000 tons of copper from Tonglu Mountain is exclusively owned by the Chu State. However, in the mining history of more than a thousand years from the late Shang Dynasty to the Western Han Dynasty, Chu State accounted for about half of the mining time. This was the golden age of Tonglu Mountain. The Chu people obtained at least tens of thousands of tons of high-quality copper from the depths of Tonglu Mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When King Zhuang of Chu aspired to conquer the Central Plains, he proudly said to Wang Sunman, a minister of Emperor Zhou, &quot;The beak of Chu&#39;s broken hook is enough to make nine tripods.&quot; This means that as long as the sharp edges of Chu&#39;s weapons are taken off, it will be enough to be melted into Jiuding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The massive amount of copper in Tonglu Mountain proves that King Chuzhuang was not exaggerating at all. His Chu country, whether it is the civil governance of the alliance princes or the martial arts of conquering cities and territories; whether it is the stubborn and domineering character of the Chu people or the Chu music of Hong Zhongda Lu; whether it is the gloomy Chu Feng that respects ghosts or the soul-stirring Chu Ci—— They are all based on copper, with copper as their bones, and with copper as their foundation...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10 /28/TngRunAON2E2ufuol8qlegxPuW9w8r9SziHNBJWV.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/10/28/TngRunAON2E2ufuol8qlegxPuW9w8r9SziHNBJWV. jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;213164&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Viewers look at the early Spring and Autumn shaft furnace model unearthed from Tonglu Mountain in the National Museum of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tonglu Mountain, those long-standing mines go deep underground and extend in all directions like a maze. Some of the wood that was laid down two to three thousand years ago to support the tunnels has not yet rotted. Walking cautiously in the restored mine, the tunnel is narrow and damp. I can&#39;t help but think of the Chu miners who worked all day long with a torch in the belly of the earth in Tonglu Mountain more than two thousand years ago. Whether they are swinging a heavy copper ax to hit the hard rock formation, or dragging a bamboo basket full of copper ore along the tunnel, the labor day after day and year after year makes them like worker bees dying. The power and glory of the Chu State, the hegemony of King Wu and King Wen, and the grand plans of King Cheng and Zhuang, they have contributed a lot, but history will not leave their names. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Main reference books: &quot;Historical Records&quot;, &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot;, &quot;Chu History&quot;, &quot;A Brief History of Chu State&quot;, &quot;Spring and Autumn History&quot; China&#39;s Pre-Qin Copper Mines&quot; &quot;Metallurgical Archeology&quot; &quot;Chinese Bronze&quot; &quot;Loess and Bronze&quot; &quot;Daye County Chronicles&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访陈冲：我没有强大的自信，只有强大的欲望]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257475]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 09/22/wZhQcinkVpws8y7jI3ZKp7XYc6l6VWrqUGmQWVtU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1439&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/22/wZhQcinkVpws8y7jI3ZKp7XYc 6l6VWrqUGmQWVtU. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;209385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1981, Chen Chong studied film production in the United States and directed his first film in 1998 &quot;Heavenly Bath&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an actor, Chen Chong is well known, and as a director, Chen Chong is well known. few. Chen Chong is one of the three directors of the movie &quot;Her in the World&quot; to be released on September 9, 2022, the other two are Sylvia Chang and Li Shaohong. The film tells an emotional story under difficult circumstances, involving mother-in-law and daughter-in-law, couples and lovers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2020, Chen Chong received a call from producer Dong Wenjie, hoping to invite several well-known female directors to jointly shoot a movie. She finally decided to tell the story of a pair of lovers separated in two places, &quot;to explore the closest expression of the oldest theme of love.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like all previous works she directed, Chen Chong wrote the script herself. She repeatedly looked at the real photos taken by her colleagues. There was a supermarket scene in the movie, so she found many supermarket CCTVs and watched them, wanting to know details such as the denseness of the crowds. The script was originally written to rain, and the rendering of rain was used to increase the atmosphere, but later she learned that there was no rain in reality on the day set in the movie, so she removed this setting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Without the rain, wouldn&#39;t the story have happened? Wouldn&#39;t the feelings be conveyed? So, whether there is rain or not is not important, but whether there is the conveyance of emotions is important.&quot; She said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Her in the World&quot; was originally scheduled to be released on the May Day holiday in 2021, but was later postponed to the Mid-Autumn Festival in 2022. During the editing of the film, a Southern Weekend staff writer interviewed Chen Chong in Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Love and loss are eternal&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;The setting of this movie sounds a bit like Love in the Time of Cholera. When you were approaching this story, did you have a clear setting from the beginning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After receiving the invitation from the producer, I searched online for a week and finally found this story about lovers who were exiled in two places. Touched me. The girl returned to Beijing to visit her parents during the Spring Festival, but she has not been able to see her boyfriend who was locked down in Wuhan since then. This melody of love, loss, and exile resonated with me—I too am unable to travel home to visit my elderly parents due to the pandemic. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For lovers who are blocked in two cities, the mobile phone screen is something that arouses their infinite desire and is warmer than real life. In fact, this is also the relationship between most people and their mobile phones. Especially during the epidemic, people’s interactions with others and their understanding of the world come from mobile phones. The contradictions and conflicts in human nature also come from people&#39;s different interpretations of online messages. We all seem to be living on isolated islands in our mobile phones. The more attractive &quot;reality&quot; on the screen seems more &quot;real&quot; than life itself. The themes of love and loss, life and death are ancient and timeless, and my challenge was to give it a new screen narrative for today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you ever considered adding a paragraph about their love history? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Absolutely no flashbacks. This story is that these two people are always in different frames, and they want you to be deeply moved by them. These are the rules I set for myself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the era of the epidemic, two people can only use mobile phones What love words can a lover say during a video call? What excites you about the process of writing a screenplay? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Their conversations are actually very simple conversations, the most daily and common conversations. My husband and I often do this too. Video communication. These two people are in love. They video chat when they wake up in the morning, before going to bed at night, and while cooking and brushing teeth. They chat casually in separate places, but it makes people feel the joy and love of two people together. , this is my excitement point. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of the emotional tone expressed in this story? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a story about true love. If a person can love like this once, he is very lucky. Not everyone can love like this. Because he has had real happiness, and the sadness of loss is sublimated into the beauty in the black mirror. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people in the world are actually not satisfied with love in their hearts. So I believe it, but the desire and demand for love still seems very strong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After we finished filming, several of the main creators climbed Xiangshan Mountain. After climbing to the top, they saw many people writing blessing signs. . I said let’s hang one too, and we wrote our blessings for the movie and hung it there. I looked through it carefully, and there were hundreds of tags, and there were countless love words in them. They were all &quot;So-and-so loves so-and-so&quot; and &quot;So-and-so will be with so-and-so forever.&quot; More than half of them, you can Did you say that love is gone?不可能。 When you fall in love, can you stop yourself? Even this bit of vitality is gone, and your life has been in vain. This thing is different from desire. It is really a gift from God to you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Princess Sissi is the Empress of Austria. She has extremely happy resources and unlimited money, and her husband loves her very much. He has worshiped her and been obsessed with her all his life, but she is not happy. I don’t know how the paradox in life is formed. Is love the greatest value of happiness in life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, this is a gift. You don’t need to be good enough or work hard. You don’t need to do your homework. You don’t need to move bricks. You don&#39;t need anything, it will come to you. Maybe love won&#39;t be important in the future, I don&#39;t know, I can&#39;t imagine it. Why refuse such a gift? I can&#39;t imagine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The role starring Yi Yang Qianxi, at the beginning Is it just set at the age of two or three years after graduating from college? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Absolutely. We met in college, have been in love for four years, and are about to get married. He is the happiest young man after graduating from college. period. The simplest dream of having this simple college sweetheart is to get married, the girl can wear a wedding dress, and the boy can put a ring on her. The definition of disaster is when the simplest dreams are destroyed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From a distant perspective, love is a An ordinary story is about a man and a woman falling in love. Your film is set in a specific time and space. What happened in this love story? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, movies are just such a thing. There is no need to make sense, and there is no reason to make love. It’s not that you think this person is a good match for this person, that has nothing to do with it. I&#39;m going to give you something that I believe you will believe. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/22/AyDbJY0ejP1bgC5wplwp0rFOdfYLmKYPeg1imHQZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1439&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/22/AyDbJY0ejP1bgC5wplwp0rFOdfYLmKYPeg1imHQZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;209384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Chong directed a short film in &quot;Her in the World&quot;, telling the story of a pair of lovers who were separated in two places during the epidemic. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I can see clues of my dishonesty”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you studied directing in the United States? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I studied TV production and took some directing classes, but that directing class was completely useless. In fact, film is an apprenticeship, and film school comes later. When the movie first started, everyone was learning on the spot, apprentice-style. The kind of learning from a master should be more useful. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You directed the first film &quot;Tianba&quot; When you were young, you cut it yourself. By then, did you already have strong confidence to complete it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no strong self-confidence, only strong desire. I&#39;m not a particularly confident person, and self-doubt is a big part of my thinking. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;But outsiders see that you have many successes, which proves that you Qualified to do it yourself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I will always think that it is a coincidence, that it is a misunderstanding, that it is confusing people. I think so, In fact, this may be the case. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have you ever gone to the cinema to watch your own movie? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Very few. I&#39;ve seen it, but it&#39;s quite unbearable. I actually have a very sensitive radar. I can see the clues of my own dishonesty. Maybe others can’t see it, but I can definitely see it. So watching your own movies is not an easy task. Movies are not an actor&#39;s tool, but a director&#39;s tool, so you are a pawn in it. If you see your own problems, it does not affect your feeling that the movie is pretty good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The films you directed are all because of yourself Do you have the desire to create, or do you have to find funds or outside sources? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Chong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Both. If funds come to me and I don’t have the desire, I will definitely not go. Because being a director is quite hard for me and not an easy thing.我不是一个天才导演，我也不是一个技术型导演，才华有限、技术有限，如果我还没有一个强烈的叙事欲望，那这件事情根本没法做了。所以肯定是要有强烈的叙事欲望才会去做的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你导演的电影都是你自己来编剧？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我必须，因为这对我来说不难。我当然希望得到志同道合主创的意见和提示，还有很多大家共同做的资料，因为我觉得资料是给我写剧本最好的东西。但是剧本其实就是我闭上眼睛脑子里看到的那部电影，我先把它写下来，主创全部进入以后，它肯定会有改变。但是起先写下来的就是你脑子里看到的那部电影，所以没有那么难。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你第一次站到奥斯卡舞台上是？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;《末代皇帝》。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那一刻是有很大的满足感吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;也没有，我年轻时对工作、对这些事情都不是特别在乎，就在乎谈恋爱。其实工作，是给我一个机会缓冲一下，它一次次把我从感情的漩涡里拯救出来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你说过那时候的主业是谈恋爱，现在会觉得那些时光是一种浪费吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;不浪费。我不知道什么是浪费的，一个劲儿地做自己不想做的事，可能是有点浪费的。比如谈恋爱，如果是做了自己想做的事，但那个事很荒唐或者错了，或者给你自己带来了很大的损失，我觉得仍然不能算浪费。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你上过舞台吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我不敢。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为我恐惧人群，我特别恐惧人群。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;中国国内电影确实很少上点年岁的女性角色，你自己有没有概念很厚实的女性角色？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很少，太少了，尤其是目前的电影文化，崇尚青春，对女人的要求和标准仍然是……你知道吧。你的丰富、你的灵魂、你的复杂，它没有一个载体，因为你的躯体没有被接受，它在哪儿安家呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你做电影会下意识要讨好女性受众吗，考虑她们怎么想的，还要不能触怒她们。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;你的责任是诚实，你的责任不是讨好，你的责任就应该是表达你自己。我拍电影，我从来不会考虑我应该为女性拍电影，我毫无这个负担。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“把这场戏放在真人秀里，怎么演都如同嚼蜡”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;媒体记者有时候会下意识把你的角色都连接起来，比如婉容、红玫瑰，可能角色里那些强悍的，能够争取自己权益的人，认为她们是女性主义的英雄，你会有这样的连接吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我当时演婉容或者演《红玫瑰与白玫瑰》，或者演姜文的电影，我从来没有想过女性的权利、女性的地位、女性的任何，从来没有考虑过。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你拍《红玫瑰与白玫瑰》的时候喜欢张爱玲吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我喜欢张爱玲，但我不是一个张迷。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;女性作家里你喜欢谁？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;玛格丽特·杜拉斯，写《情人》的，《飘》，都是一些老的，还有波兰作者奥尔加·托卡尔丘克，2018年诺贝尔获奖作家。我特别喜欢李碧华写的《烟花三月》。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;芦苇谈电影《霸王别姬》时说，李碧华的原版小说是一个二流小说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有时候一流小说真的改不了电影，你想想它已经一流了，你还能把它怎么样？就是要二流、三流的才能给它改成电影，让它更上一层楼。李碧华的书我并不太喜欢，但是《烟花三月》我看了，非常震惊。一个朋友送给我，我在火车上开始看，看到第六七十页的时候，我说有点难，这个有点太苦了，她说你坚持一下，会有回报的。我坚持看完了，极大的回报。只有长篇才能够给你这样的满足感，没有办法在任何其他地方得到，满足的同时又那么的遗憾，怎么看完了，太好看了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你写过你女儿9岁的时候，要的生日礼物就是书和游泳，读书这个传统是你小时候的家庭环境造成的吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实我小的时候没什么书，没什么好看的。我外婆有一个小箱子，里头有一些外国带回来的东西，有一些连环画什么的，董存瑞还是焦裕禄的传记，能看的东西其实特别少。我外婆有一套契诃夫的短篇，那时候已经不全了，就那么零零碎碎地读。因为他们喜欢读，我也喜欢读，我母亲那时候阻止我读，因为她觉得这个不好，最好做点功课、做家务、出去玩儿。我妈是一个医学科学家，退休以后就光看小说，喜欢看小说。这两天我还在看她的书架，中外书籍特全，王安忆、池莉、陈忠实，纳博科夫的《洛丽塔》、海明威的《老人与海》，看得特别杂。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你自己的阅读是怎样的，杂吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;没有一个规范的东西，也看过一些比方说言情小说。看马尔克斯的书，就很震惊，我那时候英语不好，刚到美国不久，《百年孤独》看得好累，查字典又不像现在按一下就给你解释了，我看得非常累、非常慢。我就震惊，书是这样写吗？所以很杂、非常杂。在国内的时候就看过，不知道从哪儿觅到了卡夫卡也看。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;写作在你的生活中占一个什么样的比例？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;不重的比例。疫情期间因为关在家里，有这样一个奢侈，不是一个常态，不是说每天必须写。但是我喜欢文字，我隔离的时候就会写。我上小学、上中学都没怎么读书，中学读了还不到一个学期就去上影了。国内古典的书籍都没有看过，真正的教育是留学以后的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最近这几年国内好几档表演节目，你去参加过真人秀吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈冲：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;参加过一个，没把我给羞死。有一次节目里让一个人演我之前扮演的婉容的一段戏，然后让我评论。我说这个怎么能评论呢，这个是不能评论的，因为无数个大师为我营造了这样一个环境和气氛。没有了电影本身的魔力，把这场戏放在真人秀里，怎么演都如同嚼蜡。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[20岁的她会是中国女子网球的希望吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257924]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 15:00:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/29/J49b237SL4yZBk0wxflFj4doMIOdarYuYzsro5qS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/J49b237SL4yZBk0wxflFj4doMIOdarYuY zsro5qS. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 29, 2023, in the women’s singles tennis final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Zheng Qinwen won 2 Defeated Zhu Lin 0-0 and won the championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The women&#39;s tennis at the Asian Games that ended on September 29, 2023 In the singles final, Chinese player Zheng Qinwen defeated teammate Zhu Lin in straight sets 6:2, 6:4 and won the gold medal in the women&#39;s singles tennis event at the Hangzhou Asian Games. This is the first time that 20-year-old Zheng Qinwen has participated in the Asian Games. With Zheng Qinwen and Zhu Lin winning both the championship and runner-up, the Chinese women&#39;s tennis team achieved its fifth consecutive Asian Games title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2022, Zheng Qinwen reached the top 16 at the French Open, setting a new age for a Chinese female tennis player to reach the top 16 in a Grand Slam event, and attracted the attention of the world&#39;s tennis community. In the first half of 2023, her state had some ups and downs, but she recovered at the US Open and reached the top 8, once again setting a personal best. Zheng Qinwen, who only turned 21 in October this year, has just begun his career. The excellent results have given fans high expectations for this Hubei girl: After Li Na, the representative Chinese female tennis player, retires, will she, who is also from Hubei, be the next hope for Chinese women&#39;s tennis? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/WBGP66uN3qIInLbWR6KFYC7U06hMeuAE5yJwTZRZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/WBGP66uN3qIInLbWR6KFYC7U06hMeuAE5yJwTZRZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252801&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 29, 2023, Zheng Qinwen returned the ball in the women&#39;s singles tennis final of the Hangzhou Asian Games&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Rocket Girl&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, tennis player Li Na officially retired. In her 15-year career, she reached the WTA women&#39;s singles finals 21 times and won a total of 9 WTA and 19 ITF singles championships, including the 2011 French Open and the 2014 Australian Open women&#39;s singles championships. She is Asia&#39;s first Grand Slam women&#39;s singles champion. She was once ranked second in the world&#39;s women&#39;s tennis singles rankings, with a total career record of 503 wins and 188 losses. When she retired, she was ranked sixth in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Na&#39;s retirement has left an insurmountable peak and a huge vacuum for Chinese women&#39;s tennis. She has retired for more than nine years. At least so far, there has not been a player in Chinese women&#39;s tennis who can surpass her or even be on par with her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, when Li Na lifted her first Suzanne Langland Cup at Roland Garros in Paris, 9-year-old Zheng Qinwen was receiving tennis training in Wuhan under Li Na’s former coach Teacher Yu Liqiao. In her memory, it seemed that people all over the country were paying attention to Li Na&#39;s game that day. &quot;Li Na&#39;s victory planted a dream in me. One day I will also win a Grand Slam.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That was the third year that Zheng Qinwen officially started tennis training. In 2008, Zheng Qinwen&#39;s father took her to Beijing to watch the tennis match at the Olympic Games. Zheng Qinwen thought quietly. After the game, she and her father repeatedly discussed the details on the court and told her father that she was very interested in tennis. His father was once an athlete. He took Zheng Qinwen to play table tennis, badminton, basketball, and volleyball... His daughter was able to get started, but she was not outstanding. This time, he decided to let Zheng Qin play tennis. The coaches at Zheng Qinwen&#39;s hometown Shiyan Sports Center recognized her talent very much and believed that the power bursting out of her body was much higher than that of her peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2014, Zheng Qinwen participated in the 12-year-old category of the National Youth Tennis Ranking Tournament and won the singles and doubles championships in one fell swoop. In the same year, the Shiyan Tennis Team she led participated in the 14th Hubei Provincial Games and won 2 gold medals. Her serving speed reached 169 kilometers per hour, which was outstanding in the country and the world at that time. Therefore, she was hailed as a &quot;genius girl&quot; by many domestic sports commentators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qinwen successfully entered the Beijing Wheel of Ingenuity Tennis School and received the guidance of Li Na’s mentor Carlos. Zheng Qinwen gradually grew from a talented player to a mature player with no shortcomings and comprehensive skills. In 2015, Zheng Qinwen won the championship in the 14-year-old group (12 to 14 years old) of the European Youth Tennis Tour. She has participated in many national and world tennis events and achieved outstanding results. When she was 16 years old, she participated in the French Open, Wimbledon, and US Open youth competitions, reaching the top 16 in each of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, my father contacted Spanish male tennis player Pere Riba, who had just retired as a coach, and the two parties decided to cooperate. Zheng Qinwen started training in Spain under the care of his mother. From Monday to Saturday, he had 2 hours of tennis training in the morning, 1 hour of physical training, and 2 hours of tennis training in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2020, tennis competitions that were temporarily suspended due to the new crown epidemic resumed, and Zheng Qinwen began to participate frequently. In an interview with the media, Zheng Qinwen recalled that in order to more conveniently compete in Europe, the team would drive around Europe, driving from Barcelona to Germany, Italy and the Czech Republic. The furthest trip took 22 hours on the road. She didn&#39;t want to be eliminated in the first round and have to take a 22-hour drive home, so she worked very hard after playing. In order to maintain the best competitive condition, she hardly used the Internet during the competition, and even turned off her mobile phone when she arrived at the competition venue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2022, 19-year-old Zheng Qinwen participated in the French Open for the first time. She defeated Zanievska, Halep, and Koné successively, reaching the top 16 of the tournament, refreshing China The youngest age for a female tennis player to reach the top 16 in a Grand Slam tournament. In the fourth round, she faced Swiatek, ranked No. 1 in the world and the last French Open champion. The first set took more than 80 minutes. Zheng Qinwen broke Swiatek&#39;s 37-day record of no opponent winning a single set. He won the &quot;tiebreak&quot; 7-5 and won the first set with difficulty. In the second set, Zheng Qinwen suffered from a right thigh injury that affected his performance. In the end, he lost 1:2 and missed the top 8. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Zheng Qinwen unfortunately stopped in the top 16 of the French Open, but the comprehensive skills and playing temperament she displayed made fans all over the world remember &#39;Chinese Zheng&#39;. The potential shown by Zheng Qinwen makes us believe that this season She will also bring more surprises!&quot; People&#39;s Daily reported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, when Zheng Qinwen first entered the professional arena, he was ranked 630th in the world. In the following more than two years, Zheng Qinwen won 8 ITF championships. He made history in his first Grand Slam tournament, reaching the second round of the Australian Open, the top 16 of the French Open, the top 32 of Wimbledon, and the top 32 of the US Open. WTA named him the &quot;Best Rookie of the 2022 Season&quot;. Because of her extremely fast rise in rankings, Zheng Qinwen was called the &quot;Rocket Girl&quot;. At the beginning of 2022, she promised to enter the top 30 in the world rankings, and at the end of the season, her ranking rose to 27th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/qFP5ZUAxB24XmnPICsOAUT3BD2qtDUSWZNNcpqVd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/qFP5ZUAxB24XmnPICsOAUT3BD2qtDUSWZNNcpqVd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252802&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 23, 2023, in the women&#39;s singles final of the Women&#39;s Tennis Players Association (WTA) 250 Palermo Station, Zheng Qinwen defeated Italian player Paolini 2-1 and won The first tour championship in her career &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Women&#39;s Tennis Players Association (WTA) official social account/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Queen Wen&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the new season starts in 2023, Zheng Qinwen vows to enter the top ten in the world rankings. In the first half of the year, she went through a difficult downturn. In the 2023 Australian Open and French Open, Zheng Qinwen failed in the second round one after another. Before the start of Wimbledon, Zheng Qinwen changed coaches, replacing Spanish coach Riba with famous Belgian coach Wim Fiset, who has coached Naomi Osaka, Azarenka and other famous players. However, the grass court season was still hard for her to win, and Wimbledon ended with a first-round trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview, Zheng Qinwen said: &quot;Although I didn&#39;t play well in the grass-court season, I don&#39;t think my (strength) will decline. I will still work hard and prepare for the next stop. Change. The team must have had an impact, but I don’t think the loss was due to the coach.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before participating in the US Open, Zheng Qinwen went to Italy to participate in the WTA250 Palermo Station. She went all the way and won her first WTA tour-level championship in her career, and began to get out of the slump. &quot;This championship is hard-won. After experiencing failures, tears, regrets and disappointments, I finally tasted the taste of victory. I believe this is just the beginning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a series of games before the US Open, Zheng Qinwen defeated Venus Williams and other famous players. After the start of the US Open, she quickly entered the state. Compared with before, she appeared calmer and more patient, with more swings and more frequent changes in long and short balls. She successfully broke into the top 16 of the US Open and expressed emotion in the interview: &quot;At the beginning of the year, I thought that reaching the second week of a Grand Slam was a basic operation, but I didn&#39;t expect that I would not have such a result until the last Grand Slam of the year. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, she defeated the 2022 tournament runner-up and No. 5 seed Kareem Abdul-Jabbar, creating the best Grand Slam record in her career and becoming the sixth woman in the Open era to enter the Grand Slam singles. /China Tennis Association players in the 4 finals. And this is only the second year that 20-year-old Zheng Qinwen has participated in a Grand Slam event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/OupjPNbKeMoXxPxbAPcVt9xOYBTg1fiYSpWsyP99.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/OupjPNbKeMoXxPxbAPcVt9xOYBTg1fiYSpWsyP99.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 28, 2023, in the women&#39;s singles tennis semifinals of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Zheng Qinwen signed autographs for fans&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qinwen’s experience is a sample of the new generation of tennis players - he started playing tennis out of interest, received professional and international training since childhood, made independent choices, and did not take any detours. A relatively smooth growth process shaped her confident attitude and unruly temperament. During interviews, she often makes some sharp remarks. On August 12, 2022, in the third round of women&#39;s singles at the WTA1000 Toronto Station, Zheng Qinwen defeated Andreescu 7-5, 5-7, 6-2 and entered the quarterfinals of the WTA1000 competition for the first time. When asked if he would celebrate after reaching the top 8, Zheng Qinwen said: &quot;I will only celebrate after winning. I will be sad if I don&#39;t win.&quot; After the game, he talked about the match with former US Open champion Andreescu. , Zheng Qinwen responded domineeringly: &quot;I am stronger than her.&quot; When asked if he would work hard to win the US Open seed, Zheng Qinwen said: &quot;It really doesn&#39;t matter. My philosophy has always been that no matter who my opponent is, I Just do your best and strive to win.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her speech became an indicator of the player&#39;s personality, and she was called &quot;Queen Wen&quot; by fans. At the US Open, fans called her &quot;Queen Wen&quot; from the sidelines. Zheng Qinwen enjoys this title very much, &quot;Of course I know, I like the name Queen Wen very much. After all, this is the Queen!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than half of the 2023 season has passed, and Zheng Qinwen is far from the top 10 in the world. There is still some distance. In an interview, she was asked why she always sets her goals very high, and why she always likes to speak out and take the initiative to withstand scrutiny from the outside world? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/hQ7JJXROxkfoyIlo0v8iU3ExH2k7g3YygxTB8n8T.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;636&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/hQ7JJXROxkfoyIlo0v8iU3ExH2k7g3YygxTB8n8T.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252804&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 4, 2023, in the fourth round of the women&#39;s singles match at the 2023 US Open, Chinese player Zheng Qinwen defeated Tunisian player Jabeul 2-0 and advanced to the eighth round. Qiang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qinwen replied: &quot;Sometimes pressure is actually necessary and can motivate me to do better. . If there is no pressure and you always stay at the same level, you will not be able to keep moving forward. I play tennis because of my love. I hope that I am always in a state of progress. Top players are also constantly improving, which I admire very much. A little bit of them. I can’t imagine the pain it would cause me to stand still.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>