<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[国家烟草专卖局原局长凌成兴落马，反腐震荡至烟草系统最高级别]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259432]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/27/JQJFMogZw7WnI1B7dpthiLXvmzRWXL7acvFQXdak.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/27/JQJFMogZw7WnI1B7dpthiLXvmzRWXL 7acvFQXdak. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ling Chengxing once proposed to &quot;prevent (tobacco control) from becoming expanded, one-sided, and absolute.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 23, 2023, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported that the former Party Secretary and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration Ling Chengxing is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that three days ago, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection announced that the Eighth Central Inspection Team will inspect the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration’s party group work mobilization meeting, which will “highlight the supervision of the ‘top leaders’ and leadership teams and conduct in-depth investigations. Corruption issues in key positions and key areas.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since this year, many former officials of the State Tobacco Administration have been dismissed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Zehua, former member of the Party Leadership Group and deputy director, was investigated in July, and Zhang Hong, former director of the Department of Science and Technology, was investigated in July. Ling Chengxing is the highest-ranking official dismissed from the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration since its establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Zhao Hongshun, a former party member and deputy director, was investigated in February 2019, and Pan Jiahua, a former party member and leader of the disciplinary inspection team, was investigated in January 2022. Zhao Hongshun was sentenced to life imprisonment in June 2020, and Pan Jiahua was sentenced to 11 years in prison in April 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The starting point of official career&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before Ling Chengxing was investigated, the tobacco system had been continuously shaken, and many department and bureau-level cadres were dismissed intensively across Yunnan, Anhui, Jiangsu and other places, among which Jiangxi, the starting point of Ling Chengxing&#39;s official career, was the hardest hit area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 1, 2023, Li Benjian, a former division-level cadre of the Jiangxi Tobacco Monopoly Bureau (Company), underwent disciplinary review and supervisory investigation. According to Caixin reports, this person once served as Ling Chengxing’s driver. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 6, Zheng Wei, Party Secretary, Director and General Manager of the Guangdong Provincial Tobacco Monopoly Bureau (Company), was dismissed. He was previously the General Manager of China Tobacco Jiangxi. On the same day, Fu Wujun, the first-level business manager of the Human Resources Department of China Tobacco Jiangxi, was subject to disciplinary review and supervisory investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanggao County in Jiangxi Province was the starting point of Ling Chengxing’s career. He started working in 1980 and was promoted to the Standing Committee and Deputy County Magistrate of Shanggao County at the age of 27. Thereafter, he served as director of the Jiangxi Provincial Tobacco Monopoly Bureau, and eventually became a member of the Standing Committee of the Jiangxi Provincial Party Committee and executive deputy governor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Ling Chengxing was elected as a deputy to the National People&#39;s Congress in Jiangxi. A media person who interviewed Ling Chengxing at the Two Sessions told Southern Weekend reporters that during the discussion, everyone still called Ling Chengxing &quot; Governor&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring in 2018, Ling Chengxing was still very concerned about his hometown Shanggao. His only public appearance after retirement was to visit the water supply company in his hometown accompanied by the local county party secretary, county People’s Congress director and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Area hardest hit by corruption&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From 2013 to 2018, Ling Chengxing served as a member of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group, and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his tenure, China&#39;s cigarette sales fell by 2.4% in 2015, the first decline since 1995, equivalent to smokers reducing their consumption of 60 billion cigarettes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason is that the tobacco tax will be raised by 6 percentage points starting from May 10, 2015. The price and tax rate of the cigarette wholesale link will be increased from 5% to 11%, and the price will be increased by 0.005 yuan/cigarette. A specific tax is levied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the trend of declining sales, Ling Chengxing, who has always been low-key, took the initiative to accept an interview with the &quot;Study Times&quot; sponsored by the Party School of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, proposing to &quot;prevent (tobacco control) from becoming expanded, one-sided, and absolute.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the National Two Sessions in 2015, this also became the focus of reporters’ questions. What is the expansion of tobacco control? Ling Chengxing replied: &quot;Let me give you an example. Some people say that bone hyperplasia is caused by smoking. I think this has no scientific basis. What do you think?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, China&#39;s cigarette sales stopped falling and rebounded. rose, with 47.378 million boxes sold throughout the year, an increase of 0.8% compared with 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the discussion of tobacco control, the tobacco industry’s government-enterprise integration system has always been the focus of discussion. In the eyes of the tobacco control party, the government-enterprise integration system has become the biggest obstacle to tobacco control in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ling Chengxing’s predecessor, former Party Secretary and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, Jiang Chengkang, made the biggest institutional reform of China’s tobacco industry by promoting the “separation of industry and commerce” at the provincial level, but the reform failed to continue. further. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Ling Chengxing took office, he followed the previous ideas and rapidly expanded the scale of the company through mergers and alliances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first stop for his research after taking office was in Yunnan. After the merger of Hongyun Group and Honghe Group, the newly established &quot;Hongyun Honghe Group&quot; became the largest group after Altria Group, British American Tobacco, and Japan Tobacco. , the world&#39;s fifth largest tobacco group after Imperial Tobacco. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 30, 2013, a symposium on cultivating major brands of Yunzhen cigarettes was held in Mile County, Honghe Prefecture. Ling Chengxing, who had just taken over as the director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, issued the tobacco &quot;Policy Agenda&quot; for the first time: Adhere to &quot; &quot;Three Stabilities&quot; (the guiding ideology determined at the beginning of the year remains unchanged, the goals and tasks remain unchanged, and the work measures remain unchanged); maintain the &quot;Three Stabilities&quot; (stabilize the leadership team, stabilize the cadre team, and stabilize the morale of the employees); think, plan, and practice &quot;Three major issues&quot; (where are the dividends of tobacco industry reform, where is the potential for development, and where is the goal of catching up). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ling Chengxing also implemented a number of reforms during his tenure. Starting in 2014, the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration issued the &quot;Key Points of the Market-oriented Reform of Cigarette Marketing&quot; for four consecutive years, but it was limited to the marketing level, focusing on &quot; How can commercial enterprises truly reflect market demand, how can industrial enterprises meet demand in a timely manner, and how can industrial and commercial enterprises respond to market demand in a timely manner?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike the previous &quot;foreign troubles&quot; in which China Tobacco faced direct competition with foreign brands, Ling Chengxing faced more internal management pressure. During his tenure, many major cases occurred in the tobacco system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, a scandal broke out in the Henan Tobacco Monopoly Bureau, and many people including the former director were arrested. There is also the case of Yang Weizu, chairman of Yunnan Ruisheng Group, who is associated with the Yunnan Tobacco Science Research Institute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, at least a dozen central officials in the tobacco system have been eliminated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Ping, Party Secretary and General Manager of Hunan China Tobacco Industry Co., Ltd., was investigated in October 2020 and was suspected of accepting bribes of 413 million yuan and misappropriating public funds of 135 million yuan. This case is known as the most serious job-related crime in the tobacco system since the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A disciplinary inspection cadre analyzed the causes of corruption in the tobacco system to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The tobacco system is different from other vertically managed departments. It is a system that integrates government and enterprises, and the path to realize power is very difficult. Short, all links are accompanied by indicators, which results in power being permanently concentrated in the hands of a few people and the lack of effective supervision, making it more difficult to fight corruption in the tobacco system.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tobacco Bureau even controls the money bags of local governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An interesting detail is that during the National People’s Congress in 2015, a mayor publicly appealed to Ling Chengxing that he wanted to improve the quality of cigarette production. “It used to be that Septwolves were basically OEM, and the taxes and profits of Septwolves were relatively low. It would be great if the next step is to produce Chinese cigarettes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was refuted by Ling Chengxing on the spot, &quot;That&#39;s impossible. China Tobacco is a banner of the tobacco industry.&quot; The mayor said with a smile that “it may not all be the pen of the (old) governor” and suggested that better equipment could be invested in production. Ling Chengxing still insisted, &quot;When you come to engage in Zhonghua Cigarettes, you will immediately destroy the Zhonghua Cigarettes (brand).&quot; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, the mayor continued, &quot;While the (old) provincial governor is in the position of the General Administration, a certain city&#39;s tobacco industry chain tax revenue can reach 10 billion yuan.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that this media record at the time was preserved under Ling Chengxing&#39;s instruction. According to an insider, &quot;He may have just wanted to show that he rejected the other party.&quot; The mayor who made this request was dismissed soon after because of his involvement in the Su Rong case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 16:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“啥都不用干”是最大的福气吗？ ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259230]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Many people have said &quot;I don&#39;t want to work&quot; when they are sleepy or frustrated, but these words are probably inappropriate. Really, if we don’t have any mines or pie from the sky, what else can we do if we don’t move bricks honestly? But there are indeed some people who regard &quot;no work and someone to support you&quot; as the highest ideal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A blogger said that since childhood, her aunt has indoctrinated a bunch of little girls, including her, with the idea that girls are &quot;blessed&quot; and can enjoy a good life without doing anything. . Not only do you not have to do anything, but you marry a good family and you don&#39;t even need to take care of the children yourself. That is what you are blessed to do. This concept is close to &quot;labor equals shame&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all have inertia and a desire for comfort. In our subconscious, we may have had the image of just lying down and enjoying ourselves. When I was a kid, I experienced the intense itching pain all over my body after harvesting and threshing rice and wheat by hand. I also had &quot;plans&quot; to stop working. But honestly, just think about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The extravagant and luxurious life in books and movies is described in the wonderful lyrics of &quot;Huang Liang Meng&quot; by the Pingdiao Luozi Theater Company in Handan City, Hebei Province: &quot;Endless generosity, endless power; Endless delicacies to eat, endless money to spend; endless carols to listen to, endless gifts to receive; endless wealth to enjoy, endless New Years to live.&quot; Ordinary people can just think about it, and really educate themselves like this Children, that&#39;s really gone astray. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For ordinary people, when they are minors, they are supported by their parents, and when they become adults, they have to support themselves and their families on their own. If you want to live a good life, you can only accumulate it step by step. This is the first meaning of work for most people: to support their families. In order to achieve this goal, many people work very hard and may not be in a career they like, but they persist because this job can bring acceptable returns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is very painful to do a job that you don&#39;t like for a long time. A friend told me that the joyless days at work day after day were really a torture. But even so, we can&#39;t &quot;just leave&quot;, we can only wait for the opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My friend’s words moved me deeply. The reason why people should work hard is because work should have a second meaning: combining it with one&#39;s own talents and interests, making the work itself a source of fulfillment and happiness. Many writers have been doing writing work for a lifetime based on their talent and interest. I have also been a media commentator for many years based on my talent and interest. This is a blessing. There is also a kind of work that may seem heavy and tiring, but it may be something that workers like to do. For example, blacksmithing is not acceptable to most people, but in reality there are people who work very hard at it. I also heard a car mechanic say that although it may be tiring and dirty all day long, it is a job that interests him and cannot let him go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These are the values ​​that ordinary people should uphold, try to do meaningful work and live a meaningful life. In other words, a livelihood should be one that can not only meet the purpose of earning money to support the family, but also satisfy interests and hobbies. Accordingly, we not only get practical benefits, such as income and evaluation, but also spiritual satisfaction. This sense of gain is the spiritual source that enriches us in this world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people envy the financial freedom of wealthy families, but they only know one aspect but not the other. Even among the envied few &quot;giant pandas&quot; in society, most of them do not relax their requirements for their children. Instead, they pay more attention to providing high-quality education and scientific employment guidance to their children, and to promote their children to pursue a decent and respectable career. jobs and better realize the value of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Usually, these families need their children to inherit the family business. In order not to be left behind for this goal, they are motivated to help their children avoid becoming &quot;waste&quot; and &quot;dandy children&quot; who only consume high amounts of money and live in vain. Look at the young people who have inherited the family business of wealthy parents today. Which one has not experienced the nourishment of a good education and the tempering of basic work. Many people have the ability to protect their children from dust, but they still let them start from the &quot;workshop&quot; and perceive the meaning of life. This is true wisdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the many second-generation rich people do not sit around doing nothing all day long, eating, drinking, and waiting to die as some people imagine. In other words, people who are more &quot;qualified&quot; than ordinary people to do nothing work harder than you. What other reason do you have for fantasizing about “doing nothing”? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don’t forget, if you really have nothing to do, you will definitely fall into emptiness. If a person does not &quot;fill&quot; his life with meaningful things, he will easily fall into emptiness and become as light as a feather. In this case, even if you get a fortune one day, you will not be able to control such wealth. In Yu Hua&#39;s novel &quot;To Live&quot;, he explained the story of a swinger brother who lost his family fortune by gambling. How many such folk narratives are there? After the demolition in my hometown many years ago, the &quot;second generation&quot; became rich instantly. However, it is not uncommon for them to lose their property overnight due to gambling, dissoluteness, and being cheated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am obviously middle class or even poor, but I still always want to live a &quot;fairy life&quot; like a powerful or wealthy family, just enjoying myself and not working. To put it mildly, this is unrealistic, but to put it seriously, it is unrealistic. This is a lack of self-awareness. This idea is difficult to realize. In short, humans are animals of meaning, and meaning is the food of the spiritual world. On top of establishing a good life, people should do meaningful work or career to nourish our spirit. Under the sun and on the earth, we should still let ourselves &quot;sink&quot;, settle down, and become human plants that are truly not afraid of wind and rain. This principle applies to both the second generation of rich people and the children of ordinary people. Meaningful work or a meaningful career is the &quot;key&quot; that helps a person lead to a happy and transparent state. Only when you find a sense of presence and cultivate your character in your work or career, can you follow the trend. For, gradually improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[取消个人医保账户？国家医保局辟谣]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259436]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 15:04:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently, an article titled &quot;Employees Attention! &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;From 2024, employee medical insurance premiums will be completely changed&quot; article and related screenshots were circulated online in some WeChat groups, WeChat Moments and other places. After verification, the relevant contents in the article such as &quot;employee medical premiums will no longer be transferred to personal accounts&quot; and &quot;individuals will no longer have their own medical insurance accounts&quot; are pure rumors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In accordance with the decisions and arrangements of the central government and the requirements of the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Establishing and Improving the Outpatient Mutual Aid Security Mechanism for Employee Basic Medical Insurance&quot; (Guobanfa [2021] No. 14), local medical insurance departments have adopted Carry out the reform of employee medical insurance outpatient mutual assistance security, establish and improve the general outpatient coordination of employee medical insurance, and effectively improve the outpatient protection level of employee medical insurance participants. After the reform, the employee medical insurance personal account system will still be retained, with three &quot;unchanged&quot; features. First, the ownership of personal account balances remains unchanged. The historical balances before the reform and the newly transferred balances after the reform are still owned by the individuals and can be used for medical expenses and other expenses for individuals and their families, and can be carried forward and inherited. Second, the proportion and flow of personal contributions of active employees remain unchanged, and the full amount is still transferred to their personal accounts. Third, the policy of retirees not paying contributions remains unchanged, and personal account funds are still transferred from the overall fund. At present, the reform has achieved positive results, and the level of outpatient benefits of employee medical insurance has been steadily improved. In the first half of 2023, general outpatient services will benefit 1.124 billion people insured by employee medical insurance. The contents and screenshots of articles and screenshots related to &quot;cancellation of personal medical insurance accounts for employees&quot; circulating on the Internet are completely false. We reserve the right to hold the relevant rumor makers accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;National Medical Security Administration Office&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;October 27, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冰川记忆：中国珠峰科考六十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259430]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuwSokpK2C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/EJVj6echhXk8xtgh755OPMJPuaLt4UDuw SokpK2C. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 23, members of the 2023 Mount Everest scientific expedition summit team were rushing to the summit&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May and October 2023, the Northwest Institute of Ecological Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, and the Tibetan Plateau Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences (&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hereinafter referred to as &quot;Northwestern Institute&quot; and &quot;Qinghai-Tibet Institute&quot;&lt;/span>;) inspected the Everest area, Gradandong Peak, Cho Oyu Peak and other places, and obtained ice core samples . This is one of the tasks of my country&#39;s second comprehensive scientific investigation and research on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice cores are like natural archives, recording natural changes and human activities. However, climate change caused by human activities is also erasing the memory in the glaciers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why ice core? Why study glaciers? Who is studying Mount Everest? With various questions, we followed the Everest scientific expedition team in 2023, traced the history of the Everest scientific expedition for more than 60 years since China&#39;s first comprehensive expedition centered on Mount Everest in 1959, and recorded the progress of the glacier scientific expedition. The goals and actions can gradually describe the outline of those engaged in glacier research: most of them come from rural areas, are brave, can endure hardship, love nature, and love field work. They find peace and joy in nature, they are not stingy with time, they are aware of and concerned about the pulse of the earth, and they believe that the world is a community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Shi Yafeng, the father of Chinese glaciers, said, glacier research is a career for brave people and a heroic career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mount Everest is the main peak of the Himalayas, the tallest and youngest mountain range in the world. The Everest region mainly includes the &quot;Everest Nature Reserve&quot; in China on the north slope and the &quot;Sagarmatha National Park&quot; in Nepal on the south slope. With widespread glaciers, it is an important treasure house of freshwater resources on the earth and is also a source of climate and environmental change. Sensitive areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UWRilmxdoeZ2bErRTuZhdK8y4UyVlv1RajRdhTFV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UWRilmxdoeZ2bErRTuZhdK8y4UyVlv1RajRdhTFV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255409&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 23, 2023, members of the scientific expedition team took snow and ice samples at the top of Mount Everest&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Ice cores, nuclear explosion tests and pesticides&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;All four drill motors were broken. If it breaks down, just go down the mountain, Chen Pengfei thought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of May 20, 2023, at a pass at an altitude of 6,500 meters on Mount Everest, in a military green tent that was blown by the wind, Chen Pengfei and his colleagues shot two Ice core and a shallow ice core. Shallow ice core is an overloaded task: we have worked hard to get there, and we have to drill more until the drill breaks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice cores are cylindrical ice and snow samples that are continuously taken out from the glacier section by section using a drill from top to bottom. A bottom-through ice core means that the ice core is drilled into the rock layer and reaches the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Snowfall falls on glaciers and ice sheets. Year after year, it is deposited into ice, and the information of nature is sealed in it. The scientific expedition team members always want to obtain longer ice cores, hoping that the ice cores will contain more physical and chemical parameters. Relying on these parameters, scientists were able to reconstruct the history of changes over millennia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Antarctica, the North Pole and the Tibetan Plateau are collectively known as the &quot;three poles&quot; of the earth. Human activities in these three poles are weak and are used as the basis for environmental research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We need to know what the earth was originally like.” Chen Pengfei’s colleague Guo Junming said. They are all associate researchers at Northwest China Institute of Technology, which belongs to the State Key Laboratory of Cryosphere Science. This laboratory originated from the Lanzhou Institute of Glaciation and Permafrost, Chinese Academy of Sciences (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;established in 1965&lt;/span>;) and was founded by the &quot;Father of Chinese Glaciers&quot; It was established under the leadership of Shi Yafeng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice cores know the original appearance of the earth. For example, the ratio of stable isotopes of hydrogen and oxygen reflects the fluctuations in climate, and high values ​​of sulfate ions represent volcanic eruptions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice cores also retain evidence of violent human activities, such as nuclear explosion tests and nuclear leaks one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Everest ice core drilled in 2005 was measured to have two beta activation peaks, corresponding to the global thermonuclear test in 1963 and the Chernobyl nuclear leak in 1986. In other words, the memory of the Cold War is sealed in the glacier. In 2017, ice cores drilled in the Aru glacier area at an altitude of 6,150 meters on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau were measured with five beta activation peaks of varying levels, which not only correspond to 1963, but also correspond to the 2004 Mihama Nuclear Power Plant in Japan. Steam leaks, the 2005 nuclear leakage accident at the Sellafield Nuclear Power Plant in the UK, the 1968 impact of a US bomber carrying four nuclear bombs and the 1970 explosion of the 10,000-ton underground nuclear device at Jakapin in the US, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WsbAJ4gjyJziZ2EIlI8fJ57HFd0b5SD0JK4b5QoT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;701&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WsbAJ4gjyJziZ2EIlI8fJ57HFd0b5SD0JK4b5QoT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255402&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 22, 2023, at the Mount Everest Mountaineering Base Camp, Kang Shichang (right), deputy director of the Northwest Institute of Ecological Environment and Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences, viewed a drill drill from an altitude of about 6,500 meters on Mount Everest. Ice core samples taken &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists have found rich records of human activities in the ice cores. The peak lead content in the Greenland ice core drilled in 1994 corresponds to the peak period of the Roman Empire; the black carbon concentration in the East Rongbuk ice core on Mount Everest reflects the continued impact of pollutants emitted by human activities since the Industrial Revolution on the atmospheric environment; more The concentration of DDT in the Everest ice core corresponds to the malaria outbreak in India. DDT is a highly effective but environmentally damaging pesticide that is difficult to decompose. It has been banned by many countries since the late 1990s, but is still used in India. Therefore, the content of DDT in the forest soil of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau is currently the highest in the world, higher than Nordic Forest 10 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice core research is difficult to do because the sample size is very small and the appropriate detection indicators are limited. Even if there are good ideas, ice core research is extremely time-consuming and laborious. But ice core research is exactly the direction of Chen Pengfei’s transformation. “At this stage, I need the quality of papers more than the quantity,” he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To ensure that the ice core does not melt, ice core drilling always starts at seven or eight o&#39;clock in the evening and ends before the sun rises. Engineers use exhalation to judge when to start work: if you can exhale &quot;white air&quot;, the temperature is low enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before finishing work at 8 o&#39;clock in the morning, Chen Pengfei always walks out of the tent to watch the sunshine on Jinshan Mountain. The golden light falls from the sky and shines on the snow-capped mountain top. He had seen this scene more than 30 times at the pass, and he was delighted and moved every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How to describe it, starting from the top of the mountain, the golden color slowly falls, and then the entire Mount Everest is golden. It is very spectacular and I like it very much.&quot; Chen Pengfei said. His WeChat avatar is Rizhao Jinshan, a photo he took when he first came to Mount Everest in 2013. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/nHTIwV6CtvarPGACGZCX91n3jXsBx6ldim9Lmia8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/nHTIwV6CtvarPGACGZCX91n3jXsBx6ldim9Lmia8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255407&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 23, 2023, the scientific expedition team members maintained and upgraded the automatic weather station at an altitude of about 8,830 meters on Mount Everest&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“The glacier snow surface is printed with a complete human shape”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Those who engage in scientific research are always the poorest, and many scientific research team members They all say this with some embarrassment or a joke. There are too many places to spend money, and the equipment and consumables in the laboratory are the real gold-swallowing beasts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for the specially designed drilling rig, the ice cores are surrounded by ordinary objects: ice cores in ordinary plastic bags, marked with black markers; the insulated box is the most common one, dark blue in appearance, one meter in diameter. It is half a meter long and wide, with soft pads inside to protect the ice core from impact; the soft pads are basically cut military green quilts, with red or black mottled cotton batting exposed here and there; as for the freezer, it is a common cold drink cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes, it seems that the difficulties Chen Pengfei encounters can be attributed to saving money. On the second day of work, the generator failed to start. It was a non-Yamaha generator. The next day I pulled up the Yamaha generator and worked all night. Closed on the third day, Yamaha was damaged by a rare strong wind. On the fourth day, I borrowed a generator from Everest Base Camp to work, and asked my colleagues to quickly transport another generator. On the fifth day, the tent was completely blown to pieces and the business was closed again. Although the strong wind made people unable to stand steadily, the working tent was just a slightly thicker outdoor tent that had been blown by the wind on the Qilian Bayi Glacier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/sEz01Dwdsa2zl4XMJ4peip4mBeM6yO7jy5wzn99V.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/sEz01Dwdsa2zl4XMJ4peip4mBeM6yO7jy5wzn99V.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255404&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Pengfei&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(our reporter Dashi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t shave, Stop shaving.&quot; Chen Pengfei recited silently every night. It wasn&#39;t until the seventh day when new tents and new generators were used that the team members began to work continuously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As everyone in the cryosphere knows, ice coring is hard work. Chen Pengfei’s teacher, Vice President and Researcher of Northwest Institute Kang Shichang wrote in his Antarctic scientific expedition diary: “Compared with the glacier scientific expedition on the Tibetan Plateau, the conditions for the Antarctic ice sheet expedition are much better... The glacier expedition on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, There are only tents, especially in high-altitude areas. They usually use stones to build a stove, use a box to support a chopping board, and cook and cook in a corner of the tent. Sometimes chefs and scientific expedition team members can only sleep in the kitchen tent. Large We don’t have beds for part of the time, so we lie on the ground.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For Everest expeditions, we usually camp on moraine ridges surrounded by rocks. We try to find a few slightly flat stones and lay them with moisture-proof mats. Leather mattress. Every night we are constantly moving and changing sleeping positions, trying to avoid the direct &#39;collision&#39; of sharp rocks and looking for a relatively flat and comfortable position. Sometimes, we also need to camp on the glacier. Once on Mt. During the inspection, I lived for a month on the 6,300-meter-high Rongbuk Glacier in the Far East. When I left, there was a complete human shape printed on the snow surface of the glacier.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kang Shichang participated in the China-U.S. Joint Pearl River Delta Initiative in 1997 The scientific expedition team on Mount Everest drilled the first ice core on Mount Everest; in 2005, he served as the captain of China’s fourth comprehensive scientific expedition team on Mount Everest; in 2013, he led the team to drill 3 ice cores on the East Rongbuk Glacier, including 142 The meter-long one is the longest Everest ice core drilled in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The suffering on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau cannot be compared to the Antarctic.&quot; He said. Almost all work in Antarctica is mechanized, but on the glaciers of the Tibetan Plateau, all work relies on human power, such as shouting slogans to drag dozens of kilograms of ice cores across the ice ridge. Not only must we overcome altitude sickness, we must also do heavy physical work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Creating ice is also a laborious activity. Therefore, in addition to scientists, there are more workers in the team. Most of them have cooperated with Northwest Institute for many years, going to the plateau to climb snow-capped mountains, and walking far away carrying a 100-pound generator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/j9gcOLRvL7U9oBvhhtHO2xip2WHxU3DuARq9qLuk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/j9gcOLRvL7U9oBvhhtHO2xip2WHxU3DuARq9qLuk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255410&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Zhaofu (left)&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(our reporter Dashi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 6500 After working continuously for more than ten days at Mi Chu, everyone felt weak. The strong wind not only damaged the tents and generators, but also made the team members unable to walk every night. &quot;It was obvious that the team members were a little out of control, their tone was a little tough, and they were a little broken.&quot; Chen Pengfei said. Sometimes everyone would sing in the tent, singing loudly without knowing the words or music, which was more like a way to vent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I couldn’t eat or sleep well, and there was strong wind and heavy rain. Everyone has had the experience of getting lost, either using Mani Stones to identify the direction, or relying on teammates&#39; calls to find someone. Everyone has worked on the plateau until they were exhausted. Kang Shichang once chased a frightened yak carrying samples at an altitude of 5,000 meters for samples, until both the yak and he were unable to move due to lack of oxygen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In your subject, will there be more children from rural areas?” We asked Kang Shichang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s absolutely true.&quot; Kang Shichang replied loudly, &quot;Almost all are rural children, and rural children can endure hardship.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The youngest member of Kang Shichang&#39;s team is Hu Zhaofu, 2023 He left his postdoctoral position in 2011 and joined Northwest Institute. He is from Suzhou, Anhui and grew up in a village next to the Lianhuo Expressway. Before going to middle school in the county town, he not only often climbed mountains, but also caught scorpions: he would lift up rocks, and when he found a scorpion, he would hold its tail and blow on it, and then skewer it with chopsticks. Small scorpions are sold for 1 or 2 cents, and larger ones are sold for 40 or 50 cents. Hu Zhaofu, a primary school student, can get more than one yuan of pocket money every time he catches a scorpion. I was stung four or five times, but I didn&#39;t deal with it, saying that the pain would be gone in a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Hu Zhaofu participated in the scientific expedition to the Geladandong Snow Mountain. He worked for 20 days at an altitude of about 5,800 meters, and was able to eat, sleep, and be physically strong. That time he was particularly happy and a little proud. &quot;I see that other people are a little high-reflex, so I feel that my body is capable of doing this job, and God is giving me food.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/10/25/8WI03FcUtgWZ3wQwrIKW9NwgjxT1P60rH0SGtYmo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/8WI03FcUtgWZ3wQwrIKW9NwgjxT1P60rH0SGtYmo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255406&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Junming&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Reporter Dashi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The ice tower forest is gradually melting&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“The ice tower forest is getting less and less.” Hu Zhaofu said. The first time he climbed Mount Everest was in 2019. In the past four years, the shrinkage of the seracs was visible to the naked eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 5800 and 6300 meters on Mount Everest, the seracs gradually shrink to become sparse and low, making them hard to find at a glance. You have to walk to the mountain col to see them. The seracs look like the teeth of a giant shark and are a form of ice unique to high-altitude areas. Seracs that appear in groups are called seracs. Unlike most seracs that are not as tall as a person, the Everest seracs are scattered in heights, with the tallest ones exceeding 30 meters. Because the seracs on Mount Everest are so tall and resemble a Gothic spire church, Western explorers call them the &quot;Penitentes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The seracs are remnants of the melting glaciers. Due to the different movement speeds and ice densities of various parts of the glacier, some cracks and gaps will appear on the surface of the glacier. Mount Everest is located at 27°59&#39; north latitude, which is a low latitude and uneven sunlight exposure. When glaciers melt, the ice in the cracks melts faster, and seracs gradually form. As the temperature rises, the seracs gradually melt and may accumulate into glacial lakes or merge into rivers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Permafrost areas are most sensitive to climate change. The Tibetan Plateau is warming at a rate more than twice the global average, and scientists warn that by 2100, the Tibetan Plateau will lose two-thirds of its glaciers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where is the boundary between man and nature changing each other? Every time he goes out to work in the field, some broad, abstract, and unanswered thoughts will envelope Guo Junming and last until he goes down the mountain. &quot;Human beings are part of the earth. When people adapt to the earth, they will inevitably change the earth. What degree of change is appropriate? The future temperature control value we call is actually the boundary where humans feel comfortable. What about the earth itself? The earth has never experienced such violent activities. Where is the boundary of the earth?&quot; He asked a series of questions and finally concluded, &quot;I sometimes wonder if the earth can be in any state without humans?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no answers to these questions, but these questions give meaning to Guo Junming’s research. His recent research focus is on the mercury cycle in the cryosphere of the Tibetan Plateau. Human activities cause large amounts of mercury to enter water bodies, atmosphere and soil, and then enter the ecological cycle. Mercury can be detected at all three of Earth&#39;s remote poles. In the 1950s, mercury-containing wastewater was discharged from Minamata Bay in Japan. Fish and shrimp were contaminated, and then entered the bodies of birds, cats, and humans through the food chain. The victims ranged from slurred speech and staggering, to neurological disorders and death. This is the &quot;Minamata Disease Incident in Japan&quot; that shocked the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2017, the Minamata Convention on Mercury came into effect, and so far 128 countries have signed it. In Guo Junming&#39;s view, it was batch after batch of scientific researchers who used research results to clarify the environmental behavior and hazards of mercury, which promoted the birth and signing of the Minamata Convention. He hopes that his research can help all parties understand mercury more fully, and then promote the implementation of the contract by signatory countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Currently, mercury emissions in many countries in Europe and the United States have dropped, but emissions in South Asia are still very large. What I want to study is what impact and how mercury emissions in South Asia have on our Qinghai-Tibet Plateau.&quot; He explain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WU7AmICxijsST7iuLs8uDqokazvx1aj00Q5JnVBx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WU7AmICxijsST7iuLs8uDqokazvx1aj00Q5JnVBx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255405&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gao Tanguang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(our reporter’s food/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Enjoyed this Such freedom, no longer wanting to do regular work&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The ice cores that were drilled were all buried in the snow. After the ice core penetrated to the bottom, the team members walked back from the pass to the camp at 6,350 meters, packed the boxes until late at night, and waited for the yaks to carry the insulated boxes down the mountain the next day. They then stored them in the base camp freezer and transported them back to Lanzhou by truck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not two days after returning to Lanzhou from the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, Guo Junming returned to the office to be busy. He is 36 years old, in his prime academic years, and the breadwinner of his family. Every day he receives a steady stream of phone calls, routine work one after another, and noises he wants to avoid again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice coring is different. There is no signal at 6,300 meters, and Guo Junming’s mobile phone hardly turns on. &quot;It&#39;s so cool not to have a mobile phone, hahaha,&quot; Guo Junming laughed, &quot;I said it a bit harsh, and that&#39;s true. As soon as I got back to the city, I kept calling, emailing, WeChat and all kinds of things. Even if I couldn&#39;t receive them on Mount Everest, I would reply. No, I didn’t do it on purpose, I just couldn’t help it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He called his home satellite phone every two or three days. In addition, Guo Junming only has three things to do on Mount Everest: eat, sleep and make ice cores. &quot;Creating ice cores with peace of mind.&quot; Guo Junming said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having been to the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau many times, Guo Junming is now quite proficient in climbing Mount Everest. He knows how far it is to walk from an altitude of 5,300 meters to 6,300 meters. He can always reach it by walking slowly at his own pace and taking his time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tjNJmoO8ystPHYNqgPbyjL9xgC3zDj1wrykNdOPl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tjNJmoO8ystPHYNqgPbyjL9xgC3zDj1wrykNdOPl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255399&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zou Qiao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going out into the wild is work, and it is also an adjustment to one&#39;s life. &quot;It&#39;s really depressing to stay in the office for a long time. Go out and see the mountains, lakes, and climb mountains. There will be a few days where you can experience another kind of life, and your mental state will be better after you come back.&quot; Guo Junming said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although going out into the field is no longer a necessary condition for geological research, and samples taken by colleagues or partners can also be used for research, in our interviews, everyone participating in the 2023 Mount Everest scientific expedition Scientific researchers all love nature and love going out into the wild. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Tanguang, associate professor at the School of Resources and Environment of Lanzhou University, offered to take us mountain climbing during the interview. &quot;Let&#39;s change places. It&#39;s a bit silly to sit here (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;café&lt;/span>;),&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who would have thought that the interview would be in Wuquan Mountain, the northern foot of Gaolan Mountain, a natural barrier in Lanzhou city. Not only does Gao Tanguang take his children to climb Wuquan Mountain every Saturday, he even holds group meetings for students by climbing the mountain first and then talking about academics after climbing to the top. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is the senior brother of Chen Pengfei and Guo Junming. He also graduated from the Tibet Institute and studied for a doctorate in Beijing for five years. As a native of Shandong, he worked as a teacher at a key high school in Beijing after graduation and also worked in his hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GKxiX67cZQvbT3hDKbojRgth2FIx0tQ9ss06yVG7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GKxiX67cZQvbT3hDKbojRgth2FIx0tQ9ss06yVG7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255398&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 22, 2023, near the Mount Everest Mountaineering Base Camp, scientific expedition team members from the School of Ecology and Environment of Tibet University collected aquatic life samples&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both of these work experiences were very short because they were boring. &quot;When you have experienced the scenery of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau for several consecutive years, when field work accounts for a large part of your life, when you have enjoyed the atmosphere of the research group chatting and laughing in the wild, and enjoyed the abundant time to search for something for several days in a row, I have been running around in the mountains, not caring about anything, completely isolated from the outside world. I have enjoyed this kind of freedom, but once I enter a regular job, it is really unbearable.&quot; Gao Tanguang said, &quot;I have always felt that cities are just reinforced concrete. It&#39;s hard to never get out of the forest.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He wanted to live freely and live freely. It is difficult to tell whether this is his nature or whether it was shaped by his five years of studying at the Institute of Tibetan Studies. In the past five years, he not only went out in the wild, but also loved to ride mountain bikes in Beijing. He rode from his dormitory to Yanqing, a round trip of more than 100 kilometers. He spent a year as a visiting scholar at the University of Jena, Germany, and traveled through Northern Europe (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;focused on playing in the Arctic Circle&lt;/span>;). He spread out a blanket at the train station and slept, not afraid or alone. &quot;I was in a small town in Norway. I was going to sleep at the train station at night. A group of German college students came in and sat together and took turns reading to everyone. My German is not good, so I couldn&#39;t understand anything I read, but it was so interesting. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tJ3R0BpP98C1XsEeQVFiJopSqi3mArE4kkE7kZYH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/tJ3R0BpP98C1XsEeQVFiJopSqi3mArE4kkE7kZYH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255401&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 22, 2023, near the Mount Everest climbing base camp, scientific expedition members collected soil samples&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Danger&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chen Pengfei refuses to miss every sunshine on the Golden Summit, Guo Junming finds peace in making ice cores, and Gao Tanguang is free due to field scientific research. But the romance and charm of glacier scientific research often belong to the lucky and brave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, the name Lin Shubiao was mentioned. In 2011, 29-year-old Lin Shubiao, a doctor from the Institute of Tibetan Studies, disappeared while inspecting the Muztag Glacier in Xinjiang. After completing the installation of the automatic weather station on the Muztag Glacier in Xinjiang, he lost contact while descending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most speculations are that he fell into a deep and winding ice crevice and could not be found by search and rescue. He is a native of Tangkou Natural Village, Zhendong Village, Jiushi City, Zhaoqing City, Guangdong Province. He won the &quot;township top scorer&quot; in the high school entrance examination. He walked out of the mountains in the college entrance examination and was called &quot;the pride of the mountain people&quot; by the villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ice crevasses are the biggest danger in glacier scientific research. Most of the time, the crevasses are covered in snow and difficult to see. Kang Shichang once fell into a half-meter-wide ice crevasse. He held his feet on both sides of the crevice, and his body was suspended in the air, waiting for rescue. &quot;I wasn&#39;t afraid at all at that time. The other team members would definitely look for me when they saw that I was missing!&quot; Today, 22 years later, when he talked about this past incident, he suddenly slapped his thigh and said, &quot;Hey! I&#39;m really scared when I think about it now, but I didn’t panic at all at that time! I was so courageous at that time.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if they have never fallen into an ice crevasse, everyone can tell a story about a serious case of high fever that they witnessed with their own eyes. Urgent transports down the mountain often encounter dangerous moments: they may get lost halfway and fail to arrive late at night; or they may have become incontinent, and the consequences would be unpredictable if they were slower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, modern glacier scientific research was born along with mountaineering expeditions that represented human courage. Early scientific expeditions to Mount Everest were always closely tied to expeditions to Mount Everest. They also began with human curiosity and desire for unknown territories. Mountaineers not only want to climb Mount Everest, but also get back precious basic information, such as images or samples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The first expedition made very valuable geological surveys, and both expeditions also observed and collected many geological and botanical specimens. The geologists wanted a stone from the summit of Mount Everest , so that you can determine whether the peak is at the top or bottom of the fold.&quot; In 1922, Mallory, the British explorer who first attempted to climb Mount Everest, introduced the scientific gains of climbing Mount Everest twice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time China organized scientific researchers to conduct a comprehensive investigation of the 7,000 square kilometers centered on Mount Everest was in 1959, in order to cooperate with the national mountaineering team in preparing for the first climb of Mount Everest. The first modern glacier scientific expedition in China was just two years ago, in 1957. At that time, regarding the activities organized by the All-China Federation of Trade Unions to climb Mount Gongga, He Long, then director of the National Sports Commission, instructed: Mountain climbing should serve scientific research and expand social effects. Three scientific workers were selected to climb Mount Gongga: Cui Zhijiu, Ma Wenfu and Ding Xingyou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;That&#39;s a hero! Our hero in the glacier world!&quot; In a chat, someone mentioned Cui Zhijiu. Kang Shichang gave a thumbs up and said in a loud voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Zhijiu’s glacier career began in 1957 when he climbed Mount Gongga. The following year, he published &quot;Preliminary Observation of Modern Glaciers in the Gongga Mountains&quot;, filling the gap in the study of modern glaciers in China. The subtitle of this paper is: &quot;In memory of the comrades who died heroically in the conquest of Gongga Mountain.&quot; In Gongga Mountain, four team members encountered mountain disasters, including scientific worker Ding Xingyou, who was an assistant professor in the Meteorology Department of Beijing Agricultural University at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next 10 years, Cui Zhijiu visited the Everest region twice and climbed Nyenchen Tanglha, Muztagh and Shishapangma. He lost five fingers from the cold, suffered from severe snow blindness, and experienced the sacrifices of 12 teammates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is true that such tragic stories have rarely been seen in glacier scientific expeditions in the past 30 years, but what the older generation of scientists experienced and persevered still has lasting power for those who come after them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Tan Guangzheng, who was born in the 1980s, read &quot;Qinghai Tibet: 50 Years of Scientific Investigation on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Published by Sanlian Bookstore in 1999), I have been fascinated by the Qinghai-Tibet scientific research since college. He also loves to read &quot;National Geographic&quot; and goes to the old market every month to buy back issues with their covers torn off. &quot;It&#39;s said to be a back issue, but it&#39;s actually only one month away. It only costs 3 yuan a copy. Hahahaha, for only 3 yuan, you can own a copy of last month&#39;s National Geographic.&quot; He learned from National Geographic&#39;s I learned about the Qinghai-Tibet Institute and Kang Shichang in the special episode of Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, and later became a disciple of Kang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/HfsJGXoMZdcG0Vr9R6cVG4oSNNbTt0HNaEXptuvu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/HfsJGXoMZdcG0Vr9R6cVG4oSNNbTt0HNaEXptuvu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255403&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 10, 2023, at the Everest Atmospheric and Environmental Comprehensive Observation and Research Station of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, scientific expedition members used scientific instruments to collect greenhouse gases in the air&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Vast Tibet&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, it seems that due to the update of scientific research results, &quot;The Vast Tibet&quot; is no longer a good book. popular science readings, but the hundreds of people mentioned in detail or in detail still exude the charisma of passing on scientific research from generation to generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1968, glaciologist Xie Zichu signed up to participate in the scientific expedition to Mount Everest. He returned home with a full load. As soon as he got off the train, he was dragged into a fight and locked up in a cowshed that night. He was criticized for three years, but he quietly compiled the investigation data in the bullpen and completed a thesis on the ice-forming effect of infiltration on Mount Everest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 1972, the Qinghai-Tibet Scientific Expedition Team was established. Many experts who had lost their jobs and had been working in the &quot;May 7th Cadre School&quot; all year round told each other that they called it a &quot;safe haven&quot;. Through this scientific expedition team, our country began to establish an understanding of the Tibetan Plateau from different subject dimensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from the 1950s, the main achievements of the 30-year first phase of modern glaciology in China were the completion of regional and national filling of snow, ice, and frozen soil. This basic work means long and arduous field expeditions and a lifelong dedication of a group in particularly harsh conditions: the starting point of the work of glaciologists is where the snow line lies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the snowy swamp area, the car was stuck and dug repeatedly, and on the extremely cold night when the wind and snow overturned the tent, you would feel the burden on the lungs and heart every step you took, and for those with severe mountain sickness, emergency rescue, the joy of surviving a desperate situation, the fragility and magnificence of life that can be experienced in the snowy mountains and ice fields, as well as the relief and countless emotions at the end of each expedition... After every danger is saved, they will always I was overjoyed: &#39;It was so dangerous!&#39; After every field trip, I couldn&#39;t help but sigh with regret. But when I went out to the field again the next year, I was brave enough to move forward courageously. Choosing this career also meant accepting it. Everything related to it.&quot; There is such a passage in &quot;Qinghai-Tibet Vast&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;The Vast Tibet&quot;, in 1980, when the International Scientific Symposium on the Tibetan Plateau was held, Deng Xiaoping smiled loudly and replied in Sichuan dialect: &quot;We in China have With so many mountains, it doesn’t matter if you take away a few stones. They can take them if they want.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, international exchanges and cooperation in Tibetan Plateau research have become routine work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My mentor is very far-sighted.” Kang Shichang talked about academician Qin Dahe, the first Chinese to cross the Antarctic continent on foot and the author of the assessment report of the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When my supervisor trains students, he must first be international. When I was studying for a Ph.D., he asked me to study abroad several times, and my postdoctoral work was also done in the United States.&quot; Kang Shichang was a little emotional, &quot;When I was in After traveling around the world, I realized that there are differences in culture and good and bad politicians, but people are very amiable. Many times, group interests and political interests lead to many conflicts on our planet. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps because the subject research he is engaged in is always related to the changes of the entire earth. In Kang Shichang’s eyes, the earth is the dust of the universe, and human beings are the dust of the earth. Disputes and conflicts are inevitable in the face of the vast universe. Lost meaning. &quot;Global warming is not caused by any country, but by all mankind. Human beings on the earth must be peaceful and united without too many conflicts.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/eqTDESi1mURABf2rWjkoots7uARONNc9rvAa7QGe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/25/eqTDESi1mURABf2rWjkoots7uARONNc9rvAa7QGe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255411&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xi Zhenhua at Everest Base Camp &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Reporter Dashi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Don’t waste time at the Mount Everest Station&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the past 10 years , every scientific researcher who goes on the scientific expedition to Mount Everest has to deal with Xi Zhenhua. He is the observation supervisor of the Mount Everest Atmosphere and Environment Comprehensive Observation and Research Station of the Chinese Academy of Sciences (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Everest Station&quot;&lt;/span>;), and is also The person in charge of various specific affairs at the Everest Station in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Zhenhua has been at the foot of Mount Everest for 10 years, and this time is constantly lengthening. He is an indispensable part of various scientific expeditions on Mount Everest. The Everest Station, 30 kilometers away from the base camp, is the last preparation area before the Everest scientific expedition. Here, the scientific expedition team members can use the power supply from the national grid, sleep in bed with air conditioning, and use the toilet normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its completion in 2005, in the past 18 years, the Everest Station has evolved from a tent to a prefabricated house to a building, and its observation and monitoring instruments have gradually been completed. After Xi Zhenhua came to the Everest Station, he added several people as helpers to perform data collection on different scientific research tasks, such as regularly monitoring the hydrology of the Rongbuk River, observing the growth of alpine shrubs, and guarding against local plum blossoms being eaten by plateau sheep, instrument The battery was stolen. During the peak season of the scientific expedition, he helped the scientific expedition team communicate with the locals, arrange food and accommodation, and deal with various practical problems, such as driving injured workers to the hospital in Shigatse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, in order to prove that he could stay at the Mount Everest station, Xi Zhenhua stayed on the mountain for more than half a year for the first time. He had diarrhea as soon as he drank water and lost more than 20 pounds. It was not until he spent the New Year at the village cadre&#39;s house that he learned that boiling water in a pressure cooker could cure his acclimatization. &quot;Now it doesn&#39;t matter whether I use a pressure cooker or not. I just get used to it as I drink,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Zhenhua is already half a local. On the way up the mountain with him, he chatted enthusiastically with his &quot;three brothers and three sisters-in-law&quot; and regretted that he missed the horse racing festival. There are two boys from the nearby Basong Village who often come to play basketball in front of the Everest Station. Xi Zhenhua watches with gusto. He went to a Tibetan home to celebrate the Tibetan New Year, where he ate steamed vegetables, drank wine, sang, danced and played dice. After the round, he came back to eat, drink and sing. He also collects donations of clothes from his circle of friends and distributes them to villagers with financial difficulties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is not good at sociability, but he has become familiar with the locals because of his time. &quot;Over the past few years, they have become familiar with this place. Maybe they think that I am very honest and I will not treat them badly, so they are very willing to help me with many things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This place was only opened in 2016 When the power was turned on, the violent storm cracked the window glass. Peppers, potatoes, leeks and rapeseed are grown in the vegetable greenhouse. During the meal, eight people share a plate of scrambled eggs with leeks. The weather is getting colder, and I shiver with cold every time I go down the river to measure data; when going up or down the mountain in the middle of the night, there are frequent rockfalls, and swarms of moths and lime hit the windshield. Every time I go forward, it is like breaking through the fog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once upon a time, Xi Zhenhua’s closest friend was a native dog named Dahuang, who had been there since he entered the station. Every time he returned to the station in the middle of the night, Dahuang would lie at the door waiting for him, and would rush at anyone he saw. Wags the tail forward. &quot;Last year, before I got on the plane, I found out that Dahuang was dead. I couldn&#39;t stop crying all the way.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a secular sense, Xi Zhenhua has many disappointments. But after seeing mountains and rocks for months and years, he forgot about that. &quot;Sometimes you can live very easily if you don&#39;t think about the messy things. Day by day passes like this, very fast.&quot; Xi Zhenhua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is not stingy with time, has few desires, and is somewhat insensitive. Staying at the Mount Everest station for 10 years is not painful for Xi Zhenhua. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He loves to pick up stones and relies on his imagination to select stones: like a lady dancing, like a white tiger lying prone, like a Tibetan antelope leaping. When I was most lonely, stones were piled up on the wall behind the Everest station. He doesn&#39;t smoke and doesn&#39;t drink much, so he passes the time by recreating stone textures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Zhenhua’s real pain is his relationship with his daughter. He spends little time with his family and knows that his children have a weak relationship with him. Sometimes the video only hangs up after saying two or three sentences. &quot;We will face this kind of problem in the wild for a long time. It is always a problem and there is nothing we can do about it,&quot; he sighed. Every time he thought about this, he felt a little regretful about coming to the Everest Station. &quot;I want to stay with my wife at home.&quot; Children.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After coming down from the mountain in 2023, Xi Zhenhua went to his daughter&#39;s school to participate in the &quot;Parents in the Classroom&quot; activity. He told the primary school students about the origin of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, his work on the station and interesting stories. The daughter was very happy that day and thought her father had done a good job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At least I can gain some status in the children&#39;s hearts.&quot; Xi Zhenhua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking from the open space in front of the Everest Station, if the sky is clear, you can see a small section of the Golden Summit at sunset. Sometimes there are colorful auspicious clouds, so colorful that they have the gentle power to soothe people&#39;s hearts. In the middle of the night, I looked up and saw the starry sky, with the Milky Way brushing across the night like a brush. Many steep unknown mountains have names in Xi Zhenhua&#39;s mouth: This one has a lion&#39;s face, that one has a horse&#39;s body. His favorite saying is: Compared with Mount Everest, these are nothing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ZQxbMx6X9tJPsw9g9DNDvqUFfmpHNtIZ1Mqdr3fi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ZQxbMx6X9tJPsw9g9DNDvqUFfmpHNtIZ1Mqdr3fi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;British explorer Mallory&#39;s photo spot&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zou Qiao/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cross Two photos from the year 102&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before reaching 6,500 meters in 2023, the scientific expedition team will stay at the base camp for many days to complete glacier end sampling, glacier lake measurement, and an idea of ​​​​slanting out: find Here’s another photo of the location of the Rongbuk Glacier in Mallory’s 1921 photo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest existing image of the Everest glacier was taken by British explorer Mallory. Mallory once said a famous sentence in the history of mountaineering - when someone asked him why he wanted to climb Mount Everest, he replied succinctly:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Because the mountain is there.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;The dream of climbing Mount Everest has attracted the British elite for many years. Veteran and mountaineer Mallory was selected by the British Mountaineering Club to become the hope of seizing the afterglow of the once &quot;empire on which the sun never sets&quot; after entering the 20th century. Since the second half of the 19th century, British exploration has ceased to lead. They repeatedly failed in the race to open the Northwest Passage and reach the North and South Poles of the Earth. After the end of World War I, Mount Everest, known as the &quot;Third Pole&quot;, became Britain&#39;s last hope to prove itself. Many newspapers in the UK published a speech by Younghusband, chairman of the Royal Geographical Society - better known as a colonist who led troops to invade Tibet in 1903-1904 and killed many people - saying that he was the first to stand on Everest. Those at the top will inspire countless comers and cheer up the whole country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mallory climbed Mount Everest with the team in 1921 and 1922. The first time he reached an altitude of 7,000 meters, he photographed the Zhongrongbuk Glacier; the second time he reached an altitude of 8,320 meters, with 7 people on the way. Sherpa killed by avalanche. His teammates found a trail leading up through the East Rongbuk Glacier: a rise of dirt and rock right in the middle of the glacier that made it possible to hike directly across the glacier. Since then, climbers and scientific expedition team members of all generations have walked through this road to reach the 6,500-meter mark of Mount Everest. Western explorers call it the &quot;Miracle Highway&quot;, and Chen Pengfei said they call it the &quot;Yak Trail&quot;: This is the last section of Mount Everest that yaks can pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1924, Mallory climbed Mount Everest for the third time. This time he had a young partner, Andrew Owen, a student from Oxford University. On the morning of June 8, the two set off from 8,300 meters with new oxygen equipment, and then disappeared on Mount Everest. It was not until 1999 that an American mountaineering team sponsored by the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) discovered Mallory&#39;s body at about 8,170 meters on the north slope of Mount Everest, but there is still no trace of Owen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether the two men had ever reached the summit during their lifetimes has become one of the most famous mysteries in the history of modern mountaineering. The climbing team did not find a photo of Mallory&#39;s wife in Mallory&#39;s well-preserved belongings. He once promised that if he reached the summit, he would leave a photo of his wife on Mount Everest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Rongbuk Glacier photographed by Mallory is a photo familiar to permafrost researchers. Kang Shichang even used this photo as the cover of a course teaching the changes in Mount Everest glaciers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finding Mallory’s shooting spot was Gao Danguang’s task, and he was quite excited about it. Mallory was his favorite explorer: full of grit, heroic tragedy, and unsolved mysteries. He initially did not know that the 1921 photo of Zhongrongbu Glacier was taken by Mallory and that it had appeared in his study materials. When he learned that the photographer was Mallory, a sense of intimacy came over him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many years ago you read bits and pieces about someone, and then suddenly discovered that you had already met him in your work, and it was like the intimacy of meeting an old acquaintance in a foreign country. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glaciers are changing all the time: accumulation and melting constitute the material balance of ice and snow. Climate change can tip this balance off at any time, causing glaciers to advance or retreat. Therefore, scientists always want to obtain as much data as possible on changes in glaciers over time to study the changing processes of glaciers and climate. Although glacier monitoring in the Himalayas has made rapid progress in the past 20 years with the help of satellite remote sensing technology, long-term continuous observations are still lacking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we can take another picture of the Zhongrongbuk Glacier at the Mallory shooting point, it will move the time scale of observing glacier changes forward by 102 years. This is the scientific significance of finding Mallory&#39;s shooting spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gaotanguang failed three times, for different reasons: unable to cross the moraine on the west side of the Rongbuk Glacier; there was a problem with the instrument; the shooting point was found but was blocked by clouds and fog. Finally, his junior brother Wang Shaoyong and an accompanying reporter took a picture of the Zhongrongbu Glacier in 2023 at the Mallory shooting point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the first glacier distribution map of the Mount Everest region drawn by the British mountaineering team in 1921, Gao Tanguang compared the two photos spanning 102 years and was surprised to find that the distribution of the Rongbuk Glacier in mid-1921 The seracs are about 4 kilometers below the current terminal seracs, and the huge glacial lake at the end of the glacier today did not exist back then. This means that as the global climate continues to warm, the end of the Zhongrongbuk Glacier is retreating by an average of 40 meters per year, and the retreat rate is increasing year by year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, the end of the Halong Glacier in the Animaqing Mountains in the Yellow River source area has retreated by 450 meters in the 11 years from 2006 to 2017, while the Gangjiaquba located in the east of Geladandang, the source of the Yangtze River The glacier has retreated more than 4 kilometers since 1969. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SGCzy0HK8bSTD86oxanq9IR03P3EWHWGGyFL5Yvq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SGCzy0HK8bSTD86oxanq9IR03P3EWHWGGyFL5Yvq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255408&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At about 12:30 on May 23, 2023, the 13 summit members of the 2023 Everest Scientific Expedition successfully climbed to the top of Mount Everest, the top of the earth. After that, they will complete important scientific research tasks such as collecting snow and ice samples from the peak&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The memory of the disappearing glaciers&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;At this time, one day in October 2023, Chen Pengfei went to the Geladandong Peak of Tanggula Mountain to take ice cores again. On the way to the foot of the mountain, the falling snow enveloped the surroundings in a white mist. The spray-like snow blown off from the snow-capped mountains looks like endless white scarves against the blue sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 40 centimeters of snow in Gradandong delayed Chen Pengfei’s work progress: every step seemed to be opening a path. &quot;I thought I could move everything in two days, but now it seems it will take five or six days.&quot; When he thought he would lose the signal, he shared a photo of the snow with us. It was a vast area. &quot;Under the snow are stones and straw bags. , It’s easy to sprain your feet and you have to return to the tent before dark. If you are too tired from walking, the team members will collapse easily.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time Kang Shichang’s team took ice cores from Gradandong was in 2005. Chen Pengfei This time we walked higher than 18 years ago: the higher the altitude, the less likely it is for the glacier to melt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2005 Gradandong ice core was cut into more than 3,000 small pieces. Zhang Qianggong, a researcher at the Tibet Institute, tried to date it by testing indicators related to nuclear explosions - this is the most mature method for dating ice cores. one. But it took him two years to locate the peak of tritium activity in the 1960s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We expected that the peak should appear at about 20 meters, but in fact it appeared at 5 meters. In another ice core from Nyenchen Tanglha Mountain, we did not find a corresponding nuclear explosion Value, this has caused us a lot of trouble, what is the problem?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, Zhang Qianggong brought the ice core to the Paul Hill Institute in Switzerland. &quot;This is the world&#39;s largest nuclear energy and chemical laboratory. The research finally determined that the top of the Gladandong ice core corresponds to 1982, but this ice core was drilled in 2005, and the top should correspond to 2005. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In other words, the records of the Gradandong ice core from 1982 to 2005 are missing. The information loss of the Nyenchen Tanglha ice core is even greater. The records only stop at 1950. Ten years of memories have disappeared.&quot; Zhang Qianggong shared this research experience in a speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Global warming is melting the ice. Research by two generations of scientists has confirmed that human activities are causing rising temperatures. Based on the six climate change policies issued by the United Nations Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (hereinafter referred to as IPCC&lt;/span>;) from 1990 to 2003) Take the first assessment report as an example. The 1990 report stated that “there is very little observational evidence to detect the impact of human activities on climate.” By 2007, the report stated that “global warming since the mid-20th century is likely to be caused by human activities.” By 2023, the IPCC is very convinced that &quot;there is no doubt that human activities have caused warming of the atmosphere, oceans and land.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glaciers remember human activities, but human activities are also erasing glaciers memory. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Fairness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As temperatures rise and glaciers melt, the consequences are of course not only the disappearance of serac forests, but more importantly, the occurrence of avalanches, floods, and the reduction of fresh water resources. There are an increasing number of large glacial lakes in the Himalayas that could burst their banks at any time and destroy high mountain communities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Global warming is not only about the environment, but also about fairness. The most vulnerable people and ecosystems are disproportionately affected by loss and damage and are suffering a disproportionate share of the adverse impacts of climate change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2006, the village of Harji in western Nepal has been hit by glacial lake floods every summer. Floods and reverse currents flew down from the glacial lake on Namunani Peak at 5,300 meters in the western Himalayas, sweeping away houses, horses and crops; in 2012, an avalanche in the Himalayas caused river flooding and killed more than 70 Nepalis; In 2016, the Nepalese military spent several months dredging Lake Imza, the glacial lake on Mount Everest. In 2018, scientists warned that climate warming will cause the glaciers in the Himalayas to melt at an alarming rate, and Lake Imza may continue to expand. Eventually it collapses, possibly causing horrific floods in Nepal. Rishi Ram Sharma, director of the Nepal Hydrological Meteorological Service, said: &quot;As a small country, it is difficult for us to prevent what happens to the glacier.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, the IPCC&#39;s Sixth Assessment &quot;Synthesis Report&quot; stated , almost half of the world’s population lives in areas that are highly vulnerable to climate change. Over the past decade, deaths from floods, droughts and storms were 15 times higher in highly vulnerable areas than in low vulnerability areas. “Taking the right actions now will bring about fundamental changes that are crucial to building a sustainable and equitable world.” IPCC emphasized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1961 to 2016, the Tibetan Plateau lost more than 43 billion tons of ice, but this is less than one percent of the global ice retreat. The global ice volume has lost more than 9 trillion tons in 55 years. In the 1990s, about 0.8 trillion tons of ice melted every year. From 2000 to 2017, the annual ice melt volume was about 1.3 trillion tons. In simple calculation, 1 trillion tons of ice is a large ice block with a length, width and height of 10 kilometers, which is higher than Mount Everest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now is the warmest time in the past two thousand years. Recovery is a very slow process. I can&#39;t imagine how to cool the earth and restore the seracs. You won&#39;t be able to see this by the end of this century. &quot;Arrived.&quot; Kang Shichang said, &quot;The amount of water released by the glacier ice sheet causes the sea level to rise by 3 millimeters per year. If the global sea level rises by 15 meters, it is equivalent to the demise of the Greenland ice sheet. Then the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei, Yangtze River Delta, The Pearl River Delta will be in catastrophe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists have made many early warnings, but the power of change often does not belong to them. IPCC Chairman Li Huisheng told government representatives around the world during discussions at the 2023 conference: “Mainstreaming effective and equitable climate action will not only reduce loss and damage to nature and people, but also bring wider benefits. If we take action now, we can still provide a livable and sustainable future for everyone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time we take ice cores, the team always asks some Tibetans to help, 24-year-old Dundang Also among them. He is from Quzong Village, one of the villages closest to Everest Base Camp. Everest tourism, Everest scientific expeditions and commercial mountaineering have brought new livelihoods to the people of Quzong Village. Dundang said, &quot;Here, Everest is our greatest resource.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What do you think of Mount Everest?&quot; Has the peak changed?&quot; a reporter asked him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Mount Everest has not changed, it is still the majestic Mount Everest.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Do you want to leave?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No, we are here There is a relationship between people and Mount Everest.&quot; He gestured a thumbs up to the camera and said with a smile, &quot;Welcome to come back next year!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Thanks to the Northwest Institute of Eco-Environmental Resources, Chinese Academy of Sciences and He Peiyun for their help with this interview.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[科幻作家糖匪：被AI替代的人如何生活？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259000]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/o4Pd43WOaAdR06Ey8U48hjSWoGqg6aRVdO7dPqZ8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/o4Pd43WOaAdR06Ey8U48hjSWoG qg6aRVdO7dPqZ8. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254468&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;An electronic zoo in an urban apartment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;How do you think about killing a person in a place with complete surveillance?&quot; Intermittent voices came from the phone. . In the early autumn of 2023, in a cafe on the streets of Shanghai, science fiction writer Tang Bandit talked about the original idea of ​​the new novel collection &quot;Later Humanity&quot; in a telephone interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2021, when it was difficult to travel freely due to the fluctuations of the new crown epidemic, Sugar Bandit began to re-examine the house where he lived. At that time, she lived in an old house in downtown Beijing. The house was small and the study was filled with books. Sugar bandits prefer this kind of tranquility amidst the hustle and bustle of urban life. Although many friends have equipped their homes with a complete set of voice-controlled smart appliances, there are not many smart appliances in her home. Sugar Bandit lives alone, and the only camera installed in his home is to take care of his dog, which has been with him for 18 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you look at your home again, you will feel a sense of alienation: a house is like a building block that makes up a city. People live in it and use their mobile phones to pull a series of smart appliances in the house—— They are electronic creatures in the technological age, listening to their master&#39;s call. When smart appliances are domesticated enough to be intelligent, will they protect their owners and families like pets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Science fiction writing is the prism through which Sugar Bandit observes the world. Winner of the Hugo Award and Nebula Award, Chinese-American science fiction writer Yukun Liu translated Sugar Bandit&#39;s first science fiction novel &quot;Dirty Stories&quot;. When he saw Sugar Bandit, he felt that she was just like the stories she wrote, not bound by conventions. , do not write fast food dessert literature for sales. In the science fiction collections &quot;The Odyssey&quot; and &quot;The Man Who Saw Cetus&quot;, the sugar bandit is obsessed with traveling through cities, illusions and the universe. &quot;Whether it&#39;s aliens or time travel, whether it&#39;s urban horror or virtual reality technology, Sugar Bandit&#39;s novels are good at using these common metaphors in science fiction to express and question our insights as human beings.&quot; In Liu Yukun&#39;s view, this is exactly what Characteristics of the science fiction world, &quot;Reality is more science fiction than fiction, and science fiction thinking has become a way to tell the truth.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The future has arrived, but it&#39;s just not popular yet.&quot; Although Kevin Kelly has already stated in &quot; &quot;Inevitable&quot; reminds people of their attitude towards technology, but when AlphaGo and ChatGPT arouse social attention, it is still difficult for people to regard artificial intelligence as the current reality. Instead, they either imagine the broad future opened by technology, or continue to maintain this alert. Sugar Bandit is a technology enthusiast who is keen on researching new technologies. However, in her collection of science fiction novels &quot;Later Humanity&quot;, she has set her sights on the &quot;posthumanity&quot; left behind by the technological era. She writes about those Ordinary people who have disappeared from society unknowingly use science fiction to re-describe the lives of those abandoned by the times, revealing the profound changes that technology has had on people&#39;s lifestyles and interpersonal communication patterns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sugar Bandit’s novel, the future has arrived and mankind has entered the era of comprehensive artificial intelligence. However, people still have memories of their past lives. Half of them have entered the clean future in the cloud, and the other half of themselves have entered the era of comprehensive artificial intelligence. The memory of the body stuck in the ground. In the cyber world where humans and machines are coupled, people have virtual clones uploaded to the cloud, brain-computer assembly surgeries to enhance brain power, artificial intelligence &quot;family masters&quot; that control everything in their apartments, and machines that satisfy the sexual desires of family members. &quot;Happy&quot;, people can also rent out their bodies in the spherical vibrator field... The sugar bandit describes the later human beings with delicate brushstrokes: He Lai who disappeared with his memory, Xin Min, the housewife who was monitored by the &quot;family mastermind&quot;, &quot; Chen Keqing, a beauty blogger who has a stable mentality and is like a plastic person...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;These stories tell the most common daily things of human beings, but they write about Zhang Ailing-like feelings in the technological age and touch the softest of human beings.&quot; and the hardest parts, I have never seen science fiction express them in such a detailed, lingering and heart-wrenching way.&quot; Science fiction writer Han Song said that he feels that such science fiction novels are real literature that belongs to the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Happy Days,&quot; Sugar Bandit imagines a new kind of apartment in the future. In the future, people will no longer worry about mortgages and rents. The housing problem that once strained the entire society has long since dissipated. The right to residence is people’s birthright. “The younger generation has forgotten that era of housing tension. Due to the climate Conditions shortened the durability of a large number of buildings, living resources were highly concentrated, and housing supply was once very tight. Even if the last generation of baby boomers has passed and the urban population has dropped sharply, the habitable land area still cannot satisfy the existing population. The emergence of new apartments has ended that period Chaotic and crowded days.&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Happy Days&quot;&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the future, intensive and intelligent Smart apartments are given temperature by technology, and the temperature is passed on to those who choose it in the future. In new apartments, the artificial intelligence &quot;home master&quot; controls everything in the apartment, from the use of various furniture and appliances to the collection of data from earphones, air composition analyzers, and infrared camera needles throughout the home, and can even be refined to the Data analysis of pressure, heat and micro-radiation in each plane of the home. Technology provides a happy, efficient, and convenient life for the people who live here, and it also controls and monitors everything in these homes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in these families, who is qualified to control the machines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WtMDY37206Cqnz5LHmqwUUSwMS9JIHXl40wpwm6V.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WtMDY37206Cqnz5LHmqwUUSwMS9JIHXl40wpwm6V.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254470&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the event site of the 4th Another Planet Science Fiction Conference, from left, Liu Cixin, Sugar Bandit, Han Song&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Interviewed (Photo courtesy of author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Man and machine, are they enemies or friends? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Novelist Liao Jing felt a little horrified when she read &quot;Happy Days&quot; by Sugar Bandit. She sent Tang Bandit a WeChat message saying that she thought of &quot;1984&quot;. In the novel, the &quot;family master&quot; of the apartment is omniscient. &quot;It appears as a server, knows everything, and takes care of the couple in every possible and subtle way, but in fact it is a monitor.&quot; , and even became a ruler.&quot; Liao Jing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Actually, in the past few years, everyone has often felt this way. It&#39;s like I spent money to buy a mobile phone, and after downloading some software, I put a chain on myself.&quot; Liao Jing shared his feelings at the Sugar Bandit&#39;s new book salon, &quot;We feel that we are the owners of the mobile phone, and that the mobile phone is about me, but if I forget to bring my mobile phone when I go out, I may not be able to go anywhere. When you think technology When you are cared for and taken care of all the time, you are actually trapped in some kind of shackles.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the penetration of technology in the digital age, people&#39;s sense of being monitored seems to be everywhere. When writing &quot;Happy Days&quot;, Sugar Bandit was curious that if people lose their initiative in the apartment where they live every day, then whether this apartment where people are taken care of in every possible way is more like the &quot;French philosopher Michel Foucault&quot; proposed &quot;Panopticon&quot;, can technology really empower the disadvantaged, or will it intensify exploitation and accelerate differentiation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the novel, even in the technological future where people can upload all their memories and ways of thinking to the cloud, families living in future apartments will still have a family model of &quot;the man is the head of the house and the woman is the head of the house&quot;. This comes from sugar. The bandit&#39;s special setting. The wife does housework at home. By arranging the &quot;domestic mastermind&quot;, the wife controls all matters in the home and appears to be the master of the home. However, the control authority of the &quot;family mastermind&quot; lies in the hands of the husband. Even if he just adjusts the electrical parameters in the home, he needs to wait for his permission after he comes home from get off work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Although it is a story that takes place in the future, the actual reading experience is very contemporary. As a housewife’s situation that we often talk about, it has also appeared in many movies and TV series. She is in her Her status in family life is even lower than that of the &#39;brain&#39; of the apartment. She has always been in an environment of being controlled and monitored. Although she seems to be the master and has constant needs, in fact she does not even have the authority to modify the parameters. She would not get this permission.&quot; Liao Jing said, &quot;She was thinking, what do I need AI for? To enable me to be more proactive and better at completing housework. The question raised actually involves a core issue, which is who is it? Who is taking advantage of whom is enslaving whom.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the technological leaps one after another, what is seen is technological progress, what is not seen is the hidden labor. In the novel, Sugar Bandit specifically depicts the relationship between this woman and the family AI: at home, the person who understands her best and gives her the most time to spend with her is the &quot;family mastermind&quot; AI that she has trained with her own hands. Her job is also to use human experience and emotions to &quot;feed&quot; AI, type it into text and input it into the AI ​​backend, so that AI can better serve humans. Faced with the ubiquitous family boss in the smart apartment, her cheating husband who turned a blind eye to her, and the sudden death of her best friend, the protagonist Xin Min fell into a fear of losing her subjectivity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of sugar bandits, the most cruel punishment is &quot;the disappearance of a person.&quot; &quot;Lock a person in a small space and pretend she doesn&#39;t exist. You seem to be free in this society, but you are made transparent. No one cares about what you think or what you like, and the occasional conversation with you is It all revolves around his needs. Your labor is small because it is covered by technology, and personal value cannot be realized through intellectual labor. Domestic labor does not count as labor, and your emotional labor is also exploited. In this case, this The heroine is the person who &#39;disappeared&#39; and does not exist.&quot; Sugar Bandit said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Science fiction is a way of thinking that saves us from our daily stereotypes and inherent thinking through extreme situations, the construction of different worlds, and other unfamiliar creative methods. Come out. So as to change the scale and angle of how we look at problems, and re-examine our current lives.&quot; In the master class of the 7th China-Europe International Literature Festival, Sugar Bandit pointed out when she was invited to share her knowledge and understanding of science fiction novels The significance of science fiction is not just to create spectacles that are different from reality. The key is to break away from ordinary perspectives and thinking. This imagination is rooted in the heavy reality and gains the power to grow upward from the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The setting of the machine in the novel is different from previous novels. When the &quot;family mastermind&quot; faces this seemingly inseparable couple, its only need is to maintain the stability of the family. It quietly helps the couple cover up traces of each other&#39;s derailments and protect the existing family&#39;s orbit. Like a parent, he wants this to happen. The home runs well. The desire of women in the novel is also to restore order, but they are not satisfied with the beautiful order restored by machines, but hope to obtain their own subjectivity. In the extreme setting of the novel, she kills her husband and disposes of the criminal tools through the smart apartment, and in the end the &quot;family mastermind&quot; also helps cover up the crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is not so much about revenge, but about her finding a way to exist as a living person after her own human value has been erased. This is not an opposition between men and women, but a social structure problem.&quot; Sugar Bandit said that the novel transfers people&#39;s helplessness and indignation towards the world into personal plight. Breaking free from it and breaking through it are actually a matter of personal confrontation with the plight of the entire world. With the help of the machine, the woman gains freedom and her true identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How will the relationship between humans and machines change in the future? In the view of the sugar bandit, people today no longer treat technology like the confrontation or blind worship they had in the early 21st century. In the future, people may stand together with machines to fight against the so-called &quot;inhumanity&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQwtjJ1QnbZJt7xvxWizVueWRn7FuM6aITaSoEru.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NQwtjJ1QnbZJt7xvxWizVueWRn7FuM6aITaSoEru.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254473&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; Later people&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The sugar bandit is in poor health and had a major operation in 2022. &quot;My condition this year is worse than last year. I have been sleeping only two to three hours a day for a long time. And in When I was in Beijing, I couldn’t go out. My whole person was in a shaky state.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the disease came, Sugar Bandit felt that he had finally entered an excellent writing state. Several novellas have been written. Different from previous novel collections, she has developed a very complete and systematic world in the new novel collection. She feels that she has found a very clear writing direction and has a very clear understanding of science fiction. Concept, can&#39;t wait to enter a new stage of creation, &quot;At that time, if you gave me an apple, I could write science fiction novels. That state was very stable and very wild, and I felt like I could do anything.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; &quot;The result was all of a sudden. I went to the hospital for a check-up and found out all of a sudden... Then I started to be rubbed by death for two years.&quot; Sugar Bandit recalled the medical treatment at that time in the noisy cafe, about her going to the hospital during the epidemic. Surgery in the hospital is difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology is always improving, and people tend to move forward with time and are good at forgetting. The English title of the new collection of novels &quot;After Humanity&quot; has two translations. The first one is &quot;posthumanity&quot;, which is a very important concept in science fiction novels. The second is to use Shanghai dialect to say that &quot;latecomers&quot; are those who are left behind. &quot;Those who arrive first will become more successful and resourceful people. Those who come later will obviously be more passive and will slowly and unknowingly slide into a marginal position. The future in the novel is very pessimistic.&quot; Sugar Bandit Said, &quot;The novel is the best mirror for the author, and the understanding of the world is presented in the text in a very honest and undisguised way.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sugar Bandit&#39;s view, science fiction is not just about carrying science and technology A fanciful literary type, she loves science fiction because it is so lively and full of possibilities. In ancient China, novels developed from myths and legends to fantasy novels. The authors presented these fictional objects to readers with a naive and enthusiastic belief. Although technology has long dispelled the darkness of human pre-modern civilization, reality and fantasy have been confused again in another form. Especially in the years of the COVID-19 epidemic, shock has become the norm. Many incredible things happen, and people use science fiction to describe reality, whether it is a dream life given by highly developed technology or a nightmare reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When people are already living in science fiction, how should science fiction literature express and respond to reality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the writing of &quot;Later Humanity&quot;, Sugar Bandit felt that this process was a &quot;flying close to the ground&quot;, and several novels imagined future cities along the lines of real life. &quot;Such science fiction gives Will the huge sense of surprise make men feel excited? Not necessarily, but I want to be a little provocative and stinging, making people understand that even if technology is so advanced, family work still requires a huge amount of labor, patience and time. . Not only family labor, but also in modern life due to the emergence of technology, many labors have been covered up due to the advancement of technology.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People often say that AI will replace humans, but when AI replaces humans, At this time, what do humans do? Humans serve and train AI.&quot; Sugar Bandit said that &quot;technology is green&quot; is a huge illusion. Whether it is ChatGPT or many well-known artificial intelligence software, it requires a lot of manpower to train it, and these simple, repetitive and boring tasks often correspond to people in less developed areas of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the novel, she writes about the future of many people who have been left behind by the technological era, but these science fiction novels are almost becoming reality. In &quot;Half Articles and Half Tune&quot; written two years ago, residents living on an island are affected by ocean microplastics and gradually become plastic people. Recently, reports about microplastics harming human health have been appearing in the news. The body for rent in &quot;Running Ball&quot; involves the exploitation of the lower class by the upper class. When productivity develops to a certain extent, what people are exploited is not their labor power and intelligence, but their subjectivity and the joy of being a human being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why should we arouse concern for these people? Because today of these people may be our tomorrow. Now everyone seems to have no worries about food and clothing, live and work in peace and contentment, but it is possible that tomorrow due to something, the trajectory of life will continue. If we take care of those on the margins and speak for them, we will do something for our future,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[珍∙古道尔：与黑猩猩共度的传奇一生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259336]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/26/wPjs2fqHqWCrluRezzRKVpWPhAYCdCV7seBpgTu2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;647&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/wPjs2fqHqWCrluRezzRKVpWPhAYCdCV7seBpg Tu2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jane Goodall&#39;s research findings break the long-held belief that only humans can make tools ” perspective has introduced brand-new data into the study of anthropology and animal behavior. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was already five o&#39;clock in the afternoon, but Jane Goodall did not meet even a chimpanzee. While there was still a glimmer of light, she planned to go to the observation point of her choice, where she expected to see chimpanzees building their nests. Suddenly, she heard the cry of chimpanzees, and four chimpanzees appeared in the telescope, eating a yellow fruit similar to plums. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She decided to get closer to them. When she cautiously approached the big tree, she found that the branches were empty—the chimpanzees had slipped away again. This situation had happened countless times for more than half a year, and she felt an almost numb despair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when her eyes moved down, she found that two adult chimpanzees were sitting on the ground less than twenty meters away from her, watching her. After a few seconds, they began to stroke each other&#39;s fur as if no one else was watching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This was truly one of the most exciting moments I have ever had the pleasure to experience in my life.” Jane Goodall wrote in the book “The Chimp Is Calling” that she finally got to see her up close. Watch the chimpanzees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, 2023, the documentary &quot;The Legendary Life of Jane Goodall&quot;, starring the 89-year-old British biologist Jane Goodall, was released in China. The film won the 71st Nominated for Best Documentary at the British Academy Film Awards, it has a Douban score of 9.2. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since childhood, Jane Goodall has had a strong interest in animals. When she was one year old, her family bought her a toy chimpanzee, which became her cutest friend; when she was 4 years old, she stayed in the chicken coop for five hours just to observe how the hens lay eggs; when she just turned 8, she Make up your mind to go to Africa when you grow up and be with wild animals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an adult, when a friend invited her to visit a farm in Kenya, she did not hesitate to quit her job and returned to her hometown to work as a waitress for a period of time to save money for her trip to Africa. &quot;I never expected to get married or start a family. That was not within my scope of consideration. Going to Africa to live with animals was the only thing I wanted to do.&quot; Jane Goodall said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/HpRcTJ1jNuZIbTwW9gO4uEWrTfojng2am9fYIoA6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/HpRcTJ1jNuZIbTwW9gO4uEWrTfojng2am9fYIoA6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255551&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jane fell in love and got married to wildlife photographer Hugo. Later, the two chose to separate for their respective careers. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The strange feeling of isolation&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;When she first arrived in Africa, someone told Jane Goodall that if she liked animals, she must visit Louis Leakey, the then director of the National Museum of Kenya. Jane Goodall followed the advice and later became Louis Leakey&#39;s secretarial assistant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1957, Louis Leakey applied for a six-month grant to study wild chimpanzees. In his view, studying the behavior of great apes is helpful in understanding the behavioral characteristics of human beings&#39; ancient ancestors. He wanted to find a researcher who could conduct fieldwork, uninfluenced by scientific theory, and unbiased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secretary Jane Goodall fits this requirement. Before going to Gombe to study chimpanzees in 1960, she had no academic training, no science degree, and even no knowledge of wild chimpanzees. However, she loved animals, was patient, and had a great passion for knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the book &quot;Chimpanzees Are Calling&quot;, Jane Goodall recalled that when she first saw the endless forest in Gombe, her mother who accompanied her was afraid, and she herself All I could think about was “the strange feeling of being isolated from the world.” However, for a young woman, approaching chimpanzees and trying to be accepted into the group was unimaginable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She could only hope that the chimpanzees would get used to her and ignore her presence. The rhythm of her life in Gombe is very fixed. No matter what the weather is like, she always goes to the mountains early in the morning to observe chimpanzees - walking through layers of trees, wading through streams, climbing steep slopes, arriving at a suitable observation point, and raising the telescope in her hand. Sometimes she could see a group of chimpanzees swinging from a fig tree, and sometimes not at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And every time she tried to get a little closer, the chimpanzee would run away. &quot;That was probably when I was most depressed.&quot; Jane Goodall said. Even more frightening is that sometimes, chimpanzees can become aggressive when facing strangers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with the New York Times, Jane Goodall recalled that the chimpanzees would sometimes climb up the tree screaming, their hair standing on end, shaking the branches vigorously, and hitting her on the head with branches. At this time, she could only pretend to be calm, not look at them, dig some small holes in the ground and eat some leaves. After the chimp left, her legs began to tremble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, after several months of observation, the chimpanzees gradually got used to her presence and accepted her. The closer she got to chimpanzees, the more Jane Goodall discovered that they are so similar to humans. They also have emotions such as fear and jealousy, and they can even make tools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One morning, Jane Goodall ran through three valleys, but she didn&#39;t even see a shadow of a chimpanzee. Just as she was struggling through the steep slope to the top of the peak, there was movement in the grass sixty meters away. Jane Goodall raised the telescope in her hand and saw a chimpanzee squatting next to a termite nest in red clay. A long and thin straw stick is inserted into the termite hole and then lifted up to lick it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days later, she observed a group of chimpanzees going to a termite nest, picking up a branch with leaves on it, then plucking the leaves from it, and shaping it into a handy tool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, people have believed that only humans can make tools. This discovery by Jane Goodall is almost subversive. When she telegraphed this to Louis Leakey, he was so excited that he responded: Humanity must be redefined, or chimpanzees must be recognized as human beings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/ccl0MFXqinTiK7UTwh1Uvrs9nSjYGFtwQNQCyMRy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/ccl0MFXqinTiK7UTwh1Uvrs9nSjYGFtwQNQCyMRy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255552&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In recent years, Jane Goodall has remained committed to animal and environmental protection, giving lectures around the world, calling on people to be aware of the endangered living situation of chimpanzees and protect ape habitats. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;I can&#39;t leave, this is my life&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>; Jane Goodall once wanted to be a man when she was a child, &quot;Maybe it was because men could do what I wanted to do at that time, but women could not.&quot; At that time, even though she made important discoveries about chimpanzees, with the praise came doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people think that because she is an untrained young woman, her research results are not worth mentioning. Some people think that she is famous because of her appearance - she is tall and has beautiful blond hair. Many newspapers at that time emphasized her female identity when publishing, and some even used her beauty as a gimmick. For example, one newspaper&#39;s title was &quot;Beauty and Her Beasts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People think I&#39;m famous because of my legs, which is stupid, and I don&#39;t take it to heart, but fame is useful because then I have to raise money myself.&quot; Jane Goodall said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She may be able to try her best to ignore outside comments about her gender and appearance, but for her, it is more difficult to achieve a balance between family and career. After Jane Goodall made her important discovery about chimpanzees, Louise Leakey received a grant from the National Geographic Society, allowing her to continue studying chimpanzees. At the same time, the National Geographic Society also sent a photographer, Hugo Van Rawick, to record the chimpanzees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to guess the direction of the story. Jane Goodall and photographer Hugo fell in love, got married, and studied chimpanzees in Gombe together. Later, however, the National Geographic Society stopped funding Hugo, and his mission as a photographer ended. It was a period of difficult decisions for them. Jane Goodall wanted to continue studying chimpanzees in Gombe, but Hugo could not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was Jane Goodall who made the sacrifice initially. She spent most of her time with Hugo in the Serengeti, Africa, while Hugo photographed wildlife while she wrote books and took care of her son Guerra. At that time, she served more as Hugo&#39;s assistant and Guerra&#39;s mother. For her work in Gombe, she no longer tracks chimpanzees and is primarily responsible for managing the research station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, something unexpected happened again, and the polio epidemic suddenly broke out among the chimpanzees in Gombe. Jane Goodall returned to Gombe and decided to spend more time with Gombe&#39;s chimpanzees. At that time, her son was also with her. In the morning, she would analyze data and manage administration, spend an hour or two at the chimpanzee camp observing them, and spend the afternoon with her son Guerra. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But humans are group animals after all, and Jane Goodall understood the importance of sociality. When Guerra reached school age, Jane Goodall had to send him back to England to study. When she was separated from Guerra, she was sad and felt like she had betrayed him. As for her relationship with her husband Hugo, due to the long-term separation between the two places, the relationship seemed to be coming to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hugo told Jane Goodall that they had to decide how to live in the future. He needed someone to stay with him in the savannah of the Serengeti, and asked her if she would leave Gombe for him. Jane Goodall wrote to her mother for help. &quot;There is no one who cannot be lost... There is no such thing as heartbreak for men. Their work always comes first, and their dreams. Women are just used to set off.&quot; The mother&#39;s reply read. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jane Goodall made a choice, &quot;I can&#39;t leave, this is my life, and he also has his ideals.&quot; They eventually divorced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Documentary director Brett Morgan interpreted their relationship in an interview with POV magazine, &quot;I think it&#39;s a love story, but it&#39;s not about Jane and Hugo. I think it&#39;s about women. and her career, and the man and his career. Because the real love in the film, the otherworldly love, is their career.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Morgan interviewed Jane∙ in Gombe for the documentary Goodall, he realized, for the couple, &quot;this is a happy ending.&quot; Hugo remained in the Serengeti for the rest of his life photographing wildlife and became recognized as one of the best wildlife photographers of all time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jane Goodall continues to study chimpanzees and write books. Starting in 1986, her focus changed, and she realized that if the plight of African chimpanzees was to be known to the world, the next generation must become better conservationists. Since then, she has been traveling to various countries and cities giving lectures almost 300 days a year. Until now, she has been committed to environmental protection and animal conservation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How long will you study chimpanzees?&quot; Jane Goodall was asked in an interview, and her answer was:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I think until I die&quot; day, but I can&#39;t tell you how many years are left.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这古典探案剧，野心真大]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259236]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Looking at the famous scenes of domestic suspense dramas, &quot; Li Toyota lit a cigarette in reverse.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/11de423cd6866c95c00a4475d3f942df.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;405&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/11de423cd6866c95c00a4475d3f942df.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255223&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Ning The physics teacher had a new memory point - extinguishing candles with bare hands and pulling out teeth. The Song Dianshi he played took off his leather gloves and used his severed fingers to wipe away the burning candlelight; if the prisoner was dishonest during interrogation, he would first use pliers to extract a tooth before interrogating him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5ba5c6aeb5058311a4b8eaad0e95578c.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;320&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5ba5c6aeb5058311a4b8eaad0e95578c.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255222&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4b5142b006d8f9b1f196f0d263062d3f.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;320&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4b5142b006d8f9b1f196f0d263062d3f.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;255219&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two clips are from the popular new drama &quot;Fanchengzhi&quot; Down&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1e175ec5605213aae8ab359171a472cc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1919&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1e175ec5605213aae8ab359171a472cc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255220&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The end of the Ming Dynasty , Jiangnan County, serial murders occurred frequently, the deaths were horrific, and strange poems were left at the scene. The first victim&#39;s apprentice, Qu Sangeng (played by Bai Yufan), and Yamen&#39;s official Song Chen (played by Ning Li) join the game and solve the case with other companions...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When following this drama, there is always a kind of thing to watch. The feeling of &quot;Along the River During Qingming Festival&quot;. &quot;Along the River During the Qingming Festival&quot; is a genre painting by the Northern Song Dynasty painter Zhang Zeduan. It is very long and full of details. What comes to mind is the antique style and worldly sentiments. Looking more closely, there are many characters with different shapes, and there are twists and turns behind each person. A long story; magnify it 10 times and it will give you a different scenery. It is rumored that there are unknown secrets hidden in the pictures, and there are lice crawling in the Chinese clothes. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This coincides with &quot;Under the City&quot;. The plot unfolds by peeling off the cocoon, using Jingwei County to observe the style of the late Ming Dynasty, lamenting the fate of the characters, and watching the moths walking through the sturdy towers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;World conditions, society and the style of the late Ming Dynasty&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When viewing paintings, it is important to first look at the overall situation, and the same is true for watching dramas. When you open &quot;Under the City&quot;, you will be drawn into the story by its highly restored late Ming aesthetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stylization is its key word. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smoky alleys covered with green moss due to perennial humidity, the smoky willow alleys with the setting sun reflected in the fragrance of rotten flowers, the yamen torture chambers with no sunlight and only the smell of blood...these seemingly inadvertent... The lens is full of long-lasting charm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6ffe9ed43a58c151859bba963bc768bd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;2700&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6ffe9ed43a58c151859bba963bc768bd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255224&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Preliminary art work When planning the design, the crew scanned many ancient architectural models for reference, and made more than 60 sets of three-dimensional models and more than 150 atmosphere pictures. The scenery and furnishings pursue realism and freehand brushwork, and perfectly restore the style of the late Ming Dynasty in a balance between reality and reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2e329b69043fad7c8d8e0ef480f8ce95.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;961&quot; height= &quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/2e329b69043fad7c8d8e0ef480f8ce95.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255221&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each role They are all designed with matching looks. The book boy Lu Zhi alone has 16 outfits. The police uniform that Qu Sangen often wears is designed based on the historical data of the Ming Dynasty and incorporates the texture of ink. The easily overlooked waist accessories reveal the differences in status between people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4727c1fdf575eecbc3eec34640648f40.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/4727c1fdf575eecbc3eec34640648f40.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255226&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;服道化是最直观的量尺，可以精准标刻出年代的风貌。只有建构了真实可信的环境，才能让观众进入剧情，更好地沉浸在繁城谜案之间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得注意的是，本剧采取的是2.042:1宽银幕画幅，区别于传统的4:3或16:9画幅。宽度的延展意味着：镜头的景深更丰富，视效也更接近目触所及，得以提升观众的沉浸感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/adc88ec691b90e917c122de13ba898f0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1623&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/adc88ec691b90e917c122de13ba898f0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255227&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;叙事视角与古典探案&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;看《清明上河图》，时常会觉得眼花缭乱，左眼观郊野春意，右眼看河畔店肆。 《繁城之下》与它一样，从任何一个视角切入都可以丝滑进入不同叙事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1-3集主打小捕快曲三更的视角，师傅冷捕头之死以他的主观镜头呈现。师傅惨死，夫子丧命，旧仆现尸，凶手猖獗，三更浑浑噩噩地周旋在不同势力间查案，意外发现了20年前的陆家失火案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/91b6957ac720f205122ffde0fbee597e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/91b6957ac720f205122ffde0fbee597e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255225&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和同侪高士聪、挚友凤可追交游；慰问师娘和师妹；走访旧案证人……曲三更的社会关系铺陈开来，引入了各怀心事的小人物们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/e7e4b9a7330a5fc284c36cb576d22c04.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/e7e4b9a7330a5fc284c36cb576d22c04.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255229&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了第4集，剧情陡然一转至20年前，陆府尚且兴旺，话头交给了他们家的书童陆直。他为人聪明伶俐，深得陆府上下欢心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/fed6dff701201c04cabac9dfa68e3b75.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/fed6dff701201c04cabac9dfa68e3b75.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255230&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;借由他的视角，陆老爷、仆人陈旺、哑巴忠爷逐一登场，热热闹闹的陆府藏着许多秘密。陆直在不经意间发现冷捕头与陆老爷情人的恋爱关系，也知道了王夫子和学生的奇怪关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/cd5a1449ca797fb69e77f9662ec00431.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/cd5a1449ca797fb69e77f9662ec00431.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255231&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看到这里再回想前3集的命案，会惊讶地发现：似乎一切都对上了，冷捕头、王夫子、陈旺都与当年的陆家有千丝万缕的联系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第5集又变为全知视角，一股脑倒给了看客新线索：衙门里来了急于立威的新捕头、曲三更和高士聪继续缉凶，以及街坊邻居嘴里的作祟猴妖。看似离题的闲笔猴妖案，又牵起了前尘旧案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每集的时长还不一样，没有刻意划分为45分钟一集，以段落的起与收为时间标记节点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;叙事视角不同，观众就能接收到不同信息，既能共情一心追凶的三更，又能屏气凝神地跟着陆直一探旧日渊源，还能在街市碎语中闲闲地搭只耳朵。前尘、今夕，旧事、新案，被灵活地串联在了一起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代悬疑剧往往走的是社会派的路子，以本剧为代表的古代悬疑则扎根于精巧扎实的古典主义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《繁城之下》强调逻辑至上，以解谜和诡计为核心：骇人的连环命案是开胃前菜，重头戏则是案中案、谜中谜、情中情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20年前，粉饰太平的陆府暗流涌动，被收养的“干少爷”陆直好奇心重得很，翻搅着成人世界的诸多奥秘，也窥探出了看似不相干之人的隐情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/7e9a57a888937c8a370640eab69e6c2f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;554&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/7e9a57a888937c8a370640eab69e6c2f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255232&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他是陆府失火案中的幸存者，也是连接过去和现在时空的一把钥匙，就像那只神秘莫测的灵猴一样行踪不明。 20年后的死者皆是昔日的局中人，那么，谁又是做局者呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;棘手的问题被抛给了捕快曲三更，他和同伴走街串巷、四处探访，从案牍库到烟柳巷都遍布了他们的足迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0ab156112d7688742ce91053be888f74.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/0ab156112d7688742ce91053be888f74.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255234&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;探案不借助怪力乱神，也没有高新科技助力，单靠脑力和腿力，可以说是相当符合古代传统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b64e9a8d6036eadcb18af6669bace0aa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b64e9a8d6036eadcb18af6669bace0aa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255236&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，由于剧集独特的叙事方式，不对观众藏掖信息，不用镜头语言误导，故观众得知的信息量总是大于捕快。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们比曲三更早一步知道冷捕头的死亡方式，也先于他知晓20年前陆直的遭遇，期待的是捕快如何将碎片拼成一张图的过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;人物命运与社会生态链&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;看《清明上河图》的时候第一感觉是：繁荣、人多。但若半卷画轴，放大研读，会看到细节里隐藏的盛世暗影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初看《繁城之下》，也觉市井繁荣、人声鼎沸。官吏乡绅、贩夫走卒、烟花女子，各路人马走马灯似的登场，粗粗勾勒出了蠹县人物群像。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但当显微镜拉近，你会发现上至州府县官，下至平民百姓，都被纳入严密相扣的社会生态链中，处处都是机巧暗隐的博弈局。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;典史宋辰、冷捕头等人具备特定职权，但归根结底还是困在日益僵化的系统里、另用一套隐规则行事的基层小吏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;典史是县令的佐杂官，无具体品阶但受命于皇帝签批，掌管缉捕、监狱等事务，所以宋辰对捕头有一定威慑力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;捕头统领的快班负责缉凶查案，皂班负责升堂打板，像剧中高士聪这样花钱进来当个临时工的人不少。所以一旦有事，高士聪们就是第一批辞退的对象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5434e1d86ea7305ac52af7967a2ad966.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;1428&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5434e1d86ea7305ac52af7967a2ad966.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255233&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;空降的夏捕头是衙门最害怕的一类人，因为短时间内很难摸清他的背景。于是平常耀武扬威的小吏只有被打板子的命，忍痛看他立威。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1eafb08470d481b123abd98e742c34fc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/1eafb08470d481b123abd98e742c34fc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255235&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“皇权不下县”这句俗语精准描绘了封建时代郡县以下的权力真空地带，底层官吏拥有了灵活自治的权力，因而基层治理也依赖黑白管理体制，对百姓是一个样子，对流氓恶霸又是另外的办法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冷捕头生前拿捏住了访行打行的命脉，并与其达成了稳固的合作关系，只要不涉及拐卖妇孺等伤天害理之事便睁一只眼闭一只眼，访行打行每月“孝敬”他固定数额的银两，用得着的时候也代行一些脏活累活。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明朝官吏俸禄很低，心思活络之人便在别处想办法。冷捕头吃下的回扣，还会补贴一部分给快班的下属们。但也有如宋辰般清廉之吏，他一月的工资只够去见一次相好的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/231e1c0322880ddcc2b8e159ef935769.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;565&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/231e1c0322880ddcc2b8e159ef935769.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255238&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冷捕头死后，换作皂班易捕头和打行做交易，但他手黑心贪，拿着账本以权谋钱，破坏了微妙的平衡，引发群氓众怒不说，还促使曲三更以计谋端掉访行打行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/eebae343f522ea7228e4ce7967f31088.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;1825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/eebae343f522ea7228e4ce7967f31088.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255237&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;用计一段很是高明，犹如一出古代官场现形记。他利用了易捕头贪得无厌的弱点，假意投诚却暗中使绊，在捕头与打行的矛盾里坐收渔翁之利。他还借着出主意让易捕头触犯宋辰两袖清风的雷区，最后落得里外不是人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6a96d12fe399c1c84c5827957b4564e3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/6a96d12fe399c1c84c5827957b4564e3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说起来，曲三更是剧中成长弧光最饱满的角色。一开始是个直肠子的爽快人，他不用深谙底层官吏的生存法则，自有如师如父的冷捕头庇护周全；师傅死后他被迫成长，开始做一些之前不愿沾染之事，如在三教九流间利用斡旋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他本质上和宋辰是同一类人，在淤泥里待久了难免戴上黑手套，但心里有一团公义之火，照亮他们仰望前路。不难推测，宋辰会是他新的指路人，将代行其师傅的职责。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/fbe94e7cb0ef6cfa0d2ece822efa9598.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/fbe94e7cb0ef6cfa0d2ece822efa9598.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说完了小吏，再来说说平民，他们的生态链同样是“大鱼吃小鱼、小鱼吃虾米”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曲三更在街面上阻拦了一起欺压百姓之事，打行人扮黑脸，他们找来的假秀才扮白脸，局中局，套中套，为的就是吞并老汉的房产。不识字的老汉若不得三更相助，将会是成百上千受害百姓中的一员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/473301c62431b66e80654a0145bc0c60.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;904&quot; height=&quot;1465&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/473301c62431b66e80654a0145bc0c60.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255244&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陆家的书童陆直天性聪颖，陆老爷高兴的时候一拍大腿，直呼给他脱贱籍，让他考个功名。明代不允许贱民参与科考，除非疏通关系脱离贱籍，另外曲三更这些胥吏也无科考权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f705ffc52289396448673bf882f0bb19.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;883&quot; height=&quot;669&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/f705ffc52289396448673bf882f0bb19.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为何陆老爷花点银子就能办好户籍之事？因为他是当地乡绅，还认识举人。明代举人数目众多，想当官得等着空缺，但不管如何，社会地位远高于普通大众，例如剧中的薛举人住着大宅，养着仆人，遣人走动着与小吏的关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从蠹县的社会生态链来看，《繁城之下》不仅是一部古代悬疑剧，还是全幅度、多细节的明末实录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何谓蠹县？ “蠹”即蛀虫。这个阴晴不定的繁城有瓜果的芬香，也有爬行的腐虫。曲三更、宋辰、陆直他们，有人拿明牌，有人站暗桩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b4fe9e9f6a1e03eb55fa6e299b4297fd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/b4fe9e9f6a1e03eb55fa6e299b4297fd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255241&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三人的名字也起得意味深远：“曲”和“直”是一对反义词，但“公道是一条绕了二十年的远路”，谁挠曲，谁枉直？ “辰”即辰光，阴暗角落里断指沾血之人会带来辰光吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a0939bb0c113b9855b6ad5d65f3fc942.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;904&quot; height=&quot;1027&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/a0939bb0c113b9855b6ad5d65f3fc942.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在最新的剧情中，宋辰的隐秘过往被揭开，曲三更主动入狱寻求破局之道，而城中的猴妖抓捕大戏也愈演愈烈，陆直是否改名换姓有了新身份呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看似站在对立面的曲宋与陆直，其实都是微不足道的小人物，而一个无所依靠的人想在系统里获得他认定的公义绝非易事，必然要付出常人想不到的艰辛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写案、写人只是《繁城之下》的表层，归根结底，它直指的是身不由心的时运及命运悲剧、湮没在时代车轮下的恸哭哀鸣，以及山雨欲来的封建社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它让人想到了同属腾讯视频X剧场的另一部剧——《漫长的季节》，它们都以案件开局，都又不止步于悬案，而是有更大的野心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;个人挽歌在时代洪流中，被记录，被镌刻。公义或许会来迟，但不会缺席，就像阴雨连绵的蠹县，总有光风霁月的一天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[居民医保一年减少2500万人？是真的但别误读，这个保险真值得买丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259366]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，有媒体称“居民医保一年减少2500万人”，并设问为什么有人主动退保，其认为：“除了正常自然减少的情况，一个重要原因是居民主动退保。这主要是因为保费持续上涨。2003年-2023年，20年时间，个人保费增长了37倍。第二个原因是，不少未参保的居民身体健康。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个解释是错误的。国家医保局《2022年医疗保障事业发展统计快报》说得很明白：截至2022年底，基本医疗保险参保人数134570万人。随着全国统一的医保信息平台上线，各省加大数据治理比对，参保人数主要由于清理重复参保同比减少1727万人……其中，参加职工基本医疗保险人数36242万人，同比增加811万人；参加城乡居民基本医疗保险人数98328万人，同比减少2538万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;城乡居民基本医疗保险（简称“居民医保”），是由以前的城镇居民基本医疗保险与新农合合并而来的，以体现对城乡居民的一体平等医疗保障。其与城镇职工基本医疗保险（简称“职工医保”）的运作模式有显著差异，最大差异在于前者是自愿参保，后者是强制参保。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理论上，因为居民医保是自愿参保，当然可以主动退保或不参保，但这样做是不明智的。因为居民医保个人每年出几百元保费是小头，政府补贴才是大头，无论男女老少，个人的优势策略是年年买、不断保。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以上海为例，上海居民医保个人缴费标准相比其他省份是较高的。 2022年，少儿学生个人缴费220元，财政补贴1660元，后者是前者的7.5倍；15-59周岁个人缴费860元，财政补贴2750元，后者是前者的3.2倍；60-69周岁个人缴费690元，财政补贴5940元，后者是前者的8.6倍；70周岁以上个人缴费520元，财政补贴6110元，后者是前者的11.8倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为个人，如果不需要强制参加职工医保，你会自愿参加居民医保吗？参加后会选择退保吗？答案是不言而喻的。说到底，居民医保是个人出小头+政府财政补贴出大头的筹款模式。当然，再往下推一步，政府财政收入或税收来自工作者与企业缴纳的税金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比较而言，职工医保是强制参保，以个人税前工资为基数，费率一般是个人缴纳2%，企业缴纳8%，有些城市养老负担重的，企业费率还会高一些。当然，无论是以个人还是企业的名义缴费，本质上都是个人全部工资或企业全部用工成本的一部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;职工医保个人最低与最高缴费基数是当地社会平均工资的60%与300%，也就是说，两个人，一个顶格缴最高保费，另一个顶格缴最低保费，前者的缴费是后者的5倍，但这两人除了个人账户余额不一样之外，门诊及住院享受的报销比例是一样的，与个人缴费多少完全无关。这反映了职工医保的代内转移支付属性：高收入者对低收入者的转移支付。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就导致一些效应：某些处于自由竞争行业、成本敏感的“边际企业”，对于员工参加职工医保，策略是只让“正式员工”参加，或者做低员工税前工资，因为，在企业眼里，职工医保强制缴费有显著的税性，自然是能避就避了；某些人是灵活就业或自由职业，TA明智的做法是不参加职工医保，因为“太贵了”，而选择参加居民医保。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再对比一下居民医保与职工医保参保者享受的医疗待遇。囿于文章篇幅，这里略过门诊不谈，只比较住院报销比例。不难发现，在两者个人支付成本相差悬殊的前提下，居民医保参保者的住院报销比例比职工医保低得并不多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样以上海为例。目前居民医保住院或急诊观察室报销比例，在50-300元的费用自负段之上，婴幼儿与学生为80%(一级)-70%(二级)-60%(三级)，19至59周岁为80%(一级)-75%(二级)-60%(三级)，60至69周岁为90%(一级)-80%(二级)-70%(三级)，70周岁以上为70%(一级)-60%(二级)-50%(三级)，括号内为医院等级。医院等级越低，报销比例越高，这是鼓励参保者尽量去基层医院。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比较而言，目前职工医保住院或急诊观察室，在职职工报销比例，起付标准以上、最高支付限额以下为85%，最高限额以上为80%；退休职工报销比例，起付标准以上、最高限额以下为92%，最高支付限额以上为80%。比居民医保报销比例是要高一些。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由此不难看出职工医保的代际转移支付属性：工作者、年轻人与下一代对退休者、老年人与上一代的转移支付，或者可以直观理解为“所有的子女养所有的父母”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，无论居民医保还是职工医保，虽然名为保险，但和一般商业保险的运作逻辑是不一样的。商业保险，会根据参保人的年龄与健康状况，精算确定与收取保费，患有某些疾病会被拒保，个人参保前不能隐瞒某些疾病否则可能被拒赔。如果每年收取一个固定的保费，其实意味着会在年轻时多收一些，因为年轻时生病的概率低，收取的保费扣除当年的消费额就是所谓的“现金价值”。而政府医保，并不会因参保人的年龄太大或身体太差而拒保，也不会根据个人的年龄与健康状况精算保费。所以，这是一种保障(Security)。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，如果你父母在城里无业或在乡下，督促或替他们购买居民医保是明智的选择。在此基础上，再给他们购买大病医疗互助补充保险也是不错的选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[莫砺锋：“花瓣飘落的方向，是风决定的”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259413]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;博士档案&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;莫砺锋，新中国第一位文学博士。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1949年4月，出生于江苏省无锡市。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1963-1966年，江苏省苏州高级中学读高中。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1968-1977年，在江苏省太仓县和安徽省泗县插队务农。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978年-1979年，安徽大学外文系英语专业本科生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1979-1981年，南京大学中文系中国古代文学专业硕士研究生，师从程千帆先生，获文学硕士学位。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1982年，成为南京大学中文系古代文学专业博士研究生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1984年10月，毕业于南京大学中国古代文学专业。钱仲联、程千帆、唐圭璋、徐中玉等大师级学者和300多位南大师生共同见证了莫砺锋博士学位论文答辩。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1984年起在南京大学任教。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2006-2007年，成为央视百家讲坛主讲人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2014年，被评为南京大学人文社会科学资深教授。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2020年9月，任南京大学梅庵书院首任院长。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2022年5月，退休。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;曾任南京大学文学院教授、博士生导师，南京大学中文系主任，南京大学中国诗学研究中心主任，第八届、九届江苏省政协委员，第十届江苏省政协常委。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;学术兼职有全国古籍整理与出版规划小组成员，教育部社会科学委员会委员，中国唐代文学学会顾问，中国宋代文学学会名誉会长，江苏省中国古代文学学会名誉会长，复旦大学中国古代文学研究中心学术委员会委员。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/EeaIWbul4Ebi5tmXLkYQgKN31ihMAUMhBpO6pPm4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/EeaIWbul4Ebi5tmXLkYQgKN31ihMAUMhBpO6pPm4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255706&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月12日，莫砺锋在自家书房。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者魏翠翠/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年5月23日，在南京大学文学院的一堂“唐宋文学研究”课上，一百多号学生挤满了教室。讲桌上放着一个黑色保温杯和一个素色背包，一位身着淡蓝色长袖衬衫，戴着无框眼镜的老先生端坐在讲台上说道，“感谢南大的同学至今没有把我轰下讲坛，让我完整地走完了教书生涯。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老先生叫莫砺锋，是南京大学文学院教授、南京大学中国诗学研究中心主任、梅庵书院首任院长，74岁的他当天完成了教学生涯的最后一课。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1979年9月，莫砺锋考进南大，开始从事古代文学的学习，之后留校任教，至此已经是第44个年头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鲜为人知的是，莫砺锋还是新中国的首位文学博士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1981年，国务院学位委员会公布了新中国第一批博士生导师名单，这批代表着当时学术界最高水准的业界精英培养出了新中国首批博士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1984年10月，莫砺锋博士论文答辩登上了中央电视台的新闻联播，他也拿到了新中国成立后的第一张文学博士学位证书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为中国古代文学研究领域的资深教授，莫砺锋的前半生却与古代文学毫无关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1949年4月，莫砺锋出生于江苏无锡。1966年，高三毕业时，他报考志愿全填的是清华的工科专业。当年7月，高考招生暂停，成为工程师的梦想在瞬间破碎。此后十年，他下乡插队，在田间地头度过苦涩的青春时光。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1977年恢复高考，他的人生迎来转机——进入安徽大学英语专业学习。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尔后，随着改革开放启幕，研究生教育恢复，莫砺锋再次抓住机会。1979年，也就是研究生考试恢复的第二年，在安徽大学英文系学习三个学期后，他考取南京大学中文系研究生，走上古代文学的研究道路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;退休后的他依然致力于唐宋诗词普及工作，办讲座、参加书展……他曾说最大的心愿是做一个站在唐诗宋词“仙山秘境”入口处，向游客指点入山之路，解说沿途风景的导游，告诉大家，哪里别有风味，哪里又曲径通幽。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月，江南阴雨连绵，路人行色匆匆，梧桐的树叶随着雨滴一起落下。在南京玄武区的一处居民小区里，莫砺锋聊起他的人生经历，他引用南朝哲学家范缜关于“随风飘落的花瓣”的比喻来形容自己的命运——“树上的花瓣被风吹落下来，飘落的方向不是花瓣决定的，而是风决定的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;除了读书别无他途&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在之前的采访中常常提及你的父亲，还讲过“兄弟姐妹与爸爸比赛背唐诗”的场景，你对文学的这种热爱是从家庭环境中萌芽的吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的父亲来自河南农村，初中读了一年多，遇日寇侵华，他辍学当兵，解放后一直在地方供销社工作，母亲也只读过初中一年级。小时候家里穷，读唐诗是因为家中正好有一本《唐诗三百首》，父亲喜欢，我们也跟着读。直到高中毕业，下乡插队后才较多地接触到古典作品。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父母对我的影响和我现在从事的专业没有任何关系，他们对我最大的影响在于做人很诚恳，很勤劳，以及与人为善的生活态度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在求学之路上，你表现一直都很优异，高考志愿填了清华的电机工程系、数学力学系，却在高考之前得知高考暂停，当时如何面对这种巨大的落差？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我当时在苏州中学上高中，这所学校非常好。我读中小学时在语文上表现得一般，但数理化还不错。我1966年高中毕业，但那一年正好废除高考，1966届到1968届前后三届的初高中生全部下乡，大学停止招生。大家都很失望，但我们没有选择，只好面对。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在1968年深秋开始下乡，在下乡的十年里，劳作之余，都在孜孜不倦地读书，甚至精读了一本《新名词辞典》，你还曾提及点煤油灯读书的经历。那时的阅读环境是怎样的，留给你的阅读时间多吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实阅读时间不多。集体劳动占据大量时间，那时江南农村真是精耕细作，每天下地的时间很长。只有在下大雨以及春节前后，地里才没活儿，那些日子可以看书。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村里没通电，只能点煤油灯照明，一个月定额供应一斤煤油，一周就点完，也买不到更多。所以，基本上天黑就必须睡觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我读的书也杂乱无章，因为到手的书都是偶然得来，完全不知道下一本能读到什么书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;其他大部分人在做什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我有很多知青伙伴基本不读书，而是打扑克。那时流行彻底的“读书无用论”，我们参加农业劳动用镰刀和锄头，生产队养了6头牛犁地，这些农业劳动都不需要书本知识，大家都认为读书是很傻的事。1972年，大学开始招收工农兵学员，但名额很少，采取推荐制，大部分人没有进入大学的希望，我更没有。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在这种彻底的“读书无用论”的情况下，你为什么爱读书？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这有多方面的原因。一是我喜欢读书，要是完全不读书，我会觉得人生毫无意义。二是我当时被彻底剥夺了上大学的机会，心里愤愤不平，决心像高尔基那样读完“我的大学”。自修式的学习，除了读书别无他途。下乡五六年以后，我彻底断绝了这辈子再进大学的希望，事实上已经没有任何可能。那时上面号召我们一辈子“扎根农村”，我已在心里准备一辈子当个喜欢读书的农民，耕读本是我们的老祖宗提倡的一种生活方式。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，我隐隐约约地感觉到，“读书无用论”的现状是不正常的，它迟早会结束，只是不知道到底要拖到何年何月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/kfYND0AoqQx1wySkbrnVoXKWkoIQEKvbM5MTtRq9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;865&quot; height=&quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/kfYND0AoqQx1wySkbrnVoXKWkoIQEKvbM5MTtRq9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255704&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1979年，莫砺锋考取南京大学中文系研究生，走上古代文学的研究道路。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;报考时，不知道程千帆是谁&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在1977年参加高考时报考安徽大学英文系的契机是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我那时人在安徽，当年省里招生规定，考生年龄不得超过25周岁，只有“学有专长”的老三届高中生才允许超龄报考。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我那时28岁，高中毕业已经11年了，但我没有任何专长。公社里的文教干事同情我。他注意到，我那段时间在读一本很厚的英文原版小说，是我从同学的舅舅那里借来的，干事认定我专长英文，就允许我以“专长英语”的资格报名参加高考。入学后，我发现有的同学其实是随意填报“学有专长”的，也根本没人来考核，但我比较老实，于是报了英文专业，就考进安徽大学的英文系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978年改革开放的当年，研究生教育也恢复了，而你当时在安徽大学英文系学习3个学期，就毅然决定报考南京大学中文系的研究生，这么做的初衷是什么？&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;初衷很简单，每个月的助学金能从18元涨到35元。我在安大每月能领到18元助学金，手头十分拮据。我从安大宿舍出发到省教育厅去查阅各著名大学的招生目录的那个早晨，都还没有想过要报考中文系。我本想考南大的外文系，但外文系要考第二外语——法语、德语或西班牙语。而我没学过，只能临时改成中文系。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你报考研究生时才大二，这在当时应该不常见？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;大二考研究生本是不被允许的，但当时比较特殊。我们77级本科生普遍的情况是学生年龄偏大，我班最大的与最小的相差13岁。那时安大外语系的英语专业分7个班，我在7班。6班是快班，很多同学来自北京、上海，英语基础不错，他们认为自身已具备本科毕业的水平。于是，他们向学校提出提前考研的要求，学校一开始不同意，但他们不停地去磨，最终校方松口说，考虑到你们年纪比较大，再读四年本科，毕业时已三十好几，才决定开这个口子。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们班同学撺掇我跟着6班的同学一起去考研。结果我碰巧考上，于是到南大来读中国古代文学。最有意思的是，我报考时，对南大的古代文学学科一无所知，看到招生简章上的导师是程千帆先生，我压根不知道他是谁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从理工科到英语，再到古代文学，在做这些重要选择时，是否有些一以贯之的原则或者理念，你如何看待其中的偶然性和必然性？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这些都不是我决定的，而是命运决定的，我是顺遂命运者。我最近几年常说，我们就像树上的花瓣，被风一吹就飘下来，事先根本不知道飘到哪里，飘的方向不是花瓣决定的，而是风决定的。我就这样飘到南大。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;偶然性中肯定包含着必然性，但从大环境来说还是偶然性。1966年如果不爆发“文革”，我要么考不上清华，要考上的话就会去学工科。我当时最大的理想是当工程师，我父亲对我的期望也是如此。可惜在他去世多年以后，我才进入大学。父亲没有看到我成为大学生、研究生以及大学教授，是我一生中最大的遗憾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老三届那一代人的命运差不多都是这样，很多事没有办法选择。当年有的同学侥幸被招工，但到城里后进哪个工厂，做什么工种，都只能听从安排。能招上工已经很幸运，我们都羡慕的不得了，毕竟能拿工资，而农民只能挣工分，一天工分的价值只有两三毛钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，这其中也有主观能动性。我一直没放弃读书，很多同学都放弃了。我在苏州中学有一些同班同学成绩很好，但恢复高考后他们早已结婚成家，有两三个娃，也就不想考了，他们后来很快就下岗，一辈子和大学无缘。这样的人很多，碰到那场“狂风”，一下被吹到泥淖里，再也没有翻身的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/lmKOzcxvroJZpvIKZIXnQFhta4ogGIFCqRVVjxH7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;865&quot; height=&quot;618&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/lmKOzcxvroJZpvIKZIXnQFhta4ogGIFCqRVVjxH7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255705&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1980年，莫砺锋和导师程千帆在书房探讨学术问题。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;苦行僧式的培养&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你和程千帆先生的师生情谊也被大家称赞，你还记得和程先生第一次见面时的情景吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;第一次见到程先生时，他66岁，头发已经花白。他对我们说的第一句话是：“有很多考生考前来找我，到家里来见我，有的还带着礼物，只有你们3个人（莫砺锋和师兄徐有富以及师弟张三夕）连封信也没写过，这样很好！”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1979年你入学时学位条例还没有正式颁布，直到1981年国务院批准《学位条例暂行实施办法》，学位制度才正式建立。那时读博算不算冒险？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在1979年9月的开学典礼上，匡亚明校长说学位条例正在制定。他是国务院学位委员会的委员，参与这项工作。我们入学时不分硕士、博士，统称研究生。匡亚明校长说，你们以后会是第一批硕士和博士。两年后我们毕业，学位条例颁布了，我拿到硕士学位，后来又跟着程先生继续读博。我觉得读博是件好事，也完全没有“冒险”的感觉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在真正开始读博前，你对于博士生活的预期是怎样的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;也没有具体的预期，谁知道博士生涯是怎样的。我只是觉得读硕都那么辛苦、紧张，读博肯定只会更加紧张，所以心里做好了坐几年冷板凳的准备。反正我年轻时吃过不少苦，“曾经沧海难为水”，读博肯定不会比种地更辛苦。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那时我们还没有自主培养的博士，作为第一批文学博士的你们是怎么读博的，如何上课和撰写博士论文？据说你刚开始读博时，程先生也不知道博士论文要写到什么程度。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;确是如此，因为博士在中国属于新生事物。当时没有完整的课程体系，培养模式也是暗中摸索的。程先生也不知道博士论文要写到什么程度，他从学校图书馆里借来一堆国外已出版的博士论文，还有不少港台高校的博士论文，读了好几本，才心中有数。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;程先生的培养方式来自哪里，是如何形成的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得是他自己揣摩的，当然也可能是从国外或港台的博士论文的学术水准上推导出来的。由于当时全系只有我一个博士生，所以程先生没有为我在课堂开课，除了外语，我的课程学习完全采取专书阅读的方式，也就是自己读书，遇到难点去先生家请教。程先生规定我攻读8部典籍：《诗经》《楚辞》《论语、孟子》《老子、庄子》《左传》《史记》《文选》《文心雕龙》。每部书都要交读书报告，其中有4篇报告后来作为学术论文公开发表。那种培养模式有点像旧时的手艺人带学徒，师傅手把手地教，学徒边干活边学习。对于中国古代文学这样的学科，那种方式是相当有效的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978年恢复研究生教育时，当年录取了1万人。如今，在读博士约为56万人。许多博士生不免担忧就业前景，对未来迷茫，文科博士更甚。你博士毕业时也会迷茫吗，以及如何看待他们当下的担忧和迷茫？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我1984年博士毕业时，分配工作，可以挑很多单位，最后我选择留在南大。那时国家培养的硕博人数少，客观上没有就业压力，这点跟现在很多文科博士的处境不一样。我很理解现在的同学们，现在博士生人数多，而岗位少。经过多年大规模研究生扩招，大部分单位都不缺人，所以就业越来越难。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这完全是时代的问题，不是个人的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的学生找工作也难。要是找不到工作，压力也会延伸到我这里。当然，今年毕业的3个博士生都已找到工作，分别去了四川大学、中南民族大学和浙江师范大学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/1oMhfOmrHc3MQsFfLDaH9gy2B27iG9KPackfRB5z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;865&quot; height=&quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/1oMhfOmrHc3MQsFfLDaH9gy2B27iG9KPackfRB5z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255703&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2008年，莫砺锋在北京签售百家讲坛图书。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;致力于研究“大家”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你曾提及古代文学研究主要是做翻案工作，因为所有的观点都被人说过了，新观点就是做翻案文章。而你的研究对象多为杜甫、苏东坡、黄庭坚这些大家，选择研究这些“大家”的初衷是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;其实所有学术研究都是做翻案工作，理工科也一样。我在南大读博时，第一届全校就招了10位博士生，每个同学都来自不同系科。我们宿舍住3个人，一个化学系，一个计算机系，我跟他们交流，发现他们做研究，找题目写论文，跟我们一模一样，都是在前人成果的夹缝里面求生活，在很细小的方向上追求一些创新，补充或推翻前人的研究结果。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但对于古代文学学科来说，真正能代表一个时代学术成就的，应该是“大家”研究。一个时代的研究在整体上是否有突破，就看“大家”研究得如何。“小家”研究只是填补空白，不可能成为一个时代学术水准的象征。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你最喜欢的两位诗人是杜甫和苏轼，甚至曾说愿意穿越到宋朝去黄州帮苏轼种地，你认为在研究杜甫和苏轼的过程中，他们带给你最大的体悟是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这可能跟程先生主张的“文学研究，感字当头”有关。我在进大学前开始阅读杜甫和苏轼，当时的唯一动机就是我喜欢他们，我读他们时感到亲切，得到安慰。我多次说过，当我在那座被狂风刮破屋顶的茅屋里过夜，眼看着满天繁星而冻得瑟瑟发抖的时候，杜甫的《茅屋为秋风所破歌》给我带来心灵的震撼。我种过十年地，我觉得自己当个农民并不算屈才。但我真心不愿意让苏东坡也在黄州开荒种地，他那样德才兼备的杰出人物有更重要的事情要做！&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杜、苏二人给我带来的最大体悟就是“安得广厦千万间”的人间情怀，和“一蓑烟雨任平生”的人生态度，我愿意尽我可能来宣扬他们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在“大家”研究中是如何做到创新的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;真正的创新很难，我哪能做到。因为创新要求你比别人看得更深或更远，我没有那么高的水平。此外创新也需要偶然的机会，正好出现很好的新题目，或者很珍贵的新材料，这都是可遇不可求的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我只能尽量不人云亦云，不炒冷饭。我现在普及工作做得较多，讲一些常识性的内容，但如何将常识性内容讲得准确，要求也很高，这和学术的严谨性应该是统一的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;注意到从走进《百家讲坛》之后，你就一直致力于古典诗词的普及工作，开始做普及工作有什么契机？你曾说最大的心愿是做在唐诗宋词“仙山秘境”入口处的导游，这个愿望现在实现了吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我上《百家讲坛》也是偶然。南大百年校庆时，邀请央视的编导来录节目，录完后在《百家讲坛》播出，效果还不错，后来他们就来找我讲唐诗。节目播出后，很多观众来信，反响热烈，我感觉普及工作蛮有意义。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我现在最想达到的目的，是让普通读者和我一样喜欢唐诗宋词，喜欢杜甫和苏东坡。所谓普及，就是走出学校的小教室，走向社会的大教堂。让我欣慰的是，我开讲座时的听众里各个年龄层次各种身份的人都有，我真的走到社会大众中间，也算实现了自己的愿望。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那你认为古代文学的学术研究和普及工作在当下是否面临一些困境？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在的研究有概念化、碎片化的趋势，普及工作则有庸俗化的趋势。前者比如一定要强行发掘某些古典诗词中的现代性，实际上可能没有。如果生搬硬套一些新名词来贴标签，结论就不符合历史真相。还有一些学者选题过于细碎，意义不大。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;普及工作则有庸俗化的趋势。为了吸引观众，切合年轻人的口味，有不少戏说、曲解，而且把古人完整的意境弄得碎片化，缺乏整体感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有什么解决方法吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这个问题难以避免，走向大众，必然会带来不同的口味和要求。我只能要求自己尽量做好。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对当下的年轻人，特别是大学生和研究生群体有什么人生建议吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫砺锋：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我今年6月应邀到安徽大学参加毕业典礼并致辞。我40年前离开安大时没有获得毕业证书，如今以“杰出校友”的身份参加典礼，心中感慨万分。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在典礼上引用东坡的《定风波》来勉励学弟学妹们学习东坡的人生精神，来迎接自己的风雨人生。因为我们普通人的人生必然是充满风雨的，我们不能幻想走上一帆风顺的人生道路，所以一定要做好充分的思想准备。请让我引用在安大的致辞中的几句话来送给其他高校的大学生和研究生群体：“我衷心祝愿同学们像东坡那样始终以&#39;自强不息&#39;的积极态度来对待人生，有所作为。我也衷心希望同学们遇到人生坎坷时以&#39;一蓑烟雨任平生&#39;的格言自我勉励，从容应对！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[演唱会刷屏朋友圈，李健是中产抚慰者？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259370]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;When I miss you, you are in the sky; when I miss you, you are right in front of me.&quot; Recently, Li Jian held the &quot;Like the Sea&quot; online concert, which received more than 30 million views in 2 hours and quickly became a hit in the circle of friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In today&#39;s crowded entertainment industry, there are indeed few singers as lovable as Li Jian. We rarely hear music critics criticizing him, and we don’t see various marketing accounts on Weibo spreading any negative information about him. He is just famous, so popular that it is so natural and so popular that everyone expects it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/huSjlbT3I3FOoTHypGp5yeS64ovaHlSp8XRIbh88.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height= &quot;440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/huSjlbT3I3FOoTHypGp5yeS64ovaHlSp8XRIbh88.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255635&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; Birth: &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Intellectual temperament&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Li Jian has such confidence. He graduated from Tsinghua University with a major in electronic engineering. Compared with many singers whose academic qualifications or cultural qualities are “meager”, Li Jian is outstanding. “Tsinghua top student” is an extremely enviable status, but it is also different from our expectations of science and engineering. The impression that a man is slovenly, unkempt, and ordinary-looking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s more important is Li Jian’s intellectual temperament. Li Jian’s home is neatly filled with records and books. The records he listens to include Leonard Cohen, The Beatles, Freshly Ground, Michael Buble, and Fabio Zanon, and the books he reads include Borges, Zweig, and Lawrence Bubble. Locke, George Orwell, and the last thing he took out was Leonard Cohen&#39;s biography &quot;I&#39;m Your Man.&quot; He has the sobriety and self-control of an intellectual. He consciously keeps a certain distance from the materialistic world and pursues advancement in the spiritual world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From his song selection, we can also see his independent temperament. Some people say that he is a &quot;musical poet&quot;, but in fact, he highlights more of his &quot;musical pride.&quot; For example, the online concert included 10 private covers and 14 original works, explaining his inner feelings about the sea and poetry. Li Jian is always singing in a low voice. He does not show off his skills or hit the high notes. His melody is soft and beautiful, and his singing voice is ethereal and graceful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the side of Li Jian&#39;s birth - he does not pursue external fame and wealth, but rather his pursuit, pride and persistence as an independent individual. In the lavish entertainment industry, he has not lost himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/eAAaCHmRWWJ7NoJc5uuf8J6QNxhWB6R48hPNeYUt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;660&quot; height= &quot;440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/26/eAAaCHmRWWJ7NoJc5uuf8J6QNxhWB6R48hPNeYUt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255636&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; Entering the WTO: I wish the newly graduated &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;all the best&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If this was all Li Jian looked like, maybe it would be difficult for him to be so lovable. After all, there are many aloof singer-songwriters in the music industry - for example, Liang Bo, whose song &quot;Soul Singer&quot; shocked everyone, but his popularity and audience base are far less than those of Li Jian, not to mention other niche singers. What is unique about Li Jian is that he also has a worldly side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Li Jian is not obsessed with material things, he is able to live a good life. He works out, travels, knows coffee, has a special tea room at home, and collects records... Every time he appears in front of the camera, his clothes always make people feel comfortable and comfortable. Li Jian&#39;s life has a cold style. He is not a popular brand that can be seen everywhere on the street. He is Fendi, LV and Hermes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In some interviews, you can see that Li Jian is concerned about some issues that arise in social development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the topic &quot;I hope everyone will experience less setbacks and hardships&quot; became a hot topic on Weibo. Not long ago, he told young people at a concert: &quot;I hope all people can live a simple and easy life.&quot; &quot;You can live a good life without putting in a lot of effort, especially those who have just graduated. It would be better if you experience less setbacks and tribulations. I wish you all the best.&quot; He is not cynical about the predicament. , not hoarse, but blessing and moving forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like his song selection, he is always singing about love, hometown, childhood, moonlight, stars, years and other beautiful things. He does not directly criticize vulgarity, but he sings about beautiful things in a tortuous way. this purpose. You might say Li Jian is &quot;conservative&quot;, but he is very safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s more, Li Jian is also a down-to-earth &quot;upright boy + cute jokester + cute foodie&quot;. He can dispel many serious and stereotyped ways of saying things with ease and make people smile. , and noticed his cuteness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, in Li Jianyan, birth and entry into the world are so perfectly combined. Many people can only do one thing, or they can&#39;t do even one thing well, or they are torn between the two. Li Jian perfectly possesses both. He is the personality ideal of many people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No wonder many comments say that Li Jian is the soul comforter of the middle class. Although Li Jian&#39;s fans include various groups, as media person Zhu Wei said, those who like Li Jian are mainly &quot;literary youth&quot;, &quot;petty bourgeoisie&quot; and &quot;well-educated and delicate emotional groups&quot;. These people belong to the middle class or pre-middle class. If there are any distinctive characteristics of China&#39;s middle class, one of them is the &quot;tearing&quot; between worldliness and worldliness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The middle class have a worldly side. They pursue material things, pursue style, keep to themselves, be conservative and moderate, and long for a quiet and peaceful life in this world. Unfortunately, for the sake of this quiet and peaceful life, they also Having to run around in the reinforced concrete forest of the metropolis, struggling to cope with the fast pace and complex interpersonal relationships in the workplace, and enduring huge life and mental stress, a stable and comfortable life seems out of reach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So they have a worldly side. They want to escape from it all and ignore the house, car, children, and workplace. They want to carve out a spiritual home of their own and block out all the disturbances from the outside world. ; But if they really want to let go of all this, they will feel attached to and unwilling to accept it. The middle class is torn apart because they are unavailable no matter whether they are born in the world or join the world. So they often hesitate between the two, with Ma Yun on their left and Nebula on their right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jian was born perfectly and entered the world perfectly. He lived the way many middle-class people wanted to live, and in this way he became the comforter of the middle-class. Saying this is not to belittle Li Jian. Li Jian has no intention of playing such a role. He just happened to step on the node of the times-the middle class in this era is really tired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李克强同志逝世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259418]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-27 08:11:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 17th, 18th and 19th CPC Central Committee, State Council Comrade Li Keqiang, the former Prime Minister, was resting in Shanghai recently. He suffered a heart attack on October 26, 2023. After all-out rescue efforts, he failed. He died in Shanghai at 0:10 on October 27 at the age of 68. An obituary will be posted later. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>