<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[野泳要防“食脑虫”：全球范围内从无到有，应予以关切]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258373]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the hot summer, people like to swim in lakes and rivers, but now they may face a new risks of. A doctor said on Weibo: &quot;A child during consultation was swimming in a reservoir and was infected with cerebral amoeba. The brain tissue has softened, and the family is unwilling to give up. The friend who swam with the child was fine, but he was infected. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amoeba is a kind of microorganism. Due to different living environments, it can be divided into entamoeba and free-living amoeba. The former is parasitic on humans and animals, and the latter lives in water and In the soil, it occasionally invades animal bodies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many types of amoeba, which can cause dysentery and liver abscesses, meningoencephalitis, keratitis, oral infections and skin lesions. Encephalitis is caused by the amoeba Naegleria. Naegleria-containing amoeba prefers hot and humid environments, and is commonly found in warm water environments above 25°C. Its fecundity is strongest at about 42°C. In nature, they are found in rivers, ponds, puddles and other water bodies, and they may also be found in hot springs and moist soil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a person swims in rivers, lakes or washes his nose with infected water, Naegleria enters the nasal cavity. After proliferating, it passes through the nasal mucosa and cribriform plate, travels up the olfactory nerve, enters the brain, and invades Central nervous system, causing primary amoebic meningoencephalitis (PAM). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Brain tissue is the best place for amoeba to survive. It is rich in phospholipids and has a suitable temperature. Primary amoebic meningoencephalitis has a short incubation period, usually only 3 to 5 days, and a maximum of 7 to 15 days. The onset is sudden and the disease progresses rapidly. Early symptoms of infection include: headache, fever, nausea and vomiting, and neck stiffness; late symptoms include: dizziness, loss of balance, epileptic seizures, abnormal taste and smell, and hallucinations, followed by rapid transition to delirium, paralysis, and coma. Patients often die from brain infection, swelling, and brain function cessation caused by a sudden increase in intracranial pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is still a lack of ideal drugs for the treatment of this disease. Amphotericin B and sulfonamides may have certain effects, but in general, infected people often only have three to seven days to live after symptoms appear, and they die from the infection. The rate can reach more than 95%. Because of this characteristic, this amoeba also has a terrifying name: brain-eating worm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This disease first &quot;appeared&quot; in Australia in 1965, and there are only a few hundred cases of infection worldwide. About half of the cases reported in the past occurred in the United States, and reports have also been reported in the United Kingdom, France, Belgium and other countries. According to the records of the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in the past 53 years, there have been only 133 reports of amoeba infection in the United States. The mortality rate of such patients is high, and only 3 people have survived. In July 2015, a young woman in central California, USA, died from infection with the brain-eating amoeba amoeba. In 2015, 14-year-old track and field player Mike Riley in Houston, Texas, contracted the amoeba &quot;brain-eating worm&quot; after swimming in a lake and died a week later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first case in China occurred in Zhumadian area of ​​Henan Province in 1978 and was reported by Shanghai First Medical College in 1984. Since then, Beijing Friendship Hospital reported one case each in 1991 and 1996, one case was reported in Qiongzhong County, Hainan Province in 2003, and one case was reported in Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province in 2006. None of the cases survived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is alarming is that the doctor also said on Weibo: &quot;I have heard of several cases of cerebral amoeba infection this summer.&quot; A very rare disease broke out in one summer vacation. I have heard several times that it may reflect that primary amoebic meningoencephalitis is increasing. On October 7, 2020, the US &quot;Newsweek&quot; reported that &quot;brain-eating worms&quot; are migrating north across the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, purely based on risk, the risk of contracting &quot;brain-eating worms&quot; from wild swimming is currently very low, so don&#39;t scare yourself by taking advantage of it. However, we must pay attention to the serious consequences of infection and the trend that the probability of infection is increasing globally. The case this doctor came into contact with is an important warning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until authoritative guidance comes out, the way to prevent infection with &quot;brain-eating worms&quot; is to avoid or minimize swimming in warm, unsterilized rivers, lakes, ponds, hot springs and other natural water bodies. , bathe, wash your face, if necessary, keep your head above the water or wear a nose clip, and be careful to avoid disturbing the sediment layer of lakes or ponds, because there may be a large number of amoeba living in it. If you have any suspicious symptoms such as headache, vomiting, abnormal sense of smell, or fever after swimming, you should seek medical attention immediately. The doctor also reminded on Weibo: Do ​​not swim in natural water bodies because there is a risk of drowning and infection. There is also a risk of infection with schistosomiasis and other parasites in southern rivers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Human beings are social animals, and the natural challenges faced by humans must rely on the power of civilized society to solve them. There is no problem swimming in sterilized tap water, which points to the problem of swimming pool construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every summer vacation, schools always set strict rules, requiring students to stay away from rivers and lakes; various places also strictly guard against it and guard the water surfaces. However, China&#39;s swimming pool construction is still insufficient. Relevant statistics show that the per capita sports venue area in my country is 2.41 square meters, while according to estimates, the per capita sports venue area in rural my country is only 1.15 square meters, less than half of the national average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, various places are also strengthening the construction of swimming pools to reduce the cost of using swimming pools. Hainan Province has opened swimming pools in primary schools for free during the summer. The relevant person in charge of the safety department of the province’s Department of Education said, “The free opening has further tightened the protective network to prevent student drowning. So far, the total number of student drowning accidents in Hainan Province this summer has been The number of drowning deaths has dropped significantly year-on-year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The construction of swimming pools can be completely adapted to local conditions and does not necessarily have to be of high standards. As long as it is clean and sanitary and has people on duty, it will be good. After two students drowned in July 2022, Tang Huan, a rural physical education teacher at a rural primary school in Hengshan County, Hunan, built a swimming pool at his own expense to teach children swimming and drowning prevention knowledge. During the same summer vacation, in Xintao Village, Zhaixia Town, Yuanzhou District, Yichun City, Jiangxi Province, a pond of more than 400 square meters was transformed into a swimming pool according to local conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children have an innate love for water. Taking the initiative to provide students with a safe and controllable swimming environment can not only avoid drowning and contracting diseases, but also help to draw children away from the screen and into sports. Go in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[中国2022年出生人口956万 二孩占比近4成]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258467]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The National Health Commission today (October 12) released the 2022 Statistical Bulletin on my country’s Health Care Development ( (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Communique&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The total number of diagnosis and treatment visits in 2022 will be 8.42 billion, which is basically the same as the previous year.&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Bulletin&quot; shows that the total number of diagnosis and treatment visits in medical and health institutions nationwide in 2022 will be 8.42 billion, which is basically the same as the previous year. Residents visit medical and health institutions an average of 6 times per person per year. The &quot;Communique&quot; shows that our country&#39;s government investment has continued to increase, medical and health resources have been improved and expanded, the health service system has been continuously improved, and the construction of a healthy China has been steadily advancing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Communique&quot; shows that my country&#39;s total medical and health resources continue to increase. By the end of 2022, the number of medical and health institutions nationwide will reach 1,032,918, an increase of 1,983 over the previous year. There are 13 national medical centers and national regional medical centers for children across the country. There are 9.75 million beds in medical and health institutions nationwide, and the number of beds in medical and health institutions per 1,000 people will increase from 6.70 in 2021 to 6.92 in 2022. The total number of health personnel nationwide is 14.411 million, an increase of 425,000 over the previous year (an increase of 3.0%). There are 3.15 practicing (assistant) physicians per 1,000 population and 3.71 registered nurses per 1,000 population. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total national health expenditure in 2022 is initially estimated to be 8.48467 billion yuan, of which government health expenditure accounts for 28.2%; social health expenditure accounts for 44.8%; personal health expenditure is 2.29145 billion yuan, accounting for 27.0%. The total health expenditure per capita is 6,010.0 yuan, and the total health expenditure accounts for 7.0% of GDP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the total number of visits to medical and health institutions across the country will be 8.42 billion, which is basically the same as the previous year. The number of admissions to medical and health institutions across the country was 246.86 million, basically the same as the previous year, and the annual hospitalization rate of residents was 17.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the hospital’s average outpatient cost is 342.7 yuan, the average hospitalization cost is 10,860.6 yuan, and the average daily hospitalization cost is 1,186.5 yuan. Among them, the average outpatient drug expense of the hospital was 130.3 yuan, accounting for 38.0% of the average outpatient expense, an increase of 0.5 percentage points from the previous year (37.5%); the average inpatient drug expense of the hospital was 2,640.5 yuan, accounting for 24.3% of the average inpatient expense. A decrease of 0.8 percentage points from the previous year (25.1%). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among public hospitals at all levels, the average outpatient expenses in tertiary hospitals increased by 3.1%, while the average inpatient expenses decreased by 4.0%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;By the end of 2022, there will be 17,555 county-level hospitals in the country&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In terms of primary health services, the 2022 my country Health Care Development Statistical Bulletin shows that by the end of 2022, there will be 17,555 county-level hospitals across the country (including There are 17,555 hospitals in county-level cities), 34,000 township health centers, and 588,000 village clinics. There are 1.35 billion diagnoses and treatments in county-level (including county-level cities) hospitals nationwide, 1.21 billion diagnoses and treatments in township health centers, and 1.21 billion diagnoses and treatments in village clinics. 1.28 billion. 36,448 community health service centers (stations) were established, with 690 million visits to community health service centers and 140 million visits to community health service stations across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of basic public health service projects, the per capita financial subsidy standard for basic public health service projects will increase from 79 yuan in 2021 to 84 yuan in 2022. In 2022, there will be 127.083 million elderly people aged 65 and above receiving health management in primary medical and health institutions. In 2022, the total number of visits to traditional Chinese medicine medical and health institutions across the country will be 1.23 billion, an increase of 20 million over the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The second child will account for nearly 40% of the 9.56 million people born in 2022&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In terms of population development and maternal and child health, the 2022 Statistical Bulletin on the Development of my country’s Health Careers shows that the number of children born nationwide in 2022 The population is 9.56 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The proportion of second children among the population born in 2022 will be 38.9%, the proportion of three children and above will be 15.0%, and the sex ratio at birth will be 111.1. In 2022, there will be a total of 75,700 childcare service institutions nationwide, providing There are 3.624 million institutions in the country, and 2.57 institutions per 1,000 people nationwide. A total of 27.80 billion yuan was invested in the “two systems” of incentives and assistance for some rural family planning families and special assistance for family planning families, an increase of 3.75 billion yuan over the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of maternal and child health, in 2022, the prenatal checkup rate for pregnant women in my country will be 97.9%, and the postpartum visit rate will be 96.5%. Compared with the previous year, the rate of prenatal check-ups and postpartum visits has increased. In 2022, the national hospital delivery rate will be 99.94%, basically achieving all hospital deliveries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Maternal and Child Health Monitoring, in 2022, my country’s child mortality rate under 5 years old will be 6.8‰, infant mortality rate will be 4.9‰, and the national maternal mortality rate will be 15.7/100,000, all of which have declined to varying degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, a total of 8.162 million couples planning pregnancy will be provided with free examinations across the country, with an average target population coverage rate of 91.8%. All risk groups identified through screening received targeted consultation, guidance, treatment referral and other services, and implemented pre-pregnancy preventive measures, effectively reducing the risk of birth defects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中办、国办：调整中国人民银行职责、机构、编制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258495]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:25:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;China Institutional Establishment Network reported on October 12 that the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council issued a notice on the adjustment of the Chinese People&#39;s Notice prepared by the bank&#39;s responsible organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Notice of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council on Adjusting the Establishment of Responsible Organizations of the People&#39;s Bank of China&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;(September 24, 2023)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In accordance with the &quot;Party and State Institutional Reform Plan&quot; and upon approval by the Party Central Committee and the State Council, the People&#39;s Bank of China is hereby notified of the following adjustments to its responsibilities, structures, and establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1. Regarding the adjustment of main responsibilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;(1) The Financial Stability and Development Committee of the State Council and its office will no longer be retained. The responsibilities of the Office of the Financial Stability and Development Commission of the State Council will be transferred to the Office of the Central Financial Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(2) Transfer the daily supervision responsibilities of financial holding companies and other financial groups to the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(3) The responsibility for establishing and improving the basic system for financial consumer protection will be assigned to the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;II. Regarding the adjustment of organizational structure&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;(1) The Secretariat of the Office of the Financial Stability and Development Commission of the State Council, located at the People’s Bank of China, will be included in the central financial Committee Office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(2) The People’s Bank of China will no longer retain the Financial Consumer Rights Protection Bureau. The responsibilities of coordinating and promoting related inclusive finance, originally undertaken by the Financial Consumer Rights Protection Bureau, have been transferred to the Financial Markets Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(3) The Macro-Prudential Administration will no longer assume the daily supervision responsibilities of financial holding companies and other financial groups. The Department of Financial Markets&#39; responsibilities for coordinating Internet financial supervision and formulating and organizing the implementation of macro credit guidance policies related to the real estate finance field will be assigned to the Macro-Prudential Management Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;3. Regarding the adjustment of administrative establishment and leadership positions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Based on the transfer of responsibilities, the People&#39;s Bank of China will reduce the administrative establishment of 30 people and the number of 6 departments and bureaus accordingly. Level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the adjustment, the People&#39;s Bank of China has 20 internal institutions, an administrative staff of 714, and 87 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中办、国办：调整国家卫健委职责、机构、编制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258497]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:26:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Notice of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council on Adjusting the Responsibilities of the National Health Commission&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; (September 24, 2023)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Plan for the Reform of Party and State Institutions&quot; and the &quot;Optimization and Adjustment Plan for the Discussion and Coordination Institutions of the Party Central Committee and the State Council&quot;, and after being submitted to the Party Central Committee and the State Council for approval, it is now The National Health Commission’s responsibilities, structures, and staffing adjustments are notified as follows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. The Ministry of Science and Technology’s responsibility for organizing and formulating plans and policies for science and technology to promote health development will be assigned to the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. The responsibilities of the National Health Commission, including the organization, formulation, coordination and implementation of policies and measures to deal with population aging, and the specific work of the National Working Committee on Aging, will be assigned to the Ministry of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. The China Association on Aging, which is managed by the National Health Commission, is now managed by the Ministry of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. Transfer four administrative staff and one department-level leadership position from the Ministry of Science and Technology to the National Health Commission. The three administrative staff of the National Health Commission will be transferred to the Ministry of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the adjustment, the National Health Commission has 19 internal agencies, an administrative staff of 444, and 81 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中办、国办：调整生态环境部职责、机构、编制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258503]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:27:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 12, the China Institutional Establishment Network released the &quot;General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council on Adjustments to the Ministry of Ecology and Environment&quot; Notice on the Establishment of Responsible Organizations&quot;: According to the &quot;Party and State Institutional Reform Plan&quot; and the &quot;Optimization and Adjustment Plan for the Discussion and Coordination Institutions of the Party Central Committee and the State Council&quot;, and after being submitted to the Party Central Committee and the State Council for approval, the responsibilities, institutions, and establishment adjustments of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment are now The notice is as follows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Incorporate the Ministry of Science and Technology’s responsibilities for organizing the formulation of plans and policies for science and technology to promote ecological environment development, and its internal social development science and technology department with 4 administrative staff and 1 department-level leadership position. Ministry of Ecology and Environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. The Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas air pollution prevention and control leading group and its offices will no longer be retained. The Department of Atmospheric Environment of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment will no longer display the brand of the Atmospheric Environment Administration Bureau of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei and surrounding areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. The Central Ecological and Environmental Protection Inspection Office, an internal agency of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, was renamed the Central Ecological and Environmental Protection Inspection and Coordination Bureau, and its responsibilities were stated as “responsible for the daily activities of the State Council’s Ecological and Environmental Protection Inspection Leading Group” &quot;Work&quot; was revised to &quot;undertake specific affairs of the Central Ecological Environmental Protection Inspection Leading Group Office&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the adjustment, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment has 21 internal agencies, 504 administrative staff, and 79 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中办、国办：调整工信部职责、机构、编制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258501]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:29:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 12, the China Institutional Establishment Network released the &quot;General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the State Council on Adjusting Industry and Information Notice on the establishment of responsible agencies of the Ministry of Chemical Industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Notice of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council on Adjusting the Responsibilities of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Party and State Institutional Reform Plan&quot; and the &quot;Coordination of the Party Central Committee and the State Council&quot; &quot;Organizational Optimization and Adjustment Plan&quot;, which has been submitted to the Party Central Committee and the State Council for approval, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology&#39;s responsibilities, institutions, and establishment adjustment matters are hereby notified as follows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Organize the Ministry of Science and Technology to formulate high-tech development and industrialization plans and policies, guide the construction of science and technology parks such as national independent innovation demonstration zones and national high-tech industrial development zones, and guide the science and technology service industry, technology Responsibilities such as marketing and the development of science and technology intermediary organizations are assigned to the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. The State Council’s Leading Group for Promoting the Development of Small and Medium-sized Enterprises and its office will no longer be retained. The relevant specific work will be undertaken by the Small and Medium-sized Enterprise Bureau of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. The High-tech Department of the Ministry of Science and Technology will have an administrative establishment of 25 and 4 bureau-level leaders; the Achievements Transformation and Regional Innovation Department will have an administrative establishment of 6 and 2 bureau-level leaders. The number is transferred to the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the adjustment, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology has 23 internal agencies, an administrative staff of 725, and 110 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[西安某大学女生被63页PPT控诉出轨：如此行为侵犯隐私吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258474]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州警方：编造“广州地铁遭恐怖袭击”谣言嫌疑人被抓获]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258493]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 22:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/12/c82153854f91b207d8f0e5d238279f5e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;582&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c82153854f91b207d8f0e5d238279 f5e. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253974&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 12, a rumor about the Guangzhou Metro went viral on the Internet According to the news, the Guangzhou police quickly filed a case and launched an investigation. At about 18:19 that day, they arrested the suspect Tan Mou (male, 23 years old, Guangxi) who deliberately fabricated and released the information in a village in the city of Tianhe District. After interrogation, Tan confessed that he made up the rumor to show off his ability to generate specific pages through computer programming technology. At present, the criminal suspect Tan has been criminally detained by the police in accordance with the law, and the case is still under further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The police remind: The Internet is not a place outside the law. Illegal and criminal acts such as fabricating and deliberately spreading Internet rumors will be severely punished by law. Please do not believe or spread rumors, and work together to maintain a clean space on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[太原理工大学书记郑强婚内出轨？山西省纪委回应：正了解相关情况]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258482]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a netizen reported that Zheng Qiang, secretary of the Party Committee of Taiyuan University of Technology and Internet celebrity professor, had an affair with his ex-girlfriend, causing extensive attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, the informant stated that Zheng Qiang called his girlfriend in the early morning of one morning in July 2015 and was discovered by him. The two parties broke up a few months later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whistleblower said that he and Zheng Qiang met once in March this year, and the other party advised him to be cautious. This year, he reported it to the relevant school authorities and disciplinary inspection departments, but so far there has been no result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response, the Shanxi Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection responded: It is understanding the relevant situation. Zheng Qiang himself released information through his public account saying: The report is untrue and the police have been called. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, Zheng Qiang commissioned a law firm to issue a statement, saying that the above-mentioned content posted by netizens was seriously inconsistent with the facts and that it had protected its rights through legal channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/02d6806979a40195e6c55dfd834494d8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;557&quot; height=&quot;874&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/02d6806979a40195e6c55dfd834494d8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253918&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/d4b37d8ce7d1da72a49bde39c21207d3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;549&quot; height=&quot;371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/d4b37d8ce7d1da72a49bde39c21207d3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253917&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 12, the &quot;Professor Zheng Qiang&quot; public account issued a &quot;Stern Statement on the Recent False News Related to Comrade Zheng Qiang on the Internet&quot; stating that the account &quot;Huaqu&quot; has recently published and spread false information on the Internet. , it has been confirmed that the real name of the publisher is Lv, who is a criminal released from prison. All the text and picture content published are maliciously fabricated and fictitious false information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statement stated: In March 2023, Lu contacted Zheng Qiang in the name of a &quot;fan&quot; and told his personal experience and feelings about serving time in prison, hoping to get relevant help. In June 2023, Lv contacted Zheng Qiang again, hoping to get Zheng Qiang&#39;s support in his social work and asked to introduce resources to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Lv’s actual request was for me to come forward as a guarantee for a loan of 10 million yuan, which was directly and sternly rejected. So Lv began to continuously fabricate all kinds of false information and evidence, and successively passed the online My personal reputation was defamed in various ways, both online and offline, with the intention of blackmailing and extorting property, and posing a threat to my personal safety. In late June, I took the initiative to report to the leadership of the Shanxi Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Explain the relevant circumstances of the incident.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qiang emphasized in the statement that Lv published false information and the content was fabricated to extort and extort him, seriously damaging his personal reputation. Cause extremely bad effects and great harm. &quot;If I have any words or deeds that violate disciplines and laws, I am willing to accept the review and handling of the organization.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 12th, the staff of the Discipline Inspection Commission of Taiyuan University of Technology responded that they have paid attention to the public opinion and yesterday In the evening, several departments of the school held meetings overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 12th, staff from the Propaganda Department of the Shanxi Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision stated that they were understanding the relevant situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of press time, the reporter contacted Zheng Qiang himself many times, but no calls were answered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Qiang’s resume&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Qiang, male, Han nationality, from Wuyishan, Fujian, born in September 1960, member of the Communist Party of China , Ph.D., professor, doctoral supervisor. Distinguished professor of the &quot;Changjiang Scholars Award Program&quot; of the Ministry of Education, winner of the National Science Fund for Distinguished Young Scholars, national candidate for the &quot;New Century Talents Project&quot;, expert enjoying special government subsidies, director of the Key Laboratory of Polymer Synthesis and Functional Structure of the Ministry of Education . He is currently the Secretary of the Taiyuan University of Technology Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1978 to 1982, he studied at Zhejiang University for his undergraduate degree (Bachelor of Science); from 1985 to 1988, he studied for a master&#39;s degree (Master of Engineering) at Chengdu University of Science and Technology (now Sichuan University); from 1990 to 1992, he studied at Chengdu University of Science and Technology (now Sichuan University). Studied for a doctoral degree at Chengdu University of Science and Technology (now Sichuan University). From October 1992 to October 1994, China and Japan jointly trained doctoral students to study at Kyoto University in Japan. In December 1994, he received a doctorate in engineering from Sichuan United University (now Sichuan University); 1998 He was promoted to professor of Zhejiang University in 2001. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has successively served as deputy dean of the School of Materials and Chemical Engineering and director of the Department of Polymer Science and Engineering of Zhejiang University, deputy provost and executive vice dean of the Undergraduate College of Zhejiang University, and dean of Qiushi College. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From February 2009 to November 2012, he served as deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Zhejiang University. During this period: from October 2009 to October 2011, he served as vice president of Guizhou Academy of Sciences (temporary position);&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;From May 2012 to June 2017, he served as President and Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of Guizhou University;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2016, he served as Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of Zhejiang University (department level);&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020 In April 2010, he was appointed as Secretary of the Party Committee of Taiyuan University of Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[早教机构成“爆雷”高发区，千亿蛋糕怎么也不香了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258349]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/10/cfe30e52f0d700dbc5f19cc233ad4c0d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/10/cfe30e52f0d700dbc5f19cc233ad4c0d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253572&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The former &quot;early education star&quot; Mejim is now caught in the storm of store closures in many places across the country. According to media reports, many Mejim stores in many cities across the country have suddenly closed, making it difficult for parents to refund their fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, not only Magim, but also early education institutions such as Nanadazhen and Gymboree have also been in trouble recently. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Once upon a time, the early childhood education industry with a market worth hundreds of billions was very prosperous, and famous early education institutions such as Mejim were developing very rapidly. Why has the situation changed so suddenly now? What is the future of the early childhood education industry? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The high-profile &quot;100 billion market&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From the birth of a child to primary school Education in previous stages can be called early education. Based on the physical and mental development characteristics and brain development characteristics of infants and young children, providing them with scientific, rich, and appropriate information stimulation and training can develop children&#39;s physical and mental potential and promote their all-round development. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Early education can be divided into two stages: 0-3 years old, infants and young children do not go to kindergarten, but early education can already be carried out; after 3 years old, children can formally When entering kindergarten, in addition to systematic early education in schools, early education institutions outside schools also play a supplementary role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For a long time in the past, the concept of early education in China was not popular, and many parents were not aware of the function of early education. After the 1990s, with the continuous development of China&#39;s economy and the closer economic and ideological exchanges with foreign countries, foreign early childhood education concepts began to influence Chinese parents, and a number of early childhood education institutions came into being. However, the industry is still in its infancy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second decade of the new century, the early childhood education industry has truly ushered in rapid development. As Chinese people become richer, they pay more attention to their children’s education and are more willing to invest in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people born in the 1980s and 1990s have become parents. Young people are more likely to accept some new educational concepts. They pay more attention to their children&#39;s early education than their parents, believing that this is the first and most important thing for children. But it is also the &quot;starting line&quot; that has been ignored in the past. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, foreign early childhood education institutions represented by Mejim have entered our country in a large scale. The more mature and systematic operating models they represent have emerged from first- and second-tier cities. It continues to spread to third- and fourth-tier cities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Data from Zhiyan Consulting shows that since 2014, the number of investment events in the domestic early childhood education service industry has increased, and the amount of investment has increased significantly. The number of investment and financing events in 2014 was nearly 50, and it exceeded 110 in 2015. From 2015 to 2018, there were more than 90 investment and financing events every year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From 2012 to 2016, the amount of investment in the early childhood education industry has increased year by year, exceeding 4 billion yuan in 2017. In 2018, the investment amount soared to 9.644 billion Yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to &lt;/span>; research reports, the market size of my country’s early childhood education industry has increased year by year from 2016 to 2020, with the market size reaching 327.6 billion yuan and 327.6 billion yuan respectively in 2021 and 2022. 350 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although with the decline in fertility rates, the number of newborns born every year is decreasing. Because of the huge population base, the early childhood education market is still favored by the outside world &lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/f504711fea7233163eb90242fcedefc6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/f504711fea7233163eb90242fcedefc6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253570 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;From unlimited glory to the edge of thunder&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the pre-epidemic era, the early childhood education industry has been in a state of expansion: various online and offline institutions have shown their respective Supernatural powers; there are various subdivisions - English, mathematical thinking, Chinese language, children&#39;s songs, picture books, young children&#39;s animation, etc., all of which have formed specialized tracks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2018, Mejim successfully landed on the A-share market and became the “No. 1 early childhood education stock”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Meijim’s 2018 financial report shows that the company’s total revenue in 2018 was 265 million yuan, and its total profit was 60.49 million yuan; in 2019, the company’s total revenue increased by 137.35% year-on-year. %, to 630 million yuan, and the total profit increased by 302.54% to 243 million yuan; as of Q1 2019, there were 451 US Jim centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The arrival of the epidemic has had a huge impact on all offline industries, and Mejim is no exception. Mejim&#39;s total revenue in 2020 was 356 million yuan - almost halved compared to 2019. The total revenue in 2021 was 336 million yuan, and the total revenue in 2022 was 154 million yuan - only half of 2021. Revenue in the first quarter of 2023 was only 29.54 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company&#39;s operating profit is even worse. The total profit in 2020 was -531 million yuan, and the total profit in 2021 was -57.4551 million yuan. The total profit was -610 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sluggish early childhood education industry raises the risk of “explosion” because almost all early childhood education institutions are in the form of prepaid consumption, that is, the institutions sell lesson packages to parents, and a lesson package can easily cost It costs tens of thousands of yuan, and the course package covers a period ranging from a few months to a few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although in August 2018, the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Regulating the Development of Off-Campus Training Institutions&quot;, it put forward clear requirements for early childhood education and other off-campus training institutions to collect tuition fees from &lt;span>;educated persons: &quot;No A one-time charge for a time span of more than 3 months.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, it is common for early childhood education institutions to charge a one-time fee for a time span of more than 3 months, and it has even become Industry practice. When the institution is operating normally, the course package format will be more &quot;favorable&quot;; once the institution becomes unsustainable and the offline institution closes, parents will have no place to take the remaining courses they purchased and would like&lt;/span>; a refund. But it is also difficult to get a refund, which is like a &quot;thunder&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is true that the epidemic is an important reason for the difficulties encountered by many early childhood education institutions. In fact, the crisis of many early childhood education institutions has already been laid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, blind expansion leads to a sharp increase in costs. Early childhood education institutions are mostly offline education. They are usually rented in bustling shopping malls, with an average area of ​​about 200 square meters. The monthly rent and labor costs are very high, and the monthly operating costs can easily reach tens of thousands of yuan. If customer renewal and new acquisition are not ideal, you will lose money. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the pre-epidemic era, many early childhood education institutions were eager for quick success and expansion too fast, and had already shown signs of operational difficulties. The impact of the epidemic has completely erupted the crisis. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Secondly, due to the rapid development of the early childhood education industry in the past few years, many people want to get a piece of the pie and have opened early childhood education institutions. Due to the lack of standards and insufficient teachers in the early childhood education industry, many practitioners do not even have kindergarten teacher qualification certificates and can directly take up their posts after simple training. This has also resulted in the overall level of the early childhood education industry being low, and many parents have lost trust in early childhood education institutions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Under the impact of the epidemic, many parents found that their children actually grew very well without attending early childhood education classes. They couldn’t help but reflect on whether the early childhood education classes they enrolled in before were paying attention.&lt;/span>; IQ tax. Nowadays, many parents will search for relevant information on social media when registering for classes. Once there are more voices of &quot;distrust&quot; of early childhood education institutions, parents&#39; willingness to register for classes will decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, although the epidemic is over, early childhood education institutions have not &lt;span>; experienced the rapid recovery expected. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Standardized development will have a future&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Early childhood education is still a market worth hundreds of billions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although the fertility rate has declined, Chinese parents currently attach great importance to their children’s education; under the “double reduction” policy, the early childhood education industry has not been greatly affected, but instead the discipline The weakening of training has made many parents more willing to invest in their children in aspects such as painting and physical fitness, and these are areas that early childhood education has always been involved in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The early childhood education industry is now facing difficulties, which is an opportunity for the industry to take a break. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, in the pre-epidemic era, although the early childhood education industry developed rapidly, it was generally in a state of barbaric growth: there were no standards and a lack of regulations. &lt;span>;For example, my country&#39;s nurseries and kindergartens adopt a &quot;dual-track system&quot; model. Childcare services for infants aged 0-3 years old are separated from care and education for children aged 3-6 years old. The former is managed by the Health Commission and the latter is managed by the education department. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In terms of curriculum connection, our country currently has clearer educational suggestions for the learning and development goals and child care work of children aged 3 to 6 years old. Relatively speaking, children aged 0 to 3 years old There is a lack of educational advice for infants and young children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This gives many early childhood education institutions room to fish in troubled waters. Although parents spend a lot of money to send their children to institutions, there is actually no way to judge whether the courses are reasonable and whether the teachers are qualified. I don&#39;t know if it has any effect. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as this &quot;fuzzy&quot; space exists and the standards of excellence and inferiority are not clear, it will be difficult to establish the rules of survival of the fittest. To establish industry norms, not only early childhood education institutions need self-discipline, but also relevant departments such as education need to gather industry experts and issue relevant standards so that early childhood education has rules to follow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, regarding the current prepaid consumption problem that is common in early childhood education institutions, it is necessary to effectively strengthen the supervision of funds to prevent early childhood education institutions from misappropriating funds, which in turn triggers the risk of thunderstorms. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Early childhood education institutions should be more cautious when expanding and not misappropriate consumers&#39; money to do risky things. Only when funds are safer, the industry is more orderly, and parents&#39; trust is established, can the early childhood education industry truly develop in the long run. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《大宅门》导演郭宝昌去世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258485]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-12 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On October 11, 2023, Guo Baochang died in Beijing at the age of 83. He lost his father when he was young, was sold into a mansion by his biological mother, went through labor reform, directed more than 30 film and television dramas, and once mentored Zhang Yimou... Throughout his life, he has tasted the warmth and ups and downs of human relationships, experienced the ups and downs of the world, and learned to survive carefully in the cracks. No loss of heroism and courage. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>