<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com<item><title><![CDATA[安徽芜湖一医院超收患者21万余元医疗费，省医保局通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261764]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 14:37:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Notice on the illegal use of medical insurance funds by Wuhu Second People’s Hospital&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;On July 18, 2023, our bureau received a petition report from Yang Moumou, which reflected that Wuhu Second People’s Hospital illegally and illegally used fictitious and exchanging diagnostic and treatment services while his father was hospitalized for cerebral hemorrhage. Medical insurance fund. Our bureau attaches great importance to it. Based on the data screening and analysis, on August 8, a provincial and municipal joint inspection team of more than 20 people was formed with the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau to station in the hospital to conduct an investigation on the hospital charges and medical insurance reimbursements during the hospitalization of the reporter’s father. Conduct a comprehensive verification. Through medical record verification, on-site questioning and data comparison, it was verified that 10 of the 15 issues involved in the report were basically true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, the hospital had problems such as over-diagnosis and treatment, over-examination, over-prescribing of medicines, repeated charges, fraudulent charges, and excessive charges, involving illegal medical expenses of 218,200 yuan, including illegal use of medical insurance funds. 187,000 yuan. In order to maintain the safety of the medical insurance fund and protect the legitimate rights and interests of patients, according to the medical insurance service agreement for designated medical institutions signed between the hospital and the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Department, the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau first handled the matter in accordance with the agreement: First, the medical insurance fund used in violation of regulations was recovered in full , and a penalty of 56,074.41 yuan was deducted at the maximum rate of 30%; the second was to interview the relevant person in charge of the hospital and order him to make immediate rectifications; the third was to hand it over to the public security and health departments for further verification and processing. At present, all the above treatment measures have been completed. At the same time, the Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau has initiated administrative penalty procedures in accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Supervision and Management of the Use of Medical Security Funds&quot;. While verifying the reported issues, the provincial and municipal joint inspection teams drew inferences from one example and conducted a comprehensive and extended inspection of the hospital&#39;s use of medical insurance funds from April 1, 2022 to May 31, 2023. Further verification is currently underway, and follow-up will be based on The procedures will be handled seriously in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 25, Wuhu Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau, in accordance with the &quot;Implementation Rules for Handling Reporting Clues in the Supervision and Management of Anhui Medical Security Fund (Trial)&quot;, gave written feedback on the verification and handling to the whistleblower in the form of a supervision notice. . In accordance with the &quot;Measures for Reporting Rewards for Illegal Use of Medical Security Funds in Anhui Province&quot;, the whistleblower was given a reporting reward of RMB 5,364.04. We welcome all sectors of society to supervise the use of medical insurance funds in designated medical institutions. We will deal with the verified problems seriously and will never tolerate them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;Anhui Provincial Medical Security Bureau&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;December 2, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[朱丹为闺蜜担保背负巨债：友谊塑料，情比金坚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261762]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Being let down, betrayed, and deceived by friends can have many endings - such as &quot;stabbing in the back&quot;, such as when I Nearly 30 years ago, I lent a large sum of money to my best friend, but it was never repaid. This money was supposed to be used to prepare me for big things. But there are very few people who are as miserable as Zhu Dan and have no friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Zhu Dan revealed when participating in a program that he was defrauded of all his savings by a friend many years ago. She was deceived by her friend into being a debt guarantor and wrote her name on a blank piece of paper. As a result, she was forced to use all her savings to pay off all her friend&#39;s debts. Even if he won the lawsuit, the matter would end in Zhu Dan&#39;s misfortune because his shameless friend declared &quot;bankruptcy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How much this money is, many people are concerned about this issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the parties did not disclose specific figures, it is impossible to confirm. But this is not important, because we only need to know that this amount of money is beyond the imagination of ordinary people. The important thing is that this incident happened while Zhu Dan and Yiwei Yiwei were in love, but Yiwei Yi chose to repay the debt with Zhu Dan. In the program, when Zhu Dan recounted this unbearable event in a calm tone with red eyes under the wind chimes, Yiwei Yiwei looked at her with a distressed and forgiving look, as if he were facing a child who had been wronged. This scene It’s very emotional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe that many people have met people who do things without thinking, otherwise there would be so many &quot;easy to deceive people&quot; in the world. How stupid is Zhu Dan&#39;s hasty behavior? As one netizen said, your behavior as a human being should not be too outrageous, and you must have a basic bottom line. Zhu Dan&#39;s best friend sent her a piece of white paper, and she dared to sign it. It was difficult for a middle school student to do this. Even the judge couldn&#39;t help &quot;teaching&quot; Zhu Dan that he was legally illiterate. As long as he signed on the white paper, It is equivalent to admitting everything on this piece of paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This netizen said that he does not have such a wife, but he has such a mother. These words also touched the sensitive parts of many people&#39;s hearts. I have relatives and friends who are like this. They don&#39;t listen to anything they say, and they only wake up after being deceived. However, it doesn&#39;t take long for them to fall into new routines again. As the saying goes, &quot;Dangdang is different&quot;, some people just can&#39;t get out of this tragic scam &quot;reincarnation&quot;. What can you do? Anyway, I heard that in addition to some parents &quot;paying the bill&quot; for their deceived children, there are many examples of couples breaking up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I very much agree with what this netizen said: Yiwei Yi helped her pay off the debt. This behavior cannot be described as high-spirited and upright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, Yiwei Yi seems to be indifferent to Zhu Dan, which is one of the reasons why some &quot;black fans&quot; have been criticizing Yiwei. Not only do they feel that Yiwei is not good to Zhu Dan, but they also habitually show off in public places. The &quot;poker-faced&quot; Zhou Yiwei got a lot of insults on his head. There are even rumors that the two are getting married. But now, many netizens woke up from the misunderstanding and discovered that Yiwei Yiwei is so good - &quot;I apologize for talking about Yiwei before. If he can avoid divorce after such a thing, I respect him as a real man.&quot; &quot;We endure hardships and enjoy happiness together.&quot; &quot;There are not many people who can repay debts together. And it&#39;s a man, even less.&quot; &quot;I thought he was quite shrewd, and it seemed like he was in love. I thought this kind of thing could only be done by parents to their children.&quot; &quot;Come out&quot; &quot;Yiwei Zhou is a relatively aloof but loyal type&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You know, at that time Yiwei could have broken up with Zhu Dan without having to sacrifice himself. Even if the two are already married, Yiwei Yi has every reason to ignore the &quot;bad debt&quot;. After all, even according to the marriage law, it is not his responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Dan was tricked by his friends, which is a typical example of being defrauded. According to legal principles, whether you have an obligation to repay debts caused by being defrauded depends on whether the debts are used jointly by the husband and wife. Unless there is evidence to prove that the debt belongs to the couple&#39;s common living use, the other party has no obligation and responsibility to repay it. Obviously, the occurrence of Zhu Dan&#39;s debt had nothing to do with Zhou Wei, nor was it the result of a joint discussion between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s ridiculous is that one netizen even commented that Zhou Yiwei actually used this matter to manipulate Zhu Dan and gain a useful slave. This is illogical. What can you do if you have tens of millions in your hand? What can you buy and eat? Do you have to give up half your life savings to someone else? Those who say this, and those who believe this, can also pay 10 million or 20 million for someone to treat you as a &quot;master&quot; and see if you are willing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is really sad to see people without knowing their surroundings. We should feel lucky to still have such a kind and loving man like Yiwei Yi in our sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is precisely because of the old saying that &quot;husband and wife are originally birds of the same forest, and they fly separately when disaster strikes&quot;, acts of friendship are particularly noble. If a couple wants to maintain a long-term relationship, it is not enough to just have an emotional foundation. In a world that is difficult and full of changes, if there is a lack of moral support and a little noble personality from both parties, it is not surprising that the couple breaks up halfway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 14:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[阿童木会流泪吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261742]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/H4PoJ90PIQJmpKm7m3yKcQmBPcEXKYYenxj2YfGt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;648&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/H4PoJ90PIQJmpKm7m3yKcQmBPcEXKYYenx j2YfGt. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260022&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recently launched animated series &quot;PLUTO&quot; by Netflix, the audience once again saw the familiar robot Astro Boy from their childhood. This animated work depicts the existential crisis of humans and robots after the Central Asian War. The information is dense, neat and compact, and its lightness is as impressive as its heaviness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hideo Kojima, the game producer and a well-known science fiction fan and animation fan, said, &quot;This work is completely different from robot animations and hero animations that can only fight. This is Japanese manga (&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Comics&lt;/span>;), this is animation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The birth of ChatGPT made mankind realize that it may be replaced in the new technological environment Species crisis, the Palestinian-Israeli conflict caused tragic casualties. In this reality, &quot;PLUTO&quot; appeared: the shadow of the post-war period shrouded the entire earth, and Persia, which had lost its country, created the giant robot Pluto and wanted to destroy him. Seven of the world&#39;s strongest robots, including Astro Boy. In the fictional story, &quot;war robot crisis&quot; replaces &quot;nuclear crisis&quot;, and &quot;robot sanctions&quot; replace &quot;nuclear sanctions&quot; in international politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1964, Japanese cartoonist Osamu Tezuka released the special &quot;Astro Boy&quot; episode &quot;The Strongest Robot on Earth&quot;. From the 1950s to the 1970s when Japanese comics were on the rise, most cartoonists of Tezuka’s generation took a left-leaning political stance because of their experience in World War II. They were anti-war, respectful of life, and advocating equality in their works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2003, with the permission of Osamu Tezuka&#39;s son, cartoonist Naoki Urasawa created &quot;PLUTO&quot; based on &quot;The Strongest Robot on Earth&quot;. &quot;PLUTO&quot;, born in 2023, is an animated series created by Netflix on this basis. From the anti-war thoughts in 1964, to the Iraq War in 2003, to the Palestinian-Israeli conflict in 2023, the three creations of &quot;PLUTO&quot; correspond to the war backgrounds of different eras. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan has long allowed the world to accept the artistic language of comics. Tokiwa-so cartoonists headed by Osamu Tezuka have redefined the depth and breadth of comics. Their depiction and exploration of emotions have made their works Crossing the boundaries of the audience. Although &quot;PLUTO&quot; takes place in the context of a grand robot war, its setting is still classical: How can a robot become more like a human? On the one hand, humans are afraid of being replaced by machines; on the other hand, they are full of discrimination against androids - humans have emotions, and robots are just inferior species. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Robot, are you really not sad? When robots cry, even they themselves are surprised. Who am I? Am I really grieving? Are these reactions emotions, or a set of codes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While watching this animation, I needed to press the pause button several times and stop for a while. Its perception and depiction of emotions are very innocent and beautiful, and sadness comes in an extremely light way. When Astro Boy is destroyed, will he be allowed to declare &quot;death&quot;? Or it can only be declared &quot;damaged and scrapped&quot;. Naoki Urasawa continues Tetsuka&#39;s exploration of &quot;the relationship between man and others&quot;, and still almost stubbornly depicts the possibility of &quot;understanding&quot; in a world full of fragmentation and disputes. For example, the robot North 2 went to the hometown of a stubborn artist to find the piano music in the artist&#39;s dream; the dinner between the robot Astro Boy and Dr. Pegasus; Ulan, who lost Astro Boy, could not face his own perception. The little robot keeps running around, trying to help sad humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I haven’t seen such an animated work for a long time. The last time it gave me such an emotional experience was the animated film &quot;Ghost in the Shell&quot;. Its English name is &quot;Ghost in the Shell&quot;. Those whispers in the machine body may be just ghosts that are difficult to define, but it happened after all, didn&#39;t it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 13:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[母亲起诉儿子返还购房款：对家庭是一个警示丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261756]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 11:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to CCTV&#39;s &quot;Today&#39;s Statement&quot; report, Yang&#39;s mother is a single mother, and her original condom was located in Dongcheng District, Beijing. The only house I have is my only son, Xiao Yang. She got 3.7 million from selling her house and transferred it to her son. She used it to buy a larger house in Tongzhou District, which she lived in and used as a wedding house for her son. Only her son&#39;s name was written on the property ownership certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2019, Xiao Yang got married, and Yang’s mother lived with Xiao Yang and his wife in the new house. Soon after the marriage, the daughter-in-law had conflicts with Yang&#39;s mother over daily trivial matters. The relationship between Xiao Yang, who firmly stands by his wife, and Yang&#39;s mother continues to deteriorate. After that, Xiao Yang and his wife moved out of their new house. Later, because his wife had another quarrel with Yang&#39;s mother, Xiao Yang became angry and blocked Yang&#39;s mother on WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, in order to solve the problem of her daughter’s schooling, Xiao Yang sent a WeChat message to her grandmother: “Sell the house in Tongzhou and let my mother use the money from her original sale to buy another house, and I will save money. Buy a house.&quot; &quot;If my mother can&#39;t agree, I will go to court to sue my mother in one month. If it really goes to court, there will be no turning back on our mother-son relationship.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Known After what her son said, Yang&#39;s mother said she was &quot;completely heartbroken&quot; and said she would be &quot;homeless&quot; if Xiao Yang sued her for obstruction. So Yang&#39;s mother sued Xiao Yang to return the purchase price of 3.7 million yuan for future pension purposes, and received the support of the court. This decision is in accordance with common law, or good customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a typical case of the conflict between the extended family orientation and the small family orientation. The current statutory legal framework talks about the individual standard and the small family standard: the division of property is based on the boundaries between individuals and small families, and small families implement the &quot;community property system&quot;; parents have raised their children to adulthood and have done their best to support them. Adult children have the obligation to support their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children who are minors must rely on their parents’ care, care and protection. Parents have custody and control over their children. When children become adults, they separate from their parents and form a nuclear family. If they get married and buy a house on their own, and do not receive support from their parents, nor do they expect to receive large amounts of property or inheritance from their parents, then the parents have not interfered with their children. A legitimate reason and effective starting point in life, children are &quot;independent&quot; from the extended family and gain the &quot;sovereignty&quot; of the small family. This is a normal intergenerational power transfer in a family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if on the one hand, the children get a large amount of support from their parents when they get married and buy a house, but on the other hand, they want to have a soft life and refuse their parents&#39; interference in their lives (whether it is &quot;suggestions&quot; or &quot;pointing fingers&quot;) Well, it’s actually the same thing), which essentially refuses parents to fulfill their “investor rights/powers”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as this case is concerned, the quarrel between the daughter-in-law and Yang&#39;s mother over &quot;daily trivial matters&quot; may have started because the daughter-in-law couldn&#39;t stand her mother-in-law&#39;s lifestyle, or she couldn&#39;t accept her mother-in-law&#39;s interference in the couple&#39;s lifestyle. The specific quarrel may have different rights and wrongs, but the underlying reason must be: the mother-in-law and daughter-in-law are fighting for the right to speak or dominate the house or the family, or one party believes that the other party has usurped his rights to the things in the house or the family. power or dominance. This is the essence of many conflicts between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are a lot of poisonous chicken soups on the Internet nowadays, such as &quot;A husband must stand for his daughter-in-law, otherwise he will be a mama&#39;s boy.&quot; This is probably because the daughter-in-law or the person who acts as the daughter-in-law by herself is online more, while the mother-in-law is less online, and the former has a higher voice. bigger. After Yang&#39;s mother paid 3.7 million yuan to provide a wedding house for the young couple, after the conflict between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law, the son did not reconcile the conflict, but blindly sided with the daughter-in-law, further intensifying the conflict, which shows that the son has nothing to do with his mother, who is an elder and investor. respect. There are many voices on the Internet who ridicule Xiao Yang for &quot;taking a wife and forgetting her mother.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, it was originally a tough and feasible plan to &quot;sell the house in Tongzhou and let my mother use the money from her original sale to buy another house while I save money to buy another house.&quot; But at the same time, Xiao Yang threatened his mother with &quot;prosecution&quot; and &quot;mother-child affection&quot;, which made her a little confused. During the court hearing, Yang&#39;s mother requested that the 3.7 million be recognized as a loan, while Xiao Yang requested that it be recognized as a gift from his mother, which seemed to contradict his promise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court ultimately determined that the money was a loan. But even if it is a gift, it is conditional and can be withdrawn. Mother Yang gave the money to her son to buy a house and only wrote his son&#39;s name on it. What she really meant was not &quot;I gave this money to you unconditionally. The house I bought will be written on your name.&quot; You can name it whatever you want.&quot; Instead, &quot;Mom, I have given all my belongings to prepare a wedding room for you. I will live with you. You have to take good care of me when I grow old. I only write your name because I hope you can compare my feelings with mine. Not only do they have the right to live, they should also be respected.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xiao Yangs not only failed to manage intergenerational conflicts and despised the rights/rights of investors, but instead took the initiative to escalate conflicts and regarded their widowed mother as an enemy. Such a move is morally wrong, and it is unfair to weigh the interests and benefits. Sensible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s okay to adhere to individual orientation + small family orientation, and at the same time insist on living independently and rejecting large-amount funding from parents; if you accept large-amount funding from parents, you must respect the rights/powers of the investor, and even You must have the awareness to be a low-key child. Of course, high-profile parents may not intervene, but in this case, not intervening is a sign of affection, not a duty. &quot;Having both&quot; doesn&#39;t work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, this case is also a warning to parents. By raising the children to adulthood, the parents&#39; duty has been completed and the legal responsibilities have been fulfilled. You cannot hand over your old capital to your children casually, and your main assets must be in your own hands. If a child needs a large amount of financial aid, it can be lent in a clear way, stipulating the principal, interest and repayment plan, or at least it should be clear that the parents have the right to claim it back. Don&#39;t let the children feel that their parents&#39; love for them is unconditional and they can take whatever they want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parent-child love must be two-way. It is sad that many parents become the tools of their children, providing money and effort, and then being picked on and stabbed by their young couples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[霞浦：摄影与旅游之间的距离]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261748]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/1TJD3qtqOhvQJaFThYraZxJdd9xdF8ml83fADU1S.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/1TJD3qtqOhvQJaFThYraZxJdd9xdF8ml8 3fADU1S. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259981&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take pictures of the sunrise at the seaside of Huazhu Village, Sansha Town, Xiapu County&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Becoming a photography resort&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When the sunset was about to dissipate, a group of foreign photographers returned At the B&amp;B on the mountain, we stood on the observation deck facing the coast and chatted. Looking down from the observation deck, there are still tourists taking pictures on the highway bridge at the foot of the mountain. Dongbi Village and Yugongting Village in Sansha Town, Xiapu County are famous for their sunset scenery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While waiting for the seafood banquet, a local member of the team introduced the owner of this B&amp;B to the photographers, Zheng Dexiong, the president of the Xiapu Photography Association, the person who famously photographed the Xiapu beach. His last introduction was: , &quot;The man who made Xiapu housing prices increase countless times.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facts are more powerful than words. An abandoned rural self-built house in Sansha Town can be sold for more than 100,000 yuan a year. Rented to B&amp;B owners, if the property rights can be traded, the price of a house can be as high as several million. And B&amp;B owners just for a piece of land, they knocked down their houses and rebuilt them, decorating them carefully. The price for a sea view room per night in the off-season is four figures. The skyrocketing housing prices have become a difficult problem for Sansha people who moved away due to lack of local industries in the early years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After greetings, Zheng Dexiong sat back on the outdoor seat on the other side of the observation deck and was busy planning the shooting schedule for another upcoming photography group. There were two more shoots arranged by the local government the next day. meeting. Everyone who comes to Xiapu for research and inspection wants to meet Zheng Dexiong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before Zheng Dexiong, no one focused on tidal flat photography, and almost no one realized that the beautiful scenery of Xiapu was rare enough to be displayed. Zheng Dexiong, who has been engaged in commercial photography since the 1990s, was convinced of the uniqueness of Xiapu scenery after seeing many photos of seaside scenery. In 2002, Zheng Dexiong began photographing the tidal flats in his hometown in his spare time. Two years later, at the suggestion of a friend, he held the first photography exhibition in Xiapu on the street of Longshou Road. He also submitted articles to many photography magazines. His works were repeatedly published and won awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kasumigaura and its tidal flats are famous in the photography circle. Xiapu was rated as &quot;the first of China&#39;s top ten landscape photography holy places&quot;. Photography bases were built in small fishing villages along the coast. Fishermen who were engaged in seafood fishing returned to the shore, and young people who went out to work returned to their hometowns and started the tourism industry from scratch. . Zheng Dexiong remembers that 20 years ago, Xiapu County had only one short street and no foreign population. But now the city has expanded all the way to the seaside, and Taikang Road filled with food stalls is busy until late at night. In 2022, Xiapu, with a population of just over 500,000, received 7.2 million tourists. A few photos changed the fate of a county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s easy to say, but it’s not that simple. Over the past 20 years, we have actually invested a lot in transforming from private power to strong government support and from free services to a business model.” Zheng Dexiong objects to easy generalizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first started photographing the tidal flats, Zheng Dexiong walked along the more than 400 kilometers of Xiapu coastline. It turned out that there were no roads on the shore and it was a barren mountain. He had to bring a machete and a hoe to open a road while walking. When shooting at Shajiang Pier, in order to find a shooting point with a suitable height, he climbed up from the bottom of the mountain. When he reached the top of the mountain, he discovered that there was a stone road built by the village on the other side. Several of Xiapu&#39;s early famous photography spots were discovered by Zheng Dexiong in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Dexiong paid for the early foreign photographers who came to Xiapu with his own money, until he could no longer afford the money. On May 1, 2007, he opened the first paid photography group. A one-week trip for 20 people cost more than 1,000 yuan per person. The local government saw the power of photography in the tourism industry and began to hold national photography competitions and create logos for photography spots. More importantly, the government has taken the lead in gradually building and improving supporting infrastructure for photography spots, including roads, parking lots, and observation decks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, new photography spots are constantly being discovered. The 2017 edition of the &quot;Xiapu Photography Guide&quot; issued by the Xiapu Culture and Tourism Bureau lists 28 photography spots, and the number has increased to 33 in the 2021 edition. The infrastructure and tourism model around the photography spots have not yet been fully finalized, and both locals and tourists are adapting to the differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/xcAgdGZJ83aXw3hloXo7guXtXzsKDTWVPvIFJqAp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/xcAgdGZJ83aXw3hloXo7guXtXzsKDTWVPvIFJqAp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259979&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiapu tidal flat scenery through Zheng Dexiong&#39;s lens&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Perfect Photo&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first people to profit from photography are the characters closely related to the shooting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Dexiong believes that shooting in Xiapu is a test of skills and experience. &quot;The ebb and flow, changes in light and shadow, the alternation of four seasons, and different labor scenes in each season.&quot; This also means that shooting in Xiapu is uncertain. There are too many factors, including weather, tides, and seasons. The absence of any one element will lead to deviation from the default. Weather and tides can be grasped by experience, while labor scenes out of season can only be reproduced through performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the winter of 2005, a Taiwanese photographer came to Xiapu to take pictures, but the whole series was missing a picture of Xiaohao Village catching fish fry in spring. Considering that it was not easy to travel from Taiwan to the mainland, Zheng Dexiong asked local fishermen to cooperate in posing for photos. This is how the new profession of fishing model was born in Xiapu. To this day, even if no one buys fish fry anymore, the fishing models in Xiaohao Village still hold up a triangular fishing net frame every time they perform - this kind of special-shaped net is specially used to catch fish fry, and because of the award-winning photo shoot There are three fishing models, so the trio is also fixed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Three people make a good photo.” Every time they perform, Bao Xuexian, who is in her fifties, her aunt in her seventies, and her aunt’s brother-in-law will put on knee-length rubber shoes, wearing Put on your straw hat, carry your fishing net and bamboo basket, and walk on the Xiaohao beach after low tide. The photographer would stand on the top of the mountain behind the village and shoot with a telephoto lens from a distance. Bao Xuexian&#39;s uncle Lin Jisong was responsible for reception on the mountain and conveyed the photographer&#39;s instructions to Bao Xuexian and others via radio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The performance fee for a performance is 300 yuan, and the fishing model costs 100 yuan per person. More than half of the days a month, people will be invited to perform, but Bao Xuexian does not think that fishing models are an enviable job. &quot;Only those who can&#39;t make money become fishing models, and those who can make money go to cultivate oysters and grow seaweed.&quot; &quot;When there are no performances, Bao Xuexian and her aunt weave fishing nets and sell them for money. A two-layered large fishing net sells for 31 yuan, and a three-layered one sells for 42 yuan. They can weave up to two per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Jisong receives guests at the top of the mountain, but does not participate in the distribution of performance fees. He has other income. Most of the people in Xiaohao Village were originally fishermen. Lin Jisong did not know how to fish. 24 years ago, he built a temple on the top of the mountain and made a living by collecting incense money. When fishermen go to sea, life and death are determined by fate, and they will worship gods before leaving. After the Xiaohao Tidal Flat became famous, the government built an observation deck on the top of the mountain, right next to the temple built by Lin Jisong. He felt that the angle of the path on the cliffside was better, so he paved a stone road and placed a few plastic stools. Anyone who goes to take pictures on the stone road must &quot;donate&quot; 10 yuan for the film fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Famous photography spots have regular fishing models, such as Jiang Lianshui in Beiqi Tidal Flat and Lao Cheng in Yangjiaxi. They have taken award-winning photos together and know better than novice photographers about how to take photos. &quot;They all know the angle, focal length, aperture, and speed.&quot; Zheng Dexiong found it very interesting. &quot;Initially, we went to the village to select models. There were no special criteria. They just had to be fishermen.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the government building In front of the roads and observation decks, outsiders who come to take pictures of Xiapu have to find local photographers who know their way around. Photography directors came into being, referred to as photography directors. With supporting facilities in place, photography guides are still needed because outsiders can’t figure out the tide schedule and the best time to take photos at photography spots. Nowadays, the threshold for photography guides is much lower. Not only members of the local photography association, but also taxi drivers, travel agencies and villagers have joined in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early years, Zheng Dexiong also proposed to the Culture and Tourism Bureau to provide centralized training for people engaged in photography and photography to improve their service awareness and photography skills. Later, there were too many people and it was difficult to coordinate. When he was out shooting, Zheng Dexiong heard the cameraman introducing him to the tourists. They stood face to face and neither could recognize the other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/GTBvngW7gqrVPIMUmksJuIhHm4SEcIpFR8OCw4jE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/GTBvngW7gqrVPIMUmksJuIhHm4SEcIpFR8OCw4jE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259980&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists vacation at a B&amp;B in Dongbi Village, Sansha Town, Xiapu County&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;Advantage Judgment&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the minds of photographers, different photography spots have different ratings. Zheng Dexiong believes that although Xiaohao Village has the most award-winning films, the scenery does not change much and is the same regardless of the season; Huazhu Village only has sunrise, and the location is best only in winter, which is relatively monotonous; Beiqi Village can be photographed in any season. However, the pole frames for planting seaweed have been moved from the coast to the edge of the inland sea, and the beauty of the tidal flat patterns and pole shadows can no longer be photographed. The coast of his hometown, Dakyo Village, is more suitable for tourism than photography, because there are only beaches in that area and no tidal flats, and tidal flats are the core of Kasumigaura photography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What Zheng Dexiong likes most is the east wall. The scenery changes endlessly throughout the year. In 2019, Sansha Town invested 20 million to build a light and shadow plank road to connect the photography spots along the east wall, making this area more popular. When the tide goes out a few days after the first and fifteenth day of the lunar month, more people come to the road. I can&#39;t even stand on either side. The highway bridge where the Dongbi Photography Spot is located is on one side of Dongbi Village and on the other side is Yugongting Village. The two villages have become a gathering place for boutique B&amp;Bs. Zheng Dexiong and his students all stay here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter what the photographer thinks, the villagers have their own way of judging their own advantages. Uncle Zhang, the owner of Huazhu in the countryside of Huazhu Village, was originally doing business abroad. In 2020, he returned to the village to run a B&amp;B. He saw the potential of Huazhu. “Huazhu is a scenic spot for watching the sunrise. It is a must-go spot for anyone who comes to Xiapu. You must watch the sunrise. , you will most likely have to stay the night before.&quot; Uncle Zhang currently has 6 rooms, and the price per night is 400 to 600 yuan. According to his statistics, the occupancy rate is about 80%, and it is fully booked almost every day in the peak season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another characteristic of Huazhu is that it is the Hokkien-speaking area of ​​this small town in eastern Fujian. Uncle Zhang talked about the history of Huazhu, starting from three hundred years ago, &quot;Our ancestors were Those who moved from southern Fujian didn’t have big boats before. Fishermen fished along the coast and came all the way along the coast. Maybe they came here to escape the wind and rain. Later, they saw the abundant seafood here and settled down.” Huazhu Village speaks Hokkien and lives in stone houses. , pronounced &quot;厝&quot; in Hokkien. When building the B&amp;B, the village committee required that the exterior appearance must retain the appearance of a house. Uncle Zhang plans to do a crowdfunding project to raise 8 million yuan to build 8 more B&amp;Bs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/UOC1TGi6Zn3AvbzELnYAgfV5g5HwSETROd1qh1iY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/UOC1TGi6Zn3AvbzELnYAgfV5g5HwSETROd1qh1iY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259978&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bao Xuexian’s aunt is in her seventies. When she is not performing, she makes money by weaving fishing nets&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Nie Yang Xin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the light and shadow plank road was built on the east wall, Niulangang Natural Village was gradually lost, but they were not willing to lag behind. Niulangang Village is the opening point of Xiapu’s first boutique B&amp;B CaoMuRen Teahouse. It has always regarded itself as the birthplace of Xiapu B&amp;B and is close to the county seat and the entrance to the highway. The introduction reads: “It is surrounded by mountains and sea, with beautiful scenery and convenient transportation. The location advantage is obvious and the tourism resources are unique.&quot; In the summer of 2023, Niulangang Village began construction to build an asphalt road and a viewing platform on the mountain where B&amp;Bs gather, hoping to regain the limelight as the first choice for tourists in the off-season. However, the construction team still started work during the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day, which caused several negative reviews for surrounding B&amp;Bs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sightseeing route from Gaoluo Beach, Dajing Beach to Hawei Island is named Donghai Route 1. Although there are few photographers, it is the route recommended by everyone in Xiapu. According to the observation of Xiaona, a stall owner on Xiawei Island, the sea caves on Xiawei Island are the internet celebrity photo spots that occupy the high traffic volume of social platforms. Since being photographed by an Internet celebrity at the end of 2021, it has attracted countless tourists. &quot;On May Day, one kilometer of road can be blocked for several hours.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Na and the young people in the stall area They originally worked in the county or around Ningde City. After their hometown became a tourist attraction in the past two years, they came back to set up stalls. &quot;No matter how much or how little you earn, at least you have more freedom.&quot; Xiaona&#39;s husband also came back to work as a photo guide, using his home An idle small off-road vehicle will charge 150 yuan to pick up passengers from Xiawei Island to another nearby scenic spot, the lighthouse; if it is a chartered vehicle, the price per day is 600 yuan, and you can choose Donghai Line 1 or Sansha Dongbi Line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It only takes two days to visit all the popular photography spots in Kasumigaura, and most tour groups’ itineraries are customized within two or three days. Xiaona has heard from many tourists that a three-day and two-night tour that includes transportation, food, and accommodation only costs more than a thousand yuan. “But the tour group doesn’t care about the weather and tides, and skips some spots if you can’t see them. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ttxFP6MudBOg1At6KJCYvZuBEW5ytgpsqAZwwxwM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/ttxFP6MudBOg1At6KJCYvZuBEW5ytgpsqAZwwxwM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259977&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the planning of Huazhu Village, the appearance of the B&amp;B should retain the unique stone house style of southern Fujian&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Nie Yang Xin/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Uneven&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The most common thing Ou Shao of Beiqi Village hears from tourists is, &quot;Why is it different here from the photos?&quot; &quot;So when he sees tourists now, he will explain in advance, &quot;Be sure to pay attention to the weather when visiting Xiapu. The weather is good or bad, and taking photos is completely different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zheng Dexiong&#39;s view, photography spots and tourist spots themselves It’s just different. “Some tourists come to the photography spot and feel that there is nothing to see, because photography has requirements on time and light.” The aesthetic perspectives of photographers and tourists are also different. The photographer was on the highway bridge on the east wall. There are three types of landscapes you can take pictures of - the grand landscape of the sunset, the seaweed net on the lake and the lines of the tidal flats under the bridge, but tourists generally only look at the sunset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ye Yu, who sells coffee under the observation deck of Huazhu Village, remembers that no one in the village cared about the sunrise before. When fishermen go out to catch fish, they go out at high tide and return at high tide. They look at the tide table, which has nothing to do with sunrise and sunset. On New Year&#39;s Day in 2013, CCTV broadcast the sunrise live in Huazhu, which earned Huazhu the title of &quot;China&#39;s Sun Viewing Landmark.&quot; The sunrise footage captured by CCTV was posted on the wall under the observation deck, and a stone tablet was erected next to it: &quot; How blessed to be in the same time and space as this sunrise.&quot; Ye Yu remembered that the CCTV sunrise was filmed by the staff who set up tents on the top of the mountain and lived there for a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beiqi Village was probably the first place to realize the different needs of tourism and photography. The Ou Shao family opened a B&amp;B in the village in 2013, and began taking tourists out to sea for sightseeing and fishing entertainment in 2020. So far, it has developed nearly ten projects, including tourist charters, fishing outings, parent-child trips to the sea, sales of dried seafood, and cage nets. &quot;The passenger flow here is unstable, so we can only develop more.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Shao&#39;s family used to be fishermen, and their income from fishing was unstable. &quot;There are not so many fish now, and every May The fishing season is closed from the 1st to August 31st, and large boats can park on the shore.&quot; They considered daily fishing and tourism during the fishing season, and found that it was not cost-effective to only do it for three months. &quot;Do it all year round. If you do this, you will accumulate many old customers.&quot; So they concentrated on the tourism industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Shao’s father now goes out to sea to fish, always accompanying guests on a chartered boat. The price of chartering a boat is 600 yuan, and the catch is uncertain. “It’s okay to catch more or less. Some tourists are Those who have come from the inland have never seen the sea and find it very fresh.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More tourists choose to spend 30 yuan to take a 20-minute boat ride to see the seaweed that has been planted on the edge of the inland sea. The Ou Shao family built a new boat in May 2023, costing 50,000 to 60,000 yuan. The cabin area was specially enlarged to accommodate up to 30 people. There are several families involved in the boat tour project in the village, including Ou Shao&#39;s relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ou Shao was soliciting tourists at the beach, an electric bicycle rode on the village road and he also talked to the tourists on the roadside. I asked Ou Shao, &quot;Is that your relative or a competitor?&quot; Ou Shao replied: &quot;It&#39;s my relative and a competitor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two of them stood guard in front of the entrance of the seaside parking lot, taking turns. Go up and ask the private car coming in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nRn68R4EnzQITldKMsR5Tb86hebJFP3gNZzks7Wm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nRn68R4EnzQITldKMsR5Tb86hebJFP3gNZzks7Wm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Uncle Zhang is making fire hoses for a B&amp;B by hand. He believes that returning to his hometown to build a B&amp;B is a feeling for his hometown&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Characters Weekly reporter Nie Yangxin/photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Under construction&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not all famous photography spots can catch up with the tourism boom. Xiaohao Beach is the earliest famous, but the surrounding areas The supporting facilities and B&amp;B design are lagging behind those of Dongbi and Huazhu on the same line. The B&amp;Bs in Xiaohao Village are concentrated in the new area on the edge of the old village. A large open space from the new area to the seaside is filled with sand, gravel, soil, fishing nets, construction waste and domestic garbage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The B&amp;Bs in Xiaohao Village are mainly self-built houses in rural areas. Villagers rent and sell spare rooms in their own houses. The decoration style of the rooms is basically the bedrooms of ordinary commercial houses. In order to reduce the difficulty of cleaning, a pile of public slippers are placed at the door of each B&amp;B for guests to change into. Such a room costs 300 yuan a night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Muhai B&amp;B is one of the few boutique B&amp;Bs currently in operation. It has floor-to-ceiling glass windows facing the sea and a small outdoor garden. The proprietress Wu Sister-in-law said that the design fee for the B&amp;B cost 60,000 yuan. . Sister-in-law Wu’s husband is a village cadre. When the houses in the new district first started to be decorated in 2018, he suggested that the villagers decorate them in the style of a B&amp;B, but the villagers were unwilling. Sister-in-law Wu said, “Someone asked at that time, and I bought it after all the hard work. If you decorate a house yourself and enjoy it, why should you let others live in it? By the time they want to think about a B&amp;B again, it will be too late.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sister-in-law Wu&#39;s B&amp;B will open in 2021, and only 5 of the two floors have been repaired. In the peak season, the price of a suite and bathtub room is as high as thousands of yuan per night, but in the off-season, there are almost no guests. She believes that the supporting facilities around Xiaohao Village have affected the development of B&amp;Bs. “There used to be a parking lot that could park 70 cars, and the roads were beautifully built, but it was demolished in 2021 and has not been built yet.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2021, Xiaohao Village has been caught in a storm of accountability for illegal land occupation and illegal construction in rural areas. After investigation and verification by relevant departments, Xiaohao Village actually built 121 homesteads, of which 61 were built by non-village personnel. It also introduced commercial health care projects and occupied 16 homesteads. In March 2022, information released by relevant departments at higher levels stated that &quot;all illegally sold collective land has been taken back to the village collective, and the land will be restored to its original state after demolition.&quot; The villagers also don&#39;t know what will happen to this empty land filled with waste. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Natural conditions also restrict the development of some photography spots. Although the Xiawei Island Sea Cave is popular, it can only be revealed after low tide. Tourists who want to take pictures have to climb down the seaside rocks with bare hands. A warm reminder in the &quot;Xiapu Photography Guide&quot;, &quot;The reefs on the shore are easily slippery due to corrosion by sea water. It is recommended to wear non-slip shoes and walk slowly. Elderly people with limited mobility should not go there.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sea caves are equipped with The rescue workers said, &quot;Every day, tourists slip off the rocks and fall into the sea.&quot; The scenic spot originally wanted to build a wooden boardwalk, but the rocks were severely corroded and broke when nails were hammered in, so they had to give up. &quot;Do you know why the scenic spot doesn&#39;t charge admission tickets? If it does, the compensation (if something happens) will be up to the sky.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is nearly 50 kilometers from the county seat to Xiamei Island, and there is a long stretch of road in the middle. It is a gentle mountain road. In recent years, a new road has been built close to the coastline. This road is open even before it is included in the map navigation. Just like the tourism industry here, it seems that it has not yet been completed, but the reception of tourists has already begun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我和物业博弈的这一年：解决问题有多难？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261740]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The fate that every new owner cannot escape is to deal with and confront the property. This is his homework and his of practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since I took over the house and became an owner in October last year, I have started to form a front with my neighbors and compete with the property management. Today, the team has collapsed, losing ground, and the rights protection has ended in failure. It&#39;s the same as the mental process of decorating, from being full of emotions to being discouraged, and finally giving up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the house was handed over for inspection, the quality of the house was worrying and many areas needed repairs. However, the developer did not do anything and delayed to solve most of the problems. Until now, the paint surface of the corner of my second bedroom is cracked. The seam is still there intact. This is indeed the developer&#39;s problem. The property management company can only help me communicate my needs, but they belong to the same company, and the property management company has collected property fees early. I have to discuss an explanation with the property management company. It is not unfair at all to take the blame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process of fighting with the property owners, each other&#39;s tactics also changed according to the other&#39;s actions, and they continued to see each other&#39;s progress and retreat. If the housekeeper responds politely and politely, I will also communicate politely. If I am tougher, she will get angry at me. More often than not, the housekeeper will use low-grade deception, but I can&#39;t expose her directly. I have to leave a little kindness so that we can meet each other in the future and everything can be discussed. She told lies and fully accepted my needs, saying that she would urge and reflect them, but my problems would not be advanced or solved. She treats me as a fool. If she can evade something, she will do it first. Later problems will be dealt with later. The rhetoric will always be dealt with in a unified manner later. In the end, he couldn&#39;t do anything perfunctorily and ran out of patience. The housekeeper simply stopped making excuses and played the emotional card. She admitted that the developers were rogue and the property management companies were rogue. She only received a salary of a few dollars a month, so how could she have the final say? Without pretending, I was moved by her words that were completely embarrassing, and I began to accept in my heart that this was the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before I paid the property fee, I had to ask the housekeeper to get the key when I opened the door of my house. The owner of the owner group once privately suggested that I replace the lock cylinder and argue with the property management company about when to solve the problem and when to pay. . I didn&#39;t want to take an extreme approach, and I was eager to get a property certificate to install charging piles, so I had no choice but to surrender. Once the money is handed over, it becomes even more difficult to ask them to do something. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this year’s negotiations and observations, I found that one of the main job responsibilities of the property management company is to collect fees. As early as September, before the previous year&#39;s property fees were due, the housekeeper started a show of fancy reminders to pay the next year&#39;s property fees. Taking advantage of the fact that the owners were at home at night, the housekeepers divided their forces and went door to door to collect property fees. Everyone among the owners condemned this behavior of only enjoying rights without assuming obligations. A few days later, the property management company sent out a notice with bait, offering free rice and cooking oil if the property management fee was paid during this period. So, I often see the housekeeper walking in the community carrying grain and oil, and watching her retreating back, I wonder, if the execution of solving problems is so touching, why are we here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a year of fighting, my interest in fighting for the rights of my neighbors has slowly cooled down. Recently, there have been voices in the group that want to replace the property, but I no longer have such high expectations for the final result. Confrontation between property owners and property owners has become the norm. I am afraid that my property and I, as well as the domestic property management industry, still have a long, long way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is an employee of a state-owned enterprise in Hangzhou, Zhejiang)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to you Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[香港仔：太平山B面]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261712]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Take the green-painted Star Ferry from Tsim Sha Tsui. Rows of high-rise buildings slowly approach and zoom in. Behind them The Taiping Mountains are spread out like a belt, rising and falling gently in the porthole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original name of Taiping Mountain is Hard Head Mountain, also known as Xianglu Peak. It was renamed because after the surrender of the great thief Zhang Baozai during the Jiaqing period of the Qing Dynasty, the residents of Hong Kong Island thought that there would be peace from now on. In a broad sense, Taipingshan is composed of Mount Chechi, Lufeng Gorge, Gough Hill, Kwun Lung Kok and Mount Keli; in a narrow sense, it refers to Mount Chechi, the highest peak on Hong Kong Island with an altitude of 554 meters. There are two theories about what flag-pulling is: one is that Cheung Po-tsai raised the flag as a signal when he was a thief and commanded the people at the bottom of the mountain to rob merchant ships; the other is that in 1841, the British army occupied Hong Kong Island and raised the Union Jack here. Austin, who served as Colonial Secretary of Hong Kong from 1868 to 1878, named the mountain Mount Austin, and later renamed it Victoria Peak after the Queen of England (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;Victoria Peak&lt;/span>;) and is still used today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After living in Shenzhen for more than 20 years, I have traveled to Hong Kong many times and visited Victoria Peak. To be precise, it is the crowded places on the north bank of Victoria Peak such as Central, Admiralty, Causeway Bay, and The Peak. Among Hong Kong people, the Peak refers specifically to Victoria Peak, and there is no ambiguity. However, most tourists today mistake the cable car terminal and Lingxiao Pavilion area for the top of the mountain. In fact, it is called Lufeng Gorge. Even for me, it was a few months ago that I walked through the slightly deserted Austin Mountain Road and climbed to the top of the real mountain for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing on the observation deck on the top of the mountain, leaning on the railing and overlooking the sky, the north bank is surrounded by red dust and glitz; on the south bank, countless low hills seem to be eager to embrace the South China Sea... If the noise and commotion were the Taiping Mountains The A side of Taiping Mountain, then, silence and tranquility are the B side of Taiping Mountain. A green mountain magically captures a completely different contrast. Unfortunately, due to other arrangements, I had no time to get close to Nan&#39;an Fangze that day. This time, Aberdeen, Hong Kong, where I made a special trip, is located in the center of Side B of Victoria Peak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photography of Pang Mian looking at Aberdeen Deep Bay, Hong Kong&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c1ca8b8bac.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c1ca8b8bac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 260440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Overlooking Aberdeen Deep Bay, Hong Kong&amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Looking for Hong Kong Village&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;At Admiralty, transfer to the MTR South Island Line. One stop will bring you to the famous Ocean Park in Hong Kong, and then take a short shuttle bus to the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel you booked. Speaking of which, I am no stranger to Fullerton. Many years ago, I stayed at the Fullerton Hotel in Singapore on a business trip. It was a neoclassical building completed in 1928. It is as legendary as the Peace Hotel in Shanghai. I still remember that the passage on the ground floor leads directly to the Merlion, the landmark of the Lion City. The Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel where I stayed this time is located in the geometric center of the south bank of Victoria Peak. When the bus turned around and got rid of the noisy city, the transparent windows were suddenly filled with green mountains and blue and white sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Aberdeen location map courtesy Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cd1f944deb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;734&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cd1f944deb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260441 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Aberdeen location map&amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hotel faces the sea, on the left hand side, dozens of steps away, is 2021 The Ocean Park Water Park, Asia&#39;s first all-weather seaside water park, opened in 2016, has layers of recreational facilities that spread over the entire hillside like terraces. On the right, two breakwaters piled with rocks are as gray as scratches, collecting the treasures of the rich. &quot;Toys&quot; - yachts and sailing boats; and directly ahead, Ap Lei Chau, which looks like a duck swimming in water, has half its head and body buried in the sea, vividly dividing the sea area connecting Victoria Harbor and the South China Sea into There are two waterways, wide and narrow: within Ap Lei Chau, the narrower one is called Aberdeen Strait, which is used by small boats; outside, the wider one is called East Lamma Strait, which is used by large ships. Stop for a moment, and before your eyes, you can see the endless busyness of various ocean-going ships and the slow and leisurely pace of various yachts and sailing boats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;View of Ap Lei Chau from The Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel. Photography by Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/dc6241d429.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/dc6241d429.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;260442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Overlooking Ap Lei Chau from the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel. &amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The entrance to Aberdeen Country Park is on Nam Fung Road near Ocean Park. Like Hong Kong citizens, hiking in Aberdeen Country Park is one of my bucket list for this trip. Unexpectedly, after walking a few steps along Nanfeng Road, I encountered a small black and white road sign with an arrow pointing north to &quot;Wong Chuk Hang Stone Carvings 250m Meters&quot;. Soon, on the north side of the Jockey Club Science Building, behind a stack of easily overlooked cement steps and next to a rushing stream, I saw the Wong Chuk Hang rock carvings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a relic dating back about 3,500 years. A yellow mountain cliff stands on the right bank of the creek. Although it has been weathered and eroded, three groups of slightly blurred swirling patterns on the six or seven square meters of rock surface still look like the eyes of an animal staring at me as I &quot;break in&quot;. This reminds me of the similar Shang and Zhou bronzes &lt;span>;Taotie pattern&lt;/span>;. Taotie is a vicious and greedy monster in ancient Chinese mythology. &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; believes: &quot;Greed for money is gluttony, gluttony is gluttony.&quot; In modern times, with the rise of peace, its meaning has become a description of a foodie who is fond of delicious food. As for the Taotie pattern, it first appeared on the pottery and jade of the Liangzhu Culture in the lower reaches of the Yangtze River. Because the patterns often have heads but no bodies, they are also called &quot;animal face patterns.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perusing the on-site cultural relics plaque, I learned that there are nine ancient stone carvings in Hong Kong. Only two existing ones on the south coast of Hong Kong Island are Tai Long Bay and Wong Chuk Hang. Among them, the Tai Long Wan Stone Carvings were the first to be listed as a statutory monument (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978&lt;/span>;), while the Wong Chuk Hang Stone Carvings are the only ones located inland. , stone carvings far away from the coast. So, why is the stone at this moment? According to my judgment, if the stream under my feet has flowed forever, this is probably the place where ancestors worshiped water sources and drew fresh water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where there is fresh water, there must be villages. When I turned back along the original road, I noticed that the stream took advantage of the grass and rocks to penetrate into the underground culvert of Nanfeng Road and disappeared without a trace. Fortunately, there is a blue sign reading &quot;Old Walled Village&quot; erected at the opposite intersection, eye-catchingly pointing to the Nanfeng Trail branching off from Nanfeng Road. &quot;Wei&quot; is a common name for villages in Lingnan in the past. It not only means &quot;gathering people here&quot;, but also has an &quot;image summary&quot; of the walls and houses built in the village. Jiuwei and Laowei are equivalent to the old villages and old villages in the north, and refer to the villages with the longest history in the area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The full name of Jiu Wai Village is Wong Chuk Hang Jiu Wai, because of the ravine with flowing water in the former village (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; span>;) is named after the broom-shaped yellow bamboos that grow all over the place. However, according to Ye Lingfeng&#39;s book &quot;Hong Kong Stories&quot;, Jiuwei Village was first called Hong Kong Village or Hong Kong Wai. It is recorded in ancient books such as &quot;Yue Da Ji·Guangdong Coastal Map&quot; by Wanli in the Ming Dynasty and &quot;Xin&#39;an County Chronicle&quot; by Kangxi in the Qing Dynasty. At that time, the production and sales of Wanxiang (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;referring to the agarwood produced in Dongguan, Shenzhen, Hong Kong and other areas today) were booming, and this area became prosperous. As the initial distribution center. As late as 1866, the &quot;Comprehensive Map of Xin&#39;an County&quot; printed in Leipzig, Germany still marked the name of the village &quot;Hong Kong Wai&quot;. The name of Hong Kong today &quot;was gradually popularized based on the name of this small village.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The south wind path is not long, and the old walled village is huddled on the steep slope at the end. The lower slope is filled with vehicles; the upper slope is incredibly covered with squatter houses made of iron sheets. Entering the village and walking around, except for a small Buddhist hall and a small mountain shrine that were dimly lit by incense, I didn&#39;t find any ancient meaning. I asked the grandmother who tended the vegetable garden and learned that many years ago, the Aberdeen Tunnel Toll Station and Wong Chuk Hang Hospital were built, and the old houses were demolished. While I was talking, suddenly, four or five big yellow dogs came close to me and barked at me. When I was young, my experience in fighting dogs in the countryside came in handy. I forced myself to stay calm and made steady progress. At this time, I saw a bamboo pavilion and a nest of slender bamboos at the entrance of the village, which perfectly echoed the name of the village in Wong Chuk Hang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The swimming pool of the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel faces the East Lamma Strait. Photo courtesy of Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/12/02/d712e53ef0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/ d712e53ef0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;The swimming pool of the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel faces the East Lamma Strait. &amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Hiking in Aberdeen&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Returning to Nanfeng Road, after hiking for several miles, I plunged into the Aberdeen Country Park embrace. As you walk higher and farther, your body and mind rise and fall with the mountains, as if you are immersed in the fragrance of the forest and the occasional singing of birds. Aberdeen Country Park is one of the first country parks in Hong Kong. It was established in 1977 and covers an area of ​​about 423 hectares. It encompasses the Nip Ko Sun, Cameron Highlands, Ban Na and Tin Wan mountains from east to west. The hiking trails in between are connected with those elsewhere, and can reach the entire Hong Kong Island. At the end of the 19th century, the old houses in Jiuwei Village were still there, and the surrounding fields and grassy fields attracted visitors from Victoria City (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;today’s Central and Sheung Wan, Hong Kong High-ranking officials, wealthy businessmen, gentlemen and ladies from the area (&lt;/span>;) came in droves to spend time. The more people walking, the more roads there are in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climbing to the mountainside, a water diversion channel (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Aqueduct&lt;/span>;), which is more than 1 meter wide and deep, is clearly visible. Eyes, U-shaped bottom trickling gurgling. As we all know, fresh water in Hong Kong is poor, especially on Hong Kong Island. In order to alleviate the tension, in the 1960s, Guangdong Province successively built the Shenzhen Reservoir and the Dongjiang-Shenzhen Water Supply Project to provide support. The Hong Kong government excavated diversion channels and other facilities in the mountains to collect spring water and rainwater, and then directed them into reservoirs (&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That is, the reservoir&lt;/span>;). Today, aqueducts and reservoirs have become &quot;standard features&quot; in almost all country parks in Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/3ead0c739e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/3ead0c739e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Lady King&#39;s Horse Racing Trail offers a bird&#39;s eye view of the center of Aberdeen. &amp;nbsp; Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the water diversion channel turned around and rushed down the pit, at the feet, the road surface of Mrs. Jin’s Horse Racing Trail changed from gravel to loess. Mrs. King&#39;s Horse Racing Trail, also known as Mrs. Gold&#39;s Trail, is named after the wife of the 17th Hong Kong Governor Clementi Clementi. It is about 5 kilometers in length, and some sections overlap with the famous Hong Kong Island Trail. Mrs. King&#39;s name was Mary Ayers. She was born in 1889 and later moved to Hong Kong with her father, Admiral C.J. Ayers. In 1912, she married Clementi, who was 14 years older than her. The two were deeply in love as a couple and loved traveling and Chinese culture. Clementi was even promoted to Governor of Hong Kong in 1925 because of this. During his tenure, Clementi worked hard to eliminate the negative impact of the general strike in the province and Hong Kong on Hong Kong, improve relations with the mainland, and promote Chinese education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under his initiative, the University of Hong Kong established a Chinese Department in 1927 and invited a group of former Qing Dynasty officials to teach old classics. Unexpectedly, this move aroused verbal and written criticism from figures in the New Culture Movement such as Lu Xun and Hu Shi. What is right and what is wrong has changed with time. However, it is also an indisputable fact that the Department of Chinese Language and Literature of the University of Hong Kong set off a trend of attaching importance to Chinese education, and later emerged famous literary figures such as Zhang Ailing, Huang Zhan, and Lin Xi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to official duties, Clementi often accompanied his wife on horseback riding outings here to appreciate the mountains and seas of Aberdeen. Writer Liu Kexiang pointed out in &quot;Three Quarters of Hong Kong&quot; that in winter, there are six to seven hundred &quot;mountain eagles&quot; in the Aberdeen Country Park area. &lt;/span>;) favored urban green fields&quot;. Maybe I came a little early in the season and only saw a few flying birds. But the Clementi couple should have seen the scene of the eagle circling and covering the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hiking in Nanlang Mountain, photo provided by Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/27c1665f22.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/27c1665f22.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 260445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Hiking in Nanlang Mountain&amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Dan Family and Seafood Fang&lt;/strong>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;At this moment, at 4 o&#39;clock in the afternoon, I arrived at the Buchang Bay Pier and was immediately surrounded by ships on the sea and shipyards on the shore. At this time, the sun jumped down from Yuguishan, the main peak of Ap Lei Island on the opposite side, catching red, blue, green and white reflections to fight. In a daze, I was placed in the background of a certain Hong Kong movie, which was a bit outdated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bu Ching Bay is adjacent to Tai Shue Wan, where the Fullerton Hotel is located, to the south and Sham Wan to the north. Many online posts explain that Buchang Bay got its name from the many garment factories that used to be there. In fact, this is not the case. According to my on-site observation, &quot;cloth factory&quot; should be a homophonic corruption of &quot;bunchang&quot;. Yangjiang Pichang, the hometown of Guan Shanyue, the master of traditional Chinese painting, is a wharf close to the sea and wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photography of Pang Mian on a sampan swimming from Shenwan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/ 474c20fddd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/474c20fddd.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;260446&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Sampans swimming from the other side of Shenwan&amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shaoqing, the other side of Shenwan A small boat with a red hood swam up, with yellow flags on all sides, fluttering in the wind. After getting on the boat and sitting down, we found that the tent was full of decorations: red lanterns, artificial flowers and plants, and small &quot;ten thousand flags&quot; with the names of Hong Kong places. As soon as the boat started to sail, it swayed slightly. Grandma Zhu, who was driving the boat, said proudly: &quot;This sampan is the most beautiful one on the water in Aberdeen, Hong Kong.&quot; The most handsome among the people on the water in Aberdeen.&quot; The boat made a beautiful arc, the motor hummed, and headed in the direction it came from. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The people on the water are called &lt;span>;對&lt;/span>; in the mainland and are mainly distributed along the southeast coast. Historically, the Dan family had various names, such as Yaiyazi, Baishuilang, Danmin, 蜑, Zhi, Yaohu, etc. Until the Tang and Song Dynasties, they were collectively called &quot;獍&quot;. Liu Zongyuan&#39;s &quot;Lingnan Jiedushijuntang Ji&quot; of the Tang Dynasty is the earliest document in which &quot;獍&quot; appears. Regarding the views on the origin of the Dan family, scholar Chen Xujing has made statistics, and there are as many as thirty kinds. Among them, the most romantic ones: first, they are derived from the mermaids, or mermaids; second, they are the descendants of Fan Li and Xi Shi of the Yue Kingdom in the Spring and Autumn Period. The generally accepted view is that the Dan family are descendants of the Baiyue people who fled the country during the Qin Emperor and Han Dynasty&#39;s expedition to the southeast. The &quot;Lingwai Daida&quot; written by Zhou Qufei of the Southern Song Dynasty said: &quot;Those who use boats as houses, regard water as land, and float on rivers and seas are Dan&quot;; Yang Wanli&#39;s &quot;Poems of Dan Households&quot; says: &quot;God divides his life by water. , taught him to step on the waves since he was a child. When cooking crabs as food, you can recognize rice, and when you gather bananas for cloth, you don’t need gauze.&quot; Since the 1950s, Dan families from the mainland have come ashore to settle one after another, but there are still survivors in Hong Kong and Macao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Grandma Zhu did not agree with the views in the book. She told me that in the past, people and boats on the water were too small to raise pigs and cows, so we had to raise chickens, ducks and geese. People on the shore come to the beach to buy eggs. After a long time, they call the people on the water &quot;Dan (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tongdan&lt;/span>;) home. &quot;If my mother were still alive and heard about the Dan family, she would curse people. It&#39;s so taboo.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Pang Mian, Granny Zhu, who has been driving a sampan all her life&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/d9bf2e440b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/02/d9bf2e440b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260447&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Grandma Zhu who has been driving sampans all her life&amp;nbsp; Photography Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1841, when the British army first came, Chen Qun, a Dan family member, was asked to lead the way. When passing through Hong Kong Village, when asked about the name of the place, Chen Qun, who had a Dan family accent, answered &quot;Kang Kong&quot;, so the British army recorded it as &quot;Hong Kong&quot;. Of course, this is just a legend. As far as I know, in 1793, when the British Macartney mission left China, relevant reports already mentioned &quot;HongKong&quot;: &quot;Lingding (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;Now Shenzhen&lt;/span>;) and Hong Kong are suitable for colonization.&quot; But no matter what, this legend also reflects the relationship between Hong Kong and the Dan family. As for the origin of Aberdeen, it is also related to this legend: after Hong Kong became the name of the entire island, in order to avoid confusion, the people changed the name to &quot;Aberdeen&quot;, that is, &quot;Little Hong Kong&quot;. Later, the British Hong Kong government changed the English name of Aberdeen from &quot;LittleHongKong&quot; to Aberdeen (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Aberdeen&lt;/span>;) to commemorate the George Hamilton-Gordon, the fourth Earl of Aberdeen and British Foreign Secretary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boat entered the deep bay, revealing an empty water surface, with a huge neon sign reading &quot;Welcome&quot; coldly. A little far away, there is a dim painted boat - Taibai Seafood Boat - moored, like an aging lady reminiscing about her youth. &quot;The original location of Jumbo Seafood Restaurant,&quot; Grandma Zhu said, and the guests turned their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 1930, the Dan family from Guangzhou brought the &quot;Getang Chu&quot; to Aberdeen. This kind of floating restaurant that combines singing, dancing, entertainment and sightseeing, coupled with the famous local fresh seafood, quickly became popular. Even a number of cultural celebrities who visited Hong Kong from the south, such as Hu Shi and Cai Yuanpei, came here to enjoy the aroma, follow the smell, invite friends and company, and enjoy the food here. After entering the 1950s, there were more than ten upgraded versions of the &quot;Getang Chu&quot; seafood boats. In 1971, a fire broke out during the decoration of Jumbo Seafood Restaurant and was seriously damaged. When Macau gambling king Stanley Ho heard the news, the Dan family gene in his bones awakened (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;his great-grandmother was a Dan family&lt;/span>;), he formed a partnership with others and made huge investments It was bought and renovated for more than 30 million Hong Kong dollars. In 1976, the Zhenbao Seafood Restaurant, designed in the style of the Ming Dynasty palace and able to accommodate more than 2,300 people, opened. A few years later, Stanley Ho acquired his biggest competitors, Taibai Seafood Restaurant and Haijiao Palace. The world&#39;s largest restaurant at sea - Treasure Kingdom was born, becoming a feasting landmark in Hong Kong. At that time, when politicians and celebrities visited Hong Kong, they all came here to &quot;check in.&quot; Grandma Zhu, a young and vigorous woman, earns over 10,000 yuan a month by ferrying guests to and from people on a ferry boat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interestingly, the glorious era of the &quot;Treasure Kingdom&quot; was also the period when Hong Kong films were at their peak and most prosperous. From Bruce Lee to Jackie Chan, from &quot;Enter the Dragon&quot; to &quot;Infernal Affairs 2&quot;, this place has become a popular filming location for Hong Kong films. Especially in &quot;The God of Cookery&quot;, the scene where Stephen Chow flutters in white clothes, steps on the clear waves, and flies through a broken window has left a deep memory for star fans. By the way, the real shooting location of &quot;God of Cookery&quot; was at Taibai Seafood Restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1998, the Asian financial crisis severely damaged the &quot;Jewel Kingdom&quot;. Haijiao Palace first closed down and then moved to Qingdao. From then on, the &quot;Treasure Kingdom&quot; went from bad to worse. In 2022, the Jumbo Seafood Boat towed away from Hong Kong was swallowed up by wind and waves near the Paracel Islands in the South China Sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo courtesy of Pang Mian, Taibai Seafood Restaurant, the filming location of &quot;The God of Cookery&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02 /fc2b691b61.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/fc2b691b61.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;260448&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Taibai Seafood Restaurant, the filming location of &quot;The God of Cookery&quot;&amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Typhoon Shelter View Sunset&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Crossing the Ap Lei Chau Bridge, more and more water birds appeared, flapping their wings up and down to welcome us. Guests constantly stood on the bow of the boat to take selfies, capturing the moment of being in the same frame with the water birds. The girl next to me also excitedly held up her mobile phone and looked around, but she didn&#39;t know which one to take a good picture of. &quot;Look, there is a big fake bird beside the boat.&quot; We looked along the girl&#39;s fingertips. Perhaps the sea breeze carried her words, and the &quot;fake bird&quot; instantly &quot;resurrected&quot;, twisted its long neck, and &quot;glared&quot; at us. Amid roars of laughter, the Aberdeen Typhoon Shelter arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original meaning of a typhoon shelter is a water surface where small and medium-sized boats can temporarily take shelter from typhoons. When Aberdeen was still called Seac Pai Wan, the Dan family was already engaged in fishing and short-distance water transport here, and participated in the bulk transshipment of stones, incense, etc. But what I saw before me was unexpected. It was clearly a floating city on the water. Vegetable selling boat, shop boat, house boat, repair boat, trafficking boat, ferry boat, marine police boat, fish collecting boat, sightseeing boat, catering boat, cleaner&#39;s boat, selling seafood Ships, luxurious ships, simple ships, dilapidated ships, brand new ships, hurried ships, slow and leisurely ships... I can&#39;t help but think of American William C. Hunter&#39;s comments on the Pearl River Estuary 198 years ago. Description: “The river was crowded with local boats... In addition, there were sampans and ferries plying to and from Henan (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;South Bank of the Pearl River&lt;/span>;) , there are also some barber boats and boats selling various food, clothes, toys and daily necessities sold in shops on the shore.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grandma Zhu slowed down and moved closer to a sampan with pots and stoves on it. Over there, they waved their hands early; here, Grandma Zhu praised &quot;Business is good&quot; and resumed the boat&#39;s speed. It turned out that it was a &quot;fenzai boat&quot; that specialized in selling fish egg noodles and roasted pork noodles. In the 1960s and 1970s, Aberdeen&#39;s fishery production reached its peak, and &quot;pink boats&quot; became very popular and could be seen everywhere in typhoon shelters. In addition to frequent visits by fishermen and sailors, citizens and tourists also come here and wave for boats on the shore. Now, there are still three or two boats doing it from time to time. &quot;It depends on your luck whether you can eat or not.&quot; Grandma Zhu continued, &quot;This boat is the most popular on the Char Siu River (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Powder&lt;/span>;). Right.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What also needs to be &quot;checked for luck&quot; is the Zhu Daxian Jiao Festival in the typhoon shelter. According to Grandma Zhu, the Zhu Daxian worshiped at the Zhu Daxian Jiao Festival is Zhu Bajie. Because he served as the Grand Marshal of Tianpeng and was in charge of the Tianhe River, he was regarded as the god of the sea by the people on the water in Aberdeen and recognized as &quot;Master Qi&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Godfather&lt;/span>;)&quot;, whose status is second only to Queen Mazu. Among all the Jiao festivals in Hong Kong and Macao, only the Zhu Daxian Jiao Festival is held entirely at sea every year, so it is also called the Jiao Festival on the water. Since the meeting period is not fixed, when to hold the meeting has to be determined in advance. Whether you can enjoy the prosperity depends entirely on luck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the countless boats, we found one, no, two Zhu Daxian Temples. It looks like it was transformed from a double-decker cruise ship, with a towering flagpole on the cabin and a fluttering yellow triangular red flag against the setting sun. The reason why there are two, Granny Zhu explained, is because &quot;Old Zhu Daxian&quot; needs to lead &quot;New Zhu Daxian&quot; to get familiar with the personnel of the typhoon shelter. After a few days, the shift will be completely handed over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Watching the sunset on a sampan is one of the &quot;compulsory courses&quot; for traveling in Aberdeen. Photo provided by Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/fae0742e11.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/fae0742e11.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Sitting on a sampan to watch the sunset is one of the &quot;compulsory courses&quot; for traveling in Aberdeen. &amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to the boat with great excitement, we passed by the &quot;ruins&quot; of Zhenbao Seafood Boat again. The night rose, submerging the neon sign in a mass of black shadow. And ahead, the lights are bright and brilliant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雄心勃勃的印度海军扩张计划丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261746]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/8VKWWkFNgROpwdXswGako2MkS5jhghhKp18mAPPx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/8VKWWkFNgROpwdXswGako2MkS5jhgh hKp18mAPPx. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259964&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 17, 2023, Kolkata, the Indian Navy&#39;s new warship INS Vindhyagiri sailed in Hooghly River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Indian Navy has made a request to purchase the French Scalp long-range cruise missile, hoping to use this missile It serves as the standard anti-ship and ground attack weapon for the 26 Rafale-M carrier-based aircraft equipped with the aircraft carrier INS Vikrant. A month ago, Ukraine used a Scalp cruise missile to destroy a Russian Black Sea Fleet submarine that was being repaired in a Crimean shipyard. This is the only submarine sunk by a cruise missile so far. In addition, the Scalp missile also accurately hit the headquarters building of the Black Sea Fleet, and its performance in actual combat was quite outstanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this is not the only naval equipment that India has recently purchased from France. On October 28, 2023, the Indian Navy just submitted a purchase request for 26 Rafale carrier-based aircraft to the French government. It can be seen that India is preparing to The carrier-based aircraft will be completely replaced with French Rafales instead of upgrading the Russian-made MiG fighters that have been used for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The procurement plan is by no means simple. It is part of India&#39;s ambitious naval reorganization plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Indian Navy Vice Admiral Ajendra Bahadur Singh told the media: “Some naval ships will be decommissioned in the next few years, and at the same time By adding some more ships, we hope that the number of naval ships will reach more than 200 within 15 years (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;to 2037&lt;/span>;).&quot;&lt;/span>; p>; &lt;p>;Since India’s independence in 1948, the Indian Navy has always hoped to become a blue water navy with 142 ships and operating two aircraft carriers at the same time. However, so far, the Indian Navy has only about 132 ships and 200 ships. The ship&#39;s target seemed a bit difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difficulty of India&#39;s naval expansion is far from a matter of quantity being far from 200 ships. It is that India not only needs to add 68 ships within 15 years, but also needs to acquire most of the navy&#39;s main battle equipment within these 15 years. NATOization. This also means that India must eliminate at least one-third of its active main warships, that is, more than 40 ships, in order to achieve the initial goal of NATOization. In this case, India must equip more than 100 ships within 15 years, and India currently equips about 4 new ships every year. At this rate, the Indian Navy may only maintain its current scale, not to mention India&#39;s huge equipment expansion The plan also includes building a new aircraft carrier, which is undoubtedly more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a realistic perspective, India&#39;s naval reorganization plan may not be as ambitious as it claims. The Indian Navy has long relied on Russia to supply equipment, and Russia suffered huge losses in the war. Most of the supporting supply chains for large surface ships in the Soviet era were in Ukraine. Since the Crimean crisis in 2014, Russia has been unable to obtain supporting products from Ukraine. As a result, its large surface ships have difficulty even in overhaul and maintenance, and may no longer be able to continue to supply India in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When India and Russia previously cooperated on the &quot;Chaori King&quot; aircraft carrier renovation project, the progress was delayed and the cost was seriously overrun. At that time, India realized that relying on Russia was unsustainable, so it had begun to build large surface ships on its own. Industry Planning. Unfortunately, India was sanctioned by the United States because of nuclear weapons issues, and could only make do with continuing military cooperation with Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As relations with the United States have heated up rapidly in recent years, India&#39;s plan to manufacture its own naval equipment is accelerating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first indigenous aircraft carrier &quot;Vikrant&quot; manufactured by India&#39;s Cochin Shipyard Limited (CSL) will be officially commissioned in 2022, marking that India has the ability to build its own aircraft carrier - although this The construction of the difficult-to-deliver aircraft carrier has been delayed from the start of construction to the official commissioning. The Indian Navy has been waiting for this for 17 years. However, compared with aircraft carriers, the construction process of India&#39;s domestic destroyers can be said to be quite smooth. It only took ten years from the project establishment in 2011 to the commissioning of the first ship in 2021, and it is being launched at a rate of one per year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, India has built three 7,000-ton Visakhapatnam-class destroyers on its own. The ships have a stealth appearance and an Aegis air defense system. India claims that its localization rate has reached 75%. It is a model of Indian warships made in China. It can be seen that the Indian shipbuilding industry has no big problems with technology and construction capabilities, at least in building large battleships of the destroyer level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thing that is good for the Indian shipbuilding industry is the signing of an agreement between India and the United States in 2021, announcing that India will become the future large-scale equipment maintenance center of the U.S. Navy in the Indo-Pacific region. The 2022 US-India 2+2 ministerial dialogue announced that the United States intends to inspect Indian shipyards. Immediately afterwards, the USS Charles Drew (T-AKE-10) docked at Kattupalli Shipyard for maintenance and repairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This agreement means that the United States will help India improve its maintenance and construction capabilities of large warships, and even directly provide technical cooperation, allowing India to master the construction and maintenance technology of large U.S. warships, as well as related technical standards and management. process. Judging from the experience of Japan and South Korea, the cooperative weapons and equipment maintenance bases established by the United States after the Korean War played a key role in improving the technology of the local shipbuilding industry and optimizing management processes. In particular, a country like South Korea, which became independent after World War II, has a weak industrial base and a lack of talent. The technical support provided by the United States is crucial to the establishment of its industrial system. Thanks to this, South Korea has also established its own military industry, and even Now it has begun to become a new type of weapons and equipment exporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although India&#39;s independent manufacturing capabilities for main battle equipment have long been poor, it has to admit that it has at least independent manufacturing capabilities for naval equipment. The remaining problem is how to connect with American standards and become a Part of the U.S. global military equipment logistics maintenance system. Considering that India&#39;s economic development momentum is booming, and the technical restrictions on it by the United States and Europe have been almost completely lifted, it is possible to replace the original Soviet-Russian system and Westernize its naval equipment in 15 years, at least while maintaining the existing Given the scale, it is a completely achievable goal to replace the old and adopt the new. As for whether it can be expanded to a scale of 200 ships, it depends on the execution capabilities of the Indian shipbuilding industry and economic development. However, it is foreseeable that with the help of Western technology, the combat effectiveness of Indian naval ships will definitely be greatly improved. This is also the goal that the United States and India hope to achieve in military cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北极光：极夜中的极致绚烂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261722]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我匆匆地走入森林中丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/NQsVYC8CantGXtnTIuGm3J0qDiNMceoDGzXZeGIW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/NQsVYC8CantGXtnTIuGm3J0qDiNMceoDGzX ZeGIW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259217&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/260804 &quot; title=&quot;The dispute between the 94-year-old man and his nanny for 2 million pension funds&quot;>;The dispute between the 94-year-old man and his nanny for 2 million pension funds&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer, a dazzling news: 94 Lu Delin, a 20-year-old Shanghainese man, told on social media that he was abused by his nanny and defrauded of his pension. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai is the super-large city with the highest aging population in the country. According to Shanghai&#39;s 2022 elderly population and aging undertaking monitoring statistics, the registered elderly population aged 60 and above in Shanghai in 2022 will be 5.5366 million, accounting for nearly 40% of the total registered population. Among them, the number of elderly people living alone is 300,600. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The connection between individual circumstances and the lifeline of the times is about to emerge. It is a topic of public value. After encountering countless stories, I still can’t help but feel the initial excitement and impulse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, standing in winter and thinking back to that summer, the first thing that comes to mind is the part about mosquitoes. The scene we first arrived at was the community where the incident occurred. The community is located in Huangpu District, Shanghai, in the city center. It was built in the early 1990s and has 4 high-rise buildings interspersed with lush tall trees and low grass. It was a summer evening in Shanghai, and there were two or three old people sitting on the benches downstairs enjoying the shade. I wanted to know some surrounding information, and I became the target of &quot;mosquitoes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The culprit is probably the &quot;flower mosquito&quot; as the local elderly call it. In just three or two hours, it left more than a dozen red and swollen bumps on my legs that were already wearing trousers. It was obviously not appropriate to scratch and chat at the same time, so I had to scratch twice quickly in the gap from one bench to another. The physical feeling was real, and this unspeakable and unseemly detail became the first fragment that hit me in my memory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This feeling is like a coincidence, and it has been fulfilled in several recent questions, which are about the body. In the topic of Lu Delin, the accused nanny is no longer in the local area. Even during the exchange of evidence before the court session, she still did not appear. The subjects on the other side, the two elderly people, were taken to Hangzhou by their son and daughter-in-law, and their mental condition was not very good for a time. Well, considering that I was afraid that the visit of strangers would bring excitement to the two old people, I did not go to see them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the message left for me? It&#39;s an empty house, and there are surrounding clues that need to be found. Room number 2401, pushing open the closed door, the first thing that came out was a sour smell. This is supposed to be well-ventilated, with a square shape, looking into the other side of the living room, with a wide balcony and large windows. There are several orchids on the balcony. The flower pots are quite old, and the branches and leaves are wilting. For a moment, people don&#39;t know whether they should be described as being well-groomed or not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moldy cutting boards, dirty yellow clothes, expired food, all indicating the disorder of life, suddenly broke into my eyes in an instant. In the eyes of young people, in the undisordered time, what I discussed with my friends around me was more about the spiritual part, and the instinct of the body was automatically ignored in the surface respectability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last topic was in Xi&#39;an. The interview subjects were some disabled people. In the continuous rain, we could not wait for the scene of their &quot;reunion&quot; and had to go door to door to chat. During the process, everyone The disorder of the body was mentioned invariably; and after Lu Delin chose the topic, I continued my business trip in Shanghai. The new topic was about Alzheimer&#39;s disease. The wife who became a caregiver told the story of taking care of her sick husband for nine years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From these stories, we can see what everyone is trying their best to maintain, and this effort seems to be an inevitable disorder of life. As a bystander, I hurriedly walked into this forest and felt the &quot;disorder&quot; that I had never experienced in real life. Some disorders are accidental, such as a car accident or sudden illness. They are also unprepared and rush into the forest and never get out; some disorders are slow, such as aging. They are already on the road to aging. It has been too long, so long that I have to admit that aging has come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to the perspective of journalism, when we encounter these stories, how should we report this disorder? After the initial excitement and impulse, it’s time to write. I think that we should not visit this forest with a pair of curious eyes and notice something unsightly. It should not be regarded as the author&#39;s delicate observation and be presented freely. It’s better to enter this forest with a level gaze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this time we entered this forest because of work, such a forest may break into our real life at any time, and in addition to the accident that breaks in at any time, its final arrival is a kind of inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“巴基斯坦可以从中国学到很多”:专访巴参议院国防委员会主席]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261738]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73936&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70727&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/4eecfa1ded.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Exclusive interview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At noon on December 1, Mshahi De accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporter. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Wang Hang)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/12/02/4eecfa1ded.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260507&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December At noon on the 1st, Mushahid accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Wang Hang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of December 1, Guangzhou Yuexiu International Conference Center. After the one-hour press conference, Pakistani guest Mushahid Hussain Saeed walked out of the venue quickly. Entering December, the weather in Guangzhou turns cooler. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I like Guangzhou. It has a pleasant climate and is a very dynamic place in China.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mushahid is the chairman of the Defense Committee of the Senate of Pakistan and the chairman of the Pakistan-China Society. From December 1st to 3rd, he was invited to participate in the 2023 &quot;Understanding China&quot; international conference to discuss and communicate with domestic and foreign guests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past fifty years, Mushahid came to China many times. In his words, he witnessed the poverty-stricken China in the 1970s and the reform and opening-up China in the 1980s. &quot;What we see today is a prosperous and powerful China that is leading the development of globalization.&quot; Mushahid said, &quot;I am very happy to witness the rise of China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Mushahid Shahid spent four years in Washington, the United States, and obtained a master&#39;s degree in international relations from Georgetown University&#39;s School of Foreign Service, &quot;with an understanding of the U.S. political system and how it operates.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He proposed that there are two different &quot;roads&quot; in the world today. One proposed by the United States and Western countries is security-centered, military-led, and focused on conflicts and confrontations. On the contrary, China insists on connectivity and cooperation, respecting diversity and being more inclusive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 10 years, the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor, an important pilot project of the “Belt and Road Initiative”, has brought development opportunities to Pakistan. &quot;26 billion U.S. dollars of investment, 250,000 job opportunities, and 28,000 Pakistanis came to China to study. Electricity, roads, hospitals, education, etc. are constantly improving.&quot; Mushahid said, &quot;These have benefited Pakistan.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Global and regional security are also the focus of the conference. Regarding peace on the India-Pakistan border, Mushahid has optimistic expectations. &quot;Border conflicts can be resolved as long as there is will. We reject global hegemony and we reject regional hegemony.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on December 1, Mushahid accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“If you want to learn from China, it is crucial to understand China”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/h4>; strong>;&lt;span>;Is this your first time to participate in the &quot;Understanding China&quot; forum? How do you feel? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is my first time to participate in the &quot;Understanding China&quot; forum. This forum is very valuable. First of all, we use this platform to understand China, the region and the world, and how they change and develop. Secondly, it is important for Pakistan to understand China. Because China is our closest strategic partner and our neighbor. Third, personally, I have been dealing with China for nearly fifty years. When I first came to China, I was still a young man of 17 or 18 years old. As a friend of China and a student of Chairman Mao, I saw China at that time. It can be said that I have witnessed China&#39;s transformation. If you want to learn from China, it is crucial to understand China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Compared with the first time you came to China, now what is the difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first time I came to China was in the 1970s. At that time, China was very poor and isolated from the world. Today, China has become rich and powerful, a global leader, and a leader in globalization. China has proposed the “One Belt, One Road” initiative to lead green development and technological innovation. So, this is a huge change. In addition to China, the world has also changed. Because the global center of gravity is shifting from the West to the East. This change in China also reflects global changes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What are your impressions of Guangdong? For example, for the two big cities of Guangzhou and Shenzhen&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first time I came to Guangdong Province was in 1972, when Guangzhou A trade fair is being held. During that time, I went shopping at Guangzhou Friendship Store. I only had 200 yuan with me at that time, but I felt like a &quot;millionaire&quot;. Because no matter how I bought it, I never spent all the money. At that time, the price of Chinese goods was too cheap. There were no computers at that time, so people used calculators to calculate accounts or calculate money by hand. Then, I took a train from Guangzhou to Hong Kong, which was indeed a wonderful experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I went to Shenzhen was in 1982, and then in 1984. At that time, Shenzhen was a remote fishing village. After seeing it in person, I also felt that it was too backward and underdeveloped. When I first came to China, the city of Shenzhen did not exist. But in the subsequent 1980s, I saw the rapid rise of Shenzhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many Pakistani businessmen do business in Guangzhou. Can they find business opportunities here? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mushahid: Of course. Pakistani businessmen in Guangzhou have been working here for years, even decades. In fact, many trades began not just now, but decades or even centuries ago. Guangzhou has always been a hub of connectivity and a warm and welcoming city. Foreigners are welcome to come here to do business and stay here. It has a pleasant climate, is close to the sea, and is a beautiful city. So Pakistanis enjoy life here, we support them and they can make a lot of money. So I think it&#39;s very good and they play a very good role in promoting relations between the people of Pakistan and China. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Pakistan can learn a lot from China”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span >;Over the past 40 years, China has undergone tremendous changes. What lessons do you think this has for Pakistan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think Pakistan can learn a lot from this. First, have a clear vision. Second, there must be the will to turn this vision into reality. Deng Xiaoping, the architect of China&#39;s reform and opening up, once said, &quot;Seek truth from facts&quot; and &quot;development is the last word.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Insist on development and openness, simplify bureaucracy and cumbersome processes, give talents the attention they deserve, and put them first. Good leadership qualities, policy continuity, learning from mistakes, openness and inclusiveness, focus on people-centered development, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I said, we can learn a lot from Guangdong, China, and China&#39;s reform and opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Are you confident about Pakistan’s future development? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am very optimistic about the future of Pakistan. I studied in the United States for four years, but I didn’t want to live there. I said I would go back and serve my country. This is thanks to our relationship with China, which is our neighbor and our best friend. China invests extensively in Pakistan. We must unleash the energy and creativity of the people of Pakistan, move forward, reduce bureaucracy and allow them to develop. We need to build industries, innovate, get education, and let them focus on what they should do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73937&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70728&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c3787969cf.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Interview.png&quot; alt=&quot;At the media meeting on December 1 , Mushahid said that the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Mao Shujie)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c3787969cf.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260508&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At a media conference on December 1, Mushahid said that the “One Belt, One Road” initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Mao Shujie)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Under the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative, development opportunities have come&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot; >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Is the “One Belt, One Road” initiative a development opportunity for Pakistan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan, and we must seize this opportunity. In the past ten years, China has invested US$26 billion in Pakistan, created 250,000 jobs and produced 8,000 megawatts of electricity. These results have given Pakistan and its people confidence in the future. For example, Gwadar Port has developed and become a hub between Pakistan and Central Asian countries. So this is a big opportunity. Because of the “One Belt, One Road” initiative, a whole new world is unfolding. This is a historical opportunity for Pakistan to develop rapidly, and it is also a historical opportunity to learn from China&#39;s poverty alleviation and green development model. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people have misunderstandings about the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, but most Pakistanis fully support the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and the Maritime Silk Road. Many Pakistanis care about China. They believe that China is Pakistan&#39;s good friend and close ally. Therefore, the negative voices come from foreign propaganda. They come from misinformation, false stories and fake news. We have to fight back against this. This is the biggest challenge facing the Belt and Road Initiative in the next decade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Terrorist attacks occur frequently in Pakistan. How should the government solve the problem of terrorism? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Unfortunately, terrorist incidents do happen from time to time. Some of the terrorists come from neighboring areas, which are very unstable. Some are forces that do not want cooperation and development between Pakistan and China. In addition, we feel that there are foreign forces controlling terrorist activities in Pakistan, and they specifically target Chinese companies, individuals and projects. Therefore, we must develop an effective counter-terrorism strategy in Pakistan, carry out effective Pakistan-China security cooperation, and develop effective plans to protect Chinese projects and Chinese people living in Pakistan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“We reject global hegemony and regional hegemony”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2023, Pakistan’s Foreign Minister will visit India for the first time in 12 years. Do you think India and Pakistan have the will and motivation to deal with border conflicts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Border conflicts can be resolved as long as there is a will. India should be broader-minded and not become narrow-minded in dealing with small countries. We reject global hegemony and we reject regional hegemony. Whether it is Pakistan, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, etc., they all reject hegemony. Look at Afghanistan, they reject American hegemony even though they are a small country. Therefore, the size of a country does not equal its strength. India should learn from the mistakes of other major powers and understand how they went in the wrong (direction). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The internal and external obstacles to solving the India-Pakistan issue are What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the internal obstacles mainly come from the negative attitude of the Indian government, and their mentality must change. The external problem is the &quot;new cold war&quot; launched by the United States against China in Asia. They are using India to counter China. This is where the problem lies. Therefore, India should be part of the Asian countries and should be part of the Belt and Road Initiative. We want India to be united with us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;India is a nation-state with a great civilization. Why say no to this? Why should India work and behave like Washington or London? India should cooperate with Beijing, Kathmandu, Dhaka and Colombo. This is a regional issue. The future belongs to this region, not Europe or the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If India continues to respond negatively to relations between the two countries, will there be a risk of escalation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think escalation can be avoided because India also knows that if they try to escalate, the other country will respond . Every country hopes to safeguard its territorial integrity, safeguard sovereignty, and maintain unity and dignity. They tried to launch an attack on Pakistan in February 2019, and they sent several aircraft over Pakistan. But we fought back and shot down two helicopters. So the country will respond, and this response will come quickly and strongly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>