<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[城市排名，看看就行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258754]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the consulting company Resonance Consultancy released the &quot;Ranking of the World&#39;s Best Cities in 2024&quot;. 2024 has not arrived yet, but the ranking is so forward-looking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this ranking, the top ones are: London, Paris, New York, Tokyo, Singapore, Dubai, San Francisco, Barcelona, ​​Amsterdam, Seoul, Rome, Prague, Madrid, Berlin, Los Angeles, and Washington. Then there is Beijing, ranked 18th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some netizens sarcastically asked, did this list take into account the rarity of drug dealing, shootings, explosions, robberies, thefts, etc.? Nowadays, I increasingly don’t believe in the various rankings selected by foreigners. In some cities, local friends told me not to go out at night before I even went there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sarcasm of netizens has some truth to it. It is actually difficult to define what is the best city. In 2018, a research institution ranked 338 cities above the prefecture level in China and ranked 15 new first-tier cities. Some cities are convinced by this ranking, while others are dissatisfied. In fact, not to mention that the concept of &quot;best&quot; is too big to be defined, even the smaller &quot;urban livability&quot; is difficult to explain clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For ordinary people, whether a city is livable is nothing more than commuting to and from work, making money and development, and basic necessities, food, housing and transportation, that is, income, consumption, and public services. In terms of work, the more developed the city&#39;s economy and the higher the income, the more livable it is. In terms of life, the more convenient, higher comfort and lower the cost of living, the more livable it is. These two aspects are related to the market. Outside the market are the public services provided by the government. Among the public services provided by the government, education and medical care can be provided by the market, but public security can only be provided by the government. Public security is the foundation for a livable city. Otherwise, no matter how much money you make, you can&#39;t save your life, so what&#39;s the point? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times, these indicators are contradictory. The most typical example is that big cities have higher incomes and more development opportunities, but at the same time, housing prices and consumption in big cities are also more expensive, and the cost of living is very high. So, are big cities livable? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there are more opportunities in big cities. Big cities have economies of scale. Under the economies of scale, there will be many services and jobs that cannot be maintained in small places. This is what many people say, they cannot find a job when they return to their hometown in a small town. Therefore, large cities with higher economic indicators can often provide more jobs and higher wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a consumption perspective, due to scale effects, big cities have richer ecosystems and many services will be cheaper. For example, if you want to see an expert account, living in a big city is just a matter of registration fee. You can find corresponding experts for all kinds of difficult and complicated diseases. But living in a small town also involves extra costs such as travel, accommodation and time off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although houses in big cities are expensive, houses are also an asset. Even if you spend millions to buy a house, the money can still be recovered and liquidated. What&#39;s more, the prices of industrial products such as mobile phones, TVs, and automobiles are almost the same. This means that as long as a person&#39;s income can offset, or partially offset, the rent in a big city, his living standard in a big city will be higher and richer, his children will have more opportunities, and he will be able to spend more in emergencies. money. This is roughly what the word livable refers to. More and more people are flocking to big cities, which also proves that big cities are more livable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, people&#39;s needs are complex and diverse. Some people want to live in a 200-square-meter house and play mahjong, but have no interest in opera or luxury goods. Some people are willing to live in a small house of 60 square meters in order for their children to receive a better education. Therefore, livability ultimately depends on the individual. Whether this is an abstract evaluation of the livability of large cities or small cities, we can only give one judgment principle. If we want to evaluate the livability comparison between specific cities, it is even more confusing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anyone with statistical knowledge and research experience knows that data can lie. Not to mention the authenticity of the data, even if the data is real, there are too many ways to control the final conclusion in terms of indicator settings, sampling methods, data processing, and data interpretation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, set up a consumption indicator, consisting of online shopping activity, overseas shopping activity, takeout activity, and movie viewing frequency. Movie watching seems to reflect cultural consumption, but movies have a lipstick effect, which means that when the economy is bad, people will still entertain themselves, and even use entertainment more to comfort themselves, but they will turn to relatively cheap ones. It is possible that tourism consumption has gone down while movie consumption has increased. Therefore, the movie viewing indicator may not be objective. At least, it is not as authoritative and direct as the indicator of total social consumer goods per capita. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many other indicators selection techniques. If public security is to be regarded as the most important indicator and a number of small indicators are set, then the world ranking of Chinese cities will definitely improve a lot, because Chinese people are kind-hearted and have omnipresent eyes. If you regard fireworks as an indicator and set 10 small indicators, then New York&#39;s score may be improved a lot. After all, even Times Square is a mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, urban livability indicators are often not independent. If one indicator improves, other indicators will also improve. For example, if a city has more universities, its medical conditions will also improve. Because universities often have medical schools, there are naturally more experts in medical schools. But it seems impossible to exclude this independence. Because going to a better university and seeking medical treatment from experts are essentially citizens’ educational needs and medical needs. These are indeed two aspects of needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, by setting indicators, the livability evaluation of a city can indeed be greatly affected. The same is true for other cities&#39; economic activity, urban development, best cities and other rankings. They can be used as a reference, but they do not need to be regarded as authoritative. Generally speaking, which city you decide to work and live in will be the most livable city for you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中职学校数量十年间大减，但“这不是坏事”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258931]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/zb9jBoBeAP8o00VOnloccqJY1Ts9ggT766tPBtXF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1263&quot; height=&quot;841&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/zb9jBoBeAP8o00VOnloccqJY1Ts9ggT766 tPBtXF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 16, 2023, Hohhot, a vocational and technical school teacher introduced the professional situation to students . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A set of data on secondary vocational education once attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some media reported that in the past ten years, the number of secondary vocational schools has decreased by 3,039. Southern Weekend reporters combined data from the websites of the Ministry of Education and the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and found that from 2013 to 2022, the number of secondary vocational schools continued to decrease, with a cumulative decrease of 2,911. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the websites of the two ministries and commissions, the number of secondary vocational schools in China will be 9,752 in 2022, less than half of the peak in the 1990s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the country’s adjustment of vocational education policies is the main reason for the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools. In addition, the practical difficulties encountered in the development process of secondary vocational schools are also one of the reasons why various places have taken the initiative to merge and reduce schools. However, in recent years, with the changes in the layout of vocational education, secondary vocational schools have also ushered in new changes such as a substantial increase in the enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that, combined with the predictions of scholars, in the next few years, the gradual reduction, dissolution, merger and optimization of secondary vocational schools will continue to be a trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Anhui Province has the largest decrease&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;An easily confused concept is that in China, secondary vocational education is divided into four categories, including general technical secondary schools, vocational High schools, adult secondary schools and technical schools. In accordance with the Vocational Education Law and the current &quot;three determinations&quot; (functional configuration, internal organization and staffing) plan of the State Council, vocational high schools, general technical secondary schools and adult technical secondary schools are under the management of the education department, and technical schools are under the management of the human resources and social security department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be pointed out that the academic qualifications obtained after graduation from general technical secondary schools, vocational high schools, adult technical secondary schools and technical schools are all secondary education qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the Ministry of Education website shows that in 2013, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide was 12,300. By 2022, this number dropped to 7,201. In the past ten years, the number of secondary vocational schools has decreased by 5,100 overall. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A closer look at the year-by-year data on the Ministry of Education’s website will reveal that from 2013 to 2020, the number of secondary vocational schools decreased each year by between 151 and 676. In 2021, the number of secondary vocational schools decreased by 2,602 compared with 2020, and there were obvious abnormalities in the range of data changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, a note on the official website of the Ministry of Education shows that the statistics of secondary vocational colleges in 2021 and 2022 do not include technical schools managed by the human resources and social security departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the official website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and found that including data from 2021 and 2022, the number of technical schools increased by 69 and 59 respectively. Combined with the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools in the country from 2013 to 2022 compared with the previous year, the data shows that from 2013 to 2022, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide decreased by 2,911 in ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters inquired about the official data released by the education departments and statistics departments of 31 provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) across the country from 2012 to 2022. Whether each province (autonomous region and municipality) plans to collect data The standards for entering technical schools are not uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, looking at the overall situation, nationwide, except for the Tibet Autonomous Region, which has a slight increase in the number of secondary vocational colleges (an increase of 7) on the original basis, the remaining provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) are all. downward trend. The number of secondary vocational schools in Anhui Province has decreased the most, with a decrease of 216 in ten years, a decrease of approximately 44%. Henan Province followed, with a decrease of 198. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, the number of universities has decreased by more than 100 in 10 provinces. Except for Heilongjiang, Shandong, Guangdong, and Zhejiang, the rest are all in the central and western regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, Qinghai, Ningxia and other places have experienced single-digit declines over the past ten years due to factors such as insufficient construction of secondary vocational schools, and the change is not significant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/PxVW6rlgSziSm5VvI9A2ssWYVIZh23jljWzDL0bU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1155&quot; height= &quot;780&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/PxVW6rlgSziSm5VvI9A2ssWYVIZh23jljWzDL0bU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254656&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 25, 2022, in a clothing production company in Tongren, Guizhou, students majoring in clothing design at the Yuping Dong Autonomous County Secondary Vocational School were processing clothing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Policy adjustment is the main reason&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Secondary vocational school It once played an important role in China&#39;s economic development. Its number experienced explosive growth in the late 1980s, from 2,760 in 1978 to more than 20,000 in 1990, an increase of nearly eight times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, by the end of the 20th century, with the combined effects of multiple factors such as industrial restructuring, tightening of the employment environment, and expansion of college enrollment, the development of secondary vocational education gradually declined because it was difficult to adapt to the needs of the market and employers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Official data shows that since 1999, the number of secondary vocational schools has been declining year by year, with only a slight increase between 2004 and 2008. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, in 2007, the Ministry of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Further Improving the Enrollment Management of Various Types of Colleges and Universities&quot;, which stipulated that the corresponding enrollment plan for colleges and universities to recruit secondary vocational graduates should not exceed the number of fresh graduates of secondary vocational schools that year. 5% of students. This proportion limit actually clarifies the employment orientation of secondary vocational education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main reason for the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools is the adjustment of national policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014 and 2019, the State Council issued the &quot;Decision on Accelerating the Development of Modern Vocational Education&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Decision&quot;) and the &quot;Notice on Issuing the National Vocational Education Reform Implementation Plan&quot; respectively. It is proposed to “encourage high-quality schools to integrate school resources and optimize the layout and structure of secondary vocational education through mergers, trusteeships, cooperative education, etc.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the &quot;Decision&quot; was promulgated, the Beijing Municipal Education Commission announced the corresponding implementation opinions of Beijing, requiring the number of secondary vocational schools in the city to be adjusted from 116 to about 60, a reduction of nearly half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henan started optimizing the layout of secondary vocational schools in 2015, and integrated a number of &quot;weak, small and scattered&quot; schools in the form of cancellation, merger, and transfer. Jiangxi also introduced a new policy for secondary vocational education in 2015, proposing to merge more than 200 secondary vocational schools within three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also in 2015, Guangxi proposed that &quot;by 2020, the number of secondary vocational schools in the region will be adjusted from the current 333 to about 240.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2020, nine departments including the Ministry of Education jointly issued the &quot;Action Plan for Improving the Quality of Vocational Education (2020-2023)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Plan&quot;). Based on the original policy It is further proposed to &quot;comprehensively verify the basic conditions for running secondary vocational schools, integrate &#39;empty, small, scattered and weak&#39; schools, and optimize the layout of secondary vocational schools.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the adjustment of national policies, the difficulties encountered by secondary vocational schools in their own development are also one of the reasons for the reduction in the number of schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, before the state promulgated relevant policies, local governments had already taken measures to reduce the number of secondary vocational schools, which directly pointed to practical problems in the development of secondary vocational education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the beginning of the 21st century, in order to meet the needs of Beijing’s urban function adjustment and industrial structure upgrading, the Beijing Municipal Education Commission merged a number of small-scale, low-efficiency schools with unclear professional characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is not a bad thing. Only by merging schools with poor quality and low enrollment can we improve the quality and attractiveness of secondary vocational colleges.” Vice Chairman of China Development Research Foundation Fang Jin, the secretary-general, once said publicly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The transformation of secondary vocational schools pays more attention to quality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“The decrease in the number of secondary vocational colleges has a certain relationship with the transformation of secondary vocational education, because the government may China pays more attention to quality rather than quantity.&quot; Xu Hui, a doctoral candidate in sociology at the University of Jena in Germany and a researcher at the Sino-German Research Center for Skills and Social Development, told Southern Weekend reporters that this reduction in quantity may help concentrate resources and improve the quality of education. , to meet today’s ever-changing professional needs. According to Xu Hui’s observation, under the transformation, secondary vocational education has greatly improved in terms of curriculum diversity, technology upgrading, and career guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ensuing increase in attractiveness is also the result of policy changes. One of the key points is the substantial increase in the enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PhD candidate Jiang Beijia and scientific research assistant Fan Yilin of the National Education Macro Policy Research Institute of East China Normal University published a paper &quot;Policy Changes in Vocational Education for Higher Education: Context, Logic and &quot;Mirror&quot;, sorted out relevant policy documents and found that since the &quot;National Medium and Long-term Education Reform and Development Plan (2010-2020)&quot; issued in 2010, it was first proposed to separate the enrollment of higher vocational examinations from the general college entrance examination. The &quot;National Vocational Education Reform Implementation Plan&quot; clearly states for the first time that &quot;the establishment of a vocational education college entrance examination system&quot; will be completely liberated from the previously restricted enrollment rate in secondary vocational schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the main channels for secondary vocational school graduates to obtain undergraduate degrees include consistent training, vocational education college entrance examination, junior college to bachelor&#39;s degree, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smooth flow of channels for further education has led to an increase in the admission rate of secondary vocational schools. Data released by education departments in many places show that the enrollment rate of secondary vocational schools in recent years has generally exceeded 80%. Taking Shenzhen, which has developed secondary vocational education, as an example, the &quot;Shenzhen Secondary Vocational Education Quality Report 2023&quot; shows that in 2022, the number of graduates from Shenzhen&#39;s secondary vocational schools will be 12,485, and the number of students entering higher education will be 11,173, with the enrollment rate reaching 89.49%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Xu Hui also pointed out that a high secondary vocational education promotion rate can provide students with more opportunities, but a careful balance is also needed to ensure that the quality and resources of secondary vocational education are not ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2022, at a press conference held by the Ministry of Education to introduce the work related to promoting the high-quality development of modern vocational education, Chen Ziji, Director of the Department of Vocational Education and Adult Education of the Ministry of Education, further explained that optimizing the quality of secondary vocational education The layout structure is mainly achieved through measures such as cancellation, merger, transformation, trusteeship, land replacement, and group school running. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that in the future, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide may continue to decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女童被狗咬伤事件中，伤人的罗威纳是种什么犬？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258939]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[普通人上播客讲故事：声波起伏间，听见人生一段]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258802]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;46-year-old excavator Wang Chunyan told her life story through a podcast. This time, her voice arrived In the ears of tens of thousands of people. On the construction site where the machines are roaring, she is silent most of the time. When faced with the foreman&#39;s scolding, she just pretends not to hear it and sometimes has to smile. With only one square meter in the cab, she would listen to her favorite music and sing loudly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DNEXw9iOruxL22YwlzaDlFPOCgz64j52FhUkjWP6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DNEXw9iOruxL22YwlzaDlFPOCgz64j52FhUkjWP6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254358&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Women are in the minority among those who operate excavators. As one of them, Wang Chunyan’s experience is special. The picture shows the scene of drying chili peppers in Jiuquan, Gansu Province in September 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the collection of stories on the theme of &quot;My achievements have nothing to do with gender&quot; was issued, Kou Aizhe received a large number of submissions , he was first attracted by Wang Chunyan’s message, although she only briefly expressed that as a woman, “the excavator makes me very proud.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye, who is studying for graduate school in France, entered the podcast process as a narrator, which was full of drama. She learned that her father, whom she had not seen for many years, passed away in Cambodia. She wanted to go there, but she did not dare to leave rashly. She happened to find a podcast episode in which a Chinese man in Cambodia, Santiao, told his story about a foreign country. She finally contacted him through a message. With care, Xiaoye completed the &quot;journey to find his father&quot; with peace of mind, and later accepted the invitation to participate in the podcast recording with this story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Xiaoyushu App, Xiaoye’s story has become one of the three most popular programs among all podcasts. This kind of spread effect was expected by the host Da Meng. What he didn’t expect was that as a Content workers can help some people solve real-life problems while making programs. This is the biggest healing and encouragement Xiaoye&#39;s story brings to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Xinran listened to his podcast outside the massage parlor where he worked. He was embarrassed to listen in front of his colleagues and felt that his voice was unpleasant. When he told his story, there was something &quot;very hard to explain&quot;. He is a blind marathon runner. In the show, he said: &quot;As long as you run, you can create the wind.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kou Aizhe and Dameng are the owners of two podcasts - Story FM and Genius respectively. Founder and anchor of Catcher FM. Story FM passed its seventh birthday, and Genius Catcher FM was born at the end of 2019. The former&#39;s guest self-narration format has become a signature, while the latter uses interviews to capture the inspiration of all kinds of life. The content narrators of podcasts are often industry experts, scholars, and media people, and these two podcasts provide a stage for lay people to talk and express themselves, and amplify their voices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/djz1BWwVeyn3H4uCHyx0M6YiDijOez8Jk340CNkQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/djz1BWwVeyn3H4uCHyx0M6YiDijOez8Jk340CNkQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254360&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There are currently relatively few Chinese podcasts where amateurs tell stories. The picture is a creative picture. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They host almost the only large-scale witness story podcast in China. Dameng saw that the podcast platform classified the two into the story category, which is not a problem in itself. What is strange is that other podcasts in the same category tell ghost stories and historical stories. &quot;They are not the same &#39;storytelling&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;From listener to narrator&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan had been listening to Story FM for five years before she opened her mouth to tell the story. At first, she was attracted by the eye-catching title of Story FM, but gradually she felt that it suited her very well, as it was an &quot;unconcealed, spiritual communication program that directly faces people&#39;s hearts.&quot; She is particularly interested in stories involving life, death and human emotions, and is keenly aware that the program &quot;focuses on more vulnerable groups.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she saw Story FM’s call for submissions to collect stories about women in gender-imbalanced industries, Wang Chunyan had a lot to say. &quot;As a female excavator master, I don&#39;t know if I have a firm foothold, but I have persisted for more than ten years and I feel quite proud.&quot; She left a message, &quot;I didn&#39;t expect Ai Zhe to really see it.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;When the epidemic broke out, Xiaoye developed the habit of listening to podcasts. She described that she had some obsessive-compulsive disorder at the time. After discovering Genius Catcher FM, she listened to every program from the beginning. Xiaoye, who already likes to listen to different life stories, is like finding a treasure. He keeps listening to it until now. The program invited many people from all walks of life to tell their career stories. She was deeply impressed by the psychiatrist Chen Baiyou among them, because what she told was very touching and different from the public perception. &quot;She said that only kind people will suffer from mental illness, which touched me very much.&quot; Xiaoye told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye’s parents went to Cambodia to work together. She was also born in Cambodia. After her parents divorced, her mother took Xiaoye back to China to develop, while her father stayed in Cambodia. In June 2022, Xiaoye learned about her father&#39;s death through relatives. On Father&#39;s Day a week later, she sent her blessings to her father&#39;s WeChat, but she did not expect a response from the other party. A strange Cambodian woman contacted Xiaoye and claimed to be her father&#39;s partner. Later, she invited Xiaoye to Phnom Penh to participate in her father&#39;s 100-day festival. When she was hesitating whether to go there, she happened to see Genius Catcher FM&#39;s push &quot;I collected corpses for Chinese people in Cambodia, but I didn&#39;t dare to show the faces of the corpses to their families.&quot; She left messages for Dameng on various platforms, hoping to get to know the narrator, Santiao, and Dameng set up a connection between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sanjou said to Xiaoye: &quot;Just come, I will pick you up at the airport.&quot; As soon as she left the airport gate, Xiaoye saw the woman holding a photo of her father, but she always felt that she would just go with this stranger , feeling panicked. At this time, Sanjou appeared. He grabbed Xiaoye&#39;s suitcase and protected her from behind. On the first day of Xiaoye&#39;s arrival, Sanjou drove with him all the way, and even called his girlfriend, who could speak English and Cambodian, to act as a translator for Xiaoye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye bought an urn at the local market and took away part of his father&#39;s ashes. Among his father&#39;s belongings, there was a small box containing several photos with Xiaoye. Xiaoye also discovered that although he had not seen his father since his second year in junior high school, his passport still had records of entering China several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Xiaoye returned to daily life, Dameng chatted with her for an hour or two and recorded this life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His father was absent when Xiaoye was growing up. Whether it was on the phone or via WeChat, Xiaoye felt that he could not truly communicate with each other. But within just two or three days of staying in a foreign land, Xiaoye realized that his father had been thinking about him. From a group of strange Cambodian people, she heard her relatives call her: baby, with an exaggerated pronunciation and mouth shape, which was unique to her father. She thought about how many times her father had to say it before everyone around him remembered it. Some listeners shed tears after hearing this detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/N6yoBn0rYEuKFsOCqtCknUHP4Y8clT3ww87UIy03.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/N6yoBn0rYEuKFsOCqtCknUHP4Y8clT3ww87UIy03.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254359&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The stories of the Chinese in Cambodia have been made into a series of podcasts, including the story of Xiaoye going to participate in his father&#39;s 100-day festival. The picture shows the Day of the Dead in Phnom Penh, Cambodia in October 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan has been driving excavators for more than ten years. When she talked about taking hormones to gain weight in order to collect bills more easily and avoid being sexually harassed, Kou Aizhe was shocked and confirmed again, did you really take hormones to gain weight? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many inconveniences for women working as excavators, such as the lack of toilets at the construction site. For this reason, Wang Chunyan would leave home at around 5 a.m. and get off work at around 8 p.m. without taking a sip of water. Sometimes she couldn&#39;t hold it in any longer, so she would dig a hole for emergencies. Not many people can persist. Wang Chunyan has built a &quot;National Queen Group&quot;, which has 99 female excavator operators, roughly 1/3 of which have mature skills. She has accepted three female apprentices, and they either changed careers or started working on their own. When you are the boss, you no longer do it yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan persisted mainly to make money. Doing other jobs cannot support this family. When she was 16 years old, her abducted sister returned home nine months pregnant. Both her mother and sister suffer from mental illness, and her father-in-law is careless. The family&#39;s livelihood depends entirely on Wang Chunyan. Later, her husband was in a car accident and became a vegetative state. After he woke up and was discharged from the hospital paralyzed, he owed a large amount of medical expenses, which Wang Chunyan has been paying over the years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than two months after the podcast was released, many listeners left messages and were moved by her tenacity, courage, and optimism. Wang Chunyan didn&#39;t pay much attention to this feedback. She was working every day in the past few days and &quot;didn&#39;t stop to review those things.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Speak out your worries and hear new knowledge&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan has never told her family about the hardships she experienced outside. Her sister, mother, and husband are all patients. Her parents-in-law have never wanted to see her because of her family background. She, there was almost no emotional communication between the two parties. &quot;I don&#39;t have an outlet to vent. Sometimes I feel very depressed and want a space to talk.&quot; Talking about her life in the podcast fulfilled her wish to talk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kou Aizhe understands this mentality very well, “Everyone needs to tell something that has been buried in his heart for a long time, or some obstacles that he cannot get over, or he is confused about this matter and wants to hear some people’s opinions. Feedback, but he may not want people around him to hear it, for example, he cannot accept these people judging him.&quot; Some of the more secretive stories are basically from the narrator&#39;s initiative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, if the narrator states that he does not want certain details to be disclosed, such as name, city, and industry, they will be blurred. This protection of anonymity also gives the narrator more courage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s anonymous anyway, no one knows who I am, so I can say whatever I want.&quot; Xiaoye received Da Meng&#39;s recording invitation and readily agreed. She was very happy to be on the podcast she often listens to. , at the same time, she felt that this story was &quot;quite bizarre, outrageous, and worth telling&quot; and wanted to share it with more people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Dameng’s view, recording a podcast is a process in which the narrator and the producer complement each other. &quot;Sometimes people experience some legendary things and want to record them. Some people are willing to write and some are willing to talk about it. It is also important for the guests to record their own experiences on our program. Let me help them complete it. Content editor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Because everyone&#39;s life is boring and they are curious about what other people live, so they especially like to listen to such stories. For me, this is a way to see the world. The window is mainly for fun.&quot; Xiaoye explained why people love to listen to stories told by another ordinary person so much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For producers, the fun of doing programs is largely due to the ability to gain new knowledge and broaden their cognitive boundaries. When I first started doing a series of stories about Cambodian characters, almost every issue would refresh Da Meng’s understanding. The narrators all live in Phnom Penh and Sihanoukville, Cambodia, helping Chinese people in trouble in foreign lands. Santiao was the first one to share on the show. He volunteered to help Chinese people who died accidentally in Cambodia, process and cremate their bodies, and transport them back to China. Later, Dameng interviewed Jie Ge and Aaron one after another. They used their own methods to protect the Chinese wandering in Cambodia or guide them on their way home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Beijing Long Distance Running Festival in April 2023 made Dameng pay attention to He Yajun’s Blind Assistance Group. After contacting several blind runners in the group, he chose Song Xinran as the subject of his story. The theme of the program is about &quot;wind&quot;. Every Wednesday and Saturday morning, Song Xinran runs with nearly a hundred teammates in the Beijing Olympic Forest Park, passing through flowers, bamboo forests, and ponds. The blind friend and the running aid volunteer are connected by a running aid rope for the blind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v5xWL54vReWbjIi8ol9nJ4E7jtFpQz3b2eNNqLOk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v5xWL54vReWbjIi8ol9nJ4E7jtFpQz3b2eNNqLOk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254357&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Song Xinran, a blind man, talked about his experience in long-distance running. The picture shows a blind running rope connecting a blind marathon runner (left) and a volunteer guiding him (right) in Tai&#39;an, Shandong in 2017. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The competition that Song Xinran is most proud of is the 2019 Beijing Long Distance Running Festival. He ran hard and ran within the prescribed time. He crossed the finish line and won the qualification for his runner to pass through to the &quot;Northern Marathon&quot; competition. Running has become an indispensable part of Song Xinran&#39;s life. The customers who come for massage are also infected by him and start practicing running. Sometimes when talking about pace, they praise it, it’s so fast. You have bad eyesight and you can run faster than us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Story FM has also invited some blind narrators. Although everyone has their own interests and hobbies, when it comes to employment, most of them can only go for massages. In a later episode, a group of blind employees from Xiaomi in Shanghai were invited to talk about how they worked as markers and trained the AI ​​Xiao Ai classmates. A blind listener in Xi&#39;an listened to the program and kept sending messages to Kou Aizhe, telling him how the program inspired him. Kou Aizhe witnessed his changes little by little. The latest news was that he came to report good news: Xiaomi was recruiting blind people to do similar work in Xi&#39;an, and he successfully applied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Listening to strangers’ stories sometimes has such a direct impact on the audience that they respond in their own lives. As the popularity of the program increased, Dameng discovered that many listeners regarded Genius Catcher FM as a career guide. A program by a space organizer inspired several listeners to start engaging in related work. A person passed the police civil service examination and sent a private message saying that he was not a police major. After listening to the program, he yearned for the honor and experience of this profession and had a belief. I was so moved and frightened that I turned on the program and listened to it again, &quot;Don&#39;t say anything nonsense.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let different people &quot;penetrate each other&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye likes to listen to podcasts in the shower and while commuting. Chatting podcasts rank first in her mind. “They are the kind where the host is chatting, and you listen and feel like you can join in, so you can’t help but join in the discussion.” One time while commuting, she heard something funny, stopped and stamped her feet on the street, laughing loudly. Life seemed to have a different color because her ears were plugged and she couldn&#39;t hear the sounds outside. At that moment, she felt happy and contented, &quot;This is my world.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When operating an excavator, if the construction site is large enough, has a good view, and the work is not too tight, Wang Chunyan will turn on the stereo and listen to something. Only in the one-square-meter cab of the excavator can she have some time of her own. The rest of the time belongs to others. &quot;Coming home is like fighting a war.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan also plays Douyin. Among the bloggers she follows, there are many ideological bloggers, but she believes that &quot;Douyin is just a kind of fast food, and the real nutritious meal is podcasts.&quot; Podcasts arouse her deep understanding. There is more to think about than short videos. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A podcast episode is usually tens of minutes long, or even as long as two or three hours. Unlike short videos and other content, Dameng pointed out that the main value that podcasts, long-form content that focuses on reality, can bring to listeners is &quot;companionship and recognition.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He interviewed the founders of transgender groups, social workers who helped female domestic workers, and niche professional or hobby groups, trying to reflect the situation of a group of people through their narration of their fate and experiences, and make many people who originally felt People who are very lonely are no longer so lonely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In podcasts where amateurs tell stories, the narrator’s expressive ability is not that important. Dameng believes that the value of stories to people, the scarcity of information, and the desire of guests to share are all more important than the ability to express themselves. Kou Aizhe bluntly said that the so-called ability to express well is actually a privilege. What Story FM wants to do is to break it rather than strengthen it. &quot;Those who are not so eloquent in expression have very good stories and very good experiences, but It is a pity to remain silent.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寇爱哲采访过一个投稿人，是流水线上的女工，多年来，她尝试把孩子带在身边，与自己一同在城市里生活，结果处处碰壁，后来，她也试图回家乡找份工作，但家乡没有好工作，无法养活家庭，给孩子更好的生活。虽然她的受教育水平不高，表达也质朴无华，却令许多一线城市中产家庭父母产生共鸣，父母对子女的爱与付出、养育孩子过程中的纠结，是共通的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我不希望大家非常单一地、用某个标签去评价一个人，这可能是我的故事想要表现出来的东西。”寇爱哲想通过播客，让不同阶级或者阶层的人“彼此穿透”，了解各自的生活是什么样的，多一分理解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪春艳曾怀揣着好奇听完了“5000万相亲局的背后，亿万富豪还相信爱情吗”这期节目。她得出结论，“本身我们作为一个人基本的特征，追求的也就是真心和真诚，不管他是千万富翁也好，平民老百姓也好。&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“短视频也好，或者是短的一些帖子、图文内容，我们很快就会收获一个结论，但是在播客里面，就可以跟着亲历者，重新回溯这个人的成长、这个人的经历，就会发现每件事、每个人的背后都是复杂的。”大猛对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“你只看见我这一面就好”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;宋新然的播客被队长转发到了跑团群里，队友们夸赞他，讲的故事特别真实，希望以后还能听到他亲口讲述的故事。他在播客里还提到自己和女友相识相爱的过程，两人在跑团共同训练，逐渐产生感情。表白那天，他拥抱了女友，群里有人听见后揶揄，“现在的年轻人，胆子可真大，我们那时候可不敢那样。”女友听了节目，也嗔怪宋新然把他俩的事“说得那么直白”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小叶给身边友人听自己那期节目，有几个半生不熟的朋友，在微信上向她发送很长的小作文，中心思想是安慰与夸奖，“给我整得特别不好意思”。小叶最爱问听过的朋友，你听哭了吗&lt;span>;？ &lt;/span>;对方说哭了，小叶便觉得“可以，有一种赚到了的感觉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪春艳对于录播客这件事很低调，女儿是她唯一的分享对象。汪春艳陪同丈夫在浙江住院那三年，女儿被送回湖北老家，读小学的她遭到校园霸凌，得了抑郁症，一直比较叛逆，很少与父母交流。汪春艳不知道女儿听后的具体感受，因为她没说什么，隔了一天才和自己联系。只是从那之后，女儿开始愿意和汪春艳聊天，关心也变多了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;柬埔寨之行，小叶对包括母亲在内的亲人只字未提，自然也没有让他们知晓自己录的播客。父亲，本就是小叶和母亲心照不宣避开谈论的话题，小叶也不希望让母亲知道自己去了柬埔寨：“一方面因为她有点控制欲，我大部分时间还是在演着一个比较听话的女儿，对于这种大的事我都会尽量倾听她的意见。她之前很严肃地跟我说不希望我去，但是我出于自己的倔强，还是去了。还有我也不是很想她知道在柬埔寨还有一位女士跟我爸生活，不想让她离开我爸这么久，还要因为我爸的事情思来想去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，小叶又有些期待母亲能发现这件事，说不定两人会因此更敞开去谈。小叶决意不主动告诉她，而录播客就像埋下了一个线索，也许她会寻到，也许成为永远的秘密。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;故事FM2022年请制作人们进行“年终总结”。其中一位制作人提到自己在制作一期节目时，本来被受访者的一段自白打动不已，都想到要把这段话作为节目结尾了，受访者却接着问：“怎么样，我这么说还挺能调动听众情绪的吧？”制作人忽然意识到，就算是如此追求纪实的采访，也往往只是将某个人生命中的片段放大，所以想提醒听众：别那么在意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;节目刚播出的几天，小叶留意了评论。看见有人说好想关注小叶微博，她心想，千万别关注。 “你听我的故事，这是我的一面，但是如果你真的关注我的生活，就是另一面。人本身就是多面的，你只看见我这一面就好，我不想全方位无死角地展现在大众面前，我不喜欢这样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;播客凝结了他们的一小部分人生记忆，而真实的生活仍在继续，远比被讲述的故事复杂得多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汪春艳在节目里说，自己当时在菩萨面前许愿，如果丈夫醒过来，自己愿意给他一半的寿命，只活到50岁。还有几年就到这个岁数了，她希望能去旅行，为自己活一把。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现实里的汪春艳，在热情、勇敢之外，另有一层被境遇打磨出的清醒与冷峻。她认为，“世上的事情看多了，活那么多也没有什么用，活50岁就够了。”去精神病院看望姐姐，对方已经不认得她了，需要别人递水递饭才会进食，她想，那种状态下，维持姐姐的寿命又起到什么作用呢，只是让自己这个亲人心安而已。她将《红楼梦》读了不知多少遍，对人生空幻之感，毫不陌生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;采访最后，她忽然询问南方周末记者，骨髓捐赠（即造血干细胞捐赠的俗称）对于捐赠者的健康会否有影响，她申请过志愿捐献造血干细胞，最近与一个病人初配型成功，但女儿不同意。如果不会影响她干活，她还是希望出一份力：“一个生命等着，不去挽救，也太残忍了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中小叶、三条为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[最高法发布国家公园司法保护典型案例]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258840]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;国家公园是我国最重要的自然生态空间，是自然生态系统中最重要、自然景观最独特、自然遗产最精华、生物多样性最富集的部分。建立国家公园体制，是习近平总书记亲自谋划、亲自部署、亲自推动的“国之大者”。党的十八大以来，以习近平同志为核心的党中央站在实现中华民族永续发展的战略高度，作出一系列重大战略部署，推进建立国家公园体制，加快建设以国家公园为主体的自然保护地体系，切实加大自然生态保护力度。2021年10月12日，习近平主席在《生物多样性公约》第十五次缔约方大会领导人峰会上宣布，我国正式设立三江源、大熊猫、东北虎豹、海南热带雨林、武夷山等第一批国家公园，标志着国家公园这项重大创新制度落地生根，国家公园建设迈入新台阶。2022年11月，我国出台《国家公园空间布局方案》，明确了国家公园创建设立工作流程、主要建设任务和实施保障措施，遴选出49个国家公园候选区，擘画了构建全世界最大国家公园体系的宏伟蓝图。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;高质量建设国家公园，是我国生态文明制度建设的重要内容，对于推进自然资源科学保护和合理利用，促进人与自然和谐共生，推进美丽中国建设，具有极其重要的意义。近年来，人民法院始终坚持以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，深入践行习近平法治思想、习近平生态文明思想，深入贯彻落实能动司法理念，坚持为大局服务、为人民司法，依法妥善审理涉及国家公园的环境污染防治、生态保护修复、&lt;/span>;资源开发利用等各类环境资源案件，努力推动我国国家公园高水平保护高质量发展。为加强国家公园法治宣传，培养国家公园文化，传播国家公园理念，彰显人民法院保护国家公园取得的成效，最高人民法院发布系列国家公园司法保护典型案例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本次发布十件典型案例，具有以下亮点。一是涉及诉讼种类多、保护范围广。本批典型案例包括环境资源刑事、民事及公益诉讼等不同诉讼类型，涵盖了环境资源审判领域的主要范围；涉及的国家公园既有三江源、大&lt;span>;熊猫、东北虎豹、海南热带雨林、武夷山等五个首批设立的国家公园，还有列入《国家公园空间布局方案》遴选的国家公园候选区的钱江源-&lt;/span>;百山祖国家公园，体现了人民法院审理涉国家公园保护的案件诉讼种类多、保护国家公园范围广的特点。二是坚持能动司法。案例五王某民等六人滥伐林木、危害国家重点保护植物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案，及案例九张某彦、张某怡诉洋县林业局生命权纠纷案，人民法院对于审判中发现的国家公园管理方面的漏洞短板，没有机械司法、一判了之，而是积极延伸环境资源审判职能，主动融入生态文明建设进程，向行政主管部门发出司法建议，督促有关部门查漏补缺，是能动司法的生动实践。三是坚持一体化保护、系统治理理念。案例三杨某等三人污染环境案，体现了人民法院加强对大熊猫国家公园毗邻区域环境污染行为的治理；案例四李某华等十一人危害珍贵、濒危野生动物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案，人民法院对危害珍贵、濒危野生动物犯罪的“猎捕-收购-运输-销售”环节进行全链条打击，是一体化保护、系统治理的生动实践。四是坚持最严法治原则。案例一&lt;span>;郑某成、高某进、叶某东非法采矿案，对于非法开采国家战略性资源的行为，在法定刑幅度范围内从严处罚，并严格控制缓刑的适用，用司法利剑保障国家战略性资源的开发利用。案例七海南省人民检察院第一分院诉李某清、叶某青生态破坏民事公益诉讼案，在行为人已被另案判处刑事责任的同时，严肃追究其民事赔偿责任，体现了损害担责、最严法治的原则。案例八浙江省开化县人民检察院诉陆某燕等四人生态破坏民事公益诉讼案，对于通过录制宰杀视频验货、网络支付、邮寄交货等方式非法收购、出售野生动物行为，依法严肃惩处，彰&lt;/span>;显了以最严格制度最严密法治保护国家公园生态环境的态度。五是坚持预防性司法。案例四李某华等十一人危害珍贵、濒危野生动物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案，对于动物园经营者的犯罪人，为预防其利用从事野生动物收购、饲养、出售、运输等便利条件再实施此类犯罪，人民法院对其判处“禁止令”，体现了预防性司法理念。六是妥善处理民生、发展和保护的关系。案例二张某强非法制造枪支、非法狩猎案，对于刚刚脱贫的当地村民适用缓刑，避免刚&lt;span>;脱贫的家庭因刑返贫，较好平衡了生态环境保护和民生保障之间的关系。案例六李某良、羊某理失火、羊某理非法狩猎刑事附带民事公益诉讼案，考虑到被告经济困难，准许其通过劳务代偿的方式履行异地生态修复义务，体现了司法对民生保障的关切。案例九张某彦、张某怡诉洋县林业局生命权纠纷案，依照野生动物保护法有关规定，对野生动物造成伤亡人员的家属请求有关部门给付补偿金的诉讼请求予以支持，体现了兼顾野生动物保护与维护人民生命财产安全的双重目标。案例十青海某水电开发公司破产重整案，充分发挥审判职能作用，加强与政府相关部门的协调，促成案涉水电站全面复工，有效化解了企业破产纠纷，妥善处理了社会经济发展和生态环境保护的关系。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这十件国家公园司法保护典型案件的依法妥善审理，充分展现了人民法院发挥生态环境资源审判职能、依法保护国家公园自然生态系统的完整性和原真性、给子孙后代留下珍贵自然资产的责任担当，对维护国家生态安全，保护生物多样性，推动国家公园高水平保护高质量发展具有积极意义。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;国家公园司法保护典型案例&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;一、郑某成、高某进、叶某东非法采矿案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;二、张某强非法制造枪支、非法狩猎案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;三、杨某等三人污染环境案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四、李某华等十一人危害珍贵、濒危野生动物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;五、王某民等六人滥伐林木、危害国家重点保护植物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;六、李某良、羊某理失火，羊某理非法狩猎刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;七、海南省人民检察院第一分院诉李某清、叶某青生态破坏民事公益诉讼案&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;八、浙江省开化县人民检察院诉陆某燕等四人生态破坏民事公益诉讼案&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;九、张某彦、张某怡诉洋县林业局生命权纠纷案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;十、青海某水电开发公司破产重整案&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;一、郑某成、高某进、叶某东非法采矿案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;被告人郑某成与他人共同承包位于福建省光泽县鸾凤乡某山场的林地，该山场位于武夷山国家公园范围内。郑某成与被告人高某进系朋友关系，二人预谋在该山场合伙开采稀土牟利。2016年9月至2017年5月期间，郑某成、高某进组织冯某安、钟某明（均另案处理）和被告人叶某东等人在无采矿许可证的情况下，到该山场采用在山体打溶洞注入硫酸铵等，再对析出液体进行沉淀的方式开采稀土矿，现场查获疑似稀土半成品9300千克。经鉴定，案涉稀土矿均属离子吸附型稀土，属国家规定实行保护性开采的特定矿种，郑某成等人非法开采行为还造成稀土矿点矿产资源破坏。此外，另查明叶某东于2018年3月与他人因琐事争执并打斗，犯有故意伤害致人轻伤的犯罪事实。福建省光泽县以郑某成、高某进、叶某东犯非法采矿罪，叶某东犯故意伤害罪提起公诉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;福建省光泽县人民法院经审理认为，被告人郑某成、高某进、叶某东等人违反矿产资源法的规定，无采矿许可证擅自开采国家实行保护性开采的特定矿种离子吸附型稀土矿，情节特别严重，已构成非法采矿罪。郑某成、高某进是主犯，叶某东是从犯。遂以非法采矿罪分别判处郑某成、高某进有期徒刑四年九个月，并处罚金15万元；以非法采矿罪、故意伤害罪，数罪并罚，判处叶某东有期徒刑三年，并处罚金10万元；扣押在案的稀土半成品予以没收。宣判后，被告人高某进不服，提出上诉。福建省南平市中级人民法院二审裁定：驳回上诉，维持原判。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;武夷山国家公园是我国目前唯一一个既是世界人与生物圈保护区，又是世界文化与自然双遗产的国家公园，储有众多不可再生的宝贵矿产资源。其中的稀土是我国的重要战略资源，是新兴产业、高端制造业、现代国防科技工业的关键元素。近年来，武夷山国家公园周边地区出现了非法开采稀土的犯罪行为，损害国家稀土资源储备，严重威胁国家公园环境资源安全。本案被告人以原地浸矿法开采稀土矿，危害到武夷山国家公园的生态服务功能和生态系统稳定性，容易导致植被破坏、山体裸露、水源污染、水土流失、山体滑坡、地面裂缝和沉降等严重后果发生。人民法院在开采的矿产品价值和造成矿产资源破坏的价值均已查明的情况下，以造成矿产资源破坏的价值认定被告人非法采矿行为情节特别严重，依法严厉惩处非法开采稀土犯罪，在法定刑幅度范围内从严处罚，并严格控制缓刑的适用，有利于保障国家战略性资源的开发利用，守护国家公园生态安全。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;二、张某强非法制造枪支、非法狩猎案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2017年期间，被告人张某强到海南省海口市某五金店购买一把射钉枪、一根枪管及铁砂、射钉弹后，使用其自有工具组装枪型物1支。经鉴定，张某强制造的枪型物为利用火药为发射动力的枪支。2022年3月21日凌晨，张某强在未经野生动物行政主管部门许可，且无狩猎证和持枪证的情况下，擅自进入被划为禁猎区的海南热带雨林国家公园霸王岭分局洪水管护站内狩猎，使用枪支共猎捕赤腹松鼠3只、椰子猫1只、鼬獾1只，使用头照灯照射猎捕大绿臭蛙30只。张某强于次日下山途中被公安民警当场抓获。经鉴定，案涉椰子猫属国家二级保护野生动物，鼬獾、赤腹松鼠均被列入《国家保护的有益的或者有重要经济、科学研究价值的陆生野生动物名录》，臭蛙属于海南省重点保护陆生野生动物。海南省人民检察院第二分院以张某强犯非法制造枪支、非法狩猎罪提起公诉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;海南省第二中级人民法院经审理认为，张某强行为已构成非法制造枪支罪、非法狩猎罪，应当数罪并罚。张某强作为生活在国家公园范围区刚脱贫的村民，改变当地的传统生产生活方式，走绿色发展改善民生之路，尚需探索时间。张某强是家中主要劳动力，对其羁押既不符合刑法谦抑性原则，也可能使其家庭重返贫困。法律的权威在于刑罚的不可避免性，而非严苛，在能使用较轻刑罚达到制裁目的时，无需使用严厉的制裁方式。鉴于张某强系初犯，案发后如实供述其罪行，认罪认罚且有悔罪表现，其居住地愿意配合进行社区矫正，宣告缓刑对所居住社区没有重大不良影响。遂判决：张某强数罪并罚，决定执行有期徒刑三年，缓刑五年，没收犯罪工具等。宣判后，各方未上诉、抗诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年4月，习近平总书记在海南考察调研时明确指出热带雨林国家公园是国宝，是水库、粮库、钱库，更是碳库，要求对热带雨林实行严格保护，实现生态保护、绿色发展、民生改善相统一。尽管海南热带雨林国家公园建设过程中对环境资源保护的力度不断加大，国家公园附近的原住村民对热带雨林及生物多样性资源的损害性利用仍时有发生。本案中，被告人违反狩猎法规，在禁猎区使用改造的枪支及其它工具狩猎，破坏野生动物资源的价值较大，应当受到刑事制裁。同时，人民法院充分考虑被告人的个体因素，给予其改过自新的机会，对其适用缓刑，避免刚脱贫的家庭因刑返贫，彰显司法的人文关怀，实现了惩罚和预防犯罪相结合的目的，也较好平衡了生态环境保护和民生保障之间的关系。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;三、杨某等三人污染环境案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2020年6月至9月，被告人杨某、屈某敏、高某虎在未取得危险废物经营许可证、未采取地面防护措施的情况下，在毗邻大熊猫国家公园保护区域的四川省绵阳市安州区花荄镇某村的山林中，利用破碎机等设备对14.53吨废机油格进行破碎处置，分离出废铁和废发动机油并销售。三被告人销售废铁非法获利26450元、销售废发动机油非法获利6000余元。经绵阳市生态环境局认定，案涉废机油格为含有或沾染废发动机油的过滤吸附介质，被列入《国家危险废物名录》，废物类别HW49，废物代码900-041-49，属于危险废物。经评估，案涉地块土壤中石油烃的最高浓度为3080mg/Kg，超过《土壤环境质量建设用地土壤污染风险管控标准（试行）》（GB36600-2018）表1中第一类用地筛选值，确定该地块存在石油烃污染，此次违法生产行为对该地块的土壤生态环境造成了损害。三被告人均投案自首，自愿认罪认罚且签字具结，并主动退缴违法所得3.3万元。四川省绵阳市安州区人民检察院以污染环境罪对杨某、屈某敏、高某虎提起公诉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四川省绵阳市安州区人民法院经审理认为，杨某、屈某敏、高某虎违反国家规定，非法处置危险废物，严重污染环境，构成污染环境罪。三被告人系共同犯罪，犯罪作用相当，不区分主从犯；三被告人主动投案并如实供述自己的罪行，系自首，依法可以从轻或减轻处罚；三被告人自愿认罪认罚，可从宽处理；三被告人主动退缴全部违法所得，可酌情从轻处罚。遂判决：杨某、屈某敏、高某虎有期徒刑各九个月、缓刑各一年，并分别处以罚金1.5万元，没收三人违法所得3.3万元（已追缴）。宣判后，各方未上诉、抗诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;森林土壤是发展林业生产的物质基础。近年来，部分不法分子受利益驱使，侵占山场林地，非法回收废机油、倾倒有毒有害物质，对林地土壤及其附作物造成严重破坏，打破森林的生态平衡，损害公共利益。本案案发地毗邻大熊猫国家公园保护区域，由于废机油污染介质具有流动性、迁移性，因此针对废机油导致的环境污染事件，不应仅以国家公园边界为准，而需要对国家公园毗邻区域全方位一体化保护。本案中，人民法院依法惩处污染环境的犯罪行为，全面加强环境资源保护力度，坚守人与自然和谐共生，践行绿水青山就是金山银山理念，为加快形成绿色发展方式，促进经济发展和环境保护双赢提供法治保障。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;四、李某华等十一人危害珍贵、濒危野生动物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2019年以来，被告人李某华多次联系被告人龙某军猎捕野生小熊猫活体。2019年至2020年4月期间，龙某军将其自己捕获的野生小熊猫活体15只出售给李某华及被告人李某秋（李某华之子）；李某华父子将其中14只运至山东莱州、江苏南京等地，向被告人刘某甲出售2只，向其他三名动物园经营者（另案处理）共出售10只，非法获利29万元。2020年11月至12月期间，龙某军从被告人高某林处收购4只野生小熊猫活体后，将其中1只耳朵有缺陷的野生小熊猫放生，将3只小熊猫驾车运至四川省泸定县，李某华父子及被告人刘某乙驾车从泸定购得该3只小熊猫后返回途中被公安机关查获。2020年4月以来，李某华父子到四川省平武县锁江羌族乡从被告人马某曹处收购金丝猴活体18只；其中13只，由李某华父子二人雇佣被告人张某华、刘某乙运输至安徽铜陵出售给经营动物园的被告人徐某珍、沈某等人，非法获利56万元。经鉴定，案涉小熊猫均为国家二级保护野生动物，单只价值为4万元；金丝猴均为川金丝猴，系国家一级保护野生动物，单只价值为50万元。雅安市人民检察院以危害珍贵、濒危野生动物罪对李某华等十一人提起公诉，并提起附带民事公益诉讼，诉请李某华、李某秋、刘某甲、龙某军赔偿死亡的野生小熊猫11只公益赔偿金共计44万元，李某华、李某秋、马某曹赔偿死亡的野生金丝猴1只公益赔偿金50万元，李某华等十一名被告共同在媒体公开赔礼道歉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;四川省雅安市中级人民法院经审理认为，李某华等人非法猎捕、出售、收购、运输国家重点保护的珍贵、濒危野生动物的行为，均构成危害珍贵、濒危野生动物罪。其中李某华、李某秋非法收购、运输、出售国家一级保护野生动物川金丝猴18只，国家二级保护野生动物小熊猫18只，野生动物价值共计972万元，属情节特别严重，综合考虑李某华具有累犯、坦白等情形，李某秋具有立功等情节，判处李某华有期徒刑十四年并处罚金50万元、李某秋有期徒刑八年并处罚金30万元。马某曹非法猎捕、出售国家一级保护野生动物川金丝猴18只，野生动物价值900万元，属情节特别严重；综合考虑其系自首等情节，判处马某曹有期徒刑十一年并处罚金30万元。判处其余被告人有期徒刑三年至六年不等，并处罚金5万元至25万元不等。对于动物园经营者刘某甲、徐某珍，并处自刑罚执行完毕之日或者假释之日起五年内禁止从事与野生动物有关的一切经营性活动。判令民事公益诉讼被告李某华、李某秋、刘某甲、龙某军共同赔偿公益赔偿金44万元，李某华、李某秋、马某曹共同赔偿公益赔偿金50万元，李某华等十一人在媒体公开赔礼道歉。宣判后，马某曹等部分被告人不服提起上诉，四川省高级人民法院审理后裁定驳回上诉，维持原判。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案案发地之一的四川省绵阳市平武县，是大熊猫国家公园的核心区，素有“天下大熊猫第一县”的美誉。大熊猫国家公园对于加强大熊猫及其伞护的其他物种和典型生态脆弱区整体保护，打造国家重要生态屏障具有重要意义。本案中，被告人在大熊猫国家公园内猎捕国家重点保护野生动物用于销售，已经形成了危害珍贵、濒危野生动物犯罪的“猎捕-收购-运输-销售”完整产业链，且以民营动物园为链条终端，通过动物园收购和再次交易将野生动物“洗白”，严重破坏大熊猫国家公园内自然生态系统的原真性、完整性和系统性。本案部分被告人身为动物园经营者，具有从事野生动物收购、饲养、出售、运输等便利，其明知收购、运输珍贵、濒危野生动物必须按照法定程序审批，却为追求经济利益而利用其职业便利实施非法收购、运输野生动物犯罪，已严重违背职业道德和从业义务，为预防其再实施此类犯罪，人民法院对其判处“禁止令”，禁止犯罪人再次从事野生动物经营，体现了打击和预防犯罪并重，以最严法治守护国家公园生态安全的决心。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;五、王某民等六人滥伐林木、危害国家重点保护植物刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2022年2月，被告人王某民以其妻名义与案外人乔某某签订《林权林地转让合同书》，受让位于吉林省图们市凉水镇某村林地3785亩的林地使用权、林木所有权。同年4月，王某民使用案外人王某的身份证申请办理了林木采伐许可证，采伐地点为凉水林场的三个伐区，批准采伐总蓄积456 立方米，树种为柞树。同年4月至5月期间，王某民雇佣被告人张某奎组织多人进场作业，被告人沙某、刘某军、徐某仁等负责采伐，被告人杨某负责归楞、装车。王某民等人实际伐木区域除了上述经批准的三个伐区外，还包括未经批准的楞场东侧伐区等三个伐区，性质为集体林区或国有林区；砍伐树木包括柞树、杨树、紫椴等。经鉴定，王某民等人违反林木采伐许可的树种、数量和采伐方式，非法采伐柞树、杨树等林木立木蓄积1438立方米价值131万余元；采伐国家二级保护植物紫椴485株，立木蓄积257立方米，价值23万余元。吉林省珲春林区人民检察院以滥伐林木罪、危害国家重点保护植物罪就上述行为提起公诉；并对王某民等六被告提起附带民事公益诉讼，诉请：王某民承担修复生态环境综合费用156万余元，沙某、张某奎、杨某对此承担连带责任，刘某军、徐某仁对其中14万元承担连带责任，六被告共同承担鉴定费用5千元。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;吉林省珲春林区基层法院经审理认为，王某民、沙某等六人违反林木采伐许可证规定数量、树种和采伐方式，任意采伐林木，数量巨大，其行为构成滥伐林木罪。王某民、沙某违反国家规定，故意采伐国家重点保护植物紫椴，情节严重，构成危害国家重点保护植物罪。对王某民、沙某应当以滥伐林木罪和危害国家重点保护植物罪实行数罪并罚。王某民等六人犯罪行为严重破坏生态环境、危及生物多样性保护，使社会公共利益受到严重损害，应承担民事侵权责任。遂判处：王某民等六人二年至七年不等的有期徒刑，并处1万元至120万元不等的罚金；王某民承担修复生态环境综合费用156万余元，沙某、张某奎、杨某对此承担连带责任，刘某军、徐某仁对其中14万元承担连带责任，鉴定费用5千元由六被告共同承担。宣判后，各方未上诉、抗诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案系发生在东北虎豹国家公园范围内滥伐林木及危害国家重点保护植物的案件。东北虎豹国家公园内优质的森林资源和完整的生物链为东北虎、豹等珍稀野生动物提供了良好的生态家园。随着国家公园保护力度的加大，近年来，几十年不见的东北虎、豹重回故里繁衍生息。紫椴有“象牙板”和“世界四大行道树”的美称，具有较大的药用、欣赏和经济价值，属于国家濒危保护物种以及国家二级保护野生植物。本案中，人民法院依法对滥伐林木行为和故意采伐国家重点保护植物行为予以数罪并罚，加大对破坏森林资源犯罪的惩治和震慑力度；同时判令行为人赔偿生态环境修复费用，对保护东北虎豹栖息地生物多样性和生态系统安全具有积极作用。本案裁判后，人民法院践行能动司法理念，立足东北虎豹国家公园生态资源管护实际，向有关部门发出司法建议，推动形成国家公园保护的强大合力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;六、李某良、羊某理失火、羊某理非法狩猎刑事附带民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;被告人李某良与羊某理相约到山林内熏蜂采摘野生蜂蜜，并将该过程录制视频用于蜂蜜出售。2021年4月1日，李某良、羊某理到海南热带雨林国家公园管护站内汇合，并携带打火机、铁桶、摄像机等工具步行上山寻找蜂蜜。后李某良在点燃火把熏蜂过程中，不慎将蜂窝周围的茅草引燃。李某良一边扑火，一边喊羊某理帮忙救火。羊某理发现火势正在向其所在位置燃烧便逃离现场，李某良见状也逃离现场。经鉴定，本次森林火灾过火面积为90亩（均为有林地），系一级保护林地（重点公益林），火烧林木的树种为松树和天然阔叶树。羊某理、李某良被抓获归案后，羊某理如实供述了公安机关尚未掌握的本人非法狩猎罪的犯罪行为。海南省人民检察院第二分院以李某良、羊某理犯失火罪，以羊某理另犯非法狩猎罪提起公诉；并对二人提起附带民事公益诉讼，诉请：羊某理、李某良按照生态环境修复方案共同对被毁损的90亩林地进行异地修复，或者连带承担修复费用26.7万元（通过支付费用或劳务代偿等方式履行），连带赔偿被毁林地生态环境受到损害至修复完成期间服务功能丧失造成的损失698736元、本案鉴定及修复方案编制费用3万元。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;海南省第二中级人民法院经审理认为，李某良、羊某理违反森林保护及森林防火法规，熏蜂采蜜造成森林火灾，使公私财产遭受重大损失，构成失火罪。羊某理违反狩猎法规，在禁猎区内使用禁用工具、方法进行狩猎，破坏野生动物资源，情节严重，构成非法狩猎罪。李某良、羊某理失火行为大量烧毁林木，对当地林业资源及生态环境造成严重损害，应承担相应的民事责任。遂判处羊某理数罪并罚，决定执行有期徒刑一年六个月，李某良有期徒刑一年二个月；判令李某良、羊某理连带承担异地修复费用26.7万元（通过支付费用或劳务代偿等方式履行）、生态服务功能损失鉴定及修复方案编制费用3万元，连带赔偿被毁林地生态环境受到损害至修复完成期间服务功能丧失造成的损失698736元。宣判后，各方未上诉、抗诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案系发生在海南热带雨林国家公园范围内的一起刑事附带民事公益诉讼案件。海南热带雨林国家公园面积占全国国土面积的比例不足0.046%，但拥有全国约20%的两栖类、33%的爬行类、38.6%的鸟类和20%的兽类野生动物资源，其中属于国家重点保护野生动物的有145种，属于海南省特有野生动物的有23种，有着极其重要的生物多样性价值。保护好海南热带雨林国家公园的良好生态环境，是人民法院环境资源审判工作的重要使命。本案中，人民法院依法严肃打击对热带雨林生态平衡有严重影响的失火、非法狩猎犯罪行为的同时，判令侵权人依法承担生态赔偿责任，践行了生态环境保护领域的最严法治原则。此外，考虑到被告经济困难，准许其通过劳务代偿的方式履行异地生态修复义务，既体现了司法对民生保障的关切，也有助于判决内容的实际履行，帮助被告改变其固有的“靠山吃山、靠海吃海”思想，有利于带动周边亲友转变生产生活方式，实现人与自然的和谐共生。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;七、海南省人民检察院第一分院诉李某清、叶某青生态破坏民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2020年1月起，被告李某清、叶某青未经行政许可，陆续雇人砍伐位于海南热带雨林国家公园范围内的海南省黎母山林场鹦哥傲分站内一条土路两旁的马占树，砍伐过程中还毁坏了两株桫椤树。后两人把砍伐的马占树拉走出售得款18450元。经鉴定，被伐林木地块为二级保护林地，森林类别为省级公益林，林种为防护林；被伐林木立木蓄积量171立方米；被毁坏的两株桫椤树为国家二级保护植物大桫椤；被伐林木造成生态服务功能损失总价值74902.95元/年，案涉造林修复投资经概算为49501.8元。上述鉴定评估费用3万元。李某清因犯盗伐林木罪被另案判处有期徒刑四年六个月。海南省人民检察院第一分院就李某清、叶某青的盗伐林木行为提起生态破坏民事公益诉讼，诉请：李某清、叶某青连带承担因盗伐林木造成的生态服务功能损失费用149805.9元、生态环境损害修复费用49501.8元、鉴定评估费用3万元。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;海南省第一中级人民法院经审理认为，李某清、叶某青的侵权行为对林场生态环境造成了损害，应对造成的生态环境损害承担相应民事责任。遂判决：李某清、叶某青连带赔偿因盗伐林木造成的生态服务功能损失费用149805.9元、生态环境损害修复费用49501.8元，连带承担本案生态环境损害鉴定评估费用3万元。宣判后，各方均未上诉，一审判决已发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;涉案黎母山林区位于海南岛中部，为海南热带雨林国家公园的重要组成部分。本案被告在国家公园范围内的重点保护区砍伐毁坏林木的数量大，致使天然林生态系统的完整性、生物多样性、水土保持等生态功能和价值减损，破坏热带雨林的生态环境，损害社会公共利益。人民法院判令侵权人对生态资源损失进行赔偿，加大行为人的违法成本，有力震慑潜在违法行为的发生，有利于营造全民保护热带雨林资源、维护美好生态环境的社会氛围，也向社会公众传递了人民法院打击破坏生态环境行为、高质量护航国家公园建设的态度。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;八、浙江省开化县人民检察院诉陆某燕等四人生态破坏民事公益诉讼案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;被告陆某燕、徐某系夫妻，二人在浙江省开化县某农贸市场经营一家野味店。2018年11月，开化县森林公安局接到公益志愿者举报后，在二人仓库内当场查获并扣押疑似白鹇3只、野猪11只、野兔42只、黄麂23只。经查，2017年12月底，被告王某经由被告程某俊通过微信联系徐某购买猫头鹰1只，并通过录制宰杀视频验货、邮寄交付等方式完成交货，后由王某送给朋友食用。经鉴定，案涉3只疑似白鹇为白鹇，属国家二级保护动物；猫头鹰为雕鸮，属国家二级保护动物。经评估，陆某燕非法收购、销售珍贵、濒危野生动物和非法收购其他野生动物的行为对生态环境资源造成损害价值107860元，其中徐某共同参与的非法收购、销售珍贵、濒危野生动物和非法收购其他野生动物的行为造成损害价值97860元；程某俊、王某的非法收购珍贵、濒危野生动物行为对生态环境资源造成损害价值为1.5万元。陆某燕、徐某、王某、程某俊四人被另案追究刑事责任。浙江省开化县人民检察院以徐某等四人为被告提起民事公益诉讼，诉请：陆某燕支付生态环境和资源损害赔偿款107860元，徐某对其中97860元承担连带赔偿责任，程某俊、王某各自分别对其中的1.5万元承担连带赔偿责任；四被告在媒体上赔礼道歉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;浙江省衢州市中级人民法院经审理认为，陆某燕、徐某共同经营野味店的过程中非法收购、出售国家重点保护野生动物和没有合法来源证明的非国家重点保护野生动物，王某、程某俊为食用目的非法收购国家重点保护野生动物，四被告行为对生态环境和资源造成损害，应当承担侵权责任。其中，陆某燕就案涉全部事实承担责任，应支付生态环境和资源损害赔偿款107860元；徐某对其中97860元与陆某燕承担连带赔偿责任；王某、程某俊对其中1.5万元与陆某燕、徐某承担连带赔偿责任。遂判决支持了公益诉讼起诉人的全部诉讼请求。该判决已经发生法律效力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案发生在钱江源-百山祖国家公园钱江源园区，系由非法收购、出售国家重点保护野生动物引发的生态破坏民事公益诉讼案件。钱江源-百山祖国家公园于2016年被纳入国家公园体制试点，是《国家公园空间布局方案》遴选出的49个候选国家公园之一。钱江源-百山祖国家公园钱江源园区完整地保存着全球稀有的、大面积的中亚热带低海拔原生常绿阔叶林，被誉为“长江三角洲的最后一块生态处女地”，也是诸多珍贵、濒危野生动物的最后“基因保护地”。本案中被侵害野生动物中白鹇和雕鸮均为珍稀鸟类，属国家二级保护动物。白鹇作为明清时期五品官服的图案，是清廉、正直的象征，具有极佳的观赏性和文化蕴意。四被告非法收购、出售野生动物，通过录制宰杀视频验货、网络支付、邮寄交货等方式，企图逃避监管和追责，是为牟取一己私利对大自然的过度攫取。人民法院依法判令四被告支付生态环境和资源损害赔偿款并赔礼道歉，在刑事追责之外挽回生态损失，彰显了以最严格制度最严密法治保护国家公园生态环境的决心，警示国家公园区域内人员依法依规开展经营活动，促进现代文明与原始生态和谐交融，共建共享人与自然和谐共生的国家公园。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;九、张某彦、张某怡诉洋县林业局生命权纠纷案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2017年3月18日，巡山人员发现，陕西省汉中市洋县茅坪镇朝阳村十二组村民郑某海死于朝阳村十二组小河沟路边。经洋县公安局勘查检验、洋县林业局调查确认，郑某海系被国家一级保护动物羚牛致伤身亡。后洋县林业局、财政局联合向汉中市林业局、财政局上报，请求按照《陕西省重点保护陆生野生动物造成人身财产损害补偿办法》（以下简称《补偿办法》）及其实施细则规定，对郑某海的死亡予以补偿资金187820元（全省2016年度农民人均纯收入9396元×20倍），其中省级财政分担150336元，市、县级财政各分担18792元。2018年12月12日，汉中市财政局对郑某海被羚牛致伤身亡的省级财政负担资金150336元划拨到位。因郑某海亲属对补偿金的分配未达成一致意见，补偿金未予兑付。郑某海的父母已亡故，郑某海生前与前妻育有两个女儿即张某彦、张某怡。张某彦、张某怡遂以生命权纠纷为由提起诉讼，诉请洋县林业局赔偿损失216933元。审理中，双方对补偿金额187820元均无异议，洋县林业局亦认可二原告系死者郑某海的第一顺序法定继承人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;陕西省汉中市洋县人民法院经审理认为，《补偿办法》第二、八、九条规定，经县级以上人民政府林业行政主管部门确认，在本省行政区域内，国家和省重点保护陆生野生动物造成人身伤害或财产损失符合规定情形的，受害人有依照本办法取得政府补偿的权利；造成死亡的，给予一次性损害补偿（含丧葬补助费），标准为全省上年度农民人均纯收入的20倍；人身财产损害补偿费由省级财政负担80%，设区市、县级财政各负担10%。据此，二原告作为郑某海之女，有权利依法向政府申请补偿。洋县林业局作为洋县人民政府的林业行政主管单位，应按照《补偿办法》规定履行法定义务。遂判决：洋县林业局向张某彦、张某怡支付省级财政已划拨到位的150336元补偿金；市、县级财政各分担的18792元补偿金，由洋县林业局向财政主管部门申报后支付；驳回原告其他诉讼请求。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案系一起发生在大熊猫国家公园区域内的国家保护野生动物致人死亡引发的纠纷案件。羚牛是国家一级保护动物，与大熊猫、朱鹮、金丝猴一并被称为“秦岭四宝”，均是生活在大熊猫国家公园的珍稀物种。随着我国生态文明建设的深入推进，野生动物栖息地和生存空间不断扩大，野生动物伤人事件时有发生。《中华人民共和国野生动物保护法》第十九条规定，因保护本法规定保护的野生动物，造成人员伤亡、农作物或者其他财产损失的，由当地人民政府给予补偿，具体办法由省级人民政府制定。本案中，人民法院参照该省补偿规定，判决被告支付相应的补偿金，较好地兼顾野生动物保护与维护人民生命财产安全的双重目标，对于构建人与自然和谐共生的良好生态环境具有积极意义。同时，人民法院及时向林业主管部门发出司法建议，督促其通过在野生动物保护区设立警示标志、在动物活跃期增强巡逻等方式，切实提高周边群众防范意识，确保周边群众的人身财产安全，也是能动司法理念在环境资源审判工作中的具体体现。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;十、青海某水电开发公司破产重整案&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【基本案情】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;青海某水电开发公司承建的黄河玛尔挡水电站是首批列入国家基础设施领域鼓励社会投资的项目，是实现西电东送的重要节点工程。该项目于2010年10月开始前期工程的建设施工，先后完成导流洞、上下游围堰等施工内容，后期由于青海某水电开发公司资金链断裂，建设资金不能按期足额到位，导致玛尔挡水电站停工，国家重点项目难以落地，移民安置陷入停滞，防汛隐患日趋严峻，庭外重组引入投资人失败后向人民法院申请破产重整。2020年6月，青海省西宁市中级人民法院依法受理青海某水电开发公司破产重整案。同年11月，某能源投资集团公司作为青海某水电开发公司破产重整战略投资人，与破产管理人签署破产重整协议。2021年4月，西宁市中级人民法院组织召开第二次债权人会议，通过了重整计划草案等文件。根据重整计划，重整投资方将继续静态投资上千亿元，打造玛尔挡“水光风一体化”综合能源基地，带动抽水蓄能、光伏、风力发电及化学储能等新能源的开发利用。青海某水电开发公司管理人申请法院批准重整计划。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【裁判结果】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;西宁市中级人民法院经审查认为，青海某水电开发公司不能清偿到期债务，且有明显丧失清偿能力的可能，对青海某水电开发公司实施破产重整，将更有利于保护债权人、债务人及企业职工的整体利益，也有利于解决项目停工造成的黄河上游干流度汛安全以及生态环境修复治理难题。本案重整计划的制作、表决程序及内容均符合法律规定，且具有可行性。遂裁定：批准青海某水电开发公司重整计划，终止重整程序。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;【典型意义】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本案水电站位于青海省海南州同德县和果洛州玛沁县交界处的黄河干流，地处三江源国家公园范围内，是国家“十二五”规划建设的重点水电项目。案涉项目停工不但对经济发展和移民安置等造成负面影响，也对黄河上游干流安全度汛以及生态修复、环境治理造成极大影响。人民法院受理并开展破产重整后，充分发挥审判职能作用，妥善处理保护和发展的关系，加强与政府相关部门的协调，促成案涉水电站全面复工，有效化解了企业破产纠纷，也使三江源国家公园内黄河上游防汛工作得到加强，因项目停工可能带来的生态环境治理困境也迎刃而解。同时，玛尔挡“水光风一体化”综合能源基地的建设，也将带动三江源国家公园周边区域能源结构优化，有利于推动当地经济社会绿色高质量发展再上新台阶。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[科技部迎来重组后首位新任党组书记：直面基础研究和“卡脖子”问题两大挑战]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258919]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/LcL9VLJobzfTjb94ZRv9w50xgtafvr2FhYc2l0Kh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;631&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/LcL9VLJobzfTjb94ZRv9w50xgtafvr2FhYc2l0Kh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254642&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日下午，科技部召开领导干部会议，宣布阴和俊任党组书记。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月10日，科技部党组书记阴和俊会见来访的英国皇家工程院院长、思克莱德大学校长吉姆·麦克唐纳德爵士一行。在科技部官网的报道中，这是阴和俊上任后的首个公开活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月7日下午，科技部召开领导干部会议，宣布阴和俊任党组书记。阴和俊的前任王志刚生于1957年，担任科技部党组书记职务11年。而2023年3月发布的国务院机构改革方案中，科技部迎来5年内第二次重组。阴和俊成为科技部重组后首位新任党组书记。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为学者型官员，阴和俊曾在高校、科研机构任职多年。多名受访专家认为，相比2018年的机构改革，此次重组后，科技部着重要解决的是基础研究和“卡脖子”问题。这也是阴和俊要直面的挑战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;多次填补科技和军工装备领域空白&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;身为二十届中央委员的阴和俊是山西古交人，生于1963年1月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1980年代，阴和俊从太原工学院（现太原理工大学）毕业后先后在太原工学院、太原工业大学工作。 1986年9月，他到西安电子科技大学攻读硕士研究生，1992年又到中国科学院电子学所攻读博士研究生。 1995年，阴和俊博士毕业后选择留在中国科学院电子学所工作，直至2015年11月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中国科学院工作的20年间，阴和俊担任过中国科学院高技术研究与发展局局长，并于2008年1月升任副院长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年11月，阴和俊转任科技部副部长，分管高新技术和国际合作。 16个月后的2017年3月，54岁的阴和俊任北京市委常委，一个月后兼任北京市副市长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，北京市政府领导向人大常委会介绍阴和俊时提到，他“熟悉科研和科技管理工作，思路比较开阔……主要从事国家重大科技专项、战略性科技先导专项、国防科技创新等方面工作……多次填补我国科技和军工装备领域空白”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到地方任职后，阴和俊负责的工作依然和科技有关，分管市科委、经信委、国资委、质监局、知识产权局、中关村管委会、经济技术开发区管委会，联系市科协、市通信管理局。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年9月，到北京工作前，阴和俊在一次演讲中提到，要“围绕拓展创新发展空间，统筹国内国际两个大局，支持北京、上海建设具有全球影响力的科技创新中心”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;担任北京市领导后，阴和俊到市科委调研时强调，要充分利用首都科技创新资源，统筹协调在京高校、科研院所、企业等各方面力量参与科技创新中心建设，推动形成协同创新的更大合力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而6年后的2023年5月26日，《北京国际科技创新中心建设情况评估报告》发布。评估认为，北京原始创新和科技源头供给能力实现了提升，在建立新型举国体制方面作出了示范性探索，“初步建成具有全球影响力的科技创新中心”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在北京一年多之后，2018年10月，阴和俊跨省转任天津市委副书记。在天津工作时，阴和俊多次提到“科技创新”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年11月，阴和俊回到中国科学院，任中国科学院党组副书记、副院长。中国科学院一国家重点实验室主任告诉南方周末记者，阴和俊非常重视国家重大科技和军工方面工作，分管重大任务局。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“中央一级的重组基本落地”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;阴和俊履新科技部5天后，2023年10月12日，中国机构编制网连发5份通知，通报工信部、生态环境部、国家卫健委、中国人民银行和中国社会科学院等的职责、机构、编制调整情况。 5份通知中，有3份和科技部相关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通知显示，将科技部的组织拟订高新技术发展及产业化规划和政策等职责划入工信部；将科技部的组织拟订科技促进生态环境发展规划和政策职责划入生态环境部；将科学技术部的组织拟订科技促进卫生健康发展规划和政策职责划入国家卫健委。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和职责一同划分到其他部门的，还有对应的人员编制。华南理工大学公共管理学院教授王福涛长期关注科技政策，在他看来，编制的调整也意味着科技部“在中央一级的重组基本落地”，“这和年初的改革方案是完全一致的”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月10日，《国务院机构改革方案》发布，强调要加强科学技术等六个重点领域的机构职责优化和调整。方案提到了具体的十三项细分工作，其中，“重新组建科学技术部”为十三项工作之首。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月16日，《党和国家机构改革方案》公布，表示要组建中央科技委员会，方案强调，中央科技委员会办事机构职责由重组后的科技部整体承担。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也是在这份改革方案中，对于科技部的重组，给出了时间限制：“中央层面的改革任务力争在2023年年底前完成，地方层面的改革任务力争在2024年年底前完成。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;概括地说，在中央层面，此次科技部改革涉及科技部和其他部门在职能上的重合及科技成果转化问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在大连理工大学经济管理学院教授孙玉涛看来，科技工作涵盖了经济、社会、生态、文化等多个方面，而工信部、生态环境部、卫健委等部门也有自己的科技司，两者都包括科技在具体领域的应用问题。通过改革，科技部的这部分职能回到具体的职能部门，再加上中央科技委的设置，“加强了整体的统筹协调”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在另一位长期关注科技政策的学者看来，科技部被调整的这部分职能具有两个典型特点：“一是这些问题基本能依赖市场机制解决问题，或者说用市场机制来解决更有效率；二是这些问题影响的不是战略性问题。”他补充：“比如说数字化，当然快一点好，但是慢个一年半载，也不涉及&#39;要命的事情&#39;，即&#39;卡脖子&#39;问题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“卡脖子”等重大专项仍在&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;手里&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;把时间线再拉长一些，近十年来，涉及科技部的改革、重组共有3次。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙玉涛长期关注中国科研经费政策，他解释称，2014年，科技体制改革主要和科研经费有关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国科学院科技政策与管理科学研究所研究员李晓轩曾在《光明日报》撰文指出，《关于改进加强中央财政科研项目和资金管理的若干意见》直面经费管理中的越位和缺位并存的问题，是2014年的重磅改革措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该文件的核心内容体现在两个方面，一是针对原有经费管理存在的重复、分散、低效、监管乏力等问题，提出旨在促进规范化管理的整体改革思路。二是遵循科研活动规律，在操作层面强调按照实际成本编制经费预算，取消人员费简单按比例设置的规定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《关于深化中央财政科技计划（专项、基金等）管理改革的方案》则预示中国科技计划体系即将迎来一次“大手术”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原来分散在约40个部门近百项竞争性科技计划优化整合为国家自然科学基金、国家科技重大专项、国家重点研发计划、技术创新引导专项（基金）和基地与人才专项等5大类。政府管理仅限于宏观层面，微观层面的项目评审与管理交给专业机构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“原来的国家科技计划分很多科研项目，当时就有很多人说这些项目太分散了，各个部委都有钱去支持科技发展，&#39;九龙治水&#39;。”孙玉涛解释，“改革后，这些项目都集中到了科技部，所以有人称这次改革是&#39;扩权的改革&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科研经费改革后，2018年3月，十三届全国人大一次会议披露了科技部第一次重组的方案，提出将科学技术部、国家外国专家局的职责整合，重新组建科学技术部，作为国务院组成部门。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在前述不具名专家看来，相较于此次由中央编办推动的改革，2018年的改革更多还是由科技部本身在主导。在该专家看来，彼时的改革可以看成是此次改革的尝试：“在当时的国际环境下，我们还是主张要走开放合作的路线，只是在资源的投入方式上进行了一些调整，但效果不太理想。所以这一次改革就升格了，涉及对组织架构的深层次调整。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不在孙玉涛看来，改革的主要目的是为了应对当前面临的挑战：“为什么现在要这么调整？这说明我们当前遇到的问题需要通过改革来解决。十年之后这个问题不存在了，这些职能是不是会调回科技部，那也不好说。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科技部在此次改革后着重要解决的就是基础研究和“卡脖子”问题。前述专家解释：“&#39;卡脖子&#39;问题包含重大专项，这部分工作是科技部改革之后依然留在手里的，而且升格为由中央来抓。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙玉涛亦表示，从科研的角度来讲，基础研究的重要性非常高：“从基础研究，到应用研究，再到试验发展，越往后，要投入的钱越多；但是越往前，越重要。没有基础研究，怎么可能做得出后面的东西？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基础研究之外，国家科技重大专项来自《国家中长期科学和技术发展规划纲要(2006—2020年)》，包含了大型飞机、载人航天与探月工程等16个项目。值得注意的是，阴和俊此前就有参与重大专项的经历。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开信息显示，2008年9月25日，神舟七号载人飞船发射成功，阴和俊为神舟七号任务总指挥部副总指挥长；2013年12月，嫦娥三号发射成功，阴和俊曾以探月工程副总指挥的身份接受媒体采访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海滩失踪女童遗体发现：“疏忽父亲入刑论”应慎议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258929]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年10月19日，上海警方通报：10月18上午接宁波警方通报，宁波市镇海区某滩涂发现一具女童遗体，衣着等特征与浦东南汇新城海滩失踪女童相似；随后迅速派出工作组赶赴当地，经法医提取死者生物特征检测比对及家属辨认，确认系失踪女童黄某某，“遗体衣着完整，无暴力性损伤，符合溺水死亡特征，排除刑事案件”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这起牵动人心的儿童海滩失踪案，有了一个明确的结论。一个美好的生命就这样夭折，令人扼腕叹息。对于遭受丧女之痛的家庭来说，这是不可承受之重，很可能成为这个家庭一个永远难以愈合的伤口。在整个事件中有疏忽的孩子父亲，恐怕会长期生活在愧疚与自我谴责之中，这种精神折磨将是终身性的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当孩子在海滩失踪后，网上对这个家庭与父亲的非议不小，如诬称这个父亲是继父，造谣这个家庭“重男轻女”、故意造成女童死亡等。这种以“正义”示人的恶意与谎言，本身给这个家庭施加了更大的伤害，应该予以谴责。除此之外，网上也不乏要求将孩子父亲入刑的声音，治以“过失致人死亡罪”，这样才能震慑不负责任的父母。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如何认识后一种观点？现在，从小孩一进入幼儿园开始，每年都有各种防溺水的安全教育，但中国每年溺水死亡的儿童，从绝对数字看并不少。据中国疾控中心慢病中心和全球儿童安全组织统计，2010年-2015年，平均每年有54194名青少年儿童因伤害死亡（148人/天），溺水、道路交通伤害和跌倒/坠落为前三位伤害死因。人民网发布的《2022中国青少年防溺水大数据报告》指出，因溺水造成的伤亡位居中国0-17岁年龄段首位，占比高达33%，“截至2022年上半年，多起新闻报道不减反增，青少年群体溺水事故频发”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这些未成年人溺水死亡事件中，有父母在现场但分心疏忽而导致悲剧发生的，有游泳馆不容许父母进入而自身又没有能力保障孩子安全的，还有较大的孩子瞒着父母与同伴去河道、水库玩水或游泳而出现意外的。要是以“过失致人死亡罪”治第一类父母的罪，恐怕会出现不少案例，也很难产生显著的“震慑与预防”效果，反而不乏副作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管中国已经实施“全面三孩”政策，目前的总和生育率是非常低的，每年新生儿出生人数仍在下降通道中。在这种情况下，仍愿意生一个孩子、两个孩子的，往往真是因为爱孩子。因为传承了自己的基因，父母对孩子的爱是非常强烈的、给孩子的付出意愿是非常高的。可以说，在这个世界上，最爱孩子、最关心孩子福祉的就是他们的父母了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这种情况下，要对因本人疏忽导致孩子死亡的父母治罪，首先是不人道、不近人情的，子女是父母生命的延续，绝大部分父母没有主观意愿伤害自己的孩子或将自己的孩子置于险境，当然极少数兽父兽母故意伤害孩子理应入刑；其次，也不能起到提升父母“尽职程度”的作用，难道父母悉心养育孩子、愿意为孩子创造最好的一切，是怕被刑法惩罚吗？如果真是如此，那TA最为理性的考量一定是不生孩子，而不是每天对着刑法照看孩子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有人拿西方国家来举例：父母把幼儿独自留在家里或别的什么地方会被剥夺监护权。但客观分析可能存在的两类情况：孩子随父母长大、容许父母有偶尔疏忽；因父母偶尔把幼儿独自留在家中，然后把孩子交给别的家庭或儿童福利机构抚养，哪一种更有利于儿童的身心健康与福祉？尊重亲亲之情显然对儿童更有利。而且，这种做法属于对家庭这一自然血缘共同体的粗暴干预与践踏，产生的问题比宣称要解决的问题多得多、大得多。只有在父母故意伤害孩子、对儿童的身心健康与福祉明显不利时，才应该剥夺父母的监护权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓监护权，不是一种武断的权力，其实是满满的责任与付出，背后是爱，在孩子成年之前也不会有任何经济收益。父母要给孩子提供包括衣食住行在内的一切经济资源让孩子健康成长，还要保护孩子的安全，免受各种自然与人为风险的侵扰。君不见，有多少父母因孩子被人贩子绑架而不放弃追寻的步伐？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管悲剧已经发生，但我们也不应该要求为人父母者成神成圣，行动上永远不能出错：父母必须绝对确保孩子的安全，孩子受到任何伤害都必须追究父母的责任。这是对人性的苛求，也不符合现实。总之，尊重亲亲之情，尊重家庭，对为人父母者有共情与理解，权力对家庭保持必要的谦抑，不仅更有利于儿童的成长与福祉，本身也是捍卫家庭之为文明的根基。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子遭邻居砸门近一年：数十次报警为何换不来警方追责]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258902]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[洋葱狮子头丨云间夜话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258806]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/2TqgZmHogdWwNZBkP55vBJzgCDuzWX14PMr53ntg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/2TqgZmHogdWwNZBkP55vBJzgCDuzW X14PMr53ntg. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254352&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lion head. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone knows what Yangzhou Lion Head is. Of course it is a famous dish and no one is stupid enough to think of a fishy and dirty lion&#39;s head. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Cubans really think you are going to take a bite of a lion&#39;s head - when Tao Yan first introduced this dish to the &quot;Guard Captain&quot; in Spanish, the latter&#39;s severe facial twitching showed that he was So understood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The best Chinese restaurant in Havana is called &quot;Tiantan Hotel&quot;. The owner, Tao Yan, is my friend. He graduated from Shanghai Second Medical University and came to Havana very early. There are not many overseas Chinese in Havana. He has been The idea was to Cubanize his Chinese food. Cubans are very sweet and aromatic, so their Chinese dishes try to be as &quot;sweet and fragrant&quot; as possible, such as pig&#39;s trotters braised with sea cucumber, catfish stewed with tofu, and sweet and sour braised lamb chops, all with a large amount of Cuban sugar. Cubans can’t even figure out why Chinese food ingredients are so well matched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yangzhou lion head is the signature of the &quot;Temple of Heaven&quot;. After the captain of the guard knew that this &quot;lion head&quot; was actually a &quot;pig head&quot;, he came here often relying on his relationship with Tao Yantie. He was a tall man with a height of 1.9 meters. He was impatient with small dishes and specialized in picking big dishes. It’s a piece of meat, so I’m full of praise for the lion’s head in the “Temple of Heaven”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was sitting next to the captain of the guard that day. We also ordered the lion&#39;s head and thought it was &quot;too un-Yangzhou&quot;. It was like &quot;noodles&quot;. The ratio of starch to minced meat was wrong. The meat was too little. The ingredients were not in place. The taste was &quot;wooden&quot;. My wife felt itchy and said, I Come and give it a try! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her cooking method was passed down directly from her neighbor, a woman from Yangzhou. The first thing is the choice of pork. You cannot overemphasize the &quot;essence&quot;, it should be &quot;mixed with essence and oil (fat)&quot;, but it cannot be pork belly, it must be sandwiched. meat, and remove the fascia; minced pork cannot be the product of a meat grinder. It must be cut into small pieces first, then finely diced, and then minced into minced meat, but not too fine, as it will &quot;stick to the knife&quot;. This takes effort. Then add salt (or soy sauce), sugar, monosodium glutamate, minced green onions, diced fried dough sticks, rice wine, and appropriate amount of starch, and stir in one direction, usually clockwise, also called &quot;shangjin&quot;, until it is thick and sticky, waiting for frying. There is another trick here that is ignored by the outside world, that is, &quot;fine diced water chestnuts&quot; must be included in the ingredients. Water chestnuts are called &quot;di pear&quot; in Shanghai and &quot;horse hoof&quot; in the north. You can only buy canned water chestnuts in Cuba. . As for fried dough sticks, they are not available in Cuba, but local fried dough sticks can be substituted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Yan looked on, his eyes widened and he was dumbfounded, and said, my lion head is just a mixture of minced meat, MSG, flour, onion, ginger, and soy sauce, and then deep-fried, you have to add so much Ingredients? ! My wife said that it is best not to add ginger, but out of habit I would add less ginger, as the flavor would be too strong. The last key is that the outside of each meat ball is not smeared with egg paste until before frying. The egg paste is made as follows: Beat eggs to one ratio of flour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It must be fried hard, braised in brown sauce and reduced in juice. The lion&#39;s head is delicious when it&#39;s hard on the outside and tender on the inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cubans are straightforward and came to taste the lion’s head the next day. As soon as he tasted it, he stood up and made a phone call. Not long after, a large group of relatives came. There were more than ten of them. They sat neatly like thugs all over the yard. They all looked at the dining table and sat in rows. , eat fruit. This is a Cuban custom. Once there is delicious food, the whole family comes to share it. However, Tao Yan was frightened and explained to the guard captain in Spanish that today was just a trial production and it was impossible to supply a large group of people at once. The guard captain blinked his eyes honestly and refused to leave. My family is here and I want them to go back. Where can I put my face? ! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Yan was frightened. Please call my wife urgently. &quot;So many big eaters?!&quot; The wife couldn&#39;t help but groan. The lion&#39;s head was slightly smaller than a tennis ball. The captain of the guard could swallow 10 of them by himself. But what! How many &quot;noodles&quot; are there from the past? she asked. The answer is that there are many in the refrigerator. The wife asked to take them all out, defrost them, took a large bottle of mayonnaise, dipped the &quot;gnocchi&quot; in the heavy flavor, turned on the oil pan, and fried it over high heat. The aroma was overflowing, and served it hot to the relatives of the guard captain. Have to howl. The inside of the &quot;gnocchi&quot; is not that good, but the egg skin shell is especially crispy and salty when fried. This is a particularly pleasing thing for my wife. But the guard captain is not stupid. He knew that his wife&#39;s lion&#39;s head was better, and she knew the taste after eating the marrow, so within a few days he actually brought &quot;Whitebeard&quot;, a high-ranking official from Cuba. Of course, I didn’t forget to notify you in advance this time. &quot;Whitebeard&quot; is a close comrade of Castro. He drives a black Audi. As soon as he comes in, he says that he has brought a &quot;mysterious guest&quot; without permission. He heard that the &quot;Chinese Lion Head&quot; is particularly delicious and wants it. Have a taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Yan was dumbfounded when he saw it. She was an old lady with a noble status! He also had a young grandson with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He turned sideways and leaned back as a habit. There was a large group of people in the yard, sitting in rows, eating fruits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is our custom.&quot; The guard captain explained again. He also said that the people who paid this time were all relatives of &quot;White Beard&quot;. When Cubans go to dinner parties, they like to bring their entire family. This time I really learned the lesson. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the behavior of &quot;White Beard&quot; and the old lady is quite elegant. They gently bite open the lion&#39;s head, the inside is pink, and there is a slight gravy in the steaming heat, but the elegance does not diminish their elegance. Appetite, thumbs up while swallowing, the delicacies in the big basin are rapidly decreasing, and the guard captain&#39;s companionship has accelerated their disappearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because it was impossible to estimate the number of people who would &quot;sit in rows and eat fruit&quot;, there was a shortage of seats for the lion head, so my wife hurriedly took advantage of the opportunity to make it. Of course, it was too luxurious to chop the meat by hand, so I directly used a meat grinder, but The problem is, a catastrophic accident occurs unexpectedly. China runs out of green onions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chives are a scarce commodity in Havana. The Chinese usually save on using them. Now that they are suddenly out of stock, where should they go to replenish them? Tao Yan suddenly caught a glimpse of the onions in the corner of the room. Isn’t an onion an onion? Although the taste difference is huge, it&#39;s hard to tell. &quot;The question is, what if Cubans happen to be good at this?!&quot; The wife asked Tao Yan coldly. The two looked at each other and understood. The latter immediately jumped into action and pulled out a large bag of onions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As you can imagine, the whole room was filled with the smell of onions fried in a big oil pan, and &quot;White Beard&quot; and the old lady couldn&#39;t sit still. People in the courtyard couldn&#39;t sit still. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;White Beard&quot; said, why is it getting more and more fragrant? For the sake of the continuation of this fragrance, I am even willing to launch another cooking &quot;revolution&quot;! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The people in the compound left their original positions like the mud of a barrier lake, and squeezed into the dining room bit by bit like toothpaste. They shouted in Spanish and pushed each other. No one dared. Head straight to the table. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final outcome is predictable. A famous dish was born in Havana. It is no longer called Yangzhou lion head, but has a more Cuban name: onion lion head. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江省人大常委会原副主任宋希斌一审获刑14年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258838]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/8d32eea8c44f27b9b172302b6fc2430a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;680&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/18/8d32eea8c44f27b9b172302b6fc2430a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 17, 2023, the Shenyang Intermediate People’s Court of Liaoning Province publicly pronounced the verdict of the Heilongjiang Provincial People’s Congress Standing Committee in the first instance In the case of former party member and deputy director Song Xibin accepting bribes and embezzling public funds, the defendant Song Xibin was sentenced to 13 years in prison for accepting bribes and fined RMB 3 million; he was sentenced to three years in prison for embezzling public funds and decided to execute the term He was sentenced to 14 years in prison and fined RMB 3 million; the property obtained from bribery and the interest therefrom shall be recovered in accordance with the law and turned over to the state treasury. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;It was found after trial: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;From 2005 to 2021, the defendant Song Xibin successively used his position as the Daxinganling Prefectural Committee of Heilongjiang Province Deputy Secretary, Administrative Commissioner, Director of the Forestry Administration, Secretary of the Daxinganling Prefectural Committee, Director of the Heilongjiang Provincial Development and Reform Commission, Deputy Secretary of the Harbin Municipal Committee and Mayor, Member and Deputy Director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Heilongjiang Provincial People&#39;s Congress, Chairman of the Heilongjiang Provincial Federation of Trade Unions, etc. With the convenience in the field, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of authority and status, it provided assistance to relevant units and individuals in matters such as business operations, land replacement, project contracting, job promotion, etc., and illegally accepted property from others equivalent to more than 35.32 million yuan. In 2014, Song Xibin took advantage of his position as deputy secretary of the Harbin Municipal Party Committee and mayor to seek personal interests and decided to lend 50 million yuan of Harbin&#39;s special fiscal funds to other units in the name of his unit for profit-making activities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Shenyang Intermediate People’s Court held that defendant Song Xibin’s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes and misappropriating public funds. In view of the fact that Song Xibin truthfully confessed his crimes after arriving at the case, and took the initiative to explain most of the criminal facts of bribery and misappropriation of public funds that were not yet known to the supervisory authorities. The crime of misappropriation of public funds constituted surrender; he pleaded guilty and repented, and actively returned the stolen goods. All the bribes and stolen goods have been recovered, and the misappropriated goods have been recovered. All public funds have been recovered before the first instance trial, and there are legal, discretionary or mitigated punishment circumstances. According to the law, he can be given a lighter punishment for the crime of accepting bribes and a reduced punishment for the crime of misappropriating public funds. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电梯事故频频发生，一图读懂如何自救？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258923]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/19/9849783f0d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;8581&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 19/9849783f0d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254649&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>