<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[旋转的白森林]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258574]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/CDGLWAR98C8pWtIuxfWnkE9P6QN98wHniNqZbJhv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/CDGLWAR98C8pWtIuxfWnkE9P6QN98wHniN qZbJhv. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253666&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Grassland Sky Road Observation Deck&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All things are one and connected to each other. The signs appear, but their meaning is difficult to decipher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I spent the whole morning roaming in the wilderness. On the rolling hills, oats and sunflowers sway in the wind, waiting to be harvested. Autumn has come to Zhangbei grassland again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under a cement pole, I took off my backpack and sat down to rest. It&#39;s quiet around here. Occasionally a car would pass by silently on the road in the distance. Listen carefully to the hum of wind turbines grinding the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number &quot;76&quot; is affixed to the pole. This number has special meaning to me - the birthday of a close relative. A few black feathers and a dried neck bone were scattered on the grass. Seven years ago today, I was driving her on the highway and killed a magpie. The night before, she slept in an orchard near the China-North Korea border and had a nightmare - an eye stared at her in the night sky. After waking up, she heard a woman crying all night on the mountain - an eagle owl was crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2R802a1KiPtLOBbZJKzTQcIEW7CBNMyaP8HyiAaN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;362&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2R802a1KiPtLOBbZJKzTQcIEW7CBNMyaP8HyiAaN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253667&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mature sunflowers&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the hill Opera and the sound of tractors came from the villages. I looked away from the feathers. The village square became a threshing floor, and shelled oats were spread on the cement floor like kraft paper. Oats like cold, tolerate drought, and are resistant to salt and alkali. They have been cultivated by Guansai border people since ancient times. They are easy to feel full after eating and difficult to digest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the afternoon, I passed a poplar forest and faintly smelled the scent of sheep. There are a group of sheep in the forest, heads gathering together, as if they are performing some kind of silent ceremony. I sneaked into the woods quietly, fearing to disturb them. Unexpectedly, the owner of the sheep suddenly appeared and startled me. A woman wearing pink sneakers holds a mobile phone and a whip in her hands, and a baseball cap on her head is embroidered with the Chanel logo. I asked her what the sheep were doing together, and she said they didn&#39;t like to move when they were full. I said: There are thirty of them, right? She said there were more than seventy of them, clustered in a pile so they couldn’t be counted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;White impeller, circular pointer. Rotating, without beginning or end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/jvmN7nZl3VkQS06XfxjZbn4bpxBAThbh1jGDRrSj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/jvmN7nZl3VkQS06XfxjZbn4bpxBAThbh1jGDRrSj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253668&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Oats waiting to be harvested&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wan On the winding country road, I met another shepherd. He was old and walked slowly. He was leaning on a dead branch in his left hand and holding a ewe in his right hand. The ewe has a stubborn character and keeps wrestling with the old man, trying to break free. The reins connecting them are stretched straight. The old man told me that he went to his daughter&#39;s house in a neighboring village to tend sheep early in the morning. The ewe was two years old and had given birth to two litters of two lambs. One lamb was sold for six hundred. The ewe seemed to be eavesdropping on our conversation, nibbling on the sunflower trays on the roadside and looking at us sideways with her yellow eyes. The old man tightened the reins again and made another circle in his hand. He wore several layers of clothes, and his red baseball cap was embroidered with the logo - ×× Fertilizer. &quot;It will take an hour until we get home,&quot; he put the tip of his tongue against his sunken lips, with a hint of complaint in his tone, &quot;I forgot to put on my dentures when I went out, and my daughter stayed to eat...&quot; I glanced at his dark mouth, with only the lower gums remaining. A loose crooked tooth is like a stone monument in the dark night. I think of another &quot;mouth&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/i3VIfLsnnkMqtKL9vctv3GvstFEtBAhv7dzQi5pi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/i3VIfLsnnkMqtKL9vctv3GvstFEtBAhv7dzQi5pi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253676&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the poplar forest, well-fed sheep&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The autumn wilderness is colorful and full of temptation. Not long after driving out of Zhangbei County, I couldn&#39;t wait to leave the main road and drove toward the distant hills, dragging the yellow dust cloud behind the car. Went around several old elm trees covered with moss, turned two turns, and finally reached a plateau. A van was parked next to a wheat field, with black film on the windows and half-open side windshield of the cab, without a driver. The view here is wide and unobstructed: countless white windmills are spinning lazily; harvesters are raising puffs of dust and smoke in the wheat fields; a box of &quot;Gatling&quot; fireworks tubes are lying quietly on the grass after being discharged. Accompanying them are drink bottles, cigarette boxes, grocery bags and tissues with lip gloss stuck on them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The van started suddenly, turned around suddenly, and drove towards the road at an unusual speed. After the van drove away, I noticed that there was a commanding point on the high ground - a hill covered with grass. The hills are surrounded by wheat fields. I stepped over the wheat stubble and patrolled around the mountains. The locusts in the fields were flying like shrapnel. This is an &quot;artificial mountain&quot; about 4 meters high and nearly 8 meters in diameter. The moment I climbed to the top of the mountain, I was glad I stopped in time. There is a hole the size of a wellhead in the middle of the top of the mountain. The entrance of the cave is circular, and the cave wall gradually becomes a trapezoid as it goes down. When it is close to the ground, the tunnel turns into a side cave. The hole was dug cleanly, with no residual soil around it. The entrance of the cave is like an open mouth, shouting silently towards the sky. I turned up my collar and carefully walked down the hill. A civet cat scurried past me with a black bird in its mouth. I was stunned for a moment, then quickly got into the car and drove towards the highway at the speed of a van. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/osadEbuMuW9R6LvoBjVXPvXnJtI0VJm4orM1Oa9j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/osadEbuMuW9R6LvoBjVXPvXnJtI0VJm4orM1Oa9j.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253669&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Villers drying oats&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two Soldiers were running cross-country on the road. The short one was leading and the tall one was lagging behind. They gasped and turned to look at me. The confusion on their faces flashed across their faces. A pair of middle-aged men and women with oily hair and powdery faces seemed to have improvised. They were carrying shopping bags. They lower their heads in the forest, pick mushrooms, and shoot videos; groups of well-fed Dauri jackdaws sit on the roadside wires, chattering and quarreling. They like to forage among the domestic animals in the pasture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0DzRNolGF5qAJV0y12AMhteoCXhL88VJq6UwHivu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0DzRNolGF5qAJV0y12AMhteoCXhL88VJq6UwHivu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253671&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hills on the highlands&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Past Two villages later, I turned onto another dirt road to see what lay behind the hills. I parked my car halfway up the mountain and walked to the top of the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some cold-resistant vegetation is still taking advantage of the short time in autumn to quietly grow: cold mugwort clinging to the ground; reborn dandelions; potted white daisy; and royal blue delphiniums whose petals are like birds spreading their wings... …&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Nf1UGFVm7curjSE9vwLBXuHuigfVpjDMIWUBrxOw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Nf1UGFVm7curjSE9vwLBXuHuigfVpjDMIWUBrxOw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253675&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Black feathers under the pole&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Sharp syncopation pierced the airflow - a peregrine falcon performed aerobatics in the air, sometimes hovering, sometimes fluttering high, sometimes spiraling into a dive... It seemed to be performing specifically for me. The peregrine falcon is the fastest hunting bird in the world, with speeds exceeding 300 kilometers per hour. I stood there, holding the telescope and not daring to move. Between the loss of focus and the pursuit of focus, I stared at this unpredictable gray-white elf with almost no blinking. I was completely shocked by its transcendent dance of wind, forgetting the existence of time. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lAtDyNMvEhSKnt4nibWeIMLTMnzDui3oZ5PAkQTm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lAtDyNMvEhSKnt4nibWeIMLTMnzDui3oZ5PAkQTm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253672&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Prop horse&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/waO37yI04NzNYmclZ8TR08gDoVuU77IUxUGQGAYr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/waO37yI04NzNYmclZ8TR08gDoVuU77IUxUGQGAYr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253670&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot; >;Circular ruts created by drift&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are mountains beyond the mountains. After climbing two hills in a row, I saw the scenery behind the mountains - a basin as big as a playground that was very different from the surroundings. The flat ground was covered with a layer of black stone chips that looked like volcanic ash, and there was no grass growing on it. A strange circular rut appears in the center of the basin. On a collapsed cliff, a wall made of masonry and reinforced concrete was exposed. I looked around and saw no other buildings except the towering windmill. I guess the purpose of this place is: mining factory, school, pasture, experimental base...it seems none of them. Another possibility suddenly occurred to me - fortifications. In the 1960s, Sino-Soviet relations broke down. In order to prevent a large-scale invasion by the Soviet Union, our country built a large number of defense fortifications along the borders of North China, Northeast China, and Northwest China. Fortunately, a large-scale war did not break out, and the useless fortifications gradually turned into historical relics that no one cared about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I regret not bringing a tent with me on this trip. This is an ideal camping spot. Open, hidden, leeward, silent, the surrounding scene is shrouded in a mysterious science fiction color. Funnel spiders swung back and forth between the rocks, searching for joints; ant ants dragged the dying wasps forward; white butterflies stood on the porous basalt and fluttered their wings. Every life is the crystallization of billions of years. A blue pebble shaped like a snake egg jumped into sight. After examining it, I knocked it against a rock. Miraculously, the 3 mm-thick &quot;eggshell&quot; split into two and fell off completely. There was a hard stone heart hidden inside, as black as a crow&#39;s feathers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/eOSVuWtlfvdRqjTWJnDAhRPPxmyLunqGyGM0vdMl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/eOSVuWtlfvdRqjTWJnDAhRPPxmyLunqGyGM0vdMl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253673&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiang Road Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rotating white Paddle, the wind catcher of all seasons. White forests of wind turbines spread across the wilderness. In the past decade, they have grown on a large scale in windy areas such as grasslands, Gobis, and oceans. It&#39;s like an extraterrestrial visitor invading the earth. It&#39;s so white that it&#39;s so cold, so white that it&#39;s unexpected. I stood under the wind turbine, looking up at this behemoth a hundred meters high, counting the number of revolutions of the blades, 1, 2, 3... turn - turn - turn - unknowingly getting lost in the superposition of numbers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6cbAFysqlTsaywodYHQSKuPNfo2kU2KuvEEPGROX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6cbAFysqlTsaywodYHQSKuPNfo2kU2KuvEEPGROX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253674&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Waiting in the wind&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wind energy, Electric energy can do anything. Returning to the parking place, the windmill in my mind was still spinning. I sat on the grass and made a pot of tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ancient time, original silence. In autumn in the north of Saibei, a fish-shaped floating cloud floated in the clear sky, and after a while, it was blown away by the wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公共绿地还是私家庭院？维权五年，难拆除的违建]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258636]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/L5c5bK05T6tGtaLEzwH5N2HVFCyjZsQMUdg9OTBJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;612&quot; height=&quot;816&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/L5c5bK05T6tGtaLEzwH5N2HVFCyjZs QMUdg9OTBJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254086&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The left side is the villa, and the right wall belongs to the commercial building involved. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to defend the right to repair the outdoor unit of the air conditioner, Lu Caiyun has defended his rights in Hefei High-tech Zone nearly 5 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The air conditioner in the shop was broken, and when it was time to repair the outdoor unit, he discovered that the exterior wall of his shop had become the wall of someone else&#39;s private garden. The large green spaces behind the shops along the street are also enclosed into courtyards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are constant disputes between shop owners and villa neighbors over the ownership of this green space. Some villa owners claim that this green space is the &quot;backyard&quot; listed on the property certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2018, Lu Caiyun and other shop owners have repeatedly complained to Hefei City Letters and Calls Bureau, Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, High-tech Zone Management Committee, High-tech Zone Shulu Community Service Center and other departments. Until 2022, the Hefei Real Estate Registration Center admitted that the contents of the real estate certificates of villa owners were incorrect and needed to be updated. In May 2023, the mayor&#39;s mailbox replied that the Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau had identified the &quot;backyard&quot; as an illegal construction in accordance with the law. But so far, these &quot;backyards&quot; have not been demolished.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Businesses represented by Lu Caiyun wrote in the complaint letter: &quot;Repeated visits to the same problem have not only consumed a lot of government resources, but also affected the public health. We live a normal life. The relevant departments have also admitted their mistakes, and the facts are very clear. When will it be resolved?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Public green space has been included in the private property certificate&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;Xuhuihushanyuanzuo Community is located on Fushan Road, High-tech Zone, Hefei City. In 2016, Lu Caiyun purchased a street shop in the community and opened a Chinese restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to her recollection, after the shop was delivered, she installed the outdoor air conditioner on the south wall near the villa in accordance with the property management requirements. At that time, no one was living in the villa behind the south wall. The area between the two was planted with green plants and there was a stone road for people to pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, due to a malfunction of the air conditioner in the store, maintenance personnel needed to repair the outdoor unit of the air conditioner. At this time, the area between the shop and the villa has become the private garden of the villa area, and the south wall of the shop has become the &quot;wall&quot; of the garden. With the coordination of neighborhood committee staff, Lu Caiyun was able to enter her neighbor&#39;s &quot;garden&quot; to repair the air conditioner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Caiyun is not the only one who has disputes with the owners of villas because of the open space behind the shop. As early as 2018, some shop owners discovered that the vacant land had been turned into villa courtyards, and the east and west sides were blocked by walls, which seriously affected the use of the shops. They sued the developer Xuhui Group Co., Ltd., demanding that the 7-meter-wide space behind the shops be restored. Public land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shop owners lost both cases. However, according to the second-instance judgment (2019) Anhui 01 Minzhong No. 4059, the evidence provided by the shop owners in the second-instance trial showed that the open space between the shops and the villa area was green space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Basic Terminology Standards for Urban Planning&quot; formulated by the Ministry of Construction (later changed to the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development) states that green spaces refer to urban areas specifically used to improve ecology, protect the environment, and provide recreational areas for residents. and landscaping landscaping. The developer recognized this and stated that the actual construction was also constructed in accordance with the requirements of the green space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The general layout plan of the Xuhui Lake Shanyuan Project approved by the Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau provided by Lu Caiyun can also support this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plan map shows that there is a passage between the S5 commercial area where the shops are located and the villa area. There are clearly illustrations of multiple plants on the map, indicating that this is a green space in the residential area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 274 of the Civil Code stipulates that green spaces within building zones belong to the owners, except those that belong to urban public green spaces or that are expressly owned by individuals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Encyclopedia of Applications of the Chinese Civil Code (Property Rights Volume)&quot; compiled by the Leading Group for the Implementation of the Civil Code of the Supreme People&#39;s Court further explains: Roads and green spaces within building zones are usually owned by the owners. According to the legal theory of divided ownership of buildings, the roads and green spaces within the building zone belong to the common supporting facilities in the common property of the community. Under special circumstances, certain roads and green spaces within the building zone are not shared by the owners. As for the green space that is expressly owned by individuals, it mostly refers to the green space in front of the window of a first-floor building unit or the green space in a specific area adjacent to the building, and this part of the green space needs to be clearly sold together with the exclusive part of the building in the commercial housing sales contract. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, the originally planned green space was divided into courtyards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since May 2018, 25 shop owners, including Lu Caiyun, have repeatedly reported to the Hefei High-tech Zone Shulu Community Service Center, the High-tech Zone Management Committee, the Hefei Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, and the Municipal Government. The Complaints Bureau, the Mayor&#39;s Mailbox and other departments reported that the owners of more than 20 villas in Buildings C55, C56 and C57 had occupied green space (8 households in one building) and set up private basements. Some of the problems were solved, but there has been no substantial progress in the encroachment of green space. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local media reported that the owner of the villa produced a property certificate, which stated that the land was indeed his backyard. Southern Weekend reporters were unable to contact the owner of the villa. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Multiple consultations failed&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August 2021, the then Party Secretary of Shulu Community Service Center in Hefei High-tech Zone was interviewed by local official media It said that Lu Caiyun submitted materials to the community on June 9, 2020, reflecting the problem of encroachment on public areas. After receiving the report, community staff went to the developer’s Shanghai headquarters to interview him and required the developer to respond within 3 months. Areas related to public access were set back, and the developer also signed a letter of commitment in this regard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months later, because the developer failed to fulfill its concession promise, the community and urban management bureau planned to demolish the illegal building in the villa. However, the owner of the villa showed the property certificate on the spot, which contained the word &quot;backyard&quot;. area. Out of respect for legal and valid documents, the community temporarily suspended the demolition. At the same time, the Hefei Municipal Party Committee inspection team present was also aware of the situation and stated that it would investigate issues related to the real estate certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the problem could not be resolved, Lu Caiyun and others complained to the Anhui Provincial Letters and Calls Bureau in November 2021, requesting to find out why the green space was registered in the property certificates of more than 20 villa owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22 of that year, the Anhui Provincial Letters and Calls Bureau stated in a return visit that the Hefei Real Estate Registration Department had teamed up with relevant departments to investigate and verify the marking of the community’s personal property rights certificates, and was currently studying and handling opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 16, 2022, the Hefei Real Estate Registration Center also issued an announcement requiring the owner of the villa involved to correct the real estate certificate. The announcement stated that according to Article 81 of the &quot;Implementing Rules of the Interim Regulations on Real Estate Registration&quot;, because the owners of Buildings C55, C56 and C57 of Hushan Yuanzuo Community have incorrect content in the real estate certificates, they need to wait until they receive the notice. Change the registration and renew the real estate certificate within 30 working days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the fact that the green space is occupied has not changed. On May 9, 2023, Lu Caiyun once again reported the situation to the mayor of Hefei’s mailbox. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 23, the Hefei Real Estate Registration Center responded, saying that based on the previous request of city leaders during the interview, the High-tech Zone Management Committee organized an inspection of Buildings C55 and C56 of Xuhui Lake Shanyuan Building. An investigation into illegal construction was launched in the north yard of Building C and Building C57. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, in response to the illegal construction of fences that encroach on public green space and other issues, the Urban Management Bureau of the High-tech Zone has submitted investigation materials on the illegal construction of fences in some buildings to the Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau for identification of illegal construction. , Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau has determined it to be an illegal construction in accordance with the law, and the High-tech Zone Urban Management Bureau is handling it in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Caiyun said that they still don’t know the handling of the property certificates that were previously registered incorrectly, and there are no signs that the villa owner’s garden will be demolished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend contacted Hefei Municipal Natural Resources and Planning Bureau and Hefei Real Estate Registration Center many times, but received no positive response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend contacted Linxi Community of Shulu Community Service Center. The staff informed, “The community and self-regulatory bureau, the real estate registration center and the villa owners have negotiated many times to no avail, and it is difficult to Promote the demolition of illegal constructions.&quot; In addition, according to his understanding, the property certificate of the villa owner has been corrected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters checked the relevant regulations and found no clause that requires the consent of the illegal builders to demolish illegal buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend contacted the Urban Management Squadron of Shulu Center of Hefei High-tech Zone. The staff said that they were already going through law enforcement procedures against the courtyard walls built privately by the villa owners. “Previously, Use drones to take photos and collect evidence, and after the planning department approves it, the parties will be allowed to dismantle it by themselves within a time limit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 13:25:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲突又起，中东“和解大潮”难再续？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258634]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 11:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the early morning of October 7, 2023, local time, the Palestinian Islamic Resistance Movement (Hamas) launched an attack on Israel in recent years. The Israeli Defense Forces launched the largest rocket attack in the country, sent a large number of militants into southern Israel, and broke out in street battles with Israeli security forces. The Israel Defense Forces quickly launched a counterattack and launched a &quot;comprehensive siege&quot; of Gaza. The situation between Palestine and Israel suddenly escalated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Palestinian-Israeli conflict has aroused widespread attention and concern from the international community due to its sudden outbreak and the huge casualties it caused. It is in sharp contrast to the &quot;reconciliation trend&quot; in the Middle East this year. It reveals the complexity and variability of the Middle East issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The intensity of the conflict is limited&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with the past, this round of conflicts has more obvious high-intensity characteristics, as well as the amplification effect of war news in the Internet era, causing This has aroused people&#39;s concerns about whether the sixth Middle East war will break out, but at present, it is highly likely that the scope of this round of conflict will be limited to Hamas and Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, Arab countries such as Egypt and Jordan surrounding Palestine do not have sufficient motivation or reason to go to war with Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2022, Egypt’s economy has continued to slump due to the spillover effects of the Russia-Ukraine conflict. Exporting natural gas to Europe through the Arab Gas Pipeline and Israel’s Leviathan Gas Field has become an important channel for earning foreign exchange income. At this time, if Egypt is at odds with Israel, its economic development will undoubtedly fall into huge difficulties; Syria, in the north of Pakistan, is in jail, and its limited resources will also be prioritized for domestic economic reconstruction; Lebanon is experiencing a severe economic and financial crisis, and there is no are willing to participate in the war; Gulf Arab countries with strong economic and military strength should only provide moral support and humanitarian assistance to Palestine as long as their core interests are not affected; Fatah, which represents the legitimate Palestinian regime, chooses I watched from the sidelines. Therefore, without the actual participation of other sovereign states, this round of conflict will eventually return to become a stage in the spiral evolution of Palestinian-Israeli relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Infinite Vicious Circle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The conflict between Israel and Palestine continues. To be precise, it is a confrontation with the radical factions dominated by Hamas. It is the inevitable result of the long-term deterioration of the relationship between the two parties, and the explosive manifestation of crossing the critical point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, surrounding issues such as Palestine&#39;s pursuit of statehood, the &quot;legalization&quot; of Jewish settlements, and the competition for holy sites, the tense situation between Palestine and Israel has never changed, and has even become more intense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since January 2023, the conflict between Palestine and Israel in Jerusalem has continued to intensify. The Israeli military and police have repeatedly forcibly expelled Palestinian residents near the Al-Aqsa Mosque; in early July, the Israeli military carried out A large-scale military operation was launched in the Jenin region, causing a large number of casualties and displacement of Palestinians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Radical factions such as Hamas and Jihad, which firmly advocate armed struggle, continue to promote the spread and expansion of their political and military power, causing the Palestinian-Israeli relationship to gradually deepen into an infinite vicious cycle of &quot;reacting violence with violence&quot; , and laid hidden dangers for larger-scale conflicts and crises that may occur in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Against the background of extremely disparity in power between the two sides, the living space of the Palestinian people has been continuously compressed. The Gaza Strip has been under strict blockade and surveillance by the Israeli military for a long time, and the population density has reached approximately 10,000 people per square meter. kilometer. According to the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) statistical report, 57% of households in the Gaza Strip have experienced a significant decrease in income in 2022, the local unemployment rate has increased by 49%, and 65% of the population is in poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The continued economic downturn has brought infrastructure construction in the Gaza Strip to almost a standstill. When former United Nations Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon visited Gaza, he said that Israel&#39;s policy of blocking Gaza was &quot;unacceptable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the relations between Arab countries and Israel have gradually eased, especially the recent continuous exchanges between Saudi Arabia and Israel, and even the possibility of reaching a peace agreement, the Palestinians&#39; insecurity has been infinitely magnified. As the Palestinian issue becomes increasingly marginalized, the Palestinians have no choice but to rely on their own strength to survive. At the same time, the continued inaction of the Palestinian Authority, which legally represents Palestinian sovereignty, has actually created more public support for Hamas within Palestine, making it a &quot;firm defender&quot; of Palestinian national consciousness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this point of view, the current conflict between Pakistan and Israel is also the product of the collision between long-term conflicts that have not been resolved and changes in the game situation inside and outside the region. In fact, the Palestinian-Israeli conflict has been experiencing cyclical ups and downs since its existence, which makes it almost impossible to achieve a lasting and fair solution. The call for national self-determination and the restoration of legitimate rights and interests has been circulated among generations of Palestinians. As Israel&#39;s &quot;most right-wing government&quot; comes to power, the way Israel and Palestinian radical factions get along will also be full of violence and hatred. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Highly complex&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the short term, this round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict will still have a greater impact on peace and stability in the Eastern Mediterranean, and at the same time promote The game relationship between the various forces has undergone a series of changes. It is worth noting that the various conflicts in the region and the intricate interest relationships between countries determine the impact of this incident on the Middle East and even the world, and will not be presented in a simple linear rise or fall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the reconciliation process between the Arab-Islamic world and Israel will enter a state of suspension or even regression in the short term. On October 10, local time, Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman said when answering a call from Palestinian President Abbas that Saudi Arabia will continue to support the Palestinians in realizing their legitimate rights, which means that the Saudi-Israeli reconciliation process has attracted much attention. It has been &quot;temporarily terminated&quot;; as Iran announced its support for Hamas&#39;s actions in Israel, its relations with Israel will also fall &quot;below the freezing point&quot;. Although Turkey will actively play the role of mediator between Israel and Palestinian forces , but it is almost impossible for its relationship with Israel to return to its original state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the reconciliation process within the Arab world will be accelerated, and Palestinian affairs may become the glue to curb the &quot;fragmentation&quot; of the Arab world. In the past few months, as the crisis of Qatar&#39;s severance of diplomatic relations has been completely resolved, and Syria has returned to the Arab League family, there is a glimmer of an end to the divisions and internal strife that have lasted for more than ten years in the Arab world after the &quot;Arab Spring&quot;. Under this situation, the Arab world&#39;s political sympathy for Palestine will further promote the ill-fated Arab countries to unite and strengthen themselves, and give them the spiritual impetus to achieve true strategic independence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, the main contradictions in the Middle East may change. In the past few decades, the contradictions between Arab Islamic countries and Israel, the contradictions between Sunni and Shia forces, and the contradictions between regional countries and external interference forces have intertwined and superimposed, thus shaping the current geopolitical pattern of the Middle East— —Changes in the structural proportions of any set of contradictions will rewrite the geopolitical demands of the relevant forces. Against the dual background of the Saudi-Iranian reconciliation and the continued strategic contraction of the United States in the Middle East, this round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict will undoubtedly further highlight the contradictions between Arab Islamic countries and Israel, resulting in a series of chain reactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to the conflict itself, whether it is Hamas armed raids on Israeli targets or Israel&#39;s violent counterattacks with revenge, it has caused huge casualties and economic and property losses to both sides - a large number of Israeli hostages Being hijacked by Hamas affects the nervousness of Israeli residents. At the same time, the Gaza Strip&#39;s only power plant ceased operations due to Israeli bombing and siege, which also means that despair will spread to every street in the area. However, hatred and violence can never fundamentally solve the problem. It is difficult for both Palestine and Israel to make concessions to each other on issues involving their core interests. The Palestine-Israel issue may become even more difficult in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is an associate researcher at the Economic, Trade and Industry Investment Research Center of the Mediterranean Research Institute of Zhejiang International Studies University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国籍女子在新加坡被控罪：入乡应随法，别搞“舆论化妆师”那一套丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258632]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 10:47:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to Singapore&#39;s &quot;Lianhe Zaobao&quot; report, a Chinese woman was suspected of being hit by a driver and injured her foot. While receiving medical treatment at the Central Hospital, he allegedly insulted a nurse and refused to cooperate with the police in taking a statement. In addition, he was suspected of verbally abusing a security guard earlier. He was charged with six counts, including one count of public nuisance, two counts of contravening the Prevention of Harassment Act, and three counts. One count of contravening the Private Security Industry Act. If convicted, the woman involved may face a penalty of &quot;a fine of up to 7,500 yuan, or imprisonment of up to two years, or both.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The matter is not complicated and the facts are clear. In the early morning of October 10, the woman involved went to the emergency room of Singapore General Hospital (SGH) to seek medical treatment. She said that she was hit by a substitute driver and requested rapid treatment. The medical staff noticed that she was not wearing a mask, so they handed it to her and reminded her that she must wear a mask in the hospital. Not only did the woman refuse to cooperate, she cursed and insulted the nurse, complaining that she had &quot;waited for three hours.&quot; The hospital had no choice but to call the police, who sent police officers and investigators to the hospital to investigate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the video released by the woman involved, she not only refused to cooperate in recording a confession and let the investigator &quot;guess&quot;, but also changed the topic many times, accusing the nurse of discriminating against her, and also swore at the investigator. , and tried to pull the ID of an investigator, but was firmly stopped by the latter. According to an announcement from the Singapore police, the woman in question even had a criminal record. On October 3, she was drunk, pushed and pulled the security guard who sent her home, and used insulting and abusive language. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prosecution pointed out in court on October 13 that if the defendant intends to plead guilty, they will conduct a trial on four of the charges, and the remaining two charges will be taken into consideration by the judge when sentencing. The defendant directly said, &quot;I plead guilty and I apologize.&quot; When the judge asked the defendant whether he would hire a lawyer, the defendant asked if he could get a lighter sentence by pleading guilty early without hiring a lawyer. The judge explained that pleading guilty early would help mitigate the crime. The defendant expressed his understanding, and the judge postponed the case to October 25 and approved her bail of 15,000 Singapore dollars. In addition to the bail, a Singaporean citizen was required to vouch for her. From the news, it seemed that no one came forward to vouch for her, but she was taken back to the police station&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This case seemed to be a trivial matter, but it turned out to be more and more troublesome. Not only are the legal consequences extremely serious, but the public opinion effect can also be called &quot;full of influence&quot;. After carefully examining the timeline of this case from the incident to the aftermath, the words and deeds of the woman involved are a living lesson in the rule of law, worthy of analysis and analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the words and deeds of the woman involved during the incident may have been &quot;scripted&quot; in advance, but they hit a brick wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The woman in question refused to obey hospital regulations, did not wear a mask, and was impatient to wait for medical treatment. This is all true. She shouted foul language at the nurse, which was her intention to vent and engage in emotional blackmail. ; When facing investigators, she denied and insisted that &quot;the nurse discriminated against her&quot;, hoping to &quot;preemptively draw a portrait&quot; to take the initiative in public opinion; recording the video and publishing it on social media was also intended to launch a public opinion offensive to influence the judiciary and escape punishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，调查员严格依法办事，表示此行只为调查“当事女子有没有对护士爆粗口”这一件事，同时三次警告当事女子不要录视频。面对调查员的公事公办，当事女子不但顾左右而言他，而且态度极其蛮横，语无伦次再度爆粗口的同时，还讲出了“请全新加坡的警察都来这里”的爆笑言论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本案在国内舆论场引发不少共鸣。 “扭曲事实”“抢先画像”“录视频上网”，这三板斧堪称国内类似舆情事件的常见桥段，当事者也屡试不爽。诸如“石家庄女子背后偷袭地铁保安”“重庆女子扇保安耳光”“女子牵狗进电梯发视频污蔑保安”的新闻层出不穷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，当事女子在新加坡来这一套时遇到了麻烦：护士没有让步，调查员也没有和稀泥，事后警方的控告也依法依规进行。事后当事女子当庭认罪，显示她所指控的“护士歧视她不是新加坡人不能看病”当属污蔑，不顾三次警告录视频的行为也未能争取舆论主动，反而给自己惹来了麻烦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从当事女子“不再自辩，只求减刑”的态度看，她已意识到“剧本”不灵，只能杀跌止损。事发时企图以情绪勒索寻求特权，事中则录视频抵赖意欲逃脱惩罚，事后面对公正执法终于认罪服软。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，此案也再次显示，法律作为“明规则”的重要性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新加坡卫生部长王乙康在社媒发文感谢了警察的公正执法，重申新加坡对于此类行为的零容忍态度，“这正是我们要保护医护人员免遭的行为”。根据新加坡中央医院的急诊规定，前来就诊的患者根据轻重缓急分为四种类型。当事女子的轻伤本来就只是非紧急的“P3”级。医护人员优先将医疗资源用于“P1”与“P2”级病人，当事女子如果对此不满，大可去找私立医院花钱购买医疗服务，而不是大呼小叫寻求特权，或是编个“歧视”的理由抵赖。同时，当事女子将交通事故的情绪转嫁到与之无关的护士与调查员身上，更是不问是非的巨婴行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事件中各方的表现，也再次证明了法律作为“明规则”的重大意义。根据新加坡《防止骚扰法案》（POHA）第6节，“对公职人员使用侮辱性言语”属于刑事犯罪；当事女子不戴口罩，对护士出言不逊，未经允许拍摄视频，本身都已触犯法律，而不仅仅是某些营销号轻描淡写的“就骂了几句”而已。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对当事女子的言语攻击与拍摄行为，警方调查员骂不还口、高度克制，没有超越职权动粗，也没有因为当事女子的夸张言行就“和稀泥”，而是依循正常流程发起控告；如果当事女子对调查员与警察的问讯也不满意，事后她也可以对此投诉，而不是做出视频中明显触法的言行。而从新加坡中央医院的《行为守则》来看，当事女子如果真的遇到歧视，也完全可以经由正常的渠道进行投诉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你等了三个小时就代表你可以对护士爆粗口吗？” 视频中调查员的这句话让不少医护人员“解气”，就在于调查员强调了一个本应是共识的常识：当事女子应照章办事、依法行事，而不应该企图以情绪勒索、操纵舆论等盘外招，绕开明规则为自己寻求特权，或是绑架司法让自己免受惩罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法律作为明规则的意义，就在于“如果一个人只需要遵守法律，那么他就是自由的”。当事女子的这次“文化输出”惨败而归也再次说明，唯有坚持法治原则、不和稀泥，才能让这种“舆论化妆师”（spin doctor）行为不再得逞，在类似公共事件中保障其他当事人的利益，维护社会公正。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[用“算法”找到的舍友是完美选项吗？丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258559]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/JJWJQrgM14LzNNBhaoDc1A8mfKbnkJfWIvlQ33Xb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/JJWJQrgM14LzNNBhaoDc1A8mfKbnkJfWIvlQ33Xb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（农健/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相关报道详见《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/257236&quot; title=&quot;室同道合？一份包含MBTI的大学宿舍分配问卷背后&quot;>;室同道合？一份包含MBTI的大学宿舍分配问卷背后&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“北理工宿舍分配统计MBTI”话题登上热搜后，越来越多高校拒绝随机分配宿舍的尝试被人们关注到。但每个学校用于分配宿舍的标准不尽相同，可能是作息习惯，或者是专业、生源地，又或者是时下最为流行的MBTI（迈尔斯-布里格斯类型指标）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整个采访过程中，始终萦绕在我心头的问题是，用某些具体的指标分配宿舍，会比随机分配宿舍更好吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，很早之前，当部门需要招实习生时，我就曾尝试使用MBTI寻找最“完美”的实习生。我对“完美”的定义包括以下三个指标，有新闻热情、做事靠谱、百折不挠。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原本，根据MBTI所划分的16种人格类型的定义，我归纳出几个理想类型，但在后来连续几次的实习生招募过程中，我惊讶地发现，没有任何一个“理想类型”的同学给我们投递简历。之后和某杂志的编辑交流时，她在听我说完这几种“理想类型”后，很快找到合适的实习同学，我的一个猜测是，在投递简历时，对不同风格的报纸、杂志的偏爱，就是某种人格类型的显现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，我的策略变为，在已有的实习同学中观察，他们中身上如果流露出前述的三种特质，那么再去了解他的人格类型，之后再招募实习同学时，就可以依葫芦画瓢。当然，由于样本量远远不够，这个探索在统计学上绝对是不具有显著性的，换言之，它一定无法推广到总体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;招募实习生，本身也是一个寻找适配同伴的过程，但在采访中我们发现，不同于我们对于“完美实习生”的定义，每个高校对于“完美舍友”的定义是不一样的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有的学校希望学生聊得来，有的学生希望表现优异的学生能“先富带后富”，这就导致分配方式五花八门。即便是同样会考虑MBTI人格类型的分配方式，如何考虑不同类型的搭配，不同学校考虑的要点也有些许不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你的大学宿舍是随机分配的，那会不会进一步思考这样一个问题，为什么拥有一个完美舍友这件事儿，变得重要到需要各个学校捉摸各自的“算法”了？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个可能的答案是，语境正在发生变化。一部分意图让宿舍关系变好的人，他的大学生活是在1990年代或者2000年度过的，那时，舍友是人生最重要的伙伴。而当这些人纷纷成为大学老师之后，他们发现，今天的大学生会以另一种视角理解舍友关系。在稿子中一位受访对象就提到：“很多孩子进入大学以后有很明确的目标：保研、出国……从大一开始，他们就会遵从目标来安排自己的生活，不参与聚餐等集体活动，宿舍可能只是自己的歇脚地。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，这些“算法”是否真的有用？这个问题在四年，乃至更远的未来才能得到一个确定的答案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果仅仅看招募的“完美实习生”，后来我仍然会询问每一位同学的人格类型，通常是在聊天的最后，并从来不会因此而拒绝让某一位同学前来实习。我也会告诉他我的人格类型，提前获悉这一信息，在日后的沟通中能减少很多摩擦。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;MBTI尝试把复杂的个体用一些具体的描述简单化处理。在现实中，哪怕是同一个人格类型，面对困难都会有截然相反的应对措施。它只是人生某个阶段的切片，人的可爱之处在于时时刻刻的变化，某次困难，或者一次愉悦的经历，都会让人发生一点点改变。因此，“完美”也应该是一个过程，任何用单一指标寻找到的“完美”，都会在寻找到它的那一刻，不复存在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[证监会：调整优化融券相关制度， 取消上市公司高管、核心员工融券出借]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258614]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;为进一步加强融券业务逆周期调节，证监会经充分论证评估，根据当前市场情况，对融券及战略投资者出借配售股份的制度进行针对性调整优化，在保持制度相对稳定的前提下，阶段性收紧融券和战略投资者配售股份出借。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;融券端，将融券保证金比例由不得低于50%上调至80%，对私募证券投资基金参与融券的保证金比例上调至100%，发挥制度的逆周期调节作用。同时督促证券公司建立健全融券券源分配机制、穿透核查机制和准入机制，加强融券交易行为管理。出借端，根据有关法规规定可以对战略投资者配售股份出借予以调整，为突出上市公司高管专注主业，取消上市公司高管及核心员工通过参与战略配售设立的专项资产管理计划出借，适度限制其他战略投资者在上市初期的出借方式和比例。同时，证监会将加大对各种不当套利行为的监管，扎紧扎牢制度篱笆，进一步加强监管执法，对各种违规行为，发现一起，查处一起，从严从重处罚。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;证监会将持续强化融券业务监管，及时总结评估融券机制运行效果，并根据市场情况适时调节，更好发挥融券机制的积极作用。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[停更、逃离、迷茫：原创画师与 AI 绘画的抗争]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258543]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/xtUjGvuxHNsnkgOYpk7RpZ4s3HZPCvCq1QYs2Wp8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/xtUjGvuxHNsnkgOYpk7RpZ4s3HZPCvCq1QYs2Wp8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253661&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;梦幻赛博朋克风作品&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（插画师“榴莲煲排骨”/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月起，不少插画师发布停更通知，他们质疑小红书旗下AI绘画产品TriK未经允许，将其绘画作品“投喂”给AI训练，引发版权争议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事情最早源于插画师雪鱼质疑Trik AI发布的图片与自己的原作非常相似。几天后，陆续有多位插画师发现自己的作品疑似被AI喂图洗稿。随着事件发酵，一些原创画师宣布停更，有用户将头像更换成统一的“抵制AI”图案，以示抗议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年以来，ChatGPT在国内掀起了一场AI大模型的狂欢，生成式AI热度空前，百度、阿里、字节等互联网大厂纷纷入局。小红书也在筹备独立的大模型团队，并在4月上线“Trik”。2023年5月底发布的《中国人工智能大模型地图研究报告》显示，参数在10亿规模以上的大模型，全国已发布79个。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生成式AI带来的狂欢仍在继续，但也有不少人担忧AI是否会代替人类的工作，而原创画师目前是受冲击最大的职业之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/o90KDT5Hk9wfM5y7p8knikhOeuXT3CPOHo19GSir.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/o90KDT5Hk9wfM5y7p8knikhOeuXT3CPOHo19GSir.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253662&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;正在创作中的原创画作&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（插画师“榴莲煲排骨”/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;画师在流浪&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;插画师林梦的第一反应是愤怒，她相信每一位对作品付出时间和精力、认真做原创的人都无法接受。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林梦5岁开始画画，一直没有停止。小时候家庭条件普通，被送到绘画学前班只是因为当时比幼儿园的托管费用更便宜，也是这样的机缘，铺就了她以后的人生道路。童年时期，她就是一个喜欢安静的孩子，不会大吵大闹，能坐得住，画画对她而言是一种发泄和表达的手段。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没有漂亮衣服穿，渴望拥有，她就画出来；偷偷买过期的杂志，临摹时尚杂志的人物速写，在这个过程中感受到快乐，她很小就知道美院的存在，那是一个“向往的地方”。在美术老师口中，她就是一个“为美院而生”的孩子，也大概知道自己长大以后一定会考进美院。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从毕业于天津美术学院，到成为一名插画师，一切都是按照理想中的步伐在走。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在两年前，她就尝试过使用AI绘画。当时的技术有限，“非常小儿科，不太成熟”，但AI绘画诞生本身就已经超乎她的想象：冰冷的电子信息通过算法训练就可以完成一幅画。后来这些技术上的突破，更像是一种必然。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林梦并不排斥AI，科幻题材也一直是她创作的偏爱，就像她相信有外星人存在。“每个领域都需要科技化发展，就像小时候大家都在纸上画画，后来又在电子设备上画画一样。”从当下的时代，过渡到人工智能时代，怎么和谐相处是过渡期需要所有人去共同应对的事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;矛盾在于和谐相处是困难的，“因为它确实触犯到了我们的利益，其实也是尊严问题，别人偷了你的成果，你很难会大方地让它拿去。”林梦觉得，AI的不公平之处也在于，创作者要花一个月或者更长时间创作的作品，AI可以在几分钟内画出来差不多的效果，虽然细节不足，但已经能达到圈外人乍一看还不错的效果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为一个没有情感的AI，之所以能够达到这个效果，是因为有大量的原创作品“投喂”，对原创作者来说，这是一件不公平又难解决的事情。没有规则，没有相关法律约束，虚拟与现实就会产生冲突。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年，林梦入驻小红书，以“榴莲煲排骨”的笔名陆续发布原创作品。事件发生之后，她宣布停更，去其他网站重新开始。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原创画师李可也和林梦一样，在知晓小红书和TriK的这一做法之后，决定停更，并把自己的头像更改为“拒绝AI”的图案。在聊到这一话题时，他仍然气愤，觉得这种做法是拼接、投喂、训练而非创造，“只是剽窃前人的辛苦努力拼接而成的尸块，所以我不会认可AI，更不会把AI当成工具，它本质上是剽窃。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;离开了平台，去别处似乎也只是一个暂时的容身之地，未经授权的作品用于AI训练的现象普遍存在。浪潮卷向所有角落，似乎是早晚的事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年11月，插画师洛柒也在微博质疑二次元AI绘画应用Niji·journey涉嫌抄袭，该应用生成的许多图片与一些画师的原创作品相似。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月，网易旗下LOFTERAI绘画功能也被质疑使用用户作品进行AI训练，导致不少原创画师逃到了其他平台。随后，LOFTER下架相关产品，并发布官方致歉信。而如今，其他平台也无法保证这群“流浪”的画师能够找到一个庇护所。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月，B站也因涉嫌用AI绘画洗稿、侵犯网易游戏《一梦江湖》版权而登上热搜。当时，在B站主页更新的“七夕夜”活动宣传图被网友怀疑使用AI制作，还融合了另一位原创画师的作品，甚至留有细节bug：凹进去的手，只有一半的鞋子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不久前，风头正劲的OpenAI和微软收到了一份长达157页的集体诉讼书，被指控未经允许而使用数以亿计的互联网用户的个人信息。原告律师引述了OpenAI安全部门负责人的一段公开发言，该发言指出，它们的AI产品是“一项相当不成熟的技术”，如果没有足够的安全防范，激进地部署AI模型将是非常鲁莽的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就像画师们停更、逃离，或者在作品上标注“禁止AI”，或学习防止被AI训练的方法，都只是暂时，他们非常清楚，这将是一场漫长的挑战。AI浪潮滚滚向前，众生皆被裹挟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lzioPAjx37uyIQOyBtFaU0Qe6BpzjiXEu7UQl4OC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lzioPAjx37uyIQOyBtFaU0Qe6BpzjiXEu7UQl4OC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253656&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;插画师“榴莲煲排骨”的工作台&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（插画师“榴莲煲排骨”/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;AI冲击：一些人拥抱，一些人被裁员&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;职业画师Zela从业两年，是AI绘画最早的一批尝试者——最开始她并不认可AI，但现在已将AI作为工具运用到绘画中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她日常的工作流程是：在构图上借鉴AI，画好草图后，根据AI的一些图片进行配色，把AI当作一个素材库或导师，绘画步骤没有明显变化，但找素材的速度更快了。对她而言，耗费时间的步骤不是细化，而是前期出多种方案供甲方挑选，调整方案直到定稿，可以省下大量重复工作的时间，但因为她与AI还在磨合阶段，总体效率目前没有提高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从早期不认可AI，到接受和拥抱，最关键的原因在于，Zela发现它可以做到辅助作画，而且AI生成的作品有一半有可取之处，“我可以从中学习、吸纳。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她看来，AI绘画目前还只是工具，但以后将是绘画的趋势，“因为太便宜太方便了，尤其最底层的人受影响最大。视觉中国、Artspace、Pixiv已经开通AI供稿渠道，AI图也已经在商用，主要集中在新媒体、活动海报等设计工作中，对动漫和游戏的影响还需观望。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游戏行业从业者林源告诉《南方人物周刊》，游戏原画师包括场景原画、角色原画、美术宣发原画等，不少公司会将游戏原画设计需求外包给专门的公司去负责。外包是按照每张画的金额来付费，可以节省人力成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我所在的游戏项目，已经很明确地用AI做了一些角色设计。据我所知，还有其他几家类似的游戏公司也用了一部分AI绘画技术。最直观的影响就是，本来我们可能要发外包或内部人员去做的一个需求，直接用AI就可以解决了。”他提到，游戏领域的一些中小厂甚至大厂都有用到AI，只是运用程度和修改程度不同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林源举例，比如原来画100张原画，要招5名原画师做3个月或更长时间。现在可能只需要一名原画师，100张图用AI出图，他来做修改，这是一套已经广泛商用的模式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林源说目前AI的影响主要还在下沉市场，能够替代的是对质量和艺术造诣追求并不高的那部分市场，比如网页上的游戏广告，很多都是AI作画。一些对美术包装要求不高的游戏类型，也可以采用AI，但对一些要求较高的需求，需要花费时间设计打磨，目前AI是远远没有办法达到的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林梦的观察与此类似，大厂也有在用AI，但大部分只是辅助参考，并不是完全取代。因为目前的技术还无法取代，但它的确会取代一些快速出单的小公司，“这样的市场需求一直存在，只不过以前画师东拼西凑出来还需要一段时间。AI可以非常快，几分钟或几秒钟，所以才会威胁到这样的一部分公司。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;AI冲击的范围正在越来越广泛，不少游戏公司的美术设计岗位开始裁员，也有不少公司减少原画师岗位招聘。一位二线城市游戏公司的原画师回忆，前几年找工作还很吃香，现在公司大裁员，只留了3位原画师岗位，其余全部被裁。大厂也有危机感，某位大厂画师提到，公司专门调教AI已经花了快一年时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“原画师去面试，工资很容易被压价，不会给太高。一些做原画外包需求的公司，明显感觉需求量变少了，之前一个月不愁单子，现在可能一个月只有这几单。因为有一些需求已经能够用AI来完成了，这是原画师的窘境。”林源所在的游戏项目美术负责人提到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“AI会先从替换劳动力开始，就像在工厂里机器人替换工人，如今AI就是创作工厂的机器人。那些偏向于重复的、技术含量不是那么高的工作会被替换掉。原画师会越来越卷，整个行业越来越精英化，岗位肯定会少。除非整体的市场规模变大了。”林源认为，AI的出现还是为了满足市场需求，哪些可以被现有的AI技术替换，自然而然就会被替换掉。随着未来AI技术的提高，画师这份职业的危机感也会更强烈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使未被AI波及的画师也发现，AI出现之后，客户对时间的要求越来越高了。某种程度上，这是一个快节奏时代催生出来的需求，也倒推了整个生产链条的变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2A1UGazgFur6gR3HxRnNniCiwLt46JvYpk5KfjJj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2A1UGazgFur6gR3HxRnNniCiwLt46JvYpk5KfjJj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253660&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;插画师“是雪鱼啊”的画作（左图）与Trik AI生成图片对比&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（插画师“是雪鱼啊”社交账号/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;侵权行为难举证&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;生成式AI的训练数据库非常庞大，也导致保护知识产权成为现阶段的一个难题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海大邦律师事务所高级合伙人、知识产权律师游云庭告诉《南方人物周刊》，主要难点在于举证，作者没有办法证明平台使用了自己的作品进行训练。根据我国著作权法规定，使用他人著作权作品训练人工智能的，应当取得著作权人的许可，但训练的过程不透明，所以作者比较难维权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还提到，人工智能生成的作品哪怕与原作者的比较相似，如果在特征性文件（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;指作品的特有元素&lt;/span>;）上不一致的——比如腾讯的logo是两只企鹅，企鹅的围巾或蝴蝶结就是特征文件，如果特征文件不一致的，仅仅是一只黑白相间的企鹅——不会被认为构成著作权侵权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海曼昆律师事务所律师刘红林亦指出，根据现有法律和原则，如果平台未取得著作权或著作权授权的作品，擅自使用作者的原创作品进行AI训练、生成内容，存在侵犯著作权的风险。难点在于我国《著作权法》并不保护诸如风格或理念等抽象的“思想”，而仅保护绘画中的具体元素等“思想的表达”，但也恰恰是“思想”方能体现作者的独创能力。在此背景下，若作者发现AI绘画作品与其本人作品存在相似的画风，则维权的难度较大；只有在AI绘画作品存在明显抄袭的情形时，才可以向其主张侵权责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Wp2LUMoUI8J3ToOdjJt3JaWKtIA7Mqt3dEpNSnP3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;493&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Wp2LUMoUI8J3ToOdjJt3JaWKtIA7Mqt3dEpNSnP3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253658&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;小红书上不少原创画师发布停更通知&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在如何证明AI对原创者的侵权行为上，刘红林指出，当前AI技术发展迅速，对素材的选择随机性强，算法的计算规则复杂多样，使得生成式作品的“抄袭”痕迹容易从技术角度去规避。因此，要想证明AI图片生成器侵犯了他们的版权，就要证明具体哪一件作品被复制到AI的算法系统中。然而，算法的“不透明”，让这一证明思路在实践中并不容易落地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，平台用户协议也可能在用户并没有仔细阅读的情况下，同意平台用于AI训练。此次小红书事件引发画师抗议的原因之一也在于：根据小红书的用户协议，该平台有权直接使用用户作品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游云庭认为，平台如果使用用户的作品训练人工智能，应该取得原作者的单独同意，而不是仅凭一个用户协议就可以取得授权。“这个用户协议哪怕签了平台，可能也会因为没有提供对价，而被认定为排除另一方主要权利的格式条款，也就是俗称的霸王条款。”刘红林也指出，一些对用户权益有重大影响的条款，平台有义务重点提示用户。对于存在明显的不平等、免除自身责任而加重对方责任的条款，用户有权主张合同无效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有效的修改，可以避免AI的痕迹太重，可以达到避免侵权以及避免质量太低的问题。”林源觉得，侵权的问题很难解决，如果只用自家图片或商用图投喂AI，学习的范围就比较窄一些。避免侵权，目前更多的做法是做二次修改。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过也有比较谨慎的公司。一位海外游戏公司场景美术从业者告诉《南方人物周刊》，这个问题主要看公司，不同公司对待工具的态度不一样，“我们公司禁止AI作图只是因为AI软件的素材来源我们没法控制，可能会遇到潜在的版权纠纷。与其卷入这类诉讼，不如事先就禁止。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘红林指出，人工智能深度学习所引发的知识产权问题较之一般著作权侵权更为复杂。传统著作权法中所适用的侵权判定原则，不能充分回应人工智能深度学习的侵权问题，相关的法律法规需要逐步完善。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;AI与画师之间的矛盾，刘红林认为关键在于“目前双方之间缺乏一个合适的利益分配机制，AI数据库使用了作者的作品进行数据训练，却没有对应的激励机制。这也是AI行业未来需要着重考虑的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5岁开始学画的林梦，家中有一个角落专门属于绘画，存放着从小到大厚厚的几本画册。有时候，翻一翻过去的画作，成长中的某个情景便如电影般重现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她记得，有幅画是高中时候的一张静物水粉画，被老师批评有“很大问题”，“当时觉得有点天塌下来的感觉。”但也是老师的那次指点，也让她决定主攻色彩，用色彩表达情感，那张画是她成长当中的关键一步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;绘画与情感的连接，是AI无法取代的部分。她现在的画作，以赛博朋克风为主，但并非紫色、蓝色这类冷色调的机械感，她选用了粉色为主的色彩欢快的颜色，一种高饱和度的赛博朋克。林梦说，“我希望科技和机器，不要那么冰冷，天真烂漫和温暖，可以和赛博朋克联系在一起，也是对科技的一种期待吧，相信它能够和人类达到一个平衡点。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（为保护采访对象隐私，文中李可、林梦、林源为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以新一轮冲突已造成双方超过3500人死亡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258616]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦卫生部门公布的统计数字显示，截至当地时间14日11时55分，巴以爆发新一轮冲突以来，加沙地带已有2215人死亡，8714人受伤；约旦河西岸有54人死亡，1100多人受伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/r3ul30Yf0qpASfHeUb5c5ZXZyQhhsrSXuY3QL1Jt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/r3ul30Yf0qpASfHeUb5c5ZXZyQhhsrSXuY3QL1Jt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;此外，据《耶路撒冷邮报》13日晚报道，以色列卫生部数据显示，自本轮巴以冲突以来，以方死亡人数超过1300人，受伤人数至少达到3484人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴以本轮冲突已造成双方超过3500人死亡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[诺贝尔文学奖得主格丽克逝世：她的诗有超越创伤与丧失的力量]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258626]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/8e55339d6974425b5125d21cabec25cb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;738&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/8e55339d6974425b5125d21cabec25cb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;117172&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;图/Katherine Wolkoff&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“&#39;诗人&#39;这个词必须谨慎使用；它命名的是一种渴望，而不是一种职业。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年前，露易丝·格丽克在一篇自传性散文中写道：艺术制作的欲望产生了持续的渴望的体验，这种不安，有时以浪漫的或是性的方式结束。似乎总是有什么东西在前面，下一首诗或下一个故事，看得见，但无法触及。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“要完全理解它，就是要任它缠绕折磨；某一个声音、一块石头，变成了一个折磨——象征这个声音的那首诗似乎就在某处，已经完成，它像一座灯塔，不同的是当游向它时，它就后退。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近60年诗歌生涯，积攒下13本诗集，堆叠在房间一角。偶尔瞥见，格丽克还会刻意压抑某种“偷偷摸摸”的自得，感叹自己“没有浪费时间”。如今，她的桂冠上新添一枚花蕊——诺贝尔文学奖，颁奖词称赞其“朴实无华的诗意之声，让个体的存在普世化”。而她获奖的第一反应是：糟糕，要没朋友了！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或许是有意应和时下全球性疫情的苦难和阴影，评委会主席安德斯·奥尔森在致辞中引用了《雪花莲》，出自为格丽克赢得普利策奖的诗集《野鸢尾》（1992）。它描绘了冬天后生命奇迹般的回归，似乎也象征着诗人的“激进变革和重生”，虽不断受到生活的错误和变化境况的困扰，仍能“从深彻的丧失感中实现飞跃”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7岁看到死亡幻象，十几岁被厌食症扼住喉咙，早慧的少女负担起诗人“见证”的天命。借助神话与宗教寓言，她往返于圣冥两界，实现对“自白派诗人”的超越。如同诗句中的预言，比起圣女贞德，她确实更像拉撒路——《圣经》中经耶稣救治而复活的人，是诗人西尔维娅·普拉斯想“模仿”却最终失却的那条路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在她的诗中，自我倾听着自己剩下的梦想和幻想，在面对自我的幻想时，没有人比她更坚强。”奥尔森说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;饥饿不是为了经验，而是为了理解​&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我生来小心翼翼，在金牛座的标志下。/我在一个岛上长大，茁壮地，/在二十世纪的下半叶；/大屠杀的阴影/几乎没有触及我。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1943年，格丽克生于纽约长岛的一个匈牙利裔犹太人家庭。这寥寥数语，就是她为自己写下的《自传》。由她的第二本诗集名所暗示的是，这片“沼泽地上的房屋”，并不稳固。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;父亲是有着作家夙愿的成功商人，经常给她讲圣女贞德等传说和历史掌故。母亲毕业于名媛辈出的卫斯理女子学院，担当着家庭艺术教育的“裁判官”。她还有一个妹妹，日后成为曼哈顿的银行家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“格丽克的写作不是冷战风格的政治化，而是个人的政治，她的写作回到了对人的身份的认同。这是一个关键，她笔下的女性，无不都在寻找自己的声音。”最早将格丽克引介入国内的译者范静哗指出，美国诗歌传统中私人化写作的兴起，包括西方女性主义的兴起，是格丽克多年来屡获重要殊荣的背景。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对格丽克来说，家庭才显得像是她的“集中营”。“我有强烈的说话欲望，但这欲望经常受到挫折：我的句子，如果被打断，就彻底被改变——被转换，而不是被解释。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;简而言之，&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“她并不符合对孩子的/定义：对什么事都充满希望。”&lt;/span>;成年后，她在诗里写道，&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“所有的捍卫，精神上的固执，坚持/摘下普通人的面具，揭示悲剧，/这些实际上是对世界的无知。/意味着那局部的，变幻不定的，反复无常的——/被&#39;绝对&#39;剔除在外的一切。”（《生日》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，真正的家庭创伤发生在她出生前7天，她的“姐姐”不幸夭折。“她的死亡不是我的经历，但她的缺席是；她的死让我出生。”格丽克后知后觉，在第一本诗集中便做出如此刺目的宣告：“出生，而非死亡，才是难以承受的损失。”（《棉口蛇之国》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;母女关系的紧张，化作幻想中姐妹俩争夺母爱的零和游戏。在《阿勒山》这本“死亡之书”中，格丽克写道，&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“当妹妹死去，/妈妈的心变得很冷，很硬，像一块极小的铁坠。/后来我觉得妹妹的身体/是一块磁铁。我能感到它吸着/妈妈的心进入大地，/这样它才会生长。”（《失去的爱》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她还改写了所罗门断案的故事。两个妈妈争一个孩子，变成妈妈在两个女儿之间被撕扯，而她“甘愿摧残自己”，以证明谁才是那个有义的孩子，不忍心劈开妈妈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种精神症候与很早便意识到写作的“天命”有关。不仅仅是出于摆脱母亲压倒一切的意志，还有那“对纯洁和控制的痴迷”，十几岁时格丽克开始严格执行节食，从85磅到75磅，某种程度上也是效法贞德的苦行，最终发展为厌食症，几乎饿死自己。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“它悄悄开始/在某些女童中/对死亡的恐惧，其形式是/献身于饥饿，/因为女人的身体是坟墓；它会接受/任何东西。我记得/晚上躺在床上/触摸柔软的、离散的乳房，/触摸，在15岁时/我会牺牲的/扰人的肉体/直到四肢不再/开花和逃避:我感受到/我现在的感受，对齐这些词——/同样是完美的需要，/死亡只是副产品。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对完美的需要和反抗形式联系在一起，身体和思想既统一又分离，导向一种“形而上学的饥饿”：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“饥饿不是为了经验/而是为了理解，就好像它可以在抽象中得到。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;七年的精神分析治疗挽救了格丽克。从高中退学后，她中断了正规专业教育，转而进入哥伦比亚大学的诗歌研习班，先后师从两位美国桂冠诗人——莱奥妮·亚当斯和斯坦利·库尼茨。在后者的影响下，她从恃才傲物转向谦逊克制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她坦言，“精神分析教会我思考。教会我用我的思想倾向去反对我的想法中清晰表达出来的部分，教我使用怀疑去检查我自己的话，发现（自己表达中自我下意识地）躲避和删除（的部分）。它给我一项智力任务，能够将瘫痪——这是自我怀疑的极端形式——转化为洞察力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/5baeee3b828154edc453d9aa22355dc5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/5baeee3b828154edc453d9aa22355dc5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;117173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;露易丝·格丽克的部分作品&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;当我感到安全，我就能爱&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;此后，格丽克以积极的眼光看待这段经历，“饥饿感帮助我控制了贪欲，对于获得一个独立的自我大有帮助。”而这似乎也奠定了属于她的“欲望诗学”：在爱中，一无所求。她通过说“不”而非“是”，来表达对世界上想要占有之人或物的渴望。这里无疑显现的是人的有限性。就像《成熟的桃子》，从门口到餐桌，&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“确定性，一件死物/……那下流的嘴/伴着爱而受饿——/它像爱”&lt;/span>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或许，因为爱和死一样令人恐惧，这从童年便已种下：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“恐惧，对丧失的恐惧；/害怕疾病穿着新娘的白裙”（《圣女贞德》）&lt;/span>;；而“织出各种色调的红围巾”的妈妈，也对长大后的儿子说：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“并不奇怪你是现在这个样子，/害怕血，你的女人们/像一面又一面砖墙。”（《爱之诗》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在成熟期代表作、诗集《阿弗尔诺》中，格丽克重新诠释了希腊神话中珀尔塞福涅的故事：她误食冥王的石榴，被劫持为妻，“带着红色果汁的污点”返回家中，她意识到，“她早已是一个囚犯，自从她生为女儿”；冥王想说，“我爱你，没有什么能伤害你”，但他想到这是谎言，他最终说的是，“你已死，没有什么能伤害你。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《燃烧的心》与但丁《神曲·地狱篇》中的主人公弗兰齐斯嘉对话，诠释了“男性凝视”的威力：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“既是火又是永恒/……甚至在我被触摸之前，我已属于你；/你只需看着我。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更富争议的诗作是《山梅花》：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我痛恨它们。/我痛恨它们正如同我痛恨性，/那男人的嘴/它堵住了我的嘴，那男人的身体/它让人瘫软”&lt;/span>;，性交中身体的上下位置，和选择哪朵花“照亮院子”一样属于惯例，但本质上根植于受迫的沉默。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，格丽克一向拒绝被标签化为“连字符诗人”，“女权主义”是其中最显著的前缀。格丽克曾强调，她和妹妹被抚养长大，“为了重新组织、实现和渴望取得令人荣耀的成就……从来没有人要我们相信这种成就是不可能的，无论是因为我们的性别或是我们的历史时期。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她对于“当今一些女人决心作为女人来写作”感到逻辑上的困惑，因为这看起来是雄心受制于性别差异的现存观念。比起性别化的区分，她在意一个“更大的区别”，在对称与非对称、和声与谐音之间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，我们同样无法忘记，格丽克在诗中自称为“不可信的说话者”，在她那里，语言是一种在坦率和伪装之间转换的媒介。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《头生子》中患有产后抑郁症的母亲，《阿勒山》中为父亲哀悼的情感麻木而沉默的女儿，《草场》中面对出轨和婚姻破碎的愤怒而挑衅的妻子……这些形象或多或少，都与格丽克人生中不断遭遇的丧失和孤立相互映照：离过两次婚，一座房屋被大火焚烧殆尽。从此，她成了“梦中人和观看者”，一个“沉迷于丧失”的作者，“20年来等待着忍受无法逃避的丧失”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我想我的生活已经结束，我的心已经破碎。/于是我搬到了剑桥。”&lt;/span>;这段直白的口语，突兀地出现在整个诗集《新生》的结尾，留下一段具有余味的空白，亦不乏幽默和辛辣。&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“我曾告诉自己/从一无所有之中/没有什么能被拿去。/但你还能爱任何人吗？/当我感到安全，我就能爱”&lt;/span>;——这是《新生》给出的答案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;希腊神话中，狄多为埃涅阿斯的离去伤心自杀；在冥界重逢，他请求她的原谅，但她一言不发地走开。在格丽克笔下，她开口请求命运女神允许他回报她的激情，&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; “哪怕时间短暂。短暂与一生/有什么区别：事实上，在这些时刻。/它们都一样，都是永恒。”（《迦太基女王》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这首诗曾收入一本《美国人最喜欢的诗》选集。学者丹尼尔·莫里斯在关于格丽克的导论著作中，饶有兴致地记下这桩轶事：一位密苏里州堪萨斯城的行政助理细致描述了这首诗如何与她对话，帮助她逐渐走出与一位科学家激烈的亲密关系，继续前行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“个人主义和普遍主义的，普通和神谕的，短暂和神话的，悲剧和喜剧的……” 丹尼尔·莫里斯指出，格丽克在当代文学中的“主体地位”具有足够的可塑空间，自毕肖普以来，很难再想到另一位美国诗人能吸引如此广泛的批评家、读者和同代诗人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;格丽克早期的《花园》组诗，包含了“对出生的恐惧”、“对爱的恐惧”、“对埋葬的恐惧”几个部分，它们始终是格丽克的核心主题，然而夹杂在其中的一首《花园》，仍溢出对爱的真实渴望：&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“但仍然/有什么东西是你需要的，/你的身体这般柔软，充满活力，在石头的动物中间。/承认吧：像它们那样是可怕的，/超过了伤害。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;难怪诗人周琰会说：普拉斯之后，女性如何去爱？建议读格丽克。“像她这样的诗人，如果你被表面的那种清冷、清高、拒人于千里之外，甚至时不时的不客气蒙骗，就傻了。这种诗人，不在表面上浪费精力。她关注的是人类的情感、精神和象征。所以内里必然是悲悯和暖的。不是那种内心冷酷或者麻木的诗人，这是根本区别。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个声音在《阿基里斯的胜利》中更为坚定：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“他已经是个死人，牺牲/因为会爱的那部分，会死的那部分。”&lt;/span>;译者柳向阳把格丽克的表达式总结为“爱大于等于死”。渴望超越了自我保护的生活表象，与美德和荣耀的认可相连。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;让更多声音掉落纸面&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;正是从《阿基里斯的胜利》开始，格丽克从神话人物中获取灵感，那些被抛弃的、被惩罚的、被背叛的声音，重新被置入现代社会的语境，成为她既个人又普世的“面具”。用诗歌评论家海伦·文德勒的话说，“给经验以永久的神话形式”，而不是像普拉斯、洛威尔等自白派诗人们那样，将自己的自传经历本身变为神话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;格丽克把带有“自白派”印迹的第一本诗集视为“失败”。虽然诺贝尔奖委员会恭维她，“在她自己严厉和不愿接受简单的信仰原则方面，她比其他任何诗人都更像艾米莉·狄金森”，但格丽克说，狄金森只是她“早期的英雄之一”，后来就读不下去了，像黑板上粉笔或指甲划过，或是疯狂的小淑女的声音——小猫似的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《美国自恋主义》一文中，她尖锐地指出了里尔克式浪漫主义诱人的误导性，“在我们的诗歌中，自恋达到了最可怕的定义：它不是自我的延伸，而是自我的替代品，仿佛死气沉沉的镜子在某种程度上使幸存的男孩得以幸免。”最终导致的结果是：“他到达洞察力的尽头。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在格丽克心里有一种自动句式，以“诗人不应该……”开头，后面的空白可以用任何事物填补。原本，教学也在这个范畴内。但她意外地接受了教职，每年秋天在耶鲁开设诗歌课，还曾担任耶鲁青年诗人奖的评委。她对此抱有感激，认为激发了她的创作动力，其中一位年轻诗人的节奏和结构给了她很大的灵感，她还为此专门向他道歉，担心有任何“剽窃”之嫌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她对学生和自己一样严格，准备新诗的技巧就是彻底忘记上一首，每一本书就是对前一本书的抵制，“我对把里程碑擦亮这样的事没什么兴趣。”格丽克在采访中说，“我脑子里想的是怎么让诗活得更久一些。在这些不断扩展的诗里，他需要抵达出发点不同的目的地。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;典型的格丽克，有着“合金般质地”的语言风格，总是带着冷峻与克制。然而，有别于纸面上阴郁的形象，她会在朗读诗歌时模仿马叫，也喜欢放声大笑。幽默本身也成了她风格更新的武器。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;格丽克说，她总是尝试“让更多声音掉落到纸面上”，以便随时换挡。她喜欢这样的诗：你以为在读一首诗，其实在读另一首，又在读第三首，“每个句子本身都不是从前句推导而来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种音乐般的复调性早在《草场》便已登场，莫扎特的歌剧，成就诗行里的咏叹调。诗人尼古拉斯·克里斯托夫评论诗集《阿弗尔诺》称，18首诗丰富而和谐，“以相互关联的复杂形象、一再出现的角色、重叠的主题，形成一个统一的集合，但其中的每一部分都不失于为整体而言说。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而她所有的作品集，何尝不是一个统一的集合？译者柳向阳2007年联系格丽克，讨论“诗选”中文版出版事宜时，格丽克一开始不愿意，希望一本本完整出版。在美国，2012年面世的《诗1962-2012》也没有用“全集”的名号，除了校对没有做任何修改，也没有个人介绍。“诗是她留给世界唯一的东西。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在十年前的诗集《村居生活》中，66岁的格丽克似乎宣告了某种不可能的休战：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“身体啊，想到我们不会再同行多久，我才/开始感到我对你产生了一种全新的柔情，很生涩、陌生，/犹如我所能记得的年轻时的爱情。”（《十字路口》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她还在写，写得不慢。2014年的诗集《忠实与美德之夜》，继续以非凡的优雅和轻盈接近死亡的主题。最新诗集预计明年也将在美国出版。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去，“饥饿感”始终存在。这是西西弗斯一般的苦役，“艺术家说谎因为他为抵达所困扰，他感觉到了顶点就是他将永远栖居的地方，一个他的负担得到转换的地方：生命中的每一刻，我都站在这座山的山顶上。我两手空空。而那块石头却已增加了山的高度。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在很不一样——一点都不着急。” 格丽克在近年的采访中承认，她可以一边坐在露台上写冷知识，一边想，“这是生活当中最美好的事啊，最甜蜜的事情，就把句子换换位置，想想，哦，这样也行。那种愉悦感。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那是一个美好的夏天，花园里一切都在茁壮生长，没有任何义务。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（参考文献：露易丝·格丽克《月光的合金》《直到世界反映了灵魂最深层的需要》（柳向阳、范静哗译）；Louise Glück,《American Originality》；Daniel Morris,《The Poetry of Louise Glück : A Thematic Introduction》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王毅同美国国务卿布林肯通电话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258628]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 21:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年10月14日，中共中央政治局委员、外交部长王毅应约同美国国务卿布林肯通电话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布林肯介绍了正在访问中东的情况以及美方对当前巴以冲突的立场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王毅表示，巴以冲突不断升级，面临失控风险。中方反对一切伤害平民的行为，谴责一切违反国际法的做法。中方认为，维护自身安全不能以伤害无辜平民为代价。军事手段没有出路，以暴易暴只会造成恶性循环。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王毅指出，当务之急是尽快停火降温，避免加剧人道主义灾难；遵守国际人道法，开辟人道救援通道；支持联合国凝聚国际共识、安理会发挥应有作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王毅强调，解决巴勒斯坦问题的根本出路在于落实“两国方案”，建立独立的巴勒斯坦国，实现巴以双方和平共处。没有阿拉伯和以色列两个民族的和解，就没有中东和平。中方呼吁尽快召开国际和会，推动达成广泛共识。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王毅表示，大国在处理国际地区热点问题时，应坚持客观公正，保持冷静克制，带头遵守国际法。中方将继续根据习近平主席提出的基本原则推进劝和促谈。美方应切实发挥建设性作用，推动问题尽快回到政治解决的轨道上来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布林肯表示，美方支持以“两国方案”解决巴以问题，支持联合国为缓解局势、提供人道救援发挥作用，愿同中方加强沟通协调。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双方还就中美关系简要交换了意见。王毅表示，近期中美陆续开展一系列高层接触，双边关系出现止跌企稳势头，受到两国人民和国际社会欢迎。希望美方同中方相向而行，落实两国元首巴厘岛会晤共识，克服干扰、排除障碍，拉长正面清单，缩短负面清单，切实尊重中方核心利益和重大关切，推动中美关系回到稳定发展轨道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;布林肯表示，美方愿同中方一道，落实拜登总统和习近平主席巴厘岛会晤达成的重要共识，负责任地管理美中关系，推动美中关系保持稳定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D还原水下绝境，亚洲第一人陨命九顿天窗洞穴深处]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258618]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>