<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[华为苹果新机接连亮相，你多久会换一台手机？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256564]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the early morning of September 13th, Beijing time, the 2023 Apple Autumn Conference arrived as scheduled. The highlight of the series, the iPhone 15 series, was previously expected to no longer contain toothpaste. However, after its actual debut, netizens on social media were slightly disappointed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 29, Huawei suddenly launched the Mate 60 Pro for sale without warning, which also made many mobile phone enthusiasts happy and queued up offline to try and purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the market data is not optimistic. Many young people have now recovered from the digital craze. From following Huawei and Apple, they changed their phones every year, to now they have not changed their phones for more than three years. In the second quarter of 2023, global smartphone sales fell 8% year-on-year. This is the eighth consecutive quarter in which the global smartphone market has been in decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaomi founder Lei Jun was once surprised that 23% of users have not changed their phones for more than three years. Honor CEO Zhao Ming also revealed that Honor has the longest replacement cycle among almost all brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Do you want to change your mobile phone? How often does it take to buy a new mobile phone? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Come to the comment area to express your opinion, and we will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[两部门规范大型演出活动管理：面向公众销售门票比例不得低于85%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256578]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 14:24:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In order to strengthen large-scale commercial performance activities with an audience of more than 5,000 people (hereinafter referred to as &quot;large-scale performance activities&quot;) To standardize management and promote the healthy and orderly development of the performance market, the Ministry of Culture and Tourism and the Ministry of Public Security jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Further Strengthening the Standardized Management of Large-scale Commercial Performance Activities to Promote the Healthy and Orderly Development of the Performance Market.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; pointed out that at present, the performance market is rapidly recovering and development, and large-scale commercial performance activities such as concerts and music festivals have increased significantly. While meeting the spiritual and cultural needs of the people, ticket speculation in individual performance activities Problems such as ticket scalping, irrational star chasing, and uncivilized viewing are also prominent. It is required that in accordance with the principle of &quot;whoever organizes the performance is responsible&quot;, the performance organizer should strictly implement the responsibility of the safety subject, strictly establish and implement the safety management system, and clarify the person responsible for safety , establish and improve risk assessment and emergency response working mechanisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; makes the following clear requirements for strengthening ticket management:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Large-scale performance events implement a real-name ticket purchase and admission system. Each performance can only purchase one ticket per ID card. For each ticket, the identity information of the ticket purchaser and the visitor shall be consistent. Performance organizers and performance ticket sales platforms should strengthen the protection of consumers&#39; personal information to prevent unauthorized access and leakage, tampering, and loss of personal information;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Performance organizers should establish a refund mechanism for large-scale performance events and set up Establish reasonable tiered refund fees to protect ticket buyers’ legitimate rights to refunds;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further increase the proportion of ticket sales for large-scale performance events, and the number of tickets sold to the market by performance organizers shall not be less than the number of approved audiences 85%. For the remaining 15% of tickets, personal information should be bound 24 hours before the performance to achieve &quot;real-name binding and real-name admission&quot;;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The performance organizer should clearly indicate its authorized ticketing agency, Guide consumers to purchase tickets from legal channels. The notification obligation should be fulfilled and consumers should be informed of the rules for ticket purchase, admission and refund;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The culture and tourism administrative departments should urge performance organizers and performance ticket sales platforms to provide ticket information for large-scale performance events (including but not Limited to the name of the performance, performance time, number of performances, number of tickets, ticket sales plan, box office revenue and other information) are transmitted to the national cultural market technical supervision and service platform in real time to further strengthen the management of ticketing information for large-scale performance events;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Cultural and tourism administrative departments and public security organs should strengthen the management of local work tickets for large-scale performance event organizers and venues, strictly control the scope of issuance, and prevent work tickets from entering the market and being illegally traded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; requires: Cultural and tourism market management departments and comprehensive law enforcement agencies should strengthen on-site inspections of large-scale performance activities, verify actor information and performance content on-site, and it is strictly prohibited to change actors and performance content without authorization. Lip-singing, performing and other illegal activities; intensify the crackdown on illegal activities; the cultural and tourism administrative departments must strengthen the management of performance ticket sales platforms, and deal with those who fail to verify the qualifications of ticketing business units and performance approval documents in accordance with the law, and resell tickets for Providing services and other violations; the public security organs should intensify the crackdown on reselling performance tickets, comprehensively collect information on ticket reselling and speculation online and offline, promptly discover clues about price increases and disguised price increases, and crack down on online and offline ticket scalping and fraud. Illegal and criminal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; also clarifies: The cultural and tourism administrative departments shall, in accordance with the &quot;Cultural and Tourism Market Credit Management Regulations&quot;, handle large-scale performance activities where the number of tickets sold to the public is less than 85% of the approved number or is less than 85% of the approved number. Performance organizers and ticketing agencies that resell tickets, facilitate the purchase and sale of performance tickets, etc., are deemed to be untrustworthy entities in the cultural and tourism market in accordance with the law. To guide the audience to watch performances in a civilized manner, it is recommended that actor brokerage companies and related entertainment brokerage practitioners should strengthen education and reminders for actors, and actively guide actors to always respect the legal red line and strictly abide by the moral bottom line. Actors are encouraged to take the initiative to speak out, guide the audience to abide by the management regulations of the performance site, and jointly maintain the order of the performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[超标七千多倍？小心“毒耳环”里的有害元素]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256570]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/Q0cYLBRGe5Z0RfFYjKdB6PdQQ5EScvFfqnc512Pw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Q0cYLBRGe5Z0RfFYjKdB6PdQQ 5EScvFfqnc512Pw. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The production process of simulated jewelry includes design, molding, sand casting, welding, polishing, In many processes such as electroplating, harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead appear to be excessive, in order to make the jewelry more beautiful and cost-effective. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nong Jian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Are you here to touch porcelain?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the south of Beijing In a jewelry store near Luogu Lane, when a Southern Weekend reporter inquired about the origin of the earrings, the name of the manufacturer, and whether there was a quality inspection report, the clerk showed an incredulous expression: &quot;It&#39;s just a few dozen yuan, why do you ask? &quot;It seemed like this was the first time she was asked this question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A wall full of earrings, earrings, and ear clips are packed in small grids, densely packed. Under the spotlight, these imitation jewelry, jade and precious metals made of imitation jewelry reflect brilliant light. When the girl picks them up, she also picks up her imagination of beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But behind the beauty, there may be hidden health risks. Many earrings and other imitation jewelry are &quot;three-no products&quot; - no production date, no quality certificate, no manufacturer, and even harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead exceed the standard. Wearing them may cause &quot;allergy&quot; and threaten your health. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mandatory national standard &quot;Regulations on Limits of Hazardous Elements in Jewelry&quot; (GB 28480-2012) regulates harmful elements in non-precious metals (precious metals mainly refer to 8 metal elements such as gold, silver and platinum group metals) Relevant regulations have been set on the limit. Because piercings are in contact with the human body, earrings are more stringent than jewelry such as necklaces that are in contact with human skin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it has been ten years since the implementation of national standards. Due to high testing costs and lack of mandatory requirements, cases and recalls of alloy earrings and other imitation jewelry containing harmful elements exceeding the standard are still common. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The amount of cadmium released in &quot;hot-selling&quot; earrings exceeds the standard by more than 7,000 times&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is the quality of &quot;hot-selling&quot; earrings with a total sales volume of more than 60,000 pieces and an average price of more than five yuan? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, on an e-commerce platform, the non-toxic pioneer team of the environmental organization Shenzhen Zero Waste Environmental Protection Public Welfare Development Center (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;non-toxic pioneer&quot;) placed an order for the top-selling product 10 styles of earrings were sent to a qualified third-party laboratory for testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None of these 10 earrings have quality certificates, product names, manufacturer and other information labels. They are &quot;three noes&quot; products and violate the product quality law. The test report even showed that cadmium content in 3 models exceeded the standard by 6808 times, 6872 times, and 7208 times; nickel release in 4 models exceeded the standard by 0.25 times, 0.5 times, 0.5 times, and 1.8 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/oYt6uFkA6kDbYxGTmA7M4spKESuOui1aCpS6Apd2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1332&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/oYt6uFkA6kDbYxGTmA7M4spKESuOui1aCpS6Apd2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Test results of harmful elements in 10 earrings. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Non-Toxic Pioneer/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After &quot;Non-Toxic Pioneer&quot; reported to the e-commerce platform, 6 products with excessive heavy metals have been downloaded shelf. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a customer, Southern Weekend reporters inquired about the certificates of other products sold by these merchants. Some said that they “have no quality certificates,” while others claimed that they “have them but it is not convenient to provide them.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for imitation jewelry to contain harmful elements that exceed standards. In 2014, authors from the Zhuhai Quality, Metrology, Supervision and Inspection Institute published a paper stating that after testing 40 pieces of imitation jewelry in Zhuhai’s retail market, 19 items contained excessive levels of harmful elements, indicating “the overall quality problem is very serious.” There is basically no ingredient description on the packaging or markings of jewelry. Even large imitation jewelry processing companies only use names such as &quot;alloy/silver-plated/gold-plated jewelry&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, an author from the Guangdong Product Quality Supervision and Inspection Institute published a paper: 50 batches of simulated jewelry purchased on an online platform and the Guangzhou Jewelry Wholesale Market were tested, and 11 batches of harmful elements exceeded the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing, director of the National Jewelry Quality Inspection and Testing Center, is one of the drafters of the national standard &quot;Regulations on Limits of Hazardous Elements in Jewelry&quot;. She told Southern Weekend reporters that in 2007 and 2010, for domestic imitation jewelry , the U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) twice proposed large-scale recalls, which attracted the attention of domestic regulatory authorities and promoted the introduction of national standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;my country’s supervision of the export of imitation jewelry is also becoming increasingly strict. Starting from January 1, 2011, imitation jewelry has been included in my country&#39;s import and export legal inspection product catalog - the import and export commodities that must be inspected are formulated and adjusted by the national commodity inspection department. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even so, news of recalls of exported jewelry has remained frequent in recent years. On the official website of the &quot;Hebei Provincial Defective Product Recall Management Center&quot;, search with &quot;earrings&quot; as the keyword, from March 2018 to November 2022, there are 62 earring product recall information released by the EU, most of which are produced in China, and the defects are all Excessive levels of harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel or lead. According to statistics from the testing agency &quot;ETC Les Testing&quot;, in the second quarter of 2021, there were 66 recall notifications for imitation jewelry from European countries and Canada, including 41 cases of Chinese jewelry. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There is still a lack of quantitative research on the health effects&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Many people have this experience. Their skin becomes red or even allergic when wearing jewelry, especially earrings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jinliang, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Environmental Sciences, told Southern Weekend reporters that in addition to being related to personal constitution, another main reason for allergies may be that the amount of nickel released from jewelry exceeds the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jF5c9yTRnuv4kqrnnCTfDps3iCEoNsD9dw89Qzv2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jF5c9yTRnuv4kqrnnCTfDps3iCEoNsD9dw89Qzv2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Four earrings that were found to have excessive nickel. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Non-Toxic Pioneer/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The production process of simulated jewelry includes design, molding, sand casting, welding, polishing, electroplating, etc. Through multiple processes, harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead appear to be excessive, in order to make the jewelry more beautiful and cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hua, a designer at a jewelry factory in the south, said that nickel is mainly produced in the electroplating process. The worse the electroplating process, the lower the cost, and the easier it is to release nickel. Zhang Jinliang said that in the production of jewelry, adding cadmium will increase the gloss and have an anti-rust effect. Adding lead can improve the flexibility of the jewelry and facilitate shaping. Lead and cadmium are also the main components of many pigments. If cheap earrings and other jewelry are rich in color, the content of these two harmful elements is more likely to exceed the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/guumhbZZDicrgBhye5ii4ryU5TZwZspWZmmQXGHl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;353&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/guumhbZZDicrgBhye5ii4ryU5TZwZspWZmmQXGHl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Three earrings that were found to have excessive levels of cadmium were all around 7,000 times the standard. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Non-toxic Pioneer/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The quality of raw materials is also very important. Zhang Jinliang said that the raw materials of some jewelry are scrap metal or low-quality alloys, which are cheap and may cause excessive heavy metal content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The harmful elements in jewelry exceed the standard and will threaten human health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jinliang said that nickel can easily cause skin contact allergies, and long-term exposure to nickel may cause contact dermatitis, neurasthenia, and cancer reactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cadmium has been certified as a carcinogen by the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC), and is listed as the sixth toxic substance harmful to human health by the United Nations Environment Program and the International Committee on Heavy Metals in Occupational Health. Chronic intake may cause high blood pressure, increase a person&#39;s risk of diabetes, and even cause severe bone damage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the alloy earrings tested by Non-Toxic Pioneer, 8 models were found to contain lead. Although the content meets the standard, it is still not recommended to wear them. Because lead is a cumulative poison that can enter the human body through the respiratory tract, digestive tract, skin, etc., lead poisoning will occur when the accumulation reaches a certain value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simulation jewelry with substandard quality is more harmful to children’s health. Children like to bite jewelry, and some lead products have a sweet taste. Scientific research has proven that the absorption rate of lead in the respiratory tract and lungs of children is much higher than that of adults. my country and other countries have also specifically set limits on harmful elements for jewelry worn by children ≤14 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there have been cases of recalls of children&#39;s jewelry in recent years. For example, from March 12 to 22, 2021, Health Canada issued 4 recall notifications for children&#39;s imitation jewelry, involving 4 products, a total of 3,904 pieces, all produced in China. The reason for the recall was the lead and cadmium content in the products. Exceeds local standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Zhang Jinliang also said that the toxicity of harmful elements is only a theoretical statement. Heavy metals mainly enter the human body through the respiratory tract and digestive tract, and the skin absorption is relatively small. At present, there is no quantitative research data on the impact of heavy metal exposure in earrings on human health; in addition, the piercing part of earrings has a small contact area with the human body. If the heavy metal exceeds the standard, it may cause some adverse reactions, but the probability of causing heavy metal poisoning is very high. Small, &quot;so there is no need to be too alarmist.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jinliang suggested that if you wear earrings and other jewelry for a long time, try to choose precious metals such as gold, silver, and platinum. Their supervision is more standardized and their quality is better. Alloy jewelry with many styles, good shapes and low prices has different usage scenarios from precious metals. You can clean it with alcohol before wearing it, which will help reduce the exposure of heavy metals on the surface of the jewelry. Try not to wear alloy jewelry when exercising, bathing, swimming, etc. , because sweat may increase heavy metal exposure after contact with the alloy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are hidden tricks in the testing industry&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;my country&#39;s imitation jewelry industry started in the 1980s. China is currently the world&#39;s largest exporter of imitation jewelry, forming three major distribution centers in Yiwu, Qingdao and Guangzhou. According to data from Yiwu City, there are more than 300,000 employees in Yiwu&#39;s jewelry industry, with annual sales of more than 20 billion yuan, accounting for more than 2/3 of the total output value of the national jewelry industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gRmBhVAobWJmAbyX2sObDLPh7cQTxyOheciRUyAC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gRmBhVAobWJmAbyX2sObDLPh7cQTxyOheciRUyAC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In November 2017, Qingdao Airport Inspection and Quarantine Bureau and Liuting Airport Customs sampled a batch of incoming imitation jewelry and sent it to the laboratory for testing. The results showed that the sample of imitation jewelry contained lead. More than 30 times more than the standard. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simulated jewelry exported for sale on international e-commerce platforms such as Amazon must provide testing certificates that comply with local standards. For example, the European Union and Amazon require merchants to provide statements or test reports that can prove that products comply with &quot;REACH&quot; (Registration, Evaluation, Authorization and Restriction of Chemicals of the European Parliament and of the Council) regulations, including values ​​for harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many third-party testing companies provide testing services, but a Southern Weekend reporter’s investigation found that there are hidden “tricks” in the testing industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter consulted as a jewelry manufacturer and found that the charge for testing the release of cadmium, nickel, and lead is between 500 yuan and 800 yuan per sample, and the time required is about 7 working days. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For many imitation jewelry, this testing fee is equivalent to the cost of hundreds of products, so there are &quot;hidden rules&quot; for testing services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s possible to play around with the edges.” The customer service of a testing agency on Taobao said that REACH requires each product to provide a test report, but the agency can only conduct one actual test for multiple accessories with similar materials, and other &quot; For &quot;Hitchhiking&quot; products that have not been tested, if you replace the photos with them and the test values ​​remain unchanged, you will also have an &quot;exclusive&quot; test report. The above-mentioned customer service stated that the agency can support a maximum of 10 packages for testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The customer service of some institutions also introduced the &quot;hidden rules&quot; for packaging and testing in larger quantities. &quot;More than 100 models (packaged for testing) are a bit too exaggerated, because export customs clearance and selling on the platform are risky, and the customs and the platform may doubt the authenticity of the test report.&quot; Yang Le, customer service of this testing agency, said to the south A reporter from the weekend said that this kind of demand from customers is very common. &quot;Considering cost issues, it is impossible to test every product, so our customers will put many products together for testing in the name of &#39;series&#39;.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Le said that if jewelry companies are worried that the actual measured harmful elements in their products exceed the standard, they can also provide a &quot;certificate package&quot; service and issue a non-actually measured test report, and the test results can be filled in at will. &quot;This test report must also be uploaded and filed. Although we have not tested it, it is exactly the same as the test report of the actual test.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the premise of &quot;guaranteed&quot; is that the customer needs to sign a contract with the testing agency Disclaimer, exempting the testing company from responsibility. The disclaimer template sent by Yang Le reads: &quot;In consideration of the time relationship of customer needs, after negotiation between the two parties, the testing agency evaluates and issues certificates and reports according to customer requirements. At the same time, the customer promises that the product is qualified and ensures that the products in the sales market meet the requirements. If there is any non-compliance, the testing agency will not assume any legal responsibility or compensation obligations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Le said that the fee for &quot;package certificate&quot; and packaged testing of multiple products are the same, both 700 yuan. Since the &quot;certificate package&quot; does not require actual testing, it only takes 5 working days to complete. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New standards are being revised&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Similar to most products, the supervision of imitation jewelry is based on laws and regulations such as the Product Quality Law and the Import and Export Commodity Inspection Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Product Quality Law stipulates that producers shall be responsible for the quality of the products they produce; if there are national standards and industry standards to protect human health and personal and property safety, product quality shall comply with such standards. Li Suqing said that the simulation jewelry produced and sold by merchants must meet the national standard requirements, but when it is launched in the country, it is not required to undergo compulsory product certification like food, home appliances and other consumer goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, home appliances must obtain &quot;3C Certification&quot; (China Compulsory Certification, China Compulsory Product Certification) before they can be put on the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing believes that if imitation jewelry is included in the 3C compulsory catalog, there will be difficulties and controversy. For earrings that sell for a few yuan, it is unrealistic to ask merchants to spend hundreds of yuan to detect harmful elements. &quot;It will not only increase the costs for merchants and consumers, but also increase the cost of law enforcement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market supervision department mainly adopts random inspections to supervise imitation jewelry. For example, Yiwu City has carried out several special rectifications on alloy jewelry and carried out supervision and spot inspections on an annual basis. The 17 batches of products randomly inspected in 2022 were all qualified after being tested by third-party testing agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, whether simulated jewelry is sent for inspection mainly depends on customer demand. &quot;Many customers do not need test reports because it will increase costs.&quot; Li Hua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior person in the testing industry told Southern Weekend reporters that in China, e-commerce platforms such as Tmall and JD.com and some large supermarkets will require merchants to provide quality inspection reports for jewelry, but some e-commerce platforms Commercial platforms and many offline sales venues do not require this. Li Benben, communications director of the Shenzhen Zero Waste Environmental Protection Public Welfare Development Center, said that Toxic-free Pioneer plans to collect more earring samples from multiple e-commerce platforms in 2024 to investigate product quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing suggested that to improve the qualification rate of imitation jewelry, the illegal costs of enterprises must be increased. According to public information, few jewelry manufacturers have been punished for substandard harmful elements in their products. The Product Quality Law stipulates that those who produce or sell products that do not meet the national standards for protecting human health and personal and property safety may be fined not less than three times the value of the illegally produced or sold products; if the circumstances are serious, the product may be revoked. Business license; if it constitutes a crime, criminal liability will be pursued in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shapes of earrings and other accessories are becoming more and more complex, and the ingredients are not only simulated metals, but also textiles and even batteries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing revealed that the national standard promulgated 11 years ago is being revised. The new version of the national standard in terms of chemical properties may further tighten the limit requirements on lead content; it may also add some requirements on mechanical and physical properties. For example, there are certain regulations on the position of jewelry needle tips and battery-containing jewelry. The specific changes will be subject to the final standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Li Hua and Yang Le are pseudonyms, Southern Weekend intern Liang Chengyuan also contributed)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公职人员做发型被拒，税务局翌日上门查税：这样的营商环境如何让人安心丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256530]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a woman in Tancheng County, Linyi City, Shandong Province threatened a barber shop by showing photos of her uniform, which became a trend on social media. Search. On September 8, the Tancheng County Joint Investigation Team reported that the woman was a staff member of the County Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, and she was given a major demerit. This incident cannot be taken lightly, because it is not just a matter of &quot;the low quality of individual public officials&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to an interview with Mr. Xu, the owner of the barber shop, by Chinese Business Daily, Dafeng News and other media, on August 30, the woman came to the shop to do a &quot;protein correction&quot; hair care project. The hairstylist assessed her hair and said her hair was too dry to do the job. As a result, the woman showed the &quot;uniform photo&quot; on her mobile phone and threatened to &quot;call people from our brigade to come (investigate and deal with the case).&quot; Mr. Xu thought she was just saying harsh words to scare people, but he didn’t expect that tax bureau personnel would come to check the tax the next day. After confirming that there was no tax evasion problem in the barber shop, they would also ask for every account of Charlie’s hair shop since it opened. Mr. Xu was so angry that he posted the surveillance video online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netizens have speculated who this woman is. She can easily mobilize the tax bureau to investigate taxes if she is unhappy. However, both the Tancheng County Taxation Bureau and the Market Supervision Bureau denied that the woman was their staff. After the video attracted attention online, on September 6, two men who claimed to be the woman&#39;s colleagues went to the barber shop to apologize to the owner, but still did not reveal what company she worked for. It was not until this incident became more and more intense online that Tancheng County issued a notice in the name of the joint investigation team on September 8, confirming that the woman was Wang Moumou, a staff member of the county&#39;s Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What this Wang Moumou did reminds people of the &quot;borrowed personnel&quot; of a certain district transportation bureau in Harbin more than a year ago. Because the online ride-hailing driver refused to allow him to smoke in the car, he called the &quot;brothers&quot; from the Transportation Bureau to check on illegal cars and &quot;deal with&quot; the online ride-hailing driver. Why do public officials dare to call &quot;brothers&quot; to inspect cars when they are not performing official duties, or threaten barbershops by showing photos of themselves in uniform? I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s still a sense of superiority: If you don&#39;t follow my requirements, I can punish you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the one from Harbin is from the Transportation Bureau (although he is &quot;borrowed&quot;) and has the power to investigate and deal with illegally operated vehicles, so he can &quot;handle&quot; online ride-hailing drivers. And this Wang Moumou from Tancheng is from the Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau. How could Wang Moumou mobilize the tax bureau to investigate taxes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Tancheng County’s official announcement, she called the 12345 citizen hotline to report the incident. However, most netizens are skeptical about this. After the woman made the threat, the tax bureau came to inspect the tax the next day. Moreover, after the tax bureau confirmed that the barber shop had just opened for a few months and had not yet reached the tax filing period and that there was no tax evasion problem, it also demanded every account from Charlie&#39;s hair shop since its opening on the grounds that the whistleblower was not satisfied. If an ordinary citizen calls the hotline to report, will the tax bureau respond so quickly? Will every account within a few months be verified after confirming that there is no tax evasion? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netizens’ doubts are not unreasonable. Why is the tax bureau so concerned about such a report? Relevant parties in Tancheng County should disclose Wang&#39;s phone recordings or online reporting records to clarify the facts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to showing off his power and threatening the store, netizens also suspected that Wang Moumou was absent from work at will. According to video surveillance, the incident occurred at about 9:40 a.m. on August 30. Tancheng County did not explain in its report why Wang Moumou could go to the barber shop to have his hair done on Wednesday morning. Does the Agricultural and Rural Affairs Bureau&#39;s &quot;lax management of staff&quot; mentioned in the bulletin include its lax management of attendance? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind this incident are public concerns about the local business environment. Just imagine, an ordinary public official can show off his power and threaten, and he can torment operators at will with just a phone call. Who would dare to come here to invest and start a business? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, the investigation and processing results reported by the Tancheng County Joint Investigation Team may be difficult to eliminate public doubts about the local business environment. In an interview with CCTV, the barber shop owner said that he &quot;hopes that the normal operation of the barber shop will not be affected in the future.&quot; This also shows that he is still worried about whether he can operate normally in the future and whether he will be retaliated against again. Relevant parties in Tancheng need to disclose the incident more transparently, and at the same time introduce corresponding measures to prevent merchants operating normally from being unreasonably tortured just because of a &quot;reporting phone number.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[IPO收紧撤单潮起：36起超370亿募资喊停]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256518]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since the China Securities Regulatory Commission made it clear at the end of August that it would tighten IPOs in stages, the long-rumored market listing has become more difficult. It started slowly but gradually became solid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comprehensive interviews and research by reporters from the 21st Century Business Herald found that, in fact, as early as July 24, when the Political Bureau meeting of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China first proposed &quot;activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence,&quot; IPOs had already become obvious. Be strict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wind data statistics, from July 24 to September 10, a total of 36 companies planning to IPO on the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges withdrew or terminated their registration. Among them, there are up to 18 companies on the GEM, 4 on the Science and Technology Innovation Board, 11 on the Shanghai Stock Exchange Main Board, and 3 on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange Main Board, raising a total of 37.814 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5a2dfc0c3241535e10176d2e83b60319.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5a2dfc0c3241535e10176d2e83b60319.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250411&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;The net profit threshold for listing is raised&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A senior insurance agent of a leading brokerage firm who has been in the industry for nearly 20 years told reporters that whenever IPOs are tightened, net profit often becomes a &quot;hard indicator&quot; for listing, and various sectors have The requirements for net profit bottom line have increased. Today, this situation appears again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past, the main board could achieve success with a net profit of 80 million yuan, but now it is basically hopeless if it is less than 100 million yuan. It was more likely that the GEM would be listed at 60 million yuan last year, but now it is almost impossible to achieve less than 80 million yuan. . The fifth set of standards for the Science and Technology Innovation Board has been suspended. Once there is a large loss, even hard-core technology companies will not be able to go public; for companies with technological attributes but not hard enough, as long as they suffer losses, the listing process is likely to be blocked. Moreover, each sector has a negative impact on the listing process. The net profit requirement is not only for the most recent fiscal year. If there has been substandard performance or performance decline in recent years, sustainable profitability will be questioned, and it is also likely to be stopped.&quot; The above-mentioned Baodai told reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from Wind data, the statement of the senior insurance agent has been confirmed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From July 24th to September 10th, a total of three companies on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange main board withdrew, two of which had a net profit of less than 90 million yuan; although the other one had a net profit of 122 million yuan in 2022, it will not be listed in 2021. The annual net profit was only 94 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 20.39%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 11 companies withdrew from the Shanghai Stock Exchange Main Board, 4 had net profits of less than 90 million yuan last year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 18 companies withdrawn from the GEM, 12 will have a net profit of less than 80 million yuan in 2022, accounting for as high as 66.67%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of the four companies withdrawn from the Science and Technology Innovation Board, three have suffered losses in the past two years. Among them, Shugen Internet Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Sroot Internet&quot;), a hard-core technology company focusing on software applications, has no choice but to withdraw. Its losses since 2021 have been more than 700 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For a hard technology company like Shugen Internet, which has suffered huge losses year after year, it is naturally impossible for it to be listed on the main board or GEM. However, it has stepped on the industry trend supported by policies and placed itself on the During the loose period of IPO, it was possible to rush forward according to the fifth set of standards of the Science and Technology Innovation Board, but now that the fifth set of standards is suspended, its listing process can only come to an end.&quot; Baodai said bluntly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the fifth set of standards of the Science and Technology Innovation Board is not universal, but a green channel specially opened for star companies in special industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the requirements, companies that meet the fifth set of standards need to &quot;break through key core technologies and possess original leading technologies.&quot; Such companies may be listed on the Science and Technology Innovation Board even if they are in the research and development stage without generating revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Baodai said, the fifth set of standards is now suspended, which means that regardless of the technological attributes of a company, if it wants to go public, it must not suffer a significant loss, and must even maintain a stable net profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For companies, it will be more difficult to go public and subsequent financing will become more difficult; for investment banks, the number of projects that can be sponsored will decrease and underwriting income will decline. Naturally, they will suffer losses and do not want to see it. &quot;Another industry insider told reporters, &quot;But for investors, it is a kind of protection. Excluding loss-making companies and companies with relatively low profitability from the stock market will, on the one hand, effectively improve the quality of newly listed companies. It helps investors select high-quality stocks; on the other hand, it forces more funds to flow into existing stocks, which helps stabilize stock prices.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/12/e594ea773537f379c1452f71c5c2b28e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e594ea773537f379c1452f71c5c2b28e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>; Image source: Visual China&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Capital-driven companies have little hope of going public&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to investment bank insurance agents, in addition to the increase in net profit requirements, the number of years on the market is also a factor in whether a company can succeed. IPO assessment factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The purpose of assessing the number of years on the market is to determine whether the company is capital-driven.” An investment bank insurance agent told reporters. At present, in addition to emerging fields, hard technology and other industries, regulators expect listed companies to be established for more than ten or even twenty years, rely on their own strength to become stronger and bigger, and become leaders in subdivided industries before listing. Instead of relying on multiple rounds of financing driven by capital, IPO can be achieved in just a few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason for this is that the insurance agent believes that there are two main points: on the one hand, from the perspective of the purpose of listing, compared with companies that have been operating for many years and then apply for listing, companies that have been established for a shorter period of time and rely on capital to promote, After listing, there is a greater probability that relevant shareholders will reduce their holdings and cash out. On the other hand, companies that have been established for a longer time are more likely to enter the maturity stage, have more stable operating performance, and have relatively less risk of performance changes after listing, which is more conducive to safeguarding the interests of investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wind, as of September 10, among the 36 IPO projects that have been withdrawn since July 24, 7 projects are located in companies that have been established within 10 years, and 5 were established in 2016 or 2017. Newly established in the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Zhejiang Tongfute Meike Household Products Co., Ltd., which was established in 2017 and plans to be listed on the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange, has performed well in terms of operating income and net profit in recent years. A net profit of 126 million yuan was achieved in 2021, and the net profit in the first half of last year reached 97 million yuan; operating income is also relatively high, with operating income of 1.948 billion yuan for the whole year of 2021, and operating income from January to June 2022 totaling 916 million yuan. Since 2020, operating income and net profit have increased by more than 20% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the above-mentioned insurance agent also mentioned that the age of establishment is an important factor in whether a company can successfully IPO, but it is not an absolute factor. If the company has good quality, stable ability to continue operating, and broad prospects in the field, even if it is only established for In a few years, there is also the possibility of going public. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Food, clothing, housing, and pharmaceutical companies concentrated on withdrawing orders&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In mid-August, there was news in the market that there was basically no hope of IPO listing of new shares of food, clothing, housing, and housing companies. At that time, the relevant cancellation data was not yet clear. Now, this statement is gradually supported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wind, from September 4th to 6th, three food companies stopped IPOing, one of which has a net profit of over 100 million since 2021 and continues to grow. If the statistical time is advanced to August 14, the number of food, clothing and housing companies that have been forced to terminate the IPO process will reach 7. All seven companies plan to list on the Shanghai Stock Exchange main board. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July 24, a total of 11 companies have withdrawn orders from the Shanghai Stock Exchange main board. This means that among the companies with orders withdrawn from the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange, companies related to food, clothing and housing account for more than 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Ocean Family (Zhejiang) Co., Ltd., which terminated its IPO on August 14, was established in 2009. Since 2020, its net profit has been the lowest at 198 million yuan and operating income at the lowest at 1.835 billion yuan. Its performance far exceeds Motherboard profit requirements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that, judging from the industries of the companies that have withdrawn orders, in addition to clothing, food and housing companies, pharmaceutical companies with good operating performance and longer establishment years also have relatively more cancellations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July 24, a total of four pharmaceutical manufacturing companies have terminated the IPO process. Among them, Fujian Mindong Lijiexun Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., which is preparing for the GEM, was established in 1997. From 2020 to 2022, its net profits were 87 million yuan, 73 million yuan and 98 million yuan respectively, far exceeding those on the GEM. Profit requirements, wipe existing profit standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianjin Tongrentang, a time-honored brand in the traditional Chinese medicine industry founded in 1981, also failed to go public as expected. Its operating income and net profit have increased year by year since 2020. From January to June this year, operating income and net profit have reached 577 million yuan and 144 million yuan respectively, which is several times higher than the profit requirements of the GEM. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[抗癌且延寿——裸鼹鼠体内的神奇能力]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256544]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Both ancient and modern people, most people hope to be healthy and live a long life. The ancients made elixirs to seek the elixir of immortality, while modern scientists explore the secrets of longevity from animals. For example, scientists have discovered something that people have long dreamed of in the naked mole rat, a rodent with sparse hair and wrinkled skin that likes to live on the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This amazing story began ten years ago. Ten years ago, researchers at the University of Rochester announced on the website of Nature that they had discovered an anti-cancer ingredient, high molecular weight hyaluronic acid (HMW-HA), from naked mole rats. Ten years have passed, and on August 23, 2023, the team once again published a more interesting study on the &quot;Nature&quot; magazine website. They found a gene responsible for making high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid and transferred it into mice. As a result, the mice&#39;s health improved, they had significant anti-tumor properties, and their lifespans were extended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/mTnNMgewFJdbzlzWoxQSrfgbcH7NnQM7lEHNpH5d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1231&quot; height= &quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/mTnNMgewFJdbzlzWoxQSrfgbcH7NnQM7lEHNpH5d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The long-lived and cancer-resistant naked mole rat. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Amazing abilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;University of Rochester Biology The reason why Professors Vera Gorbunova and Andrei Seluanov studied naked mole rats was not their initial interest in the longevity characteristics of naked mole rats, but their innate Anti-cancer mechanism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mice and rats are the most common experimental animals, but their life span is generally only 3-4 years, and the incidence of tumors is relatively high, so they cannot be used to study anti-cancer mechanisms. Therefore, Professor Gerbunova The Rochester research team, co-led by Professor Seluan Ruf, focused their attention on naked mole rats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The naked mole rat is a magical rodent that is native to Africa. It lives underground most of the time and feeds mainly on ants and other insects. Compared with common rodents such as mice and rats, naked mole rats have sparse body hair, exposed flesh-colored skin, and are not good-looking. What interests biologists is that naked mole rats have a long lifespan. Their lifespan can reach 30-40 years, which is more than 10 times that of rodents of the same size. Not only do naked mole rats live long lives, they also have extraordinary cancer-fighting abilities. According to scientists’ years of observations of large naked mole rat groups, naturally occurring cancer has not been observed in naked mole rats, and it is difficult to induce cancer in them through experiments. This makes naked mole rats a prime candidate for scientists to study new anti-cancer methods. Ideal animal model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are naked mole rats not prone to cancer? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In previous studies, the Rochester research team found that naked mole rat cells have the ability to inhibit early contact. Contact inhibition is a powerful anticancer mechanism. Normally, when cells come into contact with each other, receptors on the cell surface sense other cells and send a &quot;brake&quot; signal to the interior of the cell to prevent the cell from continuing to grow. However, this mechanism fails in cancer cells. As a result, cancer cells cannot be suppressed even under high-density conditions, and continue to grow wildly until they accumulate into multi-layered lesions. Naked mole rat cells will show contact inhibition at lower densities, while mouse cells need to reach more than three times the concentration of naked mole rat cells to show similar contact inhibition. Therefore, the research team believes that naked mole rats have Early contact inhibition, while other mammalian cells such as mice only have conventional contact inhibition capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how does early contact inhibition develop in naked mole rats? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers found that the protein kinase inhibitor P16 mediated early contact inhibition in naked mole rat cells, while the protein kinase inhibitor P27 mediated regular contact inhibition in other mammalian cells. When P16 mutates and loses its normal function, the early contact inhibition mechanism of naked mole rat cells will be destroyed, and only conventional contact inhibition can be performed, making malignant transformation and even cancer more likely to occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This study did not attract much attention, but it opened the door for the Rochester research team to study the anti-cancer mechanism of naked mole rats. Even greater discoveries are yet to come. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Cancer-fighting genes&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Rochester research team continues to observe the growth of naked mole rat cells and compare them with mammals such as humans, guinea pigs and mice. Comparing the cells, they found that compared to other mammalian cells, the naked mole rat cells in the dish quickly became viscous, like syrup. After analysis, scientists found that naked mole rat cells secrete large amounts of high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hyaluronic acid is an acidic mucopolysaccharide, also known as hyaluronic acid. Hyaluronic acid is commonly found in mammalian skin, cartilage, and other connective tissues and is widely used in pharmaceutical products and cosmetics. Hyaluronic acid mainly acts as a filler and support between animal cells. According to the molecular weight, hyaluronic acid can generally be divided into high molecular weight hyaluronic acid and low molecular weight hyaluronic acid. The hyaluronic acid secreted by naked mole rat cells is mainly high molecular weight and is secreted by other mammals such as humans, mice and guinea pigs. 2-5 times the molecular weight of hyaluronic acid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through further research and analysis, the Rochester research team found that high molecular weight hyaluronic acid is a key extracellular signal for the formation of early contact inhibition in naked mole rat cells, that is, these cells secrete large amounts of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid to cause It floods between cells and forms physical constraints. Naked mole rat cells sense the hyaluronic acid signal secreted by the other party and their growth slows down. Therefore, they can undergo contact inhibition earlier than other mammalian cells and are less likely to undergo cancer. of crazy growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can naked mole rat cells alone secrete large amounts of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It turns out that in vertebrate cells, there are three types of hyaluronic acid synthases responsible for producing high molecular weight hyaluronic acid, including HAS1, HAS2 and HAS3. Among them, HAS1 and HAS3 have nothing in various mammals. The difference is that only the HAS2 molecule has undergone important mutations in naked mole rats. The HAS2 molecule consists of 552 amino acids, and these amino acid sequences are highly conserved in other mammals, but the naked mole rat version has two key amino acid substitutions. This mutation causes naked mole rat cells to secrete large amounts of high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid. At the same time, the hyaluronic acid-degrading enzyme activity of naked mole rat cells is also much lower than that of other mammals, resulting in slower degradation of high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid. Once the HAS2 gene of naked mole rat cells is destroyed through genetic engineering technology, or the hyaluronic acid degrading enzyme is over-synthesized, the high molecular weight hyaluronic acid in the genetically modified naked mole rat will be greatly reduced, and its early contact inhibition function will be reduced. Along with the loss, these naked mole rats are also prone to induce tumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These studies prove that high molecular weight hyaluronic acid is a unique anti-cancer factor in naked mole rats and will bring new ways to prevent cancer. In July 2013, this research was published in the internationally renowned academic journal &quot;Nature&quot;. This was also the first time that the research team of Professor Gerbunova and Professor Seluanruf published a paper in the &quot;Nature&quot; magazine. In this paper, they also transferred the HAS2 gene from naked mole rats into human cells and observed that the transgenic human cells could also synthesize high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid in large quantities, laying the foundation for another blockbuster study ten years later. A foreshadowing was made. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Double surprise&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since naked mole rats are less susceptible to cancer under the protection of rich high molecular weight hyaluronic acid, if other mammals can also Can synthetic high molecular weight hyaluronic acid reproduce the anti-cancer and life-extending effects seen in naked mole rats? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the ultimate goal of the research team of Professors Gerbunova and Professor Seluanruf is to find anti-cancer and life-extending drugs for humans, it is obviously not suitable to directly use them in human trials when the research is not yet mature. Research on human cells cannot completely simulate the effects on the human body, so trying it on mice first is a very good choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research idea and process are simple, but the results are surprising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The research team of Professors Gerbunova and Professor Seluanruf transferred the HAS2 gene, which is responsible for the production of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid, into mice to create transgenic mice. It was found that these transgenic mice The content of hyaluronic acid increased significantly, especially high molecular weight hyaluronic acid was detected in organs such as muscle, heart, kidney and small intestine. However, the hyaluronic acid content in the transgenic mice was not as high as that in the naked mole rats. The researchers speculated that it may be mainly because the hyaluronic acid-degrading enzyme in the mice is more active than in the naked mole rats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further observation found that the incidence of spontaneous tumors in these transgenic mice was significantly reduced, and they were significantly resistant to artificially induced tumors. Regardless of whether they are transgenic mice or non-transgenic control mice, they all age naturally, and most of them eventually die of tumors. Among them, the tumor incidence rate of control mice was 70%, while that of transgenic mice was only 57%. When the mice lived for more than 27 months, the anti-tumor properties of transgenic mice were more significant, and their spontaneous tumor incidence rate was only 49%, while In control mice, it was as high as 83%. When the researchers induced skin papillomas in mice, the incidence of papillomas in the transgenic mice was also much lower than that in the control mice, indicating that the transgenic mice were also significantly resistant to artificially induced tumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even more surprisingly, the transgenic mice also showed extended lifespan and improved health. Relative to control mice, the median lifespan of transgenic mice increased by 4.4%, while the maximum lifespan increased by 12.2%. At the same time, the researchers also conducted a physical examination on the mice participating in the experiment and found that the overall health of the transgenic mice was significantly better than that of the control mice. Especially during the aging process, the inflammation in most organs of transgenic mice was significantly less than that of control mice, and inflammation is an important indicator of organ aging, and the intestinal health of transgenic mice was also significantly improved. Further analysis found that the high molecular weight hyaluronic acid possessed by transgenic mice can reduce inflammatory responses through multiple pathways, including direct immunomodulatory effects on immune cells, protection from oxidative stress, and improvement of intestinal barrier function during aging. etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This research lays the foundation for the application of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid in human clinical trials, and also brings new hope for the development of anti-cancer and life-extending drugs or treatments. On August 23, 2023, the research team of Professors Gerbunova and Professor Seluanruf published the results of this research on the website of &quot;Nature&quot; magazine. It took a full 10 years from the discovery of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid in naked mole rats to proving that it can improve the health of mammals, which reflects the difficulty of basic research and also reflects the efforts of Professor Gerbunova and Serouanlu. This is the reward for the long-term efforts of Professor Hu’s research team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, the team also plans to conduct human clinical trials, hoping to achieve the goals of both anti-cancer and extending lifespan by increasing the synthesis of high-molecular-weight hyaluronic acid in the body or slowing down its degradation. The miraculous anti-cancer and life-extending benefits of the body are brought to humans, opening up a new way for human health and longevity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国人寿保险（集团）公司原董事长王滨一审被判死缓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256536]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/93c908a94264080cab76402e2672ddba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;3909&quot; height=&quot;2827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/12/93c908a94264080cab76402e2672ddba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023, the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Jinan City, Shandong Province publicly pronounced the verdict of the former Party Committee of China Life Insurance (Group) Company In the case of Secretary and Chairman Wang Bin accepting bribes and concealing overseas deposits, the defendant Wang Bin was sentenced to death for accepting bribes, with a two-year suspended execution, deprived of political rights for life, and all personal property was confiscated, and his death penalty was suspended for two years. After the sentence is commuted to life imprisonment in accordance with the law, he will be sentenced to life imprisonment without the possibility of commutation or parole. He will be sentenced to one year in prison for concealing overseas deposits. It is decided to execute the death penalty with a two-year suspended sentence. He will be deprived of political rights for life and all personal property will be confiscated. After the two-year suspension of execution of the death penalty is commuted to life imprisonment in accordance with the law, he will be imprisoned for life without commutation or parole; the property and accrued property obtained by Wang Bin from bribery that have been seized, detained, and frozen will be recovered and turned over to the state treasury. The remaining portion will continue to be used. Recover. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/174fe68c179a8af032bfcdd04fb3ffe6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;4635&quot; height=&quot;2566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/174fe68c179a8af032bfcdd04fb3ffe6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250450&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It was found after trial that from 1997 to 2021, the defendant Wang Binli served as deputy secretary of the party group and deputy president of the Jiangxi Branch of the Agricultural Development Bank of China, secretary of the party committee and president of the Beijing Branch of the Bank of Communications, and the president of the Bank of Communications. Member of the Party Committee and Vice President, Chairman of BoCom International Trust Co., Ltd., Secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of China Taiping Insurance Group Co., Ltd., Secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of China Life Insurance (Group) Company and Chairman of China Guangfa Bank, etc. Facilitation and the formation of convenient conditions of authority and status provided assistance to relevant units and individuals in matters such as loan financing, project cooperation, personnel arrangements, etc. I illegally received property directly or through my relatives, totaling more than RMB 325 million. Starting from January 2012, Wang Bin violated the national foreign exchange management system and the overseas deposit declaration system for state personnel by depositing a total of more than 56.42 million yuan in foreign currency into bank and securities accounts opened by his relatives in Hong Kong, without concealing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jinan Intermediate People’s Court held that defendant Wang Bin’s behavior constituted the crime of accepting bribes and concealing overseas deposits. The amount of bribes Wang Bin accepted was particularly huge, the circumstances of the crime were particularly serious, the social impact was particularly bad, and the interests of the country and the people suffered particularly heavy losses. He should be sentenced to death for the crime; Wang Bin committed the crime of concealing overseas deposits and surrendered, so he may be given a lighter punishment and be separated from the people he belongs to. The crime of accepting bribes shall also be punished. Since Wang Bin truthfully confessed his crimes after being brought to justice, confessed and repented, and actively returned the stolen goods, he had legal and discretionary circumstances for lenient punishment. He was sentenced to death, but it may not be executed immediately. At the same time, based on the facts and circumstances of Wang Bin&#39;s crime, it was decided that after the expiration of the two-year suspension of his death penalty, which would be commuted to life imprisonment in accordance with the law, he would be imprisoned for life without commutation or parole. The court then made the above judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[学生不订牛奶要医院证明：别都把锅甩在老师身上丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256542]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a piece of news about “teacher asking students to order milk” has attracted attention. On September 7, parents in Suiping County, Zhumadian, Henan Province broke the news that a primary school teacher posted a message about students ordering milk. A screenshot of the chat in the online post showed that a teacher sent a message saying that if a child cannot drink school milk due to a certain disease, Parents need to provide proof of diagnosis and treatment from a county hospital or above medical institution. The teacher also said that there are 53 students in the class, 15 of whom have completed the registration process, and he hopes that the parents of the remaining 38 students will &quot;actively cooperate with the work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This news triggered a wave of public opinion as soon as it was exposed. The teacher&#39;s words are suspected of &quot;forced ordering of milk&quot;, which seems to be &quot;unsightly&quot;. The style of &quot;forced buying and selling&quot; has also aroused doubts and ridicule from netizens, awakening everyone to &quot;order milk&quot; and &quot;order teaching materials&quot;. &quot;Childhood memories&quot; of ordering designated books. In particular, the words &quot;unless you prove to be sick, you must order milk&quot; and &quot;do you expect the teacher to treat 53 children equally&quot; were even threatening, which attracted a lot of negative comments from the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant departments in Suiping County stated on September 8 that the County Education Bureau had investigated clearly on the 7th that the matter was the &quot;personal behavior&quot; of a class teacher at the Central Primary School in Shenzhai Town, Suiping County. &quot;Medical Certificate&quot; is also an inappropriate statement by the teacher personally. At the same time, only this class has mandatory requirements, and other classes are voluntary. At present, the county education bureau has criticized the teacher and asked the teacher to apologize to the parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the only &quot;milk ordering incident&quot; in Zhumadian recently. On September 7, a parent in Zhengyang County broke the news that a primary school teacher said that he &quot;actively orders if there are conditions, but creates conditions to order if there are no conditions.&quot; Judging from the screenshots of the WeChat group posted online, the teacher posted &quot;Milk Man&quot; in the WeChat group Everyone needs to order!&quot; message, and said that &quot;taking into account the financial pressure of parents&quot;, the &quot;milk ordering quota&quot; for each semester has changed from the original &quot;440 yuan for a full portion of 4 boxes&quot; to &quot;per school consultation&quot;. People only order 3 boxes for a total of 330 yuan.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 8, the principal of the school said that ordering milk was on a voluntary basis, and the teacher’s wording was wrong, and a meeting would be held again to study it; a staff member of the local education bureau said that the higher-level department required ordering milk for the healthy growth of students. , but following the principle of parent voluntariness; the Education Bureau stated in a briefing on September 8 that the problems reported by netizens were basically true, and that the class had deviations in its interpretation of the spirit of superior documents and was suspected of violating the principle of voluntary subscription, so it would immediately suspend the promotion of drinking milk. work, rectify and standardize it, and investigate and deal with relevant responsible personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost at the same time, two &quot;personal acts&quot; of teachers forcing students to order milk occurred in Zhumadian. Looking at the timeline of the two incidents, it can be said that they are similar; the same trend followed. The &quot;mandatory ordering of milk&quot; was considered to be the teacher&#39;s &quot;personal behavior&quot;. At the same time, it was insisted that the milk ordering work for students followed the principle of voluntariness. However, upon careful review of these two incidents, there are still some questions that need to be analyzed and questioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, when teachers ask students to order milk, is it really their &quot;personal behavior&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the screenshots exposed in the two incidents, the Zhengyang County teacher mentioned that &quot;after consultation with the school&quot;, the Zhengyang County Education Bureau clearly stated in the briefing that this was a &quot;deviation in interpretation&quot; of &quot;superior documents&quot;. Without these &quot;documents&quot; being suppressed, what motivation would a mere elementary school teacher have to turn into a salesman? Why would there be any need to issue vague intimidation and inducement to many parents such as &quot;create conditions if there are no conditions&quot; and &quot;order milk if you are not sick&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the two incidents, if the teacher risked misinterpreting superior documents to do something that prompted parents to report it, what was the purpose behind it? If there is no profit motive to support it, the argument of &quot;personal behavior&quot; will obviously be more difficult to establish. In the case of conflicts between &quot;superior documents&quot; and &quot;voluntary principles&quot;, how can teachers grasp &quot;personal behavior&quot; in order to satisfy both superiors and parents at the same time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, it is necessary for the education department to publish the original text of the &quot;superior document&quot; originally issued, or to announce to the public what the specific instructions for the &quot;project&quot; of milk subscription are, so that it can be clearer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the two &quot;forced milk ordering&quot; incidents also show that grassroots teachers bear too many non-teaching burdens in their daily work, which is a major root cause of many similar incidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the current education system, teachers, as actual grassroots personnel and the end of the power chain, have a rather embarrassing situation of &quot;little power but big responsibility&quot;: this &quot;responsibility&quot; is to be responsible to the superiors, not to the superiors. Responsible to parents and students; the &quot;higher-level departments&quot; are responsible for issuing instructions and issuing notices, but in practice they have &quot;great power but little responsibility&quot;. They have great power but are not responsible for students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, grassroots teachers have taken on too many additional tasks that are not part of teaching. The DingTalk group on the left, the WeChat group on the right, check-in today, receipt tomorrow, cultural performance here, textbook subscription there, resulting in a considerable amount of time and energy being occupied by non-teaching tasks, seriously affecting the duties of teaching and educating people. In fact, grassroots teachers often have to transmit top-down pressure to parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take these two incidents as an example. Regardless of whether the subscription of milk for students is reasonable or not, this task should not be left to teachers in the first place. There are a lot of administrative staff in the education system. It would undoubtedly be much better for them to be responsible for taking care of students&#39; health and choosing better dairy products than to impose an irrelevant responsibility on teachers out of thin air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teachers in primary and secondary schools should be freed from the imposed non-educational burdens, focus on teaching and educating people, and better serve students rather than superiors. Otherwise, teachers will be allowed to do all kinds of things if nothing happens. When something has nothing to do with teaching, it is regarded as &quot;teacher&#39;s personal behavior&quot;. This is too bullying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“骂醒恋爱脑”服务：当情感变成生意，爱真的能骂醒吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256554]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/yVwqc8dgVtJ4PixgRy7l4nenvljJ6IFmUtgobDkg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;950&quot; height=&quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/yVwqc8dgVtJ4PixgRy7l4nenvlj J6IFmUtgobDkg. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The TV series &quot;Xue Pinggui and Wang Baochuan&quot; broadcast in 2012 has recently been reinterpreted by netizens. The plot In the novel, Wang Baochuan and Xue Pinggui ate wild vegetables to satisfy their hunger for eighteen years, and are known as the &quot;originators of the love brain&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Come on, how do you want to scold me?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just joined the Southern Weekend reporter Go to a friend and Z sends a message in the chat box. After confirming the request of &quot;be more direct&quot; and &quot;don&#39;t use curse words&quot;, without even asking about the gender, Z began to type:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She doesn&#39;t love you, why do you love her?&quot; , no one wants to talk to you, but you still act like an ATM machine?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Followed by a yin and yang emoticon, and then asked politely: &quot;Do you listen? If not, I will change it. species.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Z asked about the specific situation only after the Southern Weekend reporter informed him of his gender and gave a negative answer. In this chat world, the Southern Weekend reporter is a &quot;love brain&quot; who gave up the postgraduate entrance examination for her boyfriend. Now she is deeply in the pain of &quot;being broken up&quot; and longs to be &quot;scolded to wake up&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It doesn&#39;t matter, why keep it and give him money to fall in love?&quot; After listening to this &quot;story&quot;, Z tried his best to persuade him to break up and launched a series of questions: &quot;Why don&#39;t you understand, why are you still looking forward to it?&quot; , Why should you expect from him, he is handsome? Rich? Will he be gentle to you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Paying money to scold you may sound a bit unbelievable. Around Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day, this service, known as &quot;scolding to wake up the love brain,&quot; became a booming business on e-commerce platforms, and then became popular on social platforms such as Xiaohongshu and Douyin. Many users took orders on their own and paid for scolding. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/oSiDa9OXFh1Jmf8pKRUukJzleIavaabhqJpB2R2h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;767&quot; height= &quot;1695&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/oSiDa9OXFh1Jmf8pKRUukJzleIavaabhqJpB2R2h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In a Taobao store with over 10,000 sales, a Southern Weekend reporter ordered the &quot;Scolding to Wake Up Your Love Brain&quot; service. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Rongrong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person who originally coined the term &quot;love brain&quot; may not have expected that after countless interpretations , spread, this label may make some people who are already in emotional struggle more suffering, intensify their self-denial, and even declare it to the people around them becomes difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, with the release of the movie &quot;The Disappearance of Her&quot; and the launch of the TV series &quot;My Earthly Fireworks&quot;, the protagonist&#39;s series of &quot;love brain&quot; behaviors aroused active discussion among the audience. Nowadays, &quot;anti-love brain&quot; has evolved from a word of mouth to a business, and many people who are stuck in the mud are reaching out, eager for some stranger to pull them out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can find many stores that provide services by searching for &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; on Taobao. In a Taobao store with tens of thousands of sales, different levels of escorts correspond to different prices. The Southern Weekend reporter selected a &quot;blind box&quot; that could only specify gender, and was assigned female escort Z. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Z provides services using WeChat text or voice, charging 15 yuan for 20 minutes. Her avatar is that of a beautiful female Internet celebrity, and her circle of friends looks very life-like, sharing her feelings and thoughts. In this short chat, Z left a motto: &quot;Put away your tears, no one will like a girl who likes to cry, and he will not feel sorry for you crying.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Southern Weekend After the reporter expressed the pain of not being able to escape, Z persuaded him to &quot;put a filter on him&quot; and &quot;sick&quot;, and then reminded him that the time was up. Z started timing the moment he added a friend, regardless of the fact that the conversation actually started five minutes later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You can do it, believe me. All the love brains I talked to before said it&#39;s okay.&quot; The 15 yuan service came to an abrupt end. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Take the initiative to place an order, &quot;Love Brain&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Qing&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Half awake&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the store owner Li On the price list provided by Yu, the large characters &quot;Eliminate Love Brain&quot; are very eye-catching on the pink background, and a line of small characters underneath reads: &quot;Online guidance from the emotional master&quot;. The price list shows that &quot;Love Brain&quot; is divided into three levels: light, medium and heavy. Customers can choose according to their own level. The service time of an escort ranges from 15 minutes to 1 hour, and the price ranges from 20 yuan to 180 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu is 26 years old. After graduating from high school, he worked as a game companion and managed the companions and companions under his guild. Later, the guild was disbanded, and she found that there was a huge market for chatting. At the end of 2021, she opened a Taobao store to provide chatting and emotional counseling services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around Chinese Valentine&#39;s Day, the news about &quot;cursing to wake up the love brain&quot; caught her attention. According to reports, this service can earn tens of thousands of yuan a month. Li Yu, sensing a business opportunity, changed the name of his existing emotional counseling service and launched a new business called &quot;scolding to wake up the love brain&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the official launch of the service, Li Yu went to other stores to place orders and experience it. She placed two orders. One of the escorts started scolding her as &quot;too stupid&quot; before she finished telling her story. Li Yu felt that her emotional intelligence was too low and wanted to leave a bad review at the first reaction; the other almost Just chatting, not helping with analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on these experiences, Li Yu told the customer service staff in his store to try their best to send orders to escorts who are experienced in emotional counseling. They can get started quickly. In addition, the escorts are reminded to pay attention to their emotional intelligence. Although it is called a &quot;scold wake-up&quot; service, they must also be careful about their attitude, unless the client demands straightforwardness and toughness. In general, Li Yu concluded that it is a type of &quot;relatively strong emotional counseling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Lu is one of the first batch of shopkeepers to carry out &quot;cursing to awaken the love brain&quot;. In April, short videos of emotional persuasion became popular on Douyin, usually accompanied by provocative music. Bloggers were excited and launched a series of questions: &quot;To be sentimental is to humiliate oneself&quot; and &quot;If you are not proactive, you don&#39;t like it.&quot; It’s almost meaningless to hang you up.” Xiao Lu was inspired to try to develop a &quot;scolding to wake up love brain&quot; service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The escorts in his store have different backgrounds, including full-time mothers, corporate HRs, and professional psychologists. He lets them watch Douyin videos to learn the &quot;waking up&quot; technique. In this industry, the voice of the chatter is very important. Xiao Lu pays more attention to emotional intelligence and experience. Those who are older and experienced are usually not too bad in chatting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many shop owners interviewed denied that this service can earn tens of thousands a month. At its peak, Meng You&#39;s Taobao store could receive forty or fifty &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; orders every day. At its peak, it earned several thousand yuan a day, but it only lasted a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, many stores that engage in &quot;scolding to wake up your love brain&quot; are derived from the chatting business, and are provided by the original chatting teachers. Meng You claims that there are about 600 escorts in the store, most of whom work part-time, and the male to female ratio is about 2:8. The escorts in Meng You&#39;s store are divided into six levels: blind box, gold medal, town store, male and female goddess, chief, and koi. They are arranged according to the frequency of orders, academic qualifications, customer preference and other conditions. The higher the level, the higher the charges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Meng You’s observation, more than 90% of the customers who placed orders for “cursing to wake up your love brain” are women. Most of the customers are between 18 and 28 years old. About half have relationship problems themselves, and the other half order for friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Meng You’s view, if a customer can take the initiative to place an order, his “love brain” is already half awake. “People who are not awake can’t order because they don’t want to be scolded.” Meng You said Southern Weekend reporter said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5obPocoVwyvkU5ZkT3eHNwqz91VDdxsv7uqhOk9B.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1972&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5obPocoVwyvkU5ZkT3eHNwqz91VDdxsv7uqhOk9B.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Scolding to wake up the love brain&quot; has become a prosperous business on e-commerce platforms. Some shop owners said that at the peak, the daily income was several thousand yuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Whether it has any effect or not, he said it&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Just started&quot; During the service of &quot;Scolding to Wake Up Your Love Brain&quot;, Li Yu tried to take an order in person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The client is a girl. She discovered that her partner has been chatting with others on other social software. After the two broke up, she has been unable to get out. After hearing this, Li Yu did not scold her. She felt that the other party was already feeling very uncomfortable and &quot;there is no need to attack others.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu helped analyze with a straightforward attitude: The girl&#39;s partner just likes to chat everywhere. If the girl can accept it, then go to retain him and continue to be together; if not, then love yourself well. The girl did not give an answer on the spot and said she would go back and think about it. Later, the girl found the store&#39;s customer service and left a reward for Li Yu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The escort, Xia Lin, has a neutral and steady voice. She is studying for a Ph.D. and her expressions are very logical. In life, she is good at giving advice to friends and dealing with emotional problems. She has been working part-time as a chat companion for more than three months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She considers herself to have a strong &quot;sense of separation&quot;. Although she can empathize with customers when &quot;scolding her to wake up her love brain&quot;, she is more accustomed to rational analysis, &quot;What I want to do is to help you solve the problem.&quot; . Li Yu also emphasized that you can&#39;t just scold, you should focus on the other person&#39;s situation, and you can&#39;t give strong suggestions right from the beginning. You should at least listen to their story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlene will usually first understand the basic situation of the client and let the other party talk. &quot;If this girl or boy has something he wants to talk about, he doesn&#39;t need you to guide him, and he will want to talk for two hours.&quot; Charlene said that it is important to guide the other party to explain the details clearly, which is helpful for analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She received an order. A boy had been dating online for a year, and they started talking about marriage without ever meeting him. Only after they broke up did he realize that he had been cheated. He places orders with Charlene almost every day. Charlene advised him not to compete with her. Although the other party cheated during the relationship, she did not defraud him of money and provided a lot of emotional value, hoping to make him feel relieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Frankly speaking, many people are willing to listen to the truth, not necessarily to hear lies.&quot; Charlene told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Escortist Chen Qing has been engaged in escorting since January. When she first heard stories from customers who were &quot;scolding to wake up their love brain&quot;, her mood was also affected. Sometimes she just couldn&#39;t persuade her. &quot;Move&quot;, she felt a little weak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As she received more and more orders, she gradually became disinterested, &quot;That is their life, and their life has nothing to do with me. I am just a bystander, so I can&#39;t go there no matter how powerless I am.&quot; Help them do anything. That&#39;s their life, choice and attitude.&quot; Chen Qing said, &quot;That&#39;s his life, why do you want to interfere? Tell him that you must break up. If something goes wrong, you still have this responsibility. I can&#39;t afford it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Xiao Lu&#39;s view, &quot;scolding to wake up the love brain&quot; actually only provides a supporting role. Many orderers just want to find someone to talk to and vent their inner emotions. &quot;Actually, it&#39;s just a confession.&quot; He said, &quot;No matter whether it has any effect or not, he said it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After taking orders for a long time, Charlene found that most of the cases were similar. &quot;The commonality is that they may all have obsessions, and they may have suffered emotional harm, mental control, and PUA. They may have it all, but they refuse to give up.&quot; She said, &quot;Thinking and doing are two different things. You can&#39;t get rid of emotions.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Charlene once took on a case where a forty-year-old woman fell in love with a married man who was over seventy years old and could not get away for several years. Charlene felt that the other party was not going to give up, so she did not ask the other party to give up. &quot;Respect individual feelings. She has her own choice. She is an adult.&quot; She said, &quot;She just needs to reconcile with herself. She does not have to be responsible to anyone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Charlene It seems that it is useless to analyze the general principles. &quot;Can you not know the general principles?&quot; A customer once said to her that after finding so many people, Charlene was the only one who could consider it from his point of view. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“When it’s time to be in love, you’re also in love”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Li Yu has been a companion for five years and has heard many other people’s love stories. She considers herself to be quite smart and gentle in relationships. cautious. But she hasn&#39;t always been like this. &quot;When it&#39;s time to be in love, she&#39;s also in love.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her last relationship, in her words, &quot;just lost her IQ.&quot; During that period of foreign love, when the relationship was still ambiguous, the other party suddenly disappeared for two months. During that time, she often called the other party, but the other party never hung up or picked up the phone. Her friends advised her that she had met a &quot;scumbag&quot; who cheated on her feelings. She couldn&#39;t believe it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One time, the other party finally picked up the phone. Faced with Li Yu&#39;s questioning, he explained that he was traveling on vacation and knew that Li Yu had been trying to contact him, but &quot;just didn&#39;t know what to reply to.&quot; After Li Yu believed and forgave him for his &quot;disappearance&quot;, they were officially together. A few months later, when the boy returned to China, Li Yu discovered that he had another girlfriend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu feels the same way for people who place orders to &quot;swear to wake up their love brain&quot;. She knew that the process of coming out &quot;would be very sad.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her opinion, emotional problems are difficult to control rationally, &quot;I think everyone is a love brain. In a relationship, no one is so rational, and emotional emotions lead to love. Brain tendencies.&quot; Li Yu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the breakup, Li Yu couldn&#39;t get out for a long time. When talking to her friends, she pretended to be cool and did not dare to confess her pain. Because her friends have already tried to persuade her many times, but &quot;there is nothing to be persuaded&quot;, they may decide that she deserves it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu can only order online and ask someone to &quot;scold her&quot; to wake her up. She doesn&#39;t dare to go to the escorts in her store. They all know her. &quot;You can&#39;t lose this face in your own home. You have to find some strangers to throw it away.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu told the unfamiliar escort that if she felt her behavior was silly or had other feelings, she could tell her true thoughts directly without worrying too much about hurting her. Some escorts directly scolded her for being stupid, &quot;There are so many men in the world, why do they hang on a tree?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After hearing this, Li Yu was torn in her heart. In fact, she knew these truths very well, but she just couldn&#39;t get out of them. She could calm down temporarily only when she was scolded. She placed the order many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long after Zhou Ningning broke up, she tried to find someone on Douyin to &quot;scold&quot; her. She feels that her ex doesn&#39;t like her very much, but she still wants to keep him. The escort analyzed all the shortcomings of her ex, and for a moment she felt that she was &quot;sick&quot; and would actually put down her dignity to save him. But a few days later, she couldn&#39;t help but send another message to her ex to save her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a staged thing, and it cannot be solved once or twice.&quot; Li Yu said that maybe the customer figured it out at the time, but then &quot;went into the abyss of emotion.&quot; There may be many recurrences, which are normal, and the &quot;wake up&quot; service cannot be solved once and for all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Speaking out may be just the first step. In Li Yu&#39;s view, the most important thing to get out of the love brain is to rely on yourself. It took her half a year to really get out of it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After a person is tempted, it takes time to get out of the relationship. Time is a necessity.&quot; Li Yu told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Xiao Lu and Meng You are the names in the industry, Li Yu, Xia Lin, Zhou Ningning, Chen Qing (pseudonym)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日防卫费“12连涨”，“美国因素”占几何]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256562]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/HK6bzwbOV2s1RQb5E3BkZnSKhA1ThU2oKSzZDmUl.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/HK6bzwbOV2s1RQb5E3BkZnSKhA1 ThU2oKSzZDmUl. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 28, 2023 local time, Japanese Defense Minister Hamada Yasuichi was in the Cabinet The 2023 version of the &quot;Defense White Paper&quot; was released at the meeting. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the shadow of Fukushima nuclear contaminated water being discharged into the sea, the Japanese government has proposed the highest level of defense in history Budget. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Japan&#39;s &quot;Mainichi Shimbun&quot; report on September 5, 2023, Japan&#39;s Ministry of Finance announced the budget application amounts for fiscal year 2024 of various government departments on the same day. Among them, the budget application for fiscal year 2024 submitted by the Japanese Ministry of Defense More than 7.7 trillion yen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with 6.82 trillion yen in the previous year, the new defense budget increased by nearly 1 trillion yen in one fell swoop, an increase of 13.5%, setting a historical record since World War II. At this point, Japan’s defense budget has increased for 12 consecutive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is one of Japan&#39;s steps to implement &quot;doubling the defense budget&quot; and also brings the Kishida Fumio government one step closer to the goal of &quot;total defense expenditures reaching 43 trillion yen in five years.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;As early as the Abe administration was in power, Japan has been seeking to get rid of the label of a &#39;defeated country&#39; in World War II, break through the constraints of the &#39;post-war system&#39; on the development of its military power, and become a true &#39;political and military power&#39;. A big country.&quot; According to Sun Wenzhu, associate researcher at the Asia-Pacific Institute of the China Institute of International Studies, the substantial increase in Japan&#39;s defense budget is not surprising. &quot;Given that the Liberal Democratic Party holds a majority in the Japanese Congress, the probability of the budget passing review is very high. In the next few years, if there are no major changes in the political arena, Japan&#39;s defense budget will continue to maintain high growth.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Benchmarking NATO&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;In recent years, Japan&#39;s economic development has been sluggish, but its defense budget has been rising. If this budget is passed, Japan&#39;s defense spending will set a record of &quot;12 consecutive increases&quot; since 2013. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the 1960s, Japan’s defense expenditure has remained below 1% of GDP. The situation began to change in fiscal year 2016, when Japan&#39;s defense budget exceeded 5 trillion yen. In the next seven years, Japan&#39;s defense fee application amount has exceeded 6 and 7 consecutively, and the interval has continued to shorten. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Analysts pointed out that on the road to military expansion, the Japanese government has shifted from &quot;running in small steps&quot; to &quot;running in big steps.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, Japan’s defense expenditure exceeded the “GDP1% framework” for the first time, becoming a landmark event. However, Japan&#39;s ambitions are not satisfied with this. According to the plan of the Kishida Fumio government, Japan must not only break through the &quot;red line&quot; but also achieve &quot;doubling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, Japan officially adopted three security policy documents: the new version of the &quot;National Security Strategy&quot;, &quot;National Defense Strategy&quot; and &quot;Defense Force Preparation Plan&quot;, clearly proposing to step up efforts to build &quot;outside defense capabilities&quot; , increasing the total defense expenditure in the next five years to about 43 trillion yen, reaching about 2% of GDP. What needs to be emphasized is that the 2% figure is exactly what the United States proposes to NATO member states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The year-on-year increase in defense expenses essentially reflects that Japan&#39;s defense policy and national strategy have seriously deviated from the &#39;peaceful line&#39; pursued after the war.&quot; Sun Wenzhu pointed out that Japan&#39;s military strength building has clearly &quot;shifted from defense to defense.&quot; &quot;offensive&quot;, and continues to strengthen its ties with the United States, trying to re-realize its ambition of being a military power that can &quot;offend and defend&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aligning the defense budget with NATO is just the tip of the iceberg in Japan’s efforts to move closer to NATO, led by the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Fumio Kishida took office as Prime Minister, Japan and NATO have continued to deepen their cooperation mechanisms, with frequent high-level interactions between the two sides. NATO Secretary-General Stoltenberg made no bones about it and said that no Asian partner is closer to NATO than Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the deep connection in the cooperation mechanism, the two sides have also continued to shift the focus of cooperation to the field of military security. In 2022, Japan’s three major Self-Defense Forces will go to NATO to participate in military exercises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan intends to further strengthen its military and expand its armed forces by following the United States&#39; strategic thinking of maintaining its hegemony through &#39;group politics&#39;.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, faced with a series of severe challenges such as economic downturn, high inflation, depreciation of the yen, and soaring prices, rising defense costs will become an unbearable burden for the Japanese economy. According to the &quot;Japan Times&quot; report, in order to pay for expanding defense costs, the Japanese government may consider selling its shares in Japan&#39;s largest companies, but it is difficult to reach an internal consensus. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;U.S. strategic priority? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Japan’s record-breaking defense budget includes a “package plan” such as the procurement of naval warships, F-35 fighter jets and armored vehicles, and the development of new hypersonic interceptor missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan&#39;s increase in defense budget not only intends to build a strong defense system, but also highlights the ambition to accelerate the development of military strategy toward offensiveness.&quot; Zhang Xuefeng, a military expert, told Southern Weekend reporters that this is fundamentally It stems from Japan&#39;s desire to &quot;become a political power&quot; and also the strategic need to cooperate with the United States&#39; deployment in the Western Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, Japan released a new version of the &quot;Defense White Paper&quot;, continuing to reiterate that it must have &quot;counterattack capabilities&quot; and listing &quot;outside defense capabilities&quot; and &quot;joint air and missile defense capabilities&quot; as part of the Japan Self-Defense Forces The top two capabilities that need to be fully developed in the next five years. Relevant requirements are reflected in the fiscal year 2024 defense budget. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan has finalized an investment of approximately 380 billion yen to build two &quot;Aegis system carrier ships.&quot; The two ships are 190 meters long, 25 meters wide, and have a standard displacement of 12,000 tons. They will become &quot;Japan&#39;s largest post-war surface combat ships.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The &#39;Aegis System Carrier Ship&#39; is not a simple defense platform. It has powerful maritime combat capabilities after being equipped with the &#39;Type 12 Coast-to-Ship Missile Phase II Improvement&#39; and the &#39;Tomahawk&#39; cruise missile. &quot;Zhang Xuefeng analyzed that this is actually Japan building a cruiser with both offense and defense under the guise of a &quot;ballistic missile defense ship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While building an anti-missile shield, Japan has also taken a multi-pronged approach to improve its off-zone strike capabilities. According to the US &quot;Defense Post&quot;, Japan plans to spend approximately 750 billion yen on enhancing the country&#39;s &quot;standoff&quot; combat capabilities, mainly involving the development and procurement of missiles that can be launched beyond the range of enemy firepower, including the &quot;Type 12&quot; &quot;Second-stage improved shore-to-ship missile&quot;, Jasm AGM-158 joint standoff air-to-surface missile, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;These measures by Japan are to implement the goal of having a &#39;counterattack capability&#39; in the &#39;New Three Security Documents&#39;, and then make up for its own shortcomings in the offensive field.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in fact, deploying medium- and long-range missiles and extending the range of existing missiles is not only necessary for Japan&#39;s &quot;counterattack capability&quot;, but also the &quot;missile chain&quot; that the United States is eager to build on the first island chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, the United States contacted Japan and planned to deploy medium-range missiles in Japan, greatly enhancing its ability to launch attacks from the first island chain. Japan&#39;s Sankei Shimbun said that the missile planned to be deployed may be the &quot;Long Range Hypersonic Weapon&quot; (LRHW) or &quot;Tomahawk&quot; cruise missile being developed by the US military. Coupled with the missiles Japan plans to deploy to enhance its &quot;counterattack capabilities,&quot; the United States and Japan may join forces to build a &quot;medium-range missile network.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the United States’ wishful thinking is being realized step by step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 28, the U.S. State Department approved the sale of &quot;Jasm&quot; missiles to Japan, with an estimated value of 15.2 billion yen. As early as the 2023 defense budget, Japan earmarked 211.3 billion yen to purchase 400 US-made &quot;Tomahawk&quot; cruise missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The range of the &#39;Tomahawk&#39; cruise missile is only about 1,600 kilometers. If deployed in the second island chain, there will be a problem of insufficient range, so the United States has always wanted to deploy it in the first island chain.&quot; Zhang Xuefeng pointed out that Japan, which is determined to follow the United States, is naturally the best choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;From Japan&#39;s perspective, the Japan-U.S. alliance is the absolute cornerstone of Japan&#39;s security, and its own security is inseparable from the maintenance of U.S. hegemony in the Western Pacific.&quot; Sun Wenzhu believes that relevant measures are to maintain the U.S.&#39;s hegemony in the Western Pacific. relative military advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Everyone has their own plans&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After Kishida Fumio proposed doubling Japan’s defense budget, in January 2023, US Secretary of State Blinken gave a press conference Publicly praised it and said, &quot;Japan&#39;s strategy is closely related to our own national security strategy.&quot; U.S. President Biden even said in his speech that &quot;I convinced&quot; Fumio Kishida to increase defense spending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the United States is one of the main beneficiaries of the defense cost &quot;package plan&quot; announced by Japan. In the defense budget for fiscal year 2024, Japan will not only purchase a large amount of US-made equipment, but also plans to jointly develop new interceptor missiles with &quot;hypersonic weapons&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Selling weapons to Japan allows U.S. military industrial companies to earn huge profits, but more importantly, Japan’s military strength continues to increase and it is more capable of becoming a pawn in the U.S.’ Indo-Pacific strategy. .&quot; Zhang Xuefeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2022, the U.S. military decided to withdraw all two squadrons of F-15C/D fighter jets from Kadena Air Base in Japan, directly reducing the fighter force of the U.S. Air Force in Japan by half. The reason given by the United States is that the fighter planes are old and retired, but the American &quot;Stars and Stripes&quot; stated that the reason why the U.S. Air Force withdrew the F-15 fighter jets is because &quot;they cannot avoid China&#39;s attacks in the first island chain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;As defense difficulties continue to increase, the United States hopes that Japan will continue to enhance its military strength, play more roles, and reduce its military pressure on the first island chain.&quot; Zhang Xuefeng analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan is also actively integrating into the &quot;group politics&quot; of the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, Fumio Kishida attended the NATO summit again, regardless of domestic public opposition, to facilitate NATO&#39;s opening of a liaison office in Tokyo. In August just past, US President Biden, South Korean President Yoon Seok-yue, and Kishida Fumio held a summit meeting at Camp David. The Associated Press stated that the Camp David Agreement signed by the three parties consolidated the &quot;Asia-Pacific Mini-NATO&quot; and deepened the security and economic ties between the United States, Japan and South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan is well aware that promoting &#39;military power&#39; and &#39;normal nationalization&#39; must be recognized and supported by the United States, so it must dress itself up as the United States&#39; support for the so-called &#39;free and open international order&#39; &#39;Right-hand assistant&#39; or even &#39;equal partner&#39; in exchange for Western countries recognizing their status and influence in the security field.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Japan also has its own little thoughts. In the defense budget for fiscal year 2024, the Japanese Ministry of Defense included a budget of more than 50 billion yen to develop new domestically produced missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Wenzhu pointed out that after the United States withdrew from the &quot;Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces Treaty&quot;, it once intended to deploy missiles to Japan, but Japan was not willing to passively accept it, but hoped to develop or purchase medium- and long-range missiles. &quot;Once a crisis breaks out, Japan can retain some room for maneuver based on the actual situation and its own interests.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the longer term, Japan&#39;s ultimate goal is to try to get rid of US control and regain its autonomy. &quot;If the United States relaxes its vigilance against Japan and allows its military expansion, it is likely to end up in a situation where it is out of control, which may not be a good thing for the United States.&quot; Zhang Xuefeng pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[非婚女性可申领生育保险：非婚生育会瓦解婚姻制度吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256520]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;More and more places have relaxed restrictions on non-married women applying for maternity insurance. Recently, the Guizhou Provincial Medical Insurance Bureau issued the &quot;Notice on Improving the Maternity Security System&quot;. From October 1, 2023, the maternity insurance benefits of insured persons will be fully decoupled from personal marital status; the Chongqing Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau issued the &quot;Notice on Optimizing Maternity Insurance&quot; &quot;Notice on Matters Related to Handling Services&quot;, starting from September 1, for insured persons applying for maternity insurance-related benefits, maternity service certificates, reproductive service certificates, and marriage certificates will no longer be collected. Currently, mainstream public opinion interprets this relaxation as the decoupling of marriage and childbearing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the five insurances, maternity insurance used to be an independent insurance type but has now been integrated into the urban employee basic medical insurance. The special thing about this insurance is that individuals do not have to pay, only the employer pays. However, whether payment is made in the name of an individual or an organization, it is actually part of the unit&#39;s labor cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All five insurances are compulsory, but compulsory purchase is also purchase. Since an individual has purchased maternity insurance, of course he should enjoy corresponding maternity leave, maternity allowance and maternity medical services when giving birth. . If there is a prerequisite for having children after marriage in order to enjoy these benefits, then those who are not ready to get married but want children and those who are neither married nor have children should be given the option not to purchase maternity insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, allowing unmarried women to apply for maternity insurance is, in a sense, just returning to them the rights they should have enjoyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, the decoupling of marriage and childbirth does not start with localities allowing non-married women to apply for maternity insurance, nor does it start with localities liberalizing birth registration, but begins on June 26, 2021. The &quot;Decision on Optimizing Fertility Policies to Promote Long-term Balanced Development of the Population&quot; issued by the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council is a programmatic document for the implementation of the &quot;comprehensive three-child policy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This provision applies to both married and unmarried persons. From then on, having children out of wedlock was free from financial penalties and would not affect one&#39;s personal future. Decoupling fertility from marriage. Under this general principle, it is logical to relax the restrictions on non-marital childbirth and restore the rights that unmarried women should enjoy during childbirth, which will further decouple marriage and childbirth in both directions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people say that decoupling marriage from childbirth in terms of policies and systems will reduce the willingness and rate of marriage, and even disintegrate marriages and families. This statement is questionable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, as long as the essence of marriage is that men and women form a family to cooperate in raising children and transfer survival resources to the next generation, then marriage will never disappear, only a certain form of marriage will disappear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don’t have a narrow understanding of marriage. Marriage usually has two meanings. One is marriage in the sense of natural law and customary law. A man and a woman hold a wedding in accordance with the customs, rituals and terms recognized by both parties, form a family, get the approval and blessings of their parents, relatives and friends, enter each other&#39;s social circle, and then have children. Raising children and enjoying various customary rights is very ancient. This is the essence and source of marriage. The other is marriage registration, the main and substantive part of which establishes the common property relationship between husband and wife, which is a practice only in the era of nation-states. In many people&#39;s minds, marriage is the second type, but obviously the first type is more fundamental. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, &quot;couples born in the 1990s do not get a certificate after three years of marriage&quot; has caused heated discussion. It tells the story of sleepy and Zhang Shuo, a couple born in the 1990s, who went from college to getting married. It has been three years since their wedding but they still haven’t received their marriage certificate. Wang Sleepy said it was because something bad happened at the wedding that made her hesitant about Zhang Shuo, so she &quot;dodged&quot; the certificate the next two times with the excuse of not bringing a photo. Looking back at Zhang Shuo&#39;s attitude But he didn&#39;t seem to care. He admitted that he could understand Wang Sleepy&#39;s approach and he didn&#39;t value this certificate very much. Is this considered married or unmarried living together? The word used by the media is &quot;couple&quot;. Apart from not establishing the joint property relationship between husband and wife through marriage registration, are there any substantial differences between them and being married? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, even if a single child is born, it does not mean that one person is raising the child, it only means that the marriage is not registered. Even if single parents raise their children alone, this model will not become mainstream at least in the foreseeable future. Marriage and family are still the mainstream, and the more common marriage and family model is still that men are the main economic source of the family and provide transfer payments to their wives and children. This is still the lowest social cost way to raise children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if a woman with good family conditions or high personal income enters into marriage, she may be financially stronger than the man. As long as both parties do not think there is any problem, then there is no problem; if the decision is made If you have a single child and raise your children alone, as long as you don&#39;t think there is any problem, then there is no problem. Reproduction is a basic right, and it is important that everyone enjoys this right; as for whether a specific individual will exercise this right, it depends on the individual&#39;s economic conditions and values. More choice rights and range of choices are always good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, from the perspective of rights, whether it is marriage or childbirth, it is ultimately a matter of values. If anything can pose a challenge to marriage, family and childbirth, it must be values. A good value should be friendly to marriage, family and childbirth, friendly to mothers and babies, and should also see the dedication of the father. The foundation should be full of vitality, exuding strong vitality and abundant virtues. From the individual to the family, from the family to the country, life is endless and endless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>