<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[女律师参加庭审后遭袭：降低律师职业风险有赖于公众形成正确认知丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260761]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 2, 2023, a video of a man hammering a woman on the street spread online. It shows that the incident took place near the Tongxiang Municipal Court in Jiaxing, Zhejiang. The local police issued a report stating that the criminal suspect Cao Moumou (male, 36 years old, Henan nationality) armed Lou Moumou and injured Lou Moumou due to a dispute. An internal report from the law firm stated that after lawyer Lou participated in a civil case trial at the Tongxiang Municipal Court on November 2, he was followed by the other party and attacked with a hammer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is almost no time lag when the incident occurred on the same day and the video was released on the same day. News narratives can naturally influence public perception. However, in the era of decentralization, it is difficult for one party to monopolize facts and narratives, and there is even a lack of intentionality. Unintentional rumors and even rumors creep in, so public perception may change depending on which narrative prevails. This incident is another typical case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, with little other background information, what the public notices is the gender narrative. Of course, the public is still very interested in the nature of disputes and the content of civil cases. Some netizens immediately dug up: This is a real estate dispute case. Lawyer Lou is the agent of the real estate company and the man is the owner. Subsequently, it was also confirmed by media reports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on these facts, a popular rumor has appeared on the Internet: The man bought a unfinished building from a well-known developer and then sued to defend his rights. Lawyer Lou &quot;helped the tiger&quot; and won the lawsuit. , the man took the risk in anger, and some people even said with emotion, &quot;The lawyer&#39;s fees she received may be the house payment paid by the man.&quot; Based on this narrative, there are no small voices expressing sympathy for the man online. But in fact, the person who had the dispute with the man was a local real estate company called Orrick, not an online developer, which in itself weakens the credibility of the information. Of course, the truth requires further investigation, so no further speculation will be made here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We focus on the interaction between narrative and public perception. The lawyer who was attacked had multiple identity labels: female, white-collar worker, lawyer, agent of a real estate company; the perpetrator also had multiple identity labels: male, home buyer/owner, litigant... What identities did the two choose to tell the story? Can influence public perception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there is a problem with the gender narrative used by some of the earliest big Vs. If we talk about beating people, the correct value should be: no one should take the initiative to commit violence to cause physical harm to others, regardless of whether the perpetrator and victim are male, female or have other identity backgrounds. To judge the nature of an assault, one should start from the merits of the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the subsequent narrative of &quot;a real estate company agent who works as a swindler vs. an owner/home buyer who is bullied and forced to a dead end&quot; captured many people. Under this narrative, many people sympathize with the owners/home buyers, and the underlying value is that the weak are justified. If the man bought an unfinished building, he would indeed receive more sympathy; if he just wanted to check out because of the falling housing prices but did not want to bear the cost, he would receive less sympathy. In either case, though, why would the man hammer a lawyer who was merely an attorney? In addition to venting your anger, it does not help solve the problem, but instead involves yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the last unavoidable question is, what kind of correct understanding should the public have of the lawyer profession? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the female lawyer was attacked by the opposing client, there were two typical opinions in the lawyer circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One is to talk about the professional risks faced by lawyers, express a sense of indignation and tragedy, and demand that the man be severely punished to serve as a warning to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other also acknowledges the existence of occupational risks, but emphasizes that individuals should effectively avoid them. For example, a lawyer said that when he first started practicing law, an old lawyer warned him: Don&#39;t deliberately anger the other party. This is strategic risk aversion. Some lawyers also said: Lawyers should still stand on the side of fairness and justice. Lawyers should not become slaves of &quot;money&quot; and &quot;power.&quot; Lawyers serve their clients, but they cannot become an accomplice. You can&#39;t be just for profit, this is to avoid risks through the choice of values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind this is how to view the lawyer profession. I believe that there must be a considerable number of lawyers who engage in this profession just to pursue justice, protect rights and defend the rule of law. These spiritual pursuits transcend income considerations, but in addition to such idealists, there will also be practitioners who take a fancy to them. Lawyers have better income prospects and higher social status as a profession, and their talents and interests are also conducive to pursuing this profession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, for the vast majority of lawyers, it is the lawyer&#39;s work scope and professional ethics to be hired by the client to defend the client and strive for the best interests. The pursuit of factual truth and fairness and justice beyond the &quot;two creations&quot; (from &quot;Shu Jing Lu Xing&quot;, specifically referring to both parties in the dispute) are more of the primary consideration of judges rather than lawyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this reason, lawyers use all their skills and skills inside and outside the court to try to get the judge to accept the narrative version they have constructed and the legal principles they cited, and to guide the judge to reject the other party’s arguments. The structure, narrative version and legal principles cited are used to allow the parties to win the case or minimize losses. Even in such a scenario, ambiguities in the law will be used to guide the judge to interpret it favorably for his client. These are common practices used by lawyers to help clients win cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scope of work and professional ethics of lawyers are to help clients win lawsuits. If the public elevates and highlights the profession of lawyers in other directions, it will undoubtedly form a wrong understanding and thus have a negative impression of lawyers in their hearts. Having moral requirements that go beyond the scope of work and professional ethics is actually putting lawyers on the fire. Therefore, the public should still have a correct understanding of the content of lawyers&#39; profession. This will dispel many people&#39;s unrealistic fantasies and requirements for lawyers and help reduce the professional risks faced by lawyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[明学昌、明珍珍、明国平三名缅北电诈重要头目被缅甸警方逮捕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260773]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 19:19:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to Myanmar Myawaddy TV, on November 16, due to the implementation of online fraud, kidnapping, For illegal detention, extortion and other criminal activities, three important leaders of a telecom fraud criminal group in northern Myanmar, Ming Xuechang, Ming Zhenzhen, and Ming Guoping, were captured by the Myanmar police in the Kokang Autonomous Region in northern Myanmar. The Myanmar police had previously issued a wanted order for relevant personnel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[周泽雄：三部电影，三种仇恨]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260663]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;I am a moderate movie watcher. I have marked &quot;watched&quot; more than 1,800 movies on &quot;Douban&quot; Department, actually more than that. Seeing too much does not mean knowing too much. Greed will damage the aesthetic digestion function and make you afraid of topics such as &quot;favorite movie&quot; - when the word &quot;most&quot; comes out, all kinds of emotions are mixed. It seems that the emphasis on A and B means betrayal of Bing and Ding. Usually, I have something to say only through the constraints of themes and categories. Influenced by the war in distant places, I thought of some films involving the theme of &quot;hate&quot;, and I will briefly recommend them here, limited to three. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/jIuky9U1vKDmS808x28XPRDUfDVNwHuHFSC5SJ18.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;601&quot; height= &quot;841&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/jIuky9U1vKDmS808x28XPRDUfDVNwHuHFSC5SJ18.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; &quot;Munich&quot; (&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;2005&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This is the second time Steven Spielberg has directed a Jewish film. Different from &quot;Schindler&#39;s List&quot;, which is about suffering and salvation, this film is based on the racial killings that took place in the Munich Olympic Village, focusing on the grievances and vendettas between ethnic groups. The subject matter is documentary, the mood is tragic, and the melodies of funeral songs are always lingering. , conveying the tragic atmosphere of never peace. The film refuses to end in a happy ending, which not only respects the facts but also conforms to morality: despair is unpleasant, but it is a truly serious emotion. Forcibly displaying greenery in a barren land is essentially nothingness and cowardice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director used realistic techniques to reproduce the working methods of the five Jewish killers. Their deeds of eliminating their opponents one by one can easily be deified on the big screen, but the film restores their mundanity. They are not cold and capable professional killers. Their techniques are amateurish, they often make mistakes, and they are also mired in unextricable fear. Three of them died in the revenge of their rival &quot;Black September&quot;. Although the remaining two were lucky enough to survive, they were insulated from the quiet and peaceful years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They took over this dark job entrusted by the government, and their motivation was related to the national destiny and national humiliation. They have no personal grudges against their opponents. Every time they succeed, they will sharpen their opponent&#39;s will and make a tougher opponent sit in the dead man&#39;s position. Victory becomes an illusion and the result is nothing more than a pie in the sky. However, the living space of the two nations is too overlapping and squeezed, and the historical disputes are too entangled. Both sides are accustomed to sanctifying their own interests and despising or misinterpreting the other side&#39;s submissions. Hatred has become the core of justice, and revenge has become the norm. and faith. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end, the male protagonist, Mossad agent Avner, was on the verge of losing control mentally. He did not even dare to sleep on his own bed and huddled in the closet. The director probably wants to say: Hatred is not the solution. Using revenge to pursue justice will only banish peace; and peace is the heart of justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/beJdHoQckRKshl9OOoXZVL3sNGMZxfjlYqagkU9N.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;529&quot; height= &quot;748&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/beJdHoQckRKshl9OOoXZVL3sNGMZxfjlYqagkU9N.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; &quot;Black Book&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Book&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot; (2&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;006&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;People are good at Rationalizing one&#39;s own hatred, the real traces of &quot;hate&quot; are much more hidden. This is the unexpected revelation of the Dutch movie &quot;Black Book&quot;. The film is also based on real people, and hatred serves as a booster for the plot, with a changing spectrum. The blood and blood of hatred seen by the audience are mostly the phantoms of demons caused by the selfish greed of individuals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story of the heroine Rachel has the highest tear-jerking value. However, director Paul Verhoeven does not pursue a sense of documentary and solemnity. He has fast-changing rhythms and overly eye-catching scenes, and Rachel’s Her sweet looks and open demeanor all work together to prevent viewers from spiraling into grief. She originally deserved the best life, but because of her Jewish identity, she was suddenly buried under Hitler&#39;s genocide policy. All her family members died tragically. Matching bad luck. ——With another director, the film could easily be made into a tear collector. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The various hatreds present in Rachel&#39;s life have complex ingredients. She was supposed to join forces with her compatriots to avenge the sworn Nazis, but the result was extremely absurd: because the local Jews were relatively wealthy, and although Nazi military discipline supported anti-Semitism, it prohibited the SS from enriching their own pockets, poaching Jews became a problem for some locals. The Dutch made money by using the curtain provided by the Nazis to carry out sinister acts and plunder crazily. In the end, Rachel suffered major injuries, mainly from the deadly assassinations of her compatriots, while SS Captain Munz became her tragic lover who was separated forever. After the Nazis surrendered, a large number of Dutch losers who had done nothing during the war began to smear their hatred. They concealed their cowardice through their perverted enthusiasm for the &quot;anti-rape&quot; movement. When &quot;Hate&quot; puts on a costume and the streets are full of actors, Rachel&#39;s heart-wrenching grievances and hatred can only be left alone by the Sea of ​​Galilee to die in silence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bL7shqSwxMXSFexiFbunFiN7k2tHlj4r1JrCLb1E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;566&quot; height= &quot;826&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bL7shqSwxMXSFexiFbunFiN7k2tHlj4r1JrCLb1E.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; &quot;Silent as the Sea&quot; (2&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;004&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This French film is as exquisite as prose poetry, with no impurities and direct The &quot;hate&quot; of justice is degraded by the gentle touch of the beautiful couple, and the restrained love of Gujing Youbo is transformed into the audience&#39;s long sigh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of World War II, the invincible German army came to a beautiful French seaside town, breaking the peaceful life of the grandfather and granddaughter: the occupying army requisitioned one of their bedrooms for the captain with irresistible and polite words. Werner stayed. Considering that this is the third time that German soldiers have occupied France in 70 years since the Franco-Prussian War, and France suffered more than five million casualties in the last war, the grandfather and grandson are naturally hostile to everyone wearing German military boots. Never compromise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No way! Even the German officer who came to his house was like a male god in terms of truth, goodness and beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sentimental girl defends a national integrity from beginning to end, with a cold expression and never utters a word. At the same time, the captain&#39;s behavior was too beautiful. Through his extremely gentlemanly self-introduction, the audience discovered that the two of them shared each other&#39;s aesthetics, not to mention their values. It was hard not to be touched by a French heart. But she insisted on pouting her little mouth and not uttering a word, until the captain suddenly encountered danger, and the girl had to ignore everything at that moment and save him; until the captain suddenly said goodbye to him, saying that she would obey the order and go to the minus 40 degrees The Soviet front line - most likely to die, the girl broke the eternal silence, burst into tears, and faintly said to the captain the word she least wanted to say to him in this life: Goodbye. Just a word in the human world, yin and yang have parted forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Between humanity and justice, no one can do better than a girl. But what is horrifying when you think about it is that if the story of the girl calling the police to the German captain by playing the piano was known to the French anti-rape bureau after the war, the dignified and flawless heroine who later participated in the resistance activities would almost certainly be attacked by the heroine of &quot;Black Book&quot; The humiliating treatment of the protagonist. But in the eyes of today&#39;s audience, the girl&#39;s behavior at that moment shone with the most authentic beauty and should not be subject to any harsh criticism - unless the &quot;hate&quot; has deteriorated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the three movies are all excellent. The theme of &quot;hate&quot; I chose can only cover one aspect of their excellence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[下属上班“摸鱼”被领导辱骂，法院判侵犯人格权]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260749]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After the Civil Code incorporated personality rights into a separate codification, cases involving personality rights disputes accepted by courts across the country It has grown significantly. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/1a4fd954bd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/1a4fd954bd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258538&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the Civil Code incorporated personality rights into a separate chapter, the number of personality rights dispute cases accepted by courts across the country increased significantly. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Finally, we have a pretty good result. The personality of our young people must not be violated! No matter who you are as a leader, I We need to rectify the workplace!&quot; On November 8, 2023, Wan Yijian, a &quot;post-00s worker&quot;, wrote this on the social platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wan Yijian once worked for an examination training company in Nanchang City, Jiangxi Province. He was discovered by his immediate superiors for playing games in the office and was insulted in the subsequent communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Feeling insulted, Wan Yijian took his immediate boss to court. On October 25, 2023, the first instance of the Qingyunpu District People&#39;s Court of Nanchang City ordered Wan Yijian&#39;s leadership to publicly apologize to him and pay him 100 yuan in compensation for mental damage on the grounds that his personality rights were violated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the Civil Code included personality rights as an independent component, the number of personality rights dispute cases accepted by courts across the country has increased significantly. In 2021, the first year after the implementation of the Civil Code, the number of first-instance personality rights dispute cases accepted by courts across the country increased by 19.2% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the first instance verdict was announced, neither Wan Ekin nor his former leader appealed. Wan Yijian said that the sentence has been implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;First call the police, then prosecute&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Microsoft Yahei, &#39; Microsoft YaHei&#39;;&quot;>;In August 2022, Wan Yijian entered a company in Nanchang City engaged in teacher recruitment examination training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the beginning of June 2023, it is the off-season after the students&#39; exams. Wan Yijian sometimes &quot;fishes&quot; during working hours. One morning, Wan Yijian was caught playing games by his immediate boss Liu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu gave him two options. One was to resign voluntarily, with wages settled until the 15th of the month; the other was to be dismissed directly from the company. The company&#39;s management regulations provided by Ekin Wan to Southern Weekend reporters show that the penalty for playing games during working hours is a fine, not dismissal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wan Yijian said that he asked Liu to issue a formal statement of dismissal, but Liu asked him to wait. Liu did not mention the matter again the next day. , but arranged for Wan Ekin to take over the work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;(2023) Gan 0104 Minchu Judgment No. 4464 records Liu’s insult statement to the court: On June 7, 2023, Liu discovered Wanyi Jian still did not hand over the work machine to another employee and did not arrive at work during working hours. He believed that Wan Yijian had a bad attitude and insulted him as &quot;he*&quot; on the phone. On June 18, 2023, Liu also told Ekin Wan in the WeChat group, &quot;The best job for you may be to go to the cemetery to read the memorial.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wan Yijian thought he had been insulted and called the police. During the police mediation process, Liu admitted the fact of insult and agreed to apologize, but has never fulfilled it. Wan Yijian later called the police again, and the police recommended that he sue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wan Yijian recalled that he then went to the Nanchang County People’s Court to sue Liu, but the court did not accept the case due to the improper cause of the case and the lack of some information about the defendant Liu. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After sorting out the audio and screenshot evidence of the conflict, Wan Yijian hired a lawyer to send a lawyer&#39;s letter to Liu, but Liu still had no response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In August 2023, Wan Ejian redrafted the indictment. Under the guidance of lawyers and court staff, Liu was charged with infringement of personality rights. The lawsuit was filed with the People&#39;s Court of Qingyunpu District, Nanchang City, requesting that Liu be ordered to compensate Liu for 1,000 yuan in compensation for mental loss and lost work, and to make a formal and public apology. On September 13, 2023, the court officially filed the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the Civil Code, personality rights are the rights to life, body, health, name, portrait, reputation and honor enjoyed by civil subjects. rights, privacy and other rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 25, 2023, the Qingyunpu District People&#39;s Court made a first-instance judgment, finding that Liu&#39;s words to Wan Yijian were &quot;obviously insulting.&quot; &quot;Language evaluation&quot; &quot;also constitutes an infringement of the plaintiff&#39;s personality rights.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The court finally ruled that Liu publicly apologized to Wan Yijian in a WeChat group called &quot;Nanchang ×× Group&quot; within 7 days after the judgment came into effect (content (not less than 50 words), or post an apology statement (not less than 50 words) in the company office or corridor in Qingshan Lake District, Nanchang City for no less than three days, and pay Ejian Wan 100 yuan in compensation for mental damage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Is it a violation of personality rights or reputation rights? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wan Yijian’s victory in the lawsuit quickly spread on social media. In addition to comments supporting the rights protection of &quot;beating workers&quot;, there are also voices that believe that in the long run, bosses in the workplace will endanger themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the communication between superiors and subordinates in the workplace, how to define the misconduct of the boss&#39;s words and deeds? Where is the boundary between evaluating the work of subordinates and infringing on personality rights? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Weiguo, dean of the School of Civil, Commercial and Economic Law at China University of Political Science and Law, analyzed to a Southern Weekend reporter that there is a difference between reprimand and insult. It is okay to put forward some requirements for employees on specific matters, or to propose some job responsibilities that subordinates should bear. Leaders can use harsh language to point out the mistakes of their subordinates, &quot;but it cannot be insulting to the personality of their subordinates.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Judicial Statistics Bulletin of the National Courts shows that starting from 2016, &quot;personality rights disputes&quot; began to be counted as a separate category in civil cases of first instance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2021, courts across the country accepted 192,675 first-instance personality rights dispute cases, a year-on-year increase of 19.2%. Wang Weiguo believes that this trend is related to the Civil Code that will be implemented on January 1, 2021. The Civil Code separates the legal provisions of personality rights into an independent volume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the end of April 2023, among the top ten typical cases of labor and personnel disputes in Nanjing&#39;s courts released by the Nanjing Intermediate People&#39;s Court, there was one case where a boss insulting a subordinate was found to be an infringement of personality. case of rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen joined a milk tea shop in March 2017. On November 2, 2021, Chen asked about basic salary and other issues in the work group. Wang, a milk tea shop operator, insulted Chen many times in the WeChat group: &quot;Can&#39;t you understand people? You are not smart!&quot; If you are not in good health, go to bed! Don’t pretend to be sick.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Three days later, Wang organized an employee meeting to ask Chen in the work group On the grounds of personal salary and violation of store regulations, Chen was demoted from deputy store manager to intern waiter. Twenty days later, Chen sued the Nanjing Qinhuai District Court for back wages and compensation for the termination of the labor relationship on the grounds that he had been insulted for no reason by the operator and was owed wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Qinhuai District Court held that the operator’s behavior of openly verbally insulting and verbally abusing workers had actually seriously affected or even destroyed the workers’ working environment, and ultimately supported the decision. Chen’s claim for financial compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Searching on the China Judgment Documents Online using &quot;personality rights disputes&quot;, &quot;leadership&quot; and &quot;subordinates&quot; as keywords, 26 articles starting in 2018 can be retrieved Documents. Among these 26 documents, there were 6 cases involving conflicts between superiors and subordinates, and the plaintiffs were all subordinates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on public judicial documents and similar cases reported by the media, if a leader insults a subordinate and the subordinate wins the case, the court usually considers the leader&#39;s behavior to constitute a violation of personality rights. In most cases, the type of infringement in only a few cases is infringement of reputation rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The same abuse, why is it considered a different infringement? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Xiaoshu, director of the Civil and Commercial Law Teaching and Research Center of Beijing Normal University, analyzed that the right of reputation is a type of personality right. Infringement causes the social evaluation of the infringed person to be reduced, which generally constitutes Infringement of the right of reputation, &quot;If you curse in private, because it is not in public and no one else knows, it does not constitute an infringement of reputation. However, the act of insult itself is an act that infringes on personal dignity, so in judicial practice, general personality rights are generally applied to protect it. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;General personality rights refer to the general personality interests enjoyed by natural persons that summarize the entire content of personal independence, personal freedom and personal dignity, and are generated and stipulated specifically by them. Personality rights, and abstract personality rights that protect other personality interests that cannot be protected by specific personality rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 18:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[期待与遗憾：蒂勒曼和德累斯顿国立管弦乐团音乐会听后]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260597]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/14/zzg3ccsIkTYsVahCQ0vONF0oiPyEzwiYDTBQ2jv0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/zzg3ccsIkTYsVahCQ0vONF0oiPyEzwiYD TBQ2jv0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258240&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;German conductor Thielemann. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I first learned about Thielemann’s name when I watched CCTV playing Beethoven’s symphony conducted by him. After reading his interviews, I feel that his conducting and insights into music are indeed unique. Although I don’t know his background, I can’t help but pay attention to him because of his long-term cooperation with the Vienna Philharmonic and the Berlin Philharmonic. These two are the best symphony orchestras in my opinion! Soon I purchased the complete Beethoven symphonies conducted by Thielemann, but I never had time to listen to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the autumn, I learned that Thielemann led the Dresden Staatskapelle to tour China, and when I saw that Wagner&#39;s &quot;Tannhäuser Overture&quot; was on the repertoire, I looked forward to hearing him live. The Staatskapelle Dresden is known as the oldest symphony orchestra in the world. It was founded in 1548 and has a history of 475 years. Since 1817, the composer Weber has been the conductor, and has gone through composers Wagner and Richard Strauss, as well as Adolf Bush, Fritz Reiner, Carl Böhm, Rudolf Kempe, Konveschny, The continuous training of a group of outstanding conductors such as Sinopoli, Haitink, Colin Davis, Sanderling and Blomstedt finally became a world-class orchestra famous for performing operas, including Weber, Wagner, Richard ·Strauss&#39;s works were also premiered by the orchestra one after another, creating a long and glorious history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The repertoire of Thielemann’s tour this time is mainly German and Austrian music. I didn’t have time to listen to the performance in Shanghai, so I had to take advantage of the opportunity to go to Beijing for business and listened to this performance on November 7. . The repertoire is Weber&#39;s &quot;Celebration Overture&quot;, Wagner&#39;s &quot;Tannhäuser Overture&quot;, Richard Strauss&#39;s &quot;Thus Spoke Zarathustra&quot; and &quot;Der Rosenkavalier Overture&quot;. These works were written by the three musicians who have the closest relationship with the orchestra, and should also be the best repertoire for the orchestra. What I really want to hear is the Tannhäuser Overture, which is one of my favorite works and I will listen to it again in a while. I have listened to no less than thirty or forty versions, but never heard it live. Thielemann + Dresden Staatskapelle + &quot;Tannhauser Overture&quot;, this is the best reason to listen to it live. This piece also tests the conductor and orchestra the most. In the recordings I have done, few conductors and orchestras can play it well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Dresden Staatskapelle under Thielemann&#39;s baton opened with the first &quot;Celebration Overture&quot;. It felt like the musicians hadn&#39;t warmed up yet, and their voices were light and fluttery, without any solid sound. It was a celebration. The color is a bit light. The number of people in the band was not large enough. There were only about 80 people in the band of more than 130 people, and the volume was not enough. Before the performance of the second &quot;Tannhauser Overture&quot;, several more musicians came up, but the total number was less than a hundred. The melody and timbre are generally good, but it obviously lacks a bit of grand solemnity and rising atmosphere. The rhythm processing at the beginning is a bit unique and the speed is slightly faster, which does not convey the gradually increasing solemnity of the music. In the middle part, the &quot;call of temptation&quot; played by the violins in unison, and the rapid sound groups played repeatedly by the violins basically failed to produce the magic that the melody should have. The brass music at the end also seemed not powerful enough, and the rising feeling at the climax could not be conveyed. In short, my feeling is that the band composition is a bit small and cannot achieve the shocking effect it should have. Among the dozens of versions I have heard, the two most wonderful are Solti&#39;s. The Vienna Philharmonic version is better than the Chicago Symphony Orchestra version. Friends who are interested will know what is lacking in the Dresden Staatskapelle conducted by Thielemann after listening to it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two Richard Strauss works &quot;Thus Spoke Zarathustra&quot; and &quot;Der Rosenkavalier Overture&quot; in the second half were very successful. Richard Strauss and the Staatskapelle Dresden collaborated for more than 60 years, and nine operas were premiered by the orchestra, including the &quot;Der Rosenkavalier Overture&quot;. These two works in the second half finally revived the orchestra’s spirit. The Staatskapelle Dresden is responsible for both opera and concert performances. Apart from opera, they are best at German and Austrian classical music. Music critics highly praise the orchestra&#39;s elegant style and balance of parts, saying they are different from others. Unique sound from other Western European orchestras. It is difficult to appreciate these characteristics in just one concert, but the overall level and artistic expression of the orchestra can still be felt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the short overture &quot;Sunrise&quot; of &quot;Thus Spake Zarathustra&quot; is familiar because it was used as the theme music of the movie &quot;Star Wars&quot;, I have rarely listened to the entire work. , not familiar with it. What is certain is that Thielemann and the orchestra perfectly demonstrated the orchestral charm created by Richard Strauss&#39;s colorful musical ideas and gorgeous orchestration, and there was no sense of fatigue when listening to the whole piece. The peculiar structure of the &quot;Der Rosenkavalier&quot; Overture - the density of the sound of the two three-beat parts and the sharp contrast with the other two parts, well demonstrated the tension between them under Thielemann&#39;s conductor. The number of members in the band also increased slightly. In the last part of the piece, Thielemann&#39;s dramatic commanding movements made all the musicians on the stage excited and released their energy, bringing the atmosphere to a climax. When the music ended, the applause was thunderous and lasting. Thielemann took his final bow several times, but the audience still refused to give up, but in the end there was no &quot;encore&quot; (encore) to thank the audience for their enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I was not satisfied with the performance in the first half, I felt that the performance in the second half was worth the price of admission. This tour by Thielemann and the Dresden Staatskapelle was obviously quite successful, and the music fans praised it as the best concert of the year. The last time I went to the National Center for the Performing Arts was to listen to Abbado conducting the Berlin Philharmonic&#39;s Mahler. Fast forward many years, and on the eve of the beginning of winter, Thielemann&#39;s Dresden Staatskapelle gave me the last concert of autumn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People are subject to change, but music is endless. Thielemann, can you bring the Vienna Philharmonic next year? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[现制茶超长配料表“泄密”，能做到真透明吗？丨一图读懂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260734]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73540&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70343&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/136405441d.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;mmexport1700108368825.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;9599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/136405441d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258519&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73541&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70344&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/d354380823.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;mmexport1700108615676.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;9338&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/16/d354380823.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258520&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 16:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院国资委原副部长级干部骆玉林被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260729]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 15:08:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission punished Luo Yulin, a former deputy ministerial cadre of the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of the State Council, for serious violations of discipline. Illegal issues were investigated and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Luo Yulin lost his ideals and beliefs, abandoned his original intention and mission, was disloyal and dishonest to the party, was inconsistent with his appearance, and acted two-faced; he violated the spirit of the eight central regulations and accepted private enterprises in violation of regulations Banquets and travel activities arranged by the boss; violating organizational principles, concealing personal matters, seeking benefits for others and accepting property during the selection and appointment of cadres; selfish desires and profit-seeking, long-term illegal acceptance of gifts and money, illegally engaged in profit-making activities, and many A private business owner lends money to obtain large returns and engages in power, sex, and money transactions; his life is corrupt, his family tradition is not upright, his family governance is lax, and he neglects the discipline and education of his family; he has no bottom line in discipline and law, uses public tools for private purposes, and uses power for personal gain. , colluding with unscrupulous businessmen, engaging in power and money transactions, taking advantage of his position to benefit others in business operations, project contracting, etc., and illegally receiving huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Yulin seriously violated the Party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline and life discipline, constituting a serious job violation and being suspected of bribery. He did not restrain himself or stop after the 18th National Congress of the Party. His nature It is serious and has a bad impact and should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Luo Yulin from the party; The treatment he enjoys shall be canceled in accordance with regulations; his illegal gains shall be confiscated; his suspected criminal issues shall be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved shall be transferred together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年中国电影总票房已突破500亿元，国产片票房占比创十年来新高]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260699]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 14, Nandu reporters learned from the real-time data of the Beacon Professional Edition that as of November 13, 2023 The country&#39;s annual total box office (including pre-sales) exceeded 50 billion, and the top ten box office in the current year are all domestic films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8c6dc98a22c63c0267096e71b85c2ba2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1652&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8c6dc98a22c63c0267096e71b85c2ba2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258491&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Data show that the top ten films at the box office are all domestic films, including &quot;A River in Red&quot;, &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;, &quot;Desperate&quot;, &quot;The Disappearance of Her&quot;, &quot;Fengshen Part 1: Chaoge Fengyun&quot;, &quot;Eight Anise&quot; &quot;In the Cage&quot;, &quot;Thirty Thousand Miles from Chang&#39;an&quot;, &quot;Bear Infested·Stand with Me &quot;Bear Core&quot;&quot;, &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; and &quot;Unfamiliar Life&quot;, these ten films all have a box office of more than 1 billion yuan. It is reported that domestic films account for 83.4% of the current annual box office, the highest in the past 10 years; imported films account for 16.6%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/c76798310f775545d8fad770acd46742.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;944&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/c76798310f775545d8fad770acd46742.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258492&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨郑永流：学法律的自豪来自两部电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260690]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu, the first doctor of jurisprudence in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in 1957 in Macheng County, Hubei Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1963－1974&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;went to primary school and middle school in Macheng County and Huangpi County, Hubei Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978-1982, studied at the Law Department of Hubei University of Finance and Economics and received a bachelor&#39;s degree in law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1983-1986, studied at the Law Department of Central South University of Political Science and Law and received a Master of Laws degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1986-1989, studied at the Law Department of Peking University and received a doctorate in law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1989-1993, served as lecturer and associate professor of the Law Department of Central South University of Political Science and Law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1993-1996, he served as a visiting professor at the School of Law and Economics, Saarland University, Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2004, he served as Acting Professor at the Law School of the University of Freiburg, Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1998 to 2023, he worked at the University of Friborg in Switzerland, the University of Oslo in Norway, He has served as a short-term visiting scholar at the University of Frankfurt in Germany for many times. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1997 to 2022, he served as professor at the Law School of China University of Political Science and Law and China Europe Law School. Professor, doctoral supervisor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Currently a distinguished doctoral supervisor at China University of Political Science and Law, legal philosophy and interdisciplinary legal research at China Europe Law School Director. He is a member of the International Association for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy (IVR) and the editor-in-chief of the journal &quot;Philosophy of Law and Sociology of Law&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In July 2023, Zheng Yongliu (first from the right) held a lecture at the University of Munich. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4b176532a1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;593&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/16/4b176532a1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258474&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In July 2023, Zheng Yongliu ( First from right) giving a lecture at the University of Munich. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For our generation, reform and opening up has brought a great turning point in our lives.” October 2023 is the most beautiful time of the year in Beijing. In the autumn season, in a teahouse near Xueyuan Road, Zheng Yongliu recalled his youthful years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 1978, Zheng Yongliu was admitted to Hubei University of Finance and Economics (now Zhongnan University of Economics and Law) and became a freshman in the law department. At this time, 4 years had passed since he graduated from high school. During those four years, Zheng Yongliu worked as an educated youth in the countryside and as a fisherman in the lake area. When he took the college entrance examination, he was a surveyor in the water conservancy engineering team of the Water Conservancy Bureau of Huangpi County, Hubei Province (now Huangpi District, Wuhan City). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Born in a county town, Zheng Yongliu’s hometown did not have a university. He had never seen a university before. “Everyone yearns for a university, but they have no concept of it. They only know that a university is an ‘ivory tower’. &#39;, it&#39;s a world that you can&#39;t concretely imagine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After completing undergraduate and master’s degrees at Hubei University of Finance and Economics and Central South University of Political Science and Law, Zheng Yongliu was admitted to the Law Department of Peking University in 1986, where he studied under Chen Shouyi, a legal educator and one of the founders of contemporary Chinese jurisprudence. professor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1989, Zheng Yongliu graduated and became the first doctor of jurisprudence after the founding of New China. His doctoral thesis &quot;The Status and Development Path of Law in Rural Reform&quot; began to explore rural legal issues more than 30 years ago, and proposed the &quot;three-dimensional adjustment method of rural development of human ethics-law-policy&quot; and &quot;legal localization&quot;. The idea is extremely groundbreaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from Peking University, Zheng Yongliu taught at Central South University of Political Science and Law, Saarland University in Germany, University of Freiburg in Germany, and China University of Political Science and Law. In Zheng Yongliu’s view, “the first PhD in jurisprudence after the founding of the People’s Republic of China” was the starting point of his academic career, but it is his subsequent academic research that determines his reputation and academic status. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;This college is worth it&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From graduating from high school in 1974 to taking the college entrance examination in 1978, what were you doing in the intervening years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I graduated from high school, I was 17 years old. My classmates and I all went to the countryside to become educated youth. There was great enthusiasm at that time, and the countryside was a &quot;vast land with a lot to offer.&quot; We have all stated that we want to take root, blossom and bear fruit in the countryside and do not think about anything else. There are many lakes in Hubei. I worked as a fisherman in the countryside for two years. When fishing every day in winter, we have to get up at 5 o&#39;clock in the morning and set the net before the fish wake up. Otherwise, when the sun comes out, the fish will scatter and go out to look for food. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I was transferred to the Water Conservancy Bureau of Huangpi County (now Huangpi District, Wuhan City) as a surveyor, carrying a ruler and doing measurements everywhere. For example, when building a reservoir, it is necessary to measure the rain-bearing area, which determines the height and thickness of the reservoir dam. If the dam is built too high, it will be wasteful. If it is built too low or too thin, it will be easily washed away, so the watershed must be measured. Because we have not gone through any special study, our job is to go over mountains and ridges to place measuring rulers, trace and post pictures and other auxiliary tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You took the college entrance examination just after it resumed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In August 1977, Deng Xiaoping chaired a symposium on science and education and decided to resume the college entrance examination, which had been suspended for 11 years. At the end of 1977, each province resumed the college entrance examination with its own questions. When the exam notice was sent out, I was at a water conservancy construction site. If you don’t have time to review, you will naturally fail in taking the exam. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I took the college entrance examination in the second year, I had time to review by chance. At that time, a river in the county needed to be renovated, and the engineering team sent me to a cement factory in another place to purchase cement. The production environment in the cement factory was very bad. Although everyone wore masks and took other protective measures, there was a lot of dust in the factory. In May 1978, I contracted acute pleurisy. At that time, the water accumulation in my right chest was very serious, and I could even hear a &quot;gurgling&quot; sound in my chest when I breathed. A female doctor surnamed Gong said that I should be hospitalized immediately. She would use a particularly thick needle to puncture my back to my chest every day and extract about 100 ml of accumulated water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After about a week of pumping, the fluid in the chest was gone, but the inflammation was still not gone, so I could no longer go to the cement factory to purchase cement. The doctor asked me to stay in the hospital, but I said no, I had to take the college entrance examination. At that time, there were many people living in one room in the hospital, and I couldn&#39;t review. The doctor also understood. She kept me in the hospital for another three days, and then asked me to go to the hospital for injections during the day and stay at home at night. So I went to the hospital twice a day, and rested at home during the rest of the time while reviewing. In the summer of 1978, I entered college. I am very grateful to Dr. Gong. After I was admitted to college, I made a special trip to visit her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you went to college, was law your first choice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, law is my second choice. When I was filling out my application form, I preferred literature. At that time, everyone had a literary dream and wanted to be a writer. At that time, the most popular liberal arts subject was what we called &quot;xianxue&quot; - &quot;literature, history and philosophy&quot;. Students with high scores were admitted to the Chinese Department, followed by the History Department and Philosophy. At that time, I applied for the History Department of Wuhan University. In 1978, the key score for liberal arts in Hubei Province was 340 points. I scored 332.3 points, which was a few points short. Later, the key line was lowered to 330 points, and my score was enough, but at that time I had been admitted to the Law Department of Hubei University of Finance and Economics, so I missed the history major. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How is college life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was particularly impressed. On the first day of college, the school arranged a movie reception and showed us movies. The movie is called &quot;The Black Triangle&quot; and it&#39;s about catching spies in the north. The plot of the movie is average, but there is a song in it that shocked us very much. It was &quot;The Spring Water in the Border is Clear and Pure&quot; sung by Li Guyi. She sang this song using a new so-called breath singing method, which was completely different from the heroic and aspirational singing method popular in that era. That was the first time I realized that the song could still be sung like this. At that time, I felt: I went to the right university. I have never been exposed to these before. If I had not gone to college and lived in a small county, I might not have heard this singing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;University opened up a new world for me. The end of 1978 to 1979 was a period of surging ideological trends. At that time, there were many lectures in the school, such as those of Peking University and the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. Many famous scholars came to Wuhan to give lectures and spread some new ideas, which made me even more determined: this university is worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 1987, Zheng Yongliu was at the Weiming Lake of Peking University. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/16/79bc830a15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 79bc830a15.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1987, Zheng Yongliu was at the Weiming Lake of Peking University. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;What should we do when studying law&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;South Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After going to college, are you interested in law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the first half of college, I didn’t have much feelings about law. I really became interested in this major because of movies. At that time, every Saturday, the school would show movies in the playground, and we would all watch them for free. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, there was an Indian movie &quot;Wanderer&quot;, which tells the story of two young people. The woman&#39;s name is Lida. She is a lawyer who represents her friend in court. Raz defended, vehemently. Lida studied law, and we immediately felt that studying law was very impressive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, another movie was released, &quot;Tragedy on the Nile&quot;, which tells the story of a Belgian detective named Poirot who used reasoning to find the killer on the cruise ship. At that time, we felt that this was also related to the law, and we might have to do related work in the future. A classmate in the same class got the nickname &quot;Poirot&quot; because he often imitated the great detective, and his classmates still call him that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After watching the movie, we gained some pride in studying law and felt that we should eliminate violence and bring justice to everyone. At that time, some students from other departments watched these two movies and asked to transfer to our department to study law. Of course, the theory is obscure, but everyone still has a general understanding of &quot;what we should do when studying law&quot; through film and television works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After you have the pride of studying law, you are interested in jurisprudence Yet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In our freshman year, we mainly took public courses and also offered jurisprudence. At that time, I felt that jurisprudence was too abstract and difficult to understand, but the teacher Wang Yajin, who studied in the Soviet Union, asked me to be the class representative of jurisprudence, so I did. At that time, there were no subdivisions in the legal profession, but you might be interested in a certain subject. Some people are interested in criminal law, others are interested in civil law. I am very interested in international law. My graduation thesis is also in the direction of international law, discussing the subject status of international organizations in international law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduation, the school asked me to stay and teach in jurisprudence. At that time, I thought that if I wanted to stay in school to teach, I would definitely need a higher degree, so I enrolled in a graduate program at this school. Zhang Ruolong, the dean of our Central South University of Political Science and Law, is a professor of jurisprudence, so I studied jurisprudence with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still didn’t feel much about jurisprudence when I was in school, but I felt that since I was a graduate student, I should study hard. It was also at this time that I started to become interested in jurisprudence because I had invested a lot of time in it. But to truly understand and study jurisprudence, it is still at the doctoral level and beyond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you later go to Peking University to study for a PhD in Jurisprudence? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because I have entered the field of jurisprudence and want to continue my studies. At that time, only Peking University in the country was able to recruit doctors of jurisprudence. My supervisor is Chen Shouyi, who is also among the first batch of liberal arts and the first doctoral supervisors in jurisprudence in the country. According to research, in November 1981, the State Council approved four scholars from Peking University: Chen Shouyi, Rui Mu (International Economic Law), Wang Tieya (International Law) and Zhang Youyu (Constitutional Law) of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences as the first batch of law doctoral supervisors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1986, Teacher Chen was getting older, in his eighties, and needed someone to assist him. At that time, Liu Shengping was the director of the Jurisprudence Teaching and Research Office of Peking University Law Department. He was not yet sixty years old and was in the prime of life, so the specific daily work was managed by Teacher Liu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Chen is not in good health. He asks us to come to his home from time to time to talk, mainly about what is happening in the courts and procuratorates and what new problems there are. Another thing is to listen to what we think in theory. What he said the most is that we need to start from China&#39;s reality and understand more about China&#39;s reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your doctoral thesis is &quot;The Status and Development of Law in Rural Changes&quot; &quot;Road&quot;, how did you pay attention to this topic? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I entered Peking University in 1986, the topic of reform was very hot and my thoughts were very diverse. There are many various academic seminars in Beijing. After I arrived in Beijing, I also participated in these academic seminars and met some people from the China Institute of Economic Structural Reform and the Rural Development Institute of the Rural Policy Research Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. At that time, they advocated legalizing reform measures, but they were all majoring in economics and did not know how to legislate or provide legal advice, so they needed some people who studied law, so I went there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two research institutes are think tanks for reform. The Institute of Structural Reform leads urban system reform, especially enterprise restructuring; the Institute of Agricultural Research studies rural issues, including township and village enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I went to the Physical Reform Institute first and then to the Agricultural Research Institute. At the Agricultural Research Institute, I followed them to the Fuyang Township Enterprise Reform Experimental Zone in Anhui Province for investigation and did some empirical research. At that time, there was almost no legal issue in rural areas, and there were only some policies promoted by the annual No. 1 Central Document. After conducting research with people from the Agricultural Research Institute, I felt that I had found a direction and wanted to write about rural legal construction. In 1989, I co-wrote &quot;Promoting the System through the System - An Experimental Report on the Bankruptcy System of Township Enterprises in Fuyang, Anhui Province&quot; with Qiu Chengyi of the Agricultural Research Institute, which was published in &quot;Unfinalized&quot;, an internal journal of &quot;Chinese Social Sciences&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did your experience at the Agricultural Research Institute help you write your thesis? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The experience at the Agricultural Research Institute allowed me to understand and use empirical research methods instead of just deducing from theory. Scholars at the institute start from the facts, then make judgments and propose countermeasures and theories for reform. This inspired me a lot, because we used to introduce other people&#39;s theories, from theory to theory, PK was also PK between this theory and that theory. The impression given to me by the Agricultural Research Institute is that it is refreshing, and its examples are all real-life. We went there for about more than a month. We visited township enterprises and factories every day and held discussions with township cadres. This was completely different from my previous experience in college. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I proposed in my paper at that time that human ethics, policies and laws should be mutually complementary and cooperative means of adjusting rural development. No one said this at that time. Everyone either only emphasized human ethics, or only emphasized policies or laws. I think these are biased, so I proposed the three-dimensional adjustment. &lt;p>; )&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6646620582.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;789&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6646620582.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu (back row, first from right) takes a photo with Chen Shouyi (front row, first from right), associate instructor Liu Shengping (front row, first from left) and classmates. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Propose a theory of practical legal philosophy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt; /strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating with your Ph.D., will all your subsequent academic research be related to jurisprudence? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From the doctoral student stage in 1988 to before going abroad in 1993, I mainly focused on empirical research and also did some investigations, including my Several colleagues from the Central South University of Political Science and Law conducted research on farmers&#39; legal awareness in Hubei and published some articles, such as &quot;Realistic Changes in China&#39;s Farmers&#39; Legal Awareness&quot; published in &quot;Chinese Law&quot; in 1992. In terms of discipline, we call it legal sociology. It should be said that in China, I was one of the first scholars to do empirical research. Later I went abroad and did not do much research at that time. On the one hand, I did not have the conditions for empirical research. On the other hand, I had a teaching assignment at the University of Saarland in Germany. I also needed to understand German law and read their laws. Research is still in the accumulation stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to China in 1997, I continued to teach sociology of law courses, but my research direction has shifted to legal methods, that is, how to apply legal methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 2000, in addition to paying attention to legal methods, I began to study legal philosophy. Jurisprudence and legal philosophy are the same concept, which is to answer the question &quot;What is law?&quot; It not only solves the problem of how to apply and interpret the law, but also forms a new law in the process. Later I summarized it as: law in a static sense is the 1.0 state of the law; after interpretation, the law you create yourself is the 2.0 state of the law. Later, this became my own set of legal philosophy theories. I called it practical legal philosophy because it was created in the process of legal practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The legal philosophy I mentioned today is different from traditional legal philosophy. Traditional legal philosophy is divorced from empirical research, but I proposed a new legal philosophy theory based on empirical research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The theory of practical legal philosophy you proposed also partially compensated for the failure of Chinese scholars Are there any research gaps in this area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As we all know, modern legal science is the product of Western knowledge and came to China across the ocean. After more than a hundred years of &quot;apprenticeship&quot; career, Chinese legal scholars want to participate in the world&#39;s mainstream legal dialogue, and Practical Legal Philosophy is the result of such an attempt. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a theoretical origin point of view, practical legal philosophy continues the tradition of practical philosophy, and also absorbs practical theory, as well as the famous German legal philosopher Kaufman’s idea of ​​​​&quot;actual reality&quot;. Theoretical resources such as the &quot;third way&quot; opened up between &quot;should be&quot; and &quot;should be&quot; strive to integrate the wisdom of several major schools of modern Western legal philosophy. This is a theory that can dialogue with the mainstream of the West rather than talk to itself. It wants to provide an answer to the age-old question &quot;What is law?&quot; and make a Chinese scholar&#39;s own contribution to the world of legal philosophy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now let me explain, what do you think jurisprudence is? What kind of subject? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The core question of jurisprudence is to answer &quot;what is the law?&quot; This sounds simple to say, but is more complicated to actually study. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, doesn’t the National People’s Congress enact laws? What&#39;s so hard about this? But that&#39;s not the case. We call formulated and written laws statutory laws. In addition to statutory law, law also has other forms of expression. For example, we call the universal rules of society expressed in the form of concepts and thoughts natural law. Laws made by people do not necessarily contain these ideas, and statutory laws are not necessarily correct. For example, many laws in ancient China were autocratic and authoritarian laws; many laws enacted by Nazi Germany also contained many anti-human and unfair ideas. So natural law is needed to correct errors in statutory law, which is part of our answer to &quot;what is law?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also customary law, which is something that exists in real life and has been observed by us for generations. It also adjusts people&#39;s behavior, which also belongs to the scope of &quot;what is the law&quot;. So in terms of scope, statutory law, natural law, and customary law are all the content of our research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the most difficult part of studying jurisprudence is that statutory law, natural law, and customary law are all expressed in a static sense. When these concepts are related to facts, it will show Certain deficiencies and weaknesses. As Goethe said, &quot;Theory is gray, but the tree of life is evergreen.&quot; In other words, no matter what the rules are, they can never fully meet the needs of reality. In more professional terms, it is called &quot;there is an asymmetry between facts and norms.&quot; This requires us to constantly combine facts in the process of applying rules to propose our new theory about &quot;what the law is.&quot; This new theory will become binding law on specific cases, so the theory also needs to be constantly updated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We call the previous static law Law 1.0. After Law 1.0 is related to facts, it puts forward new understandings. We call it Law 2.0. Legislation and law amendment can also be regarded as this process, but the procedures for legislation and law amendment are slow and complicated. If a new type of case arises, we cannot wait for the law to be revised before deciding. Therefore, when the existing legal norms are not symmetrical to the facts, we need to judicially interpret the norms. On what basis do you base your explanation? You have to put forward your own theories and opinions in order to explain it reasonably. So at this time, jurisprudence plays a big role. In this sense, although jurisprudence sounds very theoretical, it is also highly practical, so jurisprudence is also a required course for law majors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zheng Yongliu during his study tour at the University of Oslo, Norway. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/b12ad55cd6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;732&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/b12ad55cd6 .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu while visiting the University of Oslo, Norway. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The combination of &quot;accidental&quot; and &quot;inevitable&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Does the label &quot;the first doctor of jurisprudence after the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; have a big impact on your future life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Judging from the time I got my degree, I am the first doctor of jurisprudence in the country. But when we entered school, there were actually two of us. The other one was my junior sister, and she delayed her graduation by one year. For many years after I graduated, I would not consciously mention it. It’s only in the last five or six years that some people started posting this on social media, and more people followed it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tag does not bring me much added value. Of course, my doctoral thesis is the starting point of my academic work. It can also be said that it established my academic confidence. Later, more people paid attention to me, not just because of this paper, but because I later published a series of research results in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, I publish the magazine of the International Association for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy (IVR), which is also the top international publication in the field of legal philosophy, &quot;Transactions on Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy&quot; Three papers were published on Archives for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy, one of which was &quot;On the Practical Philosophy of Law&quot; published in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back at your study experience now, I feel that many important choices were An accidental result? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If it wasn’t because of illness, I wouldn’t have time to review, and maybe I wouldn’t be able to get into college; if I had successfully become a navy when I was a fisherman , I would not have been admitted to university; if I had studied history in university, I would not have become a doctor of jurisprudence. For example, when I graduated from college, I wanted to engage in practice. At that time, many of my classmates went to work in government agencies, but the school allowed me to stay in school. I originally liked international law, but was assigned to teach jurisprudence. Later, I went abroad, and my first choice was to go to the United States. The University of Wisconsin, a stronghold of legal sociology, accidentally ended up at Saarland University, which ranks among the top universities in legal philosophy in Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So it is true that there are too many accidents, and there are also inevitable consequences among too many accidents. It is impossible to say for sure. But going to college really opened a window for me to see a bigger world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you were asked to send a message to current college students, what would you do? explain? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Sometimes students come to ask me, and I say that I really can’t say anything good, so it’s better not to say it. I am also telling myself now not to educate students or ask them to do what they want. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I have to say something, this is not a message. I always emphasize that everyone, not just students, must have their own independent thoughts and not blindly follow fads and mainstream trends. Freedom of thought is the most worthy pursuit. I usually don&#39;t write these things for students, but sometimes when I say goodbye to students, they insist on asking me to write something. I once wrote this sentence: &quot;Tranquility leads to freedom, and freedom leads to scholarship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[悔婚拒退彩礼引发血案：当从悲剧中吸取教训丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Surveillance video circulated online shows that at 13:38 on November 11, two people were killed in a mahjong parlor in Liangshan, Sichuan. A woman playing mahjong was killed by two men with knives. According to media reports, insiders revealed that a knife-wielding man and a woman who was hacked were originally lovers and had paid a bride price of 300,000 yuan, but the woman regretted the marriage and was only willing to return 150,000 yuan. The two men are father and son, and the other woman is related to the woman who regretted her marriage. The next day, local police stated that the two assailants were controlled by the police on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tragedy sparked a lot of discussion. A mother said: &quot;Ever since my daughter entered the society, I have taught her that it is OK to fall in love, but you cannot use other people&#39;s money. You are not allowed to accept money or transfers from others!&quot; Some netizens said: &quot;You can go to the court to sue and demand She would not go to this step to return the gift.&quot; However, someone immediately appeared to give their own testimony or quoted the news to prove how difficult it is to return the bride price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nature of betrothal gifts is different from the betrothal gifts in traditional society. There is a wedding ceremony of a scholar in &quot;Book of Rites&quot;. Scholars were the lowest class nobles; there were six rites for marrying a wife, which were nacai, asking for name, naji, nazheng, asking for date and personally welcoming. Nazheng was the betrothal gift. This set of common people was imitated and integrated into traditional marriage customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Betrothal gift is a &quot;new custom&quot; that has emerged in recent years. What is worrying is that betrothal gifts are becoming more and more popular. Not only are the prices getting higher and higher, but there is also a trend of generalization. Betrothal gifts were not available in some places, but now they are beginning to be given. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current legal definition of bride price is &quot;a gift for the purpose of marriage.&quot; The biggest problem caused by this characterization is that it has given rise to the stereotype that &quot;getting married is starting a business and getting divorced is getting rich&quot;. Some women disappear immediately after taking the bride price, or after receiving the marriage certificate, they refuse to live with the man, and then ask for a divorce in order to keep the high-priced bride price as their own. When more such incidents occur, social problems arise, and the judicial system has no choice but to add some patches to this characterization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme People’s Court’s Interpretation on the Application of the Marriage and Family Section of the Civil Code of the People’s Republic of China (1) Article 5 stipulates: If a party requests the return of a betrothal gift paid in accordance with customs, if it is found that it falls under the following circumstances, the People’s Court It should be supported: (1) Both parties have not completed the marriage registration procedures; (2) Both parties have completed the marriage registration procedures but have not lived together; (3) Pre-marriage payments have caused difficulties in the payer&#39;s life. The application of the provisions of the second and third items of the preceding paragraph shall be conditional on the divorce of both parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In judicial practice, some courts will use their discretion to determine whether and how much the bride price should be refunded based on the length of the marriage. Mastering the stick, but aiming for the yard. Some women have come up with some tricks: maintain the marriage for one year and then file for divorce, so that the probability of the court ruling to return the bride price is very small; install cameras at home, refuse to live as a couple, and use various methods to anger the man and induce him to take action. Photographing it will be evidence of domestic violence, so that the court will justifiably support the woman&#39;s various demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, a man in Zhumadian, Henan Province released a video saying that his wife had domestically abused him and set a fire indoors. The incident occurred at around two o&#39;clock in the morning on June 16, 2023. The video shows: the man was robbed of his mobile phone and was slapped by the woman without fighting back; the woman set fires in many places in the house, and the flames were visible on the sofa, dining table and kitchen trash can, and the man followed and doused them one by one. The man said that he had spent all his parents’ savings in order to get married, spending a total of nearly 200,000 yuan including 100,000 yuan in betrothal gifts. Now, after only four months of marriage, the woman is about to get divorced. “Tell me to get out of here, just a penny of betrothal gifts.” Neither will retreat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Rule of Law Daily&quot; report, recently, the Henan Provincial High Court concluded a divorce dispute case. In March 2022, the man Xiao Yijing introduced him to the woman Xiaoshuang. In May of the same year, the two registered their marriage; in July of the same year, Xiaoshuang announced that she was pregnant and had an abortion that month due to fetal abnormalities. Subsequently, Xiaoshuang sued for divorce, and Xiaoya agreed to the divorce, but countersued for the return of the 186,000 yuan gift. In both the first instance and the second instance, the court ruled that the parties were divorced, but did not support the request for return of the bride price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoya was dissatisfied and applied for retrial. After the retrial, the court found that: In the original trial, Xiaoya claimed that Xiaoshuang used the name of marriage to obtain property, and said that after the lawsuit, it was found that Xiaoshuang had married 6 men before getting married, and all of them got pregnant and had abortions within a short period of time after the marriage and then divorced. , and all received expensive betrothal gifts. The court held that the bride price was paid for the purpose of getting married, starting a family, and living together for a long time. Otherwise, it would violate the true intention of the party who paid the bride price and should be returned. However, it only awarded a refund of 100,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you get married once or twice, get pregnant for a short period of time, have an abortion, and get divorced, it may be true; if you repeat this routine seven times in a row, the possibility of it being true is very slim. The woman was probably trying to get the bride price by defrauding her, and the purpose was to establish evidence of living together. But even so, the 186,000 betrothal gifts received for the seventh marriage can still keep 86,000, and the &quot;profit rate&quot; is too high; plus the betrothal gifts received for the first six times, I am afraid it will easily make a profit of one million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, we can have a more profound analysis of why the Liangshan tragedy occurred. Liangshan is a very poor place in Sichuan. After receiving a bride price of 300,000 yuan, only 150,000 yuan was returned. For the father and son, it was equivalent to taking away their entire lives. Moreover, if you really go to court to sue, the court may not order a full refund; even if it orders a full refund, the woman may not fulfill it: currently, more than 10,000 people have been executed for breach of trust due to disputes over betrothal gifts. After the tragedy, the two perpetrators will also pay a heavy price for their actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Betrothal gifts are something with inherent contradictions: those who can afford the betrothal gifts often do not need to pay a betrothal gift when they get married; on the contrary, only families that cannot afford a betrothal gift or have a difficult time need to pay a betrothal gift when they get married. Moreover, it is a high-priced betrothal gift. In order to afford the betrothal gift, such families often have to live frugally, borrow here and there, and even take out loan sharks. If the latter encounters the &quot;get rich from divorce&quot; scheme in order to defraud the bride price, it will be difficult to accept it, and they may resort to extreme measures, causing irreparable consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When facing disputes over betrothal gifts, you should resolve them through reasonable and legal means and safeguard your rights and interests in accordance with the law. However, while pondering the aforementioned tragedy, it is also necessary to reflect on the legal characterization of bride price. The judiciary cannot encourage the &quot;get rich from divorce&quot; routine. When only money belongs to money and property belongs to property, marriage can belong to marriage. If marriage becomes a tool for wealth redistribution, it will inspire and encourage the evil of human nature, which will not only harm marriage, but also property, and cause various undesirable things. Tragedy will happen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山西永聚煤业发生火灾，已致11人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260696]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:25:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yongju Coal Industry Joint Construction in Lishi District, Luliang City, Shanxi Province A fire broke out in the building around 6:50 a.m. today (16th). As of press time, 11 people have been confirmed dead, and the specific casualties are still being counted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the situation at the scene, the burning building has 4 floors. A total of 63 people have been evacuated so far, 51 of whom were sent to Luliang First People&#39;s Hospital for treatment. The rescue is still in progress and the cause of the fire is under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>