<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[保障房规划与城中村改造结合，楼市祭出供给侧改革“组合拳”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259973]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The relationship positioning and development model of affordable housing and commercial housing have also been further clarified. Visual China/Picture &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/31c0abb395.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/31c0abb395.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The relationship positioning and development model of affordable housing and commercial housing have also been further clarified. Visual China/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 25, 2023, the State Council executive meeting reviewed and approved the &quot;Guiding Opinions on the Planning and Construction of Affordable Housing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A real estate expert involved in system design confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that the &quot;Guidance on Planning and Construction of Affordable Housing&quot; (Guofa [2023] No. 14) (hereinafter referred to as No. 14) was It was distributed to various cities at the end of August, mainly targeting megacities with a net inflow of population and cities with a permanent population of more than 3 million in built-up areas, a total of 35 cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Document No. 14 clarifies two major goals. The first is to increase the construction and supply of affordable housing, &quot;allowing working-income groups to gradually realize home ownership&quot;; the second is to promote the establishment of a new model of transformation and development of the real estate industry, return commercial housing to commodity attributes, meet the demand for improved housing, and promote stability. Land prices, stabilizing housing prices, and stabilizing expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is affordable housing highly valued, its relationship positioning and development model with commercial housing have also been further clarified. Some people believe that this is a &quot;new round of housing reform&quot; similar to the Singapore model. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Reform is gradual and forced”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the above-mentioned experts, a major focus of Document No. 14 is to launch allotment-type affordable housing. China has previously established a housing security system that integrates public rental housing, affordable rental housing, and shared property housing. The new allotment-type affordable housing will be connected with it to form an affordable housing system parallel to commercial housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia, chief researcher of the Housing Policy Research Center of the Guangdong Provincial Institute of Urban Planning, told Southern Weekend reporters that currently affordable housing accounts for 20%-30% of the existing housing stock, mainly for people with urban household registration, such as minimum living allowance and low-income families. Income groups, coverage is limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the changes in the population structure and the increase in housing prices, new citizens, young people and other groups are facing severe housing difficulties, and the contradiction between the scope of housing security and actual needs has become increasingly prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are 300-400 million new citizens and migrant population in the country, and most of them do not have houses. The anxiety about owning property rights houses has risen to the level of class promotion.” Li Yujia once wrote an article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, during the real estate boom period, commercial housing and land prices soared, and local governments were not very enthusiastic about investing in the construction of affordable housing. There is a big gap between affordable housing and commercial housing in terms of location, quality, and public services, making it difficult to truly meet needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If we do not vigorously build affordable housing, we must tolerate the existence of urban villages, factory dormitories and other informal housing that are free from urban public services.” Li Yujia believes that this has led to the The housing pattern shows a &quot;dual split&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, commercial housing for middle and high incomes and informal housing for low and middle incomes dominate, with the middle form weak, and there is a ladder fault in housing consumption. In the &quot;first half&quot; of the real estate market, where urbanization is advancing rapidly, house prices are not high, and price increases are expected to be strong, this problem is not yet obvious. As real estate enters a downward period, the problem becomes more prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the end of 2021, measures to rescue the real estate market have continued. Various localities have successively relaxed loan restrictions and purchase restrictions, and introduced various policies to stimulate real estate consumption, but they have not had the same immediate effect as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Reform is gradual and forced. The time has come. Otherwise, real estate may face the risk of &#39;stalling&#39;.&quot; Li Yujia said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;combination punch&quot; of supply-side reform&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The focus of Document No. 14 is the supply-side reform of real estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts who participated in the design of the No. 14 system said that the important problem caused by the past real estate development model was the mismatch between supply and demand. The leading idea of ​​​​the new round of housing reform no longer starts from the demand side, but adjusts the supply. Structure, planning and construction of affordable housing, that is, allotment-type affordable housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meaning is that it is built and sold by state-owned enterprises and supplied at cost price. The owner has complete property rights, but it can only be transferred in a closed manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some houses are for new construction, and the land is allocated and supplied. The construction entities are local state-owned enterprises and urban investment companies, and private enterprises are also encouraged to participate in agency construction. Funds come from special bonds, bank loans, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts analyzed that selling at cost will allow the investment in such affordable housing to be recovered and avoid increasing hidden debts. This also requires that this type of affordable housing must be able to be sold so that it can be built to order and provide effective supply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Revitalizing stock is also an important means of raising funds. Document No. 14 clarifies that in cities with a large inventory of commercial housing, existing commercial housing can be appropriately renovated or purchased to be used as affordable housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Document No. 14 also proposed that there is conditional support for the use of idle and inefficient industrial, commercial, office and other non-residential land to build affordable housing. If the land use is changed, the land price will not be paid back, and the original allocated land will continue to be retained. transfer method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts believe that revitalizing the stock is more important. Because new land is limited in big cities, allocable land is concentrated in the periphery of the city, making it difficult to meet the needs of job-housing balance. And under the downward pressure on housing prices, these areas will be more obviously affected, and the affordable housing constructed may not be popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, real estate has entered the era of stock. Li Yujia introduced that it will take more than five years to digest the general inventory in many peripheral areas of cities. According to a survey by the Ministry of Land and Resources, 40% of the country’s existing land is idle or inefficiently used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan of Document No. 14, this type of affordable housing is mainly aimed at working-income groups who have housing difficulties and low income, as well as groups such as imported talents needed by the city, and people who have been protected by the urban village transformation previously implemented The degree of overlap is high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the State Council executive meeting reviewed and approved the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Actively and Steadily Promoting the Transformation of Urban Villages in Mega-Cities&quot;. On October 12, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development disclosed that the urban village reconstruction information system has currently included 162 urban village reconstruction projects in the database, and the urban village reconstruction in super megacities is being implemented in three categories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia introduced that the renovation of urban villages is mainly aimed at affordable rental housing. It raises housing resources through demolition, reconstruction and inventory improvement. It is mainly to provide rental options for new citizens, young people, etc., and it is a rent-to-rent guarantee. house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The combination of the allotment-type affordable housing planning in Document No. 14 and the transformation of urban villages has formed a &quot;combination&quot; of real estate supply-side reforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The basic logic is that through government-led affordable housing, people with housing difficulties can enjoy urban public services and become citizens. Build &#39;rent before buy&#39;, &#39;small before big&#39;,&#39; &quot;Get on the bus first and then improve it,&quot; the housing asset ownership ladder will eventually become a property owner in the city.&quot; Li Yujia wrote in an article. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Challenges&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, whether the allotment-type affordable housing planned in Document No. 14 can achieve the expected results also faces challenges. One of the keys is closed circulation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 1994, China promoted affordable housing and sold it to low- and middle-income groups at a price lower than commercial housing. However, because there were no closed circulation restrictions, many houses ended up being traded in the second-hand market, which not only created space for rent-seeking, but also gradually lost their protective role. Construction was no longer available in 2003. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Xinhua News Agency&quot;, at the conference call on planning and construction of affordable housing work held on September 4, 2023, Vice Premier He Lifeng emphasized that affordable housing must implement strict closed management. Not allowed to be listed for trading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts involved in system design said that this means that this type of affordable housing will have restrictions on property rights and stipulate a closed period of a certain number of years. During the period, it cannot be transferred and can only be repurchased by the government. After the closed period, it can only be transferred internally among groups that meet the guarantee conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another key issue is whether the existing land can be revitalized and high-quality land parcels can be truly produced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts said that during the preparation process of affordable rental housing, attempts were made to revitalize existing land, but the results were not good. The reason is that the adjustment of land planning is restricted by the overall planning of the area, and whether the public facilities can be constructed after it is converted into residential buildings is also a big test. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, land is an important asset in the eyes of all economic entities. Some enterprises and institutions that occupy high-quality land are more inclined to provide housing benefits to insiders. Can they use the land to build affordable housing and provide housing to the whole world? Social cost price placement is also an issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Achieving home ownership through affordable housing will be helpful to the future development of the commercial housing market.” The above-mentioned experts believe that if the placement-type affordable housing planned in Document No. 14 can achieve the expected results, It will meet the housing purchase needs of new citizens, young people and other groups, and further solve the dilemma of demand gap and high inventory pressure in the real estate market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[逃不掉的，侯孝贤说]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259942]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/oIlWQzZZTDpZ7S7fGr5ibXWqXIxgFpINyhNeGd65.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/oIlWQzZZTDpZ7S7fGr5ibXWqXI xgFpINyhNeGd65. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256541&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the &quot;New Wave of French Films&quot; produced two big figures, Godard and Truffaut, Taiwan&#39;s new films also have two heroes, one of whom is rooted in the soil. Hou Hsiao-hsien, and the other is Edward Yang, a programmer who returned from the United States. With a Western perspective, Edward Yang is good at capturing the urban feel, and his films are more genre-based. The urban feel of Taiwan at that time was a middle ground between rural and urban areas, and the unique flavor was very iconic in his shots. To this day, many aspects of society can still be seen in their movies. Speaking more broadly, if Edward Yang had not passed away prematurely, &quot;Taiwan&#39;s New Cinema&quot; would have had a different pattern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s new film begins with the 1982 platter film &quot;The Story of Time&quot;, which was screened across Taiwan. Among the co-directors was Edward Yang, who studied and worked in the United States and later returned to Taiwan to make movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Hou Hsiao-hsien, who had already made three romance films that were very successful at the box office, joined the following year. He and two other directors made another platter movie &quot;My Son&#39;s Big Doll&quot; - —At this time, Hou Hsiao-hsien obviously hadn’t found himself yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a filmmaker &quot;sees himself&quot;, to be more specific, it means that his attitude towards things and people can be reflected in the film, and he cannot deceive others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s style first appeared in &quot;The Man From Fengkuei&quot; in 1983. A very modern emotional state, akin to melancholy and alienation, is evident when viewed from a distance. The lives of several confused young people are observed from a distance with fixed camera positions and long lenses. The camera suddenly gained an attitude, a bit pushing away the audience and asking everyone to calm down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previous Taiwanese movies were not like this. In the early 1970s, Taiwan was dominated by martial arts films and Qiong Yao-style romance films; in the late 1970s, many pornographic or violent films appeared. Business was not business, and rurality was not rural; by the 1980s, a generation of young Taiwanese people were facing The pull between Chinese traditional spirit and Western modern culture sways with the wind in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/OdDvG7jpCBunuQg2L77akjJfKs0toKpp5rKL2M2Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/OdDvG7jpCBunuQg2L77akjJfKs0toKpp5rKL2M2Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256536&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Hsiao-Hsien Zeng said in an interview: &quot;A director can only make one movie. The method of attention can change, but the angle is the same... Edward Yang left Taiwan for the United States and came back after so many years. His memory compared with his current view. I grew up in the countryside in southern Taiwan. I read classical books. Natural growth and life are my vision...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concept of modernity in Hou Hsiao-hsien is mixed and rich, oriental Form, Eastern thinking, and the core point of view connects the West. At that time, he and several directors of the same age were discussing this matter, which attracted a lot of praise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the best years of Taiwan&#39;s new films, the average annual film production could reach about 120. &quot;This film reform movement inspired by the new generation of film workers and film directors was short-lived in the 1980s. It has experienced ups and downs in a few years, and has reached a peak that is still unreachable for Taiwanese films, giving Taiwanese films a place in the history of world cinema.&quot; This is a summary of Taiwanese new films that I have read from a lot of information. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 24, 1987, the &quot;Taiwan Film Manifesto&quot; was released. At this time, the peak of new films had passed and everyone began to struggle. This declaration is divided into three parts: &quot;Our views on movies&quot;, &quot;Our concerns about the environment&quot;, and &quot;The changes we expect and our own determination&quot;. I went out of my way to see the worries and doubts of these young filmmakers back then, and they proposed: We believe that movies have many possibilities, and we must strive for space for the existence of &quot;another kind of movie&quot; besides commercial movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this point, new films as a trend have quickly dissipated. Since then, everyone’s creations have had to follow the market and personal destiny. For example, many filmmakers do not focus on the reality of Taiwan and do not seek funds from the country ( &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The same is true for Hou Hsiao-hsien&lt;/span>;). The advantage of doing this is that it will not be affected by certain policies in Taiwan. The disadvantage is that it will distance you from reality and indulge in memories. Suspicion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, Hou Hsiao-hsien is not my film inspiration. In 2015, I finally watched Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s movie &quot;The Assassin&quot; on the big screen in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wrote a paragraph after watching the movie:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;&quot;The Assassin Nie Yinniang&quot; does not tell how Nie Yinniang became an assassin, but how she did not become an assassin. First of all, the camera sets the atmosphere .When many directors take pictures of a group of talking people, Hou Hsiao-hsien pays attention to the people standing in the corner. He is behind the camera and does not lead us to see anything. Instead, he follows the movement of the camera to feel what is hidden inside. , there is always a pair of eyes lingering near the speaker.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, news came out that the director was suffering from Alzheimer&#39;s disease, and his family confirmed that he had fully returned to family life and was recuperating. In fact, there have been rumors in the circle about Director Hou suffering from dementia for several years. I think it&#39;s boring to say that a director like him has &quot;retired&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Acheng wrote about a scene in an article. He said that there was originally a braid-cutting scene in &quot;A Dream of Life&quot;, which required more than a hundred braids to be cut off at once. In one shot, it could only be filmed. once. Everyone was very nervous during the filming. As a result, the camera of a female reporter flashed as soon as the braid was cut. Everyone immediately looked at the little girl. No one dared to speak. The little girl was so frightened that she cried. Hou Hsiao-hsien said nothing. &quot;Anyway, the shot was in vain, so there&#39;s no way we can shoot it again.&quot; This quote comes from cinematographer Yao Hongyi, who has worked with Director Hou for many years. In fact, it quite reflects Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s attitude towards movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, there have been news from time to time about Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s new film &quot;Searching for the River God&quot;, but I think it may not be seen. If you can’t see it, it doesn’t matter. He likes to say to young people who make movies: &quot;You can&#39;t escape what kind of person you are when you make whatever you want!&quot; In one of his movies, the young man, regardless of what kind of person he is, shot the movie under prohibited circumstances. A group of young people rode motorcycles and passed by the Chiang Kai-shek Memorial Hall, leaving him far behind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SbJLfSLKF8mdame1OTbhxi33amRDigs5TW8L3lWS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SbJLfSLKF8mdame1OTbhxi33amRDigs5TW8L3lWS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256540&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years In the future, when I revisit these vivid and somewhat joyful movie scenes, I will feel a kind of gratitude that is difficult for others to understand. There are already so many works by Director Hou that can be watched over and over again, isn’t that enough? It just so happens that this last film has a meaningful name - &quot;River God&quot; may refer to himself. Therefore, some people speculate that this movie may be done by the descendants he has trained for many years... This is because it is too unclear what kind of person Hou Hsiao-hsien is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from &quot;The Man from Fenggui&quot; in 1983, Hou Hsiao-hsien became more and more isolated on his path until &quot;The Assassin&quot; won the award at the Cannes Film Festival in 2015. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the movie road, such people are almost extinct. What does such a person look like? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even though he could blend in, he could keep up with the new era, he could incite young people...he didn&#39;t have any of it. I am reminded here of a quote by Truffaut: “If my films contradict the times in which I live, as I am sometimes accused of doing, it is perhaps because I sympathize with those who have to struggle to enter a world from which they are excluded. People of the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The confused young filmmakers will come to their senses sooner or later. The existence of Hou Hsiao-hsien means an &quot;ecology&quot;. There is at least a gap left in the world of movies, which is much more important than countless specific movies. The bigger the bubble, the more likely it will burst; no matter how weak the hope is, it is still hope. Maybe I&#39;m pessimistic, but sometimes optimism can be deceptive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if his friend Edward Yang was still alive, even if the new movies were still a hit, and even if art films finally opened up a market of their own, Hou Hsiao-hsien might have said: &quot;There is no one like him.&quot; He had already seen clearly that All true artists, in the end, will not be able to have anyone around them - at that time, they will become &quot;everyone&quot;, the so-called &quot;see themselves, see the world, and see all living beings&quot;. There is no escaping this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[盲人“看”世界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259957]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;According to relevant data from the China Blind Association, there are approximately 17.3 million blind people in our country. The world of the blind is not just the darkness in front of them, what they have to face is struggling to live in a void. Rather than caring and pity, they want to treat each other as equals and want others to think that blind people can do more than just be masseurs.</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[爆款剧都在开售后演唱会，剧粉福利还是“割韭菜”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259330]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After-sales concerts are becoming a standard feature of hit dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Following the successful after-sales concert of the popular summer drama &quot;Lotus House&quot;, another hit drama &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; also recently held a famous concert It is an after-sales concert for the &quot;First Season Finale Celebration Wilderness Tour Carnival Night&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, during the live broadcast of the carnival night, complaints such as &quot;embarrassment&quot; and &quot;refund&quot; were hotly searched one after another. This is not a problem with the actors, but with the party planning. , the game session was a mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the earlier TV series &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; and &quot;Shan He Ling&quot; to the recent &quot;Lotus Tower&quot; and &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot;, after-sales concerts have become more and more common. It has also become a new way for the platform to make money - how did the after-sales concerts become a trend? How profitable is it? What is the risk of rollover? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fiWgxYqvKNZUfpp1H9Ub1xSPXFZE9m7IZiAkH5RK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;711&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fiWgxYqvKNZUfpp1H9Ub1xSPXFZE9m7IZiAkH5RK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256321&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills of &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;After-sales concerts are becoming more and more popular&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In an era where video websites are competing for hegemony, more and more attention is paid to the &quot;after-sales&quot; of drama series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A drama is not finished after it is aired. If we can provide drama fans with better after-sales service and experience, we can take out more from the fans&#39; pockets. More money can also increase the loyalty of drama fans to the platform, which will help increase the value of platform members. Therefore, after-sales services in the form of after-sales concerts, after-sales parties, after-sales sharing sessions, etc. are becoming more and more popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After-sales concerts are generally broadcast simultaneously online and offline. Offline tickets need to be purchased at a high price, or only by purchasing a platform membership card can you get the chance to draw tickets. Online live broadcasts require the purchase of live broadcast tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the concert, the main creators gathered together to sing theme songs, restore famous scenes, and play interactive games, which formed the main content of the concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The trend of after-sales concerts was first sparked by the 2019 &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the series ended, the platform held two Chinese-style concerts in Nanjing, selling more than 16,000 tickets in six price ranges from 627 yuan to 1,980 yuan5 It was sold out within seconds. If you didn’t grab the ticket, you can still buy the platform’s online live broadcast tickets at prices ranging from 25 yuan to 50 yuan. &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; successfully tested the waters, allowing the industry to see the huge market space for after-sales concerts of popular dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2020, the fairy tale drama &quot;Liu Li&quot; became a dark horse in the summer season and gained many loyal fans. Since it is impossible to gather offline due to the epidemic, the platform has customized a cloud singing party for drama fans. Audiences can pay to watch it at prices ranging from 25 yuan (member price) to 50 yuan (non-member price). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 2021 hit drama &quot;Shanhe Ling&quot; has replicated the amazing popularity of the &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; after-sales concert. There were two consecutive concerts in Suzhou, with the highest ticket price reaching 2,280 yuan (more expensive than a ticket for a first-line singer&#39;s concert). 600,000 people bought tickets online, and it took 14 seconds to sell out. Online live broadcast tickets also cost 68 yuan each. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Afterwards, with the official crackdown on chaos in the entertainment industry, the format of after-sales concerts for popular dramas stopped for a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This summer, an improved version of after-sales concerts will return. However, both &quot;Lotus Tower&quot; and &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; have significantly reduced the number of offline audiences, with only a few hundred people offline. This can make the approval of performances more efficient, and can also avoid some uncontrollable chaos in the entertainment industry, and avoid Public criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Offline tickets are exclusive to high-level members. Only those who have purchased a one-year membership will have the chance to win the lottery. Online viewers can choose to pay to purchase live broadcast viewing tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wsYEwtIPBpAFe4Kt5CzoPTYnxdgouKD5nps7OgrP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wsYEwtIPBpAFe4Kt5CzoPTYnxdgouKD5nps7OgrP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256320&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from &quot;Lotus Tower&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The money from drama fans is really good&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The after-sales concert is really a &quot;charity&quot; for the platform. Is it going to give back to the fans of the drama and provide benefits to the fans of the drama? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obviously not that simple. If it is really a benefit, then should online viewing be free? It may be true that the platform gives back to drama fans, but it must be true that it makes another wave of money from drama fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; has verified how strong the purchasing power of drama fans is. A single offline ticket for &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; was sold to 150,000 by scalpers; online VIP tickets are 30 yuan/ticket, non-VIP tickets are 50 yuan/ticket, and group tickets are 25 yuan/ticket. The total number of people in the live concert room exceeds 3.2 million. If Based on an average of 30 yuan per person, the total online revenue is nearly 100 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only are the offline tickets for &quot;Ling of Mountains and Rivers&quot; more expensive than those of &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot;, but the price of online live broadcast tickets is as high as 68 yuan per piece, but at no point It did not affect the enthusiasm of fans of the drama. The Douban score of &quot;Shan He Ling Born Bosom Friend Concert&quot; is as high as 9.5 points, which shows that fans of the drama are very happy with their money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lotus Tower&quot; has changed to a new format. Even if the number of offline concert tickets is limited, they are basically not sold to the outside world. Buying members and drawing tickets can also It provides a great boost to the platform’s membership fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Drama fans need to purchase a 448 yuan/year Star Diamond membership (or membership level V7) to get 1 chance to draw tickets, and the number of times they purchase a Star Diamond membership Unrestricted. In order to be able to draw tickets, some fans of the drama bought a 10-year Star Diamond membership in one go. The membership fee also costs 4,480 yuan, which is more expensive than offline concert tickets, and they may not be able to win the lottery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; is also played in a similar way. Users who purchase the SVIP annual card of the platform can get 10 lottery opportunities, and the annual card price is 488 yuan. The platform limits the number of recharges for the SVIP annual card, which can only be recharged a maximum of 3 times. This avoids excessive consumption by fans and can also increase users’ enthusiasm for paying for prize draws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In short, there are always ways to make money when the platform holds after-sales concerts. In the short term, you can directly collect money from fans of the drama. In the long term, after-sales concerts will become part of the platform’s membership services. If there is a second season like &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot;, it can also build momentum for the second season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Main actors who have starred in hit dramas will basically attend after-sales concerts. This helps extend the character&#39;s popularity to the actors. What&#39;s more, if other main creators are participating, a single leading actor may be accused of being &quot;insincere&quot; by fans of the drama, and may be &quot;out of touch&quot; or &quot;back-stepped&quot;. . Therefore, as long as most of the core creators agree to hold an after-sales concert, the remaining starring actors will only have the option of &quot;agree&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;It pays to fool drama fans&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Due to character filtering Mirror, drama fans are very tolerant of after-sales concerts. For example, if the actor is not a professional singer, they do not require him to sing well. Drama fans generally have a request, hoping to see traces of the characters in the interactions of the actors, so that the beautiful emotions in the drama can continue offline, and the regrets in the drama can be made up for offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This puts forward high requirements for the restoration and interaction of after-sales concerts - this is why many after-sales concerts have actors wearing costumes from the drama Costumes are used in performances to give drama fans a stronger sense of immersion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lotus Tower&quot; is like this, with a high degree of restoration, full of sincerity, and has been well received. Although &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; received many bad reviews, the restoration of the Qingshui Town part of the play became a highlight of the concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Once the degree of restoration is poor and the interactivity is insufficient, the after-sales concert will instead make the audience laugh and let the audience &quot;get out of the trap&quot;. The previous Cloud Song Concert of &quot;Liu Li&quot; shocked drama fans because the male and female protagonists had almost no interaction on stage. The Douban score of &quot;Liu Li Finale Cloud Song Concert&quot; was as low as 2.4 points. As soon as the after-sales concert ended, the actor dropped a few points. Thousands of fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This time the &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; after-sales concert was criticized, it was not the actor&#39;s problem. Yang Zi&#39;s emotion for the character is still very touching. Tan Jianci was late because of a traffic jam. When he arrived, he sang, danced and adjusted the atmosphere. He was very dedicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The problem mainly lies in the planning of the concert, such as asking the five main actors to pose strange poses in front of the flower arrangements, having Zhang Wanyi recite, and having Deng Wei Cooking, and having Yang Zi and Dai Luwa wearing high heels recreate the fighting scenes in the play... there was little restoration, and the interaction was awkward. It was originally intended to build momentum for the second season, but it actually caused some fans of the show to leave disappointed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After-sales concerts seem to be very profitable, but planning them well is not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the characters in the play are like each other, the offline actors may not be familiar with each other in reality. This requires efforts in planning and in the early stages. Coordinate and communicate more with the actors. For example, you can let the actors wear costumes to continue &quot;performing&quot; in the play, or you can use interesting game designs to allow the actors to have more interactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is foreseeable that after-sales concerts of &quot;small scale offline, money to watch online&quot; will become a new normal for hit dramas in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Drama fans are willing to spend money to &quot;buy benefits&quot;. However, it is worth noting that if the platform is fooled and really treats drama fans as &quot;leeks&quot;, it will It will damage the credibility of the platform and also have a negative impact on the actors. When the platform wants to organize after-sales services, actors may not participate, members are unwilling to pay, and the platform has completely lost a way to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刘家昌自曝家丑为哪般？“先小人后君子”才能财产婚姻两全丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259969]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 26 and November 1, 2023, the famous musician Liu Jiachang published two long articles in succession Accusing his ex-wife Zhen Zhen attracted public attention. Liu&#39;s first long article elaborated on his version of the inside story of the &quot;mother and son fighting for the birth&quot; of his ex-wife and their son, while the second long article accused Zhen Zhen of being incompetent in raising her son and &quot;being a shameless mother.&quot; After Liu Jiachang published his first long article, Zhen Zhen also published a thousand-word article to counterattack, and the two of them were &quot;at odds&quot; with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Weibo promotion&quot; triggered by celebrities&#39; &quot;divorce essays&quot; once again occupied the hot search, and showed a similar plot to similar incidents in the past: one party took the lead in attacking, and looked eloquent. The words are righteous and well-founded; the other party fights back and refutes point by point, which seems to be righteous and sensible. For a time, public opinion was greatly divided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jiachang’s main accusation against Zhen Zhen can be divided into two parts. The first is the issue of division of marital property. Liu Jiachang accused Zhenzhen of transferring Liu&#39;s assets to her name in various ways over the years, including but not limited to company equity, music copyrights and cash income; the second was the issue of his son&#39;s education and growth. Liu accused Zhen Zhen of controlling his son but failing to teach him how to spoil him. He made his son drop out of school again and again and became naughty. He got into troubles including drunkenness, racing, beating people, and soliciting prostitutes. Liu tried his best to encourage his son to make music, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To sum up, Liu Jiachang claimed that he &quot;disclosed his family affairs&quot; because of his failed marriage and hurt feelings. He posted a long article accusing Zhenzhen mother and son just to vent his anger so as not to &quot;die unjustly&quot;. It seems inappropriate. It was all about fighting for property, because he also promised to donate his property to charity if he won the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding Liu’s first long article, Zhen Zhen also issued a counterattack, accusing Liu Jiachang of being addicted to gambling and suppressing his son. It was Liu Jiachang who stole his property, not the other way around; Liu Jiachang After the second long article was released, Zhen Zhen also criticized Liu Jiachang for slandering herself and her son, saying, &quot;It&#39;s really shameless.&quot; Their son Zhang Liheng (formerly known as Liu Ziqian) also supported his mother on social media. The &quot;mutual conflict&quot; between the two sides shows that each has his own words, but in order to determine which is right and which is wrong, we should return to the level of facts and legal principles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the property dispute between the two parties, there are many factual issues that are not difficult to prove or falsify. Written evidence can be used to determine whether these properties were earned by Liu Jiachang, or whether they were simply &quot;registered in the name of his wife Zhenzhen&quot; as joint property of the couple. For example, the audit report mentioned by Liu Jiachang, and the Income details, tax return records, property registration records from the three places across the Taiwan Strait and the United States, as well as legal documents regarding music copyrights, company equity, real estate ownership, and the agreements between the two parties regarding the property, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhen Zhen accused Liu Jiachang of being &quot;addicted to gambling&quot;, and Liu Jiachang responded that &quot;he only used his own money for gambling.&quot; Liu Jiachang accused Zhen Zhen of &quot;not filming for forty years&quot; and that all the joint property was earned by herself. Zhen Zhen also personally told the media that every penny earned by Liu was given to Zhen Zhen and her family. It&#39;s not difficult to prove. Liu&#39;s accusation and response can be summarized as, &quot;It is normal for a husband to make money outside and leave it to his wife to take care of, but Zhen Zhen should not assume that she earned all the money.&quot; Whether this argument can be established is the key issue in determining whether the dispute is right or wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second part of Liu Jiachang’s accusation, “Unvirtuous wife and unfilial son,” is even more difficult to verify because of its rich details and specific descriptions. Liu Wen accused Zhen Zhen of failing to teach her son well and his son was naughty and naughty. He was forced to drop out of school in Hong Kong, Shanghai, and the United States. He also got into troubles including drunkenness, beating people, speed driving, and soliciting prostitutes. Zhen Zhen even &quot;solicited prostitutes on behalf of her son.&quot; , these are specific and severe public accusations. Liu Jiachang should be responsible for providing evidence and ensuring the authenticity of the accusations, otherwise it will be suspected of slander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jiachang also revealed in the long article that his son was able to successfully enroll in school or escape punishment many times by relying on his connections with &quot;big men&quot; such as Run Run Shaw. If these incidents really happened, there must be others. There are too many informed third parties who can verify one by one, and it does not rule out that there are still many cases that can be verified. Liu Jiachang also mentioned that he tried his best to help his son make music but failed. This can also be supported by the record company and related people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a legal perspective, it is meaningless for both parties to resort to personal attacks in moral trials. The focus should still be on the common property division issues in divorce proceedings. The two sides accused each other to swallow their own property. This should be handed over to professional lawyers who specialized in marriage law and company law to conduct a litigation game, and everything can be performed based on normal litigation procedures. Zhen Zhen said that the two sides were divorced in the United States in 1987. Liu Jiachang It is said that it is a divorce in Hong Kong in Hong Kong in 2015. What is the truth about the truth, it also needs to be determined by many places and even more national courts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Who should the public believe in whose little composition? This still needs to be based on facts and law as a criterion in order to obtain a more fair judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The divorce dispute between Liu Jiachang and Zhen Zhen has actually lasted for many years. The reason why old things have been floating on the water again are the disputes over the divorce of property, and the huge interest entanglement mixed with the relationship between parent -child relationship. Even a pair of ordinary couples will have similar &quot;Luo Shengmen&quot; when divorce disputes, let alone star couples who need to divide huge property and have huge conflicts of interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Judging from Liu Jiachang&#39;s allegations, he has a kind of anger of &quot;being hurt by money&quot;, and there is also the resentment of &quot;hurting money because of emotion&quot;. It is the traditional marriage and family values ​​that follow the traditional marriage and family values ​​that follow the Chinese &quot;male lead and the female owner&quot;, but they are exhausted by the &quot;marriage fight for production&quot; by his wife. The reason why their marriage failed and fell into the vicious cycle of &quot;talking about emotional hurts, talking about money and hurting feelings&quot;, and financial decision -making is also an important incentive for unclear financial decisions and not in place in marriage decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Compared with many stars&#39; &quot;Peace Breakup&quot; and &quot;divorce mutual tear&quot; cases, the key to the success of the &quot;peaceful breakup&quot; is that the two parties have done a good notarization of pre -marital property, as well as the division of post -marital property. The procedure, the method of &quot;first villain and then gentleman&quot; is to &quot;pursue common feelings in common interests&quot;, instead of &quot;seeking benefits in the name of emotion&quot;, and understanding the issue of property from the distribution of custody and custody of custody before marriage. In the end, it also better protected the respective interests of the two sides, so as not to fall into a small composition for online bombing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the field, the combination of the Fang -Kang House in the two first -tier cities is like merging two companies, and there is a problem of distribution of large amounts of property. It is best to do a good job of cutting pre -marital property to effectively eliminate possible disputes. In this comparison, the celebrity marriage involves huge amounts of property. Before marriage, you should even agreed how to divide the property with the custody of the property when breaking up. This time Liu Jiachang and Zhen Zhen tore each other again, and once again proved this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[环状RNA有望成为下一代重磅药物]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259706]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-04 15:15:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Because of the invention of MRNA vaccine technology, American scientist Katalin Karikó and Delu Wei Drew Weissman won the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 2023. The MRNA vaccine not only allowed millions of people around the world to be relieved by the new crown virus, but also brought tens of billions of dollars in income for institutions and scientists engaged in vaccine development and production. This makes RNA less stable small nucleic acid molecules attracted much attention. Scientists and pharmaceutical research and development institutions are trying to develop new RNA drugs, and the ring RNA is expected to become the next generation of heavy RNA drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/pekyi0djhc680VEP23HYPVILP2ZWRILYSNFF.JPG&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;1248&quot; height = &quot;814&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/pekyi0djhc680Vep23Hypvilp2zrilySnff.jpg&quot; data- &quot;&lt;256317&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; Circle RNA therapy is getting more and more attention. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (nature website/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; What is ring RNA &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Each per The genetic DNA molecule generally contains several exogenous sub -sequences. It is separated from the inner sub -inner sub -inner sub -chain foretophytic MRNA in the middle. The outer sub -part is stitched together to form a functional MRNA, which is combined with a ribosome to guide them to synthesize protein. Therefore, MRNA is a &quot;reduction version&quot; of gene DNA molecules, which is the complete genetic information of the most streamlined nucleotide carrying genes. The reason why MRNA can be used as a vaccine is that MRNA can directly guide cells to synthesize the corresponding antigen protein, which causes the body&#39;s immune system to produce antibodies and fight virus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, the MRNA vaccine can be described as bumpy before encountering the new crown virus, and it is basically not valued. Kariko could not get funding, and was repeatedly transferred by the unit&#39;s salary reduction or even dismissal. The relative genes of DNA molecules, the MRNA molecular structure is simple, extremely unstable, generally a single -chain linear structure, which is easily broken down by RNA enzymes. Therefore, the MRNA&#39;s half -life in the body is usually only a few hours. Such a short duration time is sufficient for the vaccine, because after the mRNA enters the cells, it can immediately guide the cell synthetic antigen protein, but for cancer, nervous diseases, and genetic diseases that need to be treated with a large number of persistent protein treatment, RNA survive in the body in the body. time is too short. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Interestingly, RNA enzymes are mainly &quot;bullying&quot; wire -shaped RNA, but the ring -shaped RNA cannot be started. In fact, scientists have discovered an RNA that can be connected to the beginning and end of the body more than forty years ago. After the continuous efforts of scientists, this ring -shaped RNA has recently showed huge medical use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1976, the Swiss virusist Daniel KOLA KOFSKY and a German research team found ring -shaped RNA in mice and plant viruses. The circular form exists in the virus, but does not attract enough attention. In the early 1990s, the researchers discovered this circular RNA molecule from humans and other mammalian cells, and proved that these ring RNAs were transcription products of certain genes. After that, scientists found that the ring RNA exists in almost all creatures. However, compared with the linear RNA, most ring RNA edges are often chaotic and cannot guide cells to synthesize the corresponding protein. Among them, people have always mistakenly believe that it is the product of errors in the process of gene transcription, so it does not attract much attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the development of RNA sequencing technology, scientists have found that the central ring -shaped RNA in mammalian cells is very rich, highly conservative, far more stable than linear RNA, and has played many functions. . Studies have shown that more than 60%of the genes can generate ring and linear transcription books at the same time. At present, more than 100,000 categories of ring RNA found in human cells are far higher than the number of human -known genes (about 20,000 people (about 20,000. ). Because it is not easily degraded by RNA enzymes, in certain cells, natural ring RNA can reach 2-4 times, or even longer, and artificially synthesized ring RNA can survive in the cell for several days, and The ring RNA in the cell can reach more than 10 times the linear RNA of the related genes. Scientists have also discovered that endogenous circular RNAs have participated in a variety of biological functions, including genetic transcription, protein translation, immune response, cell proliferation, and physiological regulation of tumor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Most ring -shaped RNAs are generally non -coded due to the lack of nucleose recognition, which can not translate protein, but there are also a few coded RNAs, and these encoded proteins can also be exerted. Normal function. In 1995, researchers at the University of Colorado&#39;s Health Science Center realized the coding function of the ring RNA in vitro for the first time. Among them, adding an internal nuclear into the site is important, which also laid the foundation for the ring RNA as a vaccine and protein drug development. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; Technical breakthrough brings hope &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Since most natural ring RNAs cannot encode protein, they must be manually designed and synthesized. Therefore The ring RNA technology has made a series of improvements and improvement, and has achieved a series of major breakthroughs. For example, in July 2022, the research team of Howard Y. Chang at Stanford University released an important study in the &quot;Natural Biotechnology&quot; magazine. They made a series of improvements on the structure of the ring RNA and optimized the translation. The initial area, the termination area, and the internal ribosome entry site and other modules, and the modular assembly is achieved, making it easier for protein translation to start and more efficient. Compared with the non -modified ring RNA, the modified restructuring protein expression level of the modified ring RNA can be increased by hundreds of times. Mouse test shows that the ring RNA can maintain more than 7 days in the cells, and only a small amount of circular RNA molecules can be maintained for a long time in the cells. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Other major technical breakthroughs also include: add complementary sequences to both ends and middle of the RNA to make the RNA automatic ring, and more stable; let the ring RNA carry longer nucleotide chains, such as more than more than more The muscle -based adverse protein gene sequence of 12,000 nucleotide is to synthesize the more complex protein; optimize the ring RNA delivery system, such as slow virus or exosocoman system, delivered the ring RNA efficiently to target cells; using gene engineering technology technology Large -scale preparation of ring -shaped RNAs, with a large number of ring -shaped RNA preparation costs and time, and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to technological improvements, the application potential of ring RNA in the medical field is another research hotspot. In March 2022, the Wei Wensheng team of Peking University published a paper on the &quot;Cell&quot; magazine confirmed that compared with the linear MRNA vaccine, the ring -shaped RNA vaccine can induce more neutralized antibodies on mice and monkeys, and more effective T. Cell response. In May 2023, the Zhang Yuanhao team of Stanford University issued a document in the &quot;Academy of the Academy of Sciences&quot; that the ring RNA has the potential for developing antiviral and anti -tumor vaccines. Immune on mice can induce the congenital activation of dendritic cells, stimulate lymph nodes and powerful antigen -specific CD8 T cell reactions in the tissue. Mouse immunity test shows that the ring RNA designed for melanoma is significantly inhibited compared with the rats without treating mice. This indicates that the circular RNA can be used as a therapeutic vaccine, inducing powerful cellular immunity and removing tumors. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Compared with the linear MRNA products, the ring RNA products have several advantages. One is that the ring RNA is more stable and easier to store than the linear mRNA. This is because of its own structural characteristics. , Storage, delivery, etc. are degraded by RNA enzymes, so low -temperature storage and cold chain transportation must be performed. Even if a series of transformations such as linear mRNA nucleotide modification, the cost and effect are still not satisfactory, and the ring RNA can be in the ring RNA in It is stored for about a month under normal temperature conditions, and can be repeatedly frozen; the second is that the safety of the ring RNA is better than the linear RNA. Studies show that natural ring RNA molecules show lower immunogenicity and cytotoxicity; The shape RNA has extended antigen production capacity, which can cause the body&#39;s long -lasting immune response, thereby promoting more antibody production, and more lasting immune protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Therefore, ring RNA products are expected to become a better choice in the field of RNA treatment. Various refreshment in viral infections, tumors, pathogenic bacterial infections, autoimmune diseases, metabolic diseases, etc. The prevention and treatment of disease play a greater role. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Has received huge investment &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; It was encouraged by great success by the MRNA vaccine. Family ring -shaped RNA companies are quickly favored and sought after by capital. Some biomedical giants have also joined the tide of circular RNA pharmaceutical products, hoping to take the initiative in future competition. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Daniel Anderson, etc. of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), founded ORNA Therapeutics in 2019. The company&#39;s pipeline products mainly include anti -tumor and anti -infection The ring -shaped RNA therapy for genetic diseases is in the early stages of research and development. The company plans to start the first clinical trial in 2024. In February and August 2022, Olners completed $ 80 million and $ 220 million in Series A and B financing. The 130 -year -old pharmaceutical giant Merck seems to be very optimistic about this startup and has paid $ 150 million prepaid. It plans to jointly develop circular RNA therapy for infectious diseases with Olner. Oerner&#39;s Series B financing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Laronde (Laronde) was founded by Flagship Pioneering. The largest financing of the RNA company. Because the flagship pioneer company once hatched the RNA vaccine star company in the United States Modner, Lao Rongde was also known as &quot;Modner 2.0&quot;. After obtaining huge financing, the company is committed to prevention and therapeutic ring -shaped RNA product development and clinical trials. However, on June 12, 2023, a joint survey report released by Boston Global News and STAT showed that the company was suspected of pre -clinical experimental data fraud. Expression, but it cannot be expressed in monkeys. In a subsequent statement, the company also acknowledged the data designed by the above report and handled the relevant responsible person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Yuanhao of MIT and MRNA vaccine technology pioneer, 2023 Nobel Prize in physiology or medical winner Dru Weisman and others in September 2022 founded ORBITAL THERAPEUTICS ) Company, the company completed a round A financing of up to $ 270 million in April 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are also many startups developed by many circular RNA drugs in China. Circle Code Bio was founded by Researcher Wang Zefeng and others in the Institute of Malp Computing Institute of the Chinese Academy of Sciences in September 2018. It is the earliest startup startup of nucleic acid -based nucleic acid drugs in the world. In December 2021, the ring code organism completed the $ 20 million Pre-A round of financing, and in August 2023, tens of millions of dollars of round A financing was completed again. At present, the company has reached a R &amp; D cooperation agreement with the US pharmaceutical giant Pfizer to jointly develop ring -shaped RNA therapy. The Yuanyin creature was founded by Professor Wei Wentsheng and others of Peking University in April 2021. In June 2022, it successfully completed more than 280 million yuan in Series A financing. In addition, the angel round and Pre-A round financing. 400 million yuan. The company&#39;s R &amp; D pipelines include ring -shaped RNA products that treat infectious diseases, metabolic diseases and tumors. The fastest -growing product is the new RNA vaccine of the ring -shaped RNA, which has completed preclinical trials and entered clinical trials. However The epidemic is calm, and the development of the new crown vaccine is expected to be stranded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, overall, the current research of circular RNA therapy has just started. To realize that as a startup prediction, the ring RNA must start a revolution or achieve 100 100 years in ten years. There is still a long way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[又见哄抢，还要纵容？？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259965]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-04 15:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Recently, the Chinese medicinal materials planted by a farmer planted by a farmer in Huaiyang District, Zhoukou City, Henan Province were robbed by local villagers. Follow. Not long ago, the city had also occurred in the city to coax corn. Within a wider range, such stolen and robbing incidents of large planting households are endless. This has a great relationship with the illegal nature of the villagers who deliberately dilutes the villagers&#39; grabbing and indulge in the violation of the rights and interests of agricultural investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the Chinese medicinal materials were robbed of the Chinese medicinal materials, the Huaiyang District Agricultural and Rural Bureau issued a notice on November 1 that the incident was not grabbing, but that the villagers &quot;mistakenly believed that&quot; the growers were harvested for the second time. After finishing, picking up the medicinal materials. The growers called the police after dissuading, and the police quickly arrived and &quot;persuaded&quot; the masses to leave. The report also said that after the second harvesting of the medicinal materials, the growers allowed villagers to go to the field to pick up the remaining medicinal materials as &quot;the habit of many years.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Picking up&quot; &quot;many years of habits&quot; and &quot;mistakenly believe&quot;. In this case, it can be described as old -fashioned, and it can be seen in almost every incident of the stealing of the growers. Half a month ago, after Dancheng County, Zhoukou City coaxed the corn incident, the response of the local agricultural and rural bureau was also &quot;picking up corn in the harvested land&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; These excuses are ridiculous. Even if there is a local habit of &quot;picking up&quot;, even after the second harvest is completed, the growers allow the villagers to pick up, but in this grabbing, the growers have repeatedly blocked. Households and don&#39;t hear it. Is this still &quot;allowed&quot;? Is this a legitimate &quot;picking up&quot;? In Dancheng County to grab the corn incident, hundreds of villagers also ran to the land that did not receive in front of the harvester to &quot;pick up&quot; regardless of the growers, forcing the harvester to stop working to avoid accidental injuries. Is this still the traditional &quot;picking up&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the incident of a police officer in Gushi County, the growers have not harvested the sorghum. Can&#39;t you always use &quot;picking up&quot; to get rid of it? However, in the eyes of some people, cutting a few sorghum sorghum is not a big deal. &quot;Rural people are not just to occupy some small and cheap.&quot; Arrange patrols to avoid safety accidents, not to stop stealing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The local official face -to -face incident not only described it lightly in words, but also rushed out of the actions for large -scale coaxing. Regardless of whether it was robbed of Huaiyang Chinese medicinal materials or grabbing Dancheng corn. After the growers reported to the government and reported to the government, the police arrived at the scene and &quot;maintained order&quot; and &quot;persuaded&quot; the villagers to leave. What order should be maintained? To grab the police still requires the order, do you still need to escort? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How to qualitatively grabbing behavior? Article 268 of the Criminal Law stipulates that those who gather public and private property, have a large amount or other serious circumstances, who are in prison and active participation, shall be sentenced to imprisonment, detention or control, and fined; the amount is huge or other special special specialties In severe cases, it is imprisoned for three years and less than ten years, and a fine. The large and huge standards are determined by various high courts. According to the standards of the Shanghai High Court, the value of more than 4,000 yuan is &quot;large&quot;, and more than 40,000 yuan is &quot;huge amount&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The crime of gathered in the crime is only punishment and active participation. For those who participate in the general participation, if you cannot convict, you can also punish administrative penalties. Public security management punishment law stipulates that those who rob the public and private property shall be detained for more than five days and less than ten days, and may be fined below 500 yuan; if the circumstances are heavy, they will be detained for more than 10 days and less than 15 days. fines below. Those who are not robbing but theft can apply the stipulation of theft and public security management punishment law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But in reality, the police often open on the Internet. A few years ago, the melon farmers who happened in Zhejiang were stolen by 30,000 pounds of watermelon overnight. After the police investigated, the police found that the melon picker was misunderstood that the rumors of &quot;the gourd boss didn’t need&quot; to pick the melon. The subjective intention is that it does not constitute the theft, but it is only a &quot;civil dispute&quot;, which requires the farmers of farmers to go to civil procedures for claims. The watermelon planted by a melon farmers in Xi&#39;an, Shaanxi was also robbed by the villagers. The speech of the village branch secretary was also the villagers&#39; &quot;rumors.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If &quot;listening to rumors&quot; can become a reason to get rid of sin, then there is no illegal crime. If you want to steal things, go to spread some &quot;rumors&quot;, and then you can sway to steal it. Is there such ridiculous things in the world? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are also some people who defend the villagers in the old farmers and lives. These reasons are also untenable. Even if your own life is in trouble, you should go to the government to reflect the problems, rather than grab the property of others. In fact, these justifications are also completely excuses for imagination. Most of the villagers who participated in grabbing are not reaching the point of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In recent years, many similar places have been robbed and theft. It must be said that it is related to the sewage and indulgence of local governments and local police. After the incident, the local government only &quot;persuaded&quot; to participate in the property that the robbers returned to grabbing, and did not punish them, and even some people refused to return it. Of course, the robbers will not stop, and will continue to grab it next time, and will not return it again. On the contrary, if the relevant departments decisively punished, the detention of the detention, the sentence of the sentence, killing chickens and monkeys, would anyone dare to grab it in the future? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2014, the fish who had also occurred in Zhangzhou, Fujian was robbed by local villagers. The local police filed a case in time to detain the three villagers who participated in the plot of the fish. Participating villagers &quot;invest&quot; and &quot;return the stolen goods&quot;. It is clearly announced that it is illegal to grab the law. If you are punished by law, the robbery is &quot;stolen goods&quot;, which must be refunded. This is the correct way to deal with such a grabbing. Only in this way can we build and maintain a good local business environment, attract more agricultural investment, and revitalize the countryside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国工商银行原副行长张红力接受审查调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259971]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-04 15:08:23 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;pan>; The former member of the Party Committee and Vice President of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Zhang Hongli Disciplinary review and supervision and investigation of the State Supervision Commission of the Discipline Inspection Commission. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 15:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[秋季以来持续偏暖影响几何？会是暖冬吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259961]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-04 14:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Since this fall, the temperature in most areas in my country has continued to be high, and it is delayed in winter. Many public doubts: Will it be a warm winter this year? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At a press conference held by the China Meteorological Administration on the 3rd, Jia Xiaolong, deputy director of the National Climate Center, introduced that the national average temperature in October was 12.2 ° C, which was 1.6 ° C higher than the same period of the year. Highest. Most of the Northeast and most Shandong, most of Inner Mongolia, most of Xinjiang and other places are high from 2 ° C to 4 ° C. Inner Mongolia, Xinjiang, Tianjin, and Liaoning have the highest temperature in the same period, and the highest temperature of 140 national meteorological stations breaks through. October historical value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Since this autumn, Eurasia&#39;s mid -to -high latitudes region is dominated by the circular circulation. my country has been controlled by high levels of positive fields. It&#39;s too high. &quot;Jia Xiaolong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Experts said that high temperature and weak cold air have a certain impact on fog, haze weather development, and agricultural production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, fog and haze weather appeared in Huanghuai and other places in North China. Zhang Jiancheng, deputy director of the National Meteorological Center, said that the main reason is that the latitude circulation is dominated by the circular circulation and cold air and weakness in North China in the near future. North China, Huanghuai and other places are located in the weak gas pressure field of the high pressure, which prevails in the south wind for a long time. At the same time, with the high humidity and atmosphere, vertical temperature structure, and the special terrain of the Taihang Mountains and the Yanshan Mountains Severe fog and haze weather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although most of the northeast, northwestern North, northwest, and other places have entered winter, the winter is late for winter, and some areas have been more than 5 days later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jia Xiaolong said that warm weather may cause the soil to be low, affecting the seedlings and growth of crops, and it is not conducive to the spring and spring sowing in the coming year; delay in winter may affect the growth season and cycle of crops, which is not conducive to agricultural production plans and agricultural production plans and Production; warm and hot climate can easily lead to overwhelming crops and benefit the wintering and reproduction of pests and insect pests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Does continuous warmth mean this year&#39;s warm winter? How does El Nino affect this winter climate? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The climate forecast released by the National Climate Center on the 3rd stated that in the winter of this winter, the temperature in most areas in my country is close to the same period or high in the same period of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Whether it is warm winter depends on whether the temperature can meet the warm winter standard.&quot; Jia Xiaolong said. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Monitoring shows that the Equator Middle East Pacific has entered the state of El Niophae, and an El Niopy incident is about to form. Affected by this, abnormal anticyclonic circulation prevails in the lower troposphere over the northwest Pacific and South China Sea in winter, the East Asian trough is weak, the East Asian winter monsoon is weak, and temperatures in most central and eastern my country are higher than normal for the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the other hand, the abnormal anti -cyclone circulation is conducive to the warm and humid water vapor from tropical, which is transported to the southern my country. With cold air movement south, it is easy to cause more precipitation in the south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Statistics show that in the context of the El Nino incident, the temperature in winter is relatively large, which affects the number of cold air in my country. It is recommended to pay close attention to the adverse effects of the process of low temperature rain and snow weather.&quot; Jia Xiaolong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贫困大学生哭诉助学金被挤占：福利如何才能落到需要的人手里？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259963]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-04 13:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Recently, a video of a poor student of college crying complains that the qualifications of the school aid were squeezed down and widely spread on social networks. Align great attention. The Tianjin University of China and Germany China University of Applied Technology, involved, said on November 2 that it had set up a special class for investigation and verification for the first time, and will be promptly announced in a timely manner according to the results of the investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the video of the Internet, a boy said that he was married to his father since his child, and his grandfather died at the age of 18. He only has one relative of his grandmother now. Poor households. After going to college, he had received a national student fund in previous years, but this year, the qualification qualification selection in the class was held. Available), use Apple 14 Pro Max phones and iPad Pro tablets, often dinner and travel. He asked the counselor to report the situation, but as a result, he was forced to move out of the dormitory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If this is true, it is really angry, this video has attracted great attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In reality, it is nothing new in some colleges and universities. The National Student Fund of Universities is an economic funding provided by the state&#39;s financial difficulties for college students in the country. It is mainly used to solve the living expenses of students. The average funding standard is 3,000 yuan per person per year (non-equal, 2-3 grades), about 20% of each person, about 20% Students can receive funding. Student aid is a benefit for the country to give some poor college students. Since it is welfare, how to allocate, and how to get the money who really needs this money is a very important issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to this student, the qualification qualifications of their class were selected by the whole class, because he was not satisfied with the results of the first selection, and went to the teacher to report. It became the person who was the most qualified to receive a funds in the class. The selection of the whole class looks very &quot;reasonable&quot;, but it is undoubtedly ridiculous here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Who is not difficult for who is in difficulties, is not a one -person one -vote. If it is selected, it becomes a &quot;connection&quot; competition, and it is inevitable that some students can help and even bribe. And the real poor students may have a piece of students who are unable to meet the conditions because they are unable to have good conditions. On the social network, a group of people &quot;united&quot; pushed a person up and got a student -assisting visitor to eat. The next time I changed my personal take turns, such posts are not uncommon. As a result, a college has issued a notice that the scholarship students may not use a student aid to invite guests, otherwise they will be verified that they will cancel their future evaluation qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some schools and classes even allow students who apply for school assistance to tell their situation in front of the classmates and &quot;campaign&quot; aid. This is to make people show their scars, and it may bring a great blow to the students&#39; self -esteem. Although some students are poor, they are unwilling to let others know, especially under the public. Because poverty is not worthy of showing off after all, nor is everyone&#39;s compassion. The school laughed at the poor classmates in the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is not a good strategy to let counselors, class teachers, etc. be able to master the qualifications to assist the qualifications. First of all, it is difficult to guarantee that these people are completely public in the process of quota distribution. Most counselors may be fair, but a few private people will inevitably appear. Sometimes, the qualifications of school assistance may even become a &quot;obedient&quot; tool for students. Secondly, the counselor may not be able to fully understand the economic situation of the students, and the lack of sufficient and correct information, and the correct judgment cannot be made. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The identification of the qualifications of the scholarship should have some objective standards, not only the subjective identification, whether it is the subjective of the individual (the counselor, the class teacher&#39;s identification), or the subjective of the whole class (the whole class selection) . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; What are the objective standards? Theoretically, it can be whether students&#39; family income is lower than certain standards. However, the school&#39;s income and assets cannot be obtained directly, so many schools will allow poor students to provide a certificate of poverty in the village committee or neighborhood committee. But these proofs are not completely credible. Over the time, these poverty certifications are not necessarily true. Especially for many rural areas, students in the village are admitted to college. Even if the family is not particularly poor, it is not difficult to open a poverty certificate in the village committee. After all, they are all villagers. A burden, many village cadres will open it, unless the income at home is significantly higher than the average level of the village. Secondly, poverty standards in different regions are also different. Poverty in economically developed regions and poverty in the western region are completely two concepts. In recent years, there are often examples of government officials visiting the &quot;poverty&quot; people who have been vomited. Of course, there are fake poverty, but there are also some misunderstandings caused by the differences in regional economic levels. Therefore, the family poverty certification issued by the source of the source can only be a reference, and should not be used as a decisive factor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How should the qualification qualification of the scholarship be determined? This is of course a very complicated problem, it is difficult to achieve completely ideal. But there are still some standards that can be referred to. For example, you can use applying for student loans as a necessary condition. In the national college student funding policy system, student loans are mainly used to solve the problem of tuition and accommodation fees for students in economic difficulties. Now the tuition and accommodation fees of most schools are much higher than the standard of student aid. If the tuition and accommodation fees can be solved by itself, it means that it is not too poor, otherwise you can apply for tuition fees for student loans and leave your money as living expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; You can also observe the consumption of students on campus. The practice of Nanjing University of Science and Technology is a good reference. In 2016, Nanjing Institute of Technology analyzed the data consumed by students in the cafeteria. It was listed as a funding target for students who had eaten more than 60 meals in the cafeteria each month and their total consumption did not exceed 420 yuan. This is a very smart approach. As we all know, the food in the school cafeteria is much cheaper than the outside. If a student eats almost every meal in the school canteen, the average consumption of each meal is not high, and it is highly likely. This is a poor student. Rich students, either eat less in the cafeteria in the school, often get off the restaurant called takeaway, or consume high in the cafeteria and eat well. Eating is a person&#39;s just need. Regardless of the poor and rich, you have to eat, so the consumption level of diet is used as a measure, and all students can be covered. And the level of diet consumption is difficult to fake. A person who is accustomed to a high standard diet, it is difficult to keep him in dietary standards for a month without changing economic conditions. Of course, this approach may also be speculated. Each meal eats a little bit in the cafeteria, and then goes outside to eat and drink, but the rich people who can stick to this are probably rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In short, the national aid as a benefit provided by a country&#39;s finances for poor students should be used on the blade to truly reduce the burden of life for poor students, and should not become the Tang monk meat that everyone wants to eat. The official claim of Tianjin Zhongde University of Applied Technology has launched an investigation, hoping that the investigation and processing results can be fair and fair. More importantly, the problem of unfair distribution of scholarships is available in many colleges and universities, which should cause all universities to be vigilant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当一个盲人想要登上珠峰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259956]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-04 12:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/olqpwxqwepurbnuztsjdfes4jsour9ieffnviot.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 641 &quot;height =&quot; 960 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm/medias/i Mage/23/11/03/olqpwxqweurbnuztsjdfes4jsour9ieffnviot. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 256991 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; During the climbing process, there was a crisscross ice crack under the foot, Zhang Hong You need to use the climbing stick to test the location and terrain, and then use your feet to measure the approximate width of the ice cracks, and finally dare to get the feet out. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (interviewee confession/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; standing on the top of the world&#39;s highest peak, the first idea of ​​the blind man Zhang Hong is &quot; Hurry up. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Most of the climbing accidents appeared on the way down the mountain.&quot; Zhang Hong said that when climbing, people&#39;s focus was in front, even if wrestling, there were mountains blocking, and down the mountain, &quot;All subconscious consciousness&quot; . He hung a heart until he returned to the Everest base camp, and the ice claw was taken off. It meant that the danger was far away. Shilba (Note: Locals living on both sides of the Himalayas are usually served as a guide) to give him a glass of milk tea and a few biscuits to fill their hunger. The road of rushing and returning almost exhausted his strength, and he was almost unconscious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After two years, the cognitive system of sound, hearing, and tactile composition has made his memories of the world&#39;s first peaks still clear. He clearly perceives the differences in the height of different altitudes: the wind of the low altitude glaciers is mixed with cold cold, and the storms at high altitude make huge sounds. It is difficult to surpass like a high wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hiking through the glacier, the ice cubes on the soles of the feet have a hard texture, and stepping on the sound of &quot;click&quot; like biting potato chips. Even if you kick with ice, the risk of slipping is unavoidable. The snow was thick, and the footsteps were stuffed inside, giving people a more solid sense of stepping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On May 24, 2021, at the peak of Mount Everest 8848.86 meters, Zhang Hong followed a few photos and a 15 -second small video. The former became his WeChat avatar, the latter is his &quot;first blind&quot; record of &quot;Asia to the top of Everest.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When the news of the success of the summit was passed to Fan Lixin&#39;s base camp, the documentary director was halfway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He was happy for Zhang Hong&#39;s years of hard work. In 2019, he heard Zhang Hong&#39;s wish from a climbing friend: a blind masseur is eager to board Mount Everest. The people around him felt unreliable, but Fan Lixin became curious about the character. Gamblers generally wanted to shoot this story that is likely to fail. In May 2020, the documentary was launched, and the fate of two &quot;paranoia&quot; had been on the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Worried that because there was a problem with oxygen, the two photographers who followed the followers failed to go up together. The video material of Zhang Hongzhong was blank, and Fan Lixin just collapsed. On October 27, 2023, the documentary &quot;Invisible Peak&quot; was released nationwide. Fan Lixin filled the gap of the material with a period of &quot;black&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;We took more than 360 hours of materials and spent one year editing. When I edited, I was thinking that if there was no material in this paragraph, it would be as much as&quot; will be calculated. &quot; (Sound feeling), substitute the audience into a blind world. &quot;Fan Lixin told the southern weekend reporter,&quot; Use this black field to bring the audience and follow Zhang Hong&#39;s footsteps to the top of the world. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt; p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/WivtRGd596cs3s9SoNMddIhhBxMGdd3QSXOa6bhS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/WivtRGd596cs3s9SoNMddIhhBxMGdd3QSXOa6bhS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256989&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text -align: center;&quot;>;张洪和妻子夏琼。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张洪对登顶珠峰有近乎偏执的渴求。那时，他在西藏的一所医院的中医医疗科做副主任，四十多岁，工作稳定，和妻子共事，还有一个儿子。所有人都对他“疯了”一样要登珠峰感到不解：“这个事完全不靠谱，手里有这么好的工作，稳定下来了，还要去做这个事情，这就是吃饱了撑的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张洪承认，执念来源于某种想要证明什么的欲望。 “以前自己给自己贴上标签，我是社会上一个不幸的人。但是攀登珠峰的过程，让我学会了一件事：其实我和其他人都是一样的，社会和大自然对我并没有怎么另眼看待。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“珠峰不会因为我是盲人，就给我更多的同情”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;正式拍摄登顶前，范立欣跟拍了张洪一年多。当时，张洪珠峰之行的最大焦虑是钱。纪录片开机时，张洪得到了一个基金会5000美金的支持，但离“小一百万”人民币的缺口还很大。镜头前，张洪借着酒劲，窘迫地和兄弟开口借。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时没什么眉目，说实话我也挺焦急的，他如果筹不到钱的话，就是想去也去不了，”范立欣对南方周末记者说，“有可能就变成一个&#39;堂吉诃德&#39;的故事。”后来通过众筹、品牌介入、医院托底，出发前一个星期，张洪才将钱堪堪凑齐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张洪走的是攀登珠峰的传统路线。从尼泊尔首都加德满都坐直升机或小型固定翼飞机到卢卡拉小镇，再徒步7天到珠峰大本营，“相当于初期的适应性训练”。在大本营稍事休整后，团队进行了两次拉练。第一次拉练的目的地是6100多米高的罗布切；第二次拉练，则要爬到海拔8300米处的C3营地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;范立欣此前没爬过山，第一次拉练的罗布切，是他攀登过的第一座山。小时候他的腿部开过刀，膝盖被挖掉了三分之一，难以陪张洪一起攀登珠峰。他请来两名高山摄影师，算上兼任录音师的制片人，团队精简，只有4个人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从大本营爬到C1营地，海拔高度上升不多，但要途经被称为“恐怖冰川”的昆布冰川，冰川中遍布沟壕。宽大的冰沟间，两节梯子叠在一起做桥，人和摄像机一起从上面颤颤巍巍经过。饶是常年和珠峰交手的夏尔巴也不能掉以轻心。纪录片拍摄时，一名夏尔巴掉进了冰沟，命悬一线。同队的人费了一番工夫救他上来后，他的身体蜷曲着，耳朵冻得紫红。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;视力正常的登山者可以走一步望十步，张洪只能老老实实盯住眼下的这步。每一步都艰难。每走一步他就在心中默念：“这个雪地又接纳了我，脚下的脚印又承载了我。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/WPjpaab7QJy6eKt9fLqo3FPrpOBP9neXcuFCWk76.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/WPjpaab7QJy6eKt9fLqo3FPrpOBP9neXcuFCWk76.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256990&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在珠峰拍摄时，最大的困难是电，因为柴油发电机的柴油需要一点点驼上来，只能靠太阳能充电，但攀登时常常三五天不见太阳，纪录片团队常常感到焦虑。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“珠峰不会因为我是盲人，就给我更多的同情。冰川下面有冰窟窿，旁边是悬崖，梯子同样是摇晃的，不会因为我看不见而降低难度。”张洪第一次登山时，就被类似的感觉击中，“我能感觉到我和所有人一样，在一个同等的、公平的环境下做一件事情，我和所有人之间没有障碍，而不是之前我认为我自己是不幸的、另类的存在”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但因无法视物，攀冰对张洪来说阻碍重重。范立欣介绍，喜马拉雅山脉那年天气恶劣，路况复杂。攀爬冰壁时，视力健全的登山者可以踩在前面人踩过的冰坑上。但张洪看不见，脚下的钢制冰爪难以准确踢进旧坑，要比常人耗费更多力气踢出新坑。在冰壁上挂着时，登山者靠三点支撑，一手拉绳子，一手用冰镐砸冰，使劲把自己的身体往上拉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们能看见，所以大概知道往哪儿砸，会拉得上劲，可是他看不见，他就是乱凿，凿一下，冰飞了就白凿了，就得再凿。爬十几米的冰壁就累得不行。”范立欣观察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在第一次拉练时，张洪突然发了火，直言不想爬了，要求派直升机来接。同行的队伍里，有人嫌他的步频跟不上进度，拖慢进程，张洪面露不悦。 “他跟团队之间是需要磨合的，他会觉得风险太过高了，他倒不是害怕自己出什么事，他最害怕的是还没有真正的攀登呢，只是在拉练就受伤了，或者体力耗尽。”范立欣对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“海拔五六千米之上，人的情绪和思维跟我们在平原地区，完全不一样。”张洪分析当时的心态，“如果还没有（正式）攀登，拉练的时候就受伤，就很不值得了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二次拉练时，张洪的胆囊炎发作，痛得五官紧紧拧在一起。回到大本营，营地的医生对他做了一番检查。张洪从旁人那里得知，医生建议把他送回加德满都治疗，“甚至要动手术”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一旦去治疗，攀登几乎就告吹了。”张洪把自己裹进睡袋，崩溃地哭了出来。 “时间不等人，天气不好，窗口期有限，就那么几天。不能因为这点事情，就放弃攀登。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他责怪自己没有对此做好预案，但又对病痛无计可施，只能尽力揉搓腹部，按摩肝经和胆经。他攀登珠峰，一个原因是为了打破外界对盲人的刻板印象，盲人不只能做按摩这行。但命定般的，按摩两三天后，病状真的缓解了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一切都是天意。”他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/pxIY9yIS7ks79vnYsbBCixImw9AWvHoKHvS1nygy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/pxIY9yIS7ks79vnYsbBCixImw9AWvHoKHvS1nygy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256987&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年5月24日，已经失明25年的张洪成功从尼泊尔一侧登上世界最高峰珠穆朗玛峰，成为亚洲首位登上珠峰的盲人。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;登顶&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;冲顶时刻在2021年5月23日晚上七点到来。张洪、中方向导、摄影师以及夏尔巴从C4营地出发向珠峰顶进发。离峰顶只有100米时，意外出现了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;恶劣的天气冻坏了所有人的氧气调节阀，导致氧气泄漏。大家一合计，现有的氧气量难以支持所有人登顶。强子是张洪的中方向导，有过15年的高山向导经验，但从未登顶过珠峰。对登山爱好者来说，2小时就能攀完的那100米，是个“巨大的诱惑”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;强子最终决定把自己的氧气让出来，两位摄影师做出同样决定，三人下撤，由夏尔巴陪同张洪一个人登顶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;范立欣后来问及放弃原因。强子说，和张洪认识三四年里，一路见证他的不易和委屈。 “我是真心不愿意让他再走一趟，可能他这辈子也不会再有第二次机会再走了。训练、筹钱，顶住周围社会的舆论，亲戚朋友的质疑——你看不见，冒这么大的险干什么？大家不会想到说一个盲人也有权利去实现自己的理想，去追寻自己的人生价值，同时也为这个家里争口气。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三个夏尔巴和张洪连在一根绳上，张洪推上升器前进。一个夏尔巴在约1.5米前引路，两人语言不通，只靠简单的英语词汇“go”“up”“down”交流。还有两个夏尔巴在后面背着氧气，其中一个夏尔巴偶尔拍拍他的腿，“表示安慰和鼓励”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;登顶前，最难的一段路程是“希拉里台阶”，那是一片刃状山脊，岩壁几近垂直，连“雪都挂不住”。张洪预估，窄处大概仅30公分，仅能容留下半只脚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;手在这时成了他的眼睛。他一只手支撑，另一只手顺着脚尖往前探路，找到下一步的脚落点后，再靠另一只手寻找支撑点，每迈一步，“得停下来休息好久好久”。张洪形容，攀爬希拉里台阶，就像穿梭在他视力尚健全时看过的那种人造假山里，石缝完全不规则，“根本不知道下一步怎么走”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“希拉里台阶”距离峰顶只有12米，却花了张洪两个多小时。攀登时，他一度失去了时间概念，隔一段时间就左右摇晃绳子，询问领路的夏尔巴：“How long? How long?”夏尔巴的回答每次都是半小时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“结果过了好几个半个小时还没到。也许我过了5分钟就问还有多久，过了10分钟又问。”张洪有点焦急，说了几次“不行”“我要死了”“我要下去”。起先夏尔巴并未理会他的抱怨，最后一次夏尔巴也被弄生气了，带着情绪同意了张洪要放弃的请求，转身准备帮他解掉上升器，换上下降器。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/FZaEOpaZ1qtetpzFuojXRkKa8TGvXX6nZFA75asj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;586&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/FZaEOpaZ1qtetpzFuojXRkKa8TGvXX6nZFA75asj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256988&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;范立欣回忆，那一年印度洋有两三个大的气旋，导致珠峰下大雪刮大风，张洪登顶那天，风速达到每小时60公里，人几乎要被吹倒，如果衣服划破、羽绒飞掉，后果将是“瞬间失温死掉”。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不甘的情绪攫住了张洪，他对夏尔巴说：“Go! Go! Go! ”“继续走。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;爬着爬着，张洪突然感觉冰爪踩上了一处软软的雪地，越往前走越觉得踩感厚实，直至积雪深得能将整只脚掌覆盖。他一下子撞上了前面人的背包。 “You summit（你登顶了）。”他听见领路的夏尔巴转过头对他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我并没有以为真的登顶了。”张洪回忆，“我也不知道走到哪里，反正就是这样走。可能是因为太累，还没能从&#39;走一步算一步&#39;的专注度里反应过来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的感官先于意识捕捉到了周边环境的变化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上山时，张洪无形中感知到，正在攀爬的山体，像一个巨大的障碍挡在面前。但在那一刻，障碍感消失了。他听出周围变得空旷，一览无余的那种空旷。他把头往左转了转，又往右转了转，仔细听了听周围的声音，风声剧烈地在他的头上打转，听得他“毛骨悚然”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们在珠峰顶上停留时间不长，张洪听见夏尔巴说，“Photo, photo”，快速了留了几张影，下了山才知道，还拍了认证video.他后来告诉范立欣，只听到对讲机里一直窜着各种听不懂的语言。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他想起那个瞬间，甚至是有一点可笑，他准备了那么多年，准备了很多姿势、豪言壮语要在珠峰上说一下，什么都没有，就2秒钟，他就醒悟过来说，赶紧往下，这个地方太可怕了，就像地狱一样，那个风声呼号。”范立欣回忆，“他以前失明的时候，真的觉得世界崩塌，就像在地狱里一样。他说我爬了20年，从地狱里爬到平地上，再从平地爬到珠峰顶。（到了峰顶）感觉好像又到了地狱一样，于是赶紧往山下下。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结束攀登后，他们被新一轮新冠疫情困在尼泊尔。那阵子，正是外部最喧腾的时候，范立欣统计过，包括BBC、法新社在内七十余家国际主流媒体都在报道他。张洪说，自己当时并未沉浸在被聚光灯照着的感觉中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他爬完珠峰以后才发现，登顶珠峰根本不是他所需要的高光时刻，而是让他明白了，当下的这一步是最重要的。因为这一步没有踩好，可能就掉下去，人就没了，根本没有什么所谓的高光时刻。真正的高光时刻有可能在你最危险的时刻才刚开始，电影里面的向导也说了：登顶不是终点，回到家里才是终点。”在尼泊尔时，范立欣和他聊天，“他说，你现在告诉我我现在站的地方就是珠峰顶，我也相信，因为我看不见”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;他想让别人觉得，盲人不只会做按摩师&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;刚开始拍摄张洪时，范立欣觉得他是个有些急躁的人，调试设备或更换电池的空隙，张洪会显得有些焦躁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;急躁来源于他的突然失明。 21岁那年，一次青光眼发作，他永久性丧失了视力。花了三四年时间，张洪尝试接受看不见这件事，性格也因此发生改变，他变得“情绪崩溃”“脾气暴躁”，要拿的东西没拿到，或者无意间碰翻了杯子都会展露急躁的一面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;妻子夏琼柔软地接住了这些瞬间。她有一次试着换位思考丈夫的处境，把自己关在屋子里，熄灭全部的灯，闭紧窗户，“感觉四面墙都向你挤压过来”。她体会到丈夫身处未知的环境里，那种对危险的紧张感。 “本来是很温顺的一只羊，自由的物种，突然间被困在一个看不见的黑色牢笼里。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张洪小时候的成长环境，和“盲”紧密黏连。他的父亲和叔叔都是盲人，视力健全的他有时充当“盲杖”，三人拉一根竹竿，张洪就在前面领路。遇上雨天，路面滑湿，张洪摔倒，连着父亲和叔叔一起摔跤。在农村社会，他很早就感知到了盲人的境遇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我从小知道他们的生活，想到自己以后也要生活在这样的环境里面，就没有办法接受。”张洪说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夏琼察觉到，家庭背景和童年记忆，在张洪内心生出一种自我防御机制。结婚前，张洪从未和她主动谈起过父亲和叔叔的情况。他们结识于张洪还能和世界目光交错时，后来张洪失明，她调侃说，自己是被金庸的武侠小说给“害”了，侠肝义胆地觉得，“不应该让他一个人孤零零的没人Tube&quot;. 1999年，相恋3年的两人决定扯证。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家族长辈们众口一致地反对，父亲在夏琼面前哭了出来。张洪承诺她：“我一定会让你家里人对你刮目相看。”她想，也许是从那个时候起，为丈夫之后的“不断折腾”埋下了伏笔。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在西藏安定下来前的二十年里，夏琼形容他们的生活是“风雨飘摇”。张洪在学校里学的专业是推拿，但并不醉心于此。失明后，专业反而救了他，让他不至于吃不上饭。夏琼也学了推拿。夫妻俩先是在成都当按摩师，日子过得“苟且偷生”。后来去上海的按摩店里打工，两人水平能排到“店里的前一二名”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年，夏琼回家待产，收到张洪从上海寄来的保健品，她知道丈夫又“折腾”了。张洪背着她把工作辞了，去干销售。 “他有时候跟人家讲，他在上海一个人在地铁里面找不到出路，被困在地铁里面，在上海的马路上被困在十字路口。”夏琼说，“他是想要让别人觉得盲人不单单只会做按摩师，还会做别的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，登上7500多米的慕士塔格峰后，张洪决定为登珠峰做准备。为了节省开销，他采用了最经济划算的训练方式——爬楼梯。爬的同时穿上高山靴，戴阻氧面罩，同时负重二十多公斤，每天爬三四个小时。他住在医院的公寓楼，每天从一楼爬到十二楼，再坐电梯下来。碰见医院的同事，他感受到压力，“身边无数人质疑，觉得这哥们不但瞎了，还疯了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;忍受身边人的异样眼光和筹措不到资金的困局，无数次，他坐上电梯后，手指在一层和自己家所在的层数犹豫、徘徊，“一直这样纠结了两年”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有的人可能会觉得让妻子温饱，儿女有钱读书就可以；有的人觉得要给孩子一个榜样，让爱的人在人前人后脸上都有光。”夏琼说，丈夫张洪“可能是后者”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张洪成功登顶珠峰后，一些细微的变化隐然发生。从前医院里的人提起张洪，是“夏医生的老公”，如今，他们称呼她为“张洪的太太”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿子两岁时，夏琼和一位亲戚关掉灯，在一片黑黢黢中问儿子：天黑了，你要保护谁？两岁的儿子奶乎乎地说：保护爸爸。夏琼和女亲戚百思不得其解：我们都是女性，为什么要保护爸爸？儿子想都不想地说：因为爸爸看不见。如今，儿子觉得爸爸“很可以”“比较强大”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;范立欣和夏琼都观察到，攀登珠峰成功之后，生活中的张洪变得松弛许多。失明之后，他曾一度难以接受弱人一等的感受。他和每一个普通人一样有自己的缺点，但他宁愿听到平视的批评，也不要俯视的褒奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“攀登珠峰之前，我在外面那么多年，从来不跟别人讲起我家人的事情，只有我老婆知道，除此之外没有第三个人知道，但是珠峰下来以后，我可以跟任何人分享我家里发生的任何事情，包括我爸爸、叔叔看不见，以前我是没有办法面对，现在我可以从容地面对这些事情。”张洪说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>