<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[高速服务区外来师傅修车受阻：背后是“独家经营权”带来的垄断收益丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258660]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;If the vehicle breaks down in the highway service area, can it only be repaired by the repair shop in the service area? The employees of the maintenance shop in the service area threatened to stop the maintenance technicians hired from outside to repair the car. Is this &quot;reasonable and legal&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Jimu News, a truck transporting fruit broke down and failed to start while resting in the Jiangxi Fengcheng service area of ​​the Shanghai-Kunming Expressway. After the auto repair shop in the service area said it could not repair the vehicle, the driver himself invited a technician from a nearby designated repair shop of the truck manufacturer to come to the service area to prepare for repairs. Unexpectedly, he was blocked and intimidated by the staff of the repair shop in the service area. The maintenance technician who was invited had no choice but to leave. The truck driver contacted several local repair shops, but they did not dare to arrange for personnel to go to the service area to repair the vehicle. There was no choice but for the driver to drag the car off the highway to repair it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for car repairs to conflict with repair shops in expressway service areas. More than a month ago, a similar incident occurred in the Jiqing service area in Hunan. A truck driver was stopped by repairmen in the service area when he was inspecting his truck. After being told that the driver made the repairs himself, he uttered wild words. On social networks, similar complaints involving car repairs and tow truck conflicts on the highway are not the same. Some service area repair shop staff even use violence or threaten violence against drivers who repair their own cars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the highway, can only repair shops in the service area repair cars? In an interview with the media, the person in charge of the Fengcheng service area said that the practices of the repair shop in the service area are &quot;reasonable and legal and have laws to follow.&quot; The law the person in charge refers to refers to the provisions of the Highway Law, Highway Safety Protection Regulations and other relevant regulations that &quot;prohibit the establishment of stalls within the scope of highways and highway land.&quot; This is obviously a misinterpretation. The so-called &quot;setting up stalls&quot; refers to setting up relatively fixed stalls for a long time and waiting for customers to come to your door. The purpose of prohibiting it is to avoid &quot;damaging, polluting the highway and affecting the smooth flow of the highway.&quot; After receiving the invitation from the customer, he temporarily went on the road to repair the car, precisely to repair the vehicle as soon as possible to avoid parking on the road for a long time and to ensure the smooth flow of the road. Regardless of the definition of &quot;setting up a stall&quot; or the legislative purpose of the regulations, it is completely legal for drivers to repair their cars by themselves or to invite repairmen to temporarily repair their cars on the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the conflict at the Jiqing service area in Hunan mentioned above, the repairmen in the service area claimed that the Provincial Department of Transportation had a document that stipulated that &quot;people below&quot; (referring to repair shops other than the expressway) cannot go to the expressway for repairs. car, but ultimately failed to produce relevant documents. Do the traffic management departments in some places really have such regulations? If such a document does exist, it should be made public and reviewed for legality. If the government department does not have such regulations, is this an internal regulation of the highway management department, or is the service area repair shop lying? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In vehicle maintenance services, drivers and car owners are consumers, and of course they have the right to freely choose repair service providers. Auto repair shops in service areas prevent drivers from repairing their cars by themselves or other repairmen, and force drivers to go to their repair shops to repair their cars. This is a &quot;forced transaction&quot; behavior that is expressly prohibited by the Consumer Rights Protection Act. The Criminal Law also stipulates that using violence or threats to forcefully buy or sell goods, force others to provide services or force others to receive services, if the circumstances are serious, constitutes the crime of forced transaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are obviously illegal behaviors so common? The root of the problem lies in the word &quot;profit&quot;. As the person in charge of the Fengcheng service area said, off-road vehicle maintenance personnel going to the service area to repair cars &quot;harms the interests of the service area repair shops.&quot; The interests of service area repair shops are actually the interests of service area and highway managers. Expressway service areas, as part of expressway service facilities, are constructed and operated by expressway managers. If a repair shop opens in a service area, it must pay space rent to the highway administrator. These rents are generally higher than those for sites outside highways, because this is not only site rent, but also implies a premium for &quot;exclusive operating rights.&quot; Precisely because highway managers also benefit from the &quot;exclusive operating rights&quot; of repair shops, they will naturally try their best to protect the interests of repair shops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;exclusivity&quot; premium is very common in closed establishments. Food prices in airport terminals and highway service areas are generally much more expensive than in urban areas. Even canteens in primary and secondary schools can be auctioned for sky-high prices. This is all due to the monopoly benefits brought by the &quot;exclusive operating rights.&quot; More importantly, these premium benefits are not obtained through market competition, but rely on franchise rights granted by administrative power. For these infrastructure operators with administrative monopolies, the common practice in various countries is to strictly limit their profit margins to maintain a balance between attracting social investment and avoiding huge profits to maintain public welfare. To this end, they must be strictly supervised to prevent them from relying on their monopoly status to harm the public interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, there was an incident in a highway service area in Guangdong where a driver repaired his own car and was threatened by a repair shop employee. Due to public opinion and the intervention of relevant departments, the auto repair shop in the service area was shut down for rectification. The same incident occurred in Fengcheng, Jiangxi this time. The public expects local market supervision and other departments to take timely action to investigate and deal with forced buying and selling, and forced transactions to safeguard the interests of consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[身份证、退伍证、婚姻信息、家庭住址……当一个明星被“开盒”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258670]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 12, Chen Muchi, who plays the role of Prince Yin Jiao in the movie &quot;Fengshen Part 1&quot;, He posted a statement on Weibo, responding that he &quot;did have a marriage.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a4e19d459cf53705edb203836a30d784.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;413&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a4e19d459cf53705edb203836a30d784.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why suddenly Admit that you have been married? It turned out that before Chen Muchi released his statement, a screenshot purporting to be his marriage registration information had been quickly circulated on the Internet. The screenshot contains very detailed information, including not only the registration certificate number, registration institution, registrar’s name and registration date, but also personal information such as the ID number and household registration location of both men and women. Some netizens even circulated an unmosaic version. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the melon-eaters discussed with enthusiasm was nothing more than: getting married and divorced at a young age? There was no response to rumors about a relationship on the Internet before, so why did you come out to respond when it was revealed that you were married? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some netizens pointed out that Chen Muchi had to respond because he was &quot;opened&quot;. Because not only his marriage registration information is spread on the Internet, but also his ID card photo, veteran information and personal contact number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/e216e7cb88a5f40d47751c7ce1ddfeef.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/e216e7cb88a5f40d47751c7ce1ddfeef.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot; Open the box”? &quot;Unboxing&quot; is not essentially different from &quot;human flesh&quot;. It is an act of publicly exposing the privacy of others on the Internet with the purpose of &quot;breaking the other party&#39;s hypocrisy&quot;. It is actually an act of cyber violence that infringes on personal privacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, celebrities, like ordinary people, have the right to marry and love freely, and they can choose to do so publicly or not. Although celebrities, as public figures, will be exposed to the public eye and accept comments from the outside world, can their personal privacy be exposed at will and involuntarily? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem of personal privacy leakage reflected in this incident is more serious than many people imagine. Nowadays, any ordinary person will receive sales calls from different banks, credit, and real estate companies every day, and the leakage of personal contact information has become a common occurrence. For celebrities, their ID numbers are almost an open secret. Taking airport pick-up and drop-off as an example, how do fans learn about a celebrity’s travel itinerary? Most of them have the ID numbers and itinerary information of celebrities, and this information usually comes from illegal &quot;scalpers&quot; selling it for a few yuan to dozens of yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/18a2b1484d42333596d077e3559bf7b8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height= &quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/18a2b1484d42333596d077e3559bf7b8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/208f5fa16d95e7cd3c26e368dbbbbe9a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;505&quot; height=&quot;404&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/208f5fa16d95e7cd3c26e368dbbbbe9a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this information, they can not only grasp the star&#39;s schedule, They can also book air tickets and steal their mileage at will. Artists such as Li Chen, Wu Lei, Jiang Yingrong and others have all experienced situations where their airplane seats were changed and their mileage was stolen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the desire for voyeurism is infinitely magnified, some people will even use public power to satisfy such dark desires. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Chen Muchi&#39;s marriage registration information was exposed, many netizens questioned the source of the screenshots - from which channel did such detailed personal privacy information leak out? Was it the work of staff from the civil affairs system? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, on January 31, 2023, Hu Ge announced that he was getting married and had a daughter. However, because his wife was not a public figure, Hu Ge did not disclose her identity. Someone also exposed Hu Ge&#39;s marriage registration information, allowing netizens to discover that Hu Ge&#39;s wife is a staff member close to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/ae1f0a396113d36fa7ceeb8745b50d52.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;630&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/ae1f0a396113d36fa7ceeb8745b50d52.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254117&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you have a lawyer Popular Science: In real life, no matter lawyers, courts, public security, or procuratorates, they cannot access citizens’ information at will. Citizens’ private information must not be accessed or leaked for non-public needs. Any access will leave traces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/26785e53c02b4b9149ebd6f7b7a5f1bc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;791&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/26785e53c02b4b9149ebd6f7b7a5f1bc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to respond to a Celebrities are &quot;hunting&quot; for privacy, and abusing their power, ignoring the law, and wantonly spreading personal privacy is the most terrifying part of the whole thing. The act of spreading other people&#39;s privacy based on the mentality of taking advantage of others will not only cause secondary harm to the victim, but is actually illegal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 1032, paragraph 1, of the Civil Code stipulates: &quot;Natural persons enjoy the right to privacy. No organization or individual may infringe on the privacy rights of others by means of spying, intrusion, disclosure, disclosure, etc.&quot; The right to privacy protects the privacy of natural persons. It can be seen from the word privacy itself that it has two characteristics: one is &quot;hidden&quot;, that is, it is not a public state. If it has been disclosed by a natural person or legally disclosed, it is not private; the second is &quot;private&quot;, That is, private matters have nothing to do with other people&#39;s rights and interests, public interests, etc. It is from these two aspects that Article 1032, Paragraph 2 of the Civil Code defines privacy as: &quot;A natural person&#39;s private life is peaceful and he does not want others to know about his private space, private activities, and private information.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Article 1033 of the Civil Code stipulates that, unless otherwise provided by law or with the explicit consent of the right holder, no organization or individual may commit the following acts:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;( 1) Intruding on the private life and peace of others through phone calls, text messages, instant messaging tools, emails, leaflets, etc.;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(2) Entering, photographing, and peeping into other people&#39;s homes, hotel rooms, and other private spaces;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;(3) Photographing, peeping, eavesdropping, and disclosing the private activities of others;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(4) Photographing, peeping at the private parts of others’ bodies;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(5) Process other people&#39;s private information;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(6) Infringe on the privacy rights of others in other ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter whether you love or hate a person, you should not use the &quot;open box&quot; method to make other people&#39;s legally protected privacy and personal information public, and you must never do anything illegal. Blind tolerance and helplessness will only encourage the voyeurs&#39; desire for control and arrogance, allowing them to hide in dark corners and continue to do whatever they want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether you are a celebrity or an ordinary person, your right to privacy is protected by law. Legal experts also emphasized that when the legitimate rights and interests enjoyed are illegally infringed, one should immediately call the police and use legal weapons to protect one&#39;s own rights and interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国足协换届选举产生新一届主席、副主席]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258674]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 10:13:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 16, the 12th Member Congress of the Chinese Football Association was held in Beijing to elect new members. A term of executive committee and chairman and vice-chairman. Song Kai was elected as the new Chairman of the Chinese Football Association, and Sun Wen, Yuan Yongqing, Yang Xu, and Xu Jiren were elected as the Vice Chairman of the Chinese Football Association. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“两弹一星”元勋钱学森｜那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258622]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“灵神星”探测器升空：星际采矿还是建立基地？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258664]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;October 13, 2023, 10:19 U.S. Eastern Time (22:19 Beijing time on the same day), carrying NASA The SpaceX &quot;Falcon Heavy&quot; launch vehicle of the &quot;Psyche&quot; probe was successfully launched from the 39A launch pad of the Cape Canaveral Space Launch Base. The probe successfully entered orbit. The two first stages of the launch vehicle All thrusters were recovered and the launch mission was a complete success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the whole mission has just begun. According to NASA: The probe will have to fly 2.2 billion miles (nearly 3.6 billion kilometers) to reach &quot;16 Psyche&quot; in the main asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter in 2029, and orbit the asteroid for 26 months. scientific investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The magnetometer on board the probe will search for evidence of the asteroid&#39;s ancient magnetic field to prove the theory that it is the remnant of a fragmented planet&#39;s core. Gamma-ray and neutron spectrometers will help scientists determine the chemical elements that make up asteroids. A multispectral imager will provide information about its mineral composition and its topography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This exploration mission includes many first-of-its-kind scientific and technological innovations: This is the first time a human spacecraft has used Hall-effect thrusters (electromagnetic propulsion) in deep space beyond the lunar orbit. vehicle), driven almost entirely by solar energy, flew to the junction of the inner solar system and the outer solar system; it was also the first time for humans to explore the first M-type asteroid metallic body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA emphasized: This project is the result of comprehensive cooperation between the American scientific community and industry. The main research team is led by Lindy Elkins-Tanton of Arizona State University, and more than a dozen other universities and research institutions participate. The Jet Propulsion Laboratory and Caltech in Southern California assist NASA with scientific management, systems engineering, integration and testing, and mission operations. Maxar Technologies&#39; team in California is responsible for the solar power system and the &quot;Hall electric pusher&quot;. SpaceX&#39;s Falcon Heavy launch vehicle is responsible for the probe launch mission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to NASA&#39;s scientific expedition mission, this project is of great significance to the future development of mankind. It can be said to be the first step in the exploration journey of &quot;interstellar mining&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;16 Psyche&quot; is located in the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter. It was discovered by the Italian astronomer Gasparis on March 17, 1852. It was named after &quot;Greek mythology&quot; by humans. Named after Psyche, the wife of the soul and Eros, the god of love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The long axis of its ellipsoidal body is 225 kilometers, and it is almost entirely made of metal. Its mass is astonishingly large, about 272 million tons, accounting for about 0.6% of the total mass of celestial bodies in the &quot;asteroid belt&quot;. The metal proportion of this asteroid reaches 82.5%, and its main components are iron, nickel, and precious metals such as gold, platinum, and copper. &quot;Forbes&quot; and others value it at between US$1 billion and US$100 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists are curious: Why is the metal content of this asteroid so high? One theory is that it is the remnant core of an early planet in the early stages of the formation of the solar system. During the growth process of a planet, it was hit by other celestial bodies, and its outer crust and mantle were shattered into countless fragments, leaving only bare metal material. The original planetary core. The reason for this speculation is that the small &quot;Psyche&quot; actually has two large impact craters, and there is no sign of water or hydrated minerals on its surface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, human research on the planet’s core is still extremely limited. We have not even drilled through 1/3 of the thin crust, the outermost layer of the Earth’s structure. Research on the mantle and core can only be done. Make inferences based on seismic waves. If &quot;Spirit Star&quot; is indeed proven to be a rocky planetary core, then this cooled planetary core will allow humans to intuitively understand the structure of the planet&#39;s core and gain a deeper understanding of the planet&#39;s origin, evolution, and development. This will further promote the rapid development of geophysical research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA’s launch of a probe to the “Spirit Star” is undoubtedly paving the way for the commercialization of space resources in the future. This kind of investment in technology and capital is very long-term. Just like Prince Enrique in the early days of the &quot;Great Navigation&quot;, he continued to invest in the ocean for decades, but it took several generations for the Portuguese royal family to get feedback from the ocean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With human aerospace technology, the cost of mining from extraterrestrials and transporting it back to earth will be so high that 1 kilogram of pig iron is more expensive than the same weight of top-quality diamonds. So, why do NASA and Musk conduct such research and exploration? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author believes that their idea is not to smelt iron on the &quot;Ling Shen&quot; and then send it back to the earth, but to &quot;colonize Mars&quot;. &quot;Ling Shen&quot; is extremely far away from the earth, but relatively close to Mars. &quot;Mars colonization&quot; requires a large amount of building materials. If iron, nickel and other metals from &quot;Spirit Star&quot; are used, it will be much cheaper than transporting materials from the earth to Mars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Iron and nickel are the basic materials for making stainless steel. Using solar energy, space metallurgy is directly performed in a vacuum space environment. The production process is completely different from that on the earth, and no carbon-based energy and catalysts are needed. Musk insists on exploring the application of stainless steel in his &quot;Starship&quot; research and development, rather than the carbon fiber aerospace materials used by other countries. This can be explained logically: they have considered the selection of materials for large-scale infrastructure and manufacturing on extraterrestrial planets. question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Musk has also invested in Solar City to develop solar energy. This can be explained by NASA taking great technical risks to use solar-powered &quot;Hall thrusters&quot; in the &quot;Psyche&quot; mission. pass. In the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter, solar radiation is already weak, so why choose a less efficient solar drive? It seems that NASA is exploring technology to improve the efficiency of its use under the conditions of low solar energy in deep space. This is the exploratory spirit of &quot;knowing that there are tigers in the mountains, and prefer to travel to the tiger mountains&quot;, which shows his great determination, firm will and action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was young, I played the video game &quot;StarCraft&quot;, and &quot;interstellar mining&quot; was the first step in building a base. Unexpectedly, before reaching old age, human beings have already begun to try to realize their dreams. It can be said that thousands of sails are racing against each other and hundreds of teams are competing against each other. The vision of humanity becoming a space-faring species is getting closer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 09:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“飞越”按摩店：两位盲人的择业折返跑]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258668]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blind masseur Sun Jingrui is massaging a customer. Photo by Wang Xinyi&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/34b826dd72.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/15/34b826dd72.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254113&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Blind masseur Sun Jingrui is massaging a customer. Photo by Wang Xinyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Wenfeng&#39;s 15-year career as a blind masseur can be divided into two periods: in the first period he struggled with &quot;what can a blind person do&quot;, and in the latter period was he answering &quot;what can I do&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interval was a two-year escape - in 2019, he decided to escape from the blind employment paradigm and worked as a barista and telephone recruiter in Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about the same time, another blind masseur, Sun Jingrui, also chose to run away. After they briefly crossed paths in Guangzhou, the two lifelines bifurcated again, but they ended up reaching the same destination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 31, Ren Wenfeng returned to his hometown of Huanggang, Hubei Province and reopened a massage parlor in the small county town. He and his wife manage the small shop, which is about 40 square meters, and entertain three or four customers every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;34-year-old Sun Jingrui also returned to the massage parlor, but he chose to work in the metropolis Guangzhou. His store is also closer to the consumption perception of modern urbanites: warm yellow lighting, the fragrance of essential oils, supplemented by Mindfulness meditation. When there are not many customers, Jingrui will write plans or go out to connect resources, like an entrepreneur, thinking about how to build more chain stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation, as of 2020, there are 17,300 blind health massage institutions in China. In the common discussion of &quot;What can blind people do without massages?&quot; Ren Wenfeng and Sun Jingrui may have many answers to this question, but one thing is for sure, although returning to a massage parlor may not seem to fit the mainstream narrative, it is Doesn&#39;t mean &quot;failed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Falling into Darkness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ren Wenfeng and Sun Jingrui are both acquired blind people, which means that they need one more layer of psychological construction than congenitally blind people. They want to eliminate all their once-visible selves, as well as their past thoughts, and learn to live in darkness from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was 8 years old, a wooden stick flew in while playing and changed the direction of Ren Wenfeng’s life. The surgery failed to save his vision, and retinal detachment was a gradual farewell, which was more painful than a sudden plunge into darkness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He began to worry about his future life: Will he have to rely on his parents for the rest of his life? How will I support myself in the future? These questions all point to the same thing: What can a blind person do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day during the summer vacation, he listened to a radio program that introduced summer training classes to people. He called and asked: &quot;What can blind people do?&quot; The other party told him that he should contact the local Disabled Persons&#39; Federation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, the process of Sun Jingrui&#39;s blindness is like a person struggling in the water. When he was in junior high school, he was diagnosed with retinal detachment. Because it is discovered late, surgery is difficult to reverse the damage, which is almost equivalent to being declared blind. The doctor suggested that he go to a school for the blind to adapt to his future outcome in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Sun Jingrui decided to race against his eyesight. He wanted to get into a good university before he lost his sight, so that he could &quot;choose a major that is not too hard on the eyes and continue to live a normal life.&quot; Before suffering from eye disease, Sun Jingrui’s dream was to major in mechanical engineering at South China University of Technology. This was a place where he could realize his dream of becoming an engineer. But in his sophomore year of high school, the fog in front of his eyes became thicker and thicker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2006 was the year of Sun Jingrui&#39;s college entrance examination. The girl he had a crush on would call him and ask him &quot;When will he come back to class?&quot; She had sorted out the class content and was waiting for him. Sun Jingrui said vaguely &quot;next month.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui could not wait until the day he returned to the classroom. With the disappearance of the last bit of light, he became completely blind. He no longer dares to go out for fear that others will notice the strangeness of his eyeballs. Occasionally, once he goes out every few months, he will outline the surrounding environment in his mind and turn his head frequently, trying to act like he was before he lost his sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For discerning people, career planning is a process of continuous focus: &quot;study-weigh-choose&quot;, and finally choose the track you are best at. But for blind people, massage parlors are one of the most common secular choices and one of the few stable careers for this special group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Blind massage parlors are like blind paths in the city, existing but not noticeable. They are scattered throughout the city, set up at street intersections, on the first floor of residential buildings, or between barber shops and grocery stores. Most stores are simply furnished, with a few lamps, a few beds, and one or two chairs placed in fixed locations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Wenfeng’s first massage parlor job was in Wuhan, and he was contacted by the Disabled Persons’ Federation in his hometown. The massage shop is located on the second floor of a residential area. Four beds and two sofas are squeezed into the 20-square-meter house. At night, he called his mother and complained: &quot;It&#39;s too shabby. I want to turn around and leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But he persisted in the end: &quot;As long as there is a job that a blind person can do, anything can be done.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, Ren Wenfeng came to Shanghai from Wuhan. When customers at the massage parlor talked about urban life, Ren Wenfeng stood aside with envy. In his world, the busiest moment in Shanghai is the store celebration in June. The heat wave carries the crowds, sending the noise and footsteps into the store. The masseurs are busy amidst the waves of people&#39;s voices and the sounds of watches. . After the store celebration, the crowd dispersed, leaving the masseur in the dark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the time is monotonous: working from 8 a.m. to 11 p.m., food and accommodation are included in the store, and most of the time is spent waiting. Time just slipped between the thick and deformed fingers. In the view of Ren Wenfeng at the time, &quot;This is a job with no future, or even a present.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ren Wenfeng first worked, his slender and soft hands with clear joints were evaluated as &quot;a pair of hands that can be used to play the piano&quot;; now, after more than ten years in the massage industry, Ren Wenfeng&#39;s His fingers became as thick as a rolling pin. &quot;A hand that specializes in massage,&quot; someone praised him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Sun Jingrui has also noticed changes in his body. The muscles on the back of the hand are broad and thick, and the top of the thumb nail is slightly buckled due to years of exertion. The skin connected to the nail has shed its skin and is slightly white. In Guangzhou, he relieves the pressure on the shoulders and necks of many white-collar workers who sit in offices for a long time, but his own cervical vertebrae are tingling due to long-term fixed posture massage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui is unwilling to live in a traditional massage shop. Pictures of the lives of discerning people in the past remind him from time to time. If he cannot return to the world of discerning people, he must at least make achievements in the massage industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sun Jingrui&#39;s thumb tip is peeling. Photo by Wang Xinyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/537b790619 .png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;877&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/537b790619.png&quot; data-key =&quot;254114&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Jingrui’s thumb tip is peeling. Photo by Wang Xinyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Beyond Making a Living&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Internet is one of the common channels for visually impaired people to contact the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2018, Ren Wenfeng learned about the &quot;Coffee in the Palm&quot; project of Hemu Innovation Center, a non-profit organization in Guangzhou, through an online forum. This is an activity to train visually impaired people to learn hand-brewed coffee skills and become baristas. As the road was being built in front of the store and business was not booming, Ren Wenfeng closed the massage parlor operating in Wuhan and went to Guangzhou to study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yingzhang, the head of Hemu Innovation Center, was deeply impressed by him: &quot;I resigned from Wuhan and occasionally do some part-time jobs to supplement my income.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Sun Jingrui also used the Internet to The community gained access to the &quot;Dialogue Academy&quot; project organized by &quot;Dialogue in the Dark&quot;, a Hong Kong social enterprise. He sold the massage parlor he was running and went to Hong Kong alone for training as one of the six members who passed the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike Ren Wenfeng who started his career with massage, Sun Jingrui had the consciousness of entering the &quot;mainstream workplace&quot; when he just lost his eyesight. With good English, he once sought opportunities to work as an interpreter through a hotline program on a radio station. This experience ended in failure, which shattered his illusions about employment for the visually impaired. Returning to the field of massage, he also considered entering a hospital. But &quot;total blindness&quot; once again prevented him from getting a stable and decent job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem goes far beyond that. Finding a position that accepts visually impaired people is the first step. After entering the workplace, the challenge really begins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After becoming blind, more than ten years of experience in massage parlors affected Ren Wenfeng&#39;s character. Sensitivity and low self-esteem were the biggest challenges he faced in the &quot;mainstream workplace&quot;. When he was a barista, some customers would initiate conversations, but he could only respond with silence. In Ren Wenfeng&#39;s narration, his perception of the &quot;mainstream world&quot; is contradictory: like a mirror: on the polished surface facing outward, he wants to be recognized and prove that he &quot;can also accomplish many things&quot;; on the coated surface It is his timidity, he is afraid that others will notice his &quot;difference&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hong Kong, in order to adapt to the teacher&#39;s rhythm and language environment, Sun Jingrui needs to listen to class recordings repeatedly. &quot;Going to bed at two or three in the morning, and getting up again at six or seven in the morning, because class starts at eight.&quot; During the course, he was deeply touched by two parts. The first part is &quot;self-advocacy&quot;, where visually impaired students learn how to seek help in the workplace; the second part is skills training, including holding regular meetings, taking notes, organizing activities, etc. These ordinary people&#39;s daily work content is very new in Sun Jingrui&#39;s eyes. &quot;There is no such thing in a massage parlor.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When visually impaired people choose other jobs, they always subconsciously compare them with the massage industry. They use the massage industry as a frame of reference to view the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the practical part of the course in Hong Kong, Sun Jingrui needed to design workshops and course content alone in a social enterprise. With the help of his instructor, he gradually grew from an initial &quot;facilitator&quot; to an &quot;implementer&quot; of the project. By&quot;. He gradually discovered: &quot;I can actually do a lot of things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from Sun Jingrui&#39;s discovery of &quot;what he can do&quot; in the workplace, Ren Wenfeng&#39;s experience as a barista made him discover &quot;what he cannot or cannot do&quot; What do you like to do?&quot; Looking back now, Ren Wenfeng feels that knowing &quot;what not to do&quot; is the beginning of career planning - in this sense, although he failed to become an excellent barista, this experience is not a failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the limited income of a barista, Ren Wenfeng wanted to do something else. His second job is telephone recruitment: 30 phone calls a day that last for more than 30 seconds, corresponding to a basic salary of more than 1,000 yuan; if the other party is willing to submit a resume and successfully joins the job, he will receive a commission. According to Ren Wenfeng&#39;s rough statistics, the call answering rate is about 50%, which means that at least 60 calls need to be made every day. What is more difficult to control is that most of the answerers will hang up the phone in about 10 seconds. Rejection is normal, and what makes Ren Wenfeng even more unbearable are those unfriendly words. After a few months, Ren Wenfeng&#39;s performance was at the bottom of the group because he was not good at speaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Sun Jingrui also experienced telephone recruitment work. He summarized the job as &quot;repetitive&quot; and &quot;boring&quot;: &quot;I keep saying repetitive words every day, and even get scolded.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Guo Siyuan, a teacher at the School of Humanities and Social Sciences of the Zhongkai College of Agricultural Engineering: &quot;The uneven quality of education for blind people is the pain point that restricts the employment of people with disabilities.&quot; Ren Wenfeng also described the problems encountered in the &quot;mainstream workplace&quot; The embarrassment is attributed to the lack of education. Blind people only need to learn the skills of living. As for spiritual nourishment and interpersonal communication skills such as literature, history and philosophy, it seems not so important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sun Jingrui&#39;s &quot;Healing Time&quot; store uses warm yellow as the main color. Photo by Wang Xinyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/da8b8d691c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/da8b8d691c. png&quot; data-key=&quot;254115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Jingrui&#39;s &quot;Healing Time&quot; store uses warm yellow as the main color. Photo by Wang Xinyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Seeing” myself&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2021, after returning to Huanggang from Guangzhou, Ren Wenfeng started a family. Now the massage parlor he runs is facing the road, with a small yard behind it. Although it cannot be seen, he bought green plants and table lamps and carefully arranged this imaginary space. In his free time, he would make himself a cup of coffee with the sound of wind chimes and sunshine, waiting for customers and learning something new at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I returned to the massage parlor because I didn’t feel safe enough.” Ren Wenfeng said, “Many jobs are not only unstable, but may also have no income at all.” The stable income brought by massage parlors means that he Be able to feel more confident in front of parents, loved ones and neighbors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Take what you have learned back and open a store. This may be Wenfeng&#39;s most practical choice.&quot; Liu Yingzhang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the rush of big cities, small cities are more casual. The guests communicated with Ren Wenfeng about the details of the massage in their hometown dialect. Sometimes Ren Wenfeng would take the initiative to ask the guests &quot;does it hurt?&quot; He was no longer content to be a silent backdrop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui’s store in Guangzhou opened in 2022. The store staff are partners who met during charity activities, and are supported by startup resources from the Hemu Innovation Center. The concept of the store is to use mindfulness to guide customers to observe their bodies, highlighting the masseurs Masseurs gain recognition through their professional skills and techniques, and no longer rely on selling essential oils and other peripheral products to gain value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of colleague Zhang Jinlan, Sun Jingrui&#39;s attempt to break through traditional massage parlors is &quot;very meaningful.&quot; Many customers will give gifts to the visually impaired masseuses in return, and will also hold their hands and show them the gifts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;White-collar workers like to call Jin Rui by his English name Ray, and some customers call him &quot;dolphin&quot;. He said he likes this nickname: when humans are drowning, dolphins will lift humans to the surface of the water.在日常生活中，静睿乐于开导他的视障朋友，把他们从情绪的“海洋”里托举出来。每当张金兰在工作上遇到难点时，孙静睿就会罗列出要点，逐条和她讲道理，“他是一个可以并肩作战的伙伴”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙静睿希望帮助更多的视障人士到外面看看，但单枪匹马的“托举”往往有些无力。他不太好意思直接劝，有时会采取“迂回战术”，比如，故作轻松和朋友说：“明天有一个演讲俱乐部，谁有空一起过去玩一下？”朋友们会觉得很新奇，但是一到真的要上台表演的时候，他们又觉得“太害羞了，不行的”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙静睿也曾面临这样的困境。在刘颖璋看来，孙静睿算是这一群体的“精英”。第一次来到该中心参加活动时，孙静睿戴着墨镜，用一口流利的英语和大家打招呼，这种“大哥”气质当时就给刘颖璋留下了很深的印象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在工作中，孙静睿最初也有“依靠明眼人管理者”的思维惯性。目前，合木创新中心的“手心咖啡”和“愈时间”按摩店项目都由视障人士担任管理者，独立带领视障与非视障的员工，共同参与市场竞争，这和以往由非视障人士领导的模式有本质不同。他们希望这种模式能够打破视障者只能在职场中扮演从属者的偏见，有一天，只需稍加引导，他们能主动探索世界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;孙静睿在网络上广为流传的个人照。网络图片&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/bd761597be.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/bd761597be.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254116&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;孙静睿在网络上广为流传的个人照。网络图片&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在网络上流传较广的一张照片中，孙静睿身着白衬衫、牛仔裤，戴着墨镜，一只手托着下巴，露出标志性露齿笑。但他记忆中自己的形象，却停留在18岁之前，静睿的梦想是未来有一天，他的视力恢复了，能够亲眼看看身边伙伴的模样，也能看看自己穿上职业装是什么样子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（陈鑫、刘颖璋和深度训练营对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我们该以什么姿态面对“牺牲者”丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258658]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/z03yFnCJiTOLmMoGQ3hWWPydrAH9HG48GZcsUjV2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1063&quot; height=&quot;681&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/z03yFnCJiTOLmMoGQ3hWWPydrAH9HG48GZcsUjV2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254109&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;年轻时的何协（左）与朋友。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，我去了内蒙古根河市郊的敖鲁古雅鄂温克自治乡采访，使鹿鄂温克人已经搬迁到那儿整20年了。这场搬迁，对鄂温克人来说，最大的变化就是禁枪。这意味着他们传统游猎生活的终结。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在乡里闲晃，和人谈起枪的事，边上的看客马上给我指路：这得找何老大啊，还有谁能比他更清楚？语气里隐约带有些揶揄的味道——在当时，我并不清楚这里头有什么故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;找到何老大也不难，大多数时候，他都和妻子卓耶在家门口的长凳上安静地坐着。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何老大的本名叫何协，“中国最后一位女酋长”玛力亚索的大儿子，鄂温克人里最后一代猎民。一到他家门前，他就招呼我坐下，还给我开了瓶海拉尔啤酒，这是他的待客之道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来我才知道，枪在去年刚给何协惹来麻烦。2003年前后收枪时，他私藏了把小口径枪，2022年卖给了别人。被人举报后，法院以倒卖枪支罪判刑。何协搞不清判决书是怎么写的，就记得“判二缓三”，退休金也没了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好在，何协也没那么在乎钱，够用就行了嘛。两口子靠卓耶每月四千多的退休金过活，是“月光族”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何协的一位朋友和我讲起不久前发生的事。前段时间，何协向他借了500块，说是要拿去还钱。结果，何协还了一百多块的账，剩下的钱全买了卤牛肉和啤酒。三百多买的肉，两口子没吃几筷子，全拿去喂了乡里的狗。“这不是糟蹋钱吗？”提起这事，这位朋友多少还有些生气。他也拿何协没辙，“这家伙，倒是什么也不操心！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何协的一些举动也的确让人无可奈何。采访期间，我和何协等人一起回了趟搬迁前的老敖乡，当晚在附近民宿住宿。即便民宿大堂醒目地贴着请勿吸烟的告示，何协还是旁若无人地抽起烟来。同行者劝他出去抽，他又犟上了：抽根烟怎么了？现代社会的规矩在他那儿基本是失效的。民宿老板只得再三叮嘱我们，一定要看住何协，房间里可绝对不能抽烟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在敖乡，他成了“没进步”的一类人。内蒙古社科院民族研究所研究员白兰关注鄂温克人已有三十多年，和何协一家成了老友。她和我讲起，2023年7月，她去敖乡参加一场旅游论坛。碰到何协时，他已经喝到差不多了。乡长赶紧让工作人员把他送回了家，“那么多领导来，（担心）何协搁那儿丢人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;离开敖乡前，我打算去和何协告个别。一进门，他正躺在屋里闷着头睡觉呢。卓耶告诉我，何协已经在床上躺了一整天，前两天有客人来，高兴，又喝猛了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到北京后，我读了纪录片导演顾桃写的《敖鲁古雅·敖鲁古雅》，这是他拍摄“鄂温克三部曲”时的日记合集。书里描写的何协同我见到的完全是两副模样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在顾桃的书里，他是山上猎民点神气的“点儿长”。“锯鹿茸时，何协总要对着喷血的茸喝上几口，眼睛眯成缝，卷卷的头发，脸上还溅着血滴，别人看了会吓一跳，他却很享受。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在猎民点，何协的气场能镇住那些偷酒喝的人。“维佳和毛谢（二人都是鄂温克猎民）没有去找鹿，而是搭上顺风车去阿龙山找酒了。中午毛谢和维佳醉醺醺地回来，看到何老大，都悄悄躲回自己家的帐篷睡去了”。“只要何协在点上，玛力亚索就不会担心”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;我忍不住想，要是他们还有枪，还能上山打猎，何协会不会和现在的状态不一样？当然，这只是个无效的假设。只有一两百人的使鹿鄂温克人，融入现代化进程中，是早晚都会发生的事情。而其中总有一两代人，会成为这一进程中的牺牲者。他们上一代，完整地享受了山林中的生活，而下一代，没那么多包袱，又探索出了新的活法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有学者认为，从国家治理的层面上看，这是必须要做出的牺牲。理性的态度是，记住牺牲的那部分人，给予他们及后代一定的补偿，“这才是现实”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;白兰说，她一直在思考，怎么让鄂温克人在发展过程中，有更多自主选择权，让传统得以延续。不过，她到现在，还是没有结论。“作为研究者，有时候我感觉自己是失败的。”听到白兰说出这句话，我心里咯噔一下。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为记者，我能做的，只能是记录下“牺牲者”如今的生活状态，抵抗遗忘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/CoPO3sir3sJ83J1WYSZA9THj2LsdK3ILWHYsS49V.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1073&quot; height=&quot;771&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/CoPO3sir3sJ83J1WYSZA9THj2LsdK3ILWHYsS49V.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254108&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年7月23日傍晚，何协坐在定居点的马路牙子上喝酒。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者韩谦/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[民政部：去年办理结婚登记683.5万对，比上年下降10.6％]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258666]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/07130c1404f69430cfe64d18eafb5200.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;597&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/15/07130c1404f69430cfe64d18eafb5200.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254111&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, the Ministry of Civil Affairs released the 2022 Statistical Bulletin on the Development of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statistical bulletin shows that in 2022, there were a total of 4,310 marriage registration institutions and venues across the country, including 1,103 marriage registration institutions. 6.835 million marriages were registered in accordance with the law throughout the year, a decrease of 10.6% from the previous year. The marriage rate was 4.8‰, down 0.6 percentage points from the previous year. There were 2.879 million divorce procedures handled in accordance with the law, an increase of 1.4% over the previous year, of which 2.100 million divorces were registered by the civil affairs department and 779,000 divorces were adjudicated or mediated by the courts. The divorce rate is 2.0‰. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a638596c90088e4bd210897dc1617082.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a638596c90088e4bd210897dc1617082.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254110&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/f2f977d08aa0a8ce648a89a5e59f8330.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/f2f977d08aa0a8ce648a89a5e59f8330.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254112&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[关于幸福这件事：与“哈佛最受欢迎讲师”沙哈尔谈反脆弱和东方哲学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258577]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/CMxvsLqwcXUy58dsdIxC7UQoClDSXwLnJuFcG6zF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/CMxvsLqwcXUy58dsdIxC7UQoCl DSXwLnJuFcG6zF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253690&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Shen Yu/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2002, Tyler Ben-Shahar, a young, reserved psychology Ph.D., stood in the classroom at Harvard University and gave his first lecture on &quot;Positive Psychology.&quot; At that time, only eight students took his course, and two more dropped out midway. He persisted. In an empty classroom, he discusses with six students once a week the ultimate question of life - how to make himself and others happier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the second academic year, the number of students taking the course increased to 380, and more than 20% of students reported that this course had improved their personal lives; in the second semester of the academic year, 855 Harvard students took the course this course. Within a year, Shahar&#39;s positive psychology course became Harvard&#39;s most popular course, and his other course, &quot;The Psychology of Leadership,&quot; was also one of the school&#39;s most popular courses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This young scholar who just stood on the podium has become one of the most popular mentors in Harvard history. Driven by the spirit of sharing, since 2006, the &quot;Positive Psychology&quot; he teaches (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;is also known as the Happiness Course&lt;/span>; ) was filmed and made into a public course and open to the Internet for free. Its influence quickly overflowed from the Harvard campus and was watched, downloaded, and shared by countless people around the world. Together with Michael Sandel, a Harvard political science professor who teaches a course on justice, Shahar has become a world-renowned scholar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shahar, 53, was born and raised in Israel. His ancestors were Jewish businessmen living in Europe. During the Zionist movement of the last century, they brought their families back to the &quot;Promised Land&quot; given by God. In Shahar’s childhood memories, his grandfather, a businessman, would spend hours every day studying the Hebrew Bible and Talmud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the influence of orthodox Jewish culture, his childhood was also shrouded in the clouds of bloody violence and terrorist incidents in the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. &quot;Every morning when we wake up, we worry about bombs on the bus going to school; when we go to the restaurant to eat, we worry about the restaurant being bombed,&quot; he recalled calmly. His first memory of the war came from the sirens outside his window when he was less than 3 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Childhood memories and the tenacity of his parents and grandparents left an indelible impression on Shahar. After studying in the United States and achieving academic success, he resigned from his position at Harvard and returned to his native Israel to establish the &quot;Happiness Research Institute&quot; to promote positive psychology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While studying at Harvard, he studied Chinese philosophy with the famous Chinese scholar Du Weiming. Confucian humanism and Taoist thought made him feel both familiar and &quot;illuminated&quot; by wisdom. In the process of promoting and developing positive psychology, he also drew theoretical and practical wisdom from traditional Chinese classics such as the Tao Te Ching, the Analects of Confucius, and the Great Learning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the outbreak of the new crown epidemic, Shahar came to China to give lectures on average twice a year. The &quot;Happiness Research Institute&quot; he founded had more than 400 students in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After four years, he visited China again at the end of September 2023. In a Shanghai hotel full of quirky 1990s style elements, we discussed trauma, antifragility, Confucianism and Taoism, and how to overcome PTSD (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Trauma &quot;Post-Stress Disorder&quot;&lt;/span>;) and to discuss topics such as growth, he was interviewed by me, a Chinese journalist who is partially skeptical of &quot;happiness science&quot; and instrumental methodologies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/w7Y894iV4LPPLjmkqLk3Qpe60cvMnPnWW9i6SQ6P.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/w7Y894iV4LPPLjmkqLk3Qpe60cvMnPnWW9i6SQ6P.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253681&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 27, 2020, due to the impact of the new crown epidemic, the training hall was closed. A mother accompanied her child to train in the community&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;No one is an island - how to deal with trauma and helplessness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Compared with four years ago, this time when you meet and communicate with your students, collaborators and academic colleagues, have you noticed the spiritual and psychological outlook of the Chinese people? Are there some changes? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I feel some. However, what I experienced and observed in China is not unique to China. The past three years have been challenging for people and they have become more anxious, sadder and more worried than before. The challenge we face is not just how to overcome anxiety, sadness, or worry, but also how to potentially become stronger after experiencing it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That’s why the science of happiness is so important today, because it provides us with tools, tips and advice to help us potentially become stronger after going through hardships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past four years, have you paid attention to the society from China? Psychological investigation reports, or any exchanges on related issues with Chinese psychology colleagues? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2021, during the epidemic, I had a conversation with Professor Peng Kaiping of Tsinghua University. We found that cultural differences certainly exist, but from a global perspective, people are more similar than different. Chinese, like Americans, Brazilians, Germans, and Australians, all have more differences than in the past. Feelings of security and anxiety. The global pandemic affects people in every corner of the world. So, that&#39;s why psychologists, political leaders need to work together to find solutions to the problem. That’s why I’m so looking forward to speaking with Professor Peng again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What kind of societies did you talk about during the epidemic? Psychological problems? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We talked about a new concept proposed by New York University professor Nassim Nicholas Taleb - &quot;antifragility&quot; , is about how it is possible for us to grow after experiencing hardship, hardship, or trauma. Repair is just returning to the past state. We should also grow from the experience, not PTSD, but PTG (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;post-traumatic growth&quot;&lt;/ span>;). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, most people do not grow after experiencing trauma. They either suffer from PTSD or other forms of psychological problems, such as anxiety, loss of security, sadness, and even depression. . So, the real question is: What can our schools, institutions, and families do to help everyone increase the likelihood of getting PTG, and what can we do to improve antifragile capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A well-known psychologist put forward an insight. He said : In China, social psychology and cultural psychology are and will continue to be the mainstream of psychological research in the future, because the mental state of Chinese people is almost determined by the era in which they live; while in the United States, clinical psychology is Mainstream, because Americans always want to find a doctor to solve his/her individual mental crisis, such as why he/she just feels unhappy. In these two countries with such different mental and personality profiles, what role can &quot;non-mainstream&quot; positive psychology play? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Indeed. I would like to answer this question from a chapter found in the Confucian classic &quot;The Great Learning&quot;. Zengzi, a disciple of Confucius, said in &quot;The Book of Rites and Great Learning&quot;: &quot;In ancient times, those who wanted to establish virtue in the world first governed their country; those who wanted to govern their country, first organized their families; those who wanted to regulate their families, first cultivated their own bodies. ; If you want to cultivate your body, you must first rectify your mind; if you want to rectify your mind, you must first be sincere in your intentions; if you want to be sincere in your intentions, you must first know how to know, and knowing can be achieved by studying things. After studying things, you will know them, and after knowing them, your thoughts will be sincere. If the mind is sincere, then the heart will be upright; if the heart is upright, then the body will be cultivated; if the body is cultivated, the family will be in order; if the family is in order, then the country will be governed; if the country is governed, then the world will be peaceful.&quot; Confucianism believes that if a person wants to promote good morals in the world, he should start with himself, and then Ascend to the task of governing your family, then to govern your country, and then to the world. Do you know Du Weiming? He was my teacher at Harvard, and I studied Confucian humanism from him. He talked about how Confucius started from the large circle of &quot;the world&quot;, to the country, to the family, and then to himself, starting from self-cultivation. To me, Chinese philosophy is very good at integrating individual people with society. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confucius was right. If we want to build a better society, we cannot just focus on social matters, and certainly not just on the clinical (treatment plans). We need to look at it holistically, analyzing, understanding, and acting at all levels, including individuals, families, countries, and the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9PlvUXlLLBpC3SxCC6bBVMWoIhmtHCr06tElGUJ7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9PlvUXlLLBpC3SxCC6bBVMWoIhmtHCr06tElGUJ7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253682&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 12, 2020, Wuhan, the iron gate leading to the main road was still closed. Residents of the old alley spontaneously danced and worked out in front of their homes after dinner&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;Can you tell me specifically how to act? For example, young people in China are now facing employment difficulties. Many people are taking public exams, editing exams, and postgraduate exams, and the competition has become extremely fierce. If you repeatedly fail in employment, public examinations, and postgraduate entrance examinations, it will lead to what is called &quot;learned helplessness&quot; in psychology. How does positive psychology play a role in this kind of representative psychological state of a specific group? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The most obvious way to deal with &quot;learned helplessness&quot; is to continue to act. Because the typical feature of &quot;learned helplessness&quot; is to no longer act, but to just give up and retreat, and trying again becomes a huge challenge. So, even if you fail, still try. If you fail five times, try the sixth time. One of the most important qualities of successful people, such as successful entrepreneurs, is the ability to succeed despite repeated failures. This is for the general case. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More specifically, one of the antidotes to &quot;learned helplessness&quot; is to help others. Let me explain: Over the years, there have been numerous social surveys in the United States focusing on high-risk groups. By &quot;high-risk&quot; we mean residents of poor neighborhoods, where crime rates are often high and children do poorly in school. Researchers first came to these poor areas to provide food, money, etc. to the residents there, and provided them with various funding projects. They found that very few of them had their situation changed. In the end, the researchers found that the most effective way to change their situation was to get them to stand up and help others. When they begin to do this, they can escape &quot;learned helplessness&quot; and become capable of helping others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the words of current Chinese people, this is very positive energy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It does work. Therefore, one of the best ways to make ourselves happier is to think about how we can make others happier instead of always leaving ourselves helpless. As Confucius taught, connect yourself to society and the community. Additionally, it is a way for people to feel better about themselves, which is often what clinical psychology is concerned with. We need to start thinking about the realities that impact society, the realities around us, because helping those around us is actually helping ourselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because no one is an island, we are all part of the whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/P80kOVKz761jkiIMtGUA8hmR7dKfGgakxO3jtsAn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/P80kOVKz761jkiIMtGUA8hmR7dKfGgakxO3jtsAn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253680&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 11, 2022, in Jerusalem, Israel, medical staff performed nucleic acid tests for people&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Spiritual life&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As As a positive psychologist, how did you spend your time during the epidemic, especially the lockdown period? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, I struggle from time to time. Life does get tough. You know I&#39;m eager to come to China, and I&#39;m eager to hug my friends. I probably couldn&#39;t see my parents for over a year. We live in New Jersey in the United States, and my parents are in Israel. They are very old, and we are worried about them getting infected with COVID-19, but we cannot travel. I miss them so much and it&#39;s challenging. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can’t go to a restaurant with my friends to eat either. We had friends visiting our house all the time, the door was always open, and there were a lot of people coming in and out, friends of my wife and I, friends of the kids. Suddenly, the pandemic hit and it was just us and the kids in the house. Of course we have to be grateful for what we have, but it’s always hard not being able to see and be with the people we love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, my main job is to attend classes and give lectures, so I also face challenges on the economic level. So, in a lot of ways, I was struggling with my feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to face these challenges, I returned to the most basic methods of positive psychology: for example, I know that fitness is important for a good life. I used to exercise three times a week, but during the epidemic, I increased it to five times; I used to do mindfulness training every day, and now I add more training, sometimes doing yoga, sometimes Tai Chi, sometimes Qigong, and sometimes meditation; I also try to spend more time with my family as much as possible, and the whole family is together every day Eating dinner, talking, and sometimes crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also continue to work, continue to write, and continue to read. The most important thing is to allow myself to experience all these emotions, not to fight the sadness, not to try to eliminate the anxiety, to accept that they are there, to allow these emotions and feelings to flow through my soul like water, that is the metaphor I use. , don’t try to “block” or block or interrupt them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During the lockdown, you had moments when you lost control of your emotions, such as Kids yelling? After all, being in the same house with three teenage kids all day can be challenging. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is very challenging. I don&#39;t usually yell at kids, but I do get really annoyed by them sometimes. Even now that I can go out freely, I still get annoyed by them sometimes. I think it&#39;s important for parents to love their children but also set boundaries for them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, during the epidemic, when one of my children didn&#39;t do his homework assigned by school, I got very angry and told him that something had to change because the teacher had complained. People think that if you are a professor of happiness, your home must always be filled with a happy and harmonious atmosphere. But that&#39;s not the case. You have to understand this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I would like to ask a very personal topic, do you have any religious beliefs? ? Personally, positive psychology is a social science that emphasizes value neutrality. However, compared with a set of tools and methods, are values, beliefs and even religion more important for a person to maintain a positive and healthy mental state for a long time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am religious. But in my classes, one of the main points I emphasize is that each of us can live a spiritual life, regardless of whether we are converted to a certain religion or not. Because when we find the meaning of what we do, we have a spiritual life. I can be a teacher, I can be an institutional administrator, I find meaning in my work and therefore feel spirituality. I was able to find meaning in raising a family and also had spiritual experiences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, instead of saying that I am a religious person, it is better to say that I am spiritual. I feel meaning and purpose in both my personal and professional life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It seems that we all agree on one thing - in positive psychology Under the iceberg of learning, there must be more basic things, such as values, beliefs, beliefs or religions, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Indeed. These things will give us purpose in life and find purpose in life. Again, we can find it in different areas, some find it in faith, some find it in work, some find it in family, or elsewhere. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, do something that you believe in, is important to you, and is of great significance. That&#39;s the point. If you want to do well and stick with it over the long term, you also need to find where your talents lie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are from Israel and have a Jewish cultural background. Have you ever summarized some experience or wisdom from the life stories of your own family and ethnic group? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many people ask me why you come to China more than other countries and why you have so many Chinese student. I replied that the first time I came to China was about 20 years ago, and it felt like I was back in my hometown. This is real. Because Jewish tradition and Chinese tradition share many similar values, such as the emphasis on family and family, the concept of family is very important in our history. I feel that I have a strong connection with China, including its history and philosophy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for you asking me what I learned from my ancestors and ethnic history? First, we are able to overcome long-standing suffering by connecting to sources of strength, including nature and community. These are two very critical factors. By nature, I mean both the external world and our nature as humans. So, Lao Tzu talks about the importance of learning from nature. Taoists say that &quot;Tao follows nature.&quot; The Tao of earth and the Tao of heaven are &quot;Tao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I want to share with you a passage from the Tao Te Ching: &quot;Man follows the earth, earth follows the sky, heaven follows the Tao, and the Tao follows nature.&quot; When we connect with nature, we can gain strength from it. . This is the first source of power, then the second source. Confucianism talks most about community, and talks a lot about the various rituals when communities come together. In Judaism, we also have many rituals when family members are together. When I visit my friends&#39; homes in China, I often sit with their parents and sometimes grandparents. They usually speak Chinese and I don&#39;t understand what they are saying, but I understand the connection because the same scene can be seen in Israel. That is the source of our strength as Jews—nature, community, and that includes family. Just like Confucianism teaches: from oneself to the family, to the larger group-the country and the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I would like to ask a question with more personal experience. I remember that when I was a child, I could see international news about the Palestinian-Israeli conflict on TV almost every day, including suicide attacks. I thought it was very scary. You spent your childhood and adolescence in Israel. Does this kind of violent information or even experience from the outside world bother you and your friends? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You know I grew up in Israel. Every morning when we wake up, we worry about the bomb on the bus to school; when we go to the restaurant to eat, we worry about the bomb in the restaurant. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My first memory of the war is from when I was less than 3 years old, when sirens rang in the streets and we had to rush to underground shelters to hide for fear of being bombed. Or get blown up. So, you understand what I grew up in and what I went through. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He is less than 3 years old. As a child, how do you face this? The fear of brushing against death every day? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Just like you do with all other traumas, hardships and hardships. You have a community around you that supports you. You talk about it, write about it. In the meantime, keep exercising, find things that are meaningful to you, and find things that you can be grateful for. These strategies are always useful when we face a traumatic experience, whether it’s COVID-19, a job loss, or the loss of a loved one. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These are the tools and techniques taught to us by the science of happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[游客擅自穿越被四姑娘山终身禁入：户外探险应合法合规且风险自担丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258650]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Siguniang Mountain Scenic Area Administration Bureau in Aba Prefecture, Sichuan reported that two tourists violated regulations and conducted private activities in the scenic area. If you cross on foot, you will be banned from entering for life. In recent years, there have been many such privately organized hiking activities, and there have been many dangerous incidents. For these illegal outdoor activities, on the one hand, the penalties must be increased, and on the other hand, the public&#39;s enthusiasm for adventure must be given an outlet. Some crossing routes can be developed to allow explorers to take risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a recent report from the Siguniang Mountain Scenic Area Management Bureau, two tourists, Wang and Cai, purchased tickets to enter the scenic area, and then ignored the signage instructions and staff dissuasion in the scenic area and started hiking through the scenic area. But because it snowed that night, the two called the police for help and were rescued down the mountain. The report stated that the two violated the prohibition regulations of the scenic spot and caused certain harm and adverse effects to the protection and management of the scenic spot. Therefore, it was decided to ban the two from entering the Siguniang Mountain Scenic Spot for sightseeing and other forms of tourism for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many netizens agreed with the decision of the Scenic Area Management Bureau. Mount Siguniang is no ordinary scenic spot. It is a world natural heritage and a national nature reserve. The Scenic Area Management Bureau is a public institution that manages the scenic area under the authorization of the Aba Prefecture Government. Although the two tourists purchased tickets to enter the scenic spot legally, they then hiked through the scenic spot privately, violating the prohibitive regulations of the scenic spot. The administration has the right to ban them from entering the scenic spot again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banning entry has become an option adopted by many scenic spots for serious violations of tourists. Since 2023, many tourists have been banned from the Chengdu Panda Base for one year, five years, and life due to uncivilized behaviors such as spitting water at giant pandas and slapping the glass of giant panda enclosures. In 2021, three tourists carved words on the walls of the Great Wall and were included in the &quot;blacklist&quot; of uncivilized tourism by the Yanqing cultural and tourism department in Beijing. 12 local scenic spots jointly banned entry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, many netizens believe that simply prohibiting entry is not a punishment. Serious violations such as unauthorized crossing should be severely punished and required to bear the cost of rescue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aggravated penalties are also legal. According to the &quot;Nature Reserve Regulations&quot; formulated by the State Council, anyone who enters a nature reserve without approval or fails to obey the management of the management agency within a nature reserve may be fined between 100 yuan and 5,000 yuan depending on the circumstances. In 2019, seven travelers hiked through the Wolong National Nature Reserve in Sichuan without authorization, and one person died. The other six people were fined 5,000 yuan each by the protected area administration and required to bear medical expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Outdoor adventure activities such as cross-country and time-traveling have become more and more popular recently. However, many of these activities involve routes that have been explicitly prohibited by the government, and accidents often occur due to insufficient logistical support and insufficient awareness of risk avoidance. For example, during the May Day holiday in 2021, many &quot;travel friends&quot; lost contact or died while illegally crossing in the Qinling Mountains. The &quot;Ao Tai Line&quot; that travel enthusiasts are keen to cross has long been banned from crossing by the Shaanxi Taibai Mountain National Nature Reserve Administration, the Shaanxi Provincial Forestry Public Security Bureau and other departments. However, these crossing activities are still prohibited frequently, and there are frequent incidents of travelers being in danger, requiring rescue by all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These rescues often require a huge investment of manpower and material resources. For example, in February 2022, a traveler was in danger while trekking through the mountains in the snow in Tibet. More than 100 auxiliary public security police, grassroots cadres, farmers and herdsmen, more than 20 rescue vehicles, and 9 horses were dispatched to search and rescue 20 people in the ice, snow, and violent storms. Many hours. In May 2021, a male traveler in Shanghai lost contact while crossing the Qinling Mountains. After the incident, more than 10 professional rescue teams with more than 200 people carried drones and other equipment into the mountains to carry out blanket search and rescue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cost of such a large-scale search and rescue operation is very high. Who should pay for these rescue costs? As such incidents increase, official rescue agencies are overwhelmed. Many places have begun to implement paid rescue. The Anhui Huangshan Paid Rescue Measures, which came into effect in July 2018, stipulate that tourists who violate the regulations of scenic spots and enter undeveloped or unopened areas without authorization shall be provided with paid rescue. Tourists who violate regulations are required to bear the labor, pre-hospital treatment, and medical expenses incurred during the rescue process. Transportation, accident insurance, logistics support, introduction of third-party rescue forces, etc. In August 2018, the Ganzi Yading Scenic Area in Sichuan also announced that it would implement a paid search and rescue system for tourists who violate regulations. The search and rescue fees start at 15,000 yuan and 20,000 yuan respectively according to different regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, paid search and rescue does not mean giving money first and then saving people. When someone is in danger and asks for help, rescue agencies still have to dispatch rescuers as soon as possible. After all, human life is at stake. However, after the rescue is completed, the rescue expenses should be settled and borne by the rescued person. If payment is refused, enforcement can be enforced through court proceedings and other means. If the rescued person dies, it is paid out of his estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, adventure is also human nature. Adventure activities can inspire people to challenge their limits. True explorers are often admired by the public. Simply banning it will not completely prevent travelers from traveling through time travel. It is better to block than to open up. Consider opening some popular crossing routes appropriately and setting up certain emergency facilities along the way to reduce the difficulty of crossing. At the same time, it should be clear that outdoor adventure is a high-risk activity. Even if you are well prepared, unexpected situations may occur. Well-known diving explorer Han Ting died in an accident while diving in a cave in Jiudun Tianluo, Guangxi. Participants in outdoor activities must fully understand the risks, be prepared for logistical support, and bear possible risks on their own. If you need rescue, you have to pay for it yourself. If you can&#39;t bear these risks, it&#39;s best not to play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[高端家教与留守儿童，时髦机车与过期月饼丨人在职场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258648]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Two years ago, after my Harvard internship psychology mentor passed away, I was a little sad and planned to briefly The perspective shifts from laboratory literature to psychological cases in real life. Coincidentally, a teacher from a &quot;high-end tutoring&quot; institution found me, and I was quite interested in it. Between July 2021 and April 2023, I briefly took a peek into this circle. After May 2023, I came into contact with the circle of local charity cram schools for left-behind children. The two circles have different terms, lifestyles, emotional patterns, and family structures, which are worth pondering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before matching with high-end families, the general process is to prepare a resume in Chinese and English, list your relevant tutoring experience and a one-minute self-introduction video in English. Then, the intermediary agency will conduct a two-way matching. Driver&#39;s license, teacher qualification certificate, and early childhood education certificate can be given extra points. Specialties such as painting, piano, and dancing are also within the requirements of many parents. Generally speaking, parents are quite picky, and as British and American graduates with undergraduate and postgraduate degrees are actively pouring into this industry, it is becoming more difficult to apply for jobs with a target monthly income of 150,000 to 350,000 yuan. It usually takes 8-10 families to interview before we hear back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the nearly 10 families I interviewed, demand is generally concentrated in the five major cities of Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, Shenzhen and Hangzhou, and other scattered families are also scattered around these cities. Most of these families live in villas or large flats with an area of ​​more than 300 square meters, and are equipped with nannies, drivers, and housekeepers. Most of them are interviewed by the mother alone (only one family is attended by the father, who works to make money), and the father is not at home. Most of the needs of mothers require teachers to formulate work schedules and study plans, supervise their implementation, take their children to and from school and complete extracurricular homework. A small number of parents have competition needs. Families who understand psychology and education better will put forward requirements for developing children&#39;s intelligence and seizing the golden period of language development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, take the example of parents in a certain megacity. Both parents have master&#39;s degrees in Hong Kong. They have three children at home and live in a relatively remote villa group. Their grandparents live with them at home, and their mother stays with their children full time. The father travels between two cities every day and has little time to take care of his children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I took over the care of two children, the children were very proficient in English, studied in private schools, and had a wide range of interests. The 4-year-old boy A is the second child in this family. He likes fashionable cars. His mother will buy a whole wall of fashionable cars and related car picture books. When he sees me, he will say: &quot;Hi, teacher, I hope you like This motorcycle!&quot; The 7-year-old girl B is her elder sister. She likes painting and ballet. She has her own dance practice room and art studio in the basement, and has won rankings in large-scale competitions in nearby areas. In addition to attending classes every week, teachers need to accompany them to football classes, swimming classes, ballet classes and math competition classes on weekends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This mother plans to use her child’s Hong Kong ID card in the future to allow her child to enter top universities in the mainland through the joint entrance examination, or to enter a prestigious Hong Kong university through DSE to study as an undergraduate. If I immigrate in the future, I will stay in the United States to study. I can advance or retreat. Therefore, children do not study hard in private schools and always feel that they are different from ordinary children and have a sense of superiority. It is obvious that the three children are emotionally healthy, lively and positive, love to say hello to others, have no stage fright, and are not afraid of difficulties. They live a carefree life every day and grow up healthily and safely in happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, primary school children still need a nanny to help them brush their teeth, wash their faces, and change their shoes every day. Their mothers also expect tutors to personally help their children clean up their house. From a psychological point of view, I think this will hinder the children to some extent. autonomous development. In May, I quit my job as a family escort and took a short break at home. A relative came to me: Are you interested in using your spare time to teach left-behind children? It doesn’t need to be the whole day, just three hours a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;得知孩子们的基本情况后，我欣然应允。我的工资在三五千元不等，可以说是大缩水。对留守儿童这一群体来说，需要很多帮助，并且要从最基础的做起。打个比方，最初我买了一本小升初的数学补习资料给初一女孩C，帮助她过渡衔接初中知识。但是她不会算分数，1/5+1/5，她算下来等于1/10。小测下来，只有20分左右。究其原因，老师说是小学贪玩，缺乏基础。在我看来，很有可能是过去几年都没有开发数学智力，现在13岁才开始正儿八经地学习数学知识，很可能需要手把手的数学启蒙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我跟留守儿童相互陪伴了一段时间。从英语方面来说，由于乡镇小学缺少英语老师，他们没学过英语，高端家庭的小孩A和B完全可以胜任他们的家庭小老师；数学，很差劲；语文，没读过课外书。由于经济水平的限制，也没有用过电脑和产生网瘾。因为父母长期不在家，睡眠不足，饮食不好，常常无精打采，也不知道如何好好地利用补习时间跟老师互动，主动提问和谈论自己的困扰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与女孩C的母亲谈及未来，孩子想转学到她附近的学校，可是那所学校很差劲，附近也没有补习班。 “老师，你看我的孩子是读书这块料吗？”妈妈表示感激我送《你当像鸟飞往你的山》这样的励志书籍给孩子，鼓励她多自学。女孩的父母均高中毕业，很好说话，对女儿的情况很关心，每天都会微信发消息给我聊几句，态度很好。而女孩自己，没有兴趣爱好，不爱说话，有一只跟母亲打电话用的智能小手表，用着破旧的书包。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中秋刚过，本地机构的老师送来一盒月饼，仔细一看，第二天过期。本来想分享几个给小朋友，但是算了。无论是时髦的机车，还是快过期的月饼，每一种生活，都有它本身的滋味。而在这两种互不交叉的社会阶层背后，是值得我在未来科研生活和应用实践中重新锚定的新方向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中家庭隐私信息已模糊处理，如有雷同，纯属巧合。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者系香港城市大学本科毕业生）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目之“人在职场”，欢迎来信分享职场心声、吐槽职场经历、打破刻板印象、揭秘行业规则。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>