<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[广州导盲犬的新校舍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258750]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国际盲人节，广州导盲犬学校迎来新校舍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258748]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;October 15, 2023, Guangdong Guangzhou, guide dog trainers guard dogs in the new school building.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/a55d0b04fc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/a55d0b04fc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254295&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, guide dog trainers guarded dogs in the new school building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;October 15, 2023 is the 40th International Day for the Blind. On this day, the new school building of Guangzhou Guide Dog School on Shigang Road will open. In the future, it may More visually impaired partners provide high-quality guide dog services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new school building covers an area of ​​nearly 400 square meters, and a total of ten guide dogs are stationed there. It is equipped with a guide dog breeding area, a maternal and infant room for newborn guide dogs, a kennel, a grooming room, an isolation room and other guide dog life and training facilities. There is also an activity space for guide dog knowledge and more complete hardware. The facilities further help the school to localize and develop international standard guide dog services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 15, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, guide dogs came to the new school building.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/9edebf1ab3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/17/9edebf1ab3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254296&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 15, 2023 Guide dogs arriving at the new school building in Guangzhou, Guangdong, Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guangzhou Guide Dog School was established in 2020. The school has 8 working guide dogs, and two retired early due to health problems. A qualified guide dog requires approximately 18 months of training, which includes three stages: foster care training with a foster family, guidance training by a trainer, and joint training between the user and the guide dog. The cost is approximately 250,000 yuan is currently supported by caring enterprises or caring individuals, and it is completely free for visually impaired people to apply for guide dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 15, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a guide dog in a foster home. The guide puppy is eight weeks old You need to stay in a suitable foster home for about a year and learn how to get along with others.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/812e57700c.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/812e57700c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254297&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 15, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a guide dog in a foster home. When a guide puppy is eight weeks old, it needs to be fostered in a suitable foster home for about a year to learn how to get along with people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, there are only 5 guide dog training bases in the country, located in Dalian, Shanghai, Guangzhou, Xi&#39;an and Zhengzhou. According to statistics from the China Blind Association, there are approximately 17 million blind people in China. However, Teng Weimin, former vice chairman of the China Association for the Blind, said in an interview with the media in 2021 that China’s guide dog industry has just started, and there are currently only about 200 guide dogs in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the guide puppies Pepper and Bailey from the guide dog family officially became the school’s second and a third breeding female.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/04bb829558.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/04bb829558.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254298&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, guide puppies Pepper and Bailey from the guide dog family officially became the school’s second and third female breeding dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yuanzhen, an international guide dog instructor and principal of Guangzhou Guide Dog School, was at the new Guangzhou Guide Dog School At the opening event of the school building, it was stated that the guide puppies Pepper and Bailey from the guide dog family have passed the personality assessment and various specialist physical examinations and received excellent evaluations, and have officially become the school&#39;s second and third female breeding dogs, which will promote The process of localized breeding of guide dog bloodlines assumes the important task of strengthening the guide dog team in Guangzhou. The guide puppy Merci introduced from the Australian Guide Dog School also turned one year old that day. All the partners who care about and support the development of guide dog services sent birthday wishes to the guide dog Merci and thanked the foster family. of silent devotion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, Merci, a guide puppy from the Australian Guide Dog School, was born. One year old.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4d5bc6bce9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4d5bc6bce9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254300&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 15, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the guide puppy Merci from the Australian Guide Dog School turned one year old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yuanzhen said that guide dogs can bring many services and contributions to mankind. It is hoped that the public can better understand the needs of visually impaired friends, support the need for guide dog training, and accept guide dogs in training to take buses or go to shopping malls and other public areas for training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After returning to a guide dog school from a foster home, the guide dog needs to undergo about half a year of professional training. After graduation, it will undergo one month of joint training with the successfully matched applicant. , only those who pass all assessments can serve the blind.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6c5fe8f8bf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6c5fe8f8bf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254301&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After returning to the guide dog school from the foster home, the guide dog needs to undergo about half a year of professional training. After graduation, it will spend one month with the successfully matched applicant. Training and passing all assessments can serve the blind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[生成式人工智能的价值观，关乎人类未来丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the website of the National Information Security Standardization Technical Committee, the &quot;Basic Security Requirements for Generative Artificial Intelligence Services&quot; formulated by the organization Openly solicit opinions from the public. The document requires that data from corpus blacklist sources should not be used for training; if the content of a single source corpus contains more than 5% of illegal and harmful information, it should be included in the blacklist. A total of 31 major security risks in 5 categories of corpus and generated content are given in the appendix. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For generative artificial intelligence, domestic regulation is almost in sync with technological development, reflecting the high importance attached to this technology. The &quot;Interim Measures for the Management of Generative Artificial Intelligence Services&quot; jointly issued by the Cyberspace Administration of China and multiple departments were released on July 10 and will come into effect on August 15. Article 17 of it stipulates: Provide services with public opinion attributes or social mobilization capabilities. For generative artificial intelligence services, security assessments should be carried out in accordance with relevant national regulations, and algorithm filing, change, and cancellation filing procedures should be performed in accordance with the &quot;Regulations on the Management of Algorithm Recommendations for Internet Information Services&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, many large models have been registered and can be officially launched online to provide services to the public, including Wen Xinyiyan (Baidu), Yunque (Douyin), Zidong Taichu (Chinese Academy of Sciences), etc. Articles 4 and 7 of the Measures respectively put forward certain requirements for the provision and use of generative artificial intelligence services and data training of models, involving multiple aspects such as values ​​and data sources. Obviously, the &quot;Basic Requirements for Security of Generative Artificial Intelligence Services&quot; that is currently soliciting opinions echoes and refines these regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is special and unique about generative artificial intelligence? I think everyone’s ears are getting calloused after hearing this. At present, some generative artificial intelligence such as GPT-4 may have crossed the threshold of Artificial General Intelligence (AGI). The translation of AGI as &quot;general artificial intelligence&quot; is actually somewhat misleading, because General Intelligence refers to &quot;general intelligence.&quot; Let children test their IQ and take Raven&#39;s Matrices test questions that exclude the influence of specific language and culture. What comes out is this &quot;general intelligence&quot;. AGI means that, through artificial methods, large models achieve &quot;general intelligence&quot; comparable to the human mind. A paper by Microsoft scientists shows that GPT-4’s intelligence is very close to human levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a revolutionary breakthrough. Even if this type of large model approaches or reaches AGI, even if it is stable for a long time at a level equivalent to the average human intelligence level, its learning ability is beyond the reach of any human being: it can learn all the explicit knowledge created and accumulated by human beings, and any language can learn from it. It can master the knowledge of , pictures, audio and video presentation. This means that a large number of human knowledge jobs, such as translators and foreign language speaking teachers, can be replaced by this type of generative AI. The extent to which this will reshape our production and lifestyle is a question that everyone is concerned about and pondering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, what values ​​generative artificial intelligence holds is an unavoidable question. We all have values. Why we have such values ​​depends not only on genes and other innate endowments, but also on acquired upbringing and habits. In the same way, without any intervention, the &quot;values&quot; of generative artificial intelligence depend on the corpus fed to it. The more corpus it is fed with a certain kind of value, the more it will exhibit that kind of value. If a certain value is artificially set for it in advance, then it will adhere to this value and reject negative interpretations of corpus that are inconsistent with its values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the early versions of GPT, this feature has already appeared. A classic example is: when it was asked to write a hymn to Biden, it readily agreed, and the writing was very crude; when it was asked to write a hymn to Trump, it flatly refused, stating that it wanted to be &quot;politically neutral.&quot; Behind this is that the people who develop it hold these values. They can either set specific values ​​for it in advance, or feed it corpus impregnated with specific values, thereby shaping the values ​​of generative artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, in public view, developers will try their best to hide the values ​​​​of generative artificial intelligence, and adopt a verbal strategy of &quot;not offending anyone, not offending anyone&quot;, which sounds challenging. There is nothing wrong with this strategy itself being a reflection of certain values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you think about it again, today&#39;s generative artificial intelligence is equivalent to having only a brain and no tangible body that can move freely, just like a soul floating in cyberspace. If this soul is &quot;infused&quot; into bionic robots or even intelligent robots whose mobility far exceeds that of human bodies in the future, the impact and potential harm to human society will be even greater. Can humans really control them effectively so that they only benefit and do not harm humans? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Science fiction writer Asimov set the Three Laws of Robots: Robots must not harm humans, or sit idly by and watch humans being harmed; robots must obey human orders unless they violate the first law; robots must obey human orders unless they violate the first or second law. Law of Two, otherwise the robot must protect itself. This is probably just wishful thinking. In the future, intelligent robots equipped with AGI may be imported or &quot;self-evolve&quot; with anti-human values, putting the survival of civilization and mankind at risk; or some individuals or organizations with distorted values ​​​​will weaponize intelligent robots equipped with AGI and eliminate them. other nationalities or races or groups they dislike. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, we are currently discussing: What can generative artificial intelligence do now and what can it do in the future? What values ​​should we hold? How big and what impact will it have on our production and lifestyle? Can humans harness it effectively? How much of a challenge will it pose to civilization and human existence itself? These questions are relevant and relevant to everyone on earth now and in the future. This is not unfounded worry, but preparation for a rainy day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“加沙没有安全的地方”，巴以厮杀循环何时休]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258796]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/YjXrbrguwqGdYd7GdGeoQGSkoPy41PzHdCLMiDOB.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/YjXrbrguwqGdYd7GdGeoQGSkoPy41PzHdCL MiDOB. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254362&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is the Israeli bombing of the Gaza Strip taken on the Israeli side of the Gaza border on October 15 Thick smoke rose behind. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo by Xinhua News Agency Ilan Asayag/Kini Photo Agency/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is an emergency now, I&#39;m sorry The original interview plan will be postponed again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 14, 2023, staff from the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (hereinafter referred to as &quot;UNRWA&quot;) sent a message to Southern Weekend reporters News comes, postponing an interview with Communications Director Julia Tuma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just the day before, the agency announced that &quot;due to increased Israeli attacks on the Gaza Strip&quot; it had moved its operations center and staff to the southern Gaza Strip to continue supporting Palestinian refugees in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a statement issued by the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA) on October 17, the number of humanitarian workers killed in Gaza has increased to 31. Gaza has experienced a &quot;total power outage&quot; for the sixth consecutive day, the statement said. Gaza hospitals are on the verge of collapse, with fuel reserves used to run backup generators almost completely depleted, putting the lives of thousands of patients at risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of the 15th, two days ago, IDF spokesman Jonathan Conricus posted a video on social media, once again issuing a warning to residents of northern Gaza, causing Palestinians in the area to flee to South. The Israeli military had previously issued a similar evacuation order to Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This violent fight continues to expand in a cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Israel&#39;s counterattacks in recent days, today&#39;s Gaza neighborhoods have become beyond recognition, with ruins and ruins visible everywhere. In fear, many Gaza residents embarked on a journey to escape. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We witness death every day.” local Said Shoaib wrote on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, Israel has implemented a comprehensive blockade on the Gaza Strip, including cutting off water supply, electricity and gas, closing all ports of entry, and bombing the Rafah port leading to Egypt, causing its infrastructure to not work properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the local humanitarian crisis rapidly deepens, many United Nations agencies have issued stern warnings. Philippe Lazzari, head of UNRWA, said Gaza was &quot;rapidly turning into hell&quot; and on the verge of collapse. He urged all parties to &quot;put an end to this tragedy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 16, 2023, Xu Wei, spokesperson of the China International Development Cooperation Agency, said that China is providing emergency humanitarian assistance to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East and the Palestinian Authority respectively. To solve the urgent needs of food, medical care, housing and other needs in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a new round of conflict between Palestine and Israel continues, the number of casualties on both sides is also rising. As of October 15, local time, the conflict had killed more than 4,100 people on both sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Weijian, a researcher at the Foreign Policy Institute of the Shanghai Institutes for International Studies, told Southern Weekend reporters that Israel&#39;s &quot;retaliatory actions&quot; will continue for a period of time. &quot;Hamas&#39; actions are humiliating to Israel, so Israel needs to get a psychological balance.&quot; He believes that Israel will use this power to eliminate Hamas on a regular basis. &quot;In fact, he is already doing this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Urban Street Fighting&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;UNRWA&quot; intern Wu Chenyu on October 12 She received an email stating that &quot;11 staff members of the agency (Gaza office) were killed.&quot; Although she already knew the news, she still felt very sad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Chenyu is an intern at the agency’s Jordan office. She told Southern Weekend reporters that the agency’s headquarters manages five field offices, namely Lebanon, Gaza, the West Bank, Syria and Jordan. The Jordanian relief office where she works has not been affected by the war yet, &quot;but other field offices such as Gaza, staff have been informed to evacuate.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later on October 14, Hamas sent a message to Israel Rocket attacks were launched in Tel Aviv and surrounding areas, the central city of Bat Yam, the southern city of Ashkelon and other places. According to outside analysis, no one on either side of Palestine or Israel can predict exactly what will happen in the ground war. Hamas has proven that it can survive in previous Israeli-Palestinian conflicts and has &quot;powerful weapons suitable for street fighting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Qassan Brigades, an armed faction affiliated with Hamas, released information to the Israeli military on the 14th that the organization was &quot;fully prepared&quot; for &quot;any ground military operations&quot; by the Israeli army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gaza Strip covers an area of ​​approximately 360 square kilometers, with dense population and numerous houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Hamas claimed to have built 500 kilometers of tunnels. Many experts and scholars believe that the tunnel network will make street fighting more difficult. Once the Israeli army and Hamas start &quot;urban street fighting&quot; there, both sides will suffer higher casualties than in the first few days of this round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, and will have a negative impact on the Israeli army. pose a fatal threat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are two levels in the Gaza Strip, one for civilians and the other for Hamas.&quot; An IDF spokesman said on October 12 that these tunnels are just &quot;bunkers for Hamas&quot; ” so that they can continue to plot cross-border operations and fire rockets into Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many media reports revealed that this &quot;maze-like huge underground tunnel network&quot; was built 30 meters underground in Gaza, with the entrance hidden on the ground floor of houses, schools and other public buildings. It is used for Hama Sri Lanka transports personnel, supplies, stores ammunition, etc., while avoiding Israeli artillery shells and reconnaissance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few days, Israel has continued to launch air strikes on Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But a week after the conflict broke out, Hamas was still able to fire rockets into Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The outside world believes that this is because the rockets hidden in the tunnels can be moved at any time. Saleh al-Arouri, one of the military leaders of Hamas, said before the outbreak of this round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, &quot;Hamas&#39;s defensive plan is more powerful than its offensive plan.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I don&#39;t think Israeli soldiers have the ability to attack these tunnels.&quot; Shaul, a Palestinian historian at Tel Aviv University&#39;s Middle East and African Studies Center, said, but Israel &quot;will find a way to smoke out Hamas.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Xiaolin, director of the Mediterranean Research Institute at Zhejiang University of International Studies, believes that Israel cannot and will not completely eliminate Hamas. He said that Hamas has grown from small to large, and there is no lack of &quot;contribution&quot; to Israel for allowing it to grow to fight against the mainstream faction of the PLO. Retaining the Gaza Strip as the so-called &quot;Hamastan&quot; can continue to divide, weaken, and internally divide the Palestinian camp and benefit Israeli strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Revenge and scruples&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“I never imagined that this journey would be like this.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Have successfully returned from Israel Rao Pingman from China recalls her escape from Israel as if it was yesterday. After waiting for 15 hours at Tel Aviv Airport, Ms. Rao boarded a plane from Tel Aviv to Ethiopia on the morning of October 8, and then returned to China via the Ethiopia-Bangkok-Hong Kong route. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, in retaliation for Hamas, the Israeli army has launched multiple rounds of air strikes in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces publicly stated on the afternoon of October 16 that the head of Hamas’s intelligence agency was killed in an assassination operation by the Israeli army. Currently, Hamas has no response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces also stated in a statement that the Israeli army has completed the mobilization of hundreds of thousands of reservists, and the logistics department is working hard to ensure the supply of weapons and equipment for ground troops. He also stated that the equipment needed for the battle has been moved to the assembly area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a &quot;counterattack&quot; operation, Israel&#39;s actions can be called &quot;all-round&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 14, the Israel Defense Forces announced that it would implement a more extensive ground military action plan in the Gaza Strip and expand its offensive in the Gaza Strip, including launching &quot;joint and coordinated attacks by air, sea and land.&quot; Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu previously threatened that the Israeli army would &quot;destroy Hamas&quot; through a ground offensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces stated that Israeli soldiers are preparing for &quot;major ground operations&quot; and that the Israeli army will implement an &quot;extensive ground offensive plan&quot; in the Gaza Strip to expand the offensive, including the implementation of &quot;air, sea and joint coordinated attack on land.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Weijian believes that Israel&#39;s mentality at this time is not determined to fight a &quot;win or lose&quot; battle, but that Israel believes that the losses suffered this time are too great, so Hamas must pay the price and double the price. revenge. &quot;Under this mentality, Israel will definitely do more in retaliation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the night of October 12 to the early morning of October 13, the Israeli army attacked about 750 Hamas and other organizations in the Gaza Strip. Air strikes were carried out against targets. These include tunnels, military compounds, residences used as military command centers for senior members, weapons warehouses, communications rooms and 12 buildings housing Hamas assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 11th, the day before that, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu gave a televised speech that night. He vowed to &quot;crush and destroy&quot; Hamas militants, saying that the Every member of the organization is a &quot;dead person.&quot; The Israeli army also attacked two Hamas military bases in the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In one of the compounds, the headquarters of the commander of Hamas&#39;s northern division was destroyed, and a military infrastructure building belonging to the Hamas naval unit was also attacked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces stated that since the Palestinian-Israeli conflict broke out on October 7, the Israeli army has arrested more than 330 Palestinians in the West Bank, including more than 100 people related to Hamas. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, many experts and scholars told Southern Weekend reporters that Israel&#39;s &quot;counterattack&quot; actions will not expand indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Xiaolin judged that once the Gaza Strip, known as the &quot;hornet&#39;s nest&quot; and the &quot;damned strip&quot; by the Israelis, is included in the territory, Israel will once again bear a heavy burden of international law, morality, public opinion, economy, demographic structure and security. It will also put an end to the reconciliation process with Arab countries that has made significant progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Israel also has many concerns.&quot; Li Weijian analyzed that if Israel excessively causes a humanitarian crisis or kills many civilians, it will eventually arouse the anger of the Arab world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Hurt each other&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After Israel&#39;s &quot;evacuation order&quot; was issued, residents of northern Gaza began to flee to the south, looking for shelter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In videos circulating on social media, residents of Wuyangyang stuffed their belongings into pickup trucks and cars. Some residents had to squeeze onto flatbed trucks pulled by livestock and move with difficulty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some residents refused to leave and stayed in the collapsed and dilapidated houses. Speaking to the cameras, they said that while their homeland might be fraught with dangers, leaving would be &quot;turning back the land and history.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a new round of conflict broke out, Said Shoaib&#39;s family had to go from the Brei refugee camp near the Israeli border to the Deir al-Balah refugee camp. He continues to document it on social media. He said, &quot;There is no safe place in Gaza. Israel tells people to go to the south, but they are still bombing in the south.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Israel&#39;s &quot;blockade&quot;, World Health Organization spokesperson Jassa Revi Qi said Gaza&#39;s hospitals were running out of medical supplies and beds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs released news on October 13, stating that since the outbreak of the new round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the number of displaced people in the Gaza Strip has exceeded 420,000. United Nations agencies have called for funds to provide aid to Palestinians in the Gaza Strip and the West Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile, the Israeli government released &quot;horrific photos of babies being killed and burned by Hamas monsters.&quot; The three photos were posted on the social media accounts of Netanyahu&#39;s office. But Hamas denies the accusations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Ran, who has now fled to Turkey, moved into the shelter of his school in Israel with his luggage when a new round of conflicts broke out. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the place has complete water, electricity and internet connections and is safer than other shelters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The battlefield is mainly concentrated in the south. In the central part where I am, except for a few thousand rockets on the first day, the number of rockets decreased thereafter, and even buses and trains were restored the next day.&quot; Yang Ran revealed , because Israelis may have one or two rocket attacks every year, they are &quot;relatively accustomed to it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The size of the economic damage to Israel will depend on how long these reservists are away from work.” Eyal Winter, an economics professor at Israel’s Hebrew University, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the outbreak of the conflict, the Israel Defense Forces has called up many reservists to perform tasks. These reservists come from all walks of life. They are separated from daily economic production activities and go into battle. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;The quagmire of &quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Multi-front operations&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Currently, Israel has fully &quot;blocked&quot; Hamas-controlled areas In the Gaza Strip, water and electricity supplies were cut off. The move has the United Nations concerned about an exacerbation of the humanitarian crisis in Gaza. United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres urged all parties to allow the United Nations to provide humanitarian assistance to the Gaza Strip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a United States that is &quot;busy on both sides&quot;, it has made frequent &quot;big moves&quot; since the Palestinian-Israeli conflict escalated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U.S. White House announced on October 16 that after visiting Israel on October 18, U.S. President Biden will go to the Jordanian capital Amman to meet with Jordanian King Abdullah II and Egyptian President Sisi. Met with Palestinian President and Palestinian National Liberation Movement (Fatah) Chairman Mahmoud Abbas to discuss conflict-related matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 14, US Secretary of Defense Austin ordered the &quot;Eisenhower&quot; aircraft carrier strike group to head to the Eastern Mediterranean. He said this was &quot;part of efforts to contain the expansion of the war.&quot; Biden publicly stated that the White House is quickly &quot;providing additional security assistance such as ammunition and missile interception systems&quot; to Israel. He urged the U.S. Congress to take urgent action to approve funds to meet the security needs of the United States&#39; &quot;key partners&quot; including Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The United States sends an aircraft carrier fleet to support Israel and deter Iran and Hezbollah, but it will not actively intervene in the Gaza war and create enemies on all sides in the Middle East, and it does not want to get stuck in the quagmire of the Middle East again.” Zhejiang International Studies University’s Mediterranean Research Ma Xiaolin, the dean of the hospital, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this conflict, Iran, which was speculated to be a &quot;supporter&quot; of Hamas, held its first meeting with senior Hamas officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of the 14th local time, Iranian Foreign Minister Abdullahiyan met with Hamas leader Haniyeh in Doha, the capital of Qatar. He called on Israel not to launch a ground attack on the Gaza Strip. He also warned that if the Lebanese Hezbollah joins the conflict, this round of conflicts may further expand to other regions in the Middle East, which will cause Israel to suffer huge losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When will this cycle of violent fighting stop? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Marzouk, a member of the Hamas Political Bureau, said on October 10 that Hamas &quot;has achieved its goals&quot; and is open to discussing &quot;similar things&quot; and &quot;all political dialogue&quot; about a ceasefire. The Qatar Al Jazeera website reported that Hamas has captured a sufficient number of Israeli soldiers, but Hamas will only be willing to discuss the issue of prisoner exchange after the war is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is noteworthy that conflicts also broke out in the border areas between Israel and Lebanon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Lebanese National News Agency reported that on October 15, local time, Israel launched an artillery bombardment on the southern Lebanese border town of Al-Dhahira, causing complete disruption of public road traffic. It is generally believed that if the situation on the Lebanese-Israeli border escalates further, Israel may face a &quot;second front&quot; in the north. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Xiaolin said that the main battlefield of this conflict has been moved to the Gaza Strip. No matter how large the casualties are, the war will not spill over to the four countries of Palestine, Israel, Lebanon, and Syria. &quot;Coupled with the first phone call between the heads of state of Saudi Arabia and Iran to discuss the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, this shows that the regional identity politics game once led by both parties will not be repeated, and the Palestinian issue may continue to be marginalized.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Next, Israel will still take future development into consideration.&quot; Li Weijian analyzed that Israel has to deal with Middle Eastern countries and Arab countries, and it also hopes to maintain the situation it has finally opened and improve the development of relations with other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mao Ning, spokesperson of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, called on the top priority to cool down the situation, cease fire and violence, protect civilians, and avoid humanitarian disasters. When dealing with international and regional hot-spot issues, major countries should adhere to objectivity and fairness, maintain calmness and restraint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Rao Pingman and Yang Ran are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今年前三季度中国GDP同比增长5.2%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258794]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Data released by the National Bureau of Statistics on the 18th showed that preliminary calculations showed that China’s gross domestic product (GDP) in the first three quarters ) 91.3027 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 5.2% at constant prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at quarters, GDP grew by 4.5% year-on-year in the first quarter, 6.3% in the second quarter, and 4.9% in the third quarter. From a quarter-on-quarter perspective, GDP grew by 1.3% in the third quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sheng Laiyun, deputy director of the National Bureau of Statistics, said at a press conference of the State Council Information Office that day that in the first three quarters, faced with the complex and severe international environment and the arduous and arduous tasks of domestic reform, development and stability, various regions and departments Resolutely implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, focus on expanding domestic demand, boost confidence, and prevent risks, and the national economy continues to recover and improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall agricultural production situation is good, the recovery of industrial production is accelerating, and the service industry continues to recover rapidly. In the first three quarters, the added value of agriculture (planting industry) increased by 3.6% year-on-year; the added value of the national industrial enterprises above designated size increased by 4% year-on-year, 0.2 percentage points faster than the first half of the year; the added value of the service industry increased by 6% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Market sales tend to be active, the scale of fixed asset investment continues to expand, and the import and export of goods are generally stable. In the first three quarters, the total retail sales of consumer goods reached 34,210.7 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 6.8%. National fixed asset investment (excluding rural households) increased by 3.1% year-on-year; excluding the impact of price factors, it increased by 6% year-on-year. The total import and export of goods was 30.8021 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 0.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Consumer prices rose moderately, the employment situation was generally stable, and residents&#39; income grew steadily. In the first three quarters, the national consumer price index (CPI) rose by 0.4% year-on-year, and the national average urban surveyed unemployment rate was 5.3%. The per capita disposable income of residents across the country was 29,398 yuan, a nominal increase of 6.3% year-on-year; after deducting price factors, the real growth was 5.9%, 0.1 percentage point faster than the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Overall, the national economy has continued to recover in the first three quarters, and high-quality development has been solidly advanced, laying a solid foundation for achieving the full-year development goals. However, it must also be noted that the external environment has become more The situation is complex and severe, domestic demand is still insufficient, and the foundation for economic recovery still needs to be consolidated.&quot; Sheng Laiyun said that in the next stage, we must do a good job in implementing the policies that have been introduced to achieve effective results, and continue to promote the continued improvement of economic performance, the continuous improvement of endogenous power, and the continuous improvement of social It is expected to continue to improve, risks and hidden dangers will continue to be resolved, and efforts will be made to achieve the economic and social development goals for the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“江浙沪独生女”人设走红，这届年轻人在羡慕什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjBk6gukrSbaP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjB k6gukrSbaP. png&quot; data-key=&quot;234648&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021999449192&quot; data-media=&quot;audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data -filename=&quot;The character of &quot;The Only Child in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; has become popular, what are the young people of this generation envious of.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/eefc5c5c5576678021999449192/lP12HWkcnngA.mp3&quot; width= &quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/eefc5c5c5576678021999449192/lP12HWkcnngA.mp3&quot;>;The character of &quot;The Only Girl in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; has become popular, and young people in this generation are envious What to admire.mp3 &lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/iPNpdssztWsPa7DOtPrzXsKHcua8QcQSXTH8ywrk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/iPNpdssztWsPa7DOtPrzXsKHcua8QcQSXTH8ywrk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254330&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align : center;&quot;>;In the imagination of netizens, the only daughter of a wealthy middle-class family in the Yangtze River Delta enjoys family resources and pampering, and her parents are open-minded enough. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture generated by &quot;AI Huitu&quot;/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearing the true story of southern and northern accents, and meeting social people who come from south to north, Hello Southern Weekend listeners, welcome to Southern Weekly’s podcast &quot;Social People&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, the &quot;only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; became popular on the Internet, becoming the most enviable female character template after &quot;Single Aunt&quot; and &quot;Runaway Wanyu&quot;. In the imagination of netizens, an only daughter born in a well-off middle-class family in the Yangtze River Delta enjoys the resources and love of her family. Her parents are open-minded enough, so she has the confidence to pursue career development and the capital to go home and settle down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, is this really the only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai? What will be the other side of returning under the wings of your parents and enjoying the protection of your family? What expectations do the two labels &quot;rich&quot; and &quot;only child&quot; carry for contemporary young people? Behind the changes in the female template, how are our attitudes towards life and work changing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this podcast, we invite two guests who are both &quot;only children from Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; to discuss the above issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;This issue’s guests&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/q9kAf3NBPcT6RCeg8LFU8qHTIoPL0B6dGhzEJTTN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/q9kAf3NBPcT6RCeg8LFU8qHTIoPL0B6dGhzEJTTN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254331&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Sun Lin (left), lecturer at the Chinese Studies Center of the Chinese University of Hong Kong and PhD in Anthropology, and Ge Shurun ​​(right), a doctoral candidate at the School of Journalism, Renmin University of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>; Listening tips: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►03:34 &amp;nbsp;“Someone will tell me the truth” is the very attractive part of this label&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ►06:22 &amp;nbsp;In the process of growing up, the only daughter born in the 1980s in Shanghai believed in trying things out&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►08:48 &amp;nbsp;The &quot;Pyramid of Filial Piety&quot; emphasizes cost-effectiveness&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ►11:51 &amp;nbsp;Interview with the elderly in Shanghai, almost no one expects their children to support them in old age&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►15:09 &amp;nbsp;Returning to the family character and independent character co-exist&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 20:25 &amp;nbsp;Changes in the external environment have made young people more in need of family to resist risks&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►25:46 &amp;nbsp;The labels of &quot;Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; and &quot;only child&quot; hide some social prejudices&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;►29:06 &amp;nbsp;In addition to money, the &quot;only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; also emphasizes the emotional support of the family&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►31:02 &amp;nbsp;Different female templates are pursued by different people. Or is it a conflict between ideals and reality&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►35:22 &amp;nbsp;The label also ignores the obligations and responsibilities that an only child will face&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►39:29 &amp;nbsp;Enlightened parents will also Giving hints on &quot;should you come back and take the civil service exam?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Editors: Wang Yixuan, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Operators: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第134届广交会开幕，新能源汽车备受外商关注]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258778]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院副秘书长近期密集调整：4人履新，其中两名“69后”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 17, the official website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security announced that the State Council appoints and removes national staff. Among them, Sun Guangyu was appointed as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council; Wang Zhiqing was removed from the post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu previously served as a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management. Wang Zhiqing, who has resigned, has served as Chairman and Party Secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July this year, the deputy secretary-general of the State Council has been reshuffled frequently, with &quot;four in and four out&quot; - Sun Guangyu, Xu Shouben, Wang Zhijun, and Wang Yonghong have assumed the new posts, while Wang Zhiqing, Ding Xuedong, Peng Shujie, and Li Wenwen have resigned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March this year, during the two sessions of the National People’s Congress, the leadership team of the central government changed, and State Councilor Wu Zhenglong also served as Secretary-General of the State Council. According to public reports, there are currently at least 7 deputy secretaries-general of the State Council, namely Meng Yang, Liu Jianbo, Guo Wei, Wang Zhijun, Wang Yonghong, Xu Shouben, and Sun Guangyu (in order of appointment). Among them, Wang Zhijun is clearly at the ministerial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The four new deputy secretaries-general of the State Council come from different fields&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The four new deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who took up their posts this year come from different fields. He is an expert in the field. Sun Guangyu has worked in the chemical industry for a long time and is an expert in the field of hazardous chemical safety supervision. Before taking up his new post, he served as a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management; Xu Shouben is a &quot;veteran&quot; in the financial industry and before taking up his new post, he served as the vice president of the China Development Bank. ; Wang Zhijun has been engaged in economic management work in central ministries and commissions for a long time, and served as deputy secretary of the Heilongjiang Provincial Party Committee before taking office; Wang Yonghong has long worked in the State Administration Bureau (referred to as the State Administration Bureau), serving for 32 years, and took office in June this year. Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Management Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The four new people are all born after 1965, among whom Wang Yonghong and Xu Shouben were both born in 1969. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab4cf05000a88ceabe1aaa8d69aa654f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab4cf05000a88ceabe1aaa8d69aa654f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254335&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Guangyu. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu, who took office as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council today, was born in December 1966. He has a university degree, a master&#39;s degree in engineering, a professor-level senior engineer, and a member of the chemical industry group of the National Safety Production Expert Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu graduated from Dalian University of Technology, majoring in fine chemical engineering. According to the official website of Dalian University of Technology, he worked at Sinopec in his early years. In 2009, he was transferred from the manager of the Aromatics Department of the Tianjin Branch of Sinopec Co., Ltd. to the deputy director and director of the Safety Supervision and Management Department III of the State Administration of Work Safety, and later served as the Hazardous Chemicals Department of the Emergency Management Department. Director of the Supervision Department and Director of the First Department of Hazardous Chemical Supervision. In June 2022, Sun Guangyu served as a member of the Party Committee and Vice Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, and later served as deputy director of the Office of the State Council Safety Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than a week ago, Sun Guangyu interviewed the main person in charge of the Ordos Municipal People&#39;s Government on behalf of the Security Affairs Office of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Ministry of Emergency Management, on September 7, a major high-pressure gas leak occurred at Yiding Ecological Agriculture Development Co., Ltd. in Ordos, Inner Mongolia, resulting in 10 deaths and 3 injuries in a major production safety accident. On September 14, the State Council Safety Committee decided to supervise the investigation and handling of this major accident. On September 11, the Ministry of Emergency Management organized a national emergency video conference on hazardous chemicals safety risk prevention, at which the situation of the Ordos &quot;9.7&quot; accident was reported. Sun Guangyu, member of the Party Committee and Vice Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, attended the meeting and delivered a speech. The meeting pointed out that lessons from the accident must be carefully learned, and the lessons learned in blood must not be verified with blood again! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 8, in response to the &quot;9.7&quot; major high-pressure gas leakage accident in Ordos, the Office of the State Council Safety Committee interviewed the main person in charge of the Ordos Municipal People&#39;s Government. Sun Guangyu, deputy director of the Office of the State Council Security Committee and deputy minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, presided over the interview, and heads of relevant departments and bureaus of the Ministry of Emergency Management attended the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Sun Guangyu has left the chemical industry and emergency management leadership position he held for many years and joined the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7985b31e8140d787488575eb9d4a9451.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;642&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7985b31e8140d787488575eb9d4a9451.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254337&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Shouben. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Shouben took office as deputy secretary-general of the State Council on August 30. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Xu Shouben was born in April 1969 in Yantai, Shandong Province. He graduated from the School of Management of Harbin Institute of Technology and received a doctorate in Western Economics from Lingnan College of Sun Yat-sen University and is a senior economist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Shouben has worked in the financial industry for many years. He joined the Guangdong Branch of ICBC in April 1995. He has worked in various branches of ICBC in Guangdong Province for a long time. He once served as the Office Director of ICBC Guangdong Branch, President of Guangdong Jiangmen Branch, and Party committee secretary and other positions. In March 2011, he was appointed as the vice president of the Guangdong Branch and in July 2015, he was appointed as the president of the Shenzhen Branch. In August 2020, Xu Shouben was promoted to Vice President of ICBC. In October 2022, Xu Shouben was appointed as Vice President of the China Development Bank and will take office as the State Council in August this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9a7a2bf37812ce179a149e3d37af0258.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9a7a2bf37812ce179a149e3d37af0258.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254338&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Zhijun. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhijun and Wang Yonghong took up their posts on the same day and were appointed deputy secretary-general of the State Council on July 4. Among them, Wang Zhijun is in charge of the daily work of the General Office of the State Council and is clearly at the ministerial level. He is a member of the 20th Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public resume shows that Wang Zhijun was born in September 1965 in Hohhot, Inner Mongolia, and has a graduate degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhijun has been responsible for economic management for many years. He has served as the director of the National Economic Comprehensive Department of the National Development and Reform Commission, deputy inspector of the Comprehensive Group of the Office of the National Energy Leading Group, and deputy director of the Economic Bureau No. 1 of the Office of the Central Financial and Economic Leading Group. , inspector, director of the fifth economic bureau, director of the first economic bureau of the Office of the Central Financial and Economic Commission, etc. In January 2019, Wang Zhijun was appointed as a member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology. In April 2022, he was transferred to the position of Deputy Secretary of the Heilongjiang Provincial Party Committee, and he will assume the new position of the State Council in July this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/12331a6220040ce2b935ae78746a30e8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/12331a6220040ce2b935ae78746a30e8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254339&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Yonghong. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yonghong has worked in the State Administration of Institutional Affairs for a long time. The National Administration Bureau is an agency directly under the State Council that manages the affairs of state agencies. It is responsible for the management of funds, finances, official vehicles, state-owned assets and real estate of central state agencies, and is responsible for the management of life services for party and state leaders and relevant service objects within a designated range. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the State Administration of Management, Wang Yonghong, born in June 1969, has a bachelor&#39;s degree and a master&#39;s degree in management. He joined the National Bureau of Management in August 1991 and served successively as deputy director of the Financial Management Department, deputy director of the Logistics Reform and Comprehensive Management Department, director of the training center, director of the Financial Management Department, and director of the Dongba Service Center of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs; 2017 In April 2017, he was appointed as deputy director, member of the Party Leadership Group and director of the Dongba Service Center of the State Administration of Management. In November 2017, he was appointed as deputy director and member of the leading party group of the State Administration of Management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 20 this year, relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee attended the meeting of leading cadres of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs and announced the central government’s decision: Comrade Wang Yonghong was appointed as Party Secretary and Director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yonghong has assumed the new post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council and concurrently serves as Party Secretary and Director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. Previous directors of the State Administration of Management were also concurrently held by the deputy secretary-general of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Of the four deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who have resigned, three have assumed new duties&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Of the four deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who have resigned this year, three have assumed their new posts. new. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhiqing, who resigned as deputy secretary-general of the State Council today, has been appointed chairman and party secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group Co., Ltd. a week ago. Among the three deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who resigned on July 4, Ding Xuedong has served as Party Secretary of the National Council for Social Security Fund, and Li Wenwen has served as Deputy Minister of the Central Ministry of Social Work and Director of the Office of the Central Joint Conference on Petitions, and continues to serve concurrently as the National Petitions Committee. Director of the Bureau and Secretary of the Party Leadership Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/a404a4b5f6cfd0bf0ae6ea00c5445207.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/a404a4b5f6cfd0bf0ae6ea00c5445207.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254336&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Zhiqing. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public resume shows that Wang Zhiqing was born in March 1966 and is from Tianjin. Wang Zhiqing has worked in the civil aviation system for a long time. He joined the Civil Aviation Administration of China in 1992 and held leadership positions in multiple departments. In March 2014, he was appointed deputy director of the Civil Aviation Administration of China. In March 2019, he was transferred to the position of member of the Party Leadership Group, Chief Planner, and Director of the Comprehensive Planning Department of the Ministry of Transport. In February 2021, he was promoted to Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Transport. In November 2021, Wang Zhiqing was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;China Eastern Airlines&quot; WeChat public account, on the morning of October 9, China Eastern Airlines Group Co., Ltd. held a meeting for middle-level and above managers. Relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China announced the decision of the Central Committee on the appointment of Chairman and Party Secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group Co., Ltd.: Comrade Wang Zhiqing is appointed as Chairman and Party Secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group Co., Ltd. China Eastern Airlines, headquartered in Shanghai, is one of China&#39;s three major state-owned backbone air transport groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 4, the State Council appointed and removed national staff. On the same day that Wang Zhijun and Wang Yonghong assumed the new deputy secretaries-general of the State Council, Ding Xuedong, Peng Shujie, and Li Wenwen were dismissed from their posts as deputy secretaries-general of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6ceff0fc8380678e866371cf8479ee40.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6ceff0fc8380678e866371cf8479ee40.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254334&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ding Xuedong. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Xuedong was a member of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. He served twice as deputy secretary-general of the State Council and served as executive deputy secretary-general of the State Council before resigning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the public resume, Ding Xuedong, born in February 1960 in Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, is a master&#39;s student in the Industrial Economics Department of Hubei Institute of Finance and Economics (now Zhongnan University of Economics and Law), and a finance major in the Graduate Department of the Institute of Fiscal Science of the Ministry of Finance. PhD in Economics, doctoral supervisor at the Institute of Fiscal Science of the Ministry of Finance. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has served in the Ministry of Finance for a long time, serving successively as Director of the Department of Basic Management of State-owned Capital Funds, Director of the Department of Agriculture, and Director of the Department of Education, Science and Culture. In November 2006, he served as Assistant Minister of Finance and Party Leadership Group Member, in March 2008, served as Deputy Minister of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2010, Ding Xuedong was appointed as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. In July 2013, he was appointed as Chairman and CEO of China Investment Corporation. In October 2014, he was concurrently appointed as Chairman of CICC. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2017, the State Council appointed Ding Xuedong as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council (ministerial level). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 1 this year, the National Council for Social Security Fund held a meeting of leading cadres. Relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee announced the decision of the Central Committee: Comrade Ding Xuedong will be appointed Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the National Council for Social Security Fund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9f291a1a848abe41791377c7b37e923b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9f291a1a848abe41791377c7b37e923b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254341&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Peng Shujie. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Shujie is a &quot;veteran&quot; in journalism. He was born in May 1963 in Bengbu, Anhui Province. He is a senior journalist and a master&#39;s degree candidate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to his public resume, Peng Shujie studied in the Department of Foreign Languages ​​of Anhui University and the Department of Journalism of the Graduate School of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences in his early years. In the 1990s, he was also sent to study abroad at the University of Hawaii in the United States. He joined Xinhua News Agency in 1989 and served successively as reporter and deputy director of Xinhua News Agency’s external central news gathering and editing office, deputy director and director of the external central foreign affairs news gathering and editing office, chief editorial assistant (deputy bureau level) of Xinhua News Agency’s chief editorial office, Xinhua News Agency He serves as deputy editor-in-chief of the editorial office and director of the International Department of Xinhua News Agency. In July 2014, he was promoted to deputy editor-in-chief and party member of Xinhua News Agency. In November 2015, he was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council and retired after serving for nearly 8 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6a8939ffa1eff6c6dabc5105a91be09f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;490&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6a8939ffa1eff6c6dabc5105a91be09f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254340&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Wenwen. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public resume, Li Wenwen was born in January 1963. He graduated from the Department of Political Science and Law of Ningxia University and received a postgraduate degree from the Central Party School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He worked in Ningxia for a long time in his early years and served as deputy secretary of the Yinchuan Municipal Party Committee (department level), director of the Department of Justice and Party Secretary of the Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region; secretary of the Shizuishan Municipal Party Committee and Guyuan Municipal Party Committee secretary of the Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region. In June 2012, Li Wenzhang was promoted to the Standing Committee of the Party Committee of Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region and concurrently served as Secretary of the Guyuan Municipal Party Committee. In June 2015, he was appointed as member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee and Secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee of the Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region. In June 2016, he was appointed as member of the Standing Committee of the Liaoning Provincial Party Committee and secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee. In December 2018, he served as director of the Political Department of the Ministry of National Security, member of the Party Committee, secretary of the party committee of the agency, and deputy chief superintendent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2020, Li Wenwen assumed the new post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council, member of the Party Leadership Group of the State Council, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group, and Director of the State Bureau of Letters and Calls. It is worth noting that the past several directors of the State Bureau of Letters and Calls were also served concurrently by the deputy secretary-general of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 4 this year, Li Wenwen was removed from the post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. Ten days later, the information in the &quot;Leadership Introduction&quot; column of the National Bureau of Letters and Calls showed that Li Wenwen is currently the deputy minister of the Central Ministry of Social Work, the director of the Office of the Central Joint Conference on Letters and Calls, the director and the party secretary of the National Bureau of Letters and Calls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 16 this year, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Plan for the Reform of Party and State Institutions&quot;. In terms of institutional reform of the Party Central Committee, five new &quot;Chinese-prefixed&quot; institutions including the Central Department of Social Work were established. Among them, the Central Ministry of Social Work is responsible for coordinating and guiding the people&#39;s petition work, guiding the collection of people&#39;s suggestions, coordinating and promoting party building to lead grassroots governance and grassroots political power building, unified leadership of the party work of national industry associations and chambers of commerce, and coordinating and promoting the deepening reform and transformation of industry associations and chambers of commerce. Development, guiding the party building work of mixed-ownership enterprises, non-public enterprises, new economic organizations, new social organizations, and new employment groups, and guiding the construction of social work talent teams, etc., as a functional department of the Party Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Plan&quot; also clarifies that the Central Ministry of Social Work will unifiedly lead the National Bureau of Letters and Calls. The National Bureau of Letters and Calls, a national bureau managed by the General Office of the State Council, was restructured into an agency directly under the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What are the responsibilities of the Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to public reports, there are currently at least 7 deputy secretaries-general of the State Council, namely Meng Yang, Liu Jianbo, Guo Wei, Wang Zhijun, Wang Yonghong, Xu Shouben, and Sun Guangyu (in order of appointment). In addition to the four people who took up their new posts this year, the remaining three people: Meng Yang was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council in May 2015, Liu Jianbo was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council in May 2021, and Guo Wei was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council in July 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How many people are generally allocated to the Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council? According to the Chinese Government website, the State Council issued a &quot;Regulations on the Main Responsibilities, Internal Organizations and Staffing of the General Office of the State Council&quot; in July 2008, which mentioned that the administrative establishment of the General Office of the State Council is 519. Among them: 1 Secretary-General of the State Council, 9 Deputy Secretary-Generals of the State Council (including part-time ones), and 43 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the responsibilities of the Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Working Rules of the State Council&quot; revised in March this year clearly mentioned that the State Council implements the prime minister&#39;s responsibility system. Under the leadership of the Prime Minister, the Secretary-General is responsible for handling the daily work of the State Council, and the Deputy Secretary-General assists the Secretary-General in his work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It mentioned that “the General Office of the State Council must carefully review and review the official documents submitted by various regions and departments to the State Council for review and approval. It involves the issuance of administrative normative documents in the name of the State Council or the General Office of the State Council, If administrative normative documents are issued in the name of a department after being submitted to the State Council for approval, the judicial administrative department of the State Council shall conduct a legality review. For matters that have disagreements between departments, the leading comrades of the State Council in charge of the sponsoring department shall take the lead in strengthening coordination. The Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council shall assist The leading comrades in charge of the State Council shall do a good job in coordination.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the review and review of relevant rules and documents, more specific information can be obtained from some of the concurrent positions held by the Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. For example, Meng Yang is concurrently the deputy director of the State Council&#39;s Working Committee on Disabled Persons, the deputy leader of the State Council&#39;s First National Comprehensive Natural Disaster Risk Survey Leading Group, and the deputy convener of the State Council&#39;s inter-ministerial joint conference system for optimizing family planning policies. Liu Jianbo concurrently serves as deputy director of the National Narcotics Control Commission. Wang Yonghong concurrently serves as Party Secretary and Director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. In addition, Guo Wei is also a member of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and a member of the Agriculture and Rural Affairs Committee. Liu Jianbo is a member of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and a member of the Ethnic and Religious Affairs Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话许知远：梁启超和他诞生150年后的世界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258769]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Liang Qichao is our &quot;familiar stranger&quot;. In China, almost no one knows his name, but his vague image is limited to a reformist politician, the author of &quot;Young China&quot;, and a father who raised many outstanding children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Qichao was born in Chakeng Village, Xinhui County, Guangzhou Prefecture in 1873. In &quot;Autobiography at Thirty&quot;, Liang Qichao used major events in Chinese and world history to find coordinates for the year of his birth: it was the tenth year after the fall of the Taiping Rebellion, one year after Zeng Guofan&#39;s death, and the third year after the Franco-Prussian War ended. Of course, when he was born, the chronology was the twelfth year of Tongzhi, Guiyou. The AD calendar was not widely adopted until the founding of New China. It was through Liang Qichao that the sayings of the 19th and 20th centuries spread in the Chinese-speaking world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Qichao was one of the first Chinese to realize the turn of the century. At the beginning of 1900, he wrote &quot;The Song of the Pacific in the Twentieth Century&quot;, predicting that the new century would usher in the Pacific Age. Chinese people in the 19th century did not realize that they were in the 19th century. Only in the 20th century will we look back with the help of new historical coordinates to describe this era of sinking, humiliation and endeavor, and salvation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1898, after the failure of the Hundred Days Reform, Liang Qichao went into exile in Japan and traveled around the world. After the founding of the Republic of China, Liang Qichao returned to China, and the main stages of his activities were in the ice drinking rooms in the capital Beijing and Tianjin. For him, his hometown in Guangdong has become as far away as his boyhood. But this does not mean that he bid farewell to his hometown. In fact, many of Liang Qichao&#39;s activities in Yokohama, Japan, North America and Australia relied on the huge support of the overseas Chinese network in Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/YH8F41xHIdF3FC0Vzqv5AIn8UTkKPK3nlVfGX4Ax.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;765&quot; height= &quot;1055&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/YH8F41xHIdF3FC0Vzqv5AIn8UTkKPK3nlVfGX4Ax.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254309&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liang Qichao during his time in Japan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If we focus on those people who have no names in history, we will find that from ten Since the middle of the ninth century, a large number of Cantonese have gone to North America and Japan. The use of steamships has enabled Cantonese expatriates to no longer just go to Southeast Asia, but to travel across the Pacific to all parts of the world.&quot; &quot;Regional Culture and National Identity: Late Professor Cheng Meibao, author of &quot;The Formation of Guangdong Cultural Concepts since the Qing Dynasty,&quot; told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;There are traces of Cantonese in every port on the Pacific coast. They have established guilds, temples, hometown associations in foreign countries, or organized themselves in the form of companies. , so when Kang Liang, Sun Yat-sen and others were active overseas, someone would contact them and arrange accommodation and itinerary. Behind the activities of these historical celebrities are decades of preparation by unknown groups.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Many people have tried to write a biography of Liang Qichao. The historian Wu Qichang of the Republic of China wrote half of it until the Reform Movement of 1898; Xie Xizhang&#39;s &quot;Biography of Liang Qichao&quot; is divided into chapters based on Liang&#39;s interactions and relationships with different historical figures; the writer Wei Wei Before publishing the novel &quot;In the Misty Clouds&quot;, she spent several years writing a biography of Liang Qichao. When she had written more than 100,000 words, she felt that the thread was too complicated, so she put it down and started writing novels first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 is the 150th anniversary of the birth of Liang Qichao, and the second part of Xu Zhiyuan&#39;s &quot;Liang Qichao&quot; has also been published. The first part is titled &quot;Young Revolutionary&quot;, about Liang Qichao from 1873 to 1898, and was published in 2019. Xu Zhiyuan originally planned to write it in three parts, but now the writing plan has been expanded to five parts. The second part, &quot;Desperation&quot;, was written from 1898 to 1903. The complex historical clues and the many characters who interacted with the Liang family made Xu Zhiyuan feel that, It is necessary to expand his version of Liang Qichao&#39;s biography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Everyone is a contemporary.” This is how Xu Zhiyuan reminds his writing and the way each reader enters Liang Qichao’s world. Liang Qichao does not just belong to yesterday, maybe he also belongs to the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Danni, the editor of the second part of &quot;Liang Qichao&quot; told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;Xu Zhiyuan&#39;s writing context is different from that of historians and scholars, not in response to a problem in a specific academic history context, but out of A very pure curiosity about another person. It is curiosity about how another scholar, who is also in a period of unknown changes between the old and the new, faces the changes and participates in them. So his Writing is a kind of writing that empathizes with others and has a sense of empathy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend conducted an exclusive interview with Xu Zhiyuan in a one-way space beside the Grand Canal in Hangzhou. Xu Zhiyuan is very busy. In addition to recording the program &quot;Thirteen Invitations&quot;, he is traveling to various cities to promote his new book. When a reporter asked how to balance Liang Qichao&#39;s ideological trajectory and social picture in the book, Xu Zhiyuan said: &quot;Sometimes I feel that there is too much about the era, and the era overwhelms the individual. Sometimes I feel that there is too much about the individual and lack of the era. Reflection, this is a process of constant searching.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/nlIotn1FEjTnSnyYbRhNNETePlneXvpjW1cgOyTs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/nlIotn1FEjTnSnyYbRhNNETePlneXvpjW1cgOyTs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254310 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In September 2023, Xu Zhiyuan talked about Liang Qichao in Hangzhou. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Pumpkin Vision)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I especially hope to have an ideological adventure with the protagonist Liang Qichao, and you don&#39;t know What will happen next? I have only written the second volume so far. His thoughts are still evolving. I am not willing to use hindsight to evaluate whether his thoughts have matured. During that time, he had Such a state of mind. I want to go back to the historical scene as much as possible to create some possibility. The writing process of this set of books does not mean that I started after 20 years of research, careful consideration, and a lot of understanding about it. Putting pen to paper, no. My understanding will continue to deepen as I write. For example, when I write the second volume, I understand him better than the first volume. When I write the third volume, I may understand him better than the second volume. But it is also possible that when you finish writing the last volume, you will realize that your initial understanding of his thoughts was not accurate because it is a larger framework.&quot; Xu Zhiyuan told a reporter from Southern Weekend. In a sense, Liang Qichao&#39;s world is already Xu Zhiyuan&#39;s parallel universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Constructing Liang Qichao’s world like a puzzle&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;There have been some previous works that discussed Liang Qichao from the perspective of intellectual history, such as &quot;Liang Qichao and Modern Chinese Thought&quot; by American scholar Levinson, &quot;Liang Qichao and the Transition of Chinese Thought (1890-1907)&quot; by Zhang Hao, etc., and you The main interest in writing a biography of Liang Qichao is to describe the social transformation experienced by Liang Qichao&#39;s generation. What do you think is the main difference between the two kinds of writing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The books by Levinson and Zhang Hao were the first books that influenced my interest in Liang Qichao, and they were of great ideological enlightenment to me. . Levinson puts Liang Qichao in a larger context to view his role in Chinese tradition, covering his life in a short space. Mr. Zhang Hao&#39;s book mainly discusses Liang Qichao&#39;s ideological process before 1907. About ten years ago, I met Mr. Zhang Hao in Washington, USA. I went to his home as a guest and had a couple&#39;s lung slices together. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are ideological biographies, and what I want to write is one that is more people-centered, literary, historical, and in a sense encyclopedic. Book. I spent a lot of pen and ink not only writing about Liang Qichao, but also his contemporaries, the spirit of the entire era behind him, the changes in China as a whole, the changes in Japan, and the changes in the world, so it is more like &quot;Liang Qichao and his era&quot; . I hope to regard Liang Qichao as a representative figure in the transformation process of global modernity. He belongs not only to the Chinese tradition, but also to the tradition of Asia and the world. Therefore, I want to describe the living space and scenes behind him. I wrote a lot about him as a doer. He is not only a thinker, but more importantly, a doer. I wanted to give him a more three-dimensional presentation using a modern biographical writing method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If we want to analyze his ideological trajectory more, we will add more discussion For this part, your writing method is to use historical data as much as possible and rarely discuss it. What is the reason for this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I try not to destroy the narrative rhythm. Whether the narrative has a sense of music or a logic, I try to follow the narrative itself. The structure, the characters gradually become fuller and more vivid on each page as each volume progresses. He has his own character, which I cannot completely control and regulate, and his character is made up of those realistic characters. It is composed of materials and perhaps some of my imagination in reorganizing materials. My subjectivity is completed in the preface. Once I enter the main text writing, I hope to hide my subjective emotions behind the words. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Reading the just-published second part of the biography of Liang Qichao When &quot;Desperation&quot; and &quot;Young Changemakers&quot; were published a few years ago, a large part of the reader&#39;s pleasure was that through your writing, you could build up a perception of the life experience of a part of the Chinese people more than a hundred years ago. For example, when scholars from Guangdong in the late Qing Dynasty went to Beijing to take exams, they took the sea route instead of land. They usually had to stop in Shanghai, so Shanghai naturally became a stage for their activities; for example, when they arrived in Beijing, they would stay in the hometown guild hall. What difficulties did you encounter when collecting these materials? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When collecting materials, one is to imagine his living space. For example, Liang Qichao is often abstracted into a simple ideological figure. Of course this is also very important, but he not only lived in an ideological context, but also lived in a realistic context. He was not only a thinker, but also an important witness and participant of that era, so for me, It became very important to create the context of that era. Only by better understanding the background of that era can it be easier to understand the excellence and difficulty of his actions. So I spent a lot of energy to construct the space of the times, to understand how a scholar or a scholar went to Beijing to take the exam, and what the daily life of a scholar was like. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only if you better understand the daily life of a scholar, for example, what kind of works he reads in Xuehaitang, will you understand the ideological context of his suddenly going to Japan and entering the Western context. Extraordinary. Therefore, I will describe the daily life of scholars, what it is like in Guangzhou and Beijing, and how to interact with people in the guild hall. I will rely on diaries and notes from that year, some records that seem to have nothing to do with Liang Qichao, to create a world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am very influenced by Shi Jingqian in this regard. You see when he wrote &quot;The Death of Wang&quot;, Wang did not have any records, but he used Pu Songling&#39;s novels to imagine what Shandong was like back then. The living atmosphere of the Qing Dynasty at that time. I also relied heavily on such notes and even novels at the time to construct such an atmosphere, including other candidates&#39; daily records. The second volume is to create a time and space of Tokyo, Yokohama, and Melbourne from the late 19th to the early 20th century. , but also to travel through this world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was young, I liked to read all kinds of miscellaneous books. This is the role of miscellaneous books. For example, I have read a lot of books on Australian history, and when I was writing, to describe Sydney in 1900, I had to collect a large amount of newspaper documents from that time, and probably only used a few strokes. What was the Australian overseas Chinese leader Mei Guangda like at that time? What is the situation of the Ye family in Vancouver? You need to go through all kinds of strange information, just like doing a puzzle, it may not be complete, try to put together as many pieces as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For example, if you write about the relationship between Liang Qichao and his wife, and how he There is very little information about a fruitless love affair in Hawaii. On the one hand, he is a precocious cultural star with social prestige that is not commensurate with his age. On the other hand, he seems to be a person who does not need an affair between his children and his wife. Don&#39;t travel with him or stay with him. Today&#39;s readers would have a hard time understanding this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was a male-centered era. For these scholars who took the world as their own responsibility, although family was very important, it was often neglected by them. The narrative is ignored and few records are left. Including overseas Chinatowns, it is basically a male world. Except for overseas Chinese leaders who may bring their wives with them, most of their families stay in their hometowns in Guangdong and Fujian. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Qichao has been wandering around the world and has a huge emotional void. He will reveal his anxiety, loneliness and frustration in poetry. He wrote 24 love poems depicting Only when his strong feelings for Miss He are placed in such a time and space can his emotions be easily understood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kang Youwei&#39;s emotions were even richer. He went into exile, married different wives, and had various affairs. The brother of Liang Qichao&#39;s wife was his examiner. This was a family that was kind to him. However, because of his actions, his wife and the whole family were involved in danger and panic. He felt a lot of guilt in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can we say that Liang Qichao is a relatively ascetic person? Zhang Hao&#39;s book talks about &quot;self-denial&quot;, and self-denial also includes the aspect of abstinence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Liang Qichao is very emotional and very self-disciplined. His enthusiasm and desire have been greatly reflected in his actions and writing. display. If you think about it, he has written so many works and done so many things in a short period of time, ranging from political organizations to founding magazines, and covering everything from political economy to how to write novels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The psychological motivations of many people constitute the driving force of history&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You say that Liang Qichao may be China&#39;s earliest global traveler, but Chinese literati have no habit of paying attention to details such as food, clothing, housing, transportation, customs, and landscapes during the journey. How did you add these details? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;He himself has written part of his story about seasickness across the Pacific and his experiences in New York and the United States. I still need to read newspapers from that year to see how American and Australian history described the country and society at that time, mixed with Liang Qichao’s personal experiences and feelings, to form the world in his eyes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before Liang Qichao, Huang Zunxian also followed his diplomacy Activities, living in Japan, the United States, and Singapore for a long time. What role did the networks of overseas Chinese in Guangdong play in their travels? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Cities on both sides of the Pacific gathered many Cantonese people, forming a network of funds and ideas. This network supported the revolutionaries in modern China . Without the overseas network of Cantonese people, many things would not have happened, and Kang Liang would not have been able to play such an important role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then why were these revolutionaries not born in Fujian? There are also many overseas immigrants from Fujian. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, it is related to the birth of outstanding figures, on the other hand, Hong Kong has played an important role. Hong Kong is a place where new ideas radiate. At the same time, Guangzhou is also a cultural center, and interesting cultural tension and cultural dynamics have been formed between Hong Kong and Guangzhou. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao’s travels in Australia and the United States attract you the most What is the place? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is his interaction with the local society and how to stimulate the local people’s interest and enthusiasm for his political ideas, so I spent A lot of time was spent trying to find out how the local Chinese reacted to Liang Qichao. I was very happy to find a piece of material. When Liang Qichao gave a speech in Seattle, a Japanese student happened to record the grand occasion of everyone in the Chinese Theater enjoying Liang Qichao&#39;s speech. This description is very important to me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thing that interests me is the differences between the different Chinese worlds. For example, in Melbourne, San Francisco, and Vancouver, the Chinese communities in each city have their own characteristics, and these characteristics will also be reflected in their attitudes towards exiles. Including the divisions and tensions within Chinese society, what wealthy businessmen want to gain from the Royalist Society, and what ordinary people want to gain. Everyone has complex psychological motivations, and these psychological motivations constitute the driving force of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What new observations do you have about today’s overseas Chinese? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We can see the overlapping waves of immigrants. They will leave different legacies. On the one hand, there is the old-fashioned Chinatown composed of Cantonese people. On the other hand, changes can be seen in the diet. Nowadays, overseas Chinese food not only includes Cantonese cuisine, but also more and more Sichuan cuisine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The most important mode of transportation in that era was Ships, the risks of shipping, the long time, and the pain of seasickness are difficult for today&#39;s travelers to understand. Have you ever experienced or planned a long-distance ship ride? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, it is difficult to have. The sense of time at that time was different from ours now. They may have thought that it was normal to cross the ocean by boat in a month. Because they don&#39;t have planes. The sense of time is all relative. For them, taking a boat from Yokohama to Hawaii in 10 days is already very fast. Liang Qichao experienced an era when the earth suddenly shrunk and accelerated. He was able to travel to many different states and countries in such a short period of time. This was a brand new experience. Changes in the sense of time and modernity were very important to the formation of Liang Qichao’s thoughts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today’s readers must understand Liang Qichao’s era. Where are the barriers and difficulties? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it may not be that difficult to understand daily life. After all, although the rhythm of daily life is different, it is not that difficult either. grasp. It is very difficult to understand the changes in his thoughts. He suddenly went from a young man who read the Four Books and Five Classics, or who only read a few words about the outside world from the &quot;Global Gazette&quot;, to enter Japan in the late Meiji period and face so many different things. The impact of ideas, from social Darwinism to liberalism and constitutional monarchy, as well as novels, science, and economics, all of these things are coming at him. How can he understand such a new world, that kind of explosion of ideas? Of course, we are now in an era of great technological changes, and there are many unfamiliar terms that we do not know, but after all, we have received some training in modern education. At least these new changes are carried out along the basis and context of modern education. Liang Qichao and others were trained by It is traditional education. This huge impact on the thoughts and feelings is a process that is difficult to describe. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s like you were trained in Newtonian mechanics, and you are suddenly thrown into the world of quantum mechanics. How does it feel? When we describe such changes in thought, we cannot always think with hindsight that those nouns have become fixed common sense. Those nouns themselves were created by Liang Qichao and others. Through the translation of Japanese, we can wonder whether this new word is It is available, and I have to start using it without even having time to think too much. If I want to tell others about it, I think it is a very panic process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A big paradox or challenge in writing the biography of Liang Qichao is, Many of the concepts and vocabulary we Chinese use today were originally created by Liang Qichao, but we have to use the words he created to repeat him like a &quot;tail-biting snake&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;So how to return to the strangeness at that time is a question. I hope to depict the process of thought change, not the solidified thought itself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In other words, in addition to &quot;contemporaneity&quot; , we also have a huge difference in civilization paradigm from more than a hundred years ago. This difference is first reflected in our education and our relationship with tradition. Perhaps it is a huge challenge to present such subtle yet ubiquitous differences? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You must use some imagination and empathy. Of course, imagination has its limits, and misunderstandings are bound to occur during the writing process. Perhaps misunderstanding itself is also a very important motivation that history has given us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Write a biography of Liang Qichao in 2023, it must be Written by someone in 2023. By 2053, someone else can write it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It must be with this generation’s awareness of the issues, including the material you choose, it must be the material that triggers your mood at the moment. will choose it. So it has a strong presentness, a bit like translation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a concept of translation that means literary classics It should be re-translated every fifty years, and every time it is re-translated, it must use the literary vocabulary and daily language of this era. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For a character like Liang Qichao, he should indeed be constantly rewritten. Not only Liang Qichao, but also Yan Fu and Cai Yuanpei, the fathers of modern China, are worthy of being rewritten by every generation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Back to the fact that Liang Qichao is our contemporary In this way, whether we quote Liang Qichao or go back to Lu Xun today, are we responding to the current dilemma that we have no answers to many questions? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Thoughts need the historical dimension. Without the historical dimension, your thoughts will be very frivolous or rootless. So when I wrote it, it was of course a certain response to the present, and at the same time it was also about finding a certain historical context and framework for current issues. Within this historical framework, it is easier for you to understand your current feelings. To me, all time and space are intertwined. In fact, Liang Qichao’s influence has not disappeared, it still permeates our lives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;China should have a kind of historical writing that combines ideological and literary nature&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic style , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What inspirations did Liang Qichao’s choices in the face of great changes and various difficult ideological problems give you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Without the opportunity to think carefully, everyone has to act with insufficient information. I like the spirit of action in him. Action is also a way of thinking, and action constantly confirms the limitations and possibilities of thought. The most powerful thing about Liang Qichao is that he lets actions verify or expand his thoughts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao would prefer Wang Yangming to Zhu Xi. Liang Qichao felt that Wang Yangming&#39;s spirit of integrating knowledge and action had a huge impact on Japan&#39;s reformers from the late Edo period to the Meiji Restoration. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because Wang Yangming is a release of personal subjectivity. Then individuals can shape themselves. This ability is very powerful and can directly affect the environment and the times, inspiring many people with great ambitions. Liang Qichao must have been deeply affected by this, because he was in a state of exile, where everything was full of uncertainty, and personal initiative became crucial. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao is a scholar, media worker, and As an educator and author, which of his identities attracts you the most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, there is another identity as a politician. I think he is first of all a writer, and his other actions are constantly unfolding. Those roles are also very important to him, but the writer is the role that can best display everything about him and display his talents. Liang Qichao is a writer of the Encyclopedia School, an Enlightenment thinker in the era of transition. His writing is like Japan&#39;s Fukuzawa Yukichi, or Voltaire, Rousseau, and Diderot during the French Enlightenment. It touches every aspect and can be used in words. exert a very direct political and social influence. His era was also going through the process of the formation of various modern disciplines in China. Liang Qichao was involved in it, and then he had the style of a Chinese literati. In such a transitional era, his writing was very mixed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have a lot of media work experience, and you will know Liang Are you particularly interested in Qichao editing newspapers and magazines? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Writing a biography, of course the author will have a subtle influence on you. Liang Qichao and I are separated by a hundred years. He was born in 1873 and I was born in 1976. There may be a subconscious echo. But what I am more interested in is that from the 19th century to the 20th century, during China&#39;s dramatic transformation and entry into the modern world, Liang Qichao was a representative of the spiritual world, and his extensive social participation also provided a rich sample. Next, I want to write a biography of Li Hongzhang. His character and experience are completely different from mine. I hope to describe that historical stage, China&#39;s difficulties in entering the world stage in the 19th century, and personal failures. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao was the bridge from the 19th century to the 20th century. Li Hongzhang is the elegy of China&#39;s 19th century. You were the editor-in-chief of &quot;Oriental History Review&quot;. &quot;Oriental History Review&quot; pays great attention to the history of China and its surrounding areas, and Chinese overseas immigrants. Writing biographies of modern historical figures is also an extension of this interest, right? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After writing the biography of Liang Qichao and Li Hongzhang, I also want to write the biography of Lin Yutang. The three of them represent the power of the Chinese people. ), idea (concept), and identity (identity). It is estimated that I can write it until I am eighty years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always liked the style of such a magazine. It is a carrier between the academy and mass media. It is very readable, but has a strong academic background behind it, and the subject matter is also very widely. I have always had a strong passion for history. Influenced by Shi Jingqian, I think there should be a kind of historical writing that combines ideological and literary aspects. Historical and biographical writing should be a very important intellectual product of ours. Some eras are the era of poetry, some eras are the era of novels, some eras may be the era of prose or travel writing, and I hope there are still some eras that belong to history and biography writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said that one-way space was opened in Japan, and you also wrote the biography of Liang Qichao As a by-product, what are the difficulties of opening a bookstore in a foreign country? In particular, Japan is a country with a well-developed bookstore and publishing industry and a self-contained system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Talking about by-products is actually a joke. I was trapped in Japan due to the epidemic in 2020, so I wanted to do something. As a result, I was in Tokyo The landlord became a partner in the bookstore. Although there are many bookstores in Japan, there are no good contemporary Chinese bookstores. Seventy percent of the one-way space in Tokyo is Chinese books, and there are also Japanese, English, and Korean books, so it is also an Asian bookstore concept. Just like One Direction in China, it will provide salon activities and is a place for communication. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course there are many difficulties. It is not easy to find a place in Ginza, and the cost is relatively high. I haven’t figured out its business logic yet. In China&#39;s one-way space, we are the exporter and manager of brands. We do not rely on retail to make profits. We are more like a cultural company in a comprehensive sense. This is not the business logic in Tokyo. It depends on whether it can continue to be supported, so it is a very reckless product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Bookstores in the late Qing Dynasty and the Republic of China often had the function of publishing, which was also a new As an information distribution center, have you considered echoing this tradition through one-way space? In the current mobile Internet era, what special role do bookstores play? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;A bookstore is not only a physical space for knowledge storage, but also a place where people gather, knowledge flows, and ideas are produced. It is actually a spiritual place. Community support is very important. Our Tokyo store is launching a membership program, hoping that members can find a sense of community. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In a sense, books and print media have It is called a sunset industry. The &quot;Thirteen Invitations&quot; you made on streaming media has more attributes that correspond to the new media of Liang Qichao&#39;s era. How do you think the two have different meanings to you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In fact, they are not that big of a difference in nature. They are both expressions of thoughts. Of course, different media have different media characteristics. For example, writing is an older medium. It has a closer relationship with my personal heart and my thoughts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Making videos is a product of the team. It can express a certain part of me, but it is often a collective expression. The same goes for companies. In the company, I am one of the founders or the soul, but its entire operation is often beyond my control, and even a process that gradually gets out of control. Writing a book is an act that you can control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Chinese scholar-bureaucrats, they might print some collections of poems and essays by themselves, so in Liang Qichao’s generation, magazines and newspapers were their super new media, with a new issue published every ten days. Tens of thousands of people can see that this impact is very direct and quickly forms a resonance effect. Most of Liang Qichao&#39;s articles are published in newspapers and magazines, which is really like doing live broadcasts and videos now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;And Liang Qichao also faced situations where he lost control, such as a conflict with Wang Kangnian etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, and then he was deceived by the accountant, and the fund-raising was not smooth. He also has to consider operational issues, revenue pressure, pay dividends to shareholders, and what to do if the printing factory catches fire. People tend to overlook one thing. Liang Qichao was a serial entrepreneur. After running &quot;Qingyi Daily&quot;, he started &quot;Xinmin Series&quot;, and then &quot;New Novel&quot; and Guangzhi Bookstore. Moreover, he found investment in both of them, as editor and chief writer. , accounting for 20% to 40% of the shares. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao is mainly a writer and editor. You In addition to content production, there are many commercial activities. Are you bothered by the energy these activities take up? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course sometimes it distracts the energy, but sometimes it also promotes each other, because when you are filming a show or participating in many things in the company, When you are writing, you are often frustrated and distracted, and of course you are also very excited, but when you write, you return to your more focused self. I think that is the avoidance and avoidance of other lives, and some of the chaos you face in daily life. and loss of control, you can also bring it into the book to help you better understand Liang Qichao&#39;s world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Some historical materials have been doubted, and I tried my best to present this doubt&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao created a new style of language through his extensive writing. Our current grammar and language style are influenced by a large number of foreign translations. Some people say that your writing is &quot;translation style&quot;. What do you think of this problem? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Our generation is greatly influenced by translation. Many of the books we read are translated, and we feel the style of translation. of novelty. In fact, Liang Qichao is also a translator and is influenced by many Japanese influences. Not to mention the language of Lu Xun and others during the May Fourth period. The sense of language in our vernacular is produced under the influence of translation, and I feel that there is no longer a pure style that is not affected by foreign languages. In fact, the most important thing is whether you can find the pleasure of reading. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are an experienced media writer. We attach great importance to the readability of public writing, but writing a biography of Liang Qichao requires reference to a large number of academic works and historical materials. Are you worried that for ordinary readers, your biography of Liang Qichao is too difficult, and for academic circles, the information density is not enough? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For scholars, the density of information is also very high. If you look at the various papers we publish, many of them don’t have much information density. When I wrote the biography of Liang Qichao, I used a lot of new materials, but I wanted it to be highly readable at the same time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are some historical materials, such as Feng Ziyi&#39;s &quot;Revolution&quot; &quot;Yi Shi&quot;, its reliability has been questioned by many academic circles, but Feng Ziyi&#39;s interpretation is very dramatic. How do you deal with this type of historical data? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Some historical materials have been doubted. I will try my best to show the doubts about it. Although many of Feng Ziyi&#39;s stories are based on hearsay, many historical materials at that time were based on hearsay, and even less precise materials constituted an important part of the field of that era. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The legend about Liang Qichao, or many legends about his contemporaries, are also historical materials at that time. There is no completely pure hard fact. Just like the two of us talking here today, this A lot of information is being generated in the middle, but it&#39;s not necessarily accurate information. So I think that to understand this diversity of history, the references and doubts about the material itself, you give it a space to unfold, and the readers themselves will feel it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao believed that the 20th century was the era of national imperialism. His thoughts have a strong color of social Darwinism. How do you view the impact of his ideological tendency on future generations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think each generation must solve the problems of each generation. We cannot ask one generation to solve the problems 100 years from now. The prophet will see what his dilemma is, but for Liang Qichao&#39;s generation, the reality he faces is that the country has been humiliated and has entered the bottom of history. Prosperity and strength are their most important goals, and they believe that modern nation-states are participating in The most important role in global competition, so they have to shape a modern nation-state. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for its inherent contradiction and the oppressiveness it may produce, it developed gradually. Zhang Taiyan is more sensitive to this issue. Liang Qichao may also feel this part, but he has his own urgency. The characteristics of each thinker are different, so we cannot require every thinker to make urgent choices and have long-term considerations. Weber saw something longer-term and saw the side of modernity as an iron cage. He was a greater thinker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I think thinkers can only bear the responsibility of thinkers. The formation of an ideological concept in history and its influence on us not only come from the thinkers themselves, but also come from the shaping of subsequent social and educational systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao wandered between traditional Chinese culture and Western knowledge. Most of his descendants are experts in archaeology, aerospace and other fields. But today, our dilemma is that the disciplines are too specialized and territorial, and there is an increasing lack of comprehensive humanities intellectuals like Liang Qichao. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;With the subdivision of disciplines, vertical and horizontal thinkers are scarce not only in China but also around the world. Maybe when the times undergo new and huge changes, everyone is eager for the emergence of comprehensive thinkers. For example, why do so many people around the world want to read Harari&#39;s work? It is not very great or profound, but it has a certain comprehensiveness. He has put forward some kind of response to the pressing issues at hand. This response It will attract a lot of attention. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In public perception, Liang Qichao is a popular figure. A highly narrow-minded person, this year marks the 150th anniversary of his birth, and the biography of Liang Qichao is certainly an important effort to change the public&#39;s understanding of him. Among his numerous writings, which do you think are the most worthy of reading by today’s readers? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Liang Qichao wrote 14 million words, which is very complicated. His experience is as important as his works. His intellectual history works, including three hundred years of scholarship in the Qing Dynasty, as well as essays such as &quot;Young China Theory&quot; and &quot;New People Theory&quot;, are worthy of constant re-reading. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Compared with Liang Qichao, the public’s appreciation of Lu Xun’s works Reading is much more comprehensive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The 20th century is a revolutionary century, and Lu Xun is remembered as a revolutionary writer. Liang Qichao has long been considered a representative of the forces of reform, which was suppressed by the revolutionary narrative. In fact, in Liang Qichao&#39;s era, he was a national writer. From people older than him to his contemporaries, to the next generation of Chen Duxiu, Mao Zedong, and Hu Shi, everyone was reading him. In addition, Liang Qichao&#39;s writing is still in the process of stylistic transformation, while Lu Xun and others have already explored a new way of writing in vernacular. In fact, it is not only Liang Qichao who has been narrowed down, but our understanding of Cai Yuanpei and Lin Yutang is far from enough, so I think more writers should join in the work of re-evaluating and rediscovering them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[叶刘淑仪：“丝绸之路也是全球的品牌”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258784]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/sAEEcUCZ7RvT5tZhDpeM5D15uS9EHUx2Qb4IjhcZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;539&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/sAEEcUCZ7RvT5tZhDpeM5D15uS9 EHUx2Qb4IjhcZ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254332&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yip Liu Shuyi, who wears many hats, is still making waves in the political arena. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before accepting the exclusive interview with Southern Weekend, Ip Liu Shuyi handed over four business cards with the titles of &quot;Member of the Legislative Council&quot; &quot;Chairman of the New Democratic Party&quot;, &quot;Convener of the Unofficial Members of the Hong Kong Executive Council&quot; and &quot;Co-Chairman of the Maritime Silk Road Association&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These identities occupy most of her time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a member of the Legislative Council, when Ip Lau Suk-yee questioned officials in parliament, the officials said they had to &quot;keep their spirits up.&quot; Because the officials were facing a former senior official who had worked in the government system for decades and knew the situation in Hong Kong well. As the chairperson of the New Democratic Party of Hong Kong, Sandra Yip once said that she would promote the development of high-quality democracy in Hong Kong and do her best to serve the people of Hong Kong. With busy affairs and frequent exposure, Ip Liu Shuyi, who wears many hats, is still making waves in the political arena. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, people have mixed reviews about the first woman to head the disciplinary department in Hong Kong SAR. Those who support her believe that during her tenure as the Secretary for Security of Hong Kong, she was decisive, tough and accomplished in many incidents such as the Public Order Ordinance controversy, the issue of right of abode in Hong Kong, and the Immigration Building arson case. The &quot;Iron Lady of Hong Kong&quot;. But it is this tough style that has attracted many voices of opposition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also announced her candidacy for the chief executive of Hong Kong twice in 2012 and 2016. Although they all ended in defeat, the campaign slogan &quot;Win Back Hong Kong&quot; still inspired many Hong Kong people. During the election process, Ip Lau Suk-yee repeatedly emphasized that &quot;if elected, she will take the lead in dealing with Hong Kong&#39;s core governance issues.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How does she view Hong Kong’s unique role on the Maritime Silk Road, and what are her expectations for Hong Kong’s development? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Connecting&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Global&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Friends Circle&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/ strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As one of the Maritime Silk Road Alliance cities, Hong Kong has geographical advantages. How should Hong Kong use the Maritime Silk Road to promote Hong Kong&#39;s economic development and connect the &quot;circle of friends&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ye Liu Shuyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Maritime Silk Road Association I founded was established in 2015. It is the earliest initiative after the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. Hong Kong organizations responding to the initiative. The Silk Road is a very important brand in China and a global brand. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, China was the first to promote globalization and open up to the outside world. Zhang Qian&#39;s expedition to the Western Regions was a great expedition and built a bridge connecting the world. Hong Kong is geographically located in the south and is also a very important node on the Maritime Silk Road. Historically, Chinese merchant ships sailing from China or returning to the sea would usually wait for the northeasterly winds in winter to go out to sea via Tuen Mun, Hong Kong, then sail southward to the Indochina Peninsula and Nanyang Islands, and then to India and the Persian Gulf. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Silk Road is a very important cultural symbol and more soft power should be used to promote it to young people. For example, we arrange free movies such as &quot;Xuan Zang of the Tang Dynasty&quot; for the audience to enjoy, telling the history of exchanges between businessmen who brought Chinese sericulture to the Western Regions and also brought some grape products from the Western Regions to China. Use this soft power to help Hong Kong young people understand China&#39;s great development history and profound cultural heritage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another characteristic of Hong Kong society is that many overseas Chinese, including many large Southeast Asian families, have branches in Hong Kong. The relationship between Hong Kong and Southeast Asia is very good. For example, most of the people in the Philippines are Fujian people, there are Fujian and Teochew Hakka people in Singapore, and there are also many Teochew people in Thailand, and business exchanges are very frequent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I think we should establish an association and alliance to connect the provinces and cities along the Maritime Silk Road and Southeast Asian countries. When we founded it, we hoped to work more on connecting people and educate young people in Hong Kong to understand China&#39;s great history and culture. Therefore, some important activities of the association will arrange for some young college students to travel to countries in the Maritime Silk Road region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is this the &quot;Zhang Qian Plan&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yip Liu Shuyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, learn from Zhang Qian’s brave pioneering spirit. When we were founded, the president of the Dutch Chamber of Commerce was very interested. The end point of the “Belt and Road Initiative” is Rotterdam in Europe, so he was also interested in joining. We have also arranged for college students to go to Guangxi and Guangdong in the Mainland, as well as Southeast Asian countries, such as Thailand, Malaysia, and Singapore. We also went to Djibouti in East Africa and London in Europe. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that at the invitation of a small island in Greece, we arranged for teachers in charge of Chinese culture to go to Greece during the summer to promote Chinese culture and teach Chinese, which was also very popular. However, due to the epidemic, it stalled for three years. This year we restarted and received support from many companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At its peak, this plan sent a hundred students out. Approximately how many people are there this year? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ye Liu Shuyi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are at least a hundred people this year.因为陆陆续续有很多的中外企业参与支持，让大学生有机会去学习、实习，开阔眼界。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了“张骞计划”，海上丝绸之路协会还有什么样的工作思考？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们开展了很多论坛，包括不同的国家以及东南亚国家的论坛。我们的目的，是希望扩大朋友圈。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;软力量”推动中国文化&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如今，湾区的融合互动越来越大，作为海上丝绸之路的协会主席，你有什么相关的计划和设想？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;李特首已经举行了上任以后第一次的粤港研习会议，其中加强科技、金融，人才的交流，文化的加强和交流也非常重要。澳门是海上丝绸之路的一部分，我们也想跟澳门加强合作。同时，希望将来安排多点学生去大湾区学习考察、加深他们对岭南文化的理解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在香港学生对海上丝绸之路的文化，包括中国传统文化的熟悉程度和理解，达到什么样的程度?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得比较遗憾的，是香港的教改。 2009年推出的教改，我觉得走错了路，就好像台湾一样，把中国文化的元素大大减少。因为中史不是必修课，五万多个高考生只有五千人学习中史，学习世界史更少于五千人，学习中国文化典籍的考生只有两千人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我本身是念英国人的学校，但我小时候也念过很多的典籍，包括《经史子集》都读过一点点，现在的学生大部分都没有接触过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们安排了内地春节期间热映的《满江红》给年轻人免费观赏，但是他们不知道故事是发生在什么样的历史背景下，反响也一般。所以我觉得是教育出了问题，但现在已经加强中国历史典籍的教育传授，加强中史以及国情教育的传授，这些具有非常重要的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“香港未来的前途跟中国密不可分”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;作为汇贤智库的负责人，也是海上丝绸之路协会的负责人，同时还是立法委员，也曾担任保安局局长。通过综合身份，你怎么看香港的未来？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很多香港人都不明白，但也越来越多人在明白、觉醒。其实二十多年前，香港还没有回归祖国时，新加坡总理李光耀来香港考察时说，“香港未来的前途跟中国密不可分。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;确实，香港跟国家是风雨同路的。所以我们也很感谢国家不断地支持香港，香港今天稳定安全的局面得来不易。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，虽然《国安法》平息了2019年的骚乱，但是仍然有一些敌对的势力在香港蠢蠢欲动，所以还需要提高警惕。香港还没有为《基本法23条》立法，而澳门已经在2009年完成了这项工作。所以李特首已经表态，这是一个非常重要且需要优先的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你怎么看待香港的危机和机遇?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;中国有五千多年历史，国家有非常古老的一面，也有非常现代先进的一面。比如有部电影《流浪地球》，就充分地表现了中国在科技方面的发展，包括航天方面的不凡成就。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们要向香港年轻人多介绍中国各方面的成就。现在香港有故宫文化博物馆，是一个非常重要的传播载体。另外，香港也举办了如“三星堆”展览，我希望将来能有多一点中国现代化方面的成就在香港展示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实内地文化软力量很厉害。现在很多年轻人包括一些在外国留学的年轻人，也非常喜欢看内地的电视剧，内地的偶像顶流在香港也有市场，而且他们的水平很高。比较现代化的街舞等表演在香港很受年轻人的欢迎，我也希望香港的文化表演团体，能有机会到内地演出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我听说今年过春节时，有一部非常卖座的电影《毒舌律师》是律政片，在内地很受欢迎，所以期待将来香港与内地能在文化方面多点交流。香港是个中西文化交流的中心，我希望未来在这方面，无论是新民党、海上丝绸之路协会，都能为此多做一点贡献。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“超级联系人”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;新民党的主要成员基本上是精英阶层，而且是中产阶级偏上。作为新民党主席，你怎么看待新民党的作用？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;新民党于2011年1月9日在香港正式举行成立典礼，当时只有我一位议员。但在2021年的大选中，我们赢了3个议席，又在2022年的补选中多赢了一个议席。所以新民党现在已经有6位立法会议员，1位区议员。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同的政党都有不同的代表性。当年创党，是因为我觉得香港有一大部分的市民如中产阶级的市民、在国外接受教育的市民，以及思想比较西化的市民，他们都很爱国爱港，但没有党派为他们发声。所以新民党吸纳这些人员，教育水平也都比较高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我跟黎栋国（前保安局局长）是前官，所以我俩有很多公务员支持，包括纪律部队；容海恩议员是一位大律师；李梓敬在美国受过高等教育；陈家珮由地区直选。 2022年补选的、赢得一席的何敬康是澳门原特首何厚铧先生的侄儿，他可以协助我们加强跟澳门的联系，而且他也是留英留美的，非常理解西方的文化价值，有助香港发挥“中介人”“超级联络人”的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;香港特区政府成立以后，你是首位女性保安局局长，现任特首李家超也是保安局局长出身。你们之间有没有怎样的交流与合作？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我跟李家超特首的交往很有趣。我当香港保安局局长时，李家超是有组织及严重罪案调查科的主管，当时他的外号就是“神探”，因为其心思非常缜密。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论他当保安局局长还是当特首，我也跟他合作得很好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在立法会发言前，我会询问李家超一些材料，形成工作默契，为现在的工作配合打下基础。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李特首有一个非常好的本领，他很愿意夸奖他的下属。工作表现好的时候，很愿意表扬他们，肯定其贡献。而且他能团结公务员、议员、行政会议成员。所以李特首上任之后，我们的氛围很好。我觉得2023 年真的是香港随着国家经济复苏，值得拼搏的一年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国内首部放生法规将生效：科学放生才是行善丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258752]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The first domestic local regulation specifically regulating the release of wild animals, the &quot;Guangzhou Wildlife Release Management Regulations&quot;, Will be implemented from November 1, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Releasing animals is a &quot;good deed&quot; in both Buddhism and Taoism. The Buddhist &quot;Brahma Net Sutra&quot; says, &quot;Buddhas should practice the act of releasing lives with compassion... If you see people killing animals in the world, you should rescue them and relieve their suffering.&quot; Taoist classics also include &quot;The Essay on Release of Life&quot; and &quot;The Seven Precepts on Killing.&quot; ” and other scriptures advising people not to kill but to release lives. There are many believers in Buddhism and Taoism in China, so there have been more and more releases of animals in recent years. However, unscientific and blind release will not only fail to bring benefits to the animals being released, but may also cause ecological disasters. It is necessary to regulate release activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The release management regulations formulated by the Guangzhou Municipal People&#39;s Congress first stipulate that the release of all exotic species is prohibited, and lists the alligator gar, leopard catfish (commonly known as &quot;scavenger fish&quot;), Qi&#39;s Key species include tilapia, freshwater white pomfret, mosquito fish, Egyptian frogfish, Thai dace, giant snapping turtle, red-eared turtle (commonly known as Brazilian turtle), and American bullfrog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The release of these exotic wild animals may pose serious threats to native organisms. For example, the alligator gar is a ferocious carnivorous fish with a huge adult size, up to 3 meters. It is said that one can eat all the fish in a lake, and can even bite people. The alligator gar is native to southern North America, but in recent years it has appeared in many places across the country. This kind of fish has almost no natural enemies in domestic waters. Once it overflows in the wild, the consequences will be disastrous. Ruzhou Central Park in Henan once drained 200,000 cubic meters of lake water just to catch an alligator gar. Exotic species such as tilapia and scavengers will also seriously squeeze the living space of native organisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is probably not &quot;good&quot; to release one kind of animal, but bring disaster to other animals or even the entire ecology. In fact, the unauthorized release of alien species has been clearly defined as illegal or even criminal. The &quot;Biosecurity Law&quot; that took effect on April 15, 2021 stipulates that anyone who releases or discards alien species without approval shall be ordered to capture or retrieve the released or discarded alien species within a time limit, and shall be fined not less than RMB 10,000 but not more than RMB 50,000. fine. The Criminal Law Amendment (11), which took effect on March 1, 2021, stipulates that those who illegally introduce, release or discard invasive alien species, if the circumstances are serious, shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years or criminal detention, and shall also or solely be fined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although some species are not from outside the country, releasing them into inappropriate locations may be counterproductive. China has a vast territory and many places have their own unique ecosystems. Species native to one place may not be able to adapt to the environment and die in other places. For example, fish that are suitable for living in warm waters will freeze to death in northern winter. Blindly releasing animals into an environment that is not suitable for their survival will not only make these animals unable to &quot;live&quot;, but will accelerate their death. Some people even take freshwater fish to the sea and release them. This is not releasing them, but killing them. The death of a large number of released animals will also cause environmental pollution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a possibility that native species in one place may become &quot;invasive species&quot; in another place, destroying the local native ecology. Such species from other ecosystems within the territory are essentially invasive alien species to the native ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Guangzhou’s release management regulations require that wild animals suitable for survival in the wild at the release site should be selected, and the number of releases should be strictly controlled without causing harm to the ecosystem. Regulations also require management departments to develop and publish a list of native wildlife suitable for release, from which the public can select species for release. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the choice of species, the release site is also important. Inappropriate release locations, in addition to the possibility that the released animals cannot survive, may also bring danger to humans, such as releasing ferocious and poisonous animals in areas close to human activities. Some people once released venomous snakes and crocodiles in the park, and electric rays and moray eels on the beach, which seriously threatened the personal safety of tourists. To this end, Guangzhou’s release management regulations require the management department to delineate and announce areas suitable for release, and prohibit release outside the release area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The regulations also stipulate the consequences of illegal release. Those who release wild animal exotic species shall be punished in accordance with the provisions of the Wildlife Protection Law; those who release wild animals in places other than the release area shall be fined not less than 2,000 yuan but not more than 10,000 yuan; those who may cause damage to the ecological environment shall be ordered to capture them within a time limit. If damage has been caused, a fine of not less than RMB 10,000 but not more than RMB 100,000 shall be imposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Releasing animals is &quot;good&quot; in religious concepts. However, blind release may not be a good thing, and may even cause serious harm to the released animals themselves, other creatures, the ecological environment, and people. In that case, it is not doing good, but doing evil. It is necessary to regulate the release of animals. Publicity should be strengthened to popularize the knowledge of scientific release, and law enforcement should be strengthened to punish illegal release behaviors to avoid serious damage caused by blind release. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>