<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《等待戈多》作者最喜欢的戏剧来中国，观众看得很精神]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A black box stood on the stage. &quot;Endgame&quot; had not officially started, but the two characters were already inside. Extremely similar clips are repeated over and over again, as if the stage has turned into a machine that plays on a loop due to malfunction. The servant Clover wrung his fingers and walked the same route repeatedly with a strange gait. He stepped back from the door to the right of Master Ham&#39;s wheelchair, walked to the corner on the left, and then to the door on the right, taking fourteen precise steps, every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dialogue has not changed either. &quot;Do you want me to leave you?&quot; &quot;Of course.&quot; &quot;Then I will leave you.&quot; &quot;You can&#39;t leave me.&quot; &quot;Then I won&#39;t leave you.&quot; The door was opened and closed again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1953, &quot;Waiting for Godot&quot; brought Beckett worldwide fame, but his favorite work was &quot;Endgame&quot; written four years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/9nCi5R8eQ6GQ8MC2uGTpV2Pz4rT7J40RVwMq7Zrj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/9nCi5R8eQ6GQ8MC2uGTpV2Pz4rT7J40RVwMq7Zrj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258749&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beckett&#39;s play &quot;Endgame&quot; will be performed at the 10th Wuzhen International Theater Festival in 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the organizer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This play shows four deformed people in an empty house that is approaching the end of the world. : The master Ham is paralyzed from the lower body, blind, and has been sitting in a wheelchair; the servant Clover has a disease in his knees and cannot sit down. Ham&#39;s parents, Nag and Nell, have lost their lower limbs and live in two trash cans. The relationships between masters and servants, husbands and wives, and parents and children all show an extremely cruel side, but they are interdependent and inseparable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the impression of Tobias Bianconi, Director General of the International Theater Association, in the past, the audience&#39;s reaction to Beckett and even absurdist plays was sometimes &quot;very frustrating and unhappy&quot;, but After he walked out of the theater, he found that after watching this version of the Vienna Volkstheater&#39;s performance, the Chinese audience was full of energy and had lively discussions. They all felt that the play was very fresh. &quot;Why is there such a reaction? What is the background that makes the audience like this play so much?&quot; he was curious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 20th century, which experienced the ravages of two world wars and was immersed in industrialization and the post-industrial era, the rationalism admired by Western civilization fell into crisis, belief in God collapsed, and self-doubt and self-denial became the themes of the times. This also brought profound conceptual changes to drama. What Beckett&#39;s drama expresses is the antagonistic relationship between human beings and nature, society, self and others who are completely alienated in social crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Absurd drama, which was born in Paris, France, in the early 1950s, was echoed again in Wuzhen, China, seventy years later. &quot;At the beginning, we thought the most exciting thing was this very unhealthy and toxic relationship. Later we discovered that it had some parts related to war. As it slowly developed, we found that it might be related to climate change. Recently, We found that it was combined with the COVID-19 epidemic.&quot; During the dialogue, theater director and German director Kai Vogels said that this version of &quot;Endgame&quot; has been performed for eleven years. &quot;The point of it being constantly performed is that it is always new. , what we see from this drama keeps changing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18 /yJd8u4hbNeQQHztSBQk6L0OvaD60hZLYPPyafubF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/yJd8u4hbNeQQHztSBQk6L0OvaD60hZLYPPyafubF.j pg&quot; data -key=&quot;258748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beckett&#39;s play &quot;Endgame&quot; was written in the late 1950s. The version that came to China has already been sold in Europe Acted for eleven years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the organizer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vogels refined the four characters into two clown-like people, retaining the main theme A very tense contrast between servants: Ham is physically disabled, but has the power to control Clover; Clough is relatively able to move freely, but is always dominated by his master to do unnecessary trivial things, and his spirit tends to be paralyzed. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most eye-catching adaptation is Vogels’ emphasis on the sense of looping. The line, which was on an infinite loop before the show even started, only appeared once in the original script. Vogels uses this as the opening or closing line of every dialogue, repeating it a dozen times throughout the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A new plot in the play brings an &quot;anti-climax&quot;: after Clover struggled, he shot Hamm, but the expected relief brought by death did not happen. After the monologue, Ham suddenly answered and got up from the ground, as if nothing had happened. Clover and he returned to their usual endless conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Beckett actually demonstrated a ritual cycle on the stage. The ending of this ritual cycle is satisfaction, nothingness, or the end of the world. Everyone can see it differently. Each point has its own interpretation, and what I present on the stage also has this meaning.&quot; At the beginning of the rehearsal, Voges hoped to show the inextricable cycle of repetition on the stage without making the audience feel bored. This balance Feeling is what he is looking for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1998 Vogels has been a theater and opera director in Austria and Germany. German drama is relatively lagging behind in digital innovation. From 2010 to 2020, while serving as the artistic director of the Dortmund Theater in Germany, Vogels began to try to combine digital media with drama and introduce digital thinking to the drama stage. He is a pioneer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among these works, digital techniques such as VR, real-time images, and on-site editing are emerging in endlessly. &quot;Endgame&quot; pursues Beckett&#39;s minimalist style. However, the artificially isolated cramped space, heavy metal-style amplified sound effects, The sudden switching of dazzling lights, the characters&#39; mechanically looping movements and lines, all give this picture of the human spiritual wasteland a cold science fiction color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more traditional images such as &quot;desert&quot; and &quot;dead branches&quot; in Beckett&#39;s original work are missing. In terms of stage design, the play chose a form that abstracted away from reality. Like the door, the few sets and props are all outlined with white chalk lines. Three-dimensional life seems to be locked in two-dimensional space. Machine guns and toy dogs are just thin wooden boards hanging on the wall when they are not picked out by actors and held in their hands. The clock has no hands and the flowers in the vase are out of proportion. The only real objects are the wooden chair with armrests in the center of the stage and the light bulb hanging in the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actors&#39; performances are consistent with German precision, and they achieve the ultimate in repetitive movements with slight changes. The actor who played Ham sat in a chair with his eyes closed throughout the performance, but still showed a strong sense of dominance and oppression in the relationship through his tone and gestures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The voice can be called the third &quot;starring&quot; of this drama, expanding the information and emotional density in the minimalist world. Clough&#39;s footsteps continued to echo in the space, powerful, but as flat as the scenery, with no specific sense of direction. Footsteps create a strong conflict with directionlessness. Every time Clover dropped something he was holding, there was a loud cracking sound, whether it was a telescope, a machine gun, or a toy dog. The laws of the physical world break down here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two people, who are both master and servant and father and son, are imprisoned in a lifeless atmosphere. The room they were in was, in a sense, like the final game board in a chess match. Ham is the general on the chessboard and needs to ensure that he is in the &quot;center&quot; of the room, controlling his pieces. The little soldier Clover could barely move a few steps, but under the command of blind Ham, the situation was certain to lose, but they could not and did not dare to leave the room, just like the chess pieces could not leave the chessboard. &quot;There is no nature anymore&quot; outside the house. Even when I opened the window, I saw &quot;ZERO&quot; written on the blackboard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They passed the time by teasing, controlling, and torturing each other, telling the old stories again, and looking at the window that they had looked at countless times, hoping that something would happen. What happened in front of my eyes was that other people passed by the window. However, their expectations were all in vain, and all their actions no longer made much sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the play, I realized that the beginning was the end. &quot;What time is it?&quot; &quot;Same as usual.&quot; They repeated the dialogue at the opening. Everything stopped suddenly, leaving silence and darkness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冒充专家行医十年，靠秘方自制抗癌药：无证“神医”的罪与罚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260877]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 08:59:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;Miracle Doctor&quot; sells a bunch of titles to patients. Nongjian illustration&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/7306a713b3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;953&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/7306a713b3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;&quot;Miracle doctors&quot; sell a bunch of titles to their patients. Nongjian Illustration&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingdao’s “old Chinese medicine doctor” Hou Yuanxiang, who pretended to be an expert and professor and practiced medicine illegally for more than ten years, fell for his homemade “anti-cancer drug” - in February 2023, Hou Yuanxiang was arrested by Qingdao at first instance The Huangdao District People&#39;s Court of the city sentenced him to 12 years in prison and fined him 12 million yuan for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Hou Yuanxiang, his daughter, son, wife and former son-in-law were also sentenced for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; and were sentenced to prison terms ranging from 11 to 3 years respectively. In addition, the son of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s third sister was also involved in the case. He was sentenced to 11 years in prison for &quot;fraud&quot; and &quot;harboring&quot; in the first instance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total prison term for the above six people is 50 years, and the total fine is 29.8 million yuan. Southern Weekend reporters searched online for judgment documents and found that among counterfeit drug cases in recent years, the first-instance verdict in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s case was extremely rare in terms of heavy sentencing and high fines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the case has not yet been settled. After the first-instance verdict, as Hou Yuanxiang and others filed an appeal, many self-media appeared on the Internet to &quot;cry out injustice&quot; for them. Some associated the case with the &quot;folk traditional Chinese medicine&quot; group, believing that &quot;if this lawsuit is lost, almost all folk Chinese medicine practitioners must close their doors.&quot; (For details, please see the report &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/260879&quot;>;&quot;The Online Public Opinion War on the &quot;Miracle Cancer Doctor&quot;&lt;/a>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s agent The lawyer questioned the characterization of the drugs involved in the case, arguing that after the revision of the Drug Administration Law in 2019, the threshold for identification of counterfeit drugs has been raised. Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine is made of traditional Chinese medicinal materials and should not be identified as counterfeit drugs. Hou Yuanxiang does not constitute “production.” , the crime of selling counterfeit medicines.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 30, 2023, the Qingdao Intermediate People’s Court ruled to revoke the original judgment and remand the case for retrial on the grounds that the first-instance judgment “had unclear facts and insufficient evidence.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;old Chinese doctor&quot; who can&#39;t take the pulse&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After being criminally detained on February 17, 2022, Hou Yuanxiang only stayed in the detention center for more than 20 days. After that, the police changed the enforcement measures to &quot;residential surveillance&quot; because of his illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Gang, the second-instance attorney, met Hou Yuanxiang after the National Day in 2023. According to him, two policemen worked in three shifts, watching him 24 hours a day, &quot;maybe because there are more patients coming to him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, 66-year-old Hou Yuanxiang is from Shandong A native of Yishui County, Linyi City, the province, he once worked as a teacher in the county, but later took a leave of absence without pay and became a doctor. After that, he moved his family to Weifang and settled down. Around 2019, after purchasing real estate in Qingdao, Hou Yuanxiang and his wife and their daughter Hou Jing and his wife both moved their household registrations to Qingdao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang’s confession cited in the first-instance verdict did not explain his medical experience. Some self-media said that Hou Yuanxiang studied under two &quot;famous Chinese medicine doctors&quot; Zhang Moumou and Lou Moumou, but Southern Weekend reporters did not find any information about the latter two as &quot;famous Chinese medicine doctors&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is certain that Hou Yuanxiang is not from a &quot;family of traditional Chinese medicine&quot; or &quot;six generations practicing medicine&quot; as some self-media said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to what Hou Yuanxiang’s wife and sister told China News Weekly, Hou Yuanxiang was originally a primary school teacher and started studying medicine when he was about 40 years old. He had “several teachers” but “all of them are gone.” This relative emphasized that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;excellent&quot; in taking his pulse - he could tell whether it was cancer or what kind of cancer it was by just touching it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a daughter-in-law, Li Jianying told Southern Weekend reporters that she did not know how Hou Yuanxiang learned Chinese medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most patients call Hou Yuanxiang &quot;Professor Hou&quot;, and Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s WeChat signature is also &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. The &quot;Central Health&quot; website, which claims to provide communication, display, and promotion services for &quot;folk doctors,&quot; still has Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s personal introduction, calling him an &quot;international doctor of medicine&quot; and &quot;an authoritative international cancer expert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, his online profiles, including “Professor of Chinese Medical College” and “Doctor of International Medicine”, “are all false” and “are intended to expand influence and make patients believe I&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Hou Yuanxiang did not even obtain a medical practicing certificate. Since the implementation of the Practicing Physician Law in 1999, regardless of whether it is traditional Chinese medicine or Western medicine, all practitioners must have a physician&#39;s practice certificate. Otherwise, it will be regarded as &quot;illegal practice of medicine&quot;, and they will be subject to administrative penalties in the lightest case and criminal liability in the worst case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A patient surnamed Xu testified that she began to seek medical treatment from Hou Yuanxiang in 2014. Since then, she has introduced many patients to Hou, and also asked Hou to attend a consultation at his winery. In 2019, she and Hou Yuanxiang co-organized When he went to the hospital, he found that Hou could not produce his medical license, so he doubted his identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only patients, but also some senior medical professionals had no doubts about Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s identity and ability. According to the first-instance verdict, Hou Yuanxiang had been a doctor at Deyi Hall, a private traditional Chinese medicine hospital in Qingdao for a long time. Later, the person in charge of Deyi Hall asked Hou Yuanxiang to attach his medical qualification to the hospital. However, Hou Yuanxiang refused, and the two parties terminated the cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the testimony of Shen Yufa, director of Zibo Yiyuan Ruikang Hospital, around 2010, he met Hou Yuanxiang at a medical academic conference in Beijing. “Many people attending the conference at that time said that Professor Hou was a doctor of traditional Chinese medicine. He is famous for tumors, cancer, and cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Shen Yufa’s wife got cancer and took Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade medicine. Shen Yufa also hired Hou as a &quot;part-time professor&quot; at Ruikang Hospital and sold Hou&#39;s medicine at the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, Shen Yufa once invited him to sit in Ruikang Hospital, but he refused because he did not have a medical license. The two parties only cooperated on selling medicines. However, Shen Yufa&#39;s son and another employee of the hospital confirmed that Hou Yuanxiang did not attend the hospital regularly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to private hospitals, Hou Yuanxiang has also worked with public hospitals. In 2016, Weifang Municipal Government Hospital, a public hospital, posted on its WeChat official account that Hou Yuanxiang was an &quot;authoritative expert in international cancer research&quot; and would conduct monthly consultations at the branch of traditional Chinese medicine. This article disappeared only recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Patients trust Hou Yuanxiang not only because of his impressive online resume, but also because of his “accurate” pulse numbering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Shijie is a relative of Hou Yuanxiang, a Jilin patient. According to him, Hou Yuanxiang once traveled to Changbai Mountain and hosted meals by himself. Hou Yuanxiang took his pulse on the spot. &quot;I have a friend who has high blood lipids and high blood pressure, and he can detect it,&quot; Dong Shijie told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to the first-instance verdict, Hou Yuanxiang admitted to the investigators that he actually could not take a pulse. The reason for pretending to know the pulse is &quot;to put it bluntly, it is to let the patient buy medicine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he learned that Hou Yuanxiang could not check the pulse, Dong Shijie was shocked: &quot;He is a traditional Chinese medicine doctor. What kind of disease would he treat if he could not check the pulse?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The whole family went into hiding&quot; after the incident&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance judgment, since 2011, Hou Yuanxiang, Hou Jing and others, without obtaining a drug production license, a drug business license, etc., posted Hou Yuanxiang’s false personal profile on the Internet to spread information in many places in Shandong Consulting and selling drugs claiming to be anti-cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hou Yuanxiang’s counterfeit drug case, the first person to be involved was his daughter Hou Jing—like her father, she did not have a medical certificate. On January 16, 2022, after receiving complaints and reports, multiple departments in Huangdao District, Qingdao City jointly conducted law enforcement and captured Hou Jing on the spot. Later, Hou Jing confessed to Hou Yuanxiang, his brother Hou Lei and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, Hou Yuanxiang was at his home in Weifang at the time. He didn’t seem to care at first. It wasn’t until Hou Jing was detained and he was interrogated by the police that he realized the seriousness of the situation and transferred the self-made medicine to Qingdao Clinic overnight. and production tools, but it was too late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court of first instance found that after Hou Jing was detained, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s wife went to the police station handling the case to inquire about information, and &quot;hidden the whole family&quot; after returning home for an excuse. The police then pursued the Hou family online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Lei’s confession, Hou Yuanxiang called him the day after Hou Jing was arrested. &quot;Two or three days later, my father said that this was a serious matter and asked me not to use my current mobile phone and to go out and hide. After hanging up the phone, I took out the phone card and threw it in the trash.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for how Hou Lei participated in these businesses, Hou Lei said that in the winter of 2019, Hou Yuanxiang &quot;asked me to apply for a bank card in the name of my wife Li Jianying... and asked me to pretend Director Li of the hospital, if a patient wants to buy medicine, call me and ask me to give the patient a bank card so that the patient can transfer money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, Hou Jing and Hou Lei had a bad relationship. After Hou Lei knew that Hou Jing was making money, he also wanted to sell medicine with his father. He asked him for the formula many times, but Hou Yuanxiang did not give it. He just asked Hou Lei to follow him and pay him a salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jianying told Southern Weekend reporters that Hou Lei helped Hou Yuanxiang deliver goods in Weifang, &quot;equivalent to a courier.&quot; In the first-instance verdict, Hou Lei was sentenced to &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; according to law, and was sentenced to 8 years in prison and fined 5 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Lei&#39;s confession, after hiding for a few days, he received a call from Hou Yuanxiang from an unknown number, suggesting that he go to the third aunt&#39;s house in Qingdao to celebrate the New Year, and then the whole family went to the third aunt&#39;s house. According to Hou Lei&#39;s confession, because he felt that &quot;the matter was quite serious&quot;, he once suggested that his father surrender. &quot;My father was very angry and said that I was not his biological child.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shuai, the son of Hou Lei’s third aunt, told Hou Lei that he had the connections to settle the matter, but he would need 4 million yuan. After several communications, Hou Lei asked his ex-brother-in-law Fu Songjie to send 2 million yuan in cash to Li Shuai after he had already paid 500,000 yuan. Li Shuai confessed that when he saw Fu Songjie coming to the door with a sack of money, he was stunned: &quot;This is the first time I have seen so much money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Songjie was originally from a district in Weifang City In 2019, he resigned and went to Qingdao at the request of his ex-wife Hou Jing. Before resigning, Hou Yuanxiang approached him and asked him to serve as the legal representative of a private hospital in which Hou was a shareholder. After Fu Songjie arrived in Qingdao, he caught up with the epidemic and had no job, so he helped his father-in-law and his ex-wife, and ended up becoming an accomplice. Fu Songjie was sentenced to 3 years in prison and fined 500,000 yuan in the first instance. The sentence was the shortest among all those involved in the case, and Fu was the only one who did not appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Hou Lei was arrested, he confessed Li Shuai. In the next three days, Li Shuai, Fu Songjie and Hou Yuanxiang were arrested one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Yuanxiang, in addition to the above 2.5 million yuan, Li Shuai also defrauded him of more than 2 million yuan. The first-instance judgment confirmed the matter and stated that &quot;it will be separately investigated and handled by the public security organs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Hou Yuanxiang counterfeit drug case, the police seized a total of 8 houses in the Hou family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In late February 2022, a week after Hou Yuanxiang was arrested, the Ministry of Public Security announced the first batch of eight major typical drug crime cases to be supervised, and Hou Yuanxiang’s fake drug case was among them. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Secret Recipes&quot; of Unknown Origin&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the Hou Yuanxiang case, the medicines that were classified as fake were four self-made medicines by Hou Yuanxiang and his daughter, two of which were named &quot; Anti-Cancer No. 1” and “Anti-Cancer No. 2”. According to Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s confession, these two medicines were made according to a &quot;secret recipe.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Hou Yuanxiang has different opinions on the origin of this &quot;secret recipe&quot;. During the investigation stage of the case, he said that the secret recipe came from one of his &quot;second grandfathers.&quot; This recipe originally contained five kinds of medicine. On this basis, Hou Yuanxiang added shiitake mushrooms, ganoderma lucidum, and cordyceps. &quot;Even if this recipe is my own creation, I I have always wanted to promote this prescription and sell the medicine to make money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, during the trial stage of the case, Hou Yuanxiang’s statement about the “secret recipe” changed—he claimed that the recipe was given to him by his “teacher” at the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang’s different statements about the source of the secret recipe puzzled a second-instance attorney: “Perhaps only he himself knows the truth.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment quoted an attorney of the Hou family According to the lawyer, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s anti-cancer &quot;secret recipe&quot; contains many Chinese medicinal materials such as shiitake mushrooms, cordyceps, Ganoderma lucidum, Prunella vulgaris, black dates, kelp, burdock root, dandelion root, ginseng, astragalus, angelica and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Chinese medicine practitioner who has been practicing for more than 40 years told Southern Weekend reporters that the Chinese medicinal materials in Hou Yuanxiang’s prescription include both “tonifying” and “attacking” ingredients, such as ginseng, Astragalus, when cancer patients reach the middle and late stages, most of them are relatively weak, so it is beneficial to use some tonics; &quot;attack&quot; medicines such as kelp, which has the effect of clearing away heat and dissipating stagnation, is only suitable for some early-stage cancer patients and is not suitable for late-stage cancer patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Hou Yuanxiang’s patients, there are many terminal cancer patients, and some came to Hou Yuanxiang because they were “sentenced to death by the hospital.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from traditional Chinese medicine (TCM), which treats patients according to prescriptions, Hou Yuanxiang’s anti-cancer drugs are prepared in advance, bagged and then sold to patients. According to his confession, around November 2020, Hou Jing purchased a decoction-making machine online. Since then, the father and daughter have taken turns using this machine to make decoctions, &quot;and can make about 80 bags a day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The price of &quot;Anti-cancer No. 1&quot; is 4,620 yuan per serving, and &quot;Anti-cancer No. 2&quot; is 1,920 yuan. One dose is taken for one course of treatment, and one course of treatment lasts for 12 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade anti-cancer drugs, Zhao Yin, a lawyer who graduated from the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine and has worked in the clinical department of traditional Chinese medicine in the hospital for many years, believes that it is definitely illegal. According to her, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self-made medicines are similar to &quot;medical institution (TCM) preparations&quot; in hospitals, which refer to fixed prescription preparations prepared by medical institutions for their own use after approval based on the clinical needs of the unit. However, hospital preparations, like medicines, generally need to be approved by the drug regulatory department before they can be produced and sold. In principle, they can only be produced by the hospital for their own use and cannot be sold externally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin said that after the promulgation of the Traditional Chinese Medicine Law in 2017, the state has relaxed its management of traditional Chinese medicine preparations. Traditional Chinese medicine preparations that only use traditional techniques do not need to obtain a preparation approval number and only need to apply for a preparation approval number. It can be prepared after registration with the provincial drug regulatory department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine has also not been registered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Traditional Chinese Medicine Law stipulates that medical institutions that prepare traditional Chinese medicine preparations that should be registered but fail to do so will be punished as producing counterfeit drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin also doubted whether Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade anti-cancer medicine really contained a sufficient amount of Chinese medicinal materials such as cordyceps claimed in the “secret recipe” because the medicine was made by Hou Yuanxiang and his daughter themselves and there was no formula. The production process standards lack proper supervision and supervision. However, quantitative detection of Cordyceps sinensis is very difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Fu Songjie’s confession, Hou Jing would send Liuwei Dihuang Pills and other Chinese patent medicines to patients together with the boiled Chinese medicine liquid. In Zhao Yin&#39;s view, in this way, even if the patient feels effective after taking the medicine, it may be the effect of the proprietary Chinese medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid the characterization of &quot;fake medicine&quot;, Hou Yuanxiang once tried to defend himself by claiming that &quot;medicine and food have the same origin&quot;, which means that what he sells is food. However, due to the labeling of drug names such as &quot;Anti-cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti-cancer No. 2&quot;, his defense is difficult to establish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin believes that the drug names &quot;Anti-cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti-cancer No. 2&quot; are nondescript, because cancer is a concept of Western medicine, and traditional Chinese medicine generally does not have the term &quot;cancer&quot; or &quot;tumor&quot;. Instead, it is called &quot;accumulation of symptoms.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Hou Yuanxiang’s practice of making homemade anti-cancer drugs, the above-mentioned traditional Chinese medicine doctors interviewed by Southern Weekend reporters called him “too courageous”. In his opinion, many Chinese medicine practitioners have secret recipes. In order not to reveal the secret recipes, they usually only sell the medicinal materials to patients. At most, they cook them for the patients. They certainly dare not make their own medicines and sell them to patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Have any cancer patients been cured?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, supporters &quot;voted injustice&quot; against Hou Yuanxiang on the Internet because he cured many cancer patients. However, a Southern Weekend reporter&#39;s investigation found that it is questionable whether any cancer patients were actually cured by Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the first-instance verdict of the Hou Yuanxiang case, a list of cancer patients who claimed to be &quot;cured by Hou Yuanxiang&quot; leaked online. There were a total of 31 personal information of patients or patients&#39; family members on the list. This list is consistent with that provided to Southern Weekend reporters by Gong Feiyun, one of Hou Yuanxiang’s supporters. According to Gong Feiyun, at the end of June 2023, he went to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang, and it was Hou Yuanxiang himself who gave him this list. Gong Feiyun is a partner of a local traditional Chinese medicine clinic. A few years ago, he was involved in a controversy when self-made medicines were deemed to be counterfeit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters made all 31 calls on the list, of which 11 were not answered and 13 were refused. Of the 7 calls answered, 6 admitted that they were patients on the list or Family members, and another person denied that he was Che Moumou, the &quot;Director of the Provincial Environmental Protection Bureau&quot; written on the list, saying that he was &quot;running business.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 6 people, 3 people refused to be interviewed on the grounds of &quot;something happened&quot; and &quot;privacy involved&quot;, and only 3 people accepted the telephone interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The patient, Song Yuanjia, is from Qingdao, Shandong. He claimed that he was &quot;sentenced to death by the hospital.&quot; He approached Hou Yuanxiang with the mentality of giving it a try, and &quot;it was fine once he tried it.&quot; &quot;It has been 7 years now. Nothing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Yuan’s family told Southern Weekend reporters that Hou Yuanxiang’s medicine was an “ancestral medicine” and he spent more than 200,000 yuan without giving a prescription, first taking “Anti-Cancer No. 1” and “in the end he became poor. Feel better, take &#39;Anti-Cancer No. 2&#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, when Hou Yuanxiang moved his homemade medicine and production tools overnight, he asked the Song Yuan family for help, and the Song Yuan family found a warehouse for him to store the items Hou Yuanxiang moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Yuanjia told Southern Weekend reporters that he had read Hou Yuanxiang’s first-instance verdict, but he was more willing to believe the “crying out injustice” video on the self-media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another interviewee, Wang Jingjiang, is a villager in a village in Zibo, Shandong, and the patient is his mother-in-law. He said that Hou Yuanxiang once planned to build a sanatorium in the village. He was driving for the village party secretary and got to know Hou. Later, his mother-in-law got cancer and there was no possibility of surgery. After undergoing chemotherapy for a period of time, he contacted &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jingjiang said that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine was &quot;good&quot; and his mother-in-law felt &quot;strong&quot; after drinking it. However, she stopped drinking it because she couldn&#39;t stand the taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of lawyer Yang Fengzhu, one of the experts in drafting and demonstrating traditional Chinese medicine laws, Hou Yuanxiang’s “anti-cancer drugs” are several Chinese medicines mixed together. Although Chinese medicine treatments rarely have “immediate results”, they are not It has no effect. &quot;Once you take the (Chinese medicine) that replenishes qi, it will definitely have an effect.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jingjiang also emphasized that his mother-in-law was not &quot;cured&quot;, but &quot;has not (re) committed the crime or been transferred.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third interviewee, Li Cheng (pseudonym), is from Yanbian, Jilin. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the patient was his grandfather, and he had indeed seen Hou Yuanxiang for medical treatment and taken his homemade medicine. The old man passed away in September 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Cheng said that his grandfather was diagnosed with rectal cancer in July 2019 and had spread to the lymph nodes. Relatives introduced him to Hou Yuanxiang. He has never met Hou Yuanxiang so far, and the two mainly communicate through WeChat. He said that after adding WeChat, Hou Yuanxiang once sent his personal profile, &quot;I also searched on Baidu about world cancer, committees, and cancer treatment experts, and I could indeed find this person. I thought this person was quite good.&quot; sharp&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When receiving a call from a Southern Weekend reporter, Li Cheng still called Hou Yuanxiang &quot;Professor Hou.&quot; When he learned that Hou Yuanxiang was not a professor and did not even have a medical license, he was surprised and said that if he had known about this situation, he would &quot;definitely consider&quot; whether to seek medical treatment from Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Cheng said that in addition to drinking Hou Yuanxiang’s anti-cancer drugs, his grandfather also ate the “nutritious meals” recommended by Hou Yuanxiang. &quot;After about three courses of treatment, (grandpa) recovered very well.&quot; Li Cheng said, for this reason, he also introduced many patients to Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Li Cheng could not confirm whether his grandfather&#39;s condition improved for a time. &quot;Whether Professor Hou&#39;s medicine played a greater role or my grandfather&#39;s personal mentality played a greater role.&quot; Li Cheng said, &quot;We all say that (Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine) is effective and easy to use, and it may have played a supporting role in grandpa&#39;s mental state.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Fengzhu has participated in many clinical trial demonstrations of drugs. . In his opinion, when patients undergo treatment, &quot;psychological effects are very important and can affect 30% of the (treatment) effect.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Cheng also said that while his grandfather was taking Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine, he also underwent other treatments, including surgery, and &quot;Chinese and Western medicine worked simultaneously.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;After &quot;slimming down&quot; with fake medicine&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Neither the attorney nor Hou Yuanxiang himself expected that the first instance would impose such a severe sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to relevant legal provisions and the amount of money involved ascertained by the driver’s agency, once Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine is deemed to be counterfeit, the sentence will not be lenient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the first trial, many attorneys representing the Hou family argued that Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine did not cause any harm to the patient. Hou Yuanxiang himself also stated that &quot;children can drink&quot; his medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the lack of any harm does not mean that Hou Yuanxiang does not commit the crime of &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot;, nor does it mean that he cannot be severely sentenced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the criminal law before the 2011 revision, the crime of &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; requires &quot;serious harm to human health&quot; and causing death or serious injury in order to be sentenced to more than ten years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin said that in order to increase the crackdown on counterfeit drugs, the Eighth Amendment to the Criminal Law in 2011 amended the &quot;crime of producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; and no longer included &quot;seriously endangering human health&quot;. &quot;As a threshold for criminalization, as long as the production and sale of counterfeit medicines constitutes a crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the Eighth Amendment to the Criminal Law no longer requires death or serious injury as the only condition for a heavy sentence. It stipulates that &quot;other particularly serious circumstances&quot; can also be harshly sentenced. In 2014, the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate issued a judicial interpretation that as long as the production and sale of counterfeit drugs reaches 500,000 yuan, it constitutes &quot;other particularly serious circumstances&quot; under the Eighth Amendment to the Criminal Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance court determined that Hou Yuanxiang’s production and sales of counterfeit drugs amounted to more than 14.36 million yuan, far exceeding 500,000 yuan. This means that once Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade medicine is determined to be counterfeit, he will be sentenced to more than ten years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine can be recognized as counterfeit medicine must be based on the Drug Administration Law. Zhao Yin believes that before the law was revised in 2019, the identification of counterfeit drugs was relatively simple - as long as the drug did not obtain a batch number, it would be &quot;treated as a counterfeit drug&quot;, thus constituting a counterfeit drug in the sense of criminal law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Drug Administration Law revised in 2019 has made major changes to the definition of counterfeit drugs. Drugs without batch numbers are no longer automatically treated as counterfeit drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The industry generally believes that the above-mentioned modifications to the Drug Administration Law are related to the Hunan Lu Yong case. Lu Yong, a leukemia patient, purchased generic drugs from informal channels and helped his patients purchase the drugs. In 2018, the movie &quot;I&#39;m Not the God of Medicine&quot; based on it was released, triggering widespread public discussion on China&#39;s drug management system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The revised Drug Administration Law stipulates that counterfeit drugs can be classified as counterfeit drugs only under four circumstances (see the information link at the end of the article for details). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Cao Guoying, director of the Beijing Changjiang Pharmaceutical Development Foundation, who has long been engaged in anti-counterfeiting practice and research on drugs, after the revision of the Drug Administration Law, the number of counterfeit drug cases handled by the drug regulatory department showed a &quot;cliff-like decline.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the website of the State Food and Drug Administration, in 2019, the number of counterfeit drug cases investigated and dealt with by drug regulatory departments across the country was 14,041. In the following year after the revision of the Drug Administration Law, the number of such cases There were only 7,361 cases, a decrease of nearly half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from Southern Weekend searched the Judgment Documents Network using the keyword &quot;counterfeit drugs&quot; and found that based on the revision of the Drug Administration Law, the number of judgments in criminal cases of counterfeit drugs dropped sharply from 5,044 in 2019 to 2020. Of the 2,361 pieces, more than half were missing. There was also a downward trend in the following years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2019 version of the Drug Administration Law has significantly increased fines while &quot;slimming down&quot; counterfeit drugs. &quot;The starting point of the fine is 15 times the production and sales amount, and if it is less than 100,000, it will be calculated as 100,000.&quot; Zhao Yin said, &quot;As long as you are producing and selling counterfeit drugs, you will be fined at least 1.5 million, and you will be punished to death (for production, sales, etc.) Selling counterfeit medicines).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Are Chinese medicinal materials medicines? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In Cao Guoying&#39;s view, under the current overall environment of drug counterfeiting, it is &quot;very difficult&quot; for Qingdao to investigate the Hou Yuanxiang case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, whether Hou Yuanxiang should be held criminally responsible for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; has caused controversy in both the legal and traditional Chinese medicine circles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hou family’s attorney cited the revised Drug Administration Law in 2019 as an excuse to believe that Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine is made from traditional Chinese medicinal materials and should not be regarded as counterfeit medicine. Hou Yuanxiang and others do not constitute “production.” , the crime of selling counterfeit medicines.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, according to the first-instance judgment of Hou Yuanxiang’s case, the public security organs initially opened a case against Hou Yuanxiang and others for “illegal business operations.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One month after the case was filed, the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau issued a counterfeit drug identification certificate, identifying Hou Yuanxiang’s four self-made medicines as counterfeit drugs. According to the relevant judicial interpretations issued by the highest law and the highest detection in 2014, it is difficult to determine the &quot;fake drugs&quot; and &quot;inferior drugs&quot;, and the judicial organs can determine the determination opinions issued by the drug supervision and management departments above the city level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the above identification, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot;, &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot;, &quot;liver&quot; claiming to treat liver cancer, and &quot;wild heart brain soup&quot; used to treat heart disease The medicine is identified as a fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the case entered the review and prosecution stage, at the request of the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Huangdao District, the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau specially issued a supplementary explanation to explain why the products involved were identified as fake medicines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Instructions point out that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s four self -made products &quot;no drug registration certificate, no medical institution preparation filing, no drug production license, no medical institution preparation permit, no national standard, etc. Pharmaceuticals that promote the treatment of cancer, liver cancer, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, etc. are sold to patients to cure diseases. P>; &lt;p>; A second -instance agent lawyer pointed out that on the one hand, the above discussion said that the product involved in the case was &quot;in line with the definition of drugs&quot;, and on the other hand, it was &quot;non -drug&quot;. In its opinion, the reason why Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau discusses this is because according to the New Drug Management Law, &quot;the only thing that can be stuck is this one (non -pharmaceutical impersonation).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made medicine identification issues, the reporter from the southern weekend contacted the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau. The bureau refused to interview on the grounds of the Hou Yuanxiang case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the first instance, almost all the acting lawyers of the Hou family questioned the false drug determination of the case. One of the lawyers pointed out that most of the medicinal materials used in &quot;Anti -Cancer 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; were in the 2020 version of &quot;Chinese Pharmacopoeia&quot;, which did not conform to &quot;impersonation of medicines with non -drug&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, in Zhao Yin&#39;s view, Chinese medicinal materials are not of course considered medicines -Chinese medicinal materials are only raw materials for making drugs and can be sold in the medicinal material market. Sale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Where is the medicinal materials used by Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s father and daughter&#39;s self -made medicine? There is no explanation in the relevant confession quoted in the first instance judgment, and Hou Jing cannot provide the purchase of the purchase and legal certification documents. According to Hou Jing&#39;s ex -husband Fu Songjie, Hou Jing&#39;s herbal medicines were sent through express delivery and logistics. The consignee generally used a pseudonym. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Gang, the acting lawyer of the second instance, questioned the fake drugs involved in the case involved in the case of the case, and questioned the fake drug identification letter based on the judgment of the first trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the newly introduced judicial interpretation of the highest law and the highest prosecution in 2022 (the old judicial interpretation of the old judicial interpretation in 2014), the situation of &quot;non -drug pretending to medicine&quot; can only be in the case where there is no controversy. Below, the municipal pharmaceutical regulatory department can be directly identified as fake medicine. For controversy, it is necessary to check or determine the pharmaceutical inspection agency set by the drug supervision and management department of the provincial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Li Gang&#39;s view, the identification of the fake drugs involved in the case of Hou Yuanxiang obviously controversial and should be tested. However, he believes that folk traditional Chinese medicine recipes lack national standards, and even if the results are tested, it lacks scientific and legitimacy. And Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine was not tested at the time, and now it has been seized for more than a year. &quot;It has been deteriorated early, how to test it?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On November 5, 2023, another agent lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang told the Southern Weekend reporter that After the case was returned to the retrial, the procuratorial organs supplemented a lot of evidence to the court, including a inspection report on Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -pharmaceutical. According to this inspection report, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made drug detected the western medicine composition to treat diabetes. The Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau still determined that the product involved was a fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s above -mentioned acting lawyer said that this shows that the pharmaceutical regulatory department may no longer determine the product involved in the case in accordance with the &quot;non -pharmaceutical impersonation medicine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s charges, Yang Zhiwei, a lawyer of Guangdong Fa Quan Law Firm, put forward another point of view to reporters from the south weekend: if Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; are clear and treating cancer &quot;Do not match the world&quot;, Hou Yuanxiang is entirely the purpose of selling medicines, so he may constitute a crime of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the Southern Weekend found such a case on the referee document network: In 2019, Li Mouxiang, who did not qualify for medicine, was arrested for production and sales of fake drugs, but the Procuratorate arrested and arrested him with fraud. The court was sentenced to 14 years in prison for fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Is Hou Yuanxiang suspected of fraud? A reporter from the Southern Weekend asked about a first -instance lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang. After a few seconds of silence, the lawyer asked: Scam? Isn&#39;t that heavier? Later, he said that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;unlikely&quot; to constitute a crime of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another first -instance lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang believes that Hou Yuanxiang constitutes &quot;the crime of obstructing drug management&quot;. The crime was newly established in the 11th Amendment of the Criminal Law issued in 2020. It pointed to the criminal behavior of drugs that did not obtain a batch number but not obtained by the production and sales. light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lawyer did not accept interviews with reporters from the Southern Weekend, but said such a sentence: &quot;If he is sentenced to being innocently guilty of his (Hou Yuanxiang) family, then we can do anything in the name of traditional Chinese medicine to do traditional Chinese medicine. . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti; &quot;>; Data link: Different definition of&quot; fake medicine &quot;before and after the revision of the Drug Management Law: &lt; /span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Before revision: one of the following situations, fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The ingredients contained in drugs are inconsistent with the ingredients specified by national drug standards; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) non-drug pretending to be medicine or pretending to be such medicines. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; A medicine with one of the following situations, according to fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The State Council&#39;s drug supervision and management department stipulates that it is prohibited; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) In accordance with this law, it must be approved without approved production and importing, or it must be tested in this law without testing without testing. ; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot; (3) deterioration; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (4) pollution; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body body body body , Kaiti_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (5) Use the raw material for the raw medicine of the approval number according to this law; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;FONT-FAMILY: Kai, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot; (6) Indications or functions marked or functional beyond the specified range. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; After the following situations: one of the following situations, fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The ingredients contained in drugs are inconsistent with national drug standards; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) non-drug pretending to medicine or impersonating such medicines in other medicines; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (3) spoiled medicine; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font -Family: Kai, Kaidi_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (4) Indications or functions indicated by drugs or functions beyond the specified range. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“抗癌神医”的网络舆论战]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260879]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Hou Yuanxiang was investigated, a large number of videos of&quot; shouting &quot;for them on the Internet appeared on the Internet. Nongjian illustration &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/a383d51fc2.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 953 &quot;data- SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/a383d51fc2.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;258747&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; Text -rign: center; &quot;>; During the investigation, Hou Yuanxiang appeared a large number of videos of&quot; shouting &quot;for him on the Internet. Nongjian Illustration &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A second -instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang admits to the reporter from the southern weekend that for Hou Yuanxiang, who was sentenced to the first instance, the second trial was a &quot;backwater battle.&quot; The second trial of the case can be returned to retrial, &quot;the media has played a great role.&quot; (Report on the Hou Yuanxiang case for details, please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/260877&quot;>; &quot;For ten years of medical practitioners, relying on the secret recipe&#39;s self -made anti &lt;/a>;) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lawyer&#39;s media refers to the Internet self -media. In fact, the media reports of the mainstream institutions reported Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine cases after the second instance ruling was returned to retrial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the help of the media, Hou Yuanxiang, who was originally unknown, was described as a &quot;cure doctor&quot; sentenced by injustice. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Women with a public security background&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In mid -March 2023, the Hou Yuanxiang fake medicine case was judged for more than a month later, and an article entitled &quot;Nine -year -old Xinxin for help: Mom Mom Articles of more than 3,000 cancer patients were sentenced to 11 years, and a fine of 30 million &quot;began to spread online. The article states that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s daughter Hou Jing used the secret recipe of Chinese medicine to heal a lot of difficulty. , The whole family is implicated. There is also a photo of Hou Jing&#39;s 9 -year -old son asking for help: &quot;Why do you sin? Mom, do you have a sin? Let netizens from all over the country comment on you ...&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This article has aroused heated discussion among netizens. The reporter from the Southern Weekend noticed that this article emphasizes that Hou Jing graduated from the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine and was a Chinese medicine division, but he could not mention Hou Jing without a physician&#39;s practice certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s daughter -in -law Li Jianying told the southern weekend reporter that after the judgment of the first instance, Hou Yuanxiang wanted to use the Internet to &quot;call unjust&quot;. At that time, she asked her children&#39;s photos. She was worried that the child would be affected and did not give it. Later, I used the photos of Hou Jing&#39;s son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of June 2023, the media person Wu Pengfei began to intervene in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine. Wu Pengfei claims to be &quot;old journalists&quot; and &quot;well -known online writers&quot;. They have an account number on platforms such as Douyin, Kuaishou, and today&#39;s headlines. A reporter in the Southern Weekend found that Wu Pengfei worked in a media in Hubei Province in his early years and set up a planning marketing company after leaving the media. When he began to intervene in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine, Wu Pengfei exposed a big news: a lady with a public security background had a price of 10 million. She wanted to buy Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s treatment secret recipe. Go to jail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many self -media bloggers quoted Wu Pengfei&#39;s above statement, so that &quot;women with a public security background to buy medicines can not report to Hou Yuanxiang&quot; said that they became the mainstream online public opinion of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Li Gang, a second -instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang, told reporters from the southern weekend that although he heard Hou Yuanxiang said this, he did not see relevant evidence. Control. As a lawyer, he &quot;does not comment&quot; on this statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Zining, the first instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang, also told the southern weekend reporter that the above statement &quot;cannot be reflected in the (case) volume.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The reporter of the Southern Weekend noticed that during the new crown epidemic in 2020, Wu Pengfei had picked up another &quot;divine doctor&quot; -Co Yuehua, who claimed that the injection phenol could cure the new crown, and released the news that Li Yuehua said Li Yuehua He was invited to resist with South Korea, but the news was denied by South Korea. Li Yuehua himself also told the media that he did not know the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the Southern Weekend tried to contact Wu Pengfei, but as of press time, the other party did not reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;How much is the reliability of folk investigation?&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; After issuing the above article, Wu Pengfei has continuously released short videos entitled &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine Injection Cases&quot; on multiple platforms. Now Episode 100 has been broadcast, of which the playback volume of the Douyin platform has exceeded 16 million. In these short videos, Wu Pengfei called Hou Yuanxiang as &quot;Hou Lao&quot;, saying that he was &quot;the first person in traditional Chinese medicine to treat cancer&quot;, with &quot;unique medical skills&quot; and &quot;shocking effect&quot;, &quot;a national treasure&quot;, &quot;on the body&quot;, &quot;on the body&quot; Each hair is gold. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, Wu Pengfei also quoted a set of data to show that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;cure cancer.&quot; He said that &quot;a national folk Chinese medicine organization&quot; investigated the efficacy of the top ten cancer names in China. Only 11 people were cured. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Li Jianying also told reporters from the south weekend that Hou Yuanxiang&quot; cured &quot;1166 cancer patients. &quot;He (Hou Yuanxiang) has records.&quot; She said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Wu Pengfei did not say which institution of &quot;National Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine Organization&quot;. In fact, even Li Gang held a question about the data that Wu Pengfei said: &quot;How much is the reliability of private investigations?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In another short video, Wu Pengfei said that Hou Yuanxiang cured more than 3,000 cancers. patient. In the personal introduction of &quot;Yangtze Health&quot; (a website that provides communication, display, and promotion services), Hou Yuanxiang is &quot;cured more than 20,000 cancer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some media have questioned Hou Yuanxiang from the media, but the click volume is not the same as Wu Pengfei&#39;s short videos. Since the media &quot;Chinese Medicine Chen Lei&quot; posted a video, saying that Hou Yuanxiang was a &quot;liar for sale of fake medicines&quot;, calling on the public to calm down the case: &quot;If the facts are ignored, it is not love Chinese medicine, but it is harming Chinese medicine.&quot; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; After the video was released, &quot;Chinese Medicine Chen Lei&quot; was siege by many supporters of Hou Yuanxiang. Wu Pengfei released 8 short videos to refute. It didn&#39;t take long for the video of &quot;Chinese medicine Chen Lei&quot; to get off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After seeing Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine on the Internet, Qian Hui, general manager of Nanjing Guishi Hall Traditional Chinese Medicine Museum, decided to support it. Qian Hui has experienced similar experiences to Hou Yuanxiang. According to media reports, Qian Hui did not have a physician&#39;s license. In order to avoid &quot;illegal medicine&quot;, his Chinese Medical Museum hired a regular doctor to prescribe prescriptions, and Qian Hui would &quot;guide&quot;. Self -making based on your own &quot;secret recipe&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of 2017, Guishi Hall was reported. Because the batch number was not obtained, its homemade medicine was identified as a fake medicine by the Nanjing Pharmaceutical Bureau. The crime of medicine was once detained by the police, and Qian Hui was locked for 28 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Why do we support Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s innocence? The main reason is from the perspective of protecting traditional Chinese medicine, because once Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s case is guilty, many traditional Chinese medicine can not do it anymore.&quot; To the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gong Feiyun, one of Guishitang&#39;s &quot;partner&quot;, traditional Chinese medicine is &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;, and Hou Yuanxiang is one of many &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;. He defines &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;: The collective name of Chinese medicine outside the system has not received formal Chinese medicine education in universities, and has no physician practicing certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of June 2013, Gong Feiyun went to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang. According to Gong Feiyun, although Hou Yuanxiang had been &quot;monitored and lived&quot; by the police at that time, he was not strict at that time. He tried to make an appointment and made a video. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Gong Feiyun also participated in the mediation of the Guishitang fake medicine. According to him, during the handling of the case, Guishi Hall had a &quot;public opinion war&quot; with Nanjing police: first a media in Nanjing stood on the police stand and exposed the case. the sound of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the end, the case stayed in the public security investigation stage and failed to enter the procuratorate for review and prosecution. After this robbery, Guishi Hall has since maintained the Shanghai market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before Qian Hui and Gong Feiyun, another &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot; supporter Guan Le also supported Hou Yuanxiang online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guanle claims to be &quot;the first principal of the University of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;, &quot;Great Wall inscription character&quot; and &quot;Chairman of the World Chinese Medicine Hall&quot;. He described &quot;the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; as the &quot;Huangpu Military Academy&quot; of folk Chinese medicine. However, the university claimed to be established 3 years ago, but it has not been established so far. Guan Le once publicly said that after the university was established, he will select &quot;Academician of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;, &quot;Doctor of Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; and &quot;Professor of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Related information shows that in June 2020, the slogan of the establishment of &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; just shouted, and Guan Le claimed to hold a establishment meeting of a branch of the university. The day after the meeting, Guan Le released an advertisement for a medical training course in multiple Chinese medicine groups, claiming that no medical foundation can learn on the spot, and the training fee is 18,000 yuan (preferential) for two days. Unexpectedly, this move with the &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine University&quot; was publicly questioned by Gu Jingyu, a doctor of a three -section of Jiangsu family in Jiangsu, and Guan Le responded: &quot;Civil Traditional Chinese Medicine University&quot; is innovation: &quot;Since it is innovation, there must be no certificate. Without a certificate, it must be illegal ... &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After going to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang, Gong Feiyun and Guan Le met in Shanghai. And ask him to speak up in the case of Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On September 9, 2023, the preparatory meeting of the Second Civil Medicine University planned by Guanle was held in Beijing. During the meeting, the Hou Yuanxiang case was discussed during the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;(Hou Yuanxiang case) is equivalent to uniting all folk Chinese medicine.&quot; Gong Feiyun told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the second trial of the Hou Yuanxiang fake medicine, after the re -review was returned, the supporters of Hou Yuanxiang were jubilant, and they released the &quot;good news&quot; online, thinking that the case had a &quot;major turnaround&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Soon after that, there was another news from the media -Hou Yuanxiang was on a hunger strike, and the news was &quot;true.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Wu Pengfei quickly posted a short video to clarify, saying that Hou Yuanxiang could not eat because he was weak, and his apprentice &quot;because he was afraid that someone would hurt Hou Lao and deliberately posted a hunger hunger strike in order to attract the attention of the whole society. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A few days later, Wu Pengfei posted a short video, saying that &quot;Hou Lao&quot; recovered, and began to &quot;drink a little wine&quot; every meal. … &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; According to Li Gang, a lawyer in the second instance, after the second trial retracement, because &quot;too many people who knew (Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s original surveillance residential place)&quot;, the police replaced Hou Yuanxiang for a place to perform surveillance and residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;I no longer participate in this matter&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng (pseudonym) is the grandson of a patient with a Jilin cancer patient in Hou Yuanxiang. In the case, he also participated in the public opinion battle for Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 8, 2022, after Hou Yuanxiang filed a appeal, a WeChat person named &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; added Li Cheng&#39;s WeChat, claiming to be the daughter -in -law of &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Can you write a joint letter to Professor Hou for a love?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;What happened to Professor Hou?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I was reported by others , Now I still can&#39;t take my own medicine in the hospital. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng knew that Hou Yuanxiang had an accident. He told&quot; Meteor and sunset &quot;that he could help Hou Yuanxiang write a joint letter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Two months later, &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; pulled Li Cheng into a WeChat group that supported Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng&#39;s mobile phone has a number marked as &quot;Director Li&#39;s anti -cancer&quot;, which was given by Hou Yuanxiang. He bought medicine for Grandpa to contact this &quot;Director Li&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before receiving a call from a reporter from the Southern Weekend, Li Cheng always thought that &quot;Director Li&quot; was called &quot;Li Jianying&quot; and was the person in charge of the medicine of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But in fact, &quot;Director Li&quot; is Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s son Hou Lei, &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; is Li Jianying. She is also the only one among all the Hou family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the judgment of the first trial, in the case of Hou Yuanxiang, Hou Yuanxiang said that &quot;Professor Hou&quot; was responsible for providing formula, diagnosis and treatment of cancer diseases, and selling medicines. Chinese herbal medicine, boiled Chinese medicine, etc., his son Hou Lei was pretending to be responsible for taking the medicine and returned medicine &quot;Director Li&quot;, which is Li Jianying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After more than a month of WeChat with &quot;Meteor and Santa&quot;, Li Cheng and Hou Yuanxiang also contacted. &quot;He (Hou Yuanxiang) said that putting my information on the Internet, I said, as long as it is helpful to your case.&quot; Li Cheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng also suggested that Hou Yuanxiang talked about this on the self -media platform to increase attention. &quot;He said, let me let the family get it at home.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Later, Hou Yuanxiang sent some case materials to Li Cheng to help him contact the media. There have been no news since then. Li Cheng failed to help Hou Yuanxiang contact the media. Until late 2023, he sent a message to Hou Yuanxiang. &quot;He gave me a sentence and said that (second instance) was about to open the trial, the problem was not big.&quot; This is Li Cheng&#39;s last contact with Hou Yuanxiang. Prior to this, the Hou family proposed that Li Cheng&#39;s personal information was put on the Internet as one of the cases of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s &quot;cure&quot; cancer patients, and he agreed. However, before the list was sent to the Internet, Li Cheng&#39;s grandfather died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After knowing the truth, Li Cheng realized that things were &quot;not so simple&quot; - &quot;I don&#39;t know these, I don&#39;t know at all. Let&#39;s help, but the premise must be within the framework of the law ... I no longer participate in this matter. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[床虱危机或已蔓延至香港：为何太阳晒不倒，杀虫剂无效？丨硬核唠科]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260875]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[同性性行为进化的逻辑]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260881]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Same-sex sexual behavior cannot directly produce offspring, and has long been regarded as a paradox of Darwinian evolution. . Because according to general understanding, in nature where natural selection and survival of the fittest occur, same-sex sexual behavior consumes precious energy and time but fails to produce offspring. Such behavior should have been eliminated in evolution, but the reality is that same-sex sexual behavior is still in the process of evolution. There is no shortage of them in nature and human society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists have discovered same-sex behavior in more than 1,500 species of animals. Such behavior is not affected by gender and can occur between two males or two females. It appears in artificial breeding environments and also in the wild. It is not an accidental behavior forced by extreme environments. This also poses a difficult problem for scientists to understand its evolutionary logic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, researchers from the University of Granada in Spain and other institutions tried to verify some relevant explanatory hypotheses through germline analysis of a large number of mammal same-sex sexual behavior information. Their latest research, published in Nature Communications, suggests that the evolution of same-sex sexual behavior is likely an adaptation to nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Maintaining same-sex social relationships&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Same-sex sexual behavior occurs in many mammalian species, including our relatives the great apes. Rather than classifying it as maladaptive or abnormal behavior, our study shows that this sexual behavior in mammals is a convergent adaptation that helps maintain social relationships and reduce same-sex conflicts.&quot; Lead author of the latest study, while at the Spanish Arid Zone Experimental Station Function and Evolution José M. Gómez, a professor at the Department of Ecology and the University of Granada, told Southern Weekend reporters that although same-sex sexual behavior occurs in many species, it is especially common among primates. This may Precisely because primates are more social than many other groups of mammals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a data point of view, research has found same-sex sexual behavior in more than 260 species of mammals. In more than 80% of the cases, it takes the form of back crawling or genital contact, and less than 30% Some species even display same-sex behavior through courtship or pairing. Judging from the age, same-sex sexual behavior mainly occurs in adult mammals, and young same-sex sexual behavior is only found in 10 species of animals. From an environmental perspective, more than 80% of the samples had same-sex sexual behavior occurring in wild or semi-wild environments. In terms of gender, same-sex behavior is relatively evenly distributed among mammals. Female same-sex behavior has been recorded in more than 160 species, and male same-sex behavior has been found in more than 190 species. Combined, about half of all species have same-sex behavior. Homosexuality involving two genders at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the latest study is only based on existing records of same-sex sexual behavior in mammals and does not represent the entire situation of mammals. In fact, because the discovery of same-sex sexual behavior in nature relies on observation, and in some species females and males look very similar, and it is even difficult to distinguish between male and female. Some scientists estimate that the current records of same-sex sexual behavior in nature should be underestimated. Moreover, compared with mammals, birds, reptiles, fish, insects and other invertebrates are either small in size or live far away from the ground, making observation difficult, but they have all recorded same-sex sexual behavior. Therefore, patterns of same-sex sexual behavior in nature are far more complex than what has been observed in mammals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, many hypotheses interpreted same-sex sexual behavior as maladaptive or abnormal behavior, speculating that this behavior may be a manifestation of specific conditions such as incorrect gender identity, lack of opposite-sex peers, or frustration with opposite-sex sexual behavior. From the perspective of sexual behavior scenarios, the latest research has found that same-sex sexual behavior does not necessarily require extremely special occasions. Although same-sex sexual behavior is rare in some species and can only be observed in very special circumstances, for about 40% of the mammals studied, same-sex sexual behavior can be regarded as moderate to high frequency activity during a specific period of time, and during mating Seasons are easy to observe. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Same-sex and opposite-sex coexist&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;And some behavioral observations have long shown that same-sex sexual behavior may play a positive role in some populations. For example, some same-sex behavior among male bottlenose dolphins may help strengthen alliances among small groups, and same-sex behavior among female bonobo groups may promote reconciliation among members. However, the latest study&#39;s germline analysis does not focus on the mechanisms of same-sex sexual behavior in specific species, but uses large-scale statistics to link same-sex sexual behavior to social behavior. This research shows that same-sex sexual behavior is similar to many other behavioral traits that have evolved through natural selection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Jose Gomez reminded that the meaning of same-sex sexual behavior here should be understood within the framework of evolutionary biology, which is still different from the current human society’s views on gender and other related issues. Because in the study of evolutionary biology, same-sex sexual behavior is a temporary behavior of individuals in a certain period of time, not a permanent behavior or life choice. They may also have heterosexual sexual behavior at the same time. Therefore, it cannot be directly related to human society. behavior analogy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In human society, issues related to same-sex sexual behavior are rooted in different cultural environments and historical traditions in different places, and are more complicated to understand. But in recent years, the discussion of distinguishing human same-sex sexual behavior has also attracted the attention of scientists. The core concern is to what extent people who have had same-sex sexual behavior can be defined as homosexual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, researchers from Harvard University and other institutions published a large-scale genetic study in Science magazine, trying to reveal the genetic characteristics of same-sex sexual behavior, which is the so-called &quot;homosexuality&quot; Gene&quot;. Through collaboration with the British Biobank and genetic testing analysis company 23andMe, researchers finally identified multiple genetic loci related to same-sex sexual behavior from hundreds of thousands of genetic samples, indicating that the &quot;gay gene&quot; is similar to other behavioral traits. It is also polygenic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in 2021, scientists from sex and gender research institutions such as Indiana University’s Kinsey Institute publicly expressed opposition to this research, believing that it only distinguishes people by whether they have had same-sex sexual intercourse. It conflates heterosexuality, bisexuality, and homosexuality, and does not accurately measure people&#39;s sexual behavior, sexual attraction, and sexual identity. Therefore, the genetic characteristics ultimately discovered may not reveal the tendency to have same-sex sexual behavior, but only reveal the preferences. The personality trait of pursuing novelty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because in the view of sexology researchers, heterosexuality should be a continuous pattern of sexual attraction. Just because a person has had same-sex sexual behavior does not mean that he is not heterosexual. Alfred Kinsey, the pioneer of sexology research, developed a scale very early to distinguish people who have had same-sex sexual behavior. According to the frequency of same-sex sexual behavior, people can be divided into multiple types, rather than Either gay or straight. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It may help reproduction&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The controversy in human society about how to distinguish same-sex sexual behavior from homosexuality also reflects a difficulty in understanding the logic of evolution to a certain extent. Compared with human society, which highly binds concepts such as &quot;same-sex sexual behavior&quot;, &quot;homosexuality&quot; and &quot;no offspring&quot;, same-sex sexual behavior may never mean &quot;no offspring&quot; in the long evolutionary history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Darwin&#39;s paradox of evolution should be put aside; it no longer exists because the existence of bisexual behavior in various animal species ensures that same-sex behavior does not hinder reproductive success.&quot; Empire Vincent Savolainen, a professor at the Department of Life Sciences of the Polytechnic Institute of Technology, told Southern Weekend reporters that there are many concepts surrounding same-sex sexual behavior, but from a biological perspective, same-sex sexual behavior may be the same as homosexuality, bisexuality, etc. There are some similar mechanisms and evolutionary logic, which biologists can continue to study in the future. At the same time, psychologists can also delve into other aspects of this complex behavior, such as sexual preferences, to better understand the evolution of same-sex behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a historical perspective on same-sex sexual behavior, the key reason why evolutionary logic is difficult to understand lies in the inference that its adaptation costs are too high and the cost of behavior is too high. However, including the latest research, many studies in recent years have shown that same-sex sexual behavior does not mean &quot;no offspring&quot; in the evolutionary process, but may have a positive impact on the reproduction of offspring in other indirect ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, Brendan Zietsch, a scientist at the Center for Psychology and Evolution at the University of Queensland in Australia, used genetic data from hundreds of thousands of samples to simulate human evolution, which also included a large number of heterosexual Partner data. The analysis shows that among people who only have heterosexual sex, genetic genes related to same-sex sexual behavior can allow people to have more opposite-sex sexual partners at the same time, which means that they have gained a sexual mating advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further analysis shows that this is also related to the personality traits of openness and risk-taking. People who are more open-minded will be more willing to try new things and have greater curiosity and imagination. Researchers speculate that genes related to same-sex behavior not only endow people with same-sex sexual tendencies, but also give people relevant personality traits, which gives people with relevant genetic genes an advantage in finding opposite-sex partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thus, although same-sex sexual behavior itself does not produce offspring, related genes can give people the advantage of having offspring, resulting in same-sex sexual behavior being preserved to this day in the long evolution. However, Brendan Zic emphasized to Southern Weekend reporters that although this study has data advantages, the relevant explanations are still exploratory, and more research is needed to gain an in-depth understanding of the manifestations related to same-sex sexual behavior in order to understand the basis of its evolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Heritability in primates&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Professor Vincent Savolainen has also conducted research on same-sex sexual behavior and reached similar conclusions supporting reproductive advantages. . In August 2023, through the analysis of three years of detailed observation data of rhesus monkeys, they found that same-sex sexual behavior is very common in the rhesus monkey community and is basically not affected by factors such as age or community structure, and it does not bring any consequences to them. What fitness costs, conversely, same-sex sexual behavior regulates peer relationships and increases reproductive success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant research was published in Nature Ecology &amp; Evolution, observing the social and sexual behavior of more than two hundred male rhesus monkeys. Combining ancestry data from decades ago, the study shows that same-sex behavior in male rhesus monkeys is both repeatable and heritable, with a heritability rate of 6.4%. This provides the first evidence of same-sex behavior in primates outside of humans. The first evidence that behavior is heritable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Rhesus macaques share more than 70% of their DNA with humans and have a common ancestor with us dating back about 25 million years. They are the main non-human primates used in biomedical research Animals are also excellent models for studying behavioral ecological issues such as same-sex sexual behavior. However, it is worth noting that there are still differences between rhesus monkeys and humans. Through research, we hope to unravel these intricate mysteries and discover the underlying Common behavior in our evolutionary history.&quot; Professor Vincent Savolainen explained to Southern Weekend reporters that the latest research shows that same-sex sexual behavior may be a common feature of primate reproductive ecology, which is important for understanding the behavior of human groups. Same-sex sexual behavior has certain enlightenment, but due to the influence of some unique social factors in human society, same-sex sexual behavior in human society does have a high cost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Humans appear to be the only species that exhibits strict homosexuality.&quot; Professor Vincent Savolainen said cultural factors can influence this phenomenon. For example, in Samoa, some gay men, although they have no offspring, actually assume the role of women in society and help raise the children of relatives. &quot;I hope our research can play a role in fostering a more inclusive culture that embraces gender diversity, both in nature and in human society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 22:25:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网购二手“人脉”真的靠谱吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260873]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[不在职业资格目录中的“律师经纪人”，3860元拿证]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260871]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lawyers and brokers&quot; have appeared in many lawsuits related to contract disputes. (People Visual courtesy)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Lawyers and brokers&quot; appear in many lawsuits related to contract disputes. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 14, 2023, a recommendation letter issued by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association was circulated in the legal community. The letter showed that the association recommended a &quot;lawyer broker&quot; to the Haicheng City People&#39;s Court as a litigation agent in a loan dispute case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the letters of recommendation were made public, many lawyers posted on social media to express concerns that lawyer brokers might corrupt the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lawyer broker&quot; is not the first time that &quot;lawyer broker&quot; has appeared. With this keyword, 27 civil and enforcement cases can be retrieved on the Judgment Document Network. Among them, 24 cases in which lawyers and brokers acted as litigation agents were heard by courts at all levels in Liaoning Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is certain that lawyer brokerage should be a job type &quot;created&quot; by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association. The association recommends others as litigation attorneys in the name of social groups. However, relevant legal persons pointed out that the operations of the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association violated relevant legal regulations, and there are no occupations related to &quot;lawyer brokerage&quot; in the national professional qualification catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After this matter was fermented in the legal community, the local lawyers association issued a reminder: Lawyers discovered the problem of &quot;lawyer agents&quot; and &quot;legal agents&quot; when performing their duties. You should raise objections to the case-handling agency where you are located, and do not participate in the operations of relevant companies or institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;For each case represented, 500 yuan is required to be paid to the association&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;In past cases, &quot;lawyer brokers&quot; mainly appeared in insurance disputes, contract disputes, and private lending disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a motor vehicle traffic accident liability dispute ruled by the Yuhong District People&#39;s Court of Shenyang City in March 2023, Xiao drove a passenger car and rode an electric bicycle and ran a red light. Yang Mou collided, causing Yang to be injured. Yang then sued Xiao and the two insurance companies that Xiao insured, demanding various compensations totaling about 250,000 yuan. Both of Yang&#39;s litigation attorneys are &quot;lawyers and agents.&quot; In the end, the Shenyang Yuhong District Court ordered the insurance company to pay compensation of about 120,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a contract dispute with the case number (2022) Liao 14 Min Zhong No. 1093, Yang and Liu signed a tableware factory transfer agreement, stipulating that Yang A certain person paid the transfer fee of RMB 170,000 in installments, but after the first payment period expired, Yang did not pay as agreed. Liu then sued Yang to perform the contract and pay liquidated damages, totaling about 200,000 yuan. Yang lost the case and appealed to the Huludao Intermediate People&#39;s Court, entrusting a &quot;lawyer agent&quot; to serve as his litigation agent. The Huludao Intermediate People&#39;s Court did not support Yang&#39;s appeal, and the second instance upheld the original verdict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The similarity between these cases is that the &quot;lawyers and brokers&quot; who represent the cases come from the same social organization: the Lawyers and Brokers Special Committee of the Liaoning Brokers Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The National Social Organization Credit Information Disclosure Platform shows that the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association was registered and established in 2007. Its supervisory unit is the Liaoning Provincial Supply and Marketing Cooperative Federation, and its business scope In order to guide the work of the brokerage industry in the province, organize broker business training and provide legal, policy, information consulting services, etc. to brokers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Special Committee for Lawyers and Brokers is a subsidiary organization of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association. The association stated in the &quot;Instructions for the Liaoning Provincial Broker Qualification Certificate&quot; that, Possessing the Liaoning Provincial Broker Qualification Certificate can solve the problem of agency litigation qualification: you only need to pay 3,860 yuan once, and you can obtain the certificate after training and examination. &quot;You can pass the test without a legal basis.&quot; After that, you can act as an agent in civil litigation in Liaoning Province. cases, and engage in related activities such as appearing in court to respond to lawsuits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, those who have obtained the broker qualification certificate need to pay 500 yuan to the association to issue a recommendation letter for each case they represent. In addition, the broker&#39;s qualification certificate needs to be inspected every year, and the fee is 50 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Obviously different from citizen agents&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lawyer broker The events have once again put citizen agency in the spotlight. However, attorney-broker representation cases initiated by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association are significantly different from normal citizen representation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the amendment of the Civil Procedure Law in 2012, the law allowed three categories of citizens to represent civil litigation cases: close relatives of the parties, relevant social groups or employees of the unit where they work. persons; other citizens entrusted by the parties concerned and approved by the People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Zhiwei, deputy director of the Supreme People&#39;s Court Applied Law Research Base of Southwest University of Political Science and Law, said that the quality of citizen agency services is poor, fees are irregular, and it is easy to breed judicial rent-seeking, Regarding issues such as bribing judges, when the Civil Procedure Law was revised in 2012, &quot;other citizens permitted by the court&quot; were deleted, and the scope of citizens as entrusted litigation agents was limited to two categories: close relatives or staff of the parties; communities where the parties are located, Citizens recommended by units and relevant social groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Further requirements for community recommendation can be found in the interpretation of the Supreme People&#39;s Court on the application of the Civil Procedure Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It stipulates that if relevant social groups recommend citizens to serve as litigation agents, the groups should be non-profit legal persons registered and established in accordance with the law. The principal shall be a member of a social group, or the domicile of one of the parties shall be in the area of ​​activity of the social group. In addition, the recommended person should also be the person in charge of the society or a staff member who has a labor relationship with the society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with relevant regulations, Wu Zhiwei believes that strictly speaking, the behavior of the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association violates the provisions of Article 87 of the Judicial Interpretation, &quot;These people do not Qualified to act as an agent in legal matters.&quot; The agency affairs must fall within the business scope specified in the articles of association of the social group. The business scope of the broker association is generally related to brokers. However, judging from the currently public judgment documents, the client in the case is not Brokers, &quot;If brokers have relevant civil disputes, they act as litigation agents, which is in compliance with the regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another question is whether social groups can provide paid services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As early as 1993, the Ministry of Justice issued the &quot;Reply on Individual Citizens Not to Engage in Paid Legal Services Without Approval&quot; which explicitly required that citizen agents No remuneration can be collected. According to relevant regulations, travel expenses in citizen representation can be reimbursed by the parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But lawyers and brokers obviously charge fees. On November 14, 2023, the verdict of a contract dispute in Liaoning Province was circulated in the lawyer community: a lawyer and agent was sued by the client for failing to perform his obligation to appear in court in a previous divorce lawsuit, and requested the return of 5,000 yuan in legal services. fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Tips for Social Organizations to Carry out Legal Service Activities&quot; issued by the Social Organization Administration Bureau of the Liaoning Provincial Department of Civil Affairs on March 22, 2023 has mentioned that individual Social organizations illegally recommend citizens to act as agents in lawsuits and seek unfair economic benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This reminder sheet mentions that in accordance with relevant regulations, law-related social organizations strictly implement a management system with dual responsibilities between the registration management agency and the business supervisory unit. Social organizations shall carry out activities in accordance with the purposes and business scope stipulated in their articles of association and shall not engage in for-profit business activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Not in the National Vocational Qualification Catalog&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although Liaoning Province The Brokers Association has issued lawyer broker qualification certificates to many people, but the profession of &quot;lawyer broker&quot; is not included in the &quot;National Vocational Qualification Catalog&quot; announced by the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security in 2021. The professional qualifications stipulated in this catalog all specify the implementing departments or units, and require that no other institution or unit can set up professional qualifications for implementation on its own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend called Chen Wencheng, president of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association, on related issues. He first stated that he could only undertake work in Liaoning Province. However, he later stated that he currently does not directly engage in civil litigation, nor does he engage in lawyer-broker-related business. As of press time, the association’s official website is no longer displayed properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 16, Southern Weekend reporters called the Liaoning Provincial Department of Justice several times. The operator said they did not know anything about &quot;lawyers and brokers&quot; and that they could consult the local authorities for specific information. Lawyers Association. Southern Weekend reporters called the Liaoning Provincial Lawyers Association several times but received no reply as of press time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to upstream news reports, relevant staff of the Liaoning Provincial Department of Civil Affairs responded that they would investigate the situation related to the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, the Beijing Tongzhou District Lawyers Association issued a reminder that if lawyers discover problems with &quot;lawyer agents&quot; and &quot;legal agents&quot; when performing their duties, , you should raise objections to the case-handling agency where you are located, and do not participate in the operations of &quot;legal brokers&quot;, &quot;lawyer brokers&quot; and other related companies and institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Liaoning Province, Fushun Civil Affairs Bureau, Tieling Civil Affairs Bureau and other agencies have issued similar reminders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国人的家当]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2003, I have been shooting the &quot;Inheritance&quot; series 20 years, a total of 148 works. I moved a family&#39;s belongings stored in different spaces into the same space and posed for photos with their owners, most of which were taken outdoors with the home as the backdrop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;90% of my past works were shot in China. It was a period of rapid economic development and modernization and globalization in China. I used this special Recorded by posing, the real internal space is briefly exposed in the external space, combining the changes in the current environment, urban expansion, technological development, and changes in people&#39;s lifestyles to create a dynamic social picture with static documentary . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, I started photographing American families. Home is the smallest unit that makes up society, and many such units make up the entire society. I continue to use the &quot;Household Possessions&quot; series to reflect the internal structure and diversity of contemporary American society. I have observed that the basic material living standards of American families, regardless of urban or rural areas, are not much different, so I pay more attention to showing their spiritual attributes. I spend a long time preparing for each photo, learning the characters’ stories in advance, visiting their rooms, thinking about the purpose of the shoot, and carefully selecting items for display. The choice of family covers both native Americans and immigrants who miss their hometown, as well as concepts about love, career, identity and gender, and the passage of time. The objects in each picture have been carefully arranged, using materials to reflect spiritual life. I moved these spiritual items in space and placed them in the same picture to visually enhance the common scenes. , highlighting the current living conditions, beliefs and emotional memories of this family or individual, and using a photo to outline a combination of reality and the spiritual world. Readers can directly think through the photos and their stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thank you so much to the families who were willing to face my camera, show off their possessions, and share their stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Whitney Jensen August 2022&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 16/cbb711c0c3.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/cbb711c0c3.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Whitney Jensen August 2022&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Whitney Jensen, 36 years old. She was a very cheerful and enthusiastic woman who was born and raised in Galesburg, Illinois, USA. She traveled to Iowa, fell in love and got married while traveling, and worked in the hospitality industry for many years. When the marriage ended and the coronavirus pandemic hit, she moved to Peoria, found work as a photographer, and was profiled in magazines while taking pictures in the park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She currently works as a salesperson in a BMW store. She also enjoys interior design and creates small art installations of her own. In addition to her job at the BMW store, she has other part-time jobs, including helping out at a non-profit organization and performing poetry readings every Thursday night at the Contemporary Arts Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many of Whitney&#39;s belongings come from family members, such as her grandma&#39;s antique box and her cousin&#39;s old sofa who was shot. She is full of affection for these items and is closely related to her. A friend who she grew up with gave her an owl necklace with her first month&#39;s salary, and she has been collecting all kinds of owls ever since. Her name Whitney itself means wise owl, which was the name given to her by her aunt. She was born during the era when singer Whitney Houston was most popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;George, the Shoeshine Man February 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/bef1b74cca.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/bef1b74cca.JPG &quot; data-key=&quot;258479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;George, the Shoeshine Man February 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;George Manias, 92, celebrated his 76th working anniversary with friends, family and customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He has worked for U.S. Presidents Gerald Ford, Ronald Reagan, George W. Bush, Bill Clinton, Barack Obama and Joe Biden, every Illinois governor since 1952, every Peoria mayor since 1957 and many celebrities, diplomats and businessmen have polished their shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1931, George was born in Peoria, Illinois, USA. His parents were Greek immigrants. When he was four, he returned to his parents&#39; native island of Crete, which the Nazis had occupied. George was captured and forced to carry water for the Germans barefoot and starve. After World War II, George and his family returned to Peoria in 1946 penniless. At the age of 15, George began working as a shoeshine boy to earn money to help his family. Through hard work, George used the money he saved to buy a store named &quot;George&#39;s Shoe Shine and Hat Shop.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;George won many honors and medals, and his decades of hard work were praised by visitors from around the world. George treated everyone equally, and treated shoes regardless of whether they were high or low. He rubbed shoe polish on the leather with his bare hands. As for other secrets, he thought it was too early to reveal them now. Every January 1st, George would write the year on a brick for good luck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now he works four hours a day, five days a week, and his 86-year-old brother Manny accompanies him every day. He considers the chairs in this room to be his most important possession; it is a place where he meets people and unites the community. In addition to his shoe polishing tools, there are photos of him with six U.S. presidents and dignitaries. George never married. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Colleen Johnson June 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 5d4803a8f6.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/5d4803a8f6.JPG&quot; data- key=&quot;258480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Colleen Johnson June 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;Colleen, 58 years old, her husband passed away due to illness a few years ago and currently lives alone. She works as the director of development for a software, website design and networking company in downtown Peoria. She was often active in events commemorating historical events, particularly the abolitionist movement and the Civil War, and she spoke on behalf of racial equality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Colleen loves old furniture and heirloom items, some of which are Asian antiques from her grandmother&#39;s collection. She loved bringing nature into the house and collected art and decorations mostly related to plants and animals. Her decorations are often paired, with lotus, leaves, and bird elements recurring, and the green plants and flowers she raises are also often paired. She likes to keep and recall beautiful things. Among these souvenirs are the dolls handmade by her grandmother, the quilts made by her mother, and the shirts of her late husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Colleen is a mother and grandmother in life. Her son and daughter-in-law live in another city 90 minutes away. Their daughter is 3 years old. There is also a son on the way. Colleen has an adorable Yorkshire terrier named Toto who enjoys the joy of a new life. Colleen enjoys walking and exercising by the river and participating in sailboat racing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She has just started a new relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Prasanna Jeer 2023-4&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 536232ce15.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/536232ce15.JPG&quot; data- key=&quot;258481&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Prasanna Jeer April 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Prasana Gill and his wife Lavanya are from Chennai, South India. After completing his education and working in India for several years, he came to India 13 years ago with many dreams and hopes. U.S. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Prasana is an IT employee who works for Caterpillar. He dances every day after work. Dance carries his passion and dreams. He founded two dance schools in his spare time, teaching traditional Indian dance and Bollywood dance. In the past seven years, he has had more than 100 students. Prasanna and his students have become the centerpiece of major festivals in Peoria. As a mainstay, they also perform voluntarily for charity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some of Prasanna’s dance items were brought from India, and some were handmade by them. Their daughters, Oviya and Iniya, learned to dance at an early age, and dance was an integral part of this Indian family&#39;s life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Prasana said that he has realized his dream in the United States and is grateful to the people who gave him the opportunity. He is willing to use his own strength to repay the community and use dance to People connect, share joy, share love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Alexander Martin May 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f7e76b5835 .JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f7e76b5835.JPG&quot; data-key =&quot;258482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Alexander Martin May 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;Alexander Martin is an artist, performer, educator, and community advocate. Born and raised in the Appalachian Mountains of West Virginia, she moved to Illinois about 9 years ago to pursue a graduate degree and has lived here ever since. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She strives to exist authentically, powerfully and joyfully in this space, and her works give her such a platform. It also allows her to share personal narratives and stories of her community and celebrate their existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This home is the first house she has ever owned and is a very important space to her. She wanted the house to be a refuge, a safe space of existence, a space of joy, a sacred place of relaxation and happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fashion and clothing play an important role in her life. From performance outfits to everyday wear, she dresses and embellishes with meaning, and it&#39;s important to her to have a variety of items to create her looks. It’s her way of expressing and living authentically every day. She truly believes that being an artist is not just about the work you create, but also about how you live your life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Meng Li &amp;amp; Chunhui Pan April 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/d4a15b82ec.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/d4a15b82ec .JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meng Li &amp;amp; Chunhui Pan April 2023 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pan Chunhui studied abroad after graduating from Peking University, and stayed in the United States to work after graduating with a doctorate. He is a very representative student who was one of the top Chinese students to study abroad. He has been working for Caterpillar, a Fortune 500 company, and has lived in the United States for 31 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The hostess Li Meng also had a similar experience. After getting married, she gave up her nine-to-five job, but spent a lot of time as a volunteer, and was especially keen on publicity. Chinese culture. She is a board member of Global Fest and the person in charge of the Chinese booth, and she also appeared in the Chinese Spring Festival Gala performances. Much of the furniture, household items and decorations were brought over from China and stayed with them for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The calligraphy work &quot;Home&quot; they held in their hands was made with their parents when they got married. Each of them wrote one or two strokes with a brush to form This &quot;home&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Burt Raabe &amp; Lisa Raabe April 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/16/61ddc6fa3c.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/61ddc6fa3c.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bert and Lisa Rabe (Burt Raabe &amp;amp; Lisa Raabe) April 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Burt and Lisa Raabe have been married for 20 years and have lived in this house 10 years. Lisa grew up in northwestern Pennsylvania and graduated from the Art Institute of Chicago. She holds a master&#39;s degree in art therapy from Illinois State University and has been involved in counseling for 15 years, as well as being a yoga teacher. She is now a full-time artist and holds an MFA from Bradley University. Her work has been exhibited throughout the Midwest and she has received several awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bert&#39;s great-grandfather came to the United States from Germany to farm in 1867. He grew up in Walnut City, Illinois, and graduated from Bradley University in 1968. , served in the Peace Corps in India as a welder, consultant and mentor. He now writes poetry and has published two books of poetry, several of which have also been published in magazines. Bert and Lisa enjoyed traveling and made many trips to India. In the United States, they love Chicago, Washington, D.C., and Myrtle Beach. They prefer taking trains to flying or driving. Many of the items in the photos are materials Lisa used for her artwork; there are also items from both homes and second-hand stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mae &amp;amp; Jonathan Wright June 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/4913f98a0a.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4913f98a0a .JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258485&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mae &amp;amp; Jonathan Wright June 2023 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;May is the executive director of the Central Illinois Arts Partnership and the public history coordinator and affiliated faculty member at Bradley University. She received her master&#39;s and doctoral degrees in theology from the University of Edinburgh in Scotland, where she studied changes in ancient Greek religious manuscripts over time. She returned to Peoria, Illinois, in 2013, and subsequently fell in love with and married Jonathan. Jonathan is a writer, editor, communications expert, vinyl DJ, and veteran of the Peoria music scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Jonathan owns more than 10,000 vinyl records; May collects art from local artists; and they both have extensive book collections. Jonathan reads mostly nonfiction. In the early years of their relationship, May was more oriented towards academic/ancient Greek books, and religious studies, but in recent years she has begun immersing herself in novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They have three cats named Luna, Hermione and Frega, but the larger family is the community. They spend a lot of time doing volunteer work. May is a member of the Central Illinois Women&#39;s Foundation and the City of Peoria&#39;s Public Art Advisory Committee, as well as a member of the Central Illinois Animal Welfare Grants Committee. Jonathan serves on the steering committees of the Peoria Symphony, the Central Illinois Jazz Society, the Turner Center for Entrepreneurship Advisory Council at Bradley University, and the Peoria City/County Racial Justice and Equity Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Their house tells the story of their time as a couple. It was an old house built in 1913 and needed a lot of maintenance when they purchased it. Jonathan and May gradually transformed it into a beautiful space that they never wanted to leave. The tree in the front yard was planted by them as a couple and has grown with their marriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Erica Pamson May 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/e6cf25f6a1.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/e6cf25f6a1.JPG &quot; data-key=&quot;258486&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Erica Pamson May 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Erica, 29, just completed her BA in Art Therapy at Millikin University in Decatur, IL, and will be attending Lesley University in Cambridge, MA to study Expression Graduate programs in healing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She is also a circus juggler, visual artist, and performance artist. On stage she is known by the name Hexli. She performs throughout the United States and her work combines different types of performance arts, including butoh, juggling, fire dance, ritual bodywork, and live painting. The &quot;Hexli&quot; tapestry is her personal vaudeville flag, a hand-sewn gift from her friend and well-known actor The Enigma, who also gave her the stage name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She has lived in this apartment for two years. Her home contains many performance costumes and props, as well as completed and in-progress paintings. This home was her first place that was truly her own, and she felt extremely grateful for the opportunity to grow and create in this space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Neng Wang &amp;amp; Lucy Feng April 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/6ba90c1112.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6ba90c1112. JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258487&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Neng Wang &amp;amp; Lucy Feng April 2023&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Neng and Feng Luxi are a pair of first-generation immigrants born in the 1980s from mainland China. I have been in the United States for more than ten years, and I have gone through many obstacles all the way, first studying and then working, and moving several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The two met through church activities in different cities, fell in love and got married, and now live in the small town of Peoria, Illinois. People also accumulate some belongings of their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Kirk Perry &amp;amp; Barbie Perry May 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/16/a7a5fc9eb1.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/a7a5fc9eb1.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kirk Perry and Barbie Perry Perry &amp;amp; Barbie Perry) May 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Barbie was born into a white Midwestern family. Her parents both experienced the Great Depression. Her father was a German prisoner of war for 18 months during World War II, and the war had a devastating impact on him and the entire family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Barbie experienced domestic violence, mental illness, drug and alcohol problems, and was hospitalized multiple times for suicidal ideation. The lack of structure in her life and inability to seek help led to a difficult life throughout her childhood and into her twenties. She gave birth to her daughter Stephanie and was a single mother for 13 years. My daughter has had 15 surgeries since she was 1 year old. The birth of her daughter became a turning point in Barbie&#39;s life, and she began to save herself through various therapies. She was able to finish school and find work, working in a variety of jobs including ice cream server, retail salesperson, waitress and more. This difficult life ended when Barbie met Kirk Perry in 1997 and married him a year later. Since then, with love and a patient ear, Barbie has lived a beautiful, fulfilling, and loving life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Kirk Perry is a retired criminal intelligence analyst who worked for the Illinois State Police. He holds an associate&#39;s degree in criminal justice, a bachelor&#39;s degree in administrative justice and a juris doctorate. In his career of more than thirty years, he not only solved many criminal cases and sent many bad guys to prison. He fell in love with books at the age of six and never stopped reading. He has a collection of over 10,000 comic books. Barbie has been making art since 2015, all about feminism, while Kirk has written three novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the couple, the Barbie collection is a testament to their love. During their marriage, Barbie and Kirk have had seven dogs, with Biscuit being their current favorite. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Brandie Centi-Fislar August 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/16/9294743f69.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/9294743f69.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258489&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brandie Sendy-Fislar Centi-Fislar) August 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Brandy Centi-Fislar, 31, from Clearfield, Pennsylvania, High School Class of 2010 After graduation, she enrolled at Lincoln College in Lincoln, Illinois, on swimming and soccer scholarships. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2012, she earned an associate degree in art and transferred to Illinois State University in Normal, IL to begin her art studies. She began with an art education and later switched professions to glassblowing. At the same time, she began dating her now-husband. Over the next 10 years, she and her husband completed their bachelor&#39;s degrees together and worked multiple jobs in an effort to stay financially stable. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After a lot of good times and some bad times, they now have a dream house filled with their fur babies (three dog and two cats) to enjoy life with less stress. She still blows glass full-time and enjoys being creative every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“从深度和广度推动中新合作” | 亚太群英荟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260859]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, on November 1, 2023, Assistant Minister of Foreign Affairs Nong Rong and the Ministry of Trade and Industry of Singapore Permanent Secretary Lin Mingliang held the China-Singapore Bilateral Cooperation Mechanism Senior Officials&#39; Meeting via video link. In March this year, Singaporean Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong visited China, and China-Singapore relations were upgraded to a comprehensive, high-quality, forward-looking partnership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking the opportunity to take China-Singapore cooperation to a new level, Southern Weekend researchers interviewed Professor Liu Hong, Associate Vice President of Nanyang Technological University in Singapore. As an alumnus of Xiamen University and Fudan University, Liu Hong has studied and worked in many countries in Asia, North America, and Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Hong said that in the past ten years or so, he has noticed from his teaching, research and management work that the relationship between China and Singapore is showing several characteristics: all-round, advancing with the times and high quality. . From the early days of China learning from Singapore, it has now become a two-way trend of learning from each other and learning from each other. As China-Singapore relations enter a new stage of development, Nanyang Technological University is also constantly improving the level of cooperation projects to further promote the friendship and cooperation between Singapore and China in terms of depth and breadth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Liu Hong&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/cac4375609.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1544&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/cac4375609.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Photo by Liu Hong&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Lou Xiaoxi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;When you go to China, seeing it once is better than hearing it a hundred times&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have studied and worked in universities in many countries around the world, and you feel that Chinese students are similar to students from other countries. What are its characteristics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The general characteristic of students in mainland China is that they are very diligent and studious. With more than 10 million college students graduating every year, competition is fierce. Among the college students from various countries I have come into contact with, Chinese students can be said to be leading in terms of diligence and studiousness. On the one hand, this is because the Chinese nation has a tradition of loving learning, but on the other hand, it is also because social competition is becoming increasingly fierce, so everyone must stand out. Employment for college students is a big challenge. Chinese students are very concerned about the development of the world situation and have a strong desire to study abroad. I personally studied in the Netherlands and the United States, and then worked in Singapore and the United Kingdom. I stayed at Kyoto University and Osaka University in Japan for almost two years, and I have many personal experiences. I think Chinese students are very diligent and studious. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think are the differences between the Eastern and Western higher education systems? Same? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have studied in the Netherlands for more than a year and in the United States for more than five years. Western countries have a tradition of pursuing knowledge. It does not take test scores as the main goal, but a more divergent and diverse goal. Students choose some subjects based on their own interests, so they can look at some issues from multiple perspectives. However, I think Western education has a major flaw - a lack of understanding of developing countries, including China. Recently, some scholars have analyzed that in international political economics textbooks and related papers in the 2010s, China only accounted for less than 11%, which is a very small proportion; but China is now the second largest economy in the world. , its total GDP is close to about 20% of the world&#39;s, which shows that there is a lack of knowledge about China in university textbooks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to let the West better understand China through education ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;During my tenure in the UK, I organized several times for hundreds of college students from different universities across the UK to go to China for two to three weeks. After Zhou’s study tour and immersion, I named this project “Experience a Dynamic China”. Many British people&#39;s understanding of China is very lacking and outdated, and most of it is what they read in books. We organize them to travel to different cities such as Beijing, Shanghai, Nanjing, Guangzhou, and Jinan, and to different places (including rural areas), allowing them to experience a constantly changing and developing China. I think that in international education and exchanges, we can have more Chinese stories and more Chinese voices. One of the sources is to let foreigners experience it for themselves. The feedback I received from the participants of these immersion activities is that after many people returned home, they said that their impressions of China had almost undergone earth-shaking changes, and that seeing a hundred times was worse than seeing it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Scientific research achievements are implemented in the Greater Bay Area&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;How does Nanyang Technological University promote cooperation in education between China and Singapore in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Greater Bay Area is now a region with the greatest development potential in China. Singapore and China have cooperated to establish the Sino-Singapore Guangzhou Knowledge City. Our university has jointly established the Sino-Singapore International Joint Research Institute with the Knowledge City and South China University of Technology, and the progress is very good. In addition to integrating industry, academia and research, the Knowledge City also arranged for some government officials to come to us for training. I am currently leading a research project on business environment improvement and enhancement commissioned by Guangzhou Development Zone and China-Singapore Knowledge City. We hope that when talking about China&#39;s development, we do not just talk about it on paper, but we have an understanding of China&#39;s latest development, and then connect China&#39;s development with the development of the world. In this process, what useful experiences can Singapore provide? How can we make progress together? In fact, the purpose of our project is to promote friendly relations between Singapore and China, and ASEAN and China. This big goal is the direction that my colleagues and I work together. This is also the main goal of the new president of Nanyang Technological University, Professor Ho Tak Wa, who recently proposed to create a &quot;Nanyang Technological University Singapore-China Knowledge Hub&quot;. Both the Singaporean government and Nanyang Technological University are paying great attention to and attaching great importance to the development of the Greater Bay Area. For example, the Sino-Singapore Guangzhou Knowledge City I just mentioned has become a national-level project between China and Singapore, relying on and benefiting from it. Against the background of the rapid development of the Greater Bay Area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As the Associate Vice-President of Nanyang Technological University, I have a lot of thoughts on the future What are the plans for cooperation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Whether it is in Guangzhou, Hong Kong, or Shenzhen, we have a lot of cooperation now and in the future. These cooperations not only focus on In cultivating talents, we also pay special attention to the integration of industry, academia and research. The relationship between New Zealand and China is more about learning from each other and advancing with the times. Our main purpose is to transform the latest scientific research results from around the world, especially Singapore, into the fertile soil of the Greater Bay Area, make them take root, sprout and promote them. This is why we set up an international joint research institute in Guangzhou, and why our cooperation with Shenzhen focuses on innovation. Singapore and Shenzhen focus on cooperating to build a series of new developments such as smart cities and digital economy. Shenzhen leads not only China but also the world in innovation. We have been cooperating a lot with universities in the Greater Bay Area. Student exchanges and scientific research cooperation with universities in Hong Kong will also be further deepened. In the future, our Nanyang Graduate School of Public Administration may further increase talent training in places such as Guangzhou and Shenzhen. Shenzhen is paying more and more attention to ASEAN. Of course, ASEAN can also use the platform of Shenzhen or Guangdong to further develop. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the field of public governance, Singapore and China have What experiences can be learned from each other? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Our research pays special attention to public governance in Asia. Now, some theories, experiences and models of global public governance are mainly based on Western experience. We hope to explore the experiences of these countries through in-depth analysis of the development of Singapore, China, and other ASEAN countries, and analyze how they contribute to global public governance theory and practice. We have many research projects, including focusing on the &quot;One Belt and One Road&quot; as a new model of cross-border governance, focusing on mutual learning and reference between Asian and African countries, and also including the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; context, Chinese enterprises &quot; Going global&quot; and different models of cooperation with other countries are several research focuses of myself and our school. We hope to continue to maintain close contact with the Chinese government, state-owned enterprises or universities in the future. As China-Singapore relations enter a new stage of development, we are constantly improving the level of projects and further promoting the friendly cooperation between Singapore and China in terms of depth and breadth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Essence of Civilized Dialogue&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;What do you think of the “One Belt, One Road” initiative? What are the key directions for future development? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This year marks the 10th anniversary of the “Belt and Road” initiative, which is a very important development milestone. In the past few months, I have been invited to give no fewer than 10 speeches on the Belt and Road Initiative. It can be seen that different countries in the world are very concerned about the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative, although their starting points are different. The &quot;five links&quot; in the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative include people-to-people connectivity and policy communication, which are two aspects that our college and I are very concerned about. I regard the people-to-people bonds and policy communication in the &quot;five links&quot; as a piece of software; infrastructure construction, trade, and investment are hardware. Only when hardware and software are organically combined can they play their best roles. For future development, on the one hand, we must think about how to further improve the quality and influence of the “One Belt, One Road” project based on the achievements made in the past 10 years, including focusing on a series of topics such as digital economy, green development, and public health. It will become the focus of the future development of “One Belt, One Road”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now the young generation is &quot;going out&quot; in Chinese culture What role can it play? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Chinese culture &quot;going out&quot; to engage in civilized dialogue requires us to further develop it. In this process, young people from China, as well as Chinese state-owned enterprises, Chinese scientific researchers, university teachers, etc., all played important roles. I think that in terms of future development, it is very important to grasp the essence of Chinese cultural development, including some characteristics of Chinese cultural traditions: being upright but not old-fashioned, respecting the past but not retrospecting. First of all, you must understand your own culture, have your own cultural roots, and then start a dialogue with other cultures. Secondly, we still need to treat other cultures with an attitude of equality, tolerance, openness and respect. In terms of culture, every country&#39;s culture has its own characteristics and advantages, which are the product of different countries&#39; own environments. We should adopt an attitude of understanding and respect and cannot say that China does this, why don&#39;t you this way? Only by understanding and communicating can we truly &quot;go global&quot; with our culture. Third, we must still pay attention to innovation. Whether it is Chinese culture or the culture of other countries, it must reflect the development characteristics of the new era, including the fourth industrial revolution we are now in, an era of parallel globalization and anti-globalization. , global geopolitics has also undergone many changes. Under such circumstances, we should look at creative transformations of Chinese culture and world culture to achieve more effective dialogue. The &quot;Global Development Initiative&quot; and &quot;Global Civilization Initiative&quot; proposed by the Chinese government have provided Chinese wisdom for the development of the world. Chinese wisdom has very profound connotations, but in terms of communication and exchange methods, we still have more room for efforts to let countries around the world understand the essence of Chinese culture. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一中学发生拥挤踩踏事件：改善硬件设施与提高管理水平当双管齐下丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260863]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A campus accident involving casualties touched people&#39;s hearts. On November 14, 2023, the People&#39;s Government of Wuzhi County, Henan Province reported a casualty incident in a local middle school: At about 10 a.m. on November 13, some boys in the first and second grades of Xinghua Middle School in Wuzhi County went to the toilet between midterm exams. At that time, he fell and was injured due to crowding going up and down the stairs. The students involved were immediately sent to the hospital for examination and treatment. Currently, one student died after all-out efforts to rescue him failed, one seriously injured student is being treated with all-out efforts, and four students with minor injuries are hospitalized for observation and treatment and will be discharged in the near future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Beijing News&quot; report, the details of the incident revealed by insiders are: &quot;The toilets in Xinghua Middle School are on two floors. The men&#39;s toilets have to be climbed up by stairs. The stair railings are all intact. I don&#39;t know. Why did a stampede happen?&quot; According to pictures of the school posted online, there were no toilets in the teaching building of the school where the incident occurred. Students had to go down to the teaching building first and then take the stairs upstairs to use the toilet. The tragedy also happened while going up and down the stairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the accident, many schools across the country required teachers on duty to be arranged on each floor during class breaks. Some media have called for more &quot;break time&quot; or &quot;examination time&quot; to allow students more time to go to the toilet. Some netizens believe that schools should improve hardware facilities and install toilets on every floor of the teaching building. In addition to these obvious problems, this accident is still worthy of analysis in terms of responsibility distribution and preventive measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the nature of the accident. Media reports all reported the accident as a &quot;stampede&quot;, but the wording in the report was &quot;crowding and falling.&quot; So, what was the nature of the accident? This deserves further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If what &quot;informed people&quot; said about &quot;the stair railings are intact&quot; and what netizens revealed about &quot;the toilets are in another building&quot; are true, then the accident may have occurred during the ten minutes between exams. Students first went down to the teaching building and then to the &quot;toilet building&quot; next door. The high-density flow of people caused congestion and falls while going up and down the stairs, which ultimately led to the tragedy of one death and five injuries. The students who died unfortunately should have died from one of the following possibilities: first, suffocation caused by high-density crowds; second, falling from a high place due to gravity; third, being trampled after falling due to crowding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second issue is the cause of the accident and the attribution of responsibility. After the accident, insufficient number of toilets and insufficient time between exams were two major objective causes identified by netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A midterm exam usually takes about two hours, at least three times the length of a normal class, which will greatly increase the frequency of bathroom breaks. Candidates need to go to the toilet to relax between exams, which will undoubtedly further increase the frequency of going to the toilet. If you add in the factors of greater psychological pressure on candidates and more hurry and panic when going to and from the toilet, the superposition of multiple variables is enough to amplify the safety risk: the common two-hour exam time, the same nervousness, which increases the group resonance The probability of occurrence also increases the probability of accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The school’s hardware facilities could not be changed on the day of the incident, and the exam time and exam time had also been determined. Then, I am afraid that the only thing the invigilator could do that day was to prevent the students from going out to use the toilet, so as to 100% eliminate any possibility of this accident. What should be asked is, who made these rules? Who is responsible for such poor hardware facilities? This is the person who should be held responsible, not the invigilator who was just enforcing the rules on the day of the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Again, how to prevent similar accidents from happening again? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time that similar accidents have occurred in China. In the stampede at the No. 3 Experimental Primary School in Puyang, Henan in March 2017, students &quot;rushed down like a flood&quot; after finishing morning reading; and in the stampede at a middle school in Xuchang, Henan in November 2000, students were studying in the evening Something happened after class. Similar accidents have occurred many times across the country. The causes of these accidents are similar: the recess time is short, or the class duration is too long. As soon as the bell rings, students rush to the toilet or go out, causing stampedes due to congestion. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, only by controlling variables and prescribing the right medicine can we find a solution to prevent such accidents. It is certainly necessary for schools to install toilets in strict accordance with the &quot;Design Code for Primary and Secondary Schools&quot;. Installing diversion barriers at densely populated entrances and exits of schools is also a way. During large-scale activities such as exams, sports games, and school celebrations, it is also indispensable for the school to arrange dedicated personnel to ensure the order of the flow of people and implement staggered peak management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to upgrading hardware facilities, schools should also focus on improving software, that is, management levels. Specific to this incident, we should also ask whether the school arranged for off-peak exams that day, and whether there was a dedicated person responsible for maintaining order in the flow of people? To be more specific, did the school allow candidates to use the toilet when the exam was in progress on the day of the incident? This will also ease the stress of going to the bathroom between exams. Also, does the school provide safety education on preventing crowding and stampeding, and does it conduct corresponding safety drills? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how good the hardware facilities are, they have an approved capacity, and their redundancy has a limit. You cannot expect that everything will be fine by building more toilets, expanding the volume of the teaching building, and installing diversion barriers. Otherwise, those facilities There will be no stampede accidents in large-scale tourist attractions that are well-established. Long-term scientific management is the best guarantee to prevent problems before they occur, and its importance is by no means inferior to improving hardware facilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, schools cannot lock students in classrooms because of such incidents, and cannot make the temporary arrangement of &quot;arranging on-duty teachers on each floor between classes&quot; permanent, as this may increase the number of students. It has reduced the non-teaching burden of teachers and led to the misunderstanding that &quot;schools should have unlimited safety responsibilities for students&quot;. To improve school management, schools can also think about delegating more power and giving students more freedom out of classrooms, teaching buildings and playgrounds, so that students can practice their ability to deal with risks and learn to protect themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么有的人睡觉打着呼噜就“嘎”了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260615]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Recently, Olympic gymnastics champion Yang Wei revealed that he has respiratory problems , attracted everyone&#39;s attention. He revealed in his social updates that he could not breathe in while sleeping. This situation once lasted for 6 minutes. According to the advice given by the doctor, &quot;The once strong athlete now wears &lt; /span>;&lt;span>;On the ventilator&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In fact, Yang Wei’s symptoms are not an isolated case. Celebrities from different industries and ages have also appeared on the hot topic due to the same situation. Search. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;When US President Biden gave a speech in June this year, the media discovered that there were traces of ventilator straps on his face; In a program, Fok Qigang disclosed the fact that he suffers from insomnia disorder and moderate sleep apnea; Chen Qiaoen once underwent surgery because his throat collapsed during sleep and he could not breathe air; artist Hu Haiquan took the initiative to wear a respirator because of snoring during the program machine to sleep. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;We all know that snoring after falling asleep generally only affects the sleep of the person next to you, but unexpectedly, in some cases, Snoring may be accompanied by apnea, causing people to &quot;repeatedly suffocate&quot; in their dreams, which may even endanger their lives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/Mrxb5DiqLERFb732b6q8D5iS8yyU84GFLNAOqBZV.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/Mrxb5DiqLERFb732b6q8D5iS8yyU84GFLNAOqBZV.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258641&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Can snoring cause apnea? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yang Wei&#39;s condition is medically called &quot;apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Syndrome&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;&quot;, including three types: obstructive, central, and mixed. Among them, &quot;obstructive sleep apnea hypopnea syndrome (OSAHS)&quot; is the most common, commonly known as &quot;snoring&quot;, and is mainly characterized by sleep Snoring, accompanied by breathlessness and hypoxia, may lead to sudden death in severe cases. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Of course, not all snoring will be diagnosed as apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Symptom&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, there is currently no confirmed necessary relationship between the two. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;According to the &quot;Multiple Obstructive Sleep Apnea in Adults&quot; released by the Sleep Respiratory Disorders Group of the Respiratory Disease Branch of the Chinese Medical Association in 2018 &quot;Discipline Diagnosis and Treatment Guidelines&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Guidelines&quot;), the diagnostic criteria for apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; mainly include two: the number of apnea and hypopnea events, and How often both occur. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The apnea mentioned here is almost literal. It means that the airflow disappears or is significantly weakened during breathing, while hypopnea means , refers to the reduction of respiratory volume and blood oxygen saturation below the basic level. During a 7-hour sleep period, if apnea and hypopnea recur more than 30 times, or the apnea-hypopnea index (AHI) is greater than 5 times per hour, you can be diagnosed with apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Sign&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Obstacles of respiratory suspension comprehensive &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 征 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; (OSA) and centrality The difference between respiratory suspension comprehensive &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Zheng &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; (CSA) is that the former is due to the obstruction of the upper airway, which causes respiratory suspension. The nose stopped but the brain was fine, the latter was caused by the abnormality of the central nervous system, the brain stopped, and the nose and nose stopped. Mixed respiratory suspension synthesis &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 征 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; (MSA) belongs to both. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Surprisingly, the complexity of the breathing suspension &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; surface It only causes interference to night sleep. In fact, this kind of sleep rhythm disorders caused by irregular breathing have caused more adverse effects on daily life, such as drowsiness during the day, decreased memory, and even psychology. Abnormal intelligence and behavior. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Medical experts who published the &quot;Guide&quot; believe that OSAHS patients have risen rapidly in the short term, with certain possibilities and hypertension, and hypertension. Coronary heart disease has abnormal heart rate, stroke, type 2 diabetes, etc., and the families of patients with the above diseases can observe more attention. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/ilqwhkpfm67777777777777FLXHRJPEG&quot; border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/ilqwhkpm677777777777flxhrjssusvu.jpeg &quot;data-key = &quot;258642&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align : left; &quot;>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>; Why is this disease easily missed diagnosis &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; 2019 academic magazine &quot;Liuye Knife-Respiratory Diseases&quot; published a name &quot;Obstructiveness Investigation reports of sleep respiratory suspension and global economic burden &quot;, based on the diagnostic criteria published by the American Sleep Medicine Society (AASM) as a reference, have compiled the data of obstructive sleep apnea from 16 countries and 17 studies. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; This report believes that the prevalence of obstructive sleep apnea has increased from 2%-4%10 years ago to 24% Above, more than 85%of sleeping respiratory suspension patients were missed. Researchers have further speculated that about 936 million adults 30 to 69 are suffering from obstructive sleep respiratory suspension in the world. China has the most affected people, followed by the United States, Brazil and India. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; When it comes to why sleep breathing is particularly easy to missed the diagnosis, the author of the report believes that this may originate from everyone&#39;s health and health. Two prejudices. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; First of all, everyone is more accustomed to blaming the fatigue in daily life on age and pressure. &quot;It is normal&quot; &quot;The work KPI is too heavy, and I can&#39;t sleep when I think of it.&quot; I rarely consider the direction of sleep disease. In fact, respiratory suspension during sleep can also cause physical function to decline, which causes migraine and other diseases such as migraine and chronic fatigue. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; In some of the traditional concepts, snoring often becomes a sign of &quot;sleeping sweetly&quot;, even if the family is noticed abnormal, It is rarely interrupted and valued. Take a step back, some people&#39;s snoring sounds are irregular, and the emergence of respiratory suspension is random, and it is difficult for relatives and family members to effectively identify. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; &quot;Guide&quot; specifically mentioned that the body&#39;s obesity (referring to the weight of the body weight of 20%or more) may increase the affected affected The risk of sleep apnea; the prevalence of the prevalence grows forward, the number of patients in women after menopause increases, and the prevalence of men during the birth period is higher than that of women. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; In addition, the sedentary people, long-term drinking smokers, and people with OSAHS family history are also faced with high problems Disease risk. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; In the end, this disease is common and common, but it is not easy to find. . Many domestic medical research has confirmed that portable blood oxygen instruments and mobile phone snoring analysis APPs will help early diagnosis and screening of OSAHS patients. Perhaps in the near future, monitoring respiratory suspension comprehensive &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Zheng &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; It is as convenient and fast as monitoring body temperature. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; More importantly, if you suspect that you or your family will have similar symptoms, you should go to the hospital for diagnosis as soon as possible. According to the doctor&#39;s order, according to the doctor&#39;s order Take surgical, appliances, ventilator, etc. for treatment. In a person&#39;s life, one -third of the time spent in sleep. Sleep health is really healthy. May the monarchs sleep well and healthy every day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>