<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[为了快乐挖土，一个考古学家决定去当美食博主]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260512]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;What happens when an archaeologist becomes a &quot;foodie&quot;? Zhang Liangren, professor of history at Nanjing University, gave an example. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A meal of soup dumplings in a roadside fly shop can reveal 7,000 years of history: from the pottery age and the Bronze Age kitchen utensils &quot;retort&quot;, From the ancient &quot;steamer&quot; on the kitchen murals of the Eastern Han Dynasty tombs in Henan, to the plum blossom buns in the caves of the Song Dynasty...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A bowl of small wontons can help him interpret the weather of the universe. : &quot;&quot;The Chronicles of Yanjing&quot; says: The shape of husband&#39;s wonton is like a chicken egg, which is quite similar to the chaos of heaven and earth, so it occurs during the winter solstice solar eclipse.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a96844643a462e214e5c9d376e7947bb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; ​​height=&quot;308&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a96844643a462e214e5c9d376e7947bb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Dumplings from the Tang Dynasty&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Eating hot pot today? Then it&#39;s time to show real technology - &quot;tell the history of whatever you see&quot;. The professor is not afraid. There was originally a legend of &quot;fried Qin Hui&quot; behind fried dough sticks, and tofu was called &quot;Plough Qi&quot; in Lu You&#39;s poem; &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; not only made Liu Genghong famous, but also recorded the method of making yuba; instant noodles are not a patent of the Japanese , but was &quot;invented&quot; by Yi Bingzhuo, a calligrapher from the Qing Dynasty in my country, who accidentally poured noodles into the oil pan at his mother&#39;s birthday party...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The temptation of delicious food hangs on the taste buds, and these historical knowledge and anecdotes remain in the audience&#39;s memory through Zhang Liangren&#39;s eloquent narration. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0d1987373b66b40f67a667c3f3c70b18.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;826&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/0d1987373b66b40f67a667c3f3c70b18.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258067 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Netizens commented that Zhang Liangren looks like the Chinese version of a lonely gourmet&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >; With this &quot;unique skill&quot;, Zhang Liangren gained 38,000 fans and 300,000 likes in just over two months after joining Douyin. He was called &quot;The Lonely Gourmet&quot; that is more suitable for Chinese babies&#39; physiques. This expressed the wish he expressed in the first video: &quot;Break the dimensional wall, take off the cold and mysterious mask of archeology, and let everyone see the lovely and warm inner nature of this subject.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;What people don’t know is that this archaeologist decided to become a food blogger because he could “dig in the soil” happily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;1. An archaeologist who only loves food&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Graduated from Peking University undergraduate and social studies A postgraduate student of the Academy of Science and Technology went to the University of California, Los Angeles to get a doctorate. He worked as a researcher for many years and later became a professor at Nanjing University. Zhang Liangren devoted his life to archeology: &quot;he can go to the field and write articles.&quot; He not only does Chinese archeology, Also doing world archeology. In his own words: &quot;The total number of countries he has visited and explored could circle the earth.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is also Zhang Liangren&#39;s habit to eat wherever he goes. Iranian mutton stew and saffron rice, Russian kebabs, and Siberian grilled fish... all impressed him. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/aac65aaf101d087bf37b6fd4b9685798.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/aac65aaf101d087bf37b6fd4b9685798.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258068 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren visited Tajikistan in 2011&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, Zhang Liangren admitted frankly that he is far from being a qualified &quot;foodie&quot;: he enjoys delicious food, but he has not yet reached the point of searching for delicious food. What really guided him to become a food blogger was his love for archeology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Last year, Zhang Liangren accidentally opened a monograph &quot;Diet in Chinese Culture&quot; from the 1970s. The editor-in-chief of the book, Zhang Guangzhi, is a famous Chinese archaeologist, anthropologist, and Zhang Liangren’s mentor. The whole book provides a panoramic display and interpretation of China&#39;s food culture. From the pre-Qin Dynasty to the Han, Tang, Yuan, Ming and Qing dynasties, how did the characteristics of agricultural society affect the evolution of food on this land? How did Confucian moral concepts and social organization methods determine the Chinese people? cooking and dining habits...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren read more than 400 pages in one breath, as if he saw a new door: he has been doing archaeology for a lifetime, and he has been eating for a lifetime. , but never realized that there was such a close connection between the two. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From then on, eating was no longer just about eating. He could not help but think about it while eating: Why must there be food and rice on the Chinese dining table? &quot;Dual diet&quot;, but Westerners are accustomed to &quot;one plate&quot;? What makes the Chinese form a shared meal system, while Westerners form a divided meal system? When were wheat and tomatoes introduced to China, and how did the stir-fry cooking method come about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, food archeology is not a brand-new research topic. It is only because food is perishable and cannot be preserved in the long history, and it is too difficult to excavate that it leads to There are very few people doing relevant research in the global archaeological community, and even fewer in China. But Zhang Liangren decided that he would face the difficulties. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Just do it. This year, Zhang Liangren recruited two students to specialize in dietary archeology, hoping to unearth more dietary cultural relics and fill the gaps in archaeological research. Zhang Liangren has always had an academic ideal: to let the world hear the voice of the Chinese archaeological community. &quot;The first is to publish Chinese archeology abroad, and the second is to participate more in international archeology and contribute to world archeology.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For this reason, he has Single-handedly initiated archaeological projects of Sino-Russian and Sino-Iranian cooperation. The Iranian team adopted the European excavation method, digging straight down like a deep well. Zhang Liangren felt that this area was too small and too inefficient, so he persuaded the other party to use the Chinese trench excavation method. The results were remarkable and were not only published in international journals. The paper attracted the attention of academic circles and was visited by members of the Iranian Congress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;How to make cold knowledge more pyrotechnic? Letting more people realize the value of archaeological history is something Zhang Liangren and his friends around him often discuss. In July this year, with the help of several friends, Zhang Liangren opened his own Douyin account and started to explore food stores. Zhang Liangren is responsible for the appearance, and friends are responsible for filming and production. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;He made no secret that the reason why he came up with the idea of ​​making short videos was to spread knowledge to the public, and the other original intention was to &quot;expand awareness&quot; and let more people People know the value of archeology and support archaeological research in more ways. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;2. Pour some cold water on young people who want to study archeology&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren The video is full of the fireworks of life and has a sense of history. He picked up a mouthful of duck blood vermicelli soup and said that this vermicelli soup has only a few decades of history, but from a can of duck eggs unearthed from a mound tomb in Jurong, Jiangsu, it can be seen that the tradition of eating waterfowl in Jiangsu dates back to 2,500 years ago. It started years ago. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is also interesting to examine the origin of imitation meat vegetarian food. Emperor Liang Wu of the Han Dynasty issued an &quot;administrative order&quot; requiring monks to stop drinking and eating. The need to be both vegetarian and satisfy one&#39;s cravings led later generations to use their brains and develop meat-like vegetarian food that can mimic meat. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although the image in the video is humorous and friendly, Zhang Liangren waved his hands and laughed at himself, saying that he is an &quot;old scholar&quot; who spends all day burying his head in old papers and not listening to what is going on outside the window. He is good at academic research, digging soil, and giving lectures; reviewing video scripts and embedding historical knowledge can also be regarded as an extension of his professional skills. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Only appearing on camera is a big problem: &quot;I am a person who is not good at words, and I cannot speak Mandarin well.&quot; In the first few videos, his eyes were habitually Avoid the camera and look away. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But what can stump a true &quot;old scholar&quot;? He began to use his scholarly spirit to make short videos, and specially hired an announcer to train himself to correct his pronunciation, improve his intonation and language rhythm, and practice facing the camera. Now, although he is still a little green and awkward, he can already look directly into the camera, clearly tell the history behind the food, and even make some funny expressions and movements to interact with the imaginary audience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The contrast between &quot;old scholar&quot; and various current buzzwords, the fresh combination of historical knowledge and gourmet temptations, and the high-frequency output of updates every two days make the book more interesting. Zhang Liangren became a &quot;top leader&quot; in the archaeological community in just over two months. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But compared with the increased traffic figures, what makes him even more happy is that many ordinary people will leave messages or private messages asking questions related to archeology and history. &quot;More people are interested in We are interested in archeology.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many young students also left messages: Can they take the postgraduate entrance examination for professors? Zhang Liangren will be more cautious towards this type of fans. On the one hand, he is pleased that more young people want to join the archaeological industry; on the other hand, he has to remind them that doing research and popular science are not the same thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/769ecce1cc954fdc3f13291282e16804.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1597&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/769ecce1cc954fdc3f13291282e16804.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258066 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The history of fried dough sticks&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren has long noticed , in recent years, with the broadcast of film and television programs such as &quot;I Repair Cultural Relics in the Forbidden City&quot; and &quot;National Treasure&quot;, archeology has gradually entered the public eye. Many of his own students were influenced by these programs and decided to apply for the archeology major. The first lesson he taught these young students was to pour cold water on them: &quot;Break their romantic imagination of archeology - TV programs present the most interesting and accomplished aspects of this subject, but behind the fun and achievements, It is extremely long and hard work. If you can’t stand the loneliness, don’t enter this industry.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, it took Zhang Liangren himself many years to fall in love with archeology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/70be4fd89711527d9429c6a323807c0b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;870&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/70be4fd89711527d9429c6a323807c0b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258069 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Let more people understand archeology&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;When I took the exam When he was in college, he had no idea what his interests were, so he muddleheadedly applied for the Department of Archeology. During his undergraduate and postgraduate years, Zhang Liangren spent his time attending classes, reading materials, and writing papers. It was difficult and boring, just like the public&#39;s stereotype of archeology. It wasn’t until I started to come into contact with a large number of historical materials from all over the world during my PhD studies and participated in field surveys and excavations around the world that I felt the joy of this subject. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The part that he enjoys the most is the most feared &quot;digging&quot; part of archeology: sleeping in the open air, exposed to the sun and rain, under the pressure of scholars Title, doing heavy physical work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“I like this kind of life to explore in inaccessible places, bask in the sun, look at the scenery, and breathe fresh air.” Moreover, compared to sitting in the library and studying Archeology can always surprise him with the achievements of predecessors and the first-hand information that is freshly excavated and stained with real historical dust, inspiring him to discover new problems. &quot;I am very excited and not boring at all.&quot;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, after using a basin of cold water to extinguish the romantic imagination of young people, he will use the true connotation of this subject to &quot;warm&quot; them back - after all, he has given This introductory course for freshmen is called &quot;The Archeology of Charm.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;3. Curiosity is the answer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;History The Xianlin campus where the department is located is 20 to 30 kilometers away from downtown Nanjing. After working here for nearly ten years, Zhang Liangren’s life trajectory has never exceeded five kilometers around the campus. He mainly eats in the school cafeteria, and goes out to hang out when friends come. A meal as a supplement. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But since he became a food blogger, he &quot;goes to the city to eat delicious food&quot; every day, and has even become a food trendsetter in Nanjing&#39;s archaeological circles. His colleagues always ask questions when they see him. One sentence: Which restaurant have you been to recently? He thought, how could he ignore so many delicious foods in Jinling, the capital of gourmet food? This kind of shop-hopping life seems to be pretty good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This career, which was originally just a means of &quot;saving the country through curves,&quot; now takes up a little more time every week than teaching. He has already begun to make long-term plans: after exploring Nanjing cuisine, he will also explore national cuisine, and then world cuisine; not only cooking food, but also introducing other archaeological related knowledge, such as the two issues of &quot;Three Whitening Tips of the Ancients&quot; and &quot;A 400-degree myopic guide to traveling through ancient times.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/711d7624ee4cef048393ea6b7813f995.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/711d7624ee4cef048393ea6b7813f995.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258070 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Zhang Liangren participated in excavations in Russia in 2019&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;One The video shooting session, which initially made him feel uncomfortable, gradually became more comfortable. Only then did he realize that those food programs on TV were all &quot;acted&quot;. &quot;A plate of meat was filmed at different angles for 20 minutes. When you eat it, it&#39;s cold in your mouth, and you have to act like it&#39;s delicious. What about &quot;Journey to the West&quot; &quot;The flat peach eaten by Sun Wukong in &quot;Water Margin&quot; could not be a real flat peach, and the bowl of wine Wu Song drank before fighting the tiger in &quot;Water Margin&quot; could not be a real bar? In order to stay awake, the actor must have drank water.&quot; He analyzed seriously. , as if he had discovered some incredible truth, which made the young man opposite him laugh. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Originally, he wanted to &quot;facilitate&quot; archeology to the public. Unexpectedly, in the process, the daily life of the public unknowingly entered his pile of old papers, which made this old scholar Got caught up in the fireworks and became a &quot;slash professor&quot; at the age of 58. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Now he can answer the question: What is the connection between archeology and daily life? Zhang Liangren’s answer is: curiosity. Whether it’s archaeology, gourmet food or being a short video blogger, it’s curiosity that pushes him to move forward. This experience can also be extended to other humans. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“People are curious and want to know where they come from and where they are going, so everyone likes to go to museums and see ruins and cultural relics. And archeology It provides a kind of tangible history that can be seen directly with the eyes, which is more intuitive than the history presented in words. It is not only a key to the historical truth, but also an entrance to explore the development laws of human society.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Nowadays, Zhang Liangren will tell his students that academic issues must be related to things that the people care about. Because there is a lot of fun in the world, and you can get it as long as you are willing to &quot;dig&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“能用的条文总是这么少”，专家呼吁立法解决网暴治理“九龙治水”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260501]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The governance of online violence needs to be solved urgently The problem is that the legislation is too fragmented. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/5bc7fffe8e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/5bc7fffe8e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258056&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;For the governance of online violence, what needs to be solved urgently is the problem of overly fragmented legislation. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;As of June 2023, the number of Internet users in China has reached 1.079 billion. A survey in early 2022 showed that 38.6% of people in China have suffered varying degrees of online violence on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;All cases of cyber violence have one thing in common, that is, they are violent and the consequences are tragic.&quot; On the morning of November 7, 2023, in the &quot;Cyber ​​Violence Rule of Law&quot; Liu Yanhong, dean of the School of Criminal Justice of China University of Political Science and Law, said at the seminar. On the forum, some scholars also expressed that they had suffered cyber violence and information intrusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From &quot;Dr. Deyang An committed suicide&quot; and &quot;Rumors were spread about a Hangzhou woman picking up express delivery&quot; to Liu Xuezhou and Zheng Linghua died in unbearable cyber violence, vicious cyber violence incidents have occurred frequently in recent years. Various reports. “When cyber violence occurs, it stings the nerves of us legal professionals, because our first reaction is to quickly search for any provision in the criminal law that can convict people, but we are very surprised to find that the available provision is always So few.&quot; Liu Yanhong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Many participating scholars believed that for the governance of cyber violence, what needs to be solved urgently is the problem of over-dispersed legislation, and anti-cyber violence legislation needs to be gradually promoted in a hierarchical manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;But on the other hand, some scholars have reminded that the essence of the governance of cyber violence is the governance of speech expression, and the difference between cyber violence and criticism needs to be carefully clarified. boundary. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“Not even the criminal law can catch up”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;2013 On September 5, 2019, the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate and the Ministry of Public Security jointly issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Punishing Illegal Crimes of Cyber ​​Violence in accordance with the Law&quot;, which classified cyber violence for the first time and explained the alleged crimes of different cyber violence behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For example, if the perpetrator of cyber violence creates and spreads rumors on the Internet, derogating others&#39; personality and damaging their reputation, and the circumstances are serious, they will be convicted of defamation; Those who publicly insult others by means of wanton abuse, malicious slander, disclosure of privacy, etc., and if the circumstances are serious, shall be convicted of the crime of insult; organize &quot;human flesh searches&quot; to illegally collect and release citizens&#39; personal information to an unspecified majority of people, and if the circumstances are serious, they shall be convicted of the crime of infringement. Conviction of citizens’ personal information crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Yanhong believes that the current judicial interpretation has a narrow definition of cyber violence and pays less attention to cyber intimidation, stalking and bullying. On the other hand, as to whether human flesh search constitutes the crime of infringing on citizens’ personal information, “it needs to reach a certain number and change from quantitative to qualitative changes to constitute a crime. Therefore, it is difficult to determine that a general manual search conducted by multiple people infringes on personal information of citizens. Information crime”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Even the criminal law is unable to catch up.&quot; Liu Yanhong said that in the field of civil adjudication and administrative law enforcement in the field of online violence, this kind of &quot;law does not punish the public&quot; &quot;The tendency remains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In terms of procedures, there is a lack of unified norms and standards for evidence collection in cyber violence cases. Yin Bo, a professor at the School of Criminal Justice of China University of Political Science and Law, mentioned that in private prosecution cases of cyber violence Among them, the party’s ability to produce evidence is relatively weak. In order to break down technical barriers, evidence is usually extracted by internal or external professionals under the auspices of the public security or other judicial organs. However, the existing electronic evidence production still lacks technology and methods. &quot; Even the grassroots public security organs do not know how to collect evidence, dare not collect evidence, and cannot collect evidence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On August 3, 2023, the Beijing Internet Court released a number of typical cases involving online violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu is a &quot;big V&quot; blogger with nearly 500,000 Weibo fans. Another Weibo user, Sun, was involved in a dispute over a current affairs issue. Liu had a different view and sent insulting words to Liu through Weibo private messages. Liu posted Sun&#39;s private messages, Weibo account, photos and other information on Weibo, along with insulting remarks, triggering online violence against Sun from netizens. In the end, the court ruled that Liu had infringed the law and deleted the Weibo and comments involved in the case that infringed on Sun&#39;s portrait and reputation. Both parties apologized to each other in writing, and the amount of mental damage compensation was offset by each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Yanhong previously wrote that netizens who posted negative comments to insult Sun could have been held liable for civil infringement and administrative liability for disrupting online order, but in the judicial process In law enforcement practice, such acts committed by non-initiators and non-organizers are generally ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the other hand, for the current governance of cyber violence, there are relevant provisions in the Civil Code, Criminal Law, Administrative Penalty Law and other laws and regulations that can be used, but different laws Each has its own value orientation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Generally speaking, the current legislation on the governance of cyber violence is like a flood in Kowloon.&quot; She advocates comprehensive and progressive legislation, such as being first formulated by the State Council. Regulations on the Prevention and Control of Cyber ​​Violence, followed by legislation on the prevention and control of cyber violence, and finally the establishment of an organic law for cyber violence governance agencies, and finally the unified rise to the Anti-Cyber ​​Violence Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Wang Sixin, deputy director of the Research Institute of a Community with a Shared Future for Mankind at Communication University of China, also said that step-by-step legislation is more likely to achieve practical results. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;To prevent platform abuse of power&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the seminar, Some scholars also warned that we should be cautious about anti-cyber violence legislation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;The governance of online violence is essentially the governance of speech.&quot; Zhi Zhenfeng, a researcher at the Institute of Law, Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, said that for normal criticism and Supervision and discussion of different opinions should be protected. &quot;Online violence must be controlled, but everyone&#39;s rights to speech and expression must also be protected.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;As to how to distinguish normal online criticism from illegal online violence, Shi Jiayou, a professor at Renmin University of China, said that subjectively speaking, online criticism is generally well-intentioned and its purpose is Often it is about safeguarding public interests or one&#39;s own legitimate rights and interests. From an objective point of view, Internet criticism is generally based on basic facts. The facts criticized are generally well-founded or have reasonable information channels, and are not groundless or randomly fabricated; even if the facts confirmed in the end are different from the initial There are discrepancies or partial inaccuracies in the critical remarks, but as long as the critical remarks do have an objective basis as a whole and the critic has reasonable grounds to believe in the authenticity of the facts cited, then the critical remarks should be considered to be a reasonable exercise of freedom of speech. scope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Therefore, Zhi Zhenfeng emphasized that the focus of combating cyber violence should be organized manipulation of public opinion. “For example, behind cyber thugs and cyber trolls, there are often Organized ones, where one organization can control dozens or millions of accounts at the same time, as well as overseas account matrices involving national security, are all targets that should be targeted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, he believes that as a platform that builds a public opinion space, it has an obligation to maintain the order of the public opinion space. &quot;The platform has technical strength and can intervene through front-end and make samples.&quot; Use database modeling and other technologies to control cyber violence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Professor Wang Limei from the Data Law Institute of China University of Political Science and Law added this. She believes that platforms should first improve the real-name system, which can be based on the different natures of the platform and spokespersons. , implement front-end or back-end real-name. Secondly, platforms should set up preventive technical measures so that those who are cyberviolated can trigger the protection mechanism with “one click”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, Zhi Zhenfeng said that it seems that the platform has been imposed obligations, but in fact it has been given power. &quot;Then will the platform abuse this?&quot; Power, to make the already uneven power between the platform and users even more imbalanced? I have found that some platforms use the banner of supervision to delete posts that they do not like.&quot; He reminded that attention should be paid to preventing platforms from abusing their power and controlling speech. Abnormal market manipulation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[犹太人向左，以色列向右：从知识分子幼稚病到游民心态]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260503]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A new round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict broke out, which also caused shock in the United States. The American intelligentsia has a tradition of sympathizing with Palestine and boycotting Israel. At this time, the mainstream media in the United States basically no longer criticized Israel for retaliation, but instead condemned Hamas as never before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also a few student organizations in American universities that refuse to condemn Hamas and continue to target Israel. In response, many Jewish entrepreneurs announced in a high-profile manner that they would cut off funding for these universities. The influence of wealthy Jewish people and Jewish organizations in the United States far exceeds its population ratio. This is regarded as another example of &quot;Jews exerting the power of money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current Israeli government is governed by the Likud Group and a group of center-right parties. The Likud Group is the right-wing core of Israeli politics. The current Prime Minister Netanyahu and the famous military strongman Sharon are all representatives of this party. It seems that this is an echo of right-wing Jews in Israel and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, people who are familiar with international relations know that Jews as a group are generally not right-wing, but are famous for being left-leaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The contemporary American political left is the liberal wing represented by the Democratic Party. There are approximately 6 million Jews in the United States, the largest number of Jews outside Israel. The vast majority of Jews vote for Democrats in every election, and this has been the case for more than a hundred years. &quot;Jews side with the Democrats&quot; is common sense in the political arena. As everyone knows, black people are the die-hard vote base of Democrats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the Republican Party&#39;s firm support for Israel, Democrats continue to criticize Israel. They often criticize the Israeli government&#39;s tough methods and ruthless style, and demand ceasefire and peace talks. American Jews&#39; criticism of the Israeli government is even more intense. On October 16, two American Jewish groups launched a large-scale protest. Hundreds of people rushed into the White House waving Palestinian flags and demanded that the United States urge Israel to cease fire. This farce was so angry that Israel called them &quot;Jewish traitors&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although American public opinion generally supports Israel this time, in the long run, most Jews in the United States are still critics of the Israeli government, sponsors of American universities that are the stronghold of liberals, and have basically nothing to do with the so-called right. Even within Israel, the left has a strong presence. After the establishment of the state of Israel, the left-wing Labor Party has been in power for more than thirty years. At the end of the 20th century, the Likud Party rose and had to form a coalition with the Labor Party to govern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you extend the time and broaden your horizons, you will find that the left-wing color of the Jews is too strong to be ignored. Whether in times of peace or war, Jews as a whole lean left. This means that they are &quot;restless&quot;, like construction, love sports, have radical political leanings, and pursue &quot;equality&quot; economically. Why do the Jewish people have such characteristics? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it is related to the experience of the Jewish nation. After the Jews lost their country, they have been wandering throughout history. They have used scriptures and religious organizations to unite the ethnic group, rarely integrating into the local ethnic groups and culture (the Kaifeng Jews in history are an exception), and their relationship with the local people is somewhat estranged, and there is no negotiation. . Many Jews hope to establish a new country where everyone is &quot;equal&quot;, which is related to their messianic religious tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the rise of Zionism, a large number of Russian and Eastern European Jews rushed to Canaan, becoming the seeds of Israel&#39;s revival and founding. Israeli agriculture includes kibbutzim and moshav, which are collective agricultural cooperatives; industry is a mixed economic system dominated by state-owned enterprises. Diplomatically, Israel opposed colonialism. During the Cold War, Israel turned to the United States and became its ally in the Middle East. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In today&#39;s Israel, although the left wing is still a considerable force, it has faded much compared to the early days of the founding of the country. In a harsh environment surrounded by powerful enemies in the Middle East, Israel has taken some measures to turn to the right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kibbutz farms have begun to be privatized, their economic role is weakening, and their community functions are increasing. Israeli agriculture no longer relies on collectivization, but relies on science and technology to develop modern agriculture. Mixed ownership, in which state-owned enterprises account for a large proportion, has also transitioned to privatization, with private enterprises becoming the main force in the economy. Israel encourages entrepreneurship and attracts foreign investment, making the country a technological and entrepreneurial powerhouse in the Middle East. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to attract overseas Jews to return and provide financial support, Israel continues to strengthen its national and religious identity. Compromising with the ultra-Orthodox and granting non-soldiers the privilege of not being educated is largely to treat them as the &quot;condensation core&quot; of the Jewish nation. The Israeli government&#39;s financial support for the ultra-Orthodox is also related to the high birth rate among the ultra-Orthodox. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the Israeli government promulgated the &quot;Jewish Nation-State Law.&quot; Article 1 of the law stipulates that Israel is the historical home of the Jewish people and the nation-state of the Jewish people, and Hebrew is the official language of Israel (removing the official status of Arabic). This approach of strengthening ethnic distinctions runs counter to Western political correctness, and Netanyahu&#39;s government has been criticized as &quot;extreme right&quot; for this reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The left-wing forces in Israel reached their peak in the early days of the founding of the country, but have declined since then. By the 21st century, left-wing parties have basically lost their governing position. At the same time, Israeli Jews abroad fully embraced American left-wing culture and became the backbone of liberal circles. This divide is related to another reason why Jews tend to lean toward the left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jews have a good educational tradition (from the priestly class tradition), the overall cultural level is high, and a large number of intellectuals have emerged. In the field of natural sciences, outstanding achievements of Jewish scientists can often be seen. More Jews entered the intellectual class and became doctors, lawyers, professors, reporters, editors, artists and professional managers. Since the last century, the proportion of Jews in knowledge industries in European and American countries has been very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jews, whose number is not very large, are the nation with the highest proportion of intellectuals in the world. This is a remarkable achievement. Problems arise. Certain problems among intellectuals (especially those in the humanities and social sciences) are evident among the Jewish community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a kind of childish disease among intellectuals, who are often obsessed with creating theories and are divorced from reality. They are eager to build a better world, but they are not very concerned about the costs and resistance in the real world, so they can only rely on the state to push it forward. Paying attention to plan construction and ignoring daily experience often results in disaster. Intellectuals often show love and compassion, and their exaggerated &quot;moral sense&quot; obscures rational thinking, which often makes them fall into sincere stupidity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jews cannot avoid these intellectual problems. They move around various countries, lack the accumulation of ancestral property in the countryside, are excluded by mainstream society, and can easily develop a &quot;nomad mentality.&quot; The homeless are dissatisfied with the existing order, lack feelings for the local culture, and lack interest in establishing and continuing their families. They just want quick success, and the loosening and disintegration of the old order is obviously to their advantage. The more wandering Jewish intellectuals are, the easier it is for them to create and spread radical ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese thinker Mencius once said, &quot;Those who have permanent property have perseverance, and those who do not have perseverance have no perseverance. If you don&#39;t have perseverance, you will do whatever it takes to ward off evil.&quot; This can also explain why many new immigrant groups are &quot;vagrants&quot; Mentality&quot;, while native peoples or old immigrants who have been rooted for generations tend to tend towards conservatism. Once wealthy Jewish businessmen from all over the world have taken root in a certain place for generations and have deep-rooted industries, they will also move closer to conservatives. The five wealthy Jewish business families in Hong Kong are considered to be old Hong Kongers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look back at Israel. Most of Israel&#39;s early immigrants were left-wing intellectuals. After a few generations, the law of &quot;perseverance comes to those who have perseverance&quot; began to take effect. Compared with overseas Jews, the local people have a long-term view and are pragmatic and cold-blooded in their approach. Many native Jews moved to the right. Diaspora Jews lack this sense of belonging, and intellectuals continue their left-leaning inertia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today’s diaspora Jews, especially young people, are almost liberal. They have complicated feelings about Israel. On the one hand, they recognize that Israel is the motherland to which they belong, and that a strong Israel can effectively deter anti-Semitic countercurrents. They also feel that the current Israeli government is too barbaric, cruel and inhumane. In every Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the protesters at the forefront are young Jewish people. However, this time, they paid a heavy price for their sincerity and kindness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The music festival tragedy stung many Western Jews. This is why wealthy American Jews and Jewish organizations immediately stopped funding universities when they heard they refused to condemn Hamas. Despite this, the public opinion of the American Jewish community is still left-leaning, and their habit of firmly supporting the Democratic Party may be difficult to change. The trend of &quot;Jews moving to the left and Israel moving to the right&quot; will continue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, it is emphasized that Jews as a whole are left-leaning, and there are still Jews who are moving toward the &quot;right&quot; ideological path.捍卫自由市场的大师米塞斯、哈耶克，两人有犹太血统；获诺贝尔经济学奖，向公众普及市场常识的弗里德曼，及自由至上主义哲学家安•兰德，他们也是犹太人。欧美思想界深刻反思犹太人左倾弊病的学者，也有不少犹太人。这些超越民族心理局限的智者，更值得人们重视。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[果敢同盟军为什么这么能打，他们打仗的钱又是哪来的？丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260332]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/4Xu03XgA21c9Frt8lwYWw3yzX5mJWg3WxMlVOdBF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/4Xu03XgA21c9Frt8lwYWw3yzX5mJWg3WxMlVOdBF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257400&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月28日，缅甸清水河，缅甸民2023年10月28日，缅甸清水河，缅甸民族民主同盟军成员与在前哨山上从缅族民主同盟军成员与在前哨山上从缅甸军队缴获的武器合影&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月27日，以果敢民族民主同盟军为首的缅甸民族地方武装发动了名为“1027联合行动”的军事行动，与缅甸军方在缅甸北部的腊戌、贵慨等地爆发了激烈交火。日前，缅军政府发言人佐敏吞已经承认，中缅边境地区的清水河已经被同盟军占据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自同盟军宣布对果敢地区发动全面进攻以来，掸邦北部的战斗愈演愈烈，一个少数民族联盟声称占领了四个城镇，和数十个军事哨所，封锁了通往中国的贸易路线。并且不断破坏政府军用于支援掸邦前线的道路、通信设施和桥梁。这使得缅甸军方不得不依赖空中运输力量对果敢首府老街进行支援，包括使用直升机运输物资、接走伤员和高官家属，甚至空投特战人员加强防御。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这可以说是缅甸自2021年昂山素季被军队抓捕后军政府面临的最大军事挑战。众所周知，2015年春节期间，果敢同盟军就曾发起军事行动，试图反攻他们自2009年失去的果敢自治区，却由于缅军全力绞杀导致行动失败，被迫撤离果敢地区，继续在萨尔温江沿岸的红岩游击区战斗。目前看来，这次果敢同盟军进攻果敢的强度和进展明显超过2015年，因此有不少人对同盟军实力大增颇为不解，围绕这一疑问甚至产生了各种阴谋论解释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;果敢同盟军为何显得实力大增，这一轮攻势为何如此强劲？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实果敢同盟军并没有突然变强。在2015年那次进攻老街的行动中，同盟军的三个主力旅就表现得相当不错。不仅拥有非常强的运动战能力，而且远程狙击手段也颇为娴熟，如此战斗力，离不开2010年同盟军重建后长期进行山地游击战的锤炼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，战斗力再强，军队也需要足够的经济基础供养。对于果敢同盟军的经济来源到底为何这个问题，外界了解甚少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;网络上流传果敢同盟军自2009年一直在原始森林里打游击，而事实上它仍保有一块比较固定的根据地，即著名的红岩区，位于果敢特区红星区东部，比邻中缅边境的怒江和白虎山，占地面积约为36平方公里。除了果敢境内的根据地，果敢同盟军还有其他的落脚点。掸邦东部第四特区自2009年后就允许同盟军领导机关和部分军队进入，第四特区现任政府主席林明贤为果敢同盟军创始人彭家声的女婿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在果敢同盟军控制的区域内，他们可以通过税收以及边境贸易的方式来筹措资金。除此之外，果敢同盟军也控制了萨尔温江和湄公河等流域的部分码头，既能用作物资中转，还可以收取过路费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外在2015年果敢冲突后，由于果敢同盟军在冲突中表现出了颇为不错的战斗力，于是被周边其他民族地方武装视为靠山，这些民族地方武装开始给果敢同盟军直接提供经济支持和后勤补给。果敢同盟军、若开军和德昂解放军进一步于2017年形成著名的三兄弟联盟（3BHA），随后经常相互协同作战，在财政和后勤上也互通有无。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;若开和德昂都有自己稳定控制的根据地，且根据地内拥有玉石翡翠、矿产、红木、茶叶、农产品、甘蔗制糖等第一产业、第二产业经济基础，也拥有边境贸易、特色旅游等第三产业，因此经济状况比根据地狭小的果敢同盟军自然好得多。他们对果敢同盟军的支持，无疑在总体上加强了整个联盟的实力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了三兄弟联盟之外，佤邦联合军和克钦独立军作为缅北民族地方武装中体量最大的两支，对于三兄弟联盟也颇有支持，这两支民地武装都有一定的军工制造能力，能自行生产轻武器、弹药甚至轻型火炮。缅北多个民族地方武装派系的不少后勤装备都有赖于克钦和佤邦的支持。已故的果敢同盟军创始人彭家声与克钦、佤邦领导人也有着不错的私交。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，区域内民族地方武装支持果敢同盟军的背后都有一个核心诉求，即希望果敢同盟军能够在缅甸政府军进攻时承担更多的压力。毕竟其他几支力量都有着稳固的根据地和族群人口，与政府军大打出手并不利于当地民生发展。而果敢同盟军“老家”丢了，剩下的地盘小，且有“打回老家”的诉求，显然更豁得出去。对果敢同盟军而言，哪怕连红岩根据地也丢了，大不了继续在游击区打游击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从本次“1027行动”的新闻画面来看，果敢同盟军并无明显的装备改善和提高，虽然部分武器有所更新，但仍是缅北常见的各种轻武器。至于作战装具、头盔以及新式军服，也是随处可以买到的民营低端产品。人员补充方面，近年来由于缅族内部分裂，果敢同盟军也开始招募非果敢人兵员，比如2022年成立的611旅，大部分成员都非果敢人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次果敢同盟军在武器装备上最大的升级其实是无人机，不过也是常见的商用型号。近年来，反政府武装开始在缅甸内战中大量使用无人机，尤其是军政府抓捕昂山素季后，昂山的支持者组成的人民防卫军（PDF）中颇有一些缅甸高校的知识分子和技术专家，他们通过购买零件能够自行制造无人机。其中还包括使用瓦楞纸蒙皮的固定翼无人机，由于本身金属件极少，在雷达面前几乎隐身。缅北民族地方武装也经常将这种无人机当巡飞弹使用，据说实战效果不错。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年后，果敢同盟军承担的角色类似于区域内民族地方武装的先锋军和教导队，通过不断的实战，一方面打开局面，一方面帮助其他友邻部队训练人员，因此战斗力一直非常稳定。 2017年3月，果敢同盟军曾突击老街赌场，造成三十多人伤亡，将赌场金库席卷一空，与赶来支援的缅甸政府军及亲政府的当地武装交火后，全身而退。所以在2023年10月27日这次冲突爆发前，果敢同盟军很可能已经具备了直接攻击老街的实力，他们等的可能就是一个合适的机会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老师，你为什么不让孩子课间离开教室？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260452]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;作为一名小学班主任，我感到最近教育界热点新闻颇多。先是“寂静无声的课间十分钟”引发热议，紧接着教师的“非教学任务”重负也冲上热搜。早前，某校对趴桌午休收费200元，也饱受争议。这几件事情在我看来，似乎有着千丝万缕的联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些孩子课间被禁锢在教室里甚至座位上，让网友们痛心疾首，回忆起自己童年自由的课间，不由得质问：为什么现在的孩子课间就不能无拘无束？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有媒体指出，部分家长动辄问责学校的做法难辞其咎。学校为降低安全事故，采取了简单粗暴的“一刀切”，禁止课间跑跳活动。至于运动能力发展滞缓、无处社交等慢性后果，学校是顾不上了。因此媒体呼吁，给学校管理松绑，做好责任划分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家长问责学校，确实是老师的切肤之痛。不久前的一个课间，我班上两名女孩手拉着手转圈圈，后来游戏升级，背对背转了起来。本是温馨美好的画面，但加速中，一名女孩摔到了地上，两颗门牙不幸磕碎。这一切我看得清清楚楚，不过，是通过走廊里的录像。事发之时，我正在楼下，跨学科带另一个班上体育课。学生牙齿已是恒牙，家长很着急。我逐级上报给学校，安全办研判后表示：不属于安全事故，只是同学间玩耍发生的意外，双方家长协商即可。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一同玩耍的女孩家长提出治疗费用双方对半分，但受伤女生的家长表示因为意外是在学校发生，学校也应负责。我三方周旋，很是为难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家长并非无理取闹，在我们常学习教育经验的欧美国家，理论上学校也要对校内意外事故负责。只是大部分家长不倾向于问责学校，而是以孩子成长中难免磕碰与伤痛的心态，自行协商。这些国家校园意外保险覆盖范围更广，能有效降低各方经济负担。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我认为，除了权责划分的软条件，师生比例、在校时长与校园场地等硬条件，也是影响学生课间自由的重要原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月3日，新华社发文《教育部回应“课间10分钟被约束”问题》。文中提出学校应“加强室外场所设施排查和人员值守……把安全事故风险降到最低，让孩子们快乐放心活动”，合情合理的一句话，却让我把心提到了嗓子眼：“人员值守”，是什么人员呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我校倒是从未因安全原因禁止学生课间活动，虽然追逐打闹也是万万不可的。但若是有班级流感等暴发，为避免交叉传染，师生课间都会紧张起来：老师要在厕所与走廊轮值，提醒学生如厕后用洗手液洗手，且不可在走廊逗留；相连两节课的老师要交接看班，确保教室有人看管。学生活动范围缩小，老师们的课间也被填满，无暇休息，还有同事在奔赴另一校区的教室时扭伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不少教师常在各社交媒体上追问：“什么时候老师才能只做教书育人的工作？”课间时刻看护学生，是老师的工作吗？趴桌午休收费事件，清晰地展示了这背后的矛盾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时热搜一出，相关部门工作人员迅速回应，称收费合理，经政府批准。午休收费主要考虑到课后老师的加班工资，而且即使有费用补贴，许多老师也并不愿意看午休。舆论却不买账，网友疑惑：学生自行午休，需要老师看护什么？不是一起休息吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;且不说有的学校不允许看管老师休息，就算学校“开恩”，安顿好三四十余名学生后，再提着心眯一会，和自行午休绝不是一种感受。学生在校午休，实质上就是增设了一个大课间；而只要学生在学校，就是学校的安全责任，并由老师直接承担。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;政府或学校可以通过补贴购买老师的午休时间，以保障学生安全。但七零八碎的课间，老师为了按时到达下一堂课的教室，或略微与学生交流，便不可能随学生奔赴室外场所活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在发达国家，课间与午休确实都是由老师看护的，但他们大多采取包班制，“一班一师”，老师随班而动。而我国教师以科目划分，教师需要跨班、跨年级教学。奔走于不同教室甚至校区之间，往往就要耗费掉一整个课间，课间看护学生便成了“不可承担之重”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;包班制优点显著：教师对学生的了解更全面，师生能缔结更深连接；多科目教学有利于培养学生跨学科意识，也避免教师职业倦怠。为何在我国难以推行呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，考试选拔制度把压力下放到了小学。老师只专注一门科目，能更熟悉“考点”，方便应试。其次，欧美国家大多采取小班制教学。而以我所在的这家普通公立小学为例，每班不少于50名学生。最后，欧美小学大多只上半天课，老师看管完半天学生，下午便拥有完整的备课等时间。而为配合我国家长工作作息，从早读到午休，再到延时服务，小学生的在校时长可达十小时。如果一名教师要包下50名学生全天的课程与看护工作，精神紧张不说，改作业和备课是绝没时间的。更何况，老师们要承担的非教学类工作也已太多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;校园场地不足也是限制学生课间自由的重要原因之一。现阶段学生人数多，校园规模也大。在寸土寸金的城市里，学校的教学楼往往有四五层。许多老学校为了应对教育局传递的扩招压力，在原有的面积上进行扩建：把楼建得更高，操场和篮球场面积却往往还是几十年前的大小。如此一来，连上体育课的几个班都要抢位置，更别说十分钟的课间学生们蜂拥而出了。若从四五楼过关斩将冲到篮球场，球还没摸上，预备铃就又响了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，除了教室在一楼的幸运儿，大部分学生的活动空间就被限制在了教室门外的走廊上。众多学生若是在如此狭小的空间里奔跑，踩踏与冲撞事件发生的概率不堪设想。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今我国出生率下降，也许会成为推行“包班制”的契机。但伴随出生率下降的，也有家长工作压力的增加，社会养育成本的提高；学生在校时长与教育财政投入难以迅速改变，校园户外空间规划等也较难迅速改观。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在现行条件下，我有一些不成熟的课间小尝试：教孩子们不需要大空间的肢体游戏，如“萝卜蹲”、脚部“石头剪刀布”等；课间轮流使用飞行棋等玩具。在学校层面，也许可以调整出更多15分钟的“大课间”，组织班级轮流下楼；若有财力，可聘用课间管理人员，加强看护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社会舆论对课间活动的关注，反映出国民对教育的关注上升。但要把课间还给学生，绝不只是呼吁学校放开手脚、家长不要苛责老师就能解决的。提高学生课间活动的安全性，扩大课间活动空间，把部分责任从老师身上收走，将老师还给学生，才能切实让学生在课间自由奔跑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为广东省深圳市小学教师）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目期待您的来稿。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说｜陈来：文化保守主义和文化开放主义都是我的立场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260488]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73440&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70249&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/9ca8375979.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;September 27, 2021, Qufu, Shandong, the 7th Nishan World The first high-end dialogue of the Civilization Forum, Chen Lai, Dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Tsinghua University..jpg&quot; alt=&quot;September 27, 2021, Qufu, Shandong, the 7th Nishan World Civilization Forum, Dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies, Tsinghua University Chen Lai. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/ 9ca8375979.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258047&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 27, 2021, Qufu, Shandong, seventh Chen Lai, Dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies at Tsinghua University, attended the Nishan World Civilization Forum. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;Doctoral File&lt;/h5>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Chen Lai was born in Beijing in 1952 and his ancestral home is Wenzhou, Zhejiang. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·1973-1976, at the Central South Institute of Mining and Metallurgy (now Central South University of Mining and Metallurgy) University) Department of Geology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·1978-1981, studied as a graduate student in the Department of Philosophy, Peking University, and stayed at Teach in school. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·In 1985, he received a doctorate in philosophy from the Department of Philosophy of Peking University, becoming the first person in New China to A self-trained Doctor of Philosophy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·In 1986, he was appointed associate professor of the Department of Philosophy of Peking University, and in 1990 he was appointed as professor of the Department of Philosophy of Peking University . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·In 1991, he was awarded &quot;Chinese Ph.D. with Outstanding Contributions&quot; by the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council and the National Education Commission. Degree Recipient”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·In 1993, he was rated as a doctoral supervisor by the Academic Degrees Office of the State Council. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;·Transferred to Tsinghua University in 2009 and currently serves as deputy director of the Academic Committee of Tsinghua University and Tsinghua University Senior professor of university liberal arts, dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies at Tsinghua University, and professor of the Department of Philosophy at Tsinghua University. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chen Lai, dean of the Institute of Chinese Studies at Tsinghua University, is renowned for his research on Confucian philosophy since 1980. Since the beginning of the 1990s, I have been thinking about a question: In a modern society, what can traditional culture still do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Reform and opening up brought a &quot;cultural craze&quot; to the ideological circles at that time. Chen Lai remembers that the most popular one was the editor-in-chief of the &quot;Towards the Future&quot; series at the time. Bao Zunxin said, &quot;When he went to Peking University and said a word, the crowd applauded.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The school of thought, represented by Bao Zunxin and others, believes that Confucianism is incompatible with modern spirit, which has caused the decline of society, the ignorance of the public and the country&#39;s decline in modern times. Being poor and weak needs to be reviewed or even abandoned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the beginning, Chen Lai was just a bystander of the &quot;cultural craze&quot;. He is the first independently trained doctor of philosophy in New China. In the autumn of 1977, Chinese colleges and universities resumed postgraduate enrollment, and Chen Lai read the news in the newspaper. A week later, he went from his workplace in the eastern suburbs of Beijing to register at Peking University in the western suburbs of Beijing, and finally chose the Chinese philosophy major. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Philosophy is the traditional strength major of Peking University. After the major restructuring of departments in 1952, all philosophy teachers from universities across the country gathered at Peking University. In the following years, the Department of Philosophy at Peking University was the only philosophy department in the country. A large number of outstanding scholars such as Tang Yongtong, Feng Youlan, Jin Yuelin, Zhu Guangqian, Zhang Dainian, Ren Jiyu, etc. gathered in Yanyuan, which can be called the &quot;Jixia Academy of the 20th century&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the resumption of enrollment in the late 1970s, the Chinese Philosophy Teaching and Research Office, where Zhang Dainian was the director, enrolled the first 10 graduate students, and Chen Lai was one of them. Chen Lai recalled that more than 200 people applied for the History of Chinese Philosophy exam at Peking University this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the context of Western modernization thoughts constantly attacking the Chinese cultural world, Chen Lai returned to Chinese tradition and completed his doctoral thesis &quot;Study on the Philosophy of Zhu Xi&quot; in 1985 , made a detailed and detailed investigation of Zhu Xi&#39;s philosophical thoughts and development. Soon after, he visited Harvard University for two years. After noticing the &quot;cultural craze&quot; in China and the ubiquitous Christian tradition in the United States, he began to think about the relationship between traditional culture and modern society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, in the &quot;cultural craze&quot; in China, an important issue was how to promote cultural modernization, and how to treat traditional Confucianism and traditional culture was the focus of debate. The opinions of Bao Zunxin and others once prevailed. When many scholars were &quot;cutting their ties&quot; with Confucianism, Chen Lai&#39;s voice seemed out of place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1987, at the &quot;China in the New Era&quot; international symposium held in Manila, Philippines, Chen Lai submitted a paper &quot;Review and Prospect of Modern Chinese Thought&quot;, It opposes the complete eradication of traditional culture, including Confucianism, advocates the protection of traditional culture, holds a cultural conservatism stance, and boldly makes the judgment that &quot;the greatest condition for the revival of traditional thought is modernization.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In February of the following year, at the International Symposium on &quot;Issues and Prospects of the Development of Confucianism&quot; held in Singapore, in response to the views of Bao Zunxin and others, Chen In response, he submitted a paper &quot;Confucianism and its Positioning in a Multicultural Structure&quot;. He talked about the spread of money worship, utilitarianism, opportunism and undisguised greed in society, and the young generation was at a loss in an atmosphere of emptiness. Siblings. It is precisely in this utilitarian trend and value rupture that the value rationality of Confucianism can provide a set of ethical values ​​and a humanistic worldview that are compatible with modernization reforms and guide the spiritual direction of contemporary Chinese people. He pointed out that modern society is a multicultural society, in which Confucianism does not propose specific designs for reform, but rather proposes a humanistic worldview that complements reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To this day, China&#39;s ideological circles are still digesting the legacy of the &quot;cultural craze&quot; many years ago. The direction of history is as he judged, and the craze for traditional culture continues to this day. Chen Lai is worried: &quot;In every era and every activity, when someone advocates it, some people will excessively push these things to extremes. This is worthy of vigilance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Mr. Zhang For classes, read Mr. Feng’s book”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the degree system was restored, You applied for a graduate degree in the Philosophy Department of Peking University and later became the first independently trained doctor of philosophy in New China. Can you talk about your educational experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am the first batch of graduate students after the reform and opening up. In October 1977, the country officially announced that it would recruit college students through the college entrance examination. A month later, &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; published another news, which was to resume the postgraduate enrollment system. At the time of admission, because there was no official document stating the nature of the postgraduate degree, we all thought that this postgraduate degree was equivalent to the Soviet associate doctoral degree. Associate doctoral students were recruited from universities in the 1950s after the country learned from the Soviet Union&#39;s experience. They are equivalent to doctoral students in the West, because in the Soviet Union, there were full doctorates on top of associate doctoral degrees, and they almost required professors. At that time, the personnel treatment for returning to China after obtaining an associate doctoral degree in the Soviet Union was equivalent to that for those who obtained a doctoral degree in Western countries. However, by 1957, this system was abolished, and associate doctorates were no longer recruited. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;When we entered school, we also thought it was based on the associate doctorate. Everyone has higher expectations for themselves, and they are all based on the standard of a doctorate. Asked by myself. It wasn’t until the second semester of the second year of graduate school that the country introduced a new system, saying that our first batch of graduate students were master’s students, which was not equivalent to associate doctorate students in the Soviet Union, but was one level lower than doctorate students in the United States. At that time, everyone still Not so satisfied. But we are disappointed. In terms of professional attainments, our first batch of graduate students strived to reach the Soviet Union&#39;s associate doctorate level at the master&#39;s level, which is close to the level of American doctorates. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;What was the opportunity to continue studying for a PhD? What were the criteria for awarding doctorates at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After graduating from graduate school in the fall of 1981, I stayed at Peking University to teach. The next year, the school announced the list of the first batch of doctoral supervisors. With the doctoral supervisors, it was stated that they would continue to award doctorates. I also decided to give it a try. Later, I was changed from a teacher to a doctoral candidate, and my original salary was paid as usual. There was nothing special about it. In addition to English writing and speaking courses, I basically focus on writing my doctoral thesis. At that time there were no clear criteria for awarding degrees. Now when you are studying for a Ph.D., you will have clear requirements for being awarded a Ph.D. after being admitted. For example, Tsinghua University School of Humanities stipulates that the number of words for a doctoral thesis should be between 150,000 and 200,000 words. We didn&#39;t establish it in this way when we were in school, so we relied on our own imagination. Referring to the requirements of the Soviet Union&#39;s associate doctorate, we probably had to write about 200,000 words. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;What do you think are the characteristics of the education you received at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The education we received is different from that of Chinese students in the 1950s and 1960s. Likewise, previous education was severely disrupted and academically weak. Speaking of my major in Chinese philosophy, there were two old gentlemen at that time, one was Mr. Feng Youlan and the other was Mr. Zhang Dainian. Mr. Zhang gave us two courses: Historical Materials of the History of Chinese Philosophy and Methodology of the History of Chinese Philosophy. Mr. Feng stopped taking classes because he was older. Once upon a time, a reporter summarized my words and said that the characteristic of our postgraduate studies was &quot;taking Mr. Zhang&#39;s class and reading Mr. Feng&#39;s books.&quot; Mr. Feng and Mr. Zhang were already leading scholars in our discipline in the 1930s, so the professional education we received was directly connected to the academic and educational traditions of the 1930s and 1940s, while those students in the 1950s received It was an education influenced by Soviet experts. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;What role did these two gentlemen play in your life? What learning methods did you learn from them? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mr. Zhang is my mentor, from scratch to PhD degree , Mr. Zhang’s academic thoughts and academic methods had a great influence on me. He specifically guided me from the primary stage of learning to the advanced stage. After graduation, I worked as an assistant to Mr. Feng, mainly helping him compile the &quot;New History of Chinese Philosophy&quot;. I took the initiative to learn from Mr. Feng through conversations, how to learn from him and how to think philosophically. Unlike Mr. Zhang, Mr. Feng helped me rise to a higher level after I had already reached a relatively advanced stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Mr. Zhang&#39;s academic method can be said in one sentence to be &quot;easy to learn and think deeply, and know what he means.&quot; The original words of this sentence come from Sima Qian&#39;s &quot;Historical Records&quot;: &quot;If you don&#39;t love to learn and think deeply, and know its meaning in your heart, you will be short-sighted and ignorant.&quot; Mr. Zhang extracted the eight words &quot;Love to learn and think deeply, and know its meaning in your heart&quot; to emphasize research. When studying the history of Chinese philosophy, on the one hand, we must conduct an in-depth and detailed interpretation of the literature to grasp its original meaning; on the other hand, we must use a clear logical analysis method to explain it layer by layer, and we must not swallow it in a hurry or explain it vaguely. Confused, this clear logical analysis method was called &quot;analyzing names and analyzing principles&quot; in ancient China. This is the fundamental method and attitude for studying and researching the history of Chinese philosophy. It can also be said to be the basic method I learned from Mr. Zhang. My doctoral thesis &quot;Study on Zhu Xi&#39;s Philosophy&quot; is to study Zhu Xi&#39;s philosophy using the method of &quot;love to learn and think deeply, and know the meaning from the heart&quot;, which fully reflects Mr. Zhang&#39;s influence on me. Mr. Feng has been a philosopher for a long time, and his research focuses on thinking about the realm of life in philosophy. Later I published another book called &quot;The Realm of Being and Absence&quot;. This &quot;realm&quot; is the &quot;realm&quot; of &quot;realm&quot;. When I was studying Wang Yangming, I put the issue of realm at the center. This was also inspired by Mr. Feng&#39;s The influence of realm emphasis. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a teacher now, what methods do you teach your students? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Now I ask students to still emphasize Mr. Zhang’s method, because Mr. Zhang’s method helps students move from the primary stage to the advanced stage. The only way is to lay the foundation, and Mr. Feng’s method is a higher-level choice. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73441&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70250&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/8a9509b256.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG111388227602.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;June 19, 2022, parents with their children Visiting the Confucius Museum in Qufu City, Shandong Province. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/13/8a9509b256.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258048&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;June 19, 2022 On the same day, parents took their children to visit the Confucius Museum in Qufu City, Shandong Province. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cultural openness is also my stance&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the reform and opening up, the discussion on &quot;tradition and modernity&quot; was very intense. In your 1987 article &quot;Review and Prospect of Modern Chinese Thought&quot;, you made &quot; &quot;The greatest condition for the revival of traditional thought is modernization&quot;, holding a cultural conservatism stance and opposing the complete eradication of tradition. Why did you choose this stance at that time? Has this position been established since your research on Zhu Xi? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The relationship between tradition and modernity was the most heated discussion in academic circles in the 1980s Regarding the issue, I started doing research on Zhu Xi in 1979, and when I completed it in 1985, I still didn’t have such a position. It wasn’t until 1986 that I visited Harvard University in the United States and observed that Christian traditions are ubiquitous in modern society in the United States. This made me think about the relationship between tradition and modernity, and whether we must completely oppose tradition. Only by completely breaking away from tradition like the New Culture Movement can we move towards modernization. Some people at that time believed that tradition was feudalism and that we must be more resolute in our anti-feudalism in order to move toward openness and modernity. I wrote some articles at that time, firmly opposing the complete eradication of tradition, and I was still writing articles on this stance until the 1990s. This is parallel to my academic research. On the one hand, I have relatively pure academic research, and on the other hand, I continue to participate in discussions of social and cultural trends of thought. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It should be said that I have two positions, one is cultural conservatism, and the other is cultural openness. I would like to emphasize cultural conservatism. American sociologist Daniel Bell once said that cultural conservatism is mainly aimed at the cultural tendency of over-commercialization in modern society, emphasizing authority and cultural value in culture, and focusing on protecting the value of traditional culture. . However, since the mid-1990s, some dogmatists have stigmatized cultural conservatism, calling it extreme retroism and conservatism. This is wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;mentioned at that time that &quot; Is &quot;conservative&quot; a bit sensitive? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The concept of &quot;conservatism&quot; does not seem to mean much in modern China. Very positive, but in Western concepts, &quot;conservative&quot; is not necessarily a bad word, but can reflect positive values. Cultural conservatism is a cultural attitude that values ​​the culture that humans have created and inherited throughout history. I emphasized from the beginning that cultural conservatism is not political conservatism and has nothing to do with politics. However, when some people hear cultural conservatism, they think it is against reform and opening up. In fact, this is not what it really means. It is about culture. value. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;You mentioned in the Qizhi interview that you suffered attacks from some scholars because of your insistence on Chinese culture in the late 1980s. For example, you mentioned that in those years, your important academic works also won awards in various awards. Only the third prize can be awarded. With the development of the times, your position has gradually been recognized and realized. Have you personally experienced the process of moving from the edge to the center? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The description from edge to center is not appropriate and I was shocked. At that time, I was not on the edge. Now that I am not affected by it, I cannot be said to be in the center. These blows only affected my personal situation and did not affect my own academic development and progress. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;You have always been firm in your stance. Many people may have stopped speaking out after being hit. Why are you so persistent? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because what I said is right, on the contrary, those things that hit me I find their behavior very despicable, but I don’t care that much. I will do my own thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In recent years, traditional culture has become more and more popular among young people In your opinion, what changes have occurred in the “traditional culture craze” in China? Which of these are exciting, and which are cause for alarm? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I can intuitively feel that young people are becoming more and more interested in elements of traditional culture. Interests, like wearing Hanfu, etc. In principle, it is gratifying to absorb the elements of traditional culture and adopt them in today&#39;s cultural forms. For example, many of the cultural and creative products in various places are related to local cultural traditions or Chinese cultural traditions. . &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for what we need to be vigilant about, in abstract terms, it is the promotion of traditional culture, which should be more natural and should not be blunt or rigid. Excessive promotion away from natural needs. For example, in the past few years, there were many classic reading classes for children, which required children to memorize hundreds of thousands or even 200,000 words. I think this is unnecessary. When children learn traditional culture, it becomes their values ​​in life, and it doesn’t matter how much they memorize. In every era and every activity, when someone advocates it, there will be people who push these things to extremes. This is something to be wary of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73442&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70251&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c856153e2f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG111457714756.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;October 4, 2023, Nanjing, Tourists wearing Hanfu visit the Laomendong Scenic Area. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;754&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/13/c856153e2f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258049&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 On the 4th, in Nanjing, tourists wearing Hanfu visited the Laomendong Scenic Area. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Confucianism is not about ideology”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What changes have occurred in society&#39;s attitude towards Confucianism in different historical periods? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The pre-Qin period was the growth period of Confucianism. Confucius founded Confucianism. Disciples continued to pass it on, but because it was in the Warring States Period, the ruling class at that time was particularly interested in military doctrine, that is, how to develop the military. They had a more positive attitude towards the Legalist thoughts of the pre-Qin era and felt that Legalist methods could be effective immediately. They were very interested in Confucianism. No interest. In the Han Dynasty, a unified country based on the system of prefectures and counties was formed. The ruling class deeply reflected on the rapid demise of the Qin Dynasty. At first, they wanted to replace Legalism with Taoism, but they soon found that the Taoist attitude was only suitable for There was no active governance strategy for the restoration of the economic ecology after the war, so Emperor Wu of the Han Dynasty decided to only respect Confucianism and regard Confucianism as the leading value. The following dynasties did not change much. They all used Confucian values ​​​​to implement state governance. Of course, they were not just Confucianists, but also absorbed Taoist and Legalist ideas. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In modern times, Western learning based on the Scientific Revolution and the Industrial Revolution entered China. The society was in a period of transformation, and the traditional society was going to Modern society based on the scientific revolution and technological revolution has some different attitudes towards traditional culture and traditional thoughts during this period. The most important one is total westernization, which takes a negative stance towards traditional Chinese culture including Confucianism. At the same time, there are also some The other type, with a relatively small number of people, adheres to Confucianism and traditional culture and has its positive significance - although the social foundation has changed, as a result of wisdom gained from historical human exploration of nature, society, life, including literature and art, Traditional culture and Confucianism are not meaningless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can it be understood as Are the values ​​advocated by Confucianism particularly important to social reform and transformation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s not just values, of course values ​​are included. The &quot;Review and Prospects of Modern Chinese Thought&quot; I wrote in 1987 was aimed at the reform issues at that time. At that time, some theorists actually put forward the slogan &quot;Everything depends on money.&quot; I emphasized at that time that &quot;all things are about money&quot; would never become the spiritual tradition of a great nation. The role of Confucianism in the process of modernization and reform is not to propose specific designs for reform, but to propose a humanistic worldview that complements reform. The task or function of Confucianism is not to directly promote reforms, but to provide a humanistic spirit that complements modernization reforms to guide people&#39;s general spiritual direction. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Confucianism does not have to be directly related to the social transformation of Westernization. Social modernization can occur while basic values ​​remain unchanged. of. For example, Japan&#39;s basic cultural values ​​did not change much from 1880 until its economic redevelopment in the 1960s. No region with a Confucian culture in Asia achieved modernization without first overthrowing Confucian culture. The success of modernization in regions and countries such as Hong Kong, South Korea, and Singapore has proven that societies that have grown up under the influence of Chinese culture can achieve modernization well. In a developed modern market economy, the general trend of commercialization makes the requirements of this society&#39;s moral norms and spiritual civilization more prominent than before. In the era of big pot rice, this problem is not prominent. Therefore, the value and significance of Confucian modernization are not just viewed from the coordinates of utilitarianism. The most important thing is that in an era when commercialization is prevalent, market economy and utilitarianism require a value system to constrain and regulate society as a whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now in the general sense From what angle do you consider the revival of Confucianism? Are there political factors? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To a large extent, it comes from philosophy or culture. Think about it, not politically. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The revival of Confucianism in the general sense began during the May Fourth Movement. Liang Shuming and Xiong Shili both wanted to inherit Confucianism philosophically. Tradition developed the New Confucianism of this era; culturally speaking, when we talk about the decline of Confucianism, it is mainly at the level of secular social culture, including the integrated forms of existence such as socialization, institutionalization, and secularization, including some aspects of all aspects of society. Basic institutions and some basic culture. Private schools, academies, etc. did not exist in the 1990s, but today there are already many. In fact, there is no shortage of metaphysical constructions of Confucian philosophy in the 20th century. The most important thing now is how to restore Confucianism as a life ethic to influence the public and society. Of course, it is impossible to completely restore, but it can be partially or improvedly restored. For example, the restoration of ancestral halls, academies, and private schools has its own positive significance today. The moral decline and value loss in society in recent years is not due to the lack of a few philosophers, but the lack of the cultural foundation of Confucianism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your opinion , Who should be responsible for the revival of Confucianism as a culture? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is not a single person, it can be a group, or it can be Social organizations, for example, many civil servants with various professions are now involved in the revival of Confucianism, including how to promote Confucianism into schools, villages, communities, and folk culture so that it can play a role in this era , there are many social forces doing this work now. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, I was in Shandong in September and went to Qufu Sage Education School. The philosophy of their two principals was to use Confucian concepts to Guiding education does not mean learning all the content, but using Confucianism to guide. Whether in primary school or middle school, the first class for students every day is to study Confucian classics, as well as some activities similar to meditation to help students become more stable and calm down for learning. It is easy for students to accept it, and parents also feel that students in this school are not impetuous and are relatively quiet. I think it is very effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to the power of the people , should the government promote it? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The government does not specifically use Confucianism as a guiding ideology for education. Instead, it is collectively referred to as Chinese cultural education. How are these policies implemented in the national education system? Courses require hours of study. It is useless to say that there are no hours of study. How are teachers trained? This is what the Ministry of Education can do. It is not difficult to provide teaching hours, develop teaching materials, and have trained teachers teach. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are in the book &quot;Watching the Value of Tradition&quot; When it comes to shaping the spiritual temperament of Chinese people, the most important thing is through education. Are you optimistic about rebuilding the value system of Confucianism through education? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are many aspects of work involved in reconstructing the value system of Confucianism. Primary school curriculum education is one aspect. Our emphasis on traditional culture in the past ten years has been more conducive to the creative transformation and innovative development of traditional Chinese culture in terms of educational environment. But this work also needs to be recognized by the entire society. From government leaders, institutional regulations and systems to grassroots school teachers, all must persist in order to do it well. This consensus is much better now than before, and we should be optimistic about rebuilding our cultural and educational system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you have the ultimate idea about social value rules? What kind of cultural structure is it? What role does Confucianism play in this? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My 1988 paper &quot;Confucianism in a Multicultural Structure&quot; As stated in &quot;And Its Positioning&quot;, my own wish is that in a new cultural structure, there will not only be institutionalized constructions such as democracy and science, but also the human interest motives provided by a rational economic structure. Confucianism has still become one of the sources of value for Chinese people, providing Chinese people with the principles of life, the meaning of life, principles and norms for dealing with the world, and even the basic attitude towards the universe, nature, society and human destiny. Today, our cultural structure is not like the single structure of traditional society. It must be a pluralistic structure. Confucianism is not intended to be an ideology, but to have a leading influence on the people as a cultural temperament and spiritual temperament. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Young people lie flat and need neither attention nor criticism&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From the perspective of students, young people nowadays are more willing to study economics and management, and it seems that they will not choose philosophy. The golden age of philosophy seems to have passed. Do you agree with this statement? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In every era, only a few people choose philosophy, and philosophy has always been It is not a popular knowledge, but a niche cultural field, but it plays a great role. Today&#39;s society is more utilitarian, so fewer people will choose it. This is a fact, but I think it doesn&#39;t matter, because it is pursued by a small number of people. But in terms of opportunities, the status of the Chinese nation in the world today is different. We who engage in philosophy are also more relaxed. We are not as squeezed by Western culture as before. What we are thinking about now is how to understand what we have learned over the years. The Western things are combined with our traditional things to form a new philosophical thinking. Therefore, it is an opportune time to study philosophy in today’s era. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;In addition to professional choices, when it comes to career choices, many young people also choose to &quot;lay down&quot; or become &quot;full-time children&quot;. Doesn&#39;t it seem to be in line with the &quot;hard work and enterprising&quot; in our traditional culture? What do you think? &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think these situations are surprising and I don’t need to pay attention to them. , no need to criticize. What we want to see is the diversity of employment, and everyone should have a variety of choices. As for choosing to live alone and stay full-time, one reason is that society has created conditions that allow children to live peacefully and have a guaranteed life. In fact, having children who live alone and work full time is not only inconsistent with the concepts in traditional culture, but also in line with the concepts of modern society. However, on the one hand, we cannot easily condemn those who care about their personal destiny. On the other hand, we must also encourage young people with strong idealism and willingness to take responsibility to pursue greater goals. For example, some students should be encouraged to teach wherever they are willing to go after graduation. &lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Now that school has started, what do you want to say to college students? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Lai: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think there is anything to worry about in professional studies. We still need to correctly establish three views, which have an important impact on life. From a small perspective, it is beneficial to personal mental health. Nowadays, many college students are mentally unhealthy. From a large perspective, it is to further develop social responsibilities and so on. In junior high school and high school, there were guidance from class teachers and parents. After reaching university, I think every college student still needs to pay attention to how to control the construction of his own three views. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安部就《电信网络诈骗及其关联违法犯罪联合惩戒办法（征求意见稿）》 面向社会公开征求意见]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260499]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 11:14:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In order to thoroughly implement the &quot;Anti-Telecommunications Network Fraud Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, the Ministry of Public Security, together with relevant competent authorities, recently The &quot;Joint Punishment Measures for Telecommunications Network Fraud and Related Illegal Crimes (Draft for Comments)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Punishment Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot;) was drafted and widely solicited opinions from the society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Punishment Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot; has a total of 19 articles, which mainly include six aspects: disciplinary principles, disciplinary objects, disciplinary measures, graded punishment, disciplinary procedures, and complaint verification. It follows the legal determination and excessive punishment. Principles of proportionate and dynamic management, clarifying the scope of individuals and units to be included in punishment targets, stipulating specific measures for financial, telecommunications network, and credit punishment, applying punishments at different levels according to the illegal behavior of punishment targets, standardizing procedures such as review and determination, punishment period and notification, and clarifying appeals , procedures and time limits for acceptance, verification, feedback and cancellation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Punishment Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot; insists on legal identification and prevention, strictly determines the scope of punishment objects and identification standards in accordance with the &quot;Anti-Telecommunications Network Fraud Law&quot;, and lists the specific behaviors that are subject to punishment in accordance with the law. , distinguishes the scope of review and identification of punishment objects by public security organs at or above the districted city level and public security organs at or above the provincial level, and effectively strengthens warning education to achieve the effect of preventing crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Punishment Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot; insists on graded punishment and proportional punishment for excessive punishment. For those who are held criminally responsible for committing telecommunications network fraud and related crimes, the punishment period is 3 years; If a person is identified as a subject of punishment by the public security organ at or above the municipal level, the period of punishment shall be 2 years. While comprehensively applying financial punishment, telecommunications network punishment, credit punishment, and incorporating financial credit information basic database and other disciplinary measures, the basic financial and communication services of the disciplinary targets are retained to ensure that their basic living needs are met and the appropriateness of the punishment is fully reflected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Disciplinary Measures (Draft for Comments)&quot; not only strengthens punishment according to law, but also implements dynamic management of disciplinary information data, clearly requires that the disciplinary basis, time limit, measures and appeal rights be informed in writing to the punished object, and The procedures and time limits for appeals, acceptance, verification, feedback and dismissal are clarified to fully protect the legitimate rights and interests of those being punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陈慧翎：日子是用来好好过的丨逝者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260372]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/YdHZeV8AZfOlptdOaA2uwe1vhw2Z1S3FmVWOCmql.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/YdHZeV8AZfOlptdOaA2uwe1vhw2 Z1S3FmVWOCmql. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chan Huiling (1975-2023) Taiwanese director and screenwriter&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, the Taiwanese idol drama &quot;Next Stop, Happiness&quot; quickly became popular as soon as it was aired, becoming the runner-up in the ratings of an idol drama in the history of Taiwanese television at that time. As this drama Director and screenwriter Chen Huiling has entered the audience&#39;s field of vision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Huiling grew up &quot;free-range&quot; and knew what her interests were early on. In the composition class in the first grade of middle school, she wrote a thick book because she wanted to express too many things. The teacher revised it very carefully and encouraged her to continue writing. This planted a seed in the heart of 13-year-old Chen Huiling - &quot;Ah, I can write. Then I will continue to write.&quot; In this way, Chen Huiling began to create her artistic world bit by bit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, when she first debuted in 2008, she won the Drama Program Director Award at the 43rd Taiwan Television Golden Bell Awards for her first drama work &quot;The Golden Thread&quot;. In the same year, his work &quot;Secret Conversations with My Boyfriend&#39;s Ex-Girlfriend&quot; won the Golden Bell Award for Miniseries Screenwriting and Editing. Therefore, &quot;Next Stop, Happiness&quot; is more like an opportunity for Chen Huiling to push her works to a more popular stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She always focuses on the subtle emotional exchanges between people. In the following three years, she created &quot;That Year, It Rained Never Stopped&quot;, which won the Drama Program Director Award at the 45th Taiwan TV Golden Bell Awards, the romantic drama &quot;The Money Worship Queen&quot;, and the feature film &quot;Moonlight in Jilin&quot; and other works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, Chen Huiling was diagnosed with cervical cancer. In the following 10 years, the disease recurred many times. The joke of fate did not stop her from creating and enjoying life: as soon as she finished her treatment, she would travel abroad while she was still in good condition. In 2016, she directed the unit drama &quot;Rolling Stone Love Story&quot;. In 2019, she starred in &quot;Your Child&quot; &quot;Not Your Child&quot; won the Golden Bell Award for Best Director again. In the interview, she mentioned her thoughts on the relationship between parents and children in the Chinese world - &quot;A baby will cry when it is hungry, but a teenager who longs for love cannot cry or scream? Our generation has already (in such an atmosphere) (Part 2) After finally growing up, do we still treat our children like this?&quot; In February 2023, she also went to Turkey to participate in the earthquake relief work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Chen Huiling, who has always shown an optimistic outlook, had not shared her anti-cancer journey on Facebook, we would not have imagined that the disease would have caused her so much suffering. &quot;The physical condition is not something you can control. Those who can maintain mindfulness, take deep breaths, and meditate when the pain makes you roll on the bed are capable people. I am just a mortal.&quot; Even so, she will still be troubled by the growth of her shaved hair. I felt happy because my blood test was normal and I had my eyebrows bleached. I was happy because I heard the teacher talk about her favorite Szymborska in the writing class. Illness can take away a healthy body, but it cannot take away the ability to perceive and convey happiness. She said, &quot;It would be good to move forward a little bit more each day. Even if it doesn&#39;t, it would be good. At least I am still alive and have finished chasing &quot;Fake&quot;. &quot;Face Girl&quot;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 3 pm on November 1, 2023, 48-year-old Chen Huiling passed away in a hospital in Taipei. The final moments were surrounded by family and friends. The splendid life did not want to be trapped in a small box, so she chose to be buried in a tree and return to the earth, which can accommodate all free souls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months before her death, Chen Huiling wrote on her Facebook, &quot;How precious life is, how lovely life is, life is not for complaining, life is for living well.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[常州通报“企业家约谈后坠楼身亡”事件：正核查案件办理情况]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260490]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 09:54:52&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, it has been reported online that Changzhou Holley Chairman Cheng Yong fell to his death after being interviewed, which has attracted public attention . On the evening of November 12, Changzhou Radio and Television Station’s WeChat public account “Zhongwu.com” issued a briefing on the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c09c94ce96d15a229789fd7f86242d29.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1448&quot; height=&quot;786&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c09c94ce96d15a229789fd7f86242d29.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258050&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the legal representative of Changzhou Huali Hydraulic Lubricating Equipment Co., Ltd. fell to his death after being interviewed. The Changzhou Municipal Party Committee and Government attach great importance to it and are organizing relevant departments to carry out investigations and disciplinary inspections in accordance with the law. The supervisory authorities are conducting in-depth verification of the handling of relevant cases, and adhere to the principles of seeking truth from facts and handling them conscientiously in accordance with rules, disciplines and laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to previous reports from Nanduwan Financial Society, at noon on November 11, Changzhou Huali Hydraulic Lubrication Equipment Co., Ltd. (referred to as &quot;Changzhou Holi&quot;) posted on the official WeChat public account that at 4 o&#39;clock in the morning that day At 36 minutes, the company chairman Cheng Yong jumped to his death. On the afternoon of the 11th, the relevant article was deleted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to an article published on Changzhou Holley’s official WeChat public account, the suicide note was signed at 0:24 a.m. on the 11th. At 4:36, Chengyong posted the last message in his life before jumping off the building. Screenshots show that jumping off the building was related to his recent interview with the Changzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the afternoon of the same day, Changzhou Holley staff confirmed the news of Cheng Yong’s death to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News, and said that the above-mentioned article was indeed officially released by the company, and the contents were the true expression of the company’s intentions. The person in charge of the company is handling related matters and does not have any more information at the moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, staff from the Propaganda Department of the Changzhou Municipal Party Committee also told reporters from Nanduwan Financial Society that they are currently understanding the situation and may issue a notice on the matter in the future. Reporters from Nanduwan Financial News repeatedly called the Changzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and the Changzhou Tianning District Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision, but there was no reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[重庆市政府原党组成员、副市长熊雪严重违纪违法被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260492]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 10:17:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission investigated Xiong Xue, a former member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Mayor of the Chongqing Municipal Government. Serious violations of discipline and law were investigated and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Xiong Xue lost his ideals and beliefs, deviated from his original intention and mission, had a weak political consciousness, disagreed with the Party Central Committee on major principles issues, engaged in &quot;seven things&quot;, formed cliques, and had a negative view of political achievements. Distortion, engaging in formalism, making false reports, resisting organizational review, and engaging in superstitious activities; violating the spirit of the eight central regulations and accepting banquets and services that may affect the fair execution of official duties; being disloyal and dishonest to the party, and not responding to organizational interviews and inquiries Explain the problem truthfully and conceal personal matters; accept gifts and gifts in violation of regulations, and obtain large returns through private loans; perform duties incorrectly; have a bad family tradition and ignore your spouse; be greedy, corrupt, and associate with unscrupulous businessmen Working together with others, they transformed public power into a tool for personal gain, engaged in power-for-money transactions, used their position to benefit others in terms of project contracting, land approval, etc., and illegally accepted huge amounts of property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiong Xue seriously violated the party&#39;s political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline and life discipline, constituted a serious job violation and was suspected of bribery crime, and did not restrain himself after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. Hands, serious nature, bad influence, should be dealt with seriously. In accordance with the &quot;Disciplinary Punishment Regulations of the Communist Party of China&quot;, the Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishments for Public Servants, and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided to expel Xiong Xue from the party; The treatment he enjoys shall be canceled in accordance with regulations; his illegal gains shall be confiscated; his suspected criminal issues shall be transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution in accordance with the law, and the property involved shall be transferred together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[常识的落脚地丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260476]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/0xtfslDmpgxIvEKPX7E3ucKcQTiHdKpooVdd1BPN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0xtfslDmpgxIvEKPX7E3ucKcQTiHdKpo oVdd1BPN. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256974&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 19, 2023, girls confided and comforted each other on the playground of Ugly Duckling Middle School &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Weng Huan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Related reports For details, see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/259838&quot; title=&quot;The Growth of the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;: Exploration and Thoughts on Preventing and Treating Teenage Depression in a School&quot;>;The Growth of the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;: 1 Exploration and reflections on the prevention and treatment of adolescent depression in one school&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is impossible for one school to cure adolescent depression.” A reader left a message after reading this magazine’s report on Ugly Duckling Middle School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;True. This was not Zhan Danian’s original intention when he founded this school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot; originally accepted so-called &quot;problem children&quot; that ordinary schools and families were unable to take care of. Zhan Danian discovered that the rate of depression among students has increased in recent years and was determined to help them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, he hopes to use the forum to arouse more people&#39;s attention to the phenomenon of teenage depression. A month ago, I heard Zhan Danian talk about this topic for the first time on the phone. I admired this middle-aged educator for his sense of social responsibility - but also secretly thought: a private school aimed at helping &quot;problem students&quot; , do you have enough professionalism and experience to share (on dealing with student depression)? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the three or four days I went to Yiliang, my doubts were solved bit by bit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on the day we arrived at the school, a small book-sized window at the gate was opened, revealing the smiling faces of several children: Auntie, we will ask someone to open the door for you. After entering the door, Zhan Danian was standing by the playground. When they saw me, they started introducing me directly from the teaching building. When he walked into the psychology room, several children greeted him with a smile, &quot;Zhan Zhan, do you still remember me?&quot; In the painting room inside, two boys were quietly drawing mandalas without raising their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During those days of &quot;ugly duckling&quot;, students were all at ease wherever they went. Except for military training and physical education classes, which require gathering on time, at other times, these children cannot see the tension of being disciplined, the exhaustion after excessive homework, and social numbness. It was the &quot;Class Culture Week&quot; and there were many children drawing in the stairwells and dormitories during class. During the interview, looking at their relaxed expressions as they chatted easily, and greedily taking a few deep breaths of the warm air on the mountain, I really felt: This is a normal campus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you get closer to these children, you will find that many of them are &quot;ridden with holes.&quot; A colleague read the manuscript and said, &quot;Today&#39;s children, aged fourteen or fifteen, have so many things on their minds...&quot; In fact, every child has an interesting soul. &quot;Things on the Heart&quot; are related to their tortuous experiences and are also their normal reactions to this weird world. It would be strange if all the excitement, curiosity, and attempts are constantly broken, misinterpreted, and &quot;formatted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back to my doubts at the beginning of the interview. Xu Kaiwen, a Ph.D. in clinical psychology at Peking University, followed up on 10 families who lost their only child during the fifth anniversary of the Wenchuan earthquake. He found that families that recovered well from the trauma had “improved living conditions and localized emotional regulation, like playing mahjong. This kind of down-to-earth social support system may be more effective than psychological counseling.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is no different for teenagers. In addition to children with symptoms of severe depression who should be treated through medical means, most teenagers need nothing more than understanding and listening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Plenty of sunshine, regular physical exercise, teaching that is not aimed at cramming or exam-taking, time for daze, opportunities to express without fear, and equality between teachers and students. Whether it&#39;s a teacher, a classmate or a parent, there is always someone who understands you. When you feel down, use him as your tree hole or &quot;handrail&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These should be the growth atmosphere that every school-age child and teenager has the right to enjoy. Now it has become a luxury and even consensus cannot be reached. Rather than visiting the Ugly Duckling Middle School in search of a cure for children’s depression, it would be better to see how a shielded educational common sense is put into practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days before publishing this article, Zhan Danian received another WeChat message from the parent of a first-year high school student. The latter told him that another student in his child’s school chose to leave in a decisive way. &quot;As parents, we are all frightened.&quot; This parent&#39;s child was also diagnosed with severe depression through a scale when he was in seventh grade. The child&#39;s parents have been committed to changing their relationship with their child. The family atmosphere is very good now. &quot;But we are in a county, and we are very scared when such a situation occurs. How should we accompany our children?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, they are not alone. After the forum, in addition to the WeChat group of 500 participants who continued to share various mutual aid information, a new WeChat group was added, and everyone discussed establishing an alliance to prevent and treat youth depression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We need to look for technologies and methods, hoping that the group will get better and better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>