<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[花里胡哨blingbling的美甲，如今成了猛男的最爱？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258696]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/28304bdf2ee9033aa0ddc5cfd9f349a4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/16/28304bdf2ee9033aa0ddc5cfd9f349a4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254160&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the nude pink nail caps, flowing silver metal lines outline the outline of the nails; the fingers are spread out, and the bright manicure with cool graffiti patterns is eye-catching; He is holding the steering wheel of a luxury car and wearing a famous watch, but the most eye-catching thing is the matte black manicure on his hands...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Who do you think it is when you see these pictures? A woman is sharing her latest manicures. In fact, the owners of these beautiful manicures are all men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Open a social media platform and search for &quot;boys&#39; manicure&quot; and you will open the door to a new world. More and more men are showing off their manicures on the Internet, just like showing off their latest clothes or new limited-edition shoes. Some are showing off the same manicure as a couple with their girlfriends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Whether it is a &quot;straight man&quot; with a big beard or a &quot;little fresh guy&quot; who is meticulous in dressing up, everyone does not worry about being criticized because of the manicure on their hands. People say &quot;girl&quot;, more and more men are enjoying the satisfaction brought by exquisite manicure. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Style on the fingertips&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In modern times, doing manicure is a matter of one&#39;s will Things, but in ancient times, manicure was not something you could just do if you wanted to. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In ancient Egypt, nail color symbolized personal identity and status. Archaeologists have discovered that Nefertiti, the legendary Egyptian beauty with great beauty and queen of Pharaoh Akhenaten, used henna plant juice to dye her fingernails and toenails rust red, symbolizing of nobility and power. Red manicure is exclusive to the royal family, and civilians are restricted to using light colors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is even more unexpected is that in ancient times, manicure was not an exclusive decoration for women. The history of men&#39;s manicure can be traced back to ancient Babylon around 3200 BC. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, men had to do manicure before going to war. This was one of the important rituals. Soldiers will paint their nails in different colors according to their class: the upper ones will be painted black, and the middle ones will be painted green. They believe that this can intimidate the enemy and enhance morale. It can be seen from this that those who do manicures are the real macho men. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In ancient my country, manicure was also a symbol of class. As we all know, working people work with their hands, and there is no way to grow or dye nails. Therefore, manicures are mostly popular among ladies from famous families. Zhang Hu, a poet of the Tang Dynasty, wrote in a poem: &quot;The ten slender fingers are red as jade bamboo shoots, and the flying geese are gently restrained in the green strings.&quot; The &quot;red jade bamboo shoots&quot; in the sentence refers to the bright red nails painted with kodan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Are men in ancient my country insulated from manicures? Not necessarily. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the north wall of Cave 335 of the early Tang Dynasty Dunhuang murals, the ministers in front of the emperor under the seat of Manjushri Bodhisattva have feathers on their heads, and one of them has his fingernails painted black. Not only that, the princes of ethnic minorities under the &quot;Vimalakīrti Sutra&quot; on the south side of the east wall of Cave 220 in the early Tang Dynasty in the Dunhuang murals, and the Uighur king and his attendants in the statue of the Xixia king on the south side of the east wall of Cave 409 of the Western Xia Dynasty, all have stained hands. nail. Some scholars believe that the color of fingernails should initially be red because the pigment gradually turns black due to long-term oxidation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It can be seen that &lt;/span>; from ancient times to the present, from China to the West, men’s manicure is not an unheard-of, absurd and weird thing. The &quot;hippie&quot; movement that was popular in the West in the 1960s and 1970s brought men&#39;s manicure into the field of popular culture. The representative figure of &quot;hippie&quot; culture, rock singer Bob Dylan, appears in public with bright and colorful manicure. British rock icon Mick Jagger also loves to show off his glossy black manicure. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Under the guidance of these rock masters, fingernails, which are about 1 square centimeter in size, have gradually become a new position for men to express themselves and show their personality. On social media, many men share their manicures. Fashion trendsetters prefer bright black, tough lines, and graffiti patterns, while sophisticated men prefer everyday nude styles. Showing your own fashion style and trendy charm through personalized nail art styles has become a new way for men to express themselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/e0288260745ac57acd46fb38166b5b2d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/e0288260745ac57acd46fb38166b5b2d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254162 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;Manicure is an attitude towards life&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is a scene in the 15th episode of &quot;Friends&quot; Season 4. Chandler follows Rachel to the salon and is Rachel flirted with trying a manicure. Seeing all the women coming and going in the store, Chandler felt a little uncomfortable. While complaining that &quot;there are no other men here for manicures&quot;, he blew on the manicures. The micro-expressions on his face revealed his secret inner thoughts. . Rachel choked him back: &quot;Getting manicures won&#39;t hurt your masculinity!&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In recent years, the &quot;appearance economy&quot; has exploded&lt;/span>;, and many Men are paying attention to their beauty needs. More and more people are using skin care products and going to beauty salons to receive beauty services. Abroad, it is very common for men to have manicures. Hammer &amp; Nails, a men&#39;s specialty store specializing in hand and foot care, already has more than 200 stores in the United States. Even during the 2021 COVID-19 pandemic, business revenue still maintained a huge growth of 270%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A survey by the Japanese beauty industry-related research organization &quot;HOTPEPPER Beauty Academy&quot; pointed out that in 2022, 5.7% of Japanese men have used manicure services, and on average, one person in less than 20 people has done so. Nail art, this has also hit a new high in the past five years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Looking back at my country, data from the young people’s lifestyle platform “Little Red Book” shows that between July 2021 and June 2022, the number of searches for “men’s manicure styles” increased for half a year. A month-on-month increase of 302%. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After experiencing the first manicure in his life, a man posted a post with emotion, &quot;I always thought it would be weird for boys to do manicures, but I didn&#39;t expect them to look good.&quot; He added #boymanicure It’s also a cool label; there are also men who said that their first manicure was brought to them by their girlfriends. After the experience, they exclaimed “it smells so good” and posted pictures of couple’s manicures to spread the word; there are also male fans. When I get a manicure, I think that after my nails are trimmed, polished, and painted with nude nail polish, my hands will look cleaner and more refined, making me more popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Internet social media provides technical support for people to construct their ideal self, and its rise has also made modern people&#39;s aesthetic standards gradually become symbolic. The popularity of manicures for men shows that manicures are gradually getting rid of the labels of &quot;exclusively for women&quot; and &quot;girly&quot;, and are endowed with social symbols such as &quot;cool&quot; and &quot;trendy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people are eyeing the trend of male manicure and are preparing to &lt;span>; take the plunge. According to Beiqing.com, Zhang, a student from the Academy of Fine Arts, started a business in a Shenzhen market. He set up a stall in the trunk of his car, specializing in male manicures. Similarly, a group of boys from Southwest Airlines Vocational College formed a club called &quot;Boy Manicure Group&quot; to provide manicure services to teachers and students. Classmate He Hao is a member of the club. He said, &quot;I feel great when I bring happiness and beauty to others!&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For students like Zhang and He, In the eyes of generations of young people, beauty is gender-neutral. As an expression of the pursuit of beauty, manicure is also a form of artistic expression to a certain extent. &quot;On the road of pursuing art, we can enjoy ourselves as much as we can, and everyone who loves beauty is equal.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《坠楼死亡的剖析》： 一部重在“关系”的电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259007]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/o9fOt7ZSGsFEBUHXLJ0AP8ZJyY9J2ZooYQNktZA0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/o9fOt7ZSGsFEBUHXLJ0AP8ZJyY9J2 ZooYQNktZA0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Palme d&#39;Or award-winning work &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; at the 2023 Cannes Film Festival is like a juggler throwing three balls at the same time. The execution is dazzling. It is both a strong plot thriller about an unsolved case and a family film about a broken marriage. In terms of scene presentation, it is also a legal drama in which all dramatic conflicts occur in the courtroom. Director Justine Trier is indispensable for being able to accomplish these three missions at the same time. The Cannes jury awarded her the grand prize undoubtedly in recognition of these visible advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the surface text, &quot;Analysis of Death from Falling from a Building&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Falling from a Building&quot;&lt;/span>; ) also hides some more complex and even theoretical intellectual issues. How can we distinguish between truth and falsehood when we cannot grasp the whole story? When truth and narrative come into conflict, can we persist in our pursuit of the former, or will we be conquered by the emotional power of the latter? From &quot;Battle of Solferreno&quot; to &quot;Sibyl&quot;, director Trier has been obsessed with exploring the complex relationship between text and reality. However, in &quot;Falling&quot;, which seems to be a straightforward commercial genre film, she has pushed her reflection on &quot;narration&quot; to the extreme. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A famous bisexual female writer who is stuck in the quagmire of an unhappy marriage is seizing a rare opportunity to be interviewed by a girl from the literature department, and flirting with her ambiguously while drinking. But noisy music was playing upstairs at this moment: her husband - a man who had just resigned from his university teaching position and tried to write full-time like his wife - was aware of his wife&#39;s schedule and deliberately did not want his wife&#39;s (&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Interview and Flirtation&lt;/span>;) plan succeeded. The interview had to be interrupted, and the girl and the son of the family left one after another to avoid the embarrassing and noisy situation. When the visually impaired son came home from a walk, the guide dog that led him first discovered the shocking fact: the music was still playing, the sun was still shining in the Alpine sky, but the child&#39;s father had blood all over his head. He fell into the snow and died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it suicide, accident or homicide? The medical examiner could not find sufficient evidence to prove or rule out any of these possibilities, so the only person present at the time of the incident, the deceased&#39;s wife Sandra, was accused of being a suspect and had to be investigated. In the next two hours of this film, we have to work with the judge, lawyers, jury and son Daniel who was unable to witness the scene to find the truth through our own eyes and clues provided by all parties. In this process, the relationship between Sandra and her husband Samuel will be cut into pieces and dismantled by a cold scalpel like the latter&#39;s corpse, and will face the most severe inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the overall setting, we can see the organizational structure of the entire film. This is an intricate network intertwined by various relationships. Everyone is trying to determine their position in the relationship with others, but they are often lost in the flow and change of relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WuQb9pbuocxqaNObwipCMpp2z5OhCYABfe8cm7ws.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;705&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WuQb9pbuocxqaNObwipCMpp2z5OhCYABfe8cm7ws.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;where The most eye-catching thing is naturally the relationship between Sandra and Samuel. Through the few words and fragments of evidence in the court, we can piece together some aspects of this relationship before Samuel&#39;s death: it was due to the uneven shouldering of family responsibilities between the two parties, the imbalance in the sense of worldly success, and the social and cultural differences between the two parties. Differences in background, different emotional appeals, and fundamental differences in personality and attitude towards life, gradually fell apart. We seem to be watching another &quot;Marriage Story&quot; or &quot;The Kramers&quot;. Neither party has made an unforgivable mistake. Everyone has their own reasons and difficulties. Even so, the two people who still love each other will still move forward. Resent and hurt each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But beneath the surface, the film also constructs a more subtle relationship: the relationship between the audience and the heroine. The legal drama format, which occupies most of the film, firmly places the audience in the position of the jury in the court. Through the guidance of facts, reasoning and emotions, we pour empathy into one of the prosecution and defense parties. And together they share the same hatred against the other party. As the truth continues to be revealed and lies continue to be exposed, our trust relationship with all parties is also undergoing subtle adjustments: at first, we will instinctively resent the inference of Sandra&#39;s guilt and the prosecutor&#39;s lawyer who questioned her; As the trial progresses, we discover that Sandra is not as honest as we first thought. As a result, the emotional balance shifts slightly: every word Sandra says from now on will be more questioned in our hearts. At the same time, every difficulty issued by the prosecutor, even including the various questions they raised before, It also makes more sense in our hindsight. The strategic game between the prosecution and the defense in the film is certainly exciting, but the psychological game between the director and the audience, based on the latter&#39;s emotional identification with the heroine, is closer to the focus of the entire film and allows the film to retain suspense. The secret to keeping it until the very last moment—and even until after the film is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At its true core, the film sets up ambiguous and complex relationships between texts of different materials. The entire film adopts a realistic audio-visual and narrative strategy as a whole, but whenever the prosecution and defense raise speculations and memories that cannot be verified by facts during the trial, the camera will start from the perspective of son Daniel sitting in the auditorium. It presents a &quot;psychological image&quot; with a highly subjective fantasy color. Sometimes it is a picture of the father committing suicide, and sometimes it is a picture of the mother punching the father in a rage. As these images accumulate, they finally become &quot;reality&quot; near the end of the film: Danielle testifies in person, reciting a suicidal monologue from his father&#39;s lifetime on the witness stand. However, the father&#39;s voice never appears in the flashback sequence shot by the director, and the son&#39;s narration also adds a bit of ambiguity that is indistinguishable from truth to falsehood because of this carefully placed misplaced detail. We can&#39;t help but wonder: Is this monologue his son&#39;s true memory, or is it a narrative he made up to the judge in order to save a family that is at risk of complete collapse? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film does not reveal the answer to us until the end. But the truth may not be very important. The judge was obviously emotionally moved by Daniel&#39;s words, and the situation was reversed. Sandra was acquitted, and Daniel also re-accepted this mother whom he might not trust, but loved enough. The most intriguing aspect of &quot;Falling&quot; is precisely related to its complex emotions towards &quot;narration&quot; itself: on the one hand, it retains ontological doubts about all narratives, but on the other hand, it unconditionally believes The emotional animal nature of human beings, thereby believing in the infinite power of narrative itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thinking about &quot;narration&quot; confirms the significance of this film being able to exist independently from similar marriage stories; as for the truth of the entire case, it may only be grasped by that language that does not understand the language but is insightful. In the hearts of Border Collie Guide Dogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 23:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当家中老人失能失智：关切老龄化引发的三大社会问题丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259216]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Ministry of Civil Affairs and the Ministry of Finance jointly issued the &quot;About Organizing and Carrying out Central Financial Support for the Central Financial Support for the Disabled Elderly People with Economic Difficulties&quot; &quot;Notice on Care Services&quot; stipulates that the recipients of assistance are tentatively designated as elderly people who have been included in the scope of minimum living security, have been assessed as completely disabled, and have voluntarily moved into a nursing home. The amount of assistance is the difference between the actual charges for staying in a nursing home after deducting the minimum living security allowance and two subsidies for persons with disabilities that the elderly have received. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from a few years ago, there are more than 40 million disabled or semi-disabled elderly people in China, many of whom are also suffering from dementia, such as Alzheimer&#39;s disease. As the population ages, this number will only continue to increase. Data from the Ministry of Civil Affairs shows that as of the end of 2022, there were 280.04 million elderly people aged 60 and over in the country, accounting for 19.8%; among them, there were 209.78 million elderly people aged 65 and over, accounting for 14.9%, a year-on-year increase of 0.9 and 0.7 percentage points respectively. Increases of 12.68 million and 9.22 million. Due to China&#39;s sluggish fertility rate, the number of newborns has almost halved in six years, and the rate of social aging is quite fast. This has led to many social problems that require our serious concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the age and physical and mental conditions of the elderly, we can sort out the specific problems they face according to the timeline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, when the elderly are still &quot;younger elderly&quot;, their physical condition is generally better, and their ability to live, work and study has not significantly declined; there are also a few elderly people who have always been in good health and mentality. These two types of elderly people do not need or need the care of young adults for the time being and do not pose any social problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as we get older, our physical functions and mental abilities will continue to weaken. A considerable number of elderly people will be driven by the instinct of seeking life and hating death, and they will turn to health regimens that claim to help health and longevity. They are particularly keen on health care products and health care equipment. It is not uncommon for people who used to be very frugal and spend two cents of a penny to suddenly turn into buying and selling or even spend a lot of money; there are also a considerable number of elderly people who long for the warmth and affection of family. Although I have no children or my children are not around, I feel extremely lonely. Under the meticulous care and emotional attack of the sales staff, it is very refreshing to spend money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;elderly economy&quot; is essentially a careful hunt for the elderly and &quot;defrauds the elderly economy.&quot; The public prosecutor and the law should show their teeth and carry out a powerful crackdown to protect the legitimate rights and interests of the elderly. Children should also care about their parents&#39; mental and emotional needs, make more phone calls and spend more time with them; if possible, try to live with their parents so that parents can enjoy the rewards of raising children in their later years, so as to avoid the situation of &quot;the children want to be raised but the parents don&#39;t wait&quot; regret. In this regard, some young people may make reasonable remarks, such as &quot;small family&quot;, &quot;independent space&quot; and &quot;border&quot;. If you have never accepted or asked for a large amount of financial support from your parents as an adult, and you have repaid your parents for their upbringing financially and emotionally, you may have the confidence to say this. But it is unjustifiable if you receive a large amount of financial support from your parents as an adult and then refuse to fulfill reciprocal responsibilities. According to natural law and customary law, parents have the right to assert their own rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, now is the era of smartphones and mobile Internet, and many public transportation services, government services, and convenience services have become online and digital. A considerable number of elderly people have been left far behind in this era and have become &quot;digitally disabled groups&quot;. They do not use mobile phones or use simple-function elderly machines, cannot understand how to use those apps, and do not know how to make electronic payments. On the one hand, the government and enterprises should reserve non-digital service channels for the elderly and provide them with guidance in a conspicuous way; on the other hand, the platform should demonstrate social responsibility and launch an &quot;aging-friendly&quot; APP version to make the operation quick, simple and convenient. Older people get started. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Children should have patience and love for their digitally disabled parents, teach them to use the apps they need, or provide regular guidance and help, just like your parents patiently taught you ancient poems over and over again when you were a child. Like arithmetic, this is about feedback and feedback. In addition, parents should be alert to prevent telecommunications and network fraud, and should &quot;not give any personal information, do not give money, and do not cooperate with the other party in any operation.&quot; They should inform themselves when they have questions or before making major financial decisions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, as body functions and organs continue to age, the vast majority of the elderly will experience a stage of disability, semi-disability or even dementia. The resulting need for medical care will have a negative impact on the lives of their children. constitute a great challenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national elderly care strategy is &quot;9073&quot;, that is, 90% of the elderly are provided with home care, 7% are provided with community care, and 3% are provided with institutional care. A 2023 Beijing survey found that more than 99% of the elderly in Beijing choose home care, while less than 1% choose institutional care. Therefore, except for some completely disabled elderly people who are supported by the government, the vast majority of disabled elderly people still rely on their children to take care of them. Children generally have to contribute both money and effort, and the most important part is contribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Disabled elderly people can only eat three meals a day in bed or in a wheelchair. If they lose the function of their hands or have dementia, they need to be fed, just like parents feeding themselves when they are one or two years old, and they must also help with defecation. , wipe your body or take a bath regularly; use a wheelchair to push outdoors on sunny days, so that the disabled elderly can enjoy the sunshine and breeze, feel happy and refresh their spirits; lying in bed for a long time, you must turn over regularly, otherwise the blood circulation will not be smooth, which will lead to vascular embolism or bedsores. ; If dementia is superimposed, it will be even more troublesome. Some elderly people will have delusions, become violent, and even smear feces all over the house, making it difficult to clean up. The odor will also attract complaints from neighbors... Disability and dementia For the elderly, it is generally impossible to hire a nanny to take care of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, as the mainstay of the family, you are in middle age, you have seniors and juniors, you have unlimited responsibilities on your shoulders, everyone relies on you and you have no one to rely on, this kind of pressure It&#39;s unprecedented. If you add a mid-life workplace crisis, it will be even more stressful. Therefore, as aging intensifies, this social problem will become more serious. But it is obviously difficult to solve this problem with a &quot;socialized&quot; system solution that transfers costs to society, unless robots are smart enough to replace human care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aging, two kinds of disability, and three major problems are all social problems that require serious consideration and treatment by the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[探访“山地之王”：高仙芝的高原足迹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259129]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 20:55:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/23/9f8Kpn5eNv9GuiP2GOXSS097RDqjQpFK5sNsyUlf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/9f8Kpn5eNv9GuiP2GOXSS097RDqjQp FK5sNsyUlf. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254965&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Aerial view of the Pamir Mountains&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-August, I set off from Kashgar and cycled along the Karakoram Highway to Pakistan-occupied Kashmir. Since my country’s Khunjerab Port does not allow cycling to pass customs, I need to take a transit bus in Taxkorgan County, check the bicycle as luggage, and continue riding after arriving at Khunjerab National Park on the Pakistani side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Khunjerab Pass is 4,783 meters above sea level. On one side of the border with my country is the wide-open and wide-open valley terrain of the eastern Pamir Plateau. The climate is arid and the vegetation is sparse. It is rare to see a tree at the foot of the mountain. Surrounded by a courtyard wall - it is a family of Tajik herders; entering Pakistan, it quickly transforms into a valley terrain with surging rapids - this is a canyon cut by the Hunza River in the southeastern part of the Pamir Plateau. It collided left and right in the mountain knot formed by the intersection of the Karakoram Mountains, Himalayas and Hindu Kush Mountains, and fell rapidly. From the border line of Khunjerab Pass to the entrance of Khunjerab National Park where Pakistan conducts border inspection, it is a short 40-kilometer journey, and the altitude drops by about one thousand meters; from the border inspection to Sost, the Pakistani port ), a distance of about 38 kilometers, and the altitude has dropped by nearly a thousand meters - which is naturally great news for cyclists. By the time I rode all the way downhill to the Ganish village in the eastern part of the Hunza Valley, the altitude had dropped to about 2,400 meters, which was only half of the Khunjerab Pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not far south of Ganish, I saw a pedestrian rope bridge flying north and south over the raging Hunza River, and a warm current suddenly surged in my heart - more than 1,200 years ago , Gao Xianzhi, a famous general in the Tang Dynasty, used a similar rope bridge in the lower reaches of this river to block the way of the fierce enemy troops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/xWctTRMmRc2MxiLpdWwLNYWZpCV4uwzyTRNSw53W.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;763&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/xWctTRMmRc2MxiLpdWwLNYWZpCV4uwzyTRNSw53W.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254966&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A pedestrian rope bridge over the Hunza River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong >;Kashmir&#39;s &quot;Great Game&quot;: Smoke and dust flying to the west of Jinshan Mountain&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before Gao Xianzhi rushed to the rope bridge, the prospect of the expeditionary force he commanded was not good: facing a surrendered enemy The fortified city, as well as a large number of enemy reinforcements coming all the way, while our own army has been on the march for more than three months, traveled more than 1,500 kilometers, and faced the extremely harsh geological and climatic conditions in Congling (&lt;em>; After continuous battles in the wind and snow, the lone expeditionary force advanced deep into the enemy&#39;s territory. They did not understand the language, had no siege equipment, lacked logistical supplies, and could not get reinforcements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a difficult situation may have been encountered by Alexander the Great during his legendary expedition to Asia and Europe. However, Alexander stationed his troops to the west of Congling and never crossed over. Gao Xianzhi&#39;s mission was precisely to cross the Congling to regain the lost territory. What&#39;s more, his military strength, animal power and material resources were far less than Alexander&#39;s expeditionary force. This may be why Gao Xianzhi later He was called the &quot;King of the Mountains&quot; by one of his rivals, Sahib jibal al-Sin. Sahib is the Turkic word for &quot;master&quot; , jibal is &quot;mountain&quot; in Arabic, and al-Sin is of China)&lt;/span>; reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Xianzhi is a descendant of the Goguryeo royal family. His ancestors were the Fuyu people who emerged in the Hunjiang River Basin and the middle reaches of the Yalu River in Northeast China. &quot;Gao was their surname&quot; and established the Goguryeo regime during the Western Han Dynasty, which lasted seven hundred years. For a long time, it once occupied Liaodong to the southwest, and then crossed the Yalu River to the southeast and entered the Korean Peninsula. After the Goguryeo regime perished under the military attacks of the Sui and Tang dynasties, the Tang Dynasty moved the defeated Gao royal family to the Central Plains and Longyou. Gao Xianzhi followed his father Gao Sheji into the army and became a border guard in the Tang Dynasty. He grew up in the Hexi Corridor. He grew up in a military camp, and when he was a boy, he was transferred to the Anxi Protectorate with his father, which is today&#39;s southern Xinjiang, Pamir Plateau and Central Asia Hezhong region. He rose to prominence in his twenties and was promoted to general, the same level as his father. Later, he was further recognized by the leader of the Qiang people and the governor of Anxi, Meng Lingjin, and was promoted to deputy governor of Anxi and commander of the four towns. The horse envoy is equivalent to Fumeng Lingjin&#39;s deputy and the military chief of the entire southern Xinjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the sixth year of Tianbao&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (747 AD)&lt;/span>;, Gao Xianzhi received an edict from Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty, appointing him In order to serve as a military envoy, I made my fourth expedition to Congling after the failure of my three predecessors to recapture Xiaobolu - the Pakistani-controlled Kashmir where I rode to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fKtCWOawnzDSfDbU6a8InBuv60cCYamb90OjqJHx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;579&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fKtCWOawnzDSfDbU6a8InBuv60cCYamb90OjqJHx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254967&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cycling in Hunza, Pakistan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s Pakistan-occupied Kashmir (Gilgit-Baltistan) is divided into two parts, Gilgit and Baltistan. The origin of the division can be traced back to the Greater and Lesser Bulu. The original name of this place was Boloristan, which means &quot;mountain country&quot;, where &quot;stan&quot; means &quot;country&quot; in Turkic language. Today, there are five &quot;stan&quot; countries in Central Asia, including Kazakhstan, and Pakistan in South Asia; Bolor means plateau and mountainous area - this place name is famous in the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty and is translated as &quot;Bolu&quot;. It is the junction area of ​​the four kingdoms of Tang, Tubo, Tianzhu and Dashi, and is divided into the western and western regions. Xiao Bolu in the Sa Valley and Big Bolu in the upper reaches of the Indus River in the east - the goal of Gao Xianzhi&#39;s expedition was Xiao Bolu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Big and Little Bolu were originally one country, and their territory included most of today&#39;s Pakistan-controlled Kashmir and the northern part of Indian-controlled Kashmir. It was a must-win territory for Tubo in its western region. At the beginning of the seventh century, Tubo annexed the ancient Shangshung Kingdom in the Ali region and unified the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. From then on, it began to implement its Western Region strategy based on the Ali region, and launched a nearly two-year-long war with the Tang Dynasty around Bolu, that is, the Kashmir region. The &quot;Great Game&quot; between Tang and Tibet for centuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/BPoP6sb1xhgMaISzFXsrbGNTYIjafKo87zl8Qs4z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/BPoP6sb1xhgMaISzFXsrbGNTYIjafKo87zl8Qs4z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254969&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hunza Valley&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Zaitian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tubo is backed by the Himalayas. It borders the Tang Dynasty in three directions: north, east and south. Why do we have to choose Kashmir to decide the outcome? Tubo initially launched the main attack on Datang on the Hehuang and Jiannan fronts, but failed to open up the situation. After occupying the Ngari region, Tibet tried to seize southern Xinjiang via the northern Qiangtang Prairie and across the Altyn Mountains. After being blocked again, they had to turn to expand northwest along the Shiquan River/Indus River Basin, intending to bypass the Himalayas and enter through the Ladakh region. Kashmir eventually joined forces with the Western Turks in the north to deal with the Tang Dynasty. In short, Tubo was like a lion trapped on a high platform. It was attacked head-on by the Tang army in Qinghai, Sichuan, Yunnan and Xinjiang. It was unable to get down to the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. In the end, it had to choose to go down the mountain from Kashmir, where there was no Tang army, and take a detour. Congling attacked the western border of Tang Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Belu Kingdom, located on this expansion route, became a &quot;soft persimmon&quot; that Tibet fought against with all its strength, and soon split into two countries: the Belu Homeland became a Tubo vassal state, known as &quot; The Great Burud&quot; was roughly located in today&#39;s Baltistan area; another royal family moved westward to the Hunza Valley and established the &quot;Little Burud&quot;, which was roughly located in today&#39;s Gilgit area, relying on the Hunza River and Gilgit The Te River&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(called Suyi River in ancient times)&lt;/span>; and the Indus River line up with deep valleys and natural chasms to resist the Tibetan invasion. King Xiao Bolu did not hesitate to send an envoy to ask for help from the Tang Dynasty, saying that Bolu was the gateway to the Western Regions of the Tang Dynasty. If it fell, all the countries in the Western Regions would fall to Tubo, and the Western Regions would no longer be controlled by the Tang Dynasty&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Bo Lu, Ximen of the Tang Dynasty. If he loses it, all the Western countries will fall to Tubo)&lt;/span>;, and was finally canonized by Emperor Xuanzong of the Tang Dynasty and became the Tang Dynasty Subject to the country. In the tenth year of Kaiyuan (722 AD), the Beiting Protectorate of the Tang Army sent 4,000 cavalry reinforcements to Xiaobolu to attack Xiaobolu. He repelled the attack of the Tibetan army and won nearly twenty years of peace for Xiaobolu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 740 AD, Tubo instigated the Tuqishi Khanate in the northern grasslands to rebel against the Tang Dynasty through marriage, and contained the main force of the Tang army in the Western Regions in the northern Xinjiang. On this occasion, he proposed to Xiao Bolu to &quot;borrow a road&quot; and build a rope bridge on the Suyi River. The Tubo army, which successfully crossed the natural barrier of the Suyi River, immediately turned against the foreigners and occupied Xiaobolu. King Su Feng of Xiaobolu was forced to marry the Tibetan princess, and together with more than 20 surrounding small countries, they rebelled against Tang and surrendered to Tibet. The Tibetan army was able to occupy the entire Bolu and get a glimpse of Congling: they captured Lianyun Fort, the fortress of the Tang army guarding the Wakhan Valley, the main road to Congling, opening the way to the north to Central Asia to make friends with the Turks, and cutting off the capital of Anxi. The road from Hufu to the Zhaowu Kingdoms in the Hezhong region also formed a condescending military advantage over the four Anxi towns of the Tang Dynasty located in the Tarim Basin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the unfavorable situation that a gap was opened in the defense line of the Western Region, the Anxi Protectorate had to concentrate all its efforts to regain Bolu and block the &quot;downhill&quot; channel of Tubo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/bZT8JG7NjiRBsR7Doyj7Jnnki6xEICEQfr28g9Y1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/bZT8JG7NjiRBsR7Doyj7Jnnki6xEICEQfr28g9Y1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254970&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The barren and pure river valley in Hunza region&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;Recovering the Wakhan Valley: The captives should be frightened after hearing this&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the most convenient way to go from China&#39;s Pamir Plateau to Pakistan-occupied Kashmir is to go south along the Hunza Valley, or That is to say, follow the Karakoram Highway, which was historically one of the important passages along the southern route of the Silk Road to South Asia. It’s just that in ancient times, caravans used to go through the Mingtie Gaidaban, and when China and Pakistan planned and built the Karakoram Highway in the 1960s, in order to avoid the military threat of the Soviet Union—Tajikistan, which today occupies most of the Pamir Plateau, was苏联的加盟共和国，阿富汗当时也受到苏联挟制，苏军在瓦罕山谷部署了一个陆军师，还修建了导弹发射场和机场，对我国南疆虎视眈眈——故而选择了明铁盖达坂以东、远离中苏边境并且山势复杂的红其拉甫山口以实现更好的战略隐蔽。其代价则是巴方一侧的中巴公路落差较大，容易遭到滑坡、泥石流等自然灾害破坏，如2010年就曾因山体滑坡形成堰塞湖，造成中巴公路中断五年之久。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而高仙芝远征小勃律时，既没有走明铁盖达坂，也没有走红其拉甫山口，因为当时这一线山地已经被吐蕃军队所控制，如果走这些山口的话就面临着被驻扎在连云堡的吐蕃军截断粮道前后夹击的巨大风险。因此，他选择的是先拔掉连云堡这颗锲入葱岭的钉子，再走罕萨河谷西侧与之平行的亚辛河谷南下，迂回攻取小勃律。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唐代的连云堡位于今天阿富汗东部的最后一个村庄萨尔哈德（Sarhad），它扼守瓦罕山谷东口，由此继续向东就进入了中阿边境地带的荒漠地区。瓦罕山谷又称喷赤河谷或瓦罕走廊，乃是帕米尔高原与兴都库什山脉之间的一条山谷，东西绵延超过六百里，是中印两国历史上重要的文化通道，也是丝绸之路南线的重要组成部分。汉代张骞由此“凿空西域”，穿过葱岭前往河中地区寻访大月氏；在高仙芝远征小勃律的近一百二十年前&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元629年）&lt;/span>;，“唐僧”玄奘历经七昼夜穿越瓦罕山谷进入南亚；近代英俄两大帝国在中亚开展“大博弈”，最终也以这条山谷作为南北分界线和隔离带，划定了两国各自的势力范围，从而引入了“瓦罕走廊”这个称谓，并且慷他人之慨，将这片当时的中国属地任性地划给了阿富汗，成为阿富汗版图东端一条突兀的阑尾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吐蕃在瓦罕山谷东口固守连云堡要塞，“据山因水，堑断崖谷，编木为城”，向东可以沿塔什库尔干河谷进入南疆，向北可以翻越帕米尔高原进入中亚，向西可以绕过兴都库什山脉进入南亚，或者沿着喷赤河前往河中地区，向南则可以依托兴都库什山脉保护新占领的大小勃律，可谓四通八达，战略要冲。而高仙芝为了稳扎稳打，则必须先扫除吐蕃的这座前进阵地，再南下收复小勃律。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我无法亲身前往瓦罕山谷探访连云堡，只得先走中巴公路抵达小勃律都城孽多——今天巴控克什米尔首府吉尔吉特（Gilgit），然后沿着当年高仙芝的进军路线反向而行，先溯吉尔吉特河西行，再沿着其支流亚辛河谷北上，抵达兴都库什山脉南坡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/ItRbcoHPJdl4kV2Y35bCnG8BbEqBsEmisEeqIQWS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/ItRbcoHPJdl4kV2Y35bCnG8BbEqBsEmisEeqIQWS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254968&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;塔什库尔干石头城&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据旧、新唐书记载，高仙芝统率一万步卒——相当于安西大都护府的一半机动兵力——于公元747年农历四月从龟兹&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今库车）&lt;/span>;出发，花了一个多月沿天山南麓经拨换城&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今阿克苏）&lt;/span>;、握瑟德&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今巴楚）&lt;/span>;西行而至疏勒&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今喀什）&lt;/span>;，沿途又调动了部分戍边骑兵，随后沿塔什库尔干河谷向南抵达葱岭守捉&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（“守捉”是唐代的小型军镇）&lt;/span>;，也就是今天塔什库尔干县城外的石头城——“塔什”便是突厥语中“石头”之意。农历七月上旬，唐军连同西域属国附庸部队约两万人翻越葱岭，抵达特勒满川&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今塔吉克斯坦霍罗格）&lt;/span>;。高仙芝在此分兵三路，自己率领唐军主力迂回到连云堡西侧，又派调自喀什和阿克苏的两路人马分别从北、东两个方向包围连云堡，约定于农历七月十三日辰时同时发动突袭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;史载吐蕃军据山固守，滚木礌石“蔽空而下”，唐军一时难以得手。高仙芝向手下勇将李嗣业和田珍下了一道严令：“不及日中，决须破虏！”。 《旧唐书》曾为李嗣业立传，说他行伍出身，“身长七尺，壮勇绝伦”，面对守军的密集防御，他和田珍手持两面开刃的陌刀，带领一支陌刀兵突击队另辟蹊径，“于绝险处先登”，也就是从吐蕃守军意料不到的绝壁悬崖攀缘而上，居高临下冲入敌寨，果然在正午前攻下了这座由万余吐蕃军驻守、以山城堡垒和山脚营寨构成复合防御体系的要塞，斩首五千级，俘虏千余人，打赢了此次远征最大的一场硬仗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唐军收复连云堡，将吐蕃赶出葱岭，重新夺回了瓦罕山谷这条连接西域的通道，下一步就要翻越兴都库什山脉，收复小勃律，清除吐蕃军对瓦罕山谷的威胁。当时已是八月中旬，如今的瓦罕走廊在一年中仅有六到八月可以通行，其他时间均被大雪封山，唐代气候谅亦如是。想必是考虑到天气因素，高仙芝没有在连云堡耽搁，留下三千多羸弱士兵留守，自己统率精锐步卒轻装疾进，长途奔袭三昼夜，抵达坦驹岭山口（Darkut Pass，&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今译达科特山口）。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8kscrApbrsiJFCskX9KcLqRJ1jVIPF19O4ElMSvA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/8kscrApbrsiJFCskX9KcLqRJ1jVIPF19O4ElMSvA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;瓦罕走廊，背景为兴都库什山脉。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;翻越兴都库什：瀚海阑干百丈冰&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;巴基斯坦与阿富汗两国在瓦罕走廊以兴都库什山脉（Hindu Kush）为界，这个波斯语名字最早见于中世纪阿拉伯旅行家伊本·白图泰的叙述，直译为“印度教徒（Hindu）的杀手（Kush）”，意思是被掳自南亚炎热地区的印度奴隶在翻越这座高峻寒冷的山脉时大量冻死；也有人把它解释为“印度之山”，意思是向南越过这座山脉就进入了印度次大陆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坦驹岭山口位于兴都库什山脉东段，但它并非纵贯这座山脉的山口——因为这里有两座分水岭和两个山口。兴都库什山脉东端起源于帕米尔高原，具有山结回转的特点，在坦驹岭附近分为平行的南北两支：北支是巴基斯坦与阿富汗的国境线，南支以南则是南北向的亚辛河谷，而南北两支之间是东西向的亚昆河谷（Yarkhun River）。坦驹岭山口是南支上的垭口，海拔为4688米，山口两侧遍布冰川，很难逾越。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么还有没有其他路呢？其实是有的。翻越兴都库什山脉北支后可以沿着亚昆河谷西行，绕过南支，再翻越著名的山杜尔山口（Shandur）向东进入吉尔吉特河谷，即可顺流而下抵达小勃律。但是这条路线直到二十一世纪的今天依然极其崎岖难行，其中亚昆河谷连铺装公路都没有，大部分路段是位于陡崖半山、仅容一辆车低速通过的简易砂石土路，骑车的话分分钟会爆胎，因此我只得寄存了自行车，雇用摩托车手载我进入亚昆河谷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/An6dIyETx5jIvnAWAGpM9XcSmAmAeJBj4xm0BGXR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/An6dIyETx5jIvnAWAGpM9XcSmAmAeJBj4xm0BGXR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;山杜尔山口，是马球发源地。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以想见，一千三百年前这里的路况只会比现在糟得多。如果高仙芝率部绕行亚昆河谷，很可能需要多走一个来月，那时就是九月中下旬，吐蕃援军早已在小勃律以逸待劳严阵以待，而兴都库什山脉和帕米尔高原很快就将因为严寒而无法通行，这意味着唐军归路将被切断——我猜想这就是高仙芝决定与时间赛跑，率军冒险翻越坦驹岭山口“直下峭峻四十馀里”的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，当兵吃粮的士卒们可没有这样的战略洞察。好不容易攀冰踏雪登上坦驹岭，他们望着脚下连绵冰川，惊慌失措地质问高仙芝：“大使将我欲何处去？”——“大使”是唐代对节度使的尊称——你难道要我们从这么陡峭的冰川顶部出溜下去吗？这是要带我们去小勃律还是阎罗殿？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;千年以降，英籍匈牙利裔探险家斯坦因在实地考察高仙芝行军路线后写道：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当我立在山口顶端闪光烁烁的积雪上，向那直到6000英尺下亚辛山谷尽头的峻坂下窥，对于起初唐军拒绝向前移动的原因，后来他们努力挣扎前进的艰难，以及高仙芝的勇敢，才能认识清楚！ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/QmEoteO6T3NeHWtoJELvU9xOW5FmFYpLIBb5Wihg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;668&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/QmEoteO6T3NeHWtoJELvU9xOW5FmFYpLIBb5Wihg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254973&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;坦驹岭&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，高仙芝无法用个人的勇敢来驱使士卒。他料到了人性的弱点，知道士卒不敢攀冰下山深入敌境，因此悄悄派出二十多名亲信，穿上勃律人的服装提前爬上坦驹岭等待大部队。正当唐军士卒在山顶惊疑不定时，这些冒牌货笑盈盈地迎上前来，自称是驻扎在山口对面的小勃律守军，代表阿弩越城守将前来投顺王师，还说小勃律已经切断了吐蕃援军的必经之路。这个天大的好（&lt;em>;假&lt;/em>;）消息让唐军士卒们顿感胜利在望，因此信心满满地服从将令越过坦驹岭，进入亚辛河谷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据史家考证，阿弩越城位于今天的古皮斯镇（Gupis），乃是亚辛河（Yasin River）汇入吉尔吉特河的河口，也是唐军向小勃律国都进军途中的最大关隘。我沿着从吉尔吉特到奇特拉尔的铺装公路骑车至此，正逢路边一座小学放学，三五百名披着黑色hijab头巾的女生兴高采烈地从校门里涌出来&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（当地男女生各上半天学）&lt;/span>;，一时间把公路挡得严严实实。待她们散入街巷，我才看到公路北侧由中国援建的铁索桥横跨水流湍急的吉尔吉特河，过桥后溯河上行不远就可以看到一条清澈的支流从西北方向汇入大河，那便是由坦驹岭冰川融雪涓汇成流的亚辛河。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a3WXffZ5FQu5EWQchTj2pAmrlpm6JAxX4OpDzaI8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/a3WXffZ5FQu5EWQchTj2pAmrlpm6JAxX4OpDzaI8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254974&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;坦驹岭下的亚辛河谷&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从阿弩越城到亚辛河源头的坦驹岭南麓，全程将近七十公里，同样是未经铺装的简易土路，我搭车花了三个小时方才抵达，而高仙芝当年率军翻山越岭走了四天。还剩最后一天山路时，喜讯传来：阿弩越城真的派使者来迎接唐军了——或许守将得知吐蕃军主力已被聚歼于连云堡，唐军又已翻越天险坦驹岭，区区一道娑夷河已无法阻挡其兵锋，因此决定向唐军开城投降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而我脑海中浮现的却是另一幕场景：唐军将士诧异地看着两伙胡人，他们都自称是阿弩越城守军，都声称是来投降的，彼此却不认识，也无法对话交流。后一伙人高鼻深目，乃是波斯人的长相，前一伙人却和自己长得差不多，操着荒腔走板的夹生“胡语”，尴尬地望着对方……&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;截断印度河谷：车师西门佇献捷&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;从阿弩越城出发，沿娑夷河东行至小勃律都城孽多，距离约为一百十公里。孽多城位于罕萨河谷与娑夷河谷的交汇处，原城址已不可考，但从史书记载来看应该位于娑夷河西岸。如今这里是巴控克什米尔的首府吉尔吉特，因河而名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从孽多城沿娑夷河再下行约六十里便是娑夷河汇入印度河的河口，由此沿印度河顺流而下便是古称“五河之地”的旁遮普平原&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（“旁遮普”在印地语中即“五河”之意）&lt;/span>;——五条源于喜马拉雅山脉南麓的支流在此陆续汇入印度河，形成肥沃的冲积平原，孕育了古印度文明；由此溯流而上，穿过从河口到斯卡杜（Skardu）之间的壮观大峡谷则可进入大勃律，最终翻越喜马拉雅山脉抵达青藏高原。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;喀喇昆仑公路沿着罕萨河、吉尔吉特河与印度河右侧的台地一路南下，在吉尔吉特河口附近走个漂亮的U形弯道下降至岸边，再通过一座公路桥跨过吉尔吉特河，对岸就是沿着印度河通往克什米尔印巴对峙地区的S1号公路，战略价值十分重要。而在高仙芝远征期间，如今公路桥的位置建有一座用藤条编成的索桥，乃是吐蕃欺骗小勃律“借道”所建。它“阔一箭道”，也就是藤桥的跨度达到当时的弓箭射程——约两百米左右。这座藤桥是吐蕃军由大勃律进入小勃律乃至北上葱岭的必经之路，可谓咽喉锁钥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;却说高仙芝率军抵达孽多城，效忠吐蕃的小勃律贵族坚守都城，不放唐军入城。高仙芝陷入了本文开头描述的窘境：如果不尽快拿下孽多城，一旦吐蕃援军赶到，失去退路的唐军势必陷入双方夹击，在即将来临的严冬中被围歼于孽多城下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，高仙芝并没有摆出攻城的态势——当然他也并不具备强攻坚城的人力和物力。这位远征军的最高指挥官首先派使者稳住小勃律国王，声称唐军既不打算攻城也不准备破坏藤桥，而是打算经过藤桥去攻打大勃律的吐蕃军；其次他用金银财物利诱守城的亲吐蕃派贵族，将他们骗入唐营全部斩首；而最重要的一件任务，高仙芝交给了先锋席元庆：兼程赶赴娑夷河口破坏藤桥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从孽多城到娑夷河口是吐蕃军铺设的军用公路，路况想必不错，但等到席元庆急行军六十里赶到藤桥时，太阳已经落入峡谷西侧的雪峰背后。在沉沉暮色之中，他看到对面山岭中群鸟惊飞，烟尘涌起——那是另一支大军正在全速赶来。席元庆没有耽搁任何时间，立刻指挥士卒一齐动手斩断藤条。藤桥刚刚堕入被古人称为弱水三千、极为湍急的娑夷河中，吐蕃援军的大队人马就冲到了对岸——可惜已经来不及渡河了&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（《旧唐书》：及暮，才斫了，吐蕃兵马大至，已无及矣）。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/PnJOz5W8HdgAwZ8xG3Di00h5CaRC2mXr2W1STqHx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/PnJOz5W8HdgAwZ8xG3Di00h5CaRC2mXr2W1STqHx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254976&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;水流湍急的娑夷河，又称弱水。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这座藤桥当年花了一年时间才建成，如今被唐军控制住了西岸，吐蕃军无法复建藤桥，也不可能徒涉渡河，只得望河兴叹后灰溜溜地原路返回了大勃律。吐蕃方的《敦煌吐蕃文书· 大事纪年》在藏历猪年的条目下如此记载：勃律国、廓地&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今青海东部）&lt;/span>;守军被唐人击败，守地失陷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至此，吐蕃守军被歼，吐蕃援军被阻，亲吐蕃派被杀，小勃律国王苏失利突然变成了四面楚歌的那一方，不得不向高仙芝投降。国王和他的吐蕃王后被送往长安献俘，小勃律则被改名为归仁军，由一千名唐军在此镇守。收复小勃律的整个战役历时四个月，但实际作战过程不过十余日，除了连云堡的半日血战之外，在小勃律境内可谓兵不血刃而收全功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;斯坦因曾如此评价：&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;数目不少的军队，行经帕米尔和兴都库什，在历史上以此为第一次。高山插天，又缺乏给养，不知道当时如何维持军队的供应？即令现代的参谋本部，亦将束手无策……中国这一位勇敢的将军，行军所经，惊险困难，比起欧洲名将，从汉尼拔，到拿破仑，到苏沃洛夫，他们之越阿尔卑斯山，真不知超过多少倍。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/TNvnijQcmMWhhIKM3mlemCmHXMeL1ssu3i3zKftF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/TNvnijQcmMWhhIKM3mlemCmHXMeL1ssu3i3zKftF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254975&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;罕萨河谷中的Ultar冰川与Baltit城堡&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;尾声：雪上空留马行处&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;天宝十载&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元751年）&lt;/span>;，高仙芝被调离安西大都护府。两年之后，由他一手提拔于草莽的继承者、新任安西节度使封常清出兵收复大勃律，从而彻底断绝了吐蕃经由勃律和葱岭方向进犯安西四镇的通道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，这次战役是大唐在西域的最后一次扩张。只过了两年，安史之乱爆发，中原陷入纷飞战火，濒临灭亡的唐王朝从此再无力经营西域。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时的吐蕃也改变了对唐战略，由面对盛唐强兵时的绕道勃律攻其安西四镇一隅，改为利用大唐反复抽调河西精锐去内地平叛导致当地兵力空虚的机会，重新开始主攻河湟地区，夺取连接大唐西域与中原的河西走廊，再将联络中断、孤立无援的西域各镇各国分别击破，大唐的西域统治体系随之轰然崩塌。到了九世纪初，安西大都护府完全陷落，天山南北直到清乾隆年间方重新纳入我国版图，故此被称为“新疆”，取其“故土新归”之意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于高仙芝为什么在军威鼎盛之际被调离西域，那就是另一段跌宕的历史了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（本文回目取自唐代边塞诗人岑参诗句。岑参是高仙芝、封常清的幕僚，曾跟随两人转战西域，走遍天山南北。）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[制造数字人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259222]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李尚福被免去国务委员、国防部部长职务，秦刚被免去国务委员职务]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259226]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 19:19:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011391102109&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Xi Jinping signed Presidential Order No. 12, No. 13, and No. 14.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud. com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/35d229ad3270835011391102109/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp12514 34507/35d229ad3270835011391102109/DQLOOyhweoEA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640 &quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35d229ad3270835011391102109/DQLOOyhweoEA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;According to CCTV&#39;s &quot;News Network&quot;, Chairman&#39;s Order No. 14 said that according to the decision of the Sixth Meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress of the People&#39;s Republic of China on October 24, 2023:&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;1. Remove Li Shangfu from the posts of State Councilor and Minister of Defense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Remove Qin Gang from his post as State Councilor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Remove Wang Zhigang from the post of Minister of Science and Technology; appoint Yin Hejun as Minister of Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. Remove Liu Kun from the post of Minister of Finance; appoint Lan Fo&#39;an as Minister of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[如何让老人在“家门口”幸福养老？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259157]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;Let rural elderly people have something to rely on in their old age&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the 2020 National Bulletin on the Development of Aging Causes, In 2020, my country&#39;s rural population aged 60 and above accounted for 23.81% of the total rural population, nearly 8 percentage points higher than that in urban areas. According to predictions from the National Office on Aging, by 2035, the proportion of people aged 60 and above in rural my country will rise to 37.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter&#39;s interview found that in the face of the aging and empty-nest problems of the rural population, various localities have adopted various measures based on local conditions to strive to provide rural elderly with something to rely on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Promote the culture of mutual aid in rural areas and develop mutual aid and elderly care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Aunt Wang, I&#39;m here to see you. How are you today?&quot; 54-year-old Li Yuqing is a neighborhood mutual aid worker in Zhuanghetun Village, Shilibao Town, Miyun District, Beijing. She often goes to the village 80 Visited Wang Xiulan, a 20-year-old man living alone, at his home. &quot;Every time I come to the door, I will help Aunt Wang measure her blood pressure and blood sugar, and ask her if she feels uncomfortable.&quot; Li Yuqing said that neighborhood mutual aid workers are equipped with a &quot;Neighbor Mutual Aid Treasure Box&quot;, which contains blood pressure monitors, blood glucose meters, etc. equipment and some commonly used medicines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/1246ac4b5caa9ef808c40e0c129fa4a8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/1246ac4b5caa9ef808c40e0c129fa4a8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255020&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Neighborhood mutual aid workers in Shilibao Town, Miyun District, Beijing, measure the blood pressure of Wang Xiulan (left). Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Tai Sicong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Hao, deputy director of the Social Child Welfare and Elderly Care Service Center of Miyun District Civil Affairs Bureau, said that in order to ensure the home safety of empty-nest elderly people living alone, Miyun District has vigorously promoted the pilot construction of neighbor mutual aid points. Local public-spirited &quot;4050&quot; villagers are hired as neighborhood mutual aid workers, and their residences are used as neighborhood mutual aid points. One point serves 10 elderly people living alone in the surrounding area, providing them with cleaning, laundry and sewing, shopping and payment services, and medicine prescriptions. Waiting for service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Do a good job in the &quot;key little things&quot; of rural elderly care and protect the safety of empty-nest elderly people living alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the Chinese Disease Surveillance System, falls have become the leading cause of death from injuries among people over 65 years old in my country. More than 40 million elderly people in my country fall at least once every year, and bathrooms are the hardest hit area for elderly people to fall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to solve the problem of &quot;unsuitable for aging&quot; in some rural housing, Lishui City, Zhejiang Province has carried out aging-friendly renovations on more than 2,300 rural elderly households since 2021, allowing the elderly to have night lights to wake up at night and assistive devices to walk. , There are seats in the bath. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Care services come into the home, allowing the elderly to have a peaceful life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Hanquan, a subsistence allowance recipient who lives in Guangfu Village, Qingshanpu Town, Changsha County, Hunan Province, has limited mobility in both lower limbs and can only rely on his wife to take care of him. The local government purchased home care services for him. Based on the needs of the elderly, caregivers at the local care center provide home care services more than 8 times a month, including haircuts, meal assistance, rehabilitation guidance, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Jiashan County, Zhejiang Province, the local government has explored and piloted a long-term care insurance system to accurately identify the needs of the elderly with disabilities and dementia, and has provided a total of more than 9,500 elderly people with life care, rehabilitation care and other services. Ensure the life of disabled and dementia elderly people in their later years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter found in interviews that rural elderly care services in some areas also face many practical difficulties. Some grassroots civil affairs cadres reported that due to the low population density in rural areas, the cost of providing meal assistance, medical assistance and other services is high. The supply of health care services in rural areas is insufficient, and some severely disabled and demented elderly people are prone to difficulty in providing care and poor quality of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The community elderly care service model continues to innovate&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Strengthening Aging Work in the New Era&quot; issued in 2021 proposed &quot;innovating the home community elderly care service model&quot;; in May this year , the &quot;Opinions on Promoting the Construction of Basic Elderly Care Service Systems&quot; issued by the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State stated that &quot;property service companies should be supported in providing home-based and community-based elderly care services according to local conditions&quot; and &quot;supported by elderly care institutions in operating community elderly care service facilities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter’s interview found that some cities rely on communities to develop diversified home-based elderly care services, allowing community services and home-based elderly care to be nested and integrated with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Gongshu District, Hangzhou City, there are 8 built-in elderly care institutions and more than 580 home elderly care beds, which can effectively meet the personalized needs of the elderly in the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e443db73131a798f830e2b794e0c77db.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e443db73131a798f830e2b794e0c77db.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Medical staff help the elderly with rehabilitation training in Desheng Community Nursing Home, Daguan Street, Gongshu District, Hangzhou City. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Ping&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puyang Hua, a 77-year-old elderly man from Desheng Community, Daguan Street, Gongshu District, due to memory loss, her children did not trust her to be alone at home, so they placed her in a community nursing home. . Every morning around 8 a.m., the staff picks her up from the institution and takes her home in the afternoon after her children get off work. The day-care fee is 80 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Changsha, Hunan, the “elderly care + housekeeping” service model has achieved initial results. The reporter saw at the Comprehensive Elderly Care Service Center in Mapoling Street, Furong District, Changsha City that caregivers can not only provide basic services such as nutritious meal preparation, cleaning assistance, and bathing assistance, but also provide professional nursing services, such as health monitoring, rehabilitation exercises, Assisted medication, etc.; it can provide long-term residential services, or provide door-to-door services by &quot;ordering&quot; the elderly or their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Beijing, personalized services provided by “elderly care butlers” have become popular in some communities. The Beijing Civil Affairs Bureau divided the pilot streets into several areas. Each area established a &quot;2+N+X&quot; management unit, equipped with 2 high-quality chief elderly care service stewards, N professional elderly care service personnel and several volunteers. , responsible for the elderly care services in 2 to 3 communities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter’s interview found that some urban community elderly care services still have some shortcomings and insufficient service guarantee capabilities. Many old communities have few public spaces, making it difficult to build senior care canteens, care centers, etc.; most community senior care stations operate in a &quot;small workshop&quot; business model, lacking industry-influential business entities; there is still a shortage of senior care nursing talents, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Multiple parties share the responsibility to allow the elderly to spend their old age peacefully &quot;at home&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Strengthening the Work on Aging in the New Era&quot; proposed that &quot;building coordinated home-based community institutions , an elderly care service system and a health support system that combine medical care and health care” and “promote the gathering of various high-quality service resources to the elderly’s side, home and surroundings.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/acbb9f4950eac6f42eaf4ffa3216b614.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/acbb9f4950eac6f42eaf4ffa3216b614.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255021&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Elderly people are having lunch at the Comprehensive Elder Care Service Center in Xijiao Street, Kongtong District, Pingliang City, Gansu Province. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wang Zixuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Where there are many elderly people, we will set up elderly care service institutions.” The Ministry of Civil Affairs and other departments stated that during the “14th Five-Year Plan” period, they will promote the development of old urban areas and completed residential areas. The (community) district has basically completed the community elderly care service facilities, and promoted the construction of a &quot;15-minute&quot; home elderly care service circle in urban communities, making home community elderly care services richer, more convenient, and of higher quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jiazeng, president of the Zhejiang Elderly Service Industry Association, believes that the focus of rural elderly care services should be on the provision of social services for people with disabilities and dementia. It is necessary to strengthen assistance and assistance to low-income groups, accelerate the establishment of a long-term care insurance system, give full play to the network advantages of township health centers and rural doctors, and encourage rural doctors to provide regular physical examinations, home visits, home hospital beds, etc. for the elderly, seriously ill, disabled and other elderly groups. Basic services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Hanqiao, deputy director of the Beijing Municipal Civil Affairs Bureau, suggested encouraging social capital to enter the elderly care industry, cultivating diversified business entities, and jointly making the elderly care service industry bigger and stronger. At present, Beijing has explored the establishment of a unified information platform for elderly care services to smooth resource docking, supply and demand matching, and support and guide business entities to actively participate in elderly care services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to problems such as the shortage of elderly care talents, Ding Fujun, director of the Civil Affairs Bureau of Shangyu District, Shaoxing City, Zhejiang Province, suggested improving the treatment of nursing staff and increasing the public’s recognition of nursing staff. At the same time, we will guide the majority of social welfare organizations, charities, and young volunteers to participate in elderly care services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, we must vigorously promote the application and digital management of smart devices to empower elderly care services. At present, some places are already exploring this aspect. For example, Hangzhou City has carried out a housing protection project, and installed intelligent monitoring equipment such as smoke alarms and emergency callers on demand for aging-appropriate renovation objects; Changsha City has carried out targeted aging-appropriate renovation projects. Some elderly people are equipped with &quot;anti-lost&quot; technology clothing, sleep monitors and other smart devices, and their health data are synchronized to the cloud in real time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1840年以来的中国与美国（中）丨倬彼云汉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259193]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/24/t0J4qtLpFTF6UmbRCvw4UEB36ori63tp3iVUJbVg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;962&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/t0J4qtLpFTF6UmbRCvw4UEB36ori63tp 3iVUJbVg. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The international landscape under the &quot;containment policy&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1949, the Kuomintang retreated to Taiwan. During this period, the United States conducted an in-depth review and determined its national policy: How to prevent and block the joint front between the Soviet Union and China? How should the so-called &quot;free world&quot;, that is, Europe and the United States led by Britain and the United States, face the socialist lineup? Will countries advocating a capitalist free economy and countries pursuing a socialist planned economy coexist peacefully, or will they be in constant confrontation? This was something the U.S. government was very concerned about at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1947, President Truman adopted a containment policy after consulting Marshall, Eisenhower and MacArthur on the above issues. On February 22, 1946, George F. Kennan, Charge d&#39;Affaires of the U.S. Embassy in Moscow, sent the famous &quot;Long Telegram&quot; to the State Department. Kennan&#39;s suggestion established the United States&#39; plan for the postwar world: the &quot;Strategy of Containment.&quot; From the Truman era to the Nixon era, various diplomatic measures were taken in this direction. During the Nixon era, Kissinger planned the &quot;Engagement&quot; policy. However, from the overall principle, &quot;connection&quot; is only a means, trying to break out a gap in the &quot;containment&quot;. Therefore, the &quot;containment policy&quot; can be said to be the highest principle for the United States to deal with world affairs for decades. Until recently, this policy evolved into a frantic situation that was not anticipated at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back from 1947 to the present, for more than seventy years, most of the Western world has been ruled by this &quot;containment policy&quot;: the United States hopes that it should take on the role of &quot;free world&quot; and &quot;free economy&quot; defender&quot; responsibility. All possible &quot;gaps&quot; must be plugged as much as possible - extending from the North Sea to the Sea of ​​Okhotsk, and from Berlin to Sakhalin. This long front was dominated by the Soviet Union, and China, as an unspecified &quot;partner&quot; - which side China&#39;s &quot;partner&quot; status was on, was not stated in this cable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the implementation of this policy, the United States decided to use the three important figures mentioned above as the main executors. The first step was for Marshall, as Secretary of State, to preside over the &quot;Marshall Plan&quot; (officially known as the &quot;European Recovery Program&quot;) aimed at promoting European recovery, and at the same time use US dollars to assist Greece and Turkey - these two countries are The Soviet fleet entered the Mediterranean Sea from the Caspian Sea and the Black Sea. In the East, after Japan surrendered, MacArthur wanted to build Japan and South Korea into &quot;the democratic fortresses of the East&quot; and personally preside over the defense of the Eastern Front. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Truman retired, Eisenhower took over, and the three maintained this situation for decades. One of the episodes was that Truman could not stand that MacArthur &quot;would not be ordered by the king&quot; and recalled this warrior from South Korea. However, Marshall and Eisenhower faithfully implemented this policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first step of this policy in the East was that the U.S. Seventh Fleet began patrolling the Taiwan Strait, allowing Kinmen and Matsu, the two remaining bases of the Kuomintang Taiwan authorities, to be isolated on the coast of mainland China. preservation. Qingdao was originally a naval base for the US military stationed in China, but the Americans withdrew before they were actually involved in the battlefield on China&#39;s mainland. Otherwise, the US military stationed in Qingdao will echo the US military stationed in South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This decision triggered a series of changes in East Asia. The United States strengthens its bases in the Philippines and uses Japan and Ryukyu as important strongholds in the United States&#39; eastern defense line. Together with Taiwan, it forms the &quot;first island chain&quot; to contain mainland China. This policy has been maintained for a long time, implemented vigorously, and has far-reaching influence until today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the United States has refused to communicate with mainland China. Even though the &quot;Republic of China&quot; was forced to withdraw from the United Nations in 1971, the United States still maintained relations with it until 1978, when Beijing and Washington formally established diplomatic relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Cold War began, defending Taiwan became one of the tasks of the United States. As far as the Taiwan authorities are concerned, without the &quot;reassurance&quot; of the United States - the United States has drawn its defense line in the Taiwan Strait - the construction of this base in Taiwan would not have been possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The grievances and grievances between Taiwan and the mainland on the other side of the Taiwan Strait cannot be resolved to this day. How will these disputes be resolved in the future? How can we &quot;reunify&quot;? How can the results of Taiwan&#39;s construction, Taiwan&#39;s talents, Taiwan&#39;s economic foundation, and the mainland&#39;s economic construction support each other? This depends on the wisdom of us Chinese people, thinking about how to take into account the Chinese blood. Of course, the DPP and I have different ideas regarding the words &quot;Chinese blood.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the two sides of the Taiwan Strait have supported each other in economic construction, and this has not stopped since the 1970s. Mainland China&#39;s economic construction is about twenty years later than Taiwan&#39;s, because it experienced thirty years of bumps caused by trying various policies. From the time when Deng Xiaoping came to power to today, the cooperation and communication between the two sides has been carried out by the Straits Affairs Committee of both sides as the &quot;bridge&quot;, and by foreign heads of state such as Lee Kuan Yew as the &quot;middleman&quot;. Before Hong Kong and Macao returned to China, they were natural points of contact between the two sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second very important thing is the institutional reform of Taiwan initiated by Chiang Ching-kuo. He declared: &quot;We, the Chiang family, will no longer be involved in politics.&quot; Later, Lee Teng-hui changed Taiwan&#39;s basic law. But paradoxically, the U.S. government continues to promise to &quot;defend Taiwan with all its strength.&quot; This statement has become a rare example in the history of international relations. People familiar with international affairs once described this arrangement as &quot;intentional ambiguity.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Chinese history, from the Spring and Autumn Period to the Warring States Period, the Jin State was the de facto leader of the &quot;Five Hegemons&quot;. Jin took possession of the cognac of its ally Weiguo. The hegemony of the Jin State was already declining at that time, and its interior was eventually divided among the three families of Korea, Zhao, and Wei. Chinese history entered the &quot;Seven Heroes&quot; era of the Warring States Period. At that time, those who really had the strength to compete for hegemony were the two marginal powers, Qin and Chu. The two hegemons Wu and Yue that appeared in the gap were just short-lived. The two marginal powers, Qin and Chu, competed. In the end, Qin unified China and became the predecessor of the &quot;Chinese Empire&quot;. The process of Qin&#39;s unification of the Central Plains and the system it established actually restricted the form of the Chinese Empire for two thousand years, and it was only changed in 1911. Here, I use this example from Chinese history to foresee possible future changes in the hegemony of the United States over the past few decades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the establishment of U.S. hegemony, East Asia has encountered many crises: a Korean War and two Vietnam Wars - Japan and South Korea have become de facto &quot;dependencies&quot; of the United States, and Okinawa&#39;s status has become unclear. white. And these are all the consequences of the &quot;containment policy.&quot; The United States was so hegemonic that it could do the same thing in other countries that the Jin State obtained the cognac of the Wei State - Cognac was a stronghold in the eastern half of the Central Plains at that time, and the Jin State could not command the northern half. This situation is very similar to the &quot;island chain&quot; situation in East Asia. Paradoxically, the Zhao State, which was separated from the Jin State, finally took away the Cognac. We cannot predict whether the United States will transform Taiwan into an &quot;extension&quot; of Japan and South Korea in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look at the situation in Europe. After the &quot;Marshall Plan&quot;, the United States established NATO and the European Union, focusing on the three countries of Britain, France, and Germany—the past enemy Germany—to guard the heart of Europe. Decades later, the European Union now feels that the United States was there to protect them, but now the United States has become their master. The United States spent a lot of effort to defend Europe. The &quot;Marshall Plan&quot; really rebuilt a world full of flowers and flowers from the ruins. Today&#39;s Germany has a prosperous economic foundation that is different from the United States we see today - Britain and France were defeated, and Germany came up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, the United States divided Germany into two: half occupied by the West and half occupied by the Soviet Union - just like North Korea was divided into South Korea, South Vietnam and North Vietnam. Berlin is an independent city, and a &quot;Berlin Wall&quot; was built in the middle. During the first Berlin Crisis in 1948, the Soviet Union blocked Berlin. The United States airdropped food, hamburgers, hot dogs, milk, eggs and even paper and other daily necessities for several months. The planes never stopped on the runway. That&#39;s a staggering expense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 25, 1963, Kennedy gave a speech in Berlin - &quot;As a free man, I am extremely proud to say: I am a Berliner.&quot; After becoming president, Kennedy also said: We Don&#39;t forget that Churchill and our old President Roosevelt once proposed that human beings should have &quot;four freedoms.&quot; (The &quot;Atlantic Charter&quot; signed by Roosevelt and Churchill actually has two &quot;versions&quot;: one is a long &quot;treaty&quot;, and the other is a short slogan of the &quot;Four Freedoms&quot; - freedom from fear, freedom from want , freedom of speech, freedom of belief.) It is our unshirkable duty to be the guardians of the world and safeguard these &quot;four freedoms.&quot; Back then, Kennedy swore an oath based on the &quot;Four Freedoms&quot;: Our mission is long and arduous. Don’t ask what the country can do for us, ask what we can do for the country. After President Roosevelt implemented the New Deal, the country fulfilled its responsibilities to its citizens and maintained their minimum standard of living. The responsibility of our government is to realize the &quot;four freedoms&quot; on American soil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These declarations are very touching, and Americans are indeed working very hard in practice. The boundaries drawn at the time still exist today - the recent conflict between Ukraine and Russia was caused by the US &quot;containment policy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What I said above is to explain the cultural background of Kennan’s “containment policy”, the United States’ expectations of itself, and its efforts. From then to now, for more than seventy years, the hegemony of the United States has been presented under the discourse system of &quot;containment policy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was also the Cuban Missile Crisis. The Soviet Union wanted to set up a missile base in Cuba, but the United States would not allow it. Kennedy and Khrushchev confronted each other and refused to give in. Eventually the Soviet Union gave in and withdrew its missiles from Cuba. The United States still occupies Guantánamo Bay in Cuba and refuses to give it up until death: it is a prison without legal control. The spies and prisoners the United States interrogates here are not protected by any human rights laws and are forced to water and whip. , electric shock and other torture, and the body was thrown away after death. I often use the word &quot;paradox&quot; to describe this kind of behavior: the United States claims to safeguard the &quot;four freedoms&quot;, but in fact there is always such a &quot;scar&quot;, but it turns a blind eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1957, mankind’s first artificial satellite was successfully launched by the Soviet Union. The United States spent a lot of money and tried hard to maintain the balance of power in space. Finally, in 1969, during the Nixon era, American astronauts landed on the moon for the first time. The year before, 59 countries, including the United States, the Soviet Union, and the United Kingdom, jointly signed the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons. Restricting new countries from developing nuclear weapons is a good thing for the world. As for countries that already possess nuclear weapons, it is unknown whether someone will use nuclear bombs first. Until the Reagan era, the arms competition between the United States and the Soviet Union continued, and even developed to the point where satellites could be used to carry nuclear bombs into space. The United States crushed the Soviet economy with its huge space arms race. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The previous description of U.S. foreign policy in history is used as a background to illustrate that U.S. foreign policy is the most important &quot;medicine&quot; in Sino-U.S. relations and is also intended to maintain the hegemonic thinking of Western culture and &quot;Containment&quot; thoughts. This is a very important principle for us to understand the complex chess game of the world since World War II. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Chinese in the United States under &quot;McCarthyism&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since World War II, many Chinese students have studied in the United States, including me. We come here to study because the curriculum and equipment of American schools are among the best in the world. At this stage, the United States is indeed recruiting a large number of foreign students, and we take this opportunity to learn skills. Of course, Chinese people like to return fallen leaves to their roots. Most of the hundreds of international students who came to the United States through the &quot;Geng Geng&quot; funds in the early days returned to China, and their main jobs were either in education or industry. At that time, China&#39;s scientific and technological development was not yet mainstream, and scientific and technological talents were roughly distributed in the above two categories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, with the civil war between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party, China was divided into two and the straits were blocked. This became a big problem: under the &quot;containment policy&quot; stance of the &quot;containment policy&quot;, the United States would not allow students from mainland China to They return to the mainland. The most important example is Qian Xuesen. At that time, American physics was at the forefront of the world. If China wanted to develop modern technological weapons, Qian Xuesen&#39;s participation would definitely make a contribution. I believe Qian Xuesen did his best in inventing missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the &quot;Iron Curtain&quot; began to fall, the United States began to be suspicious of &quot;left-leaning&quot; people in the United States. This incident occurred during Truman&#39;s term. &quot;McCarthyism&quot; not only wanted to block those intellectuals who chose to return to China or Eastern European countries, but also wanted to eradicate &quot;left-leaning&quot; elements in the country. The so-called &quot;left leaning&quot; is defined as &quot;liberal elements&quot; - anyone who is not &quot;right&quot; is labeled as &quot;left&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person mainly responsible for this matter is the Pacific International Society. Their surveillance network is very wide and covers all the bases for China research-Pittsburgh is okay because it is not a big base. Such a situation has made Chinese people across the United States fearful. One day, agents from the FBI or CIA will check your correspondence and check your tax payments. Everyone was in disbelief and fearful. When I came to Pittsburgh in 1970, I saw the remnants of this phenomenon. An old overseas Chinese named Yu - he changed his name to &quot;Lin Pan&quot; when he came here because he bought the Lin family&#39;s &quot;birth certificate&quot;; our current dentist belongs to the Yu family. The old gentleman came to my office to talk. He closed the door first, then gently talked to me about their fears, and asked me in a low voice: &quot;When will this situation end?&quot; Because they have many children from their hometown who want to come out. But the &quot;Iron Curtain&quot; has dropped; there are still dozens of fellow villagers who died in foreign lands, so they have to be cremated first and wait until one day to take them back to their hometowns. Recently, Quanzi also visited the location where the ashes are stored, and there were indeed dozens of jars there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, &quot;McCarthyism&quot; was subsided, and Taiwan resumed exchanges with the United States. I returned to Taiwan in 1962 and spent the next two or three years working in the History Department of my alma mater, National Taiwan University, arranging courses according to the modern scale and direction. My main job was to liaise with academic institutions and sinologists in the United States. My supervisors are Mr. Wang Shijie, president of Academia Sinica, and Mr. Li Ji, director of the Institute of History and Philology. This job is very difficult, and many people question my position: If we go to Taiwan, will it increase the United States&#39; suspicion of me? I said: &quot;I can&#39;t answer your question, but I went back, and I have no problem.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was not until 1971, after Nixon launched &quot;ping pong diplomacy&quot; with mainland China, that there were a large number of overseas Chinese Young people and international students returned to the mainland; subsequently, a large number of international students came from the mainland as well, more than ten times more than those from Taiwan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Wcb0MkQeDfGn11pLogqeywCkeBau6ADMYXoj9kSS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Wcb0MkQeDfGn11pLogqeywCkeBau6ADMYXoj9kSS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1956, Mr. Yang Zhenning and Li Zhengdao proposed the &quot;law of non-conservation of parity&quot;; subsequently, Ms. Wu Jianxiong proved this theory through experiments - these three are world-famous physicists. Because Mr. Yang&#39;s father was still in the mainland, he went back as soon as Sino-US relations loosened, and has never cut off contacts with the mainland since then. He also worked very hard to introduce the research situation of modern physics in the United States to China and help domestic scholars. For decades, he has helped many students study abroad based on his original intention and done his best for the development of physics in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was fortunate enough to work with him and Liu Zunyi to help Mr. Yu Jizhong set up the &quot;Chinese-English Teaching Foundation&quot; in mainland China. The purpose is to help university teachers go abroad for as short as half a year or as long as one year. Further education. As long as they put forward the visiting unit, goals, plans, time, as well as an invitation letter or commitment from the United States, as well as a letter of recommendation from the school, we will try our best to prioritize them in a professional direction. It is a very pleasant job for me to see so many outstanding scholars lining up, ready to make further efforts. Unfortunately, there are too few people and we cannot satisfy everyone&#39;s wishes. Because of this work, Mr. Yang meets with us once a year. In addition to our lectures to various schools, I also had the opportunity to ask for advice from him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, we visited the Chinese University of Hong Kong at the same time, and we would often drink tea and chat together. With such a friendship, I admire him greatly: he is old but still childlike, smart but not overbearing. He has reached the pinnacle of his specialized knowledge and is very knowledgeable about general affairs. The most admirable thing: He is completely frank with juniors of my age, which makes me feel like I am sitting on a spring breeze when talking to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[再获雨果奖，中国科幻文学更进一步]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259145]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the evening of October 21, the 2023 Hugo Awards were announced at the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, with a total of 17 Hugo categories selected Awards and Category 2 non-Hugo Awards, Chinese writer Hai Miao won the Best Short Novella Award for &quot;The Painter of Time and Space&quot;.这也是雨果奖首次在中国揭晓和颁奖。</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[检察机关依法对李春生涉嫌受贿一案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259201]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Reporters learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate on October 24 that the former deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People’s Congress Li Chunsheng&#39;s suspected bribery case was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the case was reviewed and prosecuted by the Chenzhou City People&#39;s Procuratorate of Hunan Province. Recently, the Chenzhou City People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Chenzhou City Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ informed the defendant Li Chunsheng of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant, and listened to the opinions of the defender. Prosecution charges: Li Chunsheng used his position as county magistrate and county party committee secretary of Xin County in Henan Province, deputy director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security and director of the Personnel Training Bureau, deputy governor of Guangdong Province and director of the Provincial Public Security Department, and deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress. , deputy director and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers and status, to seek benefits for relevant units and individuals in business operations, project promotion, project contracting, job promotion, etc., illegally accepting property from others, the amount is particularly huge, and should be legally accepted He will be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访经济学家吴晓求：“要把A股市场从融资市场转变为投资市场”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259197]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the Chinese capital market for more than thirty years, with more than 200 million investors and more than 5,300 listed companies, there is no A market that touches the nerves of all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the Political Bureau meeting of the CPC Central Committee proposed “activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence.” The China Securities Regulatory Commission and other departments subsequently launched a package of policies for “active capital markets”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges are the product of reform. They later underwent two historic reforms: shareholding split and registration system. But for a long time, every investor has suffered from short-term bullishness and bearishness. What loopholes have been left behind by the share-trading reform that once inspired the Long Bull market? How to fix blockage? What loopholes have arisen from the registration system? How to fix it quickly? How can the positioning of China&#39;s capital market mature through changes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the occasion of the 45th anniversary of the reform and opening up of China&#39;s financial industry, Wu Xiaoqiu, former vice president of Renmin University of China and director of the China Capital Market Research Institute, emphasized in an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend that the establishment of the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges and the split of shares Reform and comprehensive registration-based reform are three monuments in the more than 30 years since the establishment of China&#39;s capital market. While they have achieved great success, they have also left some loopholes. These loopholes are the important institutional constraints that have caused the capital market to stagnate over the past decade. At present, regulatory authorities have realized and stepped up efforts to improve system design and plug loopholes. In the longer term, the main function of China&#39;s capital market is to transform from financing enterprises to a wealth management platform for investors, and from a financing market to an investment market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xiaoqiu is the youngest professor of economics in the history of Renmin University of China and the first doctoral supervisor in the field of securities investment in China. He has been engaged in securities teaching and research for more than 30 years. He led the compilation of the first edition of China Securities Practitioner examination materials. He is also the promoter and witness of many major reforms in the capital market, such as the share-trading reform and the registration system reform. He has made many suggestions for active capital markets. Among them, his consistent assertion that &quot;the time is not ripe for the implementation of the T+0 trading system&quot; is in line with the China Securities Regulatory Commission. The current stance is consistent. The &quot;Phaseically Tightened Securities Lending and Strategic Investors Placement and Lending of Shares&quot; notice issued by the China Securities Regulatory Commission on October 14, 2023 is also related to the loopholes in the shareholding reduction rules and systems that Wu Xiaoqiu has been paying attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;569&quot; height= &quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Xiaoqiu: former vice president of Renmin University of China; currently dean of the National Institute of Financial Research and China Capital Market Research Institute of Renmin University of China, national first-class professor, and executive director of the China Society for Finance and Banking . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Engaged in the economy&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Financial and Capital Market Research&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Forty&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Years”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are a college student in the &quot;New Third Class&quot; (1977-1979). If the college entrance examination and reform and opening up had not been resumed, how would your life trajectory have evolved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I never went to high school. Before college, he worked as a carpenter and later as a secretary in the county commerce bureau. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resumption of the college entrance examination and reform and opening up changed the destiny of my life, just as it changed the destiny of thousands of my contemporaries in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee was held in December 1978, but the college entrance examination was resumed in 1977. Putting the resumption of the college entrance examination before the Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee, I think this is to prepare for reform and opening up in terms of ideology, talent, and public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resumption of the college entrance examination is a reform in itself. It is equivalent to a fundamental adjustment of the talent training system during the ten-year &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; period, bringing order to things. Looking back on the past, without reform and opening up, a key move that determines the fate of contemporary China, China would not be what it is today, and neither would I be what I am today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you apply for the national economics major of Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I initially applied for the philosophy major at Jiangxi University because I like philosophy. When my father found out, he asked me to change my major. He believes that he should study at Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics. The major in national economic planning is very good and the economy may still be very important in the future. This change is also a &quot;decisive move&quot; for me personally. I later thought about my father&#39;s decision. He foresaw the future development direction of China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my first year of college, I got to know Sun Yefang, Yu Guangyuan, Xu Dixin, Song Tao, Dong Fuzhen and other seniors. They are monuments in my mind. The dream of a scholar and the dream of an economist have been with me since I was in college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the postgraduate entrance examination in 1983, I ranked second overall and was admitted to the National Economic Planning major of Renmin University of China. For the National Economic Planning major, Renmin University is a palace. Later, I studied for a Ph.D. and stayed at the school to teach after graduation, and I never left. I first did economic research for about 10 years. From 1993 to 1994, I officially switched to financial research and capital market research, which now has a history of almost 30 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;If you don&#39;t emancipate your mind, you can&#39;t find the right path to development&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the beginning of his studies (1983-1986), reform and opening up developed from rural areas to cities, urban economic system reform began, township enterprises began to sprout, and opening up to the outside world continued to expand. During this period, which reform events impressed you the most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are four things that impressed me deeply: The first time was attending an economic system reform seminar in Chaohu, Anhui. In 1985, the central government issued the &quot;Decision on Economic System Reform&quot; and launched the economic system reform that combined planning and market. It was a historic decision. I was a second-year graduate student at the time, and my supervisor, Mr. Hu Naowu, and I attended this seminar. That was my first time to participate in a national, high-level forum. It touched me greatly and expanded my horizons. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second time was in 1985, when I participated in the Second Youth and Middle-aged Economic Forum held in Tianjin. The young people participating in the forum were active in thinking, participating in various debates, thinking about China&#39;s future, and exploring the focus of reform. I was writing an article about corporate bankruptcy. Bankruptcy is a thing of the market economy. There was no such thing as bankruptcy in China under the planned economy at that time, only &quot;shut down and transfer&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third time in 1985, I participated in a forum held in the Great Hall of the People. That forum was hosted by Mr. Dong Fucheng, and my speech attracted the attention of Li Chengrui, then director of the National Bureau of Statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth time was in 1986, when I participated in another discussion meeting on economic leverage in Leshan, Sichuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was only in my twenties at the time. It can be seen that that era gave young people many platforms and opportunities to speak freely at high-level forums held in the Great Hall of the People. This activates your mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those were sparkling days, full of youthful dreams and pursuits of young people everywhere. Only when the mind is liberated can academics prosper and the country develop. Without emancipating our minds, we cannot find the right path to development. Everything must be explored, discussed and even debated before you know which is the right path. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Cracking the mystery of China&#39;s special economic phenomenon&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During your doctoral studies (1987-1990), the basic line of &quot;one center, two basic points&quot; and &quot;science and technology are the primary productive forces&quot; were proposed. In the meantime, what are your views on China’s economic reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The most important thing when studying for a PhD is to learn advanced theories, study the Chinese economy, and how to solve the mystery of the special phenomena of the Chinese economy at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book that had the greatest impact on me at that time was &quot;The Economics of Shortage&quot; by the Hungarian economist János Korny. In the mid-to-late 1980s, many people read this work. &quot;Shortage Economics&quot; is a book that describes the basic characteristics of socialist economic operations under the traditional planned economic system. It is rich in strong theoretical logic, including soft budget constraints, paternalism, etc. Inspired by his thoughts, I started writing &quot;Theory of Compact Movement&quot; in 1987. &quot;The Theory of Tight Operation&quot; and my doctoral thesis &quot;Analysis of Socialist Economic Operation&quot; were published in 1991 and 1992 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did this book receive such special attention at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The real value of these two books is their attempt to explain the characteristics and laws of socialist economic operation under the traditional system. Because of these two books, as well as articles and papers published in People&#39;s Daily, Guangming Daily, Economic Research and Journal of Renmin University of China, I was promoted to professor by Renmin University in 1993. That year, Renmin University made an exception and promoted five professors, and I was the youngest among them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Transforming securities research and taking a road less traveled&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1994, you were transferred to the Department of Finance and Finance as a professor in the field of securities research in finance. The following year, you became the first doctoral supervisor in the field of securities investment in my country. Since then, you have been closely associated with China&#39;s securities industry. The relationship has been developing for thirty years. Why focus on securities research from now on? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was already studying finance at that time, so I offered to be transferred. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two opportunities: one is to alleviate poverty. In the early 1990s, I was about to become a professor and still lived in a Tongzi building with only 800 yuan in savings. At that time, someone gave me an idea, saying that you write a best-selling book, we will be responsible for selling it, and then give you a share. I thought of stocks and bonds. So I edited the &quot;Complete Book of Stocks and Bonds&quot;, which contained about 5 million words in two volumes. It was a great seller as soon as it was launched. Later, I was given some money, and I got out of poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because I am the editor-in-chief, people ask me to speak. This forced me to really learn securities knowledge and securities investment. This has begun to deviate from the direction of my economics research, which is entirely the study of capital markets and finance. At that time, people did not think it was a science, and even thought it was a bit &quot;crooked&quot;. An important scholar among my predecessors once talked to me. The core idea was that I should return to the mainstream track of economic research such as economic operation analysis, macroeconomics, macroeconomic management and inflation theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The path of securities research was a sparsely traveled path at that time. There were few professional researchers, a lot of noise, and very little rational research. But in my opinion, the more in-depth securities research is, the more valuable it is. I am one of the few people left who has done research in the early stages and is still doing front-line research now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The then president of Renmin University, Mr. Huang Da, was a professor in the Department of Finance, so I applied to go to the Department of Finance. I taught a course on securities investment. At that time, there were not many securities investment courses offered in colleges and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;I first entered the stock market both for making money and for research&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There was a movie called &quot;Stock Crazy&quot; in 1994, which tells the story of the various crazes caused by mass speculation in the stock market in the early days of the stock market. Was the stock market back then really like in the movies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; (The craze for stock trading) has indeed begun. The stock market has begun to enter people&#39;s lives, more and more people are investing in the stock market, and various theories, methods and stock reviews have begun to appear. Because I wrote &quot;The Complete Book of Stocks and Bonds&quot;, I also started doing research on it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a research expert on securities investment, what will happen to you? Is stock trading practical? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was only after 2000 that I really entered the stock market as an investor. After entering, I found that practice was more profoundly helpful to my theoretical research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is the difference between securities research and stock trading? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My goal in entering this market is not only to make money, but also to do research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I set two goals for myself at that time: first, not to lose money, and to see through practical operations whether what I learned theoretically would work in practice; second, to establish a direct perceptual understanding of the research object. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slowly, I understand the rules of securities investment and the market better. When I write textbooks, I will be more enriched and my writing will be more vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During that period, I presided over the compilation of the first set of teaching materials for the securities practitioner qualification examination in China. The first edition consisted of six volumes. The general structure of the later textbooks compiled by the China Securities Regulatory Commission did not deviate from this edition. It plays a very important role in the qualification examination for securities practitioners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have the expectations of making money been met? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I also wanted to catch the bull market and make a fortune. The first one I remember was buying Sichuan Changhong, and one day I suddenly discovered that it was going up quite well. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;The loopholes left over from the split-share structure reform must be closed &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once said that China’s capital market has three monuments: Shanghai The establishment of the Shenzhen Stock Exchange, the share-trading reform, and the pilot registration system. What have you been involved in promoting? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I participated in the share-trading reform and promoted the pilot registration system. The share-trading reform was launched in May 2005. However, since the theoretical preparation failed in 2001 when the reduction of state-owned shares failed, we began to think about how to carry out share-trading reform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did the reduction of state-owned shares fail in 2001? What inspiration did it provide for the subsequent share-trading reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time, the regulatory agency believed that the reduction of state-owned shares could be reduced at market price, but it was hastily stopped due to the huge market reaction. Later analysis concluded that reducing state-owned stocks based on market prices lacked both logic and theoretical support, so it was bound to fail. As a result of this failure, we were reflecting on how to promote split-share reform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During that period of reflection, the academic community organized many discussions, and I was probably one of the people who participated the most, whether in small-scale discussions hosted by the China Securities Regulatory Commission or in large-scale discussions. I participated in almost every discussion. Among them, the most impressive one was when Shang Fulin, then chairman of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, called me one day in 2004 and discussed with me alone how to change the split share structure. Later, I went to his office many times to participate in discussions, with about ten people in a small group and twenty or thirty people in a large group. After discussion, we reached a consensus on two points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first point is that the split share structure reform must be promoted. If we do not promote the reform, China&#39;s capital market will have no future. This is what I also emphasize; the second point is what method should be used to reform the split-share structure reform. The design of this path is very difficult. We slowly considered that consideration reform is appropriate. Consideration reform is only a direction. It becomes more difficult to determine the appropriate consideration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I clearly remember that during a meeting of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, Tu Guangshao, then vice chairman of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, asked me, what do you think is the appropriate proportion of the consideration? I said 30% or 30% off, because the price of additional issuance of stock is 30% off the circulating price. This provides a reference for the consideration of the share-trading reform. Later, practice proved that the consideration plans for the share-trading reform of various listed companies fluctuated around 30% off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the early days of the share-trading reform in 2005, the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets did not Too big a reaction. The big bull market seems to have started only after 2005. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. The share-trading reform was launched in May 2005. At that time, the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets had been in the doldrums for more than four years since 2001, and the market response was lukewarm. Later, the market gradually learned that this thing was serious, and more and more people had a premonition that this was an opportunity for a big bull market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We judged at that time that the long bear market in the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets would be reversed during the share-trading reform process. After the reform is completed, it will lay a good foundation for the long-term healthy development of the capital market. From today&#39;s perspective, the general direction of the share-trading reform is correct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The share-trading reform took about two years. What shortcomings does it have? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From May 2005 to March 2007, 95% of listed companies completed the share-trading reform. It is a monument, but it does have flaws. This flaw is the lack of effective constraints on the reduction of major shareholders and actual controllers. This policy loophole had an important impact on the subsequent stagnation of the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets for more than ten years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have also said recently that the most important thing that seriously restricts the development of China’s capital market is the institutional design of the asset supply side. Among them, the asset supply side is mainly the reduction rules of existing assets, which is the actual Controllers and controlling shareholders do not have financial constraints to reduce their holdings, which makes it difficult for the market to grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you think this loophole is being fixed now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;On August 27, 2023, there have been some amendments in the China Securities Regulatory Commission policy. This is a loophole left by the share-trading reform, and we must make up for it. Because it seriously damages the ecological chain of capital supply and demand in the capital market and causes a serious imbalance in the capital supply relationship. At present, major loopholes are being patched, so at least we know where they are. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Registration reform has had mixed effects”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The third monument you mentioned in China’s capital market is the registration-based reform. Why start the registration system reform? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After 2007, the theoretical research, or policy formulation, that I participated in was mainly the registration system reform. Why should we carry out registration reform? Because the approval system has major flaws. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the biggest problem with the approval system is that the choice of listing a company is not left to the market, but to the Issuance Review Committee and to visible hands. The second problem is that the pricing is not market-oriented, so there is a strange phenomenon of 20 daily limit after listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third problem is that the regulatory body and the auditing body are not separated. The China Securities Regulatory Commission both audits and supervises. This is of course problematic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the fact that the approval system has at least these three problems, if we want to correct these three defects, we must carry out the registration system reform. In accordance with the principle of marketization, the exchange adopts a flexible system, and at the same time does not adhere to the requirement that companies to be listed must be profitable. Compared with the approval system, which requires companies to be listed to be profitable for three consecutive years, one of the biggest innovations of the registration system is that major high-tech companies that are planning to be listed are allowed to have losses in the past three years, but they must have sustainable operating capabilities. This is a major change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023 is the first year of the comprehensive registration system reform. As a promoter and policy participant of the registration system reform, are you satisfied with the current results of the reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Bittersweet. Fortunately, some unicorn companies and high-tech companies have become listed companies through this mechanism. Although they are losing money in the short term, they have the ability to operate sustainably. The registration system reform naturally serves specialized and high-tech innovative enterprises, and is naturally coupled with high-tech enterprises. Only under the registration system can technology and capital markets be coupled, and we will still work in this direction in the future. I think this is of great value and significance to us in promoting the development of high-tech enterprises, transforming my country&#39;s industrial structure and upgrading and iterating industries, improving the structure of listed companies, and enhancing the investment value of China&#39;s capital market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is worrying is the generalization of the definition of loss in the registration system. This is a serious misunderstanding, which damages market confidence and is not in line with the original meaning of the registration system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why does this vulnerability occur? What are the dangers of this vulnerability? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Like the share-trading reform, the registration-based reform also has a loophole. Frankly, no one realized it at the time. Just like designing a spacecraft, there are a lot of details and a lot of sparse details. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The loophole of the registration system is that it generalizes the market-oriented functions, or it generalizes the indicators that listed companies do not strictly require profitability. So later, some listed companies seized on such a loophole and established a so-called high-tech enterprise. Under the banner of the so-called &quot;breaking the bottleneck project&quot;, they hired dozens of researchers and started to apply for IPO after two or three years. . This has done huge damage to market confidence. They do not comply with the basic spirit of the registration system, and also exceed the requirements of the risk boundaries that a public market, exchange market, and public investors can bear. The financing of this type of enterprise should mainly be completed by PE and VC, and direct IPO is not allowed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I define this loophole as: a generalized understanding of the non-profit requirement under the registration system. This is a very serious misunderstanding, which is closely related to the subsequent stagnation of the stock market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is this vulnerability currently being patched? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I once made it clear to the China Securities Regulatory Commission that the requirement that companies to be listed be unprofitable cannot be generalized. Judging from the recent IPO situation, the China Securities Regulatory Commission and exchanges have also paid special attention to the listing requirements of companies with negative financial indicators, especially those with negative net assets, negative cash flow, and negative profits. These major financial reporting indicators are all negative, and such companies cannot be listed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After fixing the loopholes, the registration system reform is completed What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Far from it. The registration-based reform is an all-round, whole-chain reform. The market-oriented reform of the issuance system is only its historical and logical starting point. It will also be followed by transactions, mergers and acquisitions, information disclosure, supervision, delisting, penalties for violations and illegal acts, legal models, etc. Adjustments in many other aspects must be incorporated into the model compatible with the registration system reform and continuously improved. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;Twin Peaks model is the ideal compromise&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2022, you proposed the &quot;twin peaks model&quot; of China&#39;s financial system. What are the deep observations and thoughts behind it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Frankly speaking, the first thing I proposed was the &quot;single bee mode&quot;. Around 2002, I believed that China’s future financial model would be dominated by the capital market. Twenty years have passed, and I have found that the &quot;single bee model&quot; is very difficult to achieve in China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite this, in the past 20 years, the scale of China&#39;s capital market has expanded relatively rapidly. From a market capitalization of two to three trillion in the past to a market capitalization of more than eighty trillion today, its proportion in the financial system has increased significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, I finally realized that China’s commercial banks play a huge role in China’s economic life, and China can only implement the bimodal model-the banking system and the capital market jointly dominate. This is an ideal compromise and a realistic situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why is it difficult for the capital market to become dominant? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The development of the capital market has not changed the dependence of the Chinese economy on money and credit. From the perspective of the capital market itself, the stock prices of listed companies have not increased in the past 20 years, and the market index has not increased. Only the market value has expanded. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the number of listed companies has increased from 1,000 to more than 5,300 in the past 20 years. Almost China’s largest and best companies have achieved IPOs, including many state-owned enterprises and central enterprises. and “unicorn” companies. In a sense, the function of China&#39;s stock market in facilitating enterprise financing has been realized, but it itself is a pie-spreading expansion, constantly expanding outwards without intensive cultivation, and the unit output rate of enterprises after obtaining financing is very low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is our index not growing? A very important reason is to go back to the two loopholes I just mentioned, especially the first loophole, which is the reduction rule, which has a huge inhibitory effect on growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;China’s stock market&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Why&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is still immature&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Our capital market has developed for more than 30 years. At the age of thirty, can it be considered a mature market? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China’s capital market has slowly found a basic direction in practice and reform, but it is still an immature market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first immaturity is that there are many loopholes in the system design. The second immaturity lies in the lack of a deep understanding of what the capital market means to China and what it means to financial reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, we often said that the main purpose of establishing the stock market was to facilitate corporate financing. This is an incorrect positioning and perception. The securities market appears to be financing, but is actually investment. If you don’t continuously strengthen your investment function, financing will be unsustainable, and people will vote with their feet. If you leave, how can you raise funds? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, we need to transform China’s capital market from a financing market that facilitates corporate financing to a wealth management platform and investment market for investors. Transforming from a financing market to an investment market is our future direction. It will take a long time to achieve this goal. For institutional effects to take effect, it will take time for corresponding institutional arrangements to be put in place. Our current institutional arrangements are closing loopholes and moving closer to this aspect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A-shares are bullish and bearish. The main problem is the loopholes in the system design and Don’t really understand the significance of the capital market to financial reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The reason for this phenomenon in China’s capital market is not only the profound cultural and legal background, but also the misalignment of rules at the meso level. For example, there are two loopholes in the share-trading reform and the registration-based reform mentioned earlier. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, part of the reason is that our entrepreneurs do not have a deep understanding of what listing means to them. Originally, going public was a means, but these company founders suddenly discovered that it was so easy to make a fortune by going public, which was much easier than working hard in the real economy. This corroded their original intention to start a business in the past. He will take listing as his goal and stop doing the real economy. He will find a way to cash out and leave as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To correct this misdirection, we can only guide it through institutional reform - only by doing a good job can you cash out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What specific suggestions do you have for this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To achieve a fundamental transformation of the functions and orientation of the capital market, the first step is to transform the overall macro-system design. On the asset supply side, the system design must be conducive to the transformation of market functions, the introduction of transparent and growth-producing assets into the market, and the attraction of more and more new investors and the entry of new funds into the market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, we should have certain restrictions on all pre-listing shareholders reducing their shareholdings, especially controlling shareholders and actual controllers, including second shareholders, third shareholders, etc. How to use Financial indicators constrain shareholding reductions and require innovative system designs to allow all shareholders to focus their attention and efforts on how to do a good job in the company, create profits, and improve distribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, we must continue to improve the ecological environment of the capital market. Whether institutional investors or individual investors, in this market, they can obtain returns commensurate with their risks, and only then will the market grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;The stock market continues to not improve, and we need to come up with the right response&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the end of July, the central government clearly proposed to &quot;activate the capital market.&quot; What signal does this send? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It should be said that the supervisory authorities have seen the problem. No field in China covers such a large scope as the capital market. There are at least 200 million investors in the capital market, and behind them may be 200 million families. Almost half of the people in China have something to do with the capital market. Second, although the global capital markets have gone through the epidemic, China&#39;s capital markets among major economies have not performed well. We need to pay more attention to the problems behind it. Third, activating the capital market is also an important measure to boost market confidence. We need to come up with the right response. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are also many expert suggestions for activating the capital market A shares switch from T+1 to T+0. But regulators have long said the opportunity is premature. What do you think? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The transaction reform has no substantive significance, T+0 is not conducive to the growth of the market, and the logical basis of the T+0 reform is unclear. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the biggest benefit of T+0 is to securities companies. T+0 will directly lead to an increase in brokerage commissions, thereby driving the rise of brokerage stocks. The goal of our reform is not to make securities companies prosperous, and the original intention of activating the capital market is not to increase commissions. An increase in commissions will instead mean the leakage of capital market funds. As for what some people say that T+0 has a correction mechanism for market prices, I think more empirical research is needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the trading rules based on T+1 were chosen in the early days of the birth of China’s capital market and against the background of many trials and errors of trading rules. After more than 30 years of practice, they have become very mature and more Suitable for China&#39;s national conditions. I like the T+1 system very much. Why do stocks bought in the morning have to be sold in the afternoon? Since you are going to sell in the afternoon, don’t buy in the morning. The logic is very clear. If you buy it wrong, it will be the same if you sell it tomorrow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the T+1 system is not unique to China and is also very mature internationally. Some countries may not use T+0, but we do too. Personally, I don’t like T+0 because this system will drive people crazy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend: Do you have confidence in the Chinese stock market? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xiaoqiu: The prerequisite for the Chinese stock market to improve is that the Chinese economy must improve. I have always said that as long as the Chinese economy wants to do well, it will definitely do well. In essence, China&#39;s economic foundation is good. As long as the market plays a leading role, adapts to historical trends, abides by market laws, respects enterprises and entrepreneurial spirit, promotes reform and opening up, and follows the road of market economy, China&#39;s economy will surely do well. How could it not do well? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current problems in China’s economy are not mainly caused by cyclical factors. I have always believed that as long as the proven successful experience of the past 45 years of reform and opening up is persisted and further improved, China&#39;s economy will continue to maintain a good trend, and China&#39;s capital market will have a foundation for growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>