<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[森林消防“全覆盖”31个省份]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260136]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;(On the morning of November 7, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce Progress in the reform of the fire rescue system. Southern Weekend reporter Li Guitu)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/26de373a44.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/26de373a44.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;On the morning of November 7, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce the progress of the reform of the fire rescue system. Southern Weekend reporter Li Guitu)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Firefighting work and the construction of fire rescue teams have undergone all-round and profound changes.&quot; On the morning of November 7, 2023, at the State Council At a press conference held by the Information Office, Qiong Se, member of the Party Committee of the Ministry of Emergency Management and director of the National Fire Rescue Bureau, introduced the construction and development of the national comprehensive fire rescue team in its fifth anniversary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In October 2018, the public security fire brigade and the armed police forest brigade retired from active service and were formally placed under the Ministry of Emergency Management to form a national comprehensive fire rescue team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se said that in the past five years, nearly 200,000 teams have successfully completed transfers of subordinates, identity changes, rank changes, title changes, and official positions. work, establish the National Fire Rescue Bureau, implement unified leadership and hierarchical command, clarify the major principles of central construction and local use, and establish a dual management system that combines sections and focuses on sections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023 is the sixth year for open recruitment of firefighters after the establishment of the national comprehensive fire rescue team. Li Shangyu, head of the Education and Training Department of the Ministry of Emergency Management, said that there was a plan to recruit 15,000 people in 2023, but nearly 110,000 people signed up, marking the fourth consecutive full recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shangyu introduced that the average age of new firefighters is 21.8 years old, and 52.6% have a college degree or above. They are currently undergoing a one-year induction training. So far, the total number of firefighters recruited after the transformation has reached more than 94,000, accounting for 65.3% of the total number of existing firefighters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Forest firefighting adds more than 8,200 people&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;National firefighting After the rescue bureau was officially established, a new mobile team was formed. Xu Zhongshun, deputy director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, said that this is &quot;a major decision made based on the basic national conditions of my country&#39;s frequent natural disasters.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Zhongshun said that as a critical force in national emergencies and major disasters, the mobile team is mainly responsible for forest and grassland firefighting duties, supplemented by flood fighting and earthquake and geological disaster rescue. Responsibilities, task arrangements focus on fire fighting in winter and spring, flood control in summer and autumn, year-round disaster relief, seasonal cross-regional garrison, and implementation of preparatory operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The National Fire and Rescue Administration has integrated the forest fire corps and related fire and rescue mobile detachments, forming 10 cross-regional fire and rescue mobile corps and several detachments, brigades, and squadrons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the original establishment of forest firefighting teams is 25,000, mainly deployed in 10 provinces including Inner Mongolia, Jilin, Heilongjiang, Fujian, and Sichuan. On this basis, the Central Organization Office has approved the establishment of more than 8,200 forest firefighting teams, mainly to strengthen the first-line firefighting and rescue mobile forces in key forest areas, national parks, seven major river basins and surrounding areas across the country, and to achieve comprehensive coverage of 31 provinces. &quot;Full coverage&quot; of all administrative regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Zhongshun said that as of now, 17 provinces in the first batch of additional mobile teams have basically completed their deployment, and are now organizing the second batch of additional mobile teams. There are teams stationed in 3 provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;All disasters, major emergencies&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Firefighting After the rescue team was reformed and transformed, its functions have also been expanded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se introduced that on the basis of the original fire fighting and emergency rescue focusing on rescuing people&#39;s lives, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau focuses on &quot;all disaster types&quot;. The comprehensive rescue expansion of &quot;big emergency&quot; covers urban and rural and forest and grassland fire fighting, as well as disaster accident rescue such as floods, earthquakes, geology, typhoons, building collapses, and hazardous chemical leakage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taking 2022 as an example, fire rescue teams across the country received reports and handled 2.092 million disasters of various types, including 824,000 fire rescues and 469,000 emergency rescues. , 597,000 cases of various types of social assistance, 126,000 cases of official duties, and 76,000 cases of other dispatches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this total number of rescues, fire fighting is still the main type of accident that the fire rescue team responds to. At the same time, police situations involving water areas, mountains, production and equipment failures, trapped elevators, and traffic accidents accounted for 87.4% of the total number of rescues. &quot;They are the main types of rescues and are also the key directions for the expansion of functional tasks after the reform and restructuring.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se said that in response to these situations, in recent years, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau has vigorously strengthened the construction of professional forces and established a total of high-rise buildings, underground spaces, large commercial complexes, etc. There are more than 3,500 professional firefighting teams in the body and petrochemical enterprises, as well as earthquake, water, air, and rain, snow and ice rescue teams. Relying on the forest firefighting team, 12 special disaster rescue brigades and 55 affiliated rapid response teams have been established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[中山二院乳腺外科多人患癌？医院通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260152]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 08:35:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 7, 2023, our hospital noticed that &quot;Zhongshan Second Hospital Breast Cancer The surgical team is suspected of being affected by the experimental environment and reagents, causing many people to develop cancer.&quot; The hospital quickly organized an investigation and verification, and initially learned that: 3 people who worked and studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center in recent years have suffered from cancer, 2 of whom are now breast surgeons in our hospital and are working in clinical practice; the other 1 is not from us. The employees or students of the institute are those who come to the institute for further study from other places and have returned to work in their original units. No current student in this laboratory has contracted cancer. The specific situation is as follows: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Huang, female, studied for a doctoral degree in our hospital from 2017 to 2022, during which she studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center, and graduated with a doctoral degree in July 2022 Later, he joined the Breast Surgery Department of our hospital and engaged in clinical work. He was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in October 2023 and underwent surgery. His current condition is stable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Liu, male, studied for a doctoral degree in our hospital from 2013 to 2018. During this period, he studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center. He joined our hospital after graduating from the Ph.D. in August 2018. Breast surgery, engaged in clinical work. In June 2023, he was diagnosed with synovial sarcoma and underwent surgery. He recovered well after the operation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the above two employees became ill, the hospital has been caring about their health and organized expert consultations, visits and condolences. Another researcher is a doctoral student who graduated from a foreign hospital. In 2021, he came to our hospital for a year of further study and worked in the laboratory of the Breast Tumor Center. He completed his further study in April 2022 and left Guangzhou. In 2023, he was diagnosed with breast cancer at his place of work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Breast Cancer Center Laboratory was opened in 2009 and has trained more than 200 students so far. Since its establishment, the laboratory has been managed in strict accordance with the regulations, and all experimental personnel have been trained on safety and standardized operations before experiments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In response to public concerns about laboratory safety management, our hospital will continue to maintain safety red lines and consciously accept inspections and supervision from superior authorities. We also thank netizens for their opinions and suggestions. . Regarding concerns about linking cancer to laboratory or reagent exposure, given that the causes of individual cancer are extremely complex, relevant departments are sincerely welcome to organize third-party agencies to conduct assessment and investigations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Finally, I would like to thank all sectors of society for their care and attention to the health of medical workers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sun Yat-sen Memorial Hospital of Sun Yat-sen University&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;November 8, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[炮弹落在畹町镇：一座边陲小镇活在缅北战火旁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260124]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wanding Town resident Wu Xia photographed the war situation in Myanmar from the roof, blue in the distance The house on the roof is in Myanmar. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/65c4f43e62.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1131&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/65c4f43e62.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wanding Town resident Wu Xia took pictures of the war in Myanmar from the rooftop. The houses with blue roofs in the distance are in Myanmar. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the fifth day of the civil war in northern Myanmar, Wu Xia, who lives in the border town of Wanding, was so scared when she heard the sound of gunfire not far away that she turned off the iron Snack bar, hiding in a home made of reinforced concrete. Having lived in Wanding for more than 20 years, she told the Southern Weekend reporter that there had been wars on the opposite side before, with mostly gunshots, but the fighting in 2023 was the most fierce, all with heavy shelling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xia climbed to the roof of her house, where she could see Myanmar across the river. In a 39-second video she shot, the sound of gunfire and artillery continued from the valley, and helicopters circled the top of the mountain. At the foot of the mountain were dense houses, stretching from Myanmar to the eastern town of Ruili City, Yunnan Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, government army strongholds in many places in northern Myanmar were attacked by armed forces and exchanges of fire broke out. The fighting was fierce and the stalemate has continued to this day. On the national border, Wanding Town, which borders Bangsai Town in Myanmar, is a Chinese town that has been greatly affected by the war. Stray bullets have fallen into this town of about 10,000 people many times. In order to ensure the safety of residents, the local government arranged for school closures and mobilized residents to leave the town to avoid the war. The town implemented a &quot;only exit, no entry&quot; control policy, and even the town government staff evacuated to work in safe places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wanding Town is located on the border of China and Myanmar. Map by Liang Shuyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/19501b6c86. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;986&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/19501b6c86.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wanding Town is located on the border of China and Myanmar. Drawing by Liang Shuyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Don’t come out of your home”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 28, a shell from Myanmar hit a residential building in Wanding Town, destroying the top four floors. A big hole was blown out of the building. A few hours after the explosion, Mr. Yang, who sells aluminum doors and windows, rushed to the scene out of curiosity. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the shell had exploded and there were no casualties. “An old lady told me that when the shell exploded, It was so shaken that she couldn&#39;t hear anything for two hours.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Peng Qi first heard the sound of shells and gunshots, she didn&#39;t know what they were. She thought someone was setting off fireworks. In June 2023, she was transferred from Ruili City to Wanding Town and worked as a store manager in a chain milk tea shop. The locals told her that it was the sound of war in Myanmar and comforted her: &quot;It&#39;s okay, we hear this sound every year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The locals who are used to the sound of gunfire seem to be also attracted by it. This time the battle was frightening. At two or three o&#39;clock in the morning on October 29, Wu Xia was awakened by several gunshots while she was sleeping. That day, she listened to the sound of gunfire outside and judged that the exchange of fire between the two parties was fierce. The windows of a house about 200 meters away from her home were shattered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wuxia Snack Shop sells some local specialty snacks, such as Pauluda, fried bait cubes, etc. It is only about 200 meters away from Wanding Port. Children in the third grade of primary school are afraid that artillery shells will penetrate the iron sheet and will go home when they hear the sound of artillery fire. Wu Xia believes that hiding at home is not necessarily safe. &quot;If there are really shells coming, you can&#39;t hide anywhere.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan, who lives by the boundary river, seems to be at greater risk. She once saw a picture of a helicopter bombing on the other side of the river on a short video platform. The community administrator also kept telling her not to come out of the house. However, She works at Wanding Town Health Center and still needs to report to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that on October 31, she was at work when she was suddenly informed that a large crater had been blown up near her home, and her son, who was in primary school, was staying at home alone. &quot;It was really urgent at the time. I called my husband and ran home. When I got home and opened the door, I saw that my son was taking a nap.&quot; Tao Wan looked at her son sleeping soundly and felt, &quot;My heart is going to be broken.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan told Southern Weekend reporters that when she was a child, the sound of fighting on the other side of the river could be heard in Wanding Town. The most intense year.&quot; The scene of community workers and street broadcasts telling residents to retreat and avoid the fighting made Tao Wan feel panic like never before, &quot;I felt like I had to leave this home.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewees told Southern Weekend reporters that on October 27, the night when the war broke out, community members came to persuade them to leave: “If you have family and friends in Ruili, go to Ruili. &quot;Not only that, the community also informed that if you hear the sound of gunfire, please do not go out, and immediately find shelter to take shelter. Do not wait and see out of curiosity, and avoid exposing your body in open spaces to avoid being hit by stray bullets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 3, an on-duty staff member of the Wanding Town Government told Southern Weekend reporters that the staff in the government building had moved to a relatively safe place to work, leaving only a few on-duty staff, and the new place was still open. Within the Wanding area, it is five or six kilometers away from the town government building. The reason why they moved out of the town government building was because the building was &quot;directly opposite Myanmar and posed a major safety hazard.&quot; The person on duty said he was unclear about how many people were transferred in Wanding Town and when students would resume classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The fourth floor of a residential building in the town was hit by a shell, but fortunately there were no casualties. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/daa5b0ac75.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1050&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/daa5b0ac75.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257283&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Town The fourth floor of a residential building was hit by a shell, but fortunately there were no casualties. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The watermelon business chain is broken&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Residents living in Wanding noticed that this war was different from usual signals. In addition to the fierce gunfire, there were also Students are completely suspended from classes. The milk tea shop where Peng Qi works is only a few hundred meters away from Wanding Middle School. She discovered that on the evening of Friday, October 27, all the high school students who were originally on holiday on Sunday were taken home by their parents. Wu Xia&#39;s snack bar is not far from the middle school. She saw many parents driving to the school gate to pick up their students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Lili, a 21-year-old girl who grew up in Wanding, recalled that there was an emergency in the local area a few years ago when classes were suspended due to the war in Myanmar, but she could not remember the time clearly. She only remembered that it was the same time at that time. There are stray bullets flying into the territory. &quot;The most serious thing in recent years is the two incidents of stray bullets flying over. The situation in Myanmar has always been unstable. Once war starts, Wanding&#39;s geographical location is destined to be affected.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cai In Lily&#39;s impression, there is only a boundary river two or three meters wide, and there are frequent exchanges between Wanding and the Myanmar town of Bangsai on the other side. She recalled that when she was five or six years old, it was easy to travel to Myanmar from the border crossing. When she was in primary school, seven or eight of the more than 40 students in her class were from Myanmar. &quot;We all studied Chinese courses and we all played together.&quot; The boundary river is also one of her recreational areas. She often goes fishing and picnicking by the river with her family and friends. A walking trail is built close to the boundary river, and Wanding residents often go for walks by the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that some Wanding residents were indeed accidentally injured, mostly with skin injuries. &quot;After we debridement, we will ask them to go home quickly, because the hospital is located on a relatively high ground and is not safe. Some people were also transferred to higher-level hospitals by ambulances.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xia discovered that since the beginning of the Northern Myanmar War Later, there were fewer and fewer people on the streets, especially tourists. As a famous border town and border port, there are endless tourists here all year round. Her snack bar is not far from the national gate and has about a hundred customers every day. But after the war broke out, only a few old customers who lived nearby came to the store, and &quot;there was no one on this street.&quot; Not only that, on October 30, the &quot;only go out, no go in&quot; rule was implemented in the central area of ​​Wanding Town. However, according to locals, the rule was only implemented for two days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Qi also obviously felt that the flow of people had dropped sharply. In an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter at 16:00 on November 2, Peng Qi said that the store&#39;s turnover that day was only more than 100 yuan, which is the price of about 10 cups of milk tea, and most of the customers were from nearby shops. Before the war, the store&#39;s daily turnover was about one thousand yuan. There are also brave tourists who go to the border to shoot short videos. Wu Xia said: &quot;Many men and women may also be afraid. They basically just take pictures and leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the men and women Wu Xia saw, Perhaps there is also Zhou Feng, a melon seller. On November 2, 37-year-old Zhou Feng also visited the national gate of Wanding, but his destination was the Wanding Watermelon Wholesale Market. As the largest watermelon market in Southeast Asia, from the end of October to May of the following year is the time when Myanmar watermelons are on the market and exported to China. Zhou Feng revealed that during peak periods, the market could have 1,000 vehicles a day, each carrying 16 tons of watermelons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of October 2023, the price of Myanmar watermelon that has just been launched can reach four or five yuan per kilogram, which is not low. After the war broke out, Wanding&#39;s national gate was closed and watermelon could not enter the territory. Zhou Feng analyzed that the most affected people in the watermelon industry chain are melon farmers. The price of contracted land in Myanmar is relatively low, only three to four hundred yuan per mu, so most of the people who plant watermelons on contracted land in Myanmar are Chinese. Zhou Feng has been engaged in this industry for 13 years. He is grateful that it is the early stage of the watermelon market. &quot;If it takes more than a month to start the war, I will be annoyed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In previous years, at the Wanding Watermelon Wholesale Market, melon stalls were filled with watermelons imported from Myanmar. Oriental IC Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/07/0f278c71c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /07/0f278c71c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257284&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In previous years, the watermelon wholesale market in Wanding was full of melon stalls Watermelons imported from Myanmar. Oriental IC Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Eerily Quiet&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not all Wanding residents were affected by the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 3 communities and 3 administrative villages within the jurisdiction of Wanding Town. 26-year-old Guo Yu lives with his family in Hunban Village, which is about 5 kilometers away from the border port and one or two kilometers away from Myanmar. Guo Yu runs a B&amp;B. Since the war started, there have been no guests staying. Fortunately, the shells did not fall near them, and the family&#39;s food, clothing, housing and transportation were not affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Yu’s mother is from Myanmar, and his father’s ancestral home is in Baoshan City, Yunnan Province. When they were young, they came to Wanding to buy land and build a house, and settled here. Guo Yu told Southern Weekend reporters that his grandmother&#39;s house was not affected by the war and was relatively safe for the time being. Guo Yu also feels safe and has no plans to move away. However, if the shells hit nearby, the family may move to Ruili, 20 kilometers away, and stay with relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan was not prepared to evacuate, but sent her youngest son back to her husband&#39;s hometown in Dehong Prefecture overnight. &quot;We all buy a house and a car on our own. This is my home. If I leave, it won&#39;t even have its roots.&quot; Since October 27, Tao Wan has felt uneasy every day. She is afraid that if an accident occurs, the house will be lost. . &quot;I don&#39;t know what to do in that situation. When I think of this possibility, I almost burst into tears.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan came to Wanding Town with her mother when she was 5 years old. Now she has Is 40 years old. Because she had to take care of her mother who didn&#39;t want to leave Wanding, Tao Wan, who went to college abroad, came back here again, until now. After the war broke out, Tao Wan placed her mother in a village far away from the border. She planned to wait until the war calmed down before taking the old man home. Tao Wan said that there are some elderly people in the town who have inconvenient legs and feet who are unwilling to move. They have deep feelings for Wanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Dai language, Wanding means &quot;the place where the sun is at the top&quot;. Today, the town&#39;s shine is no longer dazzling. In Tao Wan&#39;s impression, Wanding was prosperous 20 to 30 years ago. Later, due to road planning, administrative divisions and other reasons, Wanding was slowly declining. Tao Wan felt aggrieved for the small town where she lived, &quot;There was an epidemic in the past three years, and now there is this war.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Lili never felt that she was a girl who came out of a small town. She felt that Wanding was more like a small city. She remembers that Wanding Town was very lively around 2007, with people coming and going, and the shops on the street would sell Myanmar specialties, such as hot and sour noodles, milk candies, etc. Now, some of the shops that impressed Cai Lili have been closed, and many shops on the street are empty. &quot;After its decline in recent years, I gradually felt that it was really just a small town.&quot; Cai Lili said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, this town is facing another test. On November 6, Peng Qi told Southern Weekend reporters that compared with the chaotic sound of gunfire in the past few days, the streets in Wanding are now &quot;eerily quiet&quot;. Except for the occasional pedestrian passing by, only military green trucks are left on the street. patrol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan has not heard the sound of gunfire recently, but she feels that the government departments and schools have shown no signs of relaxing. The school has not notified the resumption of classes, teaching is conducted in the form of online classes, and the community still counts every day and has not evacuated. resident information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, the characters in the article are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“局外人”到“第一个人”：加缪110周年诞辰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRmVSmK7F8E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1241&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRm VSmK7F8E. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257306&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Albert Camus (November 7, 1913 - 1960 January 4), French writer and philosopher, born in Algeria. He won the Nobel Prize for Literature at the age of 44 and died unexpectedly at the age of 47. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, 1913, Albert Camus was born. On January 4, 1960, he died in an accidental car accident at the age of 46. Today, it has been 110 years since Camus was born and more than sixty years since his death, but people do not feel that Camus belongs to a distant era. He used his short writing career to create a series of distinctive contemporary images. , is still closely related to our living situation today. The embarrassment, discord, and sense of powerlessness of &quot;outsiders&quot;, the repeated hard labor in &quot;Sisyphus&quot;, and the struggle and dignity of people facing disaster in &quot;The Plague&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus is both a writer and a thinker. He does not capture readers with the splendor of his words, but shocks them with his postmodern understanding of life. He is the youngest winner of the Nobel Prize for Literature. one. Camus&#39;s enduring popularity is symptomatic. Just like Kafka, he wrote a &quot;clinical diagnosis&quot; of contemporary people&#39;s mental dilemma; just like Lu Xun, he does not provide bright answers, or even It&#39;s a bit dark and cold, but at the end of the coldness is a philosophy of resistance and hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus once worked as a journalist. On January 1, 1940, he wrote an editorial for the last issue of the &quot;Republican Evening News&quot;. You can get a glimpse of his restraint, coolness, and calmness with a sense of power. Words: &quot;This year, hoping for happiness will be in vain, building it through work is the key. Don&#39;t hope for anything, but do something. Don&#39;t wait for others to build your destiny from beginning to end, especially when destiny It is still in our hands. The Evening Republican will not wish you happiness this year, knowing that you are going through a severe physical and mental trauma. But it will ask you to maintain the necessary strength and sobriety to strive to maintain your own tranquility and dignity. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was the darkest moment of World War II. Shortly after Camus wrote this dedication, while fleeing on the border of France and Spain, Benjamin failed to get a pass and came to the end of his life. At the end, although Zweig fled to Brazil, he still committed suicide in despair. Camus belongs to a new generation of young people. He once joined the French Communist Party, fought and resisted, and condensed the power of his resistance into continuous writing. If the deaths of Benjamin and Zweig marked the spiritual boundaries of yesterday&#39;s world, Camus established the starting point of his writing on the wasteland of war and post-war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The postwar world is neither a wasteland nor a new heaven and a new earth. His arguments with his friend Sartre and his ambivalent attitude toward the Algerian War made Camus increasingly lonely while receiving literary honors. When he returned to autobiographical writing and the &quot;first person&quot;, an accident caused this sharp soul to bid farewell in advance. For a writer like Camus, commemorating him at any time is both our condolences and an invitation for him to return. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;France’s “outsider”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 2 a.m. on November 7, 1913, her mother Catalina gave birth to Camus, who was the first child in the family. second son. The next day, at the Mondovi Municipal Government in Algeria, the father registered the birth of his child. He was 28 years old and worked as a wine cellar manager. The mother was 31 years old and filled in the occupation column as a housewife. The birthplace of Saint-Paul Farm is located 8 kilometers south of the city of Mondovi. The nearby city of Bonny is the most important port in French Algeria, not far from the Tunisian border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Algeria became a French colony in the 19th century, most of the immigrants who immigrated here were poor people from all over France, as well as Spain, Italy and other European countries. New immigrants were granted residence rights under French protection and lived among the overwhelming majority of locals. “The French in Algeria are of mixed race. Spaniards, Alsatians, Italians, Maltese, Jews, Greeks gather there,” Camus later wrote. Camus is a mixed-race child, his mother is Spanish, and he believes that his father comes from Alsace, the battlefield where France and Germany have fought for generations. The reason for &quot;thinking&quot; is that my father&#39;s exact ancestral home has been lost and difficult to find. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus had never met his father before he could remember. My father is 1.8 meters tall, with brown hair and blue eyes. He works in a wine company, supervising the grape pressing, winemaking, storage, and shipment to the Port of Pawnee for shipment. Not long after Camus was born, World War I broke out, and his father was conscripted into the French army. Almost as soon as he entered the battlefield, he was injured in the Battle of the Marne to prevent the German army from advancing towards Paris. He was hit by shell fragments and was sent to a rear hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, 1914, my mother received the bad news by telegram, as well as a small piece of shrapnel removed from her husband&#39;s head that the widow had asked to keep. His father was mysterious to Camus. He often asked his mother: &quot;Am I really like my father?&quot; &quot;Oh, you look exactly like your father.&quot; During the four years of World War I, his mother received no After passing a penny in France, it was only a few months before the end of the war that I received official notification of her husband&#39;s death and a pension check. An accountant next door helped her fill out the pension application form because no one in her family knew how to fill it out. In order to make a living, my mother sorted warheads in an ammunition manufacturing factory until she suffered from rheumatism and was unable to continue this work, so she began to work as a domestic helper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 8 months to 17 years old, Camus lived with his mother and grandmother under the same roof in Algiers, the capital of Algeria. It was Belku, the workers&#39; district of the city, home to people who worked hard in small workshops and port equipment factories, craftsmen, small traders, grassroots civil servants and clerks. As an adult, Camus returned to the house frequently, sometimes to visit the elderly and sometimes as a temporary haven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was in middle school, football fascinated Camus. He was very brave and liked to tackle from the feet of his opponents, so he was often injured. Camus described a fierce football match, on a pitch adjacent to a cemetery, in which the opposing players pressed forward mercilessly. They “were all on top of me, spikes on my shins, knees on my crotch, squeezing me against the goal post…” “I quickly learned that the ball doesn’t come from where you expect it to. This was very helpful in my life, especially in France, where not everyone is honest,&quot; Camus later wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Camus came to settle in Paris in early 1940, he felt that &quot;I am not from here, nor from anywhere else. The world is just a strange scenery, and my spirit is helpless here. Everything It has nothing to do with yourself.&quot; He was stuck between France and Algeria, between Paris and impoverished Bercoux across the Mediterranean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;969&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257305&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Camus (first from right) is backstage with two actors during the performance of his drama &quot;Martial Law&quot; in Paris in 1948. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Sisyphus&quot;: The victorious loser&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;While Sartre, who came from a middle-class background, was dreaming of a literary hero, and Beauvoir was enjoying her books and the gifts in the candy shop window, Camus was in a home without electricity, running water, newspapers and books, and no Growing up in the world of radio, he once wrote in his diary: &quot;Living in poverty for a few years is enough to create all the sensitivity.&quot; Tuberculosis plagued Camus throughout his life, but it also exempted him from military service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1942, &quot;The Outsider&quot; and &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; were published one after another. The former tells the story of a French-Algerian named Meursault who experienced two deaths. The first was his mother&#39;s death. He couldn&#39;t even remember the date and didn&#39;t shed tears. The second was when he had an affair with a holdover on the beach. There was a conflict with the Arab about the knife. Meursault happened to be holding a friend&#39;s gun. When his eyes were dazzled by the reflection of the sea and the blade, he almost subconsciously shot the man. After being arrested, Meursault told the judge in confusion that the reason he shot was the sun. Meursault did not defend himself, and the court also lacked interest in the murder case and focused on investigating his personal life. Indifference became the biggest evidence of crime and was sentenced to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title of the essay collection &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; is taken from a story in &quot;Homer&#39;s Epic&quot;. King Sisyphus disobeyed God and was sentenced to push a huge boulder up a mountain for eternity, each time the boulder approached the top of the mountain. When the time comes, it will slip from his hand and roll down again, and he can only go back again, starting over and over again. Camus used the myth of Sisyphus, just like Freud through the Oedipus complex, to make the mythical figure deeply rooted in people&#39;s hearts again. The most famous sentence in &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; may be: &quot;There is only one philosophical question that is truly serious, and that is suicide. To judge whether life is worth living or not...&quot; Camus said in the preface of an English translation many years later , wrote this book because &quot;even within the borders of nihilism, it is possible to find ways to move beyond nihilism.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The play Caligula, published in 1944, discusses freedom and meaninglessness pushed to the extreme by recreating the story of the assassinated Roman Emperor Suetonius. These three books are collectively called Camus&#39; &quot;Trilogy of the Absurd.&quot; They were written and published in the critical state of war and occupied Paris, where everything was compromised and everything was lost. From Kierkegaard&#39;s existential philosophy, Camus saw Abraham, who sacrificed his son, as &quot;infinitely He gave up everything, and then took it all back with the help of absurd power.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus took the initiative to get to know him during the rehearsal of Sartre&#39;s play &quot;The Fly&quot;, and the two hit it off. Previously, Sartre had written an article for Camus&#39;s novel &quot;The Stranger&quot;, and Camus had commented on it. The special &quot;Disgusting&quot;. Beauvoir and Sartre found that Camus was a simple, happy man who was always funny and vulgar in his conversations, very emotional, and would even sit on a snowy street at two in the morning and talk about his love troubles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don Juan went from one woman to another not because of a lack of love, but because he loved them with equal passion and devoted himself to them every time. He must repeat this talent and harmony. Explore... Why do you have to love less to love well?&quot; &quot;The Myth of Sisyphus&quot; reads. Camus had two marriages. His first wife, Simone, was unable to quit morphine, which caused him great psychological trauma. After remarrying Francine, Camus maintained semi-public intimate relationships with many women. , including theater actress Maria Casares, who exchanged more than 800 love letters. It is as if Don Juan became an incarnation of Sisyphus pushing the boulder. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The Plague&quot;: End and Resistance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the end of World War II and the liberation of Paris, the reputations of Sartre, Beauvoir and Camus were at their peak, and the Left Bank The Flower Goddess and the Double Sole Cafe in Shanghai have shrouded the halo of existentialist writers, and the radius of the halo extends to the United States on the other side of the ocean. All three of them received invitations to visit from New York. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From March to May 1946, Camus traveled around the United States. He was more nervous than Sartre and felt that he was always affected by endless little troubles.他也是一个细致的观察者，发现美国人喜欢在早晨喝果汁，全国都爱喝苏格兰威士忌和苏打水，热衷于动物，从布朗克斯动物园的大猩猩，到自然历史博物馆的动物标本，都爱，死亡和死者能以最快的速度被打扮好，“死吧，把剩下的事交给我们”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唯一让加缪感到熟悉和安心的地方，是纽约的包厘街道，当时，这里还是一个废弃的地区，到处是廉价酒吧和破败的酒店，高架铁路从二楼的高度经过，阴影盖住了下面的一切。加缪对美国感到厌恶，觉得这里缺少痛苦和悲剧，但在许多评论家看来，《局外人》正是模仿了美国的黑色小说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1947年，长篇小说《鼠疫》出版，深受读者欢迎，两年内重印了八次。之后，《鼠疫》和《局外人》在法国的文学畅销书榜单上，长期名列前茅。 1941年到1942年间，阿尔及利亚流行瘟疫，是加缪酝酿《鼠疫》的起点，而这部小说之所以如此惊心动魄，是因为瘟疫既被描写得真实可怖，又具有象征性，它影射的是二战期间，德国纳粹肆虐逞凶的严酷现实。纳粹和法西斯主义，也是一种政治和精神的瘟疫，它的军事强权、特务系统、专制和种族主义，像死神一样席卷一切，而遭受它摆布后，或屈服，或配合，或知其不可而为之地反抗的人，也像鼠疫中的众生百态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“加缪特别突出了三种生活象征性的境况，一是分离的境况，包括亲属的分离、夫妻的分离、情人的分离，这些意味着隔离、封锁、囚禁、流亡、集中营……二是小说中没有任何一个女性的境况，这意味着失衡、畸形、苦涩、没有生机……最恐怖的氛围与境况还是死亡……”《鼠疫》中文版的译者柳鸣九说，“&#39;人人身上都潜伏着鼠疫，因为，没有人，是的，世界上没有人能免受其害&#39;……这样，加缪在《鼠疫》中也就把他关于荒诞世界的哲理大大拓宽了一步，加深了一步，并将荒诞的根由指向人类的过失和人类社会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二战的绝境中，不只是加缪选择通过瘟疫的背景来书写一种临界状态，德国剧作家布莱希特也创作了《伽利略传》，剧中的伽利略同样经历了瘟疫的九死一生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我试图通过鼠疫来表现我们所遭受的窒息以及我们所承受的威胁着人、将人流放的环境。”加缪说。在末日的阿赫兰城，小说的主人公贝尔纳·里厄医生，因为恪尽职守，成了一位平凡的英雄。加缪通过反英雄的形式重塑英雄，当灾厄降临，我们能期待的，不是一个从天而降的英雄，而是每一个普通人通过最微小的努力去反抗恶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1951年出版的随笔集《反抗者》，更是加缪继荒诞哲学之后，旗帜鲜明地提出反抗哲学，“何谓反抗者？一个说&#39;不&#39;的人。然而，他虽然拒绝，却并不放弃：他也是从一开始行动就说&#39;是&#39;的人。”然而，这本信息量巨大的书，却令他陷入四面楚歌的境地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;回到“第一个人”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《反抗者》涉及对超现实主义的评论，立刻遭到该团体从文学上的批驳。更激烈的批评来自左派思想家，由于不同意加缪对革命和苏联历史的许多看法，萨特主编的《现代》杂志发表了该刊编辑法朗西斯·尚松措辞激烈的批判文章。加缪不得不做出回应，写了一封给萨特的公开信，进行自我辩护。这又引来了萨特的《答加缪书》，极其严厉、刻薄，称加缪“是个资产者”“抛弃了历史”，《反抗者》的出版是一场反革命的“热月政变”。两人多年的友谊毁于一旦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与许多仅仅以“纯文学”来界定写作的作家不同，加缪一直是一位有机知识分子，正是《反抗者》强烈的“政治性”捅了马蜂窝。萨特与加缪这对存在主义作家的决裂，与后来法国电影新浪潮双子星戈达尔和特吕弗的割席，都成了战后文化史上轰动一时又耐人寻味的事件。萨特站在更激进的位置，连对待诺奖，他也更激进，直接拒绝。令人唏嘘的是，加缪这样一位一直属于进步阵营的作家，因为在某些议题上更温和，或者不追随某一原则、教条，提出了个人的理解和判断，就被斥为保守。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1949年，加缪曾创作了一部戏剧《正义者》，剧中一群“恐怖分子”争论在进行政治暗杀时，是否可以殃及无辜。加缪明确表示，这是错的。 1954年，阿尔及利亚爆发独立斗争时，他也认为起义军埋设炸弹、杀死无辜者，与法国政府的暴力、极刑，同样不正当。这个观点让他饱受争议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1957年，在庆祝加缪获得诺贝尔文学奖的讲话中，有人要求加缪解释他不支持反抗殖民主义的阿尔及利亚起义军的原因，他说：“现在人们正往阿尔及利亚的电车轨道上放炸弹。我母亲可能就在其中一条车轨上。如果这就是正义的话，那么我宁愿选择我的母亲。”加缪呼吁在阿尔及利亚建立一个阿拉伯人、柏柏尔人、黑脚法国人（欧洲移民）平等执政的联合政府，这让所有人都讨厌他。法国民族主义者觉得他同情阿尔及利亚人，阿尔及利亚人觉得他代表法国白人，但他的父亲却在29岁无谓牺牲，她的母亲是一个赤贫的文盲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1960年1月4日，出版商米歇尔·伽里玛开车，阿尔贝·加缪坐在后座，汽车撞向一棵树后，翻滚着撞到了另一棵树上，加缪从后窗中被甩了出去。在不远处的泥浆里，人们找到一个公文包，里面有加缪的日记和一部未完成的长篇小说书稿《第一个人》，这部书以阿尔及利亚的童年生活为原型，并想象他的父亲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加缪辞世后，萨特虽然没有原谅他，但在《法兰西观察家》上写了一篇充满溢美之词的讣告：“他是20世纪反历史潮流的伦理主义流派继承人，他的作品或许是所有法国文人中最具原创性的。他那倔强的、狭隘的、单纯的、朴素的人道主义情怀向我们时代里那些广泛而丑恶的秩序发起了未必明智的挑战。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从电话里得到加缪的死讯后，波伏娃吃下已经停用很久的安眠药，但还是无法入睡，于是下了床，冒着巴黎一月刺骨的细雨，在街头徘徊。第二天清晨，她依然神情恍惚：“他看不见今天的早晨了。”但事实上，加缪非但没有离开人世，反而因车祸带来的强烈冲击，成了世人瞩目的中心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《加缪笔记》的最后几页里，有这样几句话：“在给予你的短暂的白天，取暖吧，照亮吧，不要偏离了你的跑道。……其他几百万个太阳前来陪伴你休息。……在快乐的石板下，第一次入眠。……由风来播种，由风来收获，但创造者是人，穿越时代，以刹那的生命为傲。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（参考资料：赫伯特·洛特曼《加缪传》，莎拉·贝克韦尔《存在主义咖啡馆》，柳鸣九编《加缪全集》，郭宏安译《加缪笔记：1935—1959（精选集）》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[再访“山地之王”：高仙芝的西域足迹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260116]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;回历133年（&lt;em>;大唐天宝十载，公元&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;751年&lt;/em>;），朝圣月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朝圣月是回历的12月。这一年的朝圣月正值盛夏，在中亚草原的边缘，一支黑旗大军在塔拉斯河（Talas River）右岸向着圣地的方向跪拜祈祷完成晨礼，然后迎着朝阳布好了阵势：最前方是配备大食骏马的轻骑兵，他们手持大马士革弯刀，徒步站立以恤马力；然后是由呼罗珊人和吐火罗人为主组成的步兵集群，再往后是弓箭手和长矛手；两翼是来自河中诸国的粟特（Sogdian）骑兵，他们虽然斗志昂扬，但毕竟归化未久，又是异教徒，战斗力尚且存疑，因此被用来保护伊斯兰军队的侧翼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在黑旗大军的对面，是来自东方神秘丝绸国度的敌军。他们人数少得多，因此把步兵摆在前面组成防御阵形。这些步兵统一手持东方式的长柄陌刀，两面开刃，在朝阳下反射出刺眼的光芒，那巨大的精钢刀头极为锋利，不亚于大食人的百战弯刀，凭借其重量能够将奔马劈为两半，和长矛手一样足以承受骑兵的冲击。这些步兵也配有马匹用于行军，但这些驮马此刻已经散牧于敌军侧后方的塔拉斯河边。步兵后面是配备强弩的弓弩手，两翼则是来自北方草原的葛逻禄（Qarluks）突厥骑兵。在这些步骑主力的后面是他们的指挥官，分为主将、副将和别将，还有来自拔汗那的附庸军作为预备队——听说就是那些家伙挑起了这场战争。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黑旗军队的统帅并波悉林（Abu Muslim，&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现译阿布·穆斯林&lt;/span>;）是黑衣大食&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（现译阿巴斯王朝）&lt;/span>;首屈一指的开国元勋，也是半路出家的军事天才。他出身为波斯裔奴隶，长期在大食帝国底层传教，六年前才回到故土波斯，起兵反抗白衣大食&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（现译倭马亚王朝）&lt;/span>;。去年冬天，他率军挺进美索不达米亚，在扎卜河战役中以少胜多，先用长矛手阵列顶住对方骑兵的多轮冲击，再发动骑兵冲锋将丧失斗志的敌军步兵逼进了漂着浮冰的河水中，击溃了至少三倍于己的敌人，给享国九十年的白衣大食捶下了最后一颗棺钉，在巴格达建立起了延祚五百余年的黑衣大食。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年他再次从波斯出发，远征中亚，迎战同样远道而来的中国军队，对方的指挥官听说是一个名叫高仙芝的美男子。不过，这场战役的缘起，还得从整整一百年前的波斯说起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257248&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦的塔拉斯河谷，怛罗斯战役发生地点已不可考，但战役发生在河谷口，地势会比较平坦。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“西方的野蛮人”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大唐永徽二年（&lt;em>;公元&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;651年&lt;/em>;），年轻的“天可汗”李治在长安接见波斯萨珊帝国末代皇帝伊嗣俟派来的求救使臣。使臣说有一伙来自西方的野蛮人正在攻打波斯：他们要求我们在三种情况中选择一种：要么接受他们的信仰，要么交纳人头税，要么就开战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;使臣并不知道，在他恳求唐高宗出兵援救波斯的时候， 伊嗣俟已经死在了逃亡途中。幸免于难的王子卑路斯&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（波斯语意为“胜利者”）&lt;/span>;屡战屡败，最后也逃到了中国，并终老于此，葬于东都洛阳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;攻灭萨珊王朝的“野蛮人”被波斯人称为“大食”（Tachik），其实就是阿拉伯人。 “大食”这个名字来自阿拉伯东部的塔伊部落（Tayyi），被波斯人当成了阿拉伯穆斯林的统称，讹传到唐朝后又因为他们使用白色旗帜，故而中国史书称之为“白衣大食”。波斯人皈依伊斯兰教后又被突厥人称为Tachik，这很可能就是今天同样讲波斯语的塔吉克人（Tajik）名称的由来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即位不满三年的李治对于救援远在天边的波斯并无兴趣。当时大唐尚未完全平定南疆，有限的军事资源必须用于控制葱岭以东的安西四镇，对于葱岭以西还鞭长莫及。而大食攻取波斯后也因国内的争位之战而中止了在东方的扩张势头，直到六十年后方派名将屈底波（Qutaybah ibn Muslim）向东攻取河中地区（Transoxiana）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“河中”地区，顾名思义，乃是中亚两条大河阿姆河&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（古称乌浒水）&lt;/span>;与锡尔河（古称药杀水）之间的平原地区，它北接中亚草原，东南方是天山和兴都库什山两座悠长而高峻的雄伟山脉，西南方则是波斯高原。沿着两条大河走出葱岭的商旅在这里汇集，货物在这里转手，继续经波斯高原前往两河流域和小亚细亚，因此河中地区自古是丝绸之路的重要枢纽。汉代月氏人在匈奴、乌孙的攻击下从蒙古高原一路播迁至此，与当地人融合后形成粟特人，在干旱的河中地区建立了康、史、安、石等多个绿洲国家，中国史书称其为昭武九姓。由于粟特人扼商道而居，成为中世纪融通东西方贸易的杰出商业民族，大批行商坐贾迁居中原——唐三彩驼马上的胡人形象便是粟特人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;唐三彩骆驼载乐俑的粟特人形象&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大唐先天元年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元712年）&lt;/span>;，屈底波从波斯东北部的呼罗珊进军河中，先后攻取萨末鞬&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今译撒马尔罕）&lt;/span>;、石国&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今塔什干）&lt;/span>;、拔汗那&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今译费尔干纳）&lt;/span>;等国。那时唐玄宗李隆基刚刚登基，处心积虑谋划着如何推翻干政的姑妈太平公主一党，对于葱岭以西发生的杀伐就像他的祖父李治一样无动于衷。两年后，军事上势如破竹的屈底波在内乱中意外被杀，白衣大食军队来得急撤得也快。觊觎此地已久的吐蕃趁虚而入，在拔汗那拥立新国王阿了达，此举立刻引起了大唐的高度警惕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这又是为什么呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乌兹别克斯坦撒马尔罕&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中亚地缘政治&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“拔汗那（Bahanna）”乃是古称，如今叫“费尔干纳（Ferg&#39;ona）”，其辅音“g”还是俄国殖民者给加上的，我听当地人其实念作Fer&#39;ana，发音接近于“福阿纳”。它乃是西天山末端的一块盆地，汉代称为大宛，著名的汗血宝马就出产于此。苏联时代，俄罗斯人为了分裂突厥诸部以便分而治之，强行在中亚细分出五个民族，构建了犬牙交错的五个“斯坦国”，尤其是在小小的费尔干纳盆地，竟将其分割给了乌兹别克斯坦、吉尔吉斯斯坦和塔吉克斯坦三个加盟共和国，而且划出了大量飞地甚至是飞地中的飞地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257244&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;费尔干纳盆地地图，飞地套飞地，犬牙交错可见一斑。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唐代的拔汗那尚无这些纠纷，乃是单一民族的粟特国家，它位于唐朝西域重镇碎叶与河中诸国之间，是由安西大都护府经葱岭前往河中地区的要冲。更为要紧的是，大唐可以接受大食控制拔汗那，却无法坐视吐蕃由此进入中亚草原——这就涉及到当时中亚地区四个大国间的地缘政治。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拔汗那为大国所环绕，北有突厥，南有吐蕃，西有大食，东有大唐。突厥人是传统的草原征服者，以其强大战力向河中诸国收取保护费；白衣大食是政教合一的新兴帝国，但它在扩张初期既不是为了战争也不是为了敛财，而是为了“给各部族的好战精神找出路”——突厥与大食是新旧征服者之间的零和博弈，无法调和；吐蕃兴起于青藏苦寒之地，素以富庶的中原为目标，但苦于打不开大唐牢牢扎紧的藩篱，因此绕道葱岭，希望与北方的突厥人联手瓜分大唐西域，再沿河西走廊进入中原腹地；而大唐作为四个大国中唯一一个由农耕民族建立的政权，开拓西域的首要目标是以攻为守，保卫自己的领土：由关中经陇西、河西而至安西，最终抵达塔里木盆地的西部边界葱岭，守住高耸入云的葱岭就可以挡住外部势力进入中原。因此，唐朝的诉求并非掠土殖民&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（大食）&lt;/span>;、压榨土人&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（突厥）&lt;/span>;、开辟通道&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（吐蕃）&lt;/span>;抑或保护商路——商路只是唐朝扩张过程中的副产品而非目的——而是简简单单的据险自守，隔断南北通道以阻止强敌结盟来对付自己。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这么一来，吐蕃与突厥一南一北谋求联手进攻共同的敌人大唐，而大唐与大食一东一西各自占据葱岭两侧，井水不犯河水。一旦吐蕃越过了这条东西向的均衡线，有望进入北方草原与突厥人合流，大唐的“红色警报”就被触发了。大唐开元三年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元715年）&lt;/span>;，也就是屈底波被杀、大食军撤走、吐蕃军进占拔汗那的那一年，正在安西都护府巡察的监察御史张孝嵩当机立断，越俎代庖地征发并指挥仆从国附庸军长驱直入数千里，翻越葱岭抵达拔汗那盆地，大败吐蕃重兵，于汉武帝攻略大宛的八百年后再次占领此地，封住了吐蕃进入中亚草原的葱岭西道出口。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后吐蕃又谋求取道勃律打通葱岭东道，同样被时任北庭节度使的张孝嵩所挫败：开元十年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元722年）&lt;/span>;，张孝嵩派四千步骑援救小勃律，大破吐蕃军，此事已在上一篇《探访“山地之王”：高仙芝的高原足迹》中提及，故不再赘述。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;远征葱岭西道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大唐天宝八载&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元749年）&lt;/span>;，高仙芝收复小勃律后两年，又在播仙&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今新疆且末）&lt;/span>;大破吐蕃。在东线撞得头破血流的吐蕃军不得不调头前往西线的葱岭西道寻找唐朝西域防御体系的弱点。接到情报的高仙芝完全可以前往拔汗那，在那里以逸待劳等待劳师远征的吐蕃军前来并给予迎头痛击，但毕生追求战场主动权的高仙芝并没有那么做：既然葱岭西道尚可走通，那我就彻底切断它！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257245&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;巴基斯坦奇特拉尔街景，古代的朅师国所在地。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天宝九载&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元750年）&lt;/span>;，高仙芝第二次出兵葱岭，再次来到小勃律，由此沿娑夷河&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今吉尔吉特河）&lt;/span>;逆流而上，翻越山杜尔山口，前往兴都库什山脉中部东麓的朅师国&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今巴基斯坦奇特拉尔）&lt;/span>;。有历史学家考证朅师国是亚历山大大帝东征的终点，附近Kalasha幽谷中繁衍至今的古老部落据说就是希腊远征军的后裔。从小勃律到朅师超过七百里路程，如今走公路需要两个整天，第一天路况甚好，还有长途车可以坐，第二天就只能与乡人搭乘当地四轮驱动方可成行，沿着马斯图杰河谷（Mastuj Valley）一路向西，北面是兴都库什山脉（Hindu Kush）的连绵雪山，南面则是兴都拉吉山脉（Hindu Raj）高达6542米的雪峰Buni Zom。脚下马斯图杰河深深切入致密的黄土，形成T字形的高耸台地，令人想起嘉峪关外的讨赖河谷——高仙芝麾下将士由中原经河西而至西域途中，一定在讨赖河边饮过马吧，相信他们也发现了两地的神似。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257247&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;嘉峪关外的讨赖河谷&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《两唐书》没有记载高仙芝远征朅师走了多久，《资治通鉴》也仅提到唐军系冬季行军。根据我对朅师沿途地形的估测，古代军队带着辎重至少需要走半个月。而吐蕃军就更艰苦了：由于唐军三年前就控制了小勃律和娑夷河谷，吐蕃军不得不从南面的崇山峻岭中绕行，一个月能不能走到朅师都是问题。朅师国是吐蕃的盟友，位于葱岭西道的中点，过了朅师就可以翻越兴都库什山脉，再沿着喷赤河穿越葱岭西部和西天山的阿赖山脉，最终抵达拔汗那盆地——那又是一个多月的行程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于高仙芝奇袭朅师，截断了葱岭西道，远道而来极为疲惫的吐蕃将士就不用再翻越兴都拉吉、兴都库什、葱岭和西天山这四座伟岸的山脉，更不用在酷热的拔汗那艰难攻打唐军与粟特人联合把守的要塞，可以全须全尾地回到凉爽的青藏高原——这难道不是大唐高将军带来的和平红利吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，在失去朅师这个重要的中继点之后，吐蕃彻底打消了打通葱岭东、西两道的念头，从此将兵力集中于东线，但仍于天宝十二载、十三载被高仙芝的继任者封常清在东线的两条通道分别击破，以至于吐蕃军在此后的十年时间里都无法对大唐西域形成重大威胁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝陆续平定了东西两线的吐蕃攻势，将大唐的军事控制线由葱岭东部外推到了葱岭西部，达成了稳定西域、拱卫中原的战略目的，可以说达到了个人军事成就的巅峰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而就在此时，他收到了拔汗那的求援书，请求他在班师前顺道讨伐石国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257249&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;费尔干纳盆地的传统茶馆&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“诸胡皆怒”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;拔汗那先被白衣大食灭国，又被吐蕃扶植傀儡政权，最后依靠大唐援军方得以复国，因此是中亚地区对大唐最为忠诚的属国，可以比拟为高丽之于大明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么拔汗那为什么要吁请唐军攻打石国呢？此事缺乏明确的史料记载，一般认为可能有三方面的原因，一是拔汗那与石国有隙，拔汗那位于药杀水上游的盆地中，而石国位于药杀水流出盆地的下游方向，其首都拓折城就是今天的乌兹别克斯坦首都塔什干（Toshkent），“拓折”就是“塔什/Tosh”，乃是突厥语“石头”的意思。两国同为粟特国家，石国扼拔汗那通往中亚草原的出口，而拔汗那则扼石国的水源，两国或有积怨；二是拔汗那向大唐输诚，趁河中之地陷入权力真空之机予以控制；三是石国位于河中地区与中亚草原接壤的前沿，与突厥的主要部落突骑施的继承者黄姓突骑施交好，而突骑施长期是大唐的威胁，踩到了大唐的红线。总之高仙芝采纳了拔汗那的建议，引军北上进入费尔干纳盆地，再沿着药杀水抵达石国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石国属于河中地区的昭武九姓诸国，是大唐的羁縻之地，它们奉唐朝为宗主国，向大唐定期朝贡，但没有行政、财政和军事上的实际管控关系。高仙芝讨伐石国的名义是“无藩臣礼”，但史书上没有列举具体罪状。弱小的石国提出讲和，高仙芝假意应允，却囚禁了亲自前来和谈的石国国王那俱车鼻施——他曾在小勃律之战中使用过相似的计谋，以财货诱捕亲吐蕃的小勃律贵族出城后实施抓捕斩首——然后兵不血刃地占领了拓折城。破城后，高仙芝纵兵大肆杀戮，还掠夺了石国的大量珍宝，光其本人就获得“瑟瑟十馀斛、黄金五六橐驼、良马宝玉甚众，家赀累钜万”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里所说的“瑟瑟”乃是中世纪最为昂贵的矿石之一：青金石。它原产于乌浒水上游的巴达赫尚地区&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今阿富汗东北部）&lt;/span>;，经河中地区转口贩运至世界各地，既是珍贵的宝石、治病的“神药”，也是稀有的蓝、紫色颜料。 2022年跨年舞蹈《只此青绿》而爆火的青绿色调，其缘起就是宋徽宗以宫廷御藏的珍贵青金石供青年画家王希孟绘制的传世珍品《千里江山图》，而白居易的千古名句“半江瑟瑟半江红”，诵咏的也是江水在夕阳照射下泛出的青金石色彩。高仙芝从石国劫掠了大量青金石，想必是其府库历年蓄积的珍品，尤列于黄金之前，其价值可想而知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257251&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;北京故宫珍宝馆的青金石雕松泉人物图山子（清&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝将此次远征所俘虏的石国国王、朅师国王、吐蕃酋长以及很可能是在石国一并捕获的黄姓突骑施可汗&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（或可解释高仙芝为何屠戮拓折城以惩罚石国的通敌行为）&lt;/span>;一股脑儿送回长安献俘阙下，战功可谓煊赫。但他的背信之举和残酷屠杀激起了除拔汗那之外河中诸国的公愤，据《资治通鉴》记载，“石国王子逃诣诸胡，具告仙芝欺诱贪暴之状。诸胡皆怒，潜引大食欲共攻四镇”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而根据大食史料记载，战争的起因是拔汗那与石国敌对，向大唐求援；唐军包围石国，石国国王投降，并未受到迫害；大食得知此事后出兵与大唐交战——这一叙述前后缺乏逻辑，难以解释大食出兵的原因。据我看来，那一年大食刚好完成改朝换代，黑衣大食取代了白衣大食，正需要一场对外战争的胜利来弥合内部的分裂。统帅并波悉林则刚刚镇压了安国&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今乌兹别克斯坦布哈拉）&lt;/span>;的叛乱，得以腾出手来以安国为基地出兵侵占他的前辈屈底波曾经征服过的河中地区。如今河中诸国主动前来归顺，正中其下怀。并波悉林遂照单全收吞并了河中之地，然后率领士气正旺的大食雄师与河中诸国的附庸军沿着中亚草原向东进发，兵锋直指大唐在西域的前哨碎叶城。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而高仙芝得知河中巨变，第三次统率安西四镇的主力部队以及葛逻禄和拔汗那的附庸军越过葱岭，前往河中平叛，两支大军遂在拓折城与碎叶城之间的怛逻斯遭遇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257250&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;怛罗斯之战地图，宁远即为拔汗那。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“中亚的关原之战”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“怛逻斯”是石国东部城池的名字，得名于塔拉斯河，后者是西天山余脉中的一条山间河流，水量虽然不大但源远流长，长达一千多里。塔拉斯河的下游沿着河谷向西北方向流淌，最后进入草原地带。如今河谷内的山地属于吉尔吉斯斯坦，河谷以外的平原地带则属于哈萨克斯坦。河谷里有一座吉尔吉斯小镇叫做塔拉斯（Talas），河谷外的草原上则有一座哈萨克大城叫做塔拉兹（Taraz）。苏联时代于1975年在塔拉斯河谷山口修建了一座基洛夫水库，拦住了本就不多的河水——水库深度仅7米，用于河谷内的农业灌溉，因此塔拉斯河进入哈萨克斯坦国境后只剩下涓涓细流，形成一片饥渴的绿洲，最后断流于沙漠之中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;670&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257253&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;建于苏联时代的基洛夫水库&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鉴于年代久远，如今已经无法确认唐代的怛逻斯城究竟是今天的塔拉斯镇还是塔拉兹城，抑或位于两者之间的某一点。由于地处吉尔吉斯斯坦和哈萨克斯坦边境地带，作为外国人的我无法抵近塔拉斯河谷出口——怛逻斯之战最有可能发生的地方——开展考察，也无法放飞无人机从空中俯瞰这条河谷。但可以肯定的是，兵力较少的大唐联军占据了地势略高的河谷内侧，用山峦和河流保护自己的侧翼；兵力占优的大食联军则从草原一侧向河谷进攻，双方在塔拉斯河北岸摆开了战场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257252&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;塔拉斯河&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于双方的兵力对比，史家众说纷纭，目前一般认为大唐联军兵力为2—3万人，鉴于整个安西大都护府的兵力不超过三万人，还要守备偌大的南疆，不可能悉数调往前线，我倾向于《资治通鉴》的记载，高仙芝此次远征的总兵力约三万人，估计其中一半为唐军，以步兵为主，其余系葛逻禄和拔汗那的附庸军，其中葛逻禄军为骑兵，拔汗那军也以步兵为主。或有一种说法是唐军兵力高达六、七万人，这就意味着其中绝大部分是附庸军，并不符合当时大唐在河中地区众叛亲离，仅有拔汗那追随的实际情况，而葛逻禄作为初兴的突厥部落也无法提供这么多兵力。大食方面史料更加缺乏，一般认为有7—10万人，也有认为高达20至30万人的，我认为以当时的后勤保障条件，无法支撑如此巨大的兵力在草原上远征，所以姑且认为这场战争是7万大食联军与3万大唐联军在塔拉斯河边展开的一场野战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;史载这场战役打了五天，前四天大食军队主攻，但未能突破唐军构成的严密防御阵形，可到了第五天，战场形势发生了戏剧性的逆转。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有日本学者把这场战役比喻为“中亚的关原之战”——关原之战是日本安土桃山时代投入兵力规模最大的一场战役，西军主力以寡敌众，即将赢得战场主动之际，原本按兵不动驻扎在侧翼山顶的友军小早川秀秋部突然倒戈，切入了正与东军激战的西军主力后方，对其形成夹击之势，西军遂土崩瓦解。这一类比虽然不尽确切，但确与怛逻斯之战的逆转颇有相似：唐军精锐的陌刀队挡住了大食军的多轮攻击，原本有望复刻对方主帅并波悉林去年在扎卜河战役中的成功范例，用骑兵反冲锋压垮敌军斗志。只可惜大唐联军的骑兵部队是葛逻禄附庸军，在这个唐军即将赢得战场主动的关键时刻，与大食早有默契的葛逻禄人反戈一击，反而切入了正与大食军激战的唐军后方，对其形成夹击之势，唐军主力遂陷入重围苦战之中，伤亡殆尽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;主将高仙芝不甘心就此失败，还指望用预备队稳住阵脚，收拢前线败兵后再与敌军一决雌雄。他的副将、曾在连云堡战斗中立下奇功的猛将李嗣业在危急关头劝他撤退：将军孤军深入，没有援军，而周围胡人诸国都是追随胜者的墙头草，一定会对我们群起围攻。一旦我们全军覆没，还有谁回去守卫南疆呢？我虽然是个莽汉，也看得清形势危急，将军可不能再拘泥固执了！ &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（《旧唐书·李嗣业列传》：愚者千虑，或有一得，势危若此，不可胶柱）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是，李嗣业拽着高仙芝放弃了被包围的唐军主力，沿塔拉斯河谷向东撤退。地势渐高，山道渐窄，作为预备队最先调头撤退的拔汗那附庸军把道路堵得严严实实，后面的唐军无法通过，眼看就要被大食追兵赶上。这时李嗣业放下陌刀，抡起大棒向拔汗那友军左右开弓，“人马应手俱毙”，拔汗那军纷纷向左右避让，高仙芝得以逃出生天；而唐军的第三把手、别将段秀实挺身而出，责备上司李嗣业为了自己逃命而杀害友军，“惮敌而奔，非勇也；免己陷众，非仁也”，李嗣业这才羞惭地停止杀戮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是唐军在怛逻斯大败后的惨状。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257254&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦塔拉斯省的入口拱门&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;尾声&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;怛逻斯战役结束后，两军各自回国，大唐与大食仍以葱岭为界，战略均衡并未发生根本改变。之后的五年里，黑衣大食向大唐先后派出了八批使臣，表明双方仍然维持着密切的外交关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;葛逻禄：临阵倒戈的突厥部族，在怛逻斯之战后与吐蕃结盟，继承了突骑施的角色，成为草原上新一代的突厥征服者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拔汗那，葱岭一隅的西域属国，在怛逻斯惨败和杀戮后依然效忠大唐，“事唐最谨”。 “安史之乱”爆发后，拔汗那响应唐肃宗邀请，不远万里发兵援助中原。时至今日，费尔干纳仍是世界丝绸重镇，生丝出产量列全球第三，这便是唐代丝路花雨对这个酷热盆地的千年遗泽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;河中诸国，大国博弈下的粟特城邦，大唐在“安史之乱”后退出西域，这些波斯化国家在大食与突厥的影响下又陆续发生了伊斯兰化和突厥化的历史性转变。根据历史学家考证，造纸术早在怛逻斯战役爆发前就已经传播至此，它助力昭武九姓中的安国逐步成为穆斯林世界重要的文化中心，被誉为“伊斯兰支柱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257255&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乌兹别克斯坦布哈拉伊斯兰文化中心的象征：Mir-i-Arab经学院&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并波悉林，奴隶出身的战神统帅，在三年后卷入了黑衣大食夺位之争。他支持第二代哈里发打败了对手，却于三个月后被这位哈里发虐杀——诚所谓“飞鸟尽，良弓藏”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段秀实，直言极谏的儒将，撤回安西后被遭他斥责过的李嗣业提拔为判官，两年后又辅佐封常清攻克大勃律，在平定“安史之乱”和抗击吐蕃前线也屡立大功，64岁高龄时因反对叛臣朱泚而殉国——文天祥《正气歌》中的“或为击贼笏”说的就是他誓死讨贼的典故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李嗣业，身高两米的猛将，在“安史之乱”中回军中原勤王，曾与中兴名将郭子仪联手，以弱敌强，连战连捷，陆续收复关中平原和东都洛阳，成为积弱唐军中的“救火队员”。大唐乾元二年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元759年）&lt;/span>;，他在作战时中流矢，“出血数升，注地而卒”——每当说到李嗣业，我首先会想起“当嗣业刀者，人马俱碎”的勇武场景。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦塔拉斯省奥特莫克山口，一千二百多年前的“山地之王”没准路经此地。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝，胆识超凡但贪功爱财的名将，怛逻斯战役四年后“安史之乱”爆发，高仙芝与封常清受命统率临时纠集的乌合之众抵挡精锐叛军主力，只得依据坚城死守潼关，却因此被唐玄宗下诏双双斩杀。接替他们俩的另一位名将哥舒翰被迫出兵与叛军野战，结果全军覆没，潼关失守，长安沦陷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝临死前曾有机会翻盘：当时向玄宗进谗并奉旨到潼关处决高仙芝的太监边令诚率领百余名陌刀手为自己壮胆，却不曾想这些精锐军士齐声高呼：高将军冤枉！ “其声殷地”。高仙芝本可借助于这些忠诚的士兵收捕边令诚，或可迫使玄宗收回成命。但他最终没有这么做，而是望着老战友封常清的尸首慨然长叹，束手赴死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位盛唐名将，最终随盛唐一并化为泡影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 22:26:40 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一家经营不善的公司，承建了佳木斯5年就垮的体育馆]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260142]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 20:36:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/aPvOHwxqlK0VsO18YBywrmePYpJXnckOoBpgrqzc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/aPvOHwxqlK0VsO18YBywrmePYpJXnckOoBpgrqzc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;桦南县悦城广场全民健身体育馆塌陷事故现场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月6日19时20分左右，黑龙江省佳木斯市桦南县悦城广场全民健身体育馆内发生塌陷事故。当时有7名初中生在里面打篮球，有学生发现屋顶异常并向门口跑去，随即屋顶塌陷，总塌陷面积达675平方米。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7名学生中，有3人自行脱险，1人被救出送医，3人死亡。一位遇难者的朋友告诉媒体，那是个从小爱打篮球、被同学称为“球王”的少年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月24日，桦南县县长曾到该体育馆检查安全工作，并强调文化市场经营者要履行好安全生产主体责任，时刻紧绷安全生产这根弦。此前一天，黑龙江省齐齐哈尔第三十四中学体育馆发生楼顶坍塌事故——那次事故造成11名师生遇难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次事故发生后，佳木斯市、桦南县两级纪检监察机关第一时间介入，成立调查组开展调查。桦南县政府新闻办对外介绍说，坍塌场馆的经营者为桦南县新阳光健身俱乐部，负责人门雅男已被警方控制，事故原因正在进一步调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;体育馆的建筑所有人曾将场所租赁给他人经营，但从2022年12月起，转让给门雅男经营的新阳光健身俱乐部管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;门雅男是悦城的“老朋友”。她曾在2021年4月成立悦城体育健身俱乐部，8个月后注销该公司，于2022年7月成立新阳光健身俱乐部。她同时在桦南县悦城电影城有限责任公司任监事，该公司实控人为杨巾力，是2017年8月成立的桦南县悦城商厦有限公司的实控人和受益所有人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;悦城广场是桦南县住建部门大力招商来的项目。由北京得意音通技术有限公司投资3.8亿元，投资注册黑龙江省悦城房地产开发有限公司，在原棚户区建设城市商业综合体和高档住宅小区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/vla3O3vp9iiWs3gpanZDcsumuhpp61wNgBa0VvLJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/vla3O3vp9iiWs3gpanZDcsumuhpp61wNgBa0VvLJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;桦南县悦城广场全民健身体育馆塌陷事故现场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2015年到2022年，桦南县曾有悦城房地产开发有限公司、悦城商厦有限公司和悦城体育文化发展有限公司三家公司接连成立，其中股东、高管多有重叠，但这三家公司先后注销。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据桦南县政府新闻办介绍，事故发生的悦城广场综合体7号楼由黑龙江海峰伟业建筑安装工程有限责任公司（以下简称“海峰伟业”）于2017年7月开始建设，2018年7月竣工，监理单位为佳木斯三江建设监理公司，2020年7月通过验收。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2007年，海峰伟业由朱海、朱波（以下简称“二朱”）出资在鹤岗市成立。 2016年5月，二朱退出公司，26岁的岳城棋接手。一年后，悦城广场综合体开始建设，海峰伟业的市场主体类型从“自然人投资或控股”变更为“自然人独资”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一份案号为“(2018)黑0822民初272号”的民事判决书显示，2016年之前，主要在鹤岗做工程的海峰伟业因负债累累，便以年化利率6%的利息向岳城棋借款。 2016年，二朱彻底放弃海峰伟业，转让给岳城棋。此时，朱海、朱波仍欠鹤岗市工农区地方税务局和国税局税款加滞纳金共计2059920.94元，他们向岳城棋借钱，缴纳了税款。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年10月，岳城棋就偿还这笔借款及利息起诉了二朱，得到法院支持，但二朱称无钱，暂无法偿还。这笔总额为242万元的借款直到2020年才被强制执行完成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刚接手海峰伟业那段时间，岳城棋折腾了不少赚钱的路子，比如购买已经交付、但被几度倒手转卖的回迁安置房，后法院认为他在购买房屋时没有对实际居住人核实情况、构成重大过失，故不支持他主张对回迁房的实体所有权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还参与过赌博，带着7500元赌资下场，输光后又当场借了1万元，利息为每日300元。后在2016年12月2日被公安机关当场抓获，收缴赌资，受到行政处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岳城棋的社交软件头像是一张写着“人生靠自己”的图片，个性签名为“父母给的叫背景，自己打拼的叫江山，有一种努力叫靠自己”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在接手海峰伟业之前，岳城棋没有管理建筑公司或大型建筑项目的经验。但他通过努力，用一个当时正在被强制执行欠款的鹤岗建筑公司接下了投资1.7亿元的桦南县明星项目悦城广场。这之后，海峰伟业成了桦南县政府的招标大户。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《南方周末》梳理了公开招标信息后总结道：“（海峰伟业）参与的项目也是五花八门。市政工程方面，承建了公共停车场、道路、高铁停车场等，医疗工程有县疾控中心、县医院的传染病区、120急救中心，还有桦南县美丽乡村基础设施建设、县供电局的物资储备库、桦南经济开发区生猪屠宰厂区内的黑土转运土方。此外，还中标了县里的保障性安居工程。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故发生当晚，岳城棋曾接受《南方周末》的短暂采访。他表示已经知道体育馆坍塌事件，但不确定是不是自己的工程，“需要回去查一查资料。”次日，岳城棋手机持续无人接听，同日下午，佳木斯发布通报，确认海峰伟业为体育馆施工方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/r4q6tNkB09v3ic491piEXK0aHZ11KOMBzq7HBUEx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/r4q6tNkB09v3ic491piEXK0aHZ11KOMBzq7HBUEx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;桦南县悦城广场全民健身体育馆塌陷事故现场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一家曾承接悦城广场综合体的开发商黑龙江省华优建筑工程有限公司，实为悦城地产的二股东，亦是当地政府项目的招标大户，曾承建佳木斯市中医院修缮医疗用房、桦川县文化广电新闻出版局的文化设施建设项目和桦南县危房改造项目。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事发当日，桦南县委宣传部一名工作人员接受媒体采访时回应，房顶坍塌与降雪有关。桦南县在当日16时47分发布了暴雪红色预警信号，提示必要时停课、停业（特殊行业除外）。根据气象监测，事发地桦南县6日24小时降雪量达到44毫米，打破了11月降雪量纪录。就在两天前，该县曾召开防范应对当前极端天气的工作会议，要求各行业领域按照职责分工，做好各自安全防范工作，最大限度减少次生灾害事故的发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访港交所前行政总裁李小加：互联互通是香港资本市场成功的基石]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260126]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;李小加被誉为“中国金融证券业改革开放的最早实践者之一”。任职华尔街著名的达维(Davis Polk &amp;amp; Wardwell)与布朗伍德(Brown &amp;amp; Wood)律师事务所期间，他受&lt;span>;中国财政部&lt;/span>;邀请参与了中国第一次全球主权债的发行工作；先后担任美林中国区主席和摩根大通中国区主席时，李小加牵头中海油和中国移动等首批央国企跨境上市；他参与策划发起的中国海洋石油竞购尤尼克事件，被认为“开创了中国企业的新时代”；执掌港交所十余年，他成功推动了港交所历史上至关重要的多项战略举措，包括“沪港通”“深港通”。更令市场印象深刻的是2018年落地同股不同权上市制度改革和&amp;nbsp;2012 年收购伦敦金属交易所。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，他创业“滴灌通”，并根据澳门政府有关行政令设立和运营滴灌通澳交所，寄望“让国际资本与中国小微企业联通”。这是一项全球范围内的革命性金融实验。历时7个月，2023年10月26日，滴灌通澳交所获得伊斯兰教律监管委员会认证，符合禁止收息等伊斯兰教义。 &lt;span>;该认证包含了&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;伊斯兰金融&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;对滴灌通开创的收入分成产品不是贷款收息模式的确认，并认可滴灌通以分成共担风险的投资方式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三十多年前，中国如何首度发行全球主权债？二十多年前，中国首批央国企为何登陆美国资本市场？二十年前，央企首单海外竞购成色如何？十年来，港交所如何破冰与A股实现互联互通？接受南方周末记者专访时，李小加回顾了这些与中国金融改革开放密切相关的重大事件。他表示，国际化、拥抱新经济、实现互联互通，直到今天依然是香港资本市场成功的基石，也是中国资本市场走向世界的改革创新。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/5EWnxZd3yR8XQC3FJ53jIHcDL5jPWsU9tJYHwfSX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;635&quot; height=&quot;794&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/5EWnxZd3yR8XQC3FJ53jIHcDL5jPWsU9tJYHwfSX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;李小加：港交所前行政总裁，现任滴灌通集团创始人、主席&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;以海外上市促改革的整体收益是多边的”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你曾牵头参与我国第一次发行全球主权债，这次发行全球主权债的主要难点是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;发债首先需要一家大评级机构给中国主权进行信用评级。我参与评级工作的两个多月时间，非常紧张。如果评级不合适，中国根本不会发行主权债。其中发生了很多故事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过艰苦努力，1993年，中国拿到A级主权评级，次年年初发债成功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你也牵头主持了首批央国企跨境上市，当时主要为了解决什么问题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那时的诉求非常简单，就是为国企解困。当时大量国企非常困难，三角债严重。最主要的动因是国企改革，需要融资，依靠资金进行改革。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国企改革就要真正进入市场，按市场经济规律运行。在这个过程中，大家很快感觉到，通过上市本身融资，很容易把大家的思想统一起来。然后把境外上市作为一种催化剂，要想去境外融资，央国企就要做各种改革，政府功能、社会功能和企业功能要分开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些改革在央国企海外上市的过程中慢慢变得重要。它是靠融资把大家的认知统一起来，为了达到这个目的，让大家慢慢接受改革必须承受的一些成本、一些影响和冲击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以海外上市促改革，是否达到了预期目标？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那当然了。首先，这个目的或者说整体益处是多边的。企业本身在最关键的时候融到大笔资金。 1993 年，首批9 家企业，很快有22 家企业。这些企业用海外融资做了大量资本开支，解决了大量发展中需要的资金问题。它非常及时地解决了当时资金的迫切需求。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;央国企跨境上市真的吹响了国企改革的号角，带动和催发了原来启动相当困难的各个方面体制和机制改革。海外上市之后，国企改革慢慢进入到主赛道。大家开始全面接受国企改革。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅如此，央国企跨境上市很快催生了中国资本市场的发展。我们这么多企业不可能全部到国外上市，而且中国这么多资本，老百姓也有钱。为什么我们的资本不能投入到我们自己的企业里呢？从发行人的角度及投资者希望参与改革开放的发展红利来看，它促进了中国资本市场的诞生和发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一点也很重要，央国企第一次走向世界。外界开始认识中国企业，认识中国经济。然后外资由于投资，深度关心、参与和体验中国经济现代化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得我国央国企内部治理效率方面的提升空间有多大？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;国企也好，央企也好，只是所有权的一种形式。新加坡也有主权基金，但它的运作方式完全市场化，除了出资人身份以外，其他与私营企业一样的运作模式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有的央企也非常高效。要说效率提升，管理者激励机制和其它企业一样吗？我们不能以企业所有权形式简单地说哪个更有效，哪个更好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;世界已经基本上不可能脱钩了&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在，一批央国企可能要从纽交所退市。你怎么看目前这种形势？是否有可能走向“资本脱钩”？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;即便退市，和资本脱钩这个事，依然是相差得太远的事情。它们是如今国际资本参与中国市场发展中极小的少数。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，全世界投资到中国的外资体量如此之大，包含范围是主要民企和在香港上市的央国企。除了科技领域比较明显的脱钩外，其他方面的脱钩会有一些。但完全还没有到老死不相往来的程度。我们已经习惯了与一个高度发达的资本市场之间的相互渗入和连接。现在这个连接比它鼎盛期间已弱了很多。如果从二三十年前看如今，今天这个世界的相连已经基本上不可能脱钩了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全世界像一驾飞机一样，世界经济最大的两个引擎怎么可能脱钩？在极其深度密切合作的20 年后，目前有一些回撤。即便在回撤之后，两国的经济联系远不能用脱钩这样的字形容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“港交所改革的两大核心考量&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;对内地的历史价值和现实意义”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;执掌港交所10年，你主导了多项影响深远的改革。你对哪些改革更满意？ Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我平常不这么想问题。在历史大潮中，一个人刚好很幸运地在一个很重要很合适的位置上，然后天时地利人和的条件下做了一些事情。这些不能说成一个人的事情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;任职港交所期间，哪项改革对内地更有历史价值和现实意义？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这是港交所所有改革最主要的两个核心考量。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个大主题就是香港在很长时间作为一种国际市场，应该是帮助内地资本市场国际化，帮助国际市场更多融入内地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从这个角度讲，每一件事情都要系统性地解决。毕竟这两个市场是两个完全不同的体系，既有极大动力互相融入和互联互通，也有它很强大的内在机制和力量。这使互联互通非常困难。换言之，这两个市场各有自己的管理体制、市场体制和运作方式，愿意融合，但又不愿意为了融合而大量改变自己的制度和系统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;怎么利用香港极其独特的地位呢？我们充分认识到两边市场哪些可以为了互联互通进行一些改变，哪些是不可能改变的，哪些改变是必须的。找到一个最大公约数和最小公倍数，找到在最小成本里边达到最大幅度的互联互通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在所有改革中，我们要考虑很多问题。也许某种形式的互联互通最有效最好，但它的成本可能太高。大家不愿意承受；一些事情可能很容易改革，但没什么特别大意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如，我们开始想选择很小的事情，比如说两边交易所的交易时间段不一样，开市和收盘都不一样。看上去似乎很小的事情，但改革并不容易。它涉及两地不同的生活习惯和工作习惯。看起来大家应该没有什么争议的改革，实际上却是当时最困难的改革之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回过头看，以下几件改革对港交所有重大历史价值和现实意义。首先，港交所不能只是在香港的内地市场，港交所不仅只在亚洲，应该往欧美突破，因为内地希望通过香港市场走向国际；不能只在股票市场，要向内地最需要的大宗商品市场突破。因此，港交所兼并收购了伦敦金属交易所，也尝试过收购伦敦交易所，但没有成功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二是港交所股票市场本身。因为监管规则，中国科技企业一直无法上市。它们代表先进的生产力，却只能到美国上市。并不是之前的监管逻辑错误，但在全世界都在竞争的时候，我们为什么死死抱住原有的东西不改变呢？美国的监管逻辑原来也和港交所一致，但它可以找到非常现实的原因并允许改变。我们最后进行改革，小米、京东、阿里等等都可以回归到港交所。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A股市值已高居全球第二。这么庞大的市场与香港市场及国际市场怎么能够实现互联互通，但又不改变双方各自的规则和制度？因此，沪港通、深港通、债券通、债券互换通等等一系列改革创新陆续出笼。两个市场之间达到基本互联互通功能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国际化、拥抱新经济、实现互联互通，直到今天都还是香港市场成功的基石，也是中国资本市场走向世界的改革创新。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对任职港交所期间的工作还留有遗憾吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在互联互通是二级市场，即沪港通和深港通可以南下或北上买卖已在港交所或深交所与沪交所的股票。但互联互通没有向一级市场延伸到“新股通”。这是我的遗憾。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个产品的名字，我以前用“新股通”。新股通让中国市场最终和世界资源对接。在香港实现互联互通，能实现巨大的发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;让国际&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;资本&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;和中国小微&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;企业充分&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;联通&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;告别港交所，你以一种全球最新的投资模式和交易模式开始创业——2023年8月正式运营滴灌通澳交所。滴灌通澳交所要解决世界性难题——小微企业融资难。为何滴灌通澳交所可以解决这个难题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;滴灌通澳交所是全球首个持牌的收入分成产品（DRO）交易所。滴灌通的愿景与使命是将国际资本与中国小微经济充分联通起来，要让国际传统金融和中国小微经济这两个非常难以兼容的运营体系实现互联互通。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这件事情能突破的基础和前提是中国数字化革命全面普及。无现金社会为一种崭新的、革命性的融资形式提供了可能。有了这个革命性的前提后，加上我们自己创建的滴灌通澳交所，就把这事做成了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;万一我们没做，或者万一我们没把它搞好，一定很快就会有其他人把它搞好做起来。就像没有互联网的时候，马云跳到天上去，他啥也干不了。有了互联网以后，他就做了淘宝，但是很快也有了京东、美团等等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并不是我们带来了灵丹妙药，一下子破解了大家的难题。只能说我们是第一个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么你们会成为第一个？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;大部分从事金融的人，看不上小微生意，认为这是不可能的；从事互联网或数字化的大部分人不了解金融的本质。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么能做呢？我们知道，全世界的资本市场主要解决两个问题，一是投资的信息准确和真实，一是投资的钱和货进出的安全有保证。具体而言，全世界投资者只会投资股票或债券，而且是大公司的股票和债券，因为投资者关心的上述两个核心问题是投资的前提。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;传统交易所为解决这两个问题，依靠大量的专业人士做研究报告、做年报等等；交收安全则依靠银行、券商和交易所一系列机构背书，保证资金进出安全保障。但这两件事件都极其昂贵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这种情况下，小微企业不会通过上市和发债融资。但在中国数字化革命的当下，这两个核心问题可以低成本解决了。一个小店的收入，在支付体系里完全体现出来，即信息的准确。我们就在收入上做文章，我投资你，买你的收入行不行？从收入中分一笔行不行？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于投资进出保障的问题，我们在支付体系里直接扣款，直接在银行分账体系扣款。交收安全问题就解决了。华尔街金融体系里面解决的两个核心大功能，我们通过小芯片就解决了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;解决这个问题不是做慈善，是实实在在把回报拿回来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最近有个别人质疑这个商业模式。几乎与此同时，澳交所获得伊斯兰教律监管委员会认证。澳门金管局行政委员会委员刘杏娟也表示，将秉持“风险为本”的监管原则对澳交所进行日常监控。这种创新模式的法律监管是什么样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;投资链条非常清晰：滴灌通通过海外机构进行募资，通过外商直接投资在内地联合经营开店。目前涉及的监管包括有四个国家和地区相关法律：中国内地作为一种民事法律关系有相关法律法规、中国香港证监会监管、中国澳门金融监管条例的相关条款，认购产品的国际投资人这块，受英国法律监管。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[开庭前拍摄法庭照片，律师被扣手机己归还]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260138]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 18:42:33&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/fRThzqO2ucQtzDgTciByFDPwYgBFI0MYoVxRVLml.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/fRThzqO2ucQtzDgTciByFDPwYgBFI0MYoVxRVLml.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257292&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;迟夙生在法庭昏迷后，法院叫来了救护车。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“头痛原因待查”。 2023年11月7日上午，迟夙生拿到医院的病情证明后，仍需继续住院治疗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;67岁的迟夙生是黑龙江夙生律师事务所律师，曾连任第九届至第十一届全国人大代表。 11月6日，她代理的一起涉黑案件在云南宣威市人民法院公开审理。开庭前，迟夙生因在法庭拍摄了两张照片被认为违反法庭纪律，手机被扣留。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当天下午6时许，审判长宣布休庭。迟夙生要求返还手机，与法院工作人员沟通无果后在法庭内昏迷。一个小时后，她被送至宣威市第一人民医院急诊科就诊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月7日下午4点多，迟夙生告诉南方周末记者，宣威法院院长陈永福在当天下午1点左右到医院看望她，并在3点多归还了她的手机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;两张照片&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年11月6日上午8点40分左右，距开庭还有20分钟，迟夙生抵达法庭。她向南方周末记者回忆，现场只有一名书记员，合议庭成员、检察官和其余律师都还没到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一起涉黑案重审一审开庭的第二十一天。此前，该案已经历一审、二审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年12月10日，宣威法院一审判决，认定涉案的刘顺平等10人不构成黑社会性质犯罪，但存在以刘顺平为首要分子、组织成员经常纠集在一起，共同实施寻衅滋事、敲诈勒索、非法拘禁行为，被认定为恶势力犯罪集团。刘顺平按照集团所犯的全部罪行数罪并罚，其余人员按照其所参与的犯罪行为被处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一审判决后，刘顺平等人不服，提出上诉。检察机关未抗诉。 2022年12月9日，曲靖中院二审以“部分事实不清”为由裁定撤销原判，发回重审。案件重审期间，宣威市检察院追加了3项罪名补充起诉，并仍指控刘顺平等人涉嫌黑社会性质犯罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进入法庭后，迟夙生注意到被告人席位上并排摆放的10张黑色铁制审讯椅，带有固定手脚的装置。在这天前，此案庭审时被告人坐的一直是常规带靠背的木制椅，手脚可以自由活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她的经验中，这种状况并不常见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;依据《中华人民共和国人民法院法庭规则》（以下简称”法庭规则”），除认为被告人人身危险性大，可能危害法庭安全外，法院在庭审活动中不得对被告人使用戒具。迟夙生下意识地举起手机，拍了两张审讯椅的照片。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，她走出法庭，将手机存放到法庭外的铁皮柜内，为开庭做准备。这时，代理此案的其余律师陆续进场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迟夙生和另两名代理此案的律师均表示，从此案开庭的第一天开始，法院就口头要求他们不能带手机进入法庭。曾有律师对此提出异议，认为法庭规则只规定了不得拨打或接听电话等，并没有禁止携带手机，法院未对此作出回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;4次沟通&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;迟夙生没想到，因为庭前拍摄的照片，此后她的手机被法院扣留。整个过程中，她同法院工作人员有4次沟通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开庭前，迟夙生把手机存入铁皮柜不久，就被法警叫至法庭外。据她回忆，一名法院工作人员要求她删除照片。她拒绝了这个要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法庭规则规定，全体人员在庭审活动中不得对庭审活动进行录音、录像、拍照或使用移动通信工具等传播庭审活动，违反这项规定的，法院可以暂扣其使用的设备及存储介质，删除内容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迟夙生认为，自己拍照时庭审还没开始，没有违反法庭纪律。随后，她回到法庭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上午10时20分左右，庭审中场休息20分钟。迟夙生被要求留在法庭内，其余律师均不被允许进入法庭。她记得，审判长提出要暂扣她的手机，书记员在现场做了记录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三次沟通发生在开庭期间。下午庭审时，轮到迟夙生发言，她继续申请返还她的手机。她强调，自己是在法庭尚未宣布开庭前拍摄照片，扣押她手机的行为毫无道理。她还表示，如果法院要扣押她的手机，需提供书面材料。审判长则表示，如果合议庭有违法违规的行为，迟夙生可以向上反映情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下午6点15分左右，法庭休庭。迟夙生来到法庭外的铁皮柜处取手机时，发现手机已经不在柜内。此时她已经一天没有使用手机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上周，迟夙生接到通知，这起本计划于11月8日结束庭审的涉黑案开庭将延长一个月。她急着和其他法院协调开庭时间，“我就特别着急，喊审判长&amp;nbsp;&#39;把手机还给我呀&#39;。审判长说&#39;丢了你就报警吧&#39;。”两名在场律师均向南方周末记者证实听到了这一对话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迟夙生返回法庭，希望再找人交涉此事。随后，她感到“全身发软，站不住了”，躺在了律师席的椅子上。当天晚上7点半，迟夙生被送至宣威市第一人民医院急诊科就诊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月7日，刘顺平等人涉黑案继续开庭审理。迟夙生未能到庭。她已在当天下午出院，打算休息一段时间，检查身体状况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小金眼中的大金丨人来人往]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260080]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/06/XihIRkIUfjtnNvzYVGkjxzVxFRDTusi9UKvZB3J0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/XihIRkIUfjtnNvzYVGkjxzVxFRDT usi9UKvZB3J0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Jin Shenghua and Jin Yaoji at the translation seminar. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Jin Yiuji, former president of the Chinese University of Hong Kong, has reached his ninth year and has been retired for nearly two decades. Ten years later, I am still strong and full of energy. While admiring me, I think of the past. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day in 2004, between the administration building and the library of the Chinese University, everyone on campus unanimously called On the steps of the Central Steps, I met a colleague who was about to retire. She has served the school for many years. Starting from Li Zhuomin, the founding president of CUHK, she has worked with five presidents. She can be said to be a veteran of the past dynasties. Chatting with her, she mentioned her retirement and that Principal Jin Yaoji was leaving soon. She felt deeply sad to leave. She suddenly said: &quot;Principal Jin is such a nice person, I&#39;m not afraid of him!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Not afraid of him? Who would be afraid of Principal Kim? However, if you think about it further, why are subordinates not afraid of their supervisors? According to common sense, isn&#39;t it common for subordinates to be afraid of their supervisors? This made me have an image of this &quot;member&quot; in my mind - affable, smiling, humorous, witty, and talented; treating everyone equally, from the school director to the co-workers; when running the school, Accept advice and learn from it, follow the good as a rule; smoke a pipe when you are free, and enjoy yourself. Such a gentle and kind-hearted supervisor will of course make people &quot;respect and love him&quot; rather than &quot;keep him at arm&#39;s length&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have known Professor Jin Yaoji for decades. At the beginning, there were not many teachers named Jin in the school. Since both of us were affiliated with New Asia, our colleagues mostly used &quot;Da Jin&quot; and &quot;Xiao Jin&quot; to distinguish each other, and we also called each other &quot;the family&quot;, adding Professor Jin&#39;s There is only one character difference between his name and my eldest brother&#39;s name, so I naturally regard him as an elder brother. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first met Professor Jin, it was still in the 1970s. I still remember that back then, this &quot;member of the family&quot; had just returned to Hong Kong from the United States. He was very handsome, young and promising. Not long after, he held important positions many times, and was later elected as the president of New Asia. At that time, Jin Yaoji was only in his early forties, and he was not from New Asia. These two factors may have caused him to encounter some obstacles when he first took charge of important tasks. However, with his outstanding intelligence and amazing courage, all difficulties were in his hands. , can all be easily solved. Since then, Professor Jin has been at CUHK for decades, and as he has moved up the ladder, he has more and more affairs and heavier responsibilities, but has anyone seen him looking sad and overwhelmed? In everyone&#39;s mind, Jin Gong always talks, laughs, and fights, and does everything lightly. Because of this, whenever the school has &quot;difficult and complicated diseases&quot;, they will naturally entrust them to him, hoping that he can &quot;prescribe the right medicine&quot; and rejuvenate them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2003, the CUHK Faculty and Staff Association held a Christmas dance, and Principal Jin was also invited. At the party, the host asked me to say a few words to pay tribute to him. I said: &quot;There are two kinds of leaders in the world: the first type, others respect and fear him; the second type, people respect and love him. Professor Jin certainly belongs to the second category.&quot; These words were recognized by everyone. That night, Principal Jin, who is usually not good at dancing, actually danced very happily surrounded by everyone. He is such a considerate and easy-going person. Over the years, whenever colleagues ask for advice, no matter how busy he is, he will put everything aside and listen attentively. This makes people feel that in Professor Jin&#39;s mind, you are the most important person and your affairs are the most important things. He is listening, he is thinking, he is sharing your burdens and resolving your worries. He is busy with everything, so he will stop time, accompany you, and protect you. No matter how bumpy the road ahead is, he will help you and solve your problems. How can such a supervisor not make people convinced? When colleagues work hard and serve the school wholeheartedly, he not only hears and sees them, but also expresses his gratitude through actions. On the eve of the degree awarding ceremony every year, colleagues in the public relations team are often extremely busy and stay up all night. One time, near midnight, Principal Jin actually visited the class in person and brought chocolates to express his condolences! Such a sincere leader can make the whole school work together as one, regardless of each other, to strive for a common goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Jin is most praised for his outstanding eloquence and excellent articles. He is a person who speaks well and writes well. On important occasions such as international conferences, commemorative celebrations, opening ceremonies, etc., as long as Jin Gong is present and he opens the mouth of Jin, both the guest and the host will be happy and everyone will be moved. Jin Yaoji&#39;s eloquence is not just about his brilliant tongue and spitting jade. What is unmatched is his humor, his wit, his ability to talk and laugh freely, as if everything in the world is ready at any time. As long as he waved and nodded, he would arrange the formation and send the generals out in formation. I remember one time, Professor Jin was going to the city to host a banquet. In the car, he asked me a few questions casually and got a brief grasp of the information about the guests. As a result, he used it vividly in his speech at the banquet. After my country&#39;s first astronaut Yang Liwei successfully launched into space, Principal Jin quoted the words &quot;feeling good&quot; on different occasions, but he used it just right every time and the effect was amazing. Another time, the Department of Translation held an international seminar and invited Jin Gong to preside over the opening ceremony. He asked me to draft the lecture notes in advance. On the opening day, Jin Gong came as scheduled and spoke according to the script. Halfway through the reading, he suddenly said: &quot;I did not write this elegant speech, it was drafted by Jin Shenghua.&quot; He was humorous, calm and comfortable, It can be seen. The most recent one was a speech at the launch of my new book (&quot;Heart-to-Heart-Eighteen Years with Brigitte Lin&quot;) on September 24, 2022. On that day, Shanheng College of Chinese University held a dialogue between Qingxia and I. During the meeting, Jin Gong was specially invited to make comments after the conversation. As soon as he came on stage, he asked the audience seriously if they could take off their masks. At that time, Hong Kong was still implementing epidemic prevention measures. Of course, it was not possible. So, he went on to say: &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter if I don&#39;t take off the mask. Brigitte Lin wears a mask. Everyone will suffer a lot.&quot; .&quot; As soon as this statement came out, it immediately caused a roar of laughter and heated up the atmosphere of the entire venue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also remember that at the dinner of the Second Global Chinese Youth Literature Award in 2003, President Jin once said that the stars were shining that night, and stars of both big and small literary genres descended on CUHK. , Bai Xianyong, Yu Guangzhong, Lin Wenyue and other famous artists, as well as many minor literary stars such as the young students who won awards in each group. In fact, President Jin himself is an out-and-out literary star. On the one hand, he writes books and lectures in the field of sociology to teach future generations; on the other hand, he writes narratives and expresses his feelings in the field of literature. During his visit to the University of Cambridge in 1975, Professor Jin was impressed by the aura and beauty of Cambridge. In addition to writing major works, he also began to write short prose pieces. During his one year at JNU, through rain, fog, snow, spring, summer, autumn and winter, Professor Jin’s inspirational words came out and he completed the book &quot;Cambridge Silk&quot;. Ten years later, when he was a visiting professor at the University of Heidelberg, he put his thoughts and feelings into writing and wrote the book &quot;Heidelberg Silk&quot;. The two volumes complemented each other and became a praised &quot;gold-style prose&quot;. In 2007, after Jin Gong retired, he made another trip to his hometown. One of them was a pilgrimage to Dunhuang, the desert art capital. After returning, he published the book &quot;Dunhuang Silk&quot;, which echoed and connected the previous two volumes of &quot;Yu Silk&quot;. It is the work of the three famous &quot;Yusi&quot; sisters. Looking at Professor Jin&#39;s life, he could not only use a huge pen like a rafter, but also use the dignity of a mountain to write large articles about governing the country and criticizing the current ills, which are very resonant to read. He could also hold a thin pen like a silk thread, and use the lightness of water to describe and express his feelings directly. , the true feelings of the world come from the heart, and it is deeply touching to read. No matter whether it is a masterpiece or a short piece, there is emotion in the theory, and reason in the emotion. The two blend together without leaving any trace. The author looks down at the heaven and the earth, travels between China and the West, traces the past, discusses the present, and explores the secrets. He can not only analyze and find out the clues in the vast sea of ​​knowledge, but also find new ways and write strange works in the literary world where hundreds of flowers are blooming. . The reason is actually closely related to his personal qualities, endowments, temperament and character. In addition to his professional field, Professor Jin has a profound understanding of literature, history, philosophy, and education. In addition, he is a reasonable person in life. As the saying goes, &quot;Knowledge of worldly affairs is knowledge, and understanding of human feelings is writing.&quot; Therefore, he can not only talk about poetry and art At that time, he was outstanding, and he was also good at twisting and turning in the intricate tangle of personnel and affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Kim Yao-kee has served at CUHK for a total of thirty-four years. During his two years as president, he has experienced many difficult and difficult moments under extraordinary circumstances, including the outbreak of SARS and the government-controlled Fortunately, Principal Jin worked hard and dealt with the accidents such as salary cuts due to capital cuts, and finally overcame the difficulties one by one. During his tenure, President Jin completed many tasks, not only established the School of Law, raised huge donations for the university, and introduced new mechanisms to improve the university&#39;s governance structure. When President Jin took office, he once humorously claimed: &quot;I have a long way to go but I still have a long way to go!&quot; Indeed, two years is not a long time, but President Jin&#39;s achievements in running the school are obvious to all and are highly praised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of June 2004, on the eve of President Jin Yaoji’s retirement, CUHK held a farewell banquet. That night, the house was full of guests and the event was unprecedented. All the guests who were supposed to come came, and unexpected friends also came, including colleagues from all walks of life and departments in the school who usually do not like to have banquets. The dinner was held very successfully. There were no lengthy speeches or sensational scenes. Everything was simple and natural, just like Principal Jin&#39;s traditional style. The president said in his speech: &quot;I am the youngest dean and the oldest president in the history of CUHK. People ask me what I can do after retirement? I think, Ronald Reagan 71 I only became president at the age of 18, so I&#39;m probably qualified enough to be elected president!&quot; The fun and humor are still the same, this is Principal Kim&#39;s true character! In the middle of the dinner, there suddenly appeared a scene where everyone came forward to invite Principal Jin to take a group photo: one table after another, in good order, came forward spontaneously, with a look of reluctance in their eyes. This is A sight never seen before. From school directors to secretaries, from professors to clerks, it is hard to tell them apart. Regardless of high or low, at this moment, everyone only has in their minds the outgoing Principal Jin, the gentle, elegant and generous Principal Jin! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last program of the dinner was a choir formed temporarily by CUHK alumni to sing the song &quot;Blessings&quot; for President Jin. This famous song originally sung by Ye Qianwen, with lyrics adapted by the talented Professor He Wenhui, sings the voice of everyone: &quot;Ling Yun is talented, everyone sees it, and the principal Jin Gongyi banishes him to an immortal. He is funny, handsome, and very friendly to others. He has a large belly and can punt a boat.&quot; . People who practice benevolence can contribute, and their sincerity feels far away. Sincere and fraternal love nurtures talents without getting tired, and thousands of spring breezes blow gently and warmly. Ah! The spring breeze blows in my face again. I wave my hands gently, and the sadness of parting is still deep. Listen to me Tell me carefully, I will be happy in the future. I will have my beloved wife by my side, a pipe, and thousands of smoke rings...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Principal Jin retired, compared to the busy years in the past, his life was lighter. The wind is light, but still full and more elegant than before. In addition to his continuous writings, Jin Gong was also diligent in writing calligraphy. Jin Yaoji has worked hard to practice calligraphy under the supervision of his father since he was a child, but he never expressed his hardships. According to his self-statement, &quot;My exploration and pursuit of the art of calligraphy and calligraphy began after I retired from the Chinese University and was seventy years old.&quot; Therefore, Jin Gong, who was graceful and comfortable in his seventies, not only followed his heart&#39;s desires, but also enjoyed peace of mind. The joy of playing with grandchildren also continued the relationship between calligraphy and calligraphy that started in childhood, and carried it forward, becoming a &quot;golden calligraphy&quot; that has been praised for a while and is popular among the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My friend Lin Qingxia kept hearing about Jin Gong’s name and various anecdotes from me, and she read his masterpieces and admired his calligraphy from Ming Pao Monthly. One day, this talented woman who was thirsty for talents, He offered to meet with Principal Jin and ask him for tips on writing and calligraphy. On September 24, 2021, I hosted a banquet at the Shanghai General Assembly. As a result, the leaders in academic circles and the entertainment industry finally got to know each other in a state of mutual appreciation. That night, although the two met for the first time, they felt like old friends at first sight. During the dinner, Qingxia talked about how not long after she started learning Peking Opera, friends asked her to sing a cappella song. The words were not finished yet, but she had already spoken cheerfully and boldly. He stood up and sang &quot;Su San Qi Jie&quot; (Hua Dan) and &quot;San Jia Dian&quot; (Lao Sheng) without any shyness. When Jin Gong heard this, he cheered and shouted &quot;You are so bold&quot; in a loud voice! When the whole audience heard this, they couldn&#39;t help but burst out laughing and applauded with great joy! After that, friends often used the term &quot;bold&quot; to describe Lin Qingxia, the &quot;desperate Sanniang&quot; who is now able to do everything with ease and go all out. Qingxia herself also thought that Jin Gong&#39;s gift was remarkable, even to Jin Gong&#39;s words. When I proposed to give a calligraphy treasure as a gift, I specifically asked him to mention these words and hang them high in the living room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long after, Principal Jin presented Qingxia with a long calligraphy painting entitled &quot;The Wine Will Be Entering&quot;. This calligraphy was written with great joy, unrestrained and smart, and perfectly set off the famous work of the poet Li Bai. Qingxia asked the art master Zhang Shuping to help her frame it and hang it on the wall for viewing every day. Who knew that in July 2022, a &quot;fire&quot; incident occurred in the big house. Qingxia was far away overseas. At that time, what she was thinking about was not jewelry, clothes and other external objects, but Are you worried about whether the &quot;Will Enter the Wine&quot; hanging on the wall will be safe under the raging fire and billowing smoke? It&#39;s strange to say that&amp;nbsp;The third-level fire burned down famous paintings and furniture, but it stopped abruptly before &quot;The Wine Will Be Entered&quot;. It was separated by a wall,&amp;nbsp;but it didn&#39;t burn into Qingxia&#39;s room behind the wall. Paintings and clothes. Afterwards, Jin Yaoji sighed: &quot;I knew that Brigitte Lin was invulnerable to water and fire, Brigitte Lin is Brigitte Lin!&quot; Brigitte Lin believed that Jin Gong&#39;s calligraphy treasure was a treasure of the house and had magical powers to prevent fire and disaster. Seeing the two of them admiring and boasting about each other, I couldn&#39;t help but feel how elegant and interesting the sympathetic friendship between them was! Nowadays, &quot;About to Enter the Wine&quot; has been moved to Qingxia&#39;s mid-level study. Whenever a scholar comes to visit, the hostess will definitely invite them to take a photo in front of Jin Gong&#39;s calligraphy as a souvenir. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7P5xu1ZxGrNU2GLBli9suXEklp1ioo8P57XHwFiU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/7P5xu1ZxGrNU2GLBli9suXEklp1ioo8P57XHwFiU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257176&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brigitte Lin and Kim Yao-kee took a group photo in front of &quot;The Wine Will Come&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new crown is raging, and the epidemic has been severe in the past three years, but Principal Jin is calm and calm, and his wife Yuan Zhen is even more angry After calming down, he said: &quot;Life and death are destiny, there is no point in being afraid!&quot; Principal Jin continued to pursue the aesthetics of life, saying: &quot;Food and wine are never deliberately avoided. In a dangerous epidemic, if you have good friends and confidants, you can share them with others.&quot; Drunk, a toast, it&#39;s life!&quot; With such a broad mind and such a state of mind, he is no less generous than the free and easy Dongpo layman! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jin Yaoji, as his name suggests, is like a golden glow in the eyes of his friends, shining warmly on everything around him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[业委会成员向开发商索要好处费：监督业委会还需业主亲力亲为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260056]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, two members of the owners’ committee of a residential area in Guang’an, Sichuan, demanded 130,000 yuan in benefits from the developer, suspected of illegal The crime of accepting bribes by a state employee was investigated by the public security department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that Chen Moubing was elected as the director of the first owners committee of a community in Guang&#39;an with high votes, and Chen was appointed as the security coordination committee member and greening and sanitation committee member. At the end of May 2020, the government inspected the commercial buildings in the community and prepared to build a kindergarten. However, the developer of the community had set up some of the houses on the fourth floor as property offices and property committee offices. Chen Moubing found the developer of the community and asked for a benefit fee of 130,000 yuan, claiming that You can ask the property management committee, owners, etc. to agree to the office relocation. In June 2020, after the developer negotiated with Chen Moubing about the office relocation, he paid 80,000 yuan to Chen Moubing and 50,000 yuan to Chen Moubing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actions of Chen Bing and Chen have violated the provisions of Article 163 of the Criminal Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China and are suspected of accepting bribes by non-state personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For 130,000 &quot;benefits&quot;, Chen Bing and Chen were able to turn a commercial building in the community into a kindergarten. This shows that as members of the property committee, they have considerable &quot;power&quot;. Several key points remain to be clarified in this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, Article 30 of the &quot;Sichuan Provincial Property Management Regulations&quot; promulgated by Sichuan Province stipulates that the owners&#39; committee shall regularly announce the following information and information to the owners in the property management area: the use and operation of the common parts of the property Income and expenditure status. Has the owners&#39; committee announced relevant information to the owners&#39; meeting as soon as possible regarding the relocation of neighborhood committees and owners&#39; offices and the conversion of original houses into kindergartens? Have the owners reviewed this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if Chen Bing and Chen deliberately delayed or even concealed the report, it would be difficult to guarantee the community owners’ right to know about this important matter. This involves the second issue. According to the &quot;Guiding Rules for Owners&#39; Meetings and Owners Committees&quot; promulgated by the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the owners&#39; committee is elected by the owners&#39; meeting and consists of an odd number of 5 to 11 people. Why did the other members of the property committee, who accounted for the majority, not raise any objection to this decision and let Chen Moubing and Chen make the decision? This also reflects the inaction of other owners committee members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This points to a deeper question: Who will supervise the owners&#39; committee? The owners&#39; committee is the embodiment of community autonomy. Within the property management area, all owners form an owners&#39; meeting and elect the owners&#39; committee as the executive body of the owners&#39; meeting. However, the establishment process of the owners&#39; committees has been interfered with or even manipulated, and after the establishment of the owners&#39; committees, it has been reduced to a private area for a few members to seek personal gain. Such incidents have occurred frequently, making the independence and impartiality of some owners&#39; committees almost impossible. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as employment committee elections are concerned, some developers or property companies, in order to protect their own interests, interfere, block or even manipulate the elections of owners&#39; committees. The community where I live held a general election for the property owners committee this year. Unfortunately, the surrounding shop owners, who accounted for nearly 10% of the total property area of ​​the community, did not cast a single vote despite being notified and invited multiple times. This resulted in this The first general election failed to meet the requirement that &quot;owners accounting for more than two-thirds of the exclusive area participate in the vote&quot;, and the new property committee was therefore difficult to produce. Some owners who participated in the preparations for the new property committee reported that the property management company promised to reduce the rent to the shop owners in exchange for the other party not participating in the voting. The purpose was to hinder the election of the property committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if a homeowners committee is finally established through numerous obstacles, community owners will face more challenges. Since the owners&#39; committee exercises part of the power of the owners&#39; meeting, once it lacks professional ethics and sense of responsibility and only focuses on its own interests, regardless of the rights and interests of other owners, it will inevitably use public tools for private use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the ways in which owners&#39; committee members guard against self-stealing, there are roughly three types. First, turn public maintenance funds into your own “money bag”. According to a report by Beijing Evening News in 2018, owners of Zhujiang Junjing Community in Beijing reported that more than 4,000 yuan was spent on their public maintenance fund accounts as early as 2013 without any knowledge. Some owners also discovered that their public maintenance funds had been misappropriated. to the owners committee account. The owners&#39; committee said that this move was for everyone&#39;s benefit and investment, and it was not made public because it was afraid that someone would come to &quot;pick trouble.&quot; But this argument is unconvincing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second method is to &quot;expand financial resources&quot;, fully developing and commercializing various public facilities in the community, so that the profits that should be shared by all owners can be divided between the members of the property committee and the property management. &quot;Chongqing Evening News&quot; reported in 2010 that the property management company of Dibochundun Community in Shipingqiao, Jiulongpo District signed a contract with the property owners committee, and the public revenue was divided &quot;30-70&quot; (30% for the property owners committee and 70% for the property management party), but many The owner was unaware. In addition, the director of the owners&#39; committee also receives a monthly remuneration of 3,000 yuan from the property. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third method is to reach out to the property company for replacement. Members of the owners&#39; committee use the excuse of changing the property to make the existing property company pay &quot;protection fees&quot; to them, or to replace it with a new property company that has an interest in them, thereby making a profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at many cases, we can conclude that the moral self-discipline of owners’ committee members is unreliable and third-party supervision is indispensable. According to Article 39 of the &quot;Sichuan Provincial Property Management Regulations&quot;, if the decisions made by the owners&#39; meeting or the owners&#39; committee violate laws and regulations, the sub-district office (township people&#39;s government) or county (city, district) people&#39;s government where the property is located shall Within thirty days from the date of receipt of the complaint or discovery, the urban and rural development department shall make a decision in accordance with the law and notify all owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, as the owners of the community, the majority of owners must also realize that autonomy is not only a right, but also a manifestation of responsibility and ability. Owners should spend more time and energy to actively participate in community governance and strengthen the supervision and management of owners&#39; committees through election of owners&#39; committees, participation in owners&#39; meetings, and formulation of management regulations. At the same time, for major community matters announced by the property owners committee, such as public benefits, etc., professional auditing agencies can also be hired to audit, so as to effectively protect their own rights and interests and improve the quality of the community with stronger public awareness and legal concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[入职两个多月，00后班主任留遗书自杀，班级管理该不该单独设岗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260099]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 16:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>