<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[今年前三季度中国GDP同比增长5.2%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258794]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Data released by the National Bureau of Statistics on the 18th showed that preliminary calculations showed that China’s gross domestic product (GDP) in the first three quarters ) 91.3027 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 5.2% at constant prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at quarters, GDP grew by 4.5% year-on-year in the first quarter, 6.3% in the second quarter, and 4.9% in the third quarter. From a quarter-on-quarter perspective, GDP grew by 1.3% in the third quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sheng Laiyun, deputy director of the National Bureau of Statistics, said at a press conference of the State Council Information Office that day that in the first three quarters, faced with the complex and severe international environment and the arduous and arduous tasks of domestic reform, development and stability, various regions and departments Resolutely implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, focus on expanding domestic demand, boost confidence, and prevent risks, and the national economy continues to recover and improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall agricultural production situation is good, the recovery of industrial production is accelerating, and the service industry continues to recover rapidly. In the first three quarters, the added value of agriculture (planting industry) increased by 3.6% year-on-year; the added value of the national industrial enterprises above designated size increased by 4% year-on-year, 0.2 percentage points faster than the first half of the year; the added value of the service industry increased by 6% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Market sales tend to be active, the scale of fixed asset investment continues to expand, and the import and export of goods are generally stable. In the first three quarters, the total retail sales of consumer goods reached 34,210.7 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 6.8%. National fixed asset investment (excluding rural households) increased by 3.1% year-on-year; excluding the impact of price factors, it increased by 6% year-on-year. The total import and export of goods was 30.8021 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 0.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Consumer prices rose moderately, the employment situation was generally stable, and residents&#39; income grew steadily. In the first three quarters, the national consumer price index (CPI) rose by 0.4% year-on-year, and the national average urban surveyed unemployment rate was 5.3%. The per capita disposable income of residents across the country was 29,398 yuan, a nominal increase of 6.3% year-on-year; after deducting price factors, the real growth was 5.9%, 0.1 percentage point faster than the first half of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Overall, the national economy has continued to recover in the first three quarters, and high-quality development has been solidly advanced, laying a solid foundation for achieving the full-year development goals. However, it must also be noted that the external environment has become more The situation is complex and severe, domestic demand is still insufficient, and the foundation for economic recovery still needs to be consolidated.&quot; Sheng Laiyun said that in the next stage, we must do a good job in implementing the policies that have been introduced to achieve effective results, and continue to promote the continued improvement of economic performance, the continuous improvement of endogenous power, and the continuous improvement of social It is expected to continue to improve, risks and hidden dangers will continue to be resolved, and efforts will be made to achieve the economic and social development goals for the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“江浙沪独生女”人设走红，这届年轻人在羡慕什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjBk6gukrSbaP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;497&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/19/l7UKSj1ZmVAAXDqgQy1PA037zkzhjB k6gukrSbaP. png&quot; data-key=&quot;234648&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;audio id=&quot;contents-audio-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021999449192&quot; data-media=&quot;audio&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data -filename=&quot;The character of &quot;The Only Child in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; has become popular, what are the young people of this generation envious of.mp3&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/eefc5c5c5576678021999449192/lP12HWkcnngA.mp3&quot; width= &quot;320&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/eefc5c5c5576678021999449192/lP12HWkcnngA.mp3&quot;>;The character of &quot;The Only Girl in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; has become popular, and young people in this generation are envious What to admire.mp3 &lt;/audio>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/iPNpdssztWsPa7DOtPrzXsKHcua8QcQSXTH8ywrk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/iPNpdssztWsPa7DOtPrzXsKHcua8QcQSXTH8ywrk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254330&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align : center;&quot;>;In the imagination of netizens, the only daughter of a wealthy middle-class family in the Yangtze River Delta enjoys family resources and pampering, and her parents are open-minded enough. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Picture generated by &quot;AI Huitu&quot;/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearing the true story of southern and northern accents, and meeting social people who come from south to north, Hello Southern Weekend listeners, welcome to Southern Weekly’s podcast &quot;Social People&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, the &quot;only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; became popular on the Internet, becoming the most enviable female character template after &quot;Single Aunt&quot; and &quot;Runaway Wanyu&quot;. In the imagination of netizens, an only daughter born in a well-off middle-class family in the Yangtze River Delta enjoys the resources and love of her family. Her parents are open-minded enough, so she has the confidence to pursue career development and the capital to go home and settle down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, is this really the only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai? What will be the other side of returning under the wings of your parents and enjoying the protection of your family? What expectations do the two labels &quot;rich&quot; and &quot;only child&quot; carry for contemporary young people? Behind the changes in the female template, how are our attitudes towards life and work changing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this podcast, we invite two guests who are both &quot;only children from Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; to discuss the above issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;This issue’s guests&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/q9kAf3NBPcT6RCeg8LFU8qHTIoPL0B6dGhzEJTTN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/q9kAf3NBPcT6RCeg8LFU8qHTIoPL0B6dGhzEJTTN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254331&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Sun Lin (left), lecturer at the Chinese Studies Center of the Chinese University of Hong Kong and PhD in Anthropology, and Ge Shurun ​​(right), a doctoral candidate at the School of Journalism, Renmin University of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>; Listening tips: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►03:34 &amp;nbsp;“Someone will tell me the truth” is the very attractive part of this label&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ►06:22 &amp;nbsp;In the process of growing up, the only daughter born in the 1980s in Shanghai believed in trying things out&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►08:48 &amp;nbsp;The &quot;Pyramid of Filial Piety&quot; emphasizes cost-effectiveness&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ►11:51 &amp;nbsp;Interview with the elderly in Shanghai, almost no one expects their children to support them in old age&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►15:09 &amp;nbsp;Returning to the family character and independent character co-exist&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 20:25 &amp;nbsp;Changes in the external environment have made young people more in need of family to resist risks&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►25:46 &amp;nbsp;The labels of &quot;Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; and &quot;only child&quot; hide some social prejudices&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;►29:06 &amp;nbsp;In addition to money, the &quot;only daughter in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai&quot; also emphasizes the emotional support of the family&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►31:02 &amp;nbsp;Different female templates are pursued by different people. Or is it a conflict between ideals and reality&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►35:22 &amp;nbsp;The label also ignores the obligations and responsibilities that an only child will face&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;►39:29 &amp;nbsp;Enlightened parents will also Giving hints on &quot;should you come back and take the civil service exam?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Editors: Wang Yixuan, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Operators: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第134届广交会开幕，新能源汽车备受外商关注]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258778]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院副秘书长近期密集调整：4人履新，其中两名“69后”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 17, the official website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security announced that the State Council appoints and removes national staff. Among them, Sun Guangyu was appointed as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council; Wang Zhiqing was removed from the post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu previously served as a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management. Wang Zhiqing, who has resigned, has served as Chairman and Party Secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July this year, the deputy secretary-general of the State Council has been reshuffled frequently, with &quot;four in and four out&quot; - Sun Guangyu, Xu Shouben, Wang Zhijun, and Wang Yonghong have taken over, while Wang Zhiqing, Ding Xuedong, Peng Shujie, and Li Wenwen have stepped down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March this year, during the two sessions of the National People’s Congress, the leadership team of the central government changed, and State Councilor Wu Zhenglong also served as Secretary-General of the State Council. According to public reports, there are currently at least 7 deputy secretaries-general of the State Council, namely Meng Yang, Liu Jianbo, Guo Wei, Wang Zhijun, Wang Yonghong, Xu Shouben, and Sun Guangyu (in order of appointment). Among them, Wang Zhijun is clearly at the ministerial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The four new deputy secretaries-general of the State Council come from different fields&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The four new deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who took up their posts this year come from different fields. He is an expert in the field. Sun Guangyu has worked in the chemical industry for a long time and is an expert in the field of hazardous chemical safety supervision. Before taking up his new post, he served as a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management; Xu Shouben is a &quot;veteran&quot; in the financial industry and before taking up his new post, he served as the vice president of the China Development Bank. ; Wang Zhijun has been engaged in economic management work in central ministries and commissions for a long time, and served as deputy secretary of the Heilongjiang Provincial Party Committee before taking office; Wang Yonghong has long worked in the State Administration Bureau (referred to as the State Administration Bureau), serving for 32 years, and took office in June this year. Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Management Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The four new people are all born after 1965, among whom Wang Yonghong and Xu Shouben were both born in 1969. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab4cf05000a88ceabe1aaa8d69aa654f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ab4cf05000a88ceabe1aaa8d69aa654f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254335&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Guangyu. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu, who took office as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council today, was born in December 1966. He has a university degree, a master&#39;s degree in engineering, a professor-level senior engineer, and a member of the chemical industry group of the National Safety Production Expert Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Guangyu graduated from Dalian University of Technology, majoring in fine chemical engineering. According to the official website of Dalian University of Technology, he worked at Sinopec in his early years. In 2009, he was transferred from the manager of the Aromatic Hydrocarbons Department of the Tianjin Branch of Sinopec Co., Ltd. to the deputy director and director of the Safety Supervision and Management Department of the State Administration of Work Safety, and later served as the Hazardous Chemicals Department of the Emergency Management Department. Director of the Supervision Department and Director of the First Department of Hazardous Chemical Supervision. In June 2022, Sun Guangyu served as a member of the Party Committee and Vice Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, and later served as deputy director of the Office of the State Council Safety Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than a week ago, Sun Guangyu interviewed the main person in charge of the Ordos Municipal People&#39;s Government on behalf of the Security Affairs Office of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Ministry of Emergency Management, on September 7, a major high-pressure gas leak occurred at Yiding Ecological Agriculture Development Co., Ltd. in Ordos, Inner Mongolia, resulting in 10 deaths and 3 injuries in a major production safety accident. On September 14, the State Council Safety Committee decided to supervise the investigation and handling of this major accident. On September 11, the Ministry of Emergency Management organized a national emergency video conference on hazardous chemicals safety risk prevention, at which the situation of the Ordos &quot;9.7&quot; accident was reported. Sun Guangyu, member of the Party Committee and Vice Minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, attended the meeting and delivered a speech. The meeting pointed out that lessons from the accident must be carefully learned, and the lessons learned in blood must not be verified with blood again! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 8, in response to the &quot;9.7&quot; major high-pressure gas leakage accident in Ordos, the Office of the State Council Safety Committee interviewed the main person in charge of the Ordos Municipal People&#39;s Government. Sun Guangyu, deputy director of the Office of the State Council Security Committee and deputy minister of the Ministry of Emergency Management, presided over the interview, and heads of relevant departments and bureaus of the Ministry of Emergency Management attended the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Sun Guangyu has left the chemical industry and emergency management leadership position he held for many years and joined the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7985b31e8140d787488575eb9d4a9451.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;642&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/7985b31e8140d787488575eb9d4a9451.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254337&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Shouben. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Shouben took office as deputy secretary-general of the State Council on August 30. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Xu Shouben was born in April 1969 in Yantai, Shandong Province. He graduated from the School of Management of Harbin Institute of Technology and received a doctorate in Western Economics from Lingnan College of Sun Yat-sen University and is a senior economist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Shouben has worked in the financial industry for many years. He joined the Guangdong Branch of ICBC in April 1995. He has worked in various branches of ICBC in Guangdong Province for a long time. He once served as the Office Director of ICBC Guangdong Branch, President of Guangdong Jiangmen Branch, and Party committee secretary and other positions. In March 2011, he was appointed as the vice president of the Guangdong Branch and in July 2015, he was appointed as the president of the Shenzhen Branch. In August 2020, Xu Shouben was promoted to Vice President of ICBC. In October 2022, Xu Shouben was appointed as Vice President of the China Development Bank and will take office as the State Council in August this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9a7a2bf37812ce179a149e3d37af0258.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9a7a2bf37812ce179a149e3d37af0258.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254338&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Zhijun. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhijun and Wang Yonghong took up their posts on the same day and were appointed deputy secretary-general of the State Council on July 4. Among them, Wang Zhijun is in charge of the daily work of the General Office of the State Council and is clearly at the ministerial level. He is a member of the 20th Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public resume shows that Wang Zhijun was born in September 1965 in Hohhot, Inner Mongolia, and has a graduate degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhijun has been responsible for economic management for many years. He has served as the director of the National Economic Comprehensive Department of the National Development and Reform Commission, deputy inspector of the Comprehensive Group of the Office of the National Energy Leading Group, and deputy director of the Economic Bureau No. 1 of the Office of the Central Financial and Economic Leading Group. , inspector, director of the fifth economic bureau, director of the first economic bureau of the Office of the Central Financial and Economic Commission, etc. In January 2019, Wang Zhijun was appointed as a member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology. In April 2022, he was transferred to the position of Deputy Secretary of the Heilongjiang Provincial Party Committee, and he will assume the new position of the State Council in July this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/12331a6220040ce2b935ae78746a30e8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;768&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/12331a6220040ce2b935ae78746a30e8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254339&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Yonghong. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yonghong has worked in the State Administration of Institutional Affairs for a long time. The National Administration Bureau is an agency directly under the State Council that manages the affairs of state agencies. It is responsible for the management of funds, finances, official vehicles, state-owned assets and real estate of central state agencies, and is responsible for the management of life services for party and state leaders and relevant service objects within a designated range. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the State Administration of Management, Wang Yonghong was born in June 1969, with a bachelor&#39;s degree and a master&#39;s degree in management. He joined the National Bureau of Management in August 1991 and served successively as deputy director of the Financial Management Department, deputy director of the Logistics Reform and Comprehensive Management Department, director of the training center, director of the Financial Management Department, and director of the Dongba Service Center of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs; 2017 In April 2017, he was appointed as deputy director, member of the Party Leadership Group and director of the Dongba Service Center of the State Administration of Management. In November 2017, he was appointed as deputy director and member of the leading party group of the State Administration of Management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 20 this year, relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee attended the meeting of leading cadres of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs and announced the central government’s decision: Comrade Wang Yonghong was appointed as Party Secretary and Director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yonghong has assumed the new post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council and concurrently serves as Party Secretary and Director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. Previous directors of the State Administration of Management were also concurrently held by the deputy secretary-general of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Of the four deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who have resigned, three have assumed new duties&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Of the four deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who have resigned this year, three have assumed their new posts. new. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhiqing, who resigned as deputy secretary-general of the State Council today, has been appointed chairman and party secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group Co., Ltd. a week ago. Among the three deputy secretaries-general of the State Council who resigned on July 4, Ding Xuedong has served as Party Secretary of the National Council for Social Security Fund, and Li Wenwen has served as Deputy Minister of the Central Ministry of Social Work and Director of the Office of the Central Joint Conference on Petitions, and continues to serve concurrently as the National Petitions Bureau. Director of the Bureau and Secretary of the Party Leadership Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/a404a4b5f6cfd0bf0ae6ea00c5445207.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/a404a4b5f6cfd0bf0ae6ea00c5445207.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254336&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Zhiqing. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public resume shows that Wang Zhiqing was born in March 1966 and is from Tianjin. Wang Zhiqing has worked in the civil aviation system for a long time. He joined the Civil Aviation Administration of China in 1992 and held leadership positions in multiple departments. In March 2014, he was appointed deputy director of the Civil Aviation Administration of China. In March 2019, he was transferred to the position of member of the Party Leadership Group, Chief Planner, and Director of the Comprehensive Planning Department of the Ministry of Transport. In February 2021, he was promoted to Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Transport. In November 2021, Wang Zhiqing was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;China Eastern Airlines&quot; WeChat public account, on the morning of October 9, China Eastern Airlines Group Co., Ltd. held a meeting for middle-level and above managers. Relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China announced the decision of the Central Committee on the appointment of Chairman and Party Secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group Co., Ltd.: Comrade Wang Zhiqing is appointed as Chairman and Party Secretary of China Eastern Airlines Group Co., Ltd. China Eastern Airlines, headquartered in Shanghai, is one of China&#39;s three major state-owned backbone air transport groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 4, the State Council appointed and removed national staff. On the same day that Wang Zhijun and Wang Yonghong assumed the new deputy secretaries-general of the State Council, Ding Xuedong, Peng Shujie, and Li Wenwen were dismissed from their posts as deputy secretaries-general of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6ceff0fc8380678e866371cf8479ee40.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6ceff0fc8380678e866371cf8479ee40.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254334&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ding Xuedong. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ding Xuedong was a member of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. He served twice as deputy secretary-general of the State Council and served as executive deputy secretary-general of the State Council before resigning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the public resume, Ding Xuedong, born in February 1960 in Changzhou, Jiangsu Province, is a master&#39;s student in the Industrial Economics Department of Hubei Institute of Finance and Economics (now Zhongnan University of Economics and Law), and a finance major in the Graduate Department of the Institute of Fiscal Science of the Ministry of Finance. PhD in Economics, doctoral supervisor at the Institute of Fiscal Science of the Ministry of Finance. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has served in the Ministry of Finance for a long time, serving successively as Director of the Department of Basic Management of State-owned Capital Funds, Director of the Department of Agriculture, and Director of the Department of Education, Science and Culture. In November 2006, he served as Assistant Minister of Finance and Party Leadership Group Member, in March 2008, served as Deputy Minister of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2010, Ding Xuedong was appointed as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. In July 2013, he was appointed as Chairman and CEO of China Investment Corporation. In October 2014, he was concurrently appointed as Chairman of CICC. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2017, the State Council appointed Ding Xuedong as Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council (ministerial level). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 1 this year, the National Council for Social Security Fund held a meeting of leading cadres. Relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee announced the decision of the Central Committee: Comrade Ding Xuedong will be appointed Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the National Council for Social Security Fund. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9f291a1a848abe41791377c7b37e923b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9f291a1a848abe41791377c7b37e923b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254341&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Peng Shujie. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Shujie is a &quot;veteran&quot; in journalism. He was born in May 1963 in Bengbu, Anhui Province. He is a senior journalist and a master&#39;s degree candidate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to his public resume, Peng Shujie studied in the Department of Foreign Languages ​​of Anhui University and the Department of Journalism of the Graduate School of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences in his early years. In the 1990s, he was also sent to study abroad at the University of Hawaii in the United States. He joined Xinhua News Agency in 1989 and served successively as reporter and deputy director of Xinhua News Agency’s external central news gathering and editing office, deputy director and director of the external central foreign affairs news gathering and editing office, chief editorial assistant (deputy bureau level) of Xinhua News Agency’s chief editorial office, Xinhua News Agency He serves as deputy editor-in-chief of the editorial office and director of the International Department of Xinhua News Agency. In July 2014, he was promoted to deputy editor-in-chief and party member of Xinhua News Agency. In November 2015, he was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council and retired after serving for nearly 8 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6a8939ffa1eff6c6dabc5105a91be09f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;490&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/6a8939ffa1eff6c6dabc5105a91be09f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254340&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Wenwen. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public resume, Li Wenwen was born in January 1963. He graduated from the Department of Political Science and Law of Ningxia University and received a postgraduate degree from the Central Party School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He worked in Ningxia for a long time in his early years and served as deputy secretary of the Yinchuan Municipal Party Committee (department level), director of the Department of Justice and Party Secretary of the Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region; secretary of the Shizuishan Municipal Party Committee and Guyuan Municipal Party Committee secretary of the Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region. In June 2012, Li Wenzhang was promoted to the Standing Committee of the Party Committee of Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region and concurrently served as Secretary of the Guyuan Municipal Party Committee. In June 2015, he was appointed as member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee and Secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee of the Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region. In June 2016, he was appointed as member of the Standing Committee of the Liaoning Provincial Party Committee and secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee. In December 2018, he served as director of the Political Department of the Ministry of National Security, member of the Party Committee, secretary of the party committee of the agency, and deputy chief superintendent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2020, Li Wenwen assumed the new post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council, member of the Party Leadership Group of the State Council, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group, and Director of the State Bureau of Letters and Calls. It is worth noting that the past several directors of the State Bureau of Letters and Calls were also served concurrently by the deputy secretary-general of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 4 this year, Li Wenwen was removed from the post of Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. Ten days later, the information in the &quot;Leadership Introduction&quot; column of the National Bureau of Letters and Calls showed that Li Wenwen is currently the deputy minister of the Central Ministry of Social Work, the director of the Office of the Central Joint Conference on Letters and Calls, the director and the party secretary of the National Bureau of Letters and Calls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 16 this year, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Plan for the Reform of Party and State Institutions&quot;. In terms of institutional reform of the Party Central Committee, five new &quot;Chinese-prefixed&quot; institutions including the Central Department of Social Work were established. Among them, the Central Ministry of Social Work is responsible for coordinating and guiding the people&#39;s petition work, guiding the collection of people&#39;s suggestions, coordinating and promoting party building to lead grassroots governance and grassroots political power building, unified leadership of the party work of national industry associations and chambers of commerce, and coordinating and promoting the deepening reform and transformation of industry associations and chambers of commerce. Development, guiding the party building work of mixed-ownership enterprises, non-public enterprises, new economic organizations, new social organizations, and new employment groups, and guiding the construction of social work talent teams, etc., as a functional department of the Party Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Plan&quot; also clarifies that the Central Ministry of Social Work will unifiedly lead the National Bureau of Letters and Calls. The National Bureau of Letters and Calls, a national bureau managed by the General Office of the State Council, was restructured into an agency directly under the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What are the responsibilities of the Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to public reports, there are currently at least 7 deputy secretaries-general of the State Council, namely Meng Yang, Liu Jianbo, Guo Wei, Wang Zhijun, Wang Yonghong, Xu Shouben, and Sun Guangyu (in order of appointment). In addition to the four people who took up their new posts this year, the remaining three people: Meng Yang was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council in May 2015, Liu Jianbo was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council in May 2021, and Guo Wei was appointed Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council in July 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How many people are generally allocated to the Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council? According to the Chinese Government website, the State Council issued a &quot;Regulations on the Main Responsibilities, Internal Organizations and Staffing of the General Office of the State Council&quot; in July 2008, which mentioned that the administrative establishment of the General Office of the State Council is 519. Among them: 1 Secretary-General of the State Council, 9 Deputy Secretary-Generals of the State Council (including part-time ones), and 43 department-level leadership positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the responsibilities of the Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Working Rules of the State Council&quot; revised in March this year clearly mentioned that the State Council implements the prime minister&#39;s responsibility system. Under the leadership of the Prime Minister, the Secretary-General is responsible for handling the daily work of the State Council, and the Deputy Secretary-General assists the Secretary-General in his work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It mentioned that “the General Office of the State Council must carefully review and review the official documents submitted by various regions and departments to the State Council for review and approval. It involves the issuance of administrative normative documents in the name of the State Council or the General Office of the State Council, If administrative normative documents are issued in the name of a department after being submitted to the State Council for approval, the judicial administrative department of the State Council shall conduct a legality review. For matters that have disagreements between departments, the leading comrades of the State Council in charge of the sponsoring department shall take the lead in strengthening coordination. The Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council shall assist The leading comrades in charge of the State Council shall do a good job in coordination.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the review and review of relevant rules and documents, more specific information can be obtained from some of the concurrent positions held by the Deputy Secretary-General of the State Council. For example, Meng Yang is concurrently the deputy director of the State Council&#39;s Working Committee on Disabled Persons, the deputy leader of the State Council&#39;s First National Comprehensive Natural Disaster Risk Survey Leading Group, and the deputy convener of the State Council&#39;s inter-ministerial joint conference system for optimizing family planning policies. Liu Jianbo concurrently serves as deputy director of the National Narcotics Control Commission. Wang Yonghong concurrently serves as Party Secretary and Director of the State Administration of Institutional Affairs. In addition, Guo Wei is also a member of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and a member of the Agriculture and Rural Affairs Committee. Liu Jianbo is a member of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and a member of the Ethnic and Religious Affairs Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话许知远：梁启超和他诞生150年后的世界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258769]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Liang Qichao is our &quot;familiar stranger&quot;. In China, almost no one knows his name, but his vague image is limited to a reformist politician, the author of &quot;Young China&quot;, and a father who raised many outstanding children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Qichao was born in Chakeng Village, Xinhui County, Guangzhou Prefecture in 1873. In &quot;Autobiography at Thirty&quot;, Liang Qichao used major events in Chinese and world history to find coordinates for the year of his birth: it was the tenth year after the fall of the Taiping Rebellion, one year after Zeng Guofan&#39;s death, and the third year after the Franco-Prussian War ended. Of course, when he was born, the chronology was the twelfth year of Tongzhi, Guiyou. The AD calendar was not widely adopted until the founding of New China. It was through Liang Qichao that the sayings of the 19th and 20th centuries spread in the Chinese-speaking world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Qichao was one of the first Chinese to realize the turn of the century. At the beginning of 1900, he wrote &quot;The Song of the Pacific in the Twentieth Century&quot;, predicting that the new century would usher in the Pacific Age. Chinese people in the 19th century did not realize that they were in the 19th century. Only in the 20th century will we look back with the help of new historical coordinates to describe this era of sinking, humiliation and endeavor, and salvation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1898, after the failure of the Hundred Days Reform, Liang Qichao went into exile in Japan and traveled around the world. After the founding of the Republic of China, Liang Qichao returned to China, and the main stages of his activities were in the ice drinking rooms in the capital Beijing and Tianjin. For him, his hometown in Guangdong has become as far away as his boyhood. But this does not mean that he bid farewell to his hometown. In fact, many of Liang Qichao&#39;s activities in Yokohama, Japan, North America and Australia relied on the huge support of the overseas Chinese network in Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/YH8F41xHIdF3FC0Vzqv5AIn8UTkKPK3nlVfGX4Ax.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;765&quot; height= &quot;1055&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/YH8F41xHIdF3FC0Vzqv5AIn8UTkKPK3nlVfGX4Ax.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254309&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liang Qichao during his time in Japan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If we focus on those people who have no names in history, we will find that from ten Since the middle of the ninth century, a large number of Cantonese have gone to North America and Japan. The use of steamships has enabled Cantonese expatriates to no longer just go to Southeast Asia, but to travel across the Pacific to all parts of the world.&quot; &quot;Regional Culture and National Identity: Late Professor Cheng Meibao, author of &quot;The Formation of Guangdong Cultural Concepts since the Qing Dynasty,&quot; told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;There are traces of Cantonese in every port on the Pacific coast. They have established guilds, temples, hometown associations in foreign countries, or organized themselves in the form of companies. , so when Kang Liang, Sun Yat-sen and others were active overseas, someone would contact them and arrange accommodation and itinerary. Behind the activities of these historical celebrities are decades of preparation by unknown groups.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Many people have tried to write a biography of Liang Qichao. The historian Wu Qichang of the Republic of China wrote half of it until the Reform Movement of 1898; Xie Xizhang&#39;s &quot;Biography of Liang Qichao&quot; is divided into chapters based on Liang&#39;s interactions and relationships with different historical figures; the writer Wei Wei Before publishing the novel &quot;In the Misty Clouds&quot;, she spent several years writing a biography of Liang Qichao. When she had written more than 100,000 words, she felt that the thread was too complicated, so she put it down and started writing novels first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 is the 150th anniversary of the birth of Liang Qichao, and the second part of Xu Zhiyuan&#39;s &quot;Liang Qichao&quot; has also been published. The first part is titled &quot;Young Revolutionary&quot;, about Liang Qichao from 1873 to 1898, and was published in 2019. Xu Zhiyuan originally planned to write it in three parts, but now the writing plan has been expanded to five parts. The second part, &quot;Desperation&quot;, was written from 1898 to 1903. The complex historical clues and the many characters who interacted with the Liang family made Xu Zhiyuan feel that, It is necessary to expand his version of Liang Qichao&#39;s biography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Everyone is a contemporary.” This is how Xu Zhiyuan reminds his writing and the way each reader enters Liang Qichao’s world. Liang Qichao does not just belong to yesterday, maybe he also belongs to the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Luo Danni, the editor of the second part of &quot;Liang Qichao&quot; told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;Xu Zhiyuan&#39;s writing context is different from that of historians and scholars, not in response to a problem in a specific academic history context, but out of A very pure curiosity about another person. It is curiosity about how another scholar, who is also in a period of unknown changes between the old and the new, faces the changes and participates in them. So his Writing is a kind of writing that empathizes with others and has a sense of empathy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend conducted an exclusive interview with Xu Zhiyuan in a one-way space beside the Grand Canal in Hangzhou. Xu Zhiyuan is very busy. In addition to recording the program &quot;Thirteen Invitations&quot;, he is traveling to various cities to promote his new book. When a reporter asked how to balance Liang Qichao&#39;s ideological trajectory and social picture in the book, Xu Zhiyuan said: &quot;Sometimes I feel that there is too much about the era, and the era overwhelms the individual. Sometimes I feel that there is too much about the individual and lack of the era. Reflection, this is a process of constant searching.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/nlIotn1FEjTnSnyYbRhNNETePlneXvpjW1cgOyTs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/nlIotn1FEjTnSnyYbRhNNETePlneXvpjW1cgOyTs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254310 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In September 2023, Xu Zhiyuan talked about Liang Qichao in Hangzhou. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Pumpkin Vision)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I especially hope to have an ideological adventure with the protagonist Liang Qichao, and you don&#39;t know What will happen next? I have only written the second volume so far. His thoughts are still evolving. I am not willing to use hindsight to evaluate whether his thoughts have matured. During that time, he had Such a state of mind. I want to go back to the historical scene as much as possible to create some possibility. The writing process of this set of books does not mean that I started after 20 years of research, careful consideration, and a lot of understanding about it. Putting pen to paper, no. My understanding will continue to deepen as I write. For example, when I write the second volume, I understand him better than the first volume. When I write the third volume, I may understand him better than the second volume. But it is also possible that when you finish writing the last volume, you will realize that your initial understanding of his thoughts was not accurate because it is a larger framework.&quot; Xu Zhiyuan told a reporter from Southern Weekend. In a sense, Liang Qichao&#39;s world is already Xu Zhiyuan&#39;s parallel universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Constructing Liang Qichao’s world like a puzzle&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;There have been some previous works that discussed Liang Qichao from the perspective of intellectual history, such as &quot;Liang Qichao and Modern Chinese Thought&quot; by American scholar Levinson, &quot;Liang Qichao and the Transition of Chinese Thought (1890-1907)&quot; by Zhang Hao, etc., and you The main interest in writing a biography of Liang Qichao is to describe the social transformation experienced by Liang Qichao&#39;s generation. What do you think is the main difference between the two kinds of writing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The books by Levinson and Zhang Hao were the first books that influenced my interest in Liang Qichao, and they were of great ideological enlightenment to me. . Levinson puts Liang Qichao in a larger context to view his role in Chinese tradition, covering his life in a short space. Mr. Zhang Hao&#39;s book mainly discusses Liang Qichao&#39;s ideological process before 1907. About ten years ago, I met Mr. Zhang Hao in Washington, USA. I went to his home as a guest and had a couple&#39;s lung slices together. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are ideological biographies, and what I want to write is one that is more people-centered, literary, historical, and in a sense encyclopedic. Book. I spent a lot of pen and ink not only writing about Liang Qichao, but also his contemporaries, the spirit of the entire era behind him, the changes in China as a whole, the changes in Japan, and the changes in the world, so it is more like &quot;Liang Qichao and his era&quot; . I hope to regard Liang Qichao as a representative figure in the transformation process of global modernity. He belongs not only to the Chinese tradition, but also to the tradition of Asia and the world. Therefore, I want to describe the living space and scenes behind him. I wrote a lot about him as a doer. He is not only a thinker, but more importantly, a doer. I wanted to give him a more three-dimensional presentation using a modern biographical writing method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If we want to analyze his ideological trajectory more, we will add more discussion For this part, your writing method is to use historical data as much as possible and rarely discuss it. What is the reason for this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I try not to destroy the narrative rhythm. Whether the narrative has a sense of music or a logic, I try to follow the narrative itself. The structure, the characters gradually become fuller and more vivid on each page as each volume progresses. He has his own character, which I cannot completely control and regulate, and his character is made up of those realistic characters. It is composed of materials and perhaps some of my imagination in reorganizing materials. My subjectivity is completed in the preface. Once I enter the main text writing, I hope to hide my subjective emotions behind the words. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Reading the just-published second part of the biography of Liang Qichao When &quot;Desperation&quot; and &quot;Young Changemakers&quot; were published a few years ago, a large part of the reader&#39;s pleasure was that through your writing, you could build up a perception of the life experience of a part of the Chinese people more than a hundred years ago. For example, when scholars from Guangdong in the late Qing Dynasty went to Beijing to take exams, they took the sea route instead of land. They usually had to stop in Shanghai, so Shanghai naturally became a stage for their activities; for example, when they arrived in Beijing, they would stay in the hometown guild hall. What difficulties did you encounter when collecting these materials? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When collecting materials, one is to imagine his living space. For example, Liang Qichao is often abstracted into a simple ideological figure. Of course this is also very important, but he not only lived in an ideological context, but also lived in a realistic context. He was not only a thinker, but also an important witness and participant of that era, so for me, It became very important to create the context of that era. Only by better understanding the background of that era can it be easier to understand the excellence and difficulty of his actions. So I spent a lot of energy to construct the space of the times, to understand how a scholar or a scholar went to Beijing to take the exam, and what the daily life of a scholar was like. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only if you better understand the daily life of a scholar, for example, what kind of works he reads in Xuehaitang, will you understand the ideological context of his suddenly going to Japan and entering the Western context. Extraordinary. Therefore, I will describe the daily life of scholars, what it is like in Guangzhou and Beijing, and how to interact with people in the guild hall. I will rely on diaries and notes from that year, some records that seem to have nothing to do with Liang Qichao, to create a world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am very influenced by Shi Jingqian in this regard. You see when he wrote &quot;The Death of Wang&quot;, Wang did not have any records, but he used Pu Songling&#39;s novels to imagine what Shandong was like back then. The living atmosphere of the Qing Dynasty at that time. I also relied heavily on such notes and even novels at the time to construct such an atmosphere, including other candidates&#39; daily records. The second volume is to create a time and space of Tokyo, Yokohama, and Melbourne from the late 19th to the early 20th century. , but also to travel through this world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was young, I liked to read all kinds of miscellaneous books. This is the role of miscellaneous books. For example, I have read a lot of books on Australian history, and when I was writing, to describe Sydney in 1900, I had to collect a large amount of newspaper documents from that time, and probably only used a few strokes. What was the Australian overseas Chinese leader Mei Guangda like at that time? What is the situation of the Ye family in Vancouver? You need to go through all kinds of strange information, just like doing a puzzle, it may not be complete, try to put together as many pieces as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For example, if you write about the relationship between Liang Qichao and his wife, and how he There is very little information about a fruitless love affair in Hawaii. On the one hand, he is a precocious cultural star with social prestige that is not commensurate with his age. On the other hand, he seems to be a person who does not need an affair between his children and his wife. Don&#39;t travel with him or stay with him. Today&#39;s readers would have a hard time understanding this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was a male-centered era. For these scholars who took the world as their own responsibility, although family was very important, it was often neglected by them. The narrative is ignored and few records are left. Including overseas Chinatowns, it is basically a male world. Except for overseas Chinese leaders who may bring their wives with them, most of their families stay in their hometowns in Guangdong and Fujian. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Qichao has been wandering around the world and has a huge emotional void. He will reveal his anxiety, loneliness and frustration in poetry. He wrote 24 love poems depicting Only when his strong feelings for Miss He are placed in such a time and space can his emotions be easily understood. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kang Youwei&#39;s emotions were even richer. He went into exile, married different wives, and had various affairs. Liang Qichao&#39;s wife&#39;s brother was his examiner. This was a family that was kind to him. However, because of his actions, his wife and the whole family were involved in danger and panic. He felt a lot of guilt in it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can we say that Liang Qichao is a relatively ascetic person? Zhang Hao&#39;s book talks about &quot;self-denial&quot;, and self-denial also includes the aspect of abstinence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Liang Qichao is very emotional and very self-disciplined. His enthusiasm and desire have been greatly reflected in his actions and writing. display. If you think about it, he has written so many works and done so many things in a short period of time, ranging from political organizations to founding magazines, and covering everything from political economy to how to write novels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The psychological motivations of many people constitute the driving force of history&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You say that Liang Qichao may be China&#39;s earliest global traveler, but Chinese literati have no habit of paying attention to details such as food, clothing, housing, transportation, customs, and landscapes during the journey. How did you add these details? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;He himself has written part of his story about seasickness across the Pacific and his experiences in New York and the United States. I still need to read the newspapers of that year to see how American and Australian history described the country and society at that time, mixed with Liang Qichao&#39;s personal experiences and feelings, to form the world in his eyes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Before Liang Qichao, Huang Zunxian also followed his diplomacy Activities, living in Japan, the United States, and Singapore for a long time. What role did the networks of overseas Chinese in Guangdong play in their travels? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Cities on both sides of the Pacific gathered many Cantonese people, forming a network of funds and ideas. This network supported the revolutionaries in modern China . Without the overseas network of Cantonese people, many things would not have happened, and Kang Liang would not have been able to play such an important role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then why were these revolutionaries not born in Fujian? There are also many overseas immigrants from Fujian. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;On the one hand, it is related to the birth of outstanding figures, on the other hand, Hong Kong has played an important role. Hong Kong is a place where new ideas radiate. At the same time, Guangzhou is also a cultural center, and interesting cultural tension and cultural dynamics have been formed between Hong Kong and Guangzhou. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao’s travels in Australia and the United States attract you the most What is the place? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is his interaction with the local society and how to stimulate the local people’s interest and enthusiasm for his political ideas, so I spent A lot of time was spent trying to find out how the local Chinese reacted to Liang Qichao. I was very happy to find a piece of material. When Liang Qichao gave a speech in Seattle, a Japanese student happened to record the grand occasion of everyone in the Chinese Theater enjoying Liang Qichao&#39;s speech. This description is very important to me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thing that interests me is the differences between the different Chinese worlds. For example, in Melbourne, San Francisco, and Vancouver, the Chinese communities in each city have their own characteristics, and these characteristics will also be reflected in their attitudes towards exiles. Including the divisions and tensions within Chinese society, what wealthy businessmen want to gain from the Royalist Society, and what ordinary people want to gain. Everyone has complex psychological motivations, and these psychological motivations constitute the driving force of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What new observations do you have about today’s overseas Chinese? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We can see the overlapping waves of immigrants. They will leave different legacies. On the one hand, there is the old-fashioned Chinatown composed of Cantonese people. On the other hand, changes can be seen in the diet. Nowadays, overseas Chinese food not only includes Cantonese cuisine, but also more and more Sichuan cuisine. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The most important mode of transportation in that era was Ships, the risks of shipping, the long time, and the pain of seasickness are difficult for today&#39;s travelers to understand. Have you ever experienced or planned a long-distance ship ride? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, it is difficult to have. The sense of time at that time was different from ours now. They may have thought that it was normal to cross the ocean by boat in a month. Because they don&#39;t have planes. The sense of time is all relative. For them, taking a boat from Yokohama to Hawaii in 10 days is already very fast. Liang Qichao experienced an era when the earth suddenly shrunk and accelerated. He was able to travel to many different states and countries in such a short period of time. This was a brand new experience. Changes in the sense of time and modernity were very important to the formation of Liang Qichao’s thoughts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today’s readers must understand Liang Qichao’s era. Where are the barriers and difficulties? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think it may not be that difficult to understand daily life. After all, although the rhythm of daily life is different, it is not that difficult either. grasp. It is very difficult to understand the changes in his thoughts. He suddenly went from a young man who read the Four Books and Five Classics, or who only read a few words about the outside world from the &quot;Global Gazette&quot;, to enter Japan in the late Meiji period and face so many different things. The impact of ideas, from social Darwinism to liberalism and constitutional monarchy, as well as novels, science, and economics, all of these things are coming at him. How can he understand such a new world, that kind of explosion of ideas? Of course, we are now in an era of great technological changes, and there are many unfamiliar terms that we do not know, but after all, we have received some training in modern education. At least these new changes are carried out along the basis and context of modern education. Liang Qichao and others were trained by It is traditional education. This huge impact on the thoughts and feelings is a process that is difficult to describe. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It’s like you were trained in Newtonian mechanics, and you are suddenly thrown into the world of quantum mechanics. How does it feel? When we describe such changes in thought, we cannot always think with hindsight that those nouns have become fixed common sense. Those nouns themselves were created by Liang Qichao and others. Through the translation of Japanese, we can wonder whether this new word is It is available, and I have to start using it without even having time to think too much. If I want to tell others about it, I think it is a very panic process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A big paradox or challenge in writing the biography of Liang Qichao is, Many of the concepts and vocabulary we Chinese use today were originally created by Liang Qichao, but we have to use the words he created to repeat him like a &quot;tail-biting snake&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;So how to return to the strangeness at that time is a question. I hope to depict the process of thought change, not the solidified thought itself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In other words, in addition to &quot;contemporaneity&quot; , we also have a huge difference in civilization paradigm from more than a hundred years ago. This difference is first reflected in our education and our relationship with tradition. Perhaps it is a huge challenge to present such subtle yet ubiquitous differences? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You must use some imagination and empathy. Of course, imagination has its limits, and misunderstandings are bound to occur during the writing process. Perhaps misunderstanding itself is also a very important motivation that history has given us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Write a biography of Liang Qichao in 2023, it must be Written by someone in 2023. By 2053, someone else can write it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It must be with this generation’s awareness of the issues, including the material you choose, it must be the material that triggers your mood at the moment. will choose it. So it has a strong presentness, a bit like translation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a concept of translation that means literary classics It should be re-translated every fifty years, and every time it is re-translated, it must use the literary vocabulary and daily language of this era. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For a character like Liang Qichao, he should indeed be constantly rewritten. Not only Liang Qichao, but also Yan Fu and Cai Yuanpei, the fathers of modern China, are worthy of being rewritten by every generation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Back to the fact that Liang Qichao is our contemporary In this way, whether we quote Liang Qichao or go back to Lu Xun today, are we responding to the current dilemma that we have no answers to many questions? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Thoughts need the historical dimension. Without the historical dimension, your thoughts will be very frivolous or rootless. So when I wrote it, it was of course a certain response to the present, and at the same time it was also about finding a certain historical context and framework for current issues. Within this historical framework, it is easier for you to understand your current feelings. To me, all time and space are intertwined. In fact, Liang Qichao’s influence has not disappeared, it still permeates our lives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;China should have a kind of historical writing that combines ideological and literary nature&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic style , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What inspirations did Liang Qichao’s choices in the face of great changes and various difficult ideological problems give you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Without the opportunity to think carefully, everyone has to act with insufficient information. I like the spirit of action in him. Action is also a way of thinking, and action constantly confirms the limitations and possibilities of thought. The most powerful thing about Liang Qichao is that he lets actions verify or expand his thoughts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao would prefer Wang Yangming to Zhu Xi. Liang Qichao felt that Wang Yangming&#39;s spirit of integrating knowledge and action had a huge impact on Japan&#39;s reformers from the late Edo period to the Meiji Restoration. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because Wang Yangming is a release of personal subjectivity. Then individuals can shape themselves. This ability is very powerful and can directly affect the environment and the times, inspiring many people with great ambitions. Liang Qichao must have been deeply affected by this, because he was in a state of exile, where everything was full of uncertainty, and personal initiative became crucial. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao is a scholar, media worker, and As an educator and author, which of his identities attracts you the most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, there is another identity as a politician. I think he is first of all a writer, and his other actions are constantly unfolding. Those roles are also very important to him, but the writer is the role that can best display everything about him and display his talents. Liang Qichao is a writer of the Encyclopedia School, an Enlightenment thinker in the era of transition. His writing is like Japan&#39;s Fukuzawa Yukichi, or Voltaire, Rousseau, and Diderot during the French Enlightenment. It touches every aspect and can be used in words. exert a very direct political and social influence. His era was also going through the process of the formation of various modern disciplines in China. Liang Qichao was involved in it, and then he had the style of a Chinese literati. In such a transitional era, his writing was very mixed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have a lot of media work experience, and you will know Liang Are you particularly interested in Qichao editing newspapers and magazines? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Writing a biography, of course the author will have a subtle influence on you. Liang Qichao and I are separated by a hundred years. He was born in 1873 and I was born in 1976. There may be a subconscious echo. But what I am more interested in is that from the 19th century to the 20th century, during China&#39;s dramatic transformation and entry into the modern world, Liang Qichao was a representative of the spiritual world, and his extensive social participation also provided a rich sample. Next, I want to write a biography of Li Hongzhang. His character and experience are completely different from mine. I hope to describe that historical stage, China&#39;s difficulties in entering the world stage in the 19th century, and personal failures. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao was the bridge from the 19th century to the 20th century. Li Hongzhang is the elegy of China&#39;s 19th century. You were the editor-in-chief of &quot;Oriental History Review&quot;. &quot;Oriental History Review&quot; pays great attention to the history of China and its surrounding areas, and Chinese overseas immigrants. Writing biographies of modern historical figures is also an extension of this interest, right? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After writing the biography of Liang Qichao and Li Hongzhang, I also want to write the biography of Lin Yutang. The three of them represent the power of the Chinese people. ), idea (concept), and identity (identity). It is estimated that I can write it until I am eighty years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have always liked the style of such a magazine. It is a carrier between the academy and mass media. It is very readable, but has a strong academic background behind it, and the subject matter is also very widely. I have always had a strong passion for history. Influenced by Shi Jingqian, I think there should be a kind of historical writing that combines ideological and literary aspects. Historical and biographical writing should be a very important intellectual product of ours. Some eras are the era of poetry, some eras are the era of novels, some eras may be the era of prose or travel writing, and I hope there are still some eras that belong to history and biography writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said that one-way space was opened in Japan, and you also wrote the biography of Liang Qichao As a by-product, what are the difficulties of opening a bookstore in a foreign country? In particular, Japan is a country with a well-developed bookstore and publishing industry and a self-contained system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Talking about by-products is actually a joke. I was trapped in Japan due to the epidemic in 2020, so I wanted to do something. As a result, I was in Tokyo The landlord became a partner in the bookstore. Although there are many bookstores in Japan, there are no good contemporary Chinese bookstores. Seventy percent of the one-way space in Tokyo is Chinese books, and there are also Japanese, English, and Korean books, so it is also an Asian bookstore concept. Just like One Direction in China, it will provide salon activities and is a place for communication. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course there are many difficulties. It is not easy to find a place in Ginza, and the cost is relatively high. I haven’t figured out its business logic yet. In China&#39;s one-way space, we are the exporter and manager of brands. We do not rely on retail to make profits. We are more like a cultural company in a comprehensive sense. This is not the business logic in Tokyo. It depends on whether it can continue to be supported, so it is a very reckless product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Bookstores in the late Qing Dynasty and the Republic of China often had the function of publishing, which was also a new As an information distribution center, have you considered echoing this tradition through one-way space? In the current mobile Internet era, what special role do bookstores play? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;A bookstore is not only a physical space for knowledge storage, but also a place where people gather, knowledge flows, and ideas are produced. It is actually a spiritual place. Community support is very important. Our Tokyo store is launching a membership program, hoping that members can find a sense of community. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In a sense, books and print media have It is called a sunset industry. The &quot;Thirteen Invitations&quot; you made on streaming media has more attributes that correspond to the new media of Liang Qichao&#39;s era. How do you think the two have different meanings to you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In fact, they are not that big of a difference in nature. They are both expressions of thoughts. Of course, different media have different media characteristics. For example, writing is an older medium. It has a closer relationship with my personal heart and my thoughts. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Making videos is a product of the team. It can express a certain part of me, but it is often a collective expression. The same goes for companies. In the company, I am one of the founders or the soul, but its entire operation is often beyond my control, and even a process that gradually gets out of control. Writing a book is an act that you can control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Chinese scholar-bureaucrats, they might print some collections of poems and essays by themselves, so in Liang Qichao’s generation, magazines and newspapers were their super new media, with a new issue published every ten days. Tens of thousands of people can see that this impact is very direct and quickly forms a resonance effect. Most of Liang Qichao&#39;s articles are published in newspapers and magazines, which is really like doing live broadcasts and videos now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;And Liang Qichao also faced situations where he lost control, such as a conflict with Wang Kangnian etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, and then he was deceived by the accountant, and the fund-raising was not smooth. He also has to consider operational issues, revenue pressure, pay dividends to shareholders, and what to do if the printing factory catches fire. People tend to overlook one thing. Liang Qichao was a serial entrepreneur. After running &quot;Qingyi Daily&quot;, he started &quot;Xinmin Series&quot;, and then &quot;New Novel&quot; and Guangzhi Bookstore. Moreover, he found investment in both of them, as editor and chief writer. , accounting for 20% to 40% of the shares. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao is mainly a writer and editor. You In addition to content production, there are many commercial activities. Are you bothered by the energy these activities take up? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course sometimes it distracts the energy, but sometimes it also promotes each other, because when you are filming a show or participating in many things in the company, When you are writing, you are often frustrated and distracted, and of course you are also very excited, but when you write, you return to your more focused self. I think that is the avoidance and avoidance of other lives, and some of the chaos you face in daily life. and loss of control, you can also bring it into the book to help you better understand Liang Qichao&#39;s world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Some historical materials have been doubted, and I tried my best to present this doubt&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao created a new style of language through his extensive writing. Our current grammar and language style are influenced by a large number of foreign translations. Some people say that your writing is &quot;translation style&quot;. What do you think of this problem? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Our generation is greatly influenced by translation. Many of the books we read are translated, and we feel the style of translation. of novelty. In fact, Liang Qichao is also a translator and is influenced by many Japanese influences. Not to mention the language of Lu Xun and others during the May Fourth period. The sense of language in our vernacular is produced under the influence of translation, and I feel that there is no longer a pure style that is not affected by foreign languages. In fact, the most important thing is whether you can find the pleasure of reading. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are an experienced media writer. We attach great importance to the readability of public writing, but writing a biography of Liang Qichao requires reference to a large number of academic works and historical materials. Are you worried that for ordinary readers, your biography of Liang Qichao is too difficult, and for academic circles, the information density is not enough? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For scholars, the density of information is also very high. If you look at the various papers we publish, many of them don’t have much information density. When I wrote the biography of Liang Qichao, I used a lot of new materials, but I wanted it to be highly readable at the same time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are some historical materials, such as Feng Ziyi&#39;s &quot;Revolution&quot; &quot;Yi Shi&quot;, its reliability has been questioned by many academic circles, but Feng Ziyi&#39;s interpretation is very dramatic. How do you deal with this type of historical data? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Some historical materials have been doubted, and I will try my best to show the doubts they have received. Although many of Feng Ziyi&#39;s stories are based on hearsay, many historical materials at that time were based on hearsay, and even less precise materials constituted an important part of the field of that era. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The legend about Liang Qichao, or many legends about his contemporaries, are also historical materials at that time. There is no completely pure hard fact. Just like the two of us talking here today, this A lot of information is being generated in the middle, but it&#39;s not necessarily accurate information. So I think that to understand this diversity of history, the references and doubts about the material itself, you give it a space to unfold, and the readers themselves will feel it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao believed that the 20th century was the era of national imperialism. His thoughts have a strong color of social Darwinism. How do you view the impact of his ideological tendency on future generations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think each generation must solve the problems of each generation. We cannot ask one generation to solve the problems 100 years from now. The prophet will see what his dilemma is, but for Liang Qichao&#39;s generation, the reality he faces is that the country has been humiliated and has entered the bottom of history. Prosperity and strength are their most important goals, and they believe that modern nation-states are participating in The most important role in global competition, so they have to shape a modern nation-state. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for its inherent contradiction and the oppressiveness it may produce, it developed gradually. Zhang Taiyan is more sensitive to this issue. Liang Qichao may also feel this part, but he has his own urgency. The characteristics of each thinker are different, so we cannot require every thinker to make urgent choices and have long-term considerations. Weber saw something longer-term and saw the side of modernity as an iron cage. He was a greater thinker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I think thinkers can only bear the responsibility of thinkers. The formation of an ideological concept in history and its influence on us not only come from the thinkers themselves, but also come from the shaping of subsequent social and educational systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Liang Qichao wandered between traditional Chinese culture and Western knowledge. Most of his descendants are experts in archaeology, aerospace and other fields. But today, our dilemma is that the disciplines are too specialized and territorial, and there is an increasing lack of comprehensive humanities intellectuals like Liang Qichao. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;With the subdivision of disciplines, vertical and horizontal thinkers are scarce not only in China but also around the world. Maybe when the times undergo new and huge changes, everyone is eager for the emergence of comprehensive thinkers. For example, why do so many people around the world want to read Harari&#39;s work? It is not very great or profound, but it has a certain comprehensiveness. He has put forward some kind of response to the pressing issues at hand. This response It will attract a lot of attention. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In public perception, Liang Qichao is a popular figure. A highly narrow-minded person, this year marks the 150th anniversary of his birth, and the biography of Liang Qichao is certainly an important effort to change the public&#39;s understanding of him. Among his numerous writings, which do you think are the most worthy of reading by today’s readers? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Liang Qichao wrote 14 million words, which is very complicated. His experience is as important as his works. His intellectual history works, including three hundred years of scholarship in the Qing Dynasty, as well as essays such as &quot;Young China Theory&quot; and &quot;New People Theory&quot;, are worthy of constant re-reading. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Compared with Liang Qichao, the public’s appreciation of Lu Xun’s works Reading is much more comprehensive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xu Zhiyuan: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The 20th century is a revolutionary century, and Lu Xun is remembered as a revolutionary writer. Liang Qichao has long been considered a representative of the forces of reform, which was suppressed by the revolutionary narrative. In fact, in Liang Qichao&#39;s era, he was a national writer. From people older than him to his contemporaries, to the next generation of Chen Duxiu, Mao Zedong, and Hu Shi, everyone was reading him. In addition, Liang Qichao&#39;s writing is still in the process of stylistic transformation, while Lu Xun and others have already explored a new way of writing in vernacular. In fact, it is not only Liang Qichao who has been narrowed down, but our understanding of Cai Yuanpei and Lin Yutang is far from enough, so I think more writers should join in the work of re-evaluating and rediscovering them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[叶刘淑仪：“丝绸之路也是全球的品牌”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258784]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/sAEEcUCZ7RvT5tZhDpeM5D15uS9EHUx2Qb4IjhcZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;539&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/sAEEcUCZ7RvT5tZhDpeM5D15uS9 EHUx2Qb4IjhcZ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254332&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yip Liu Shuyi, who wears many hats, is still making waves in the political arena. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before accepting the exclusive interview with Southern Weekend, Ip Liu Shuyi handed over four business cards with the titles of &quot;Member of the Legislative Council&quot; &quot;Chairman of the New Democratic Party&quot;, &quot;Convener of the Unofficial Members of the Hong Kong Executive Council&quot; and &quot;Co-Chairman of the Maritime Silk Road Association&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These identities occupy most of her time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为立法会议员，叶刘淑仪在在议会上质询官员时，官员称都要“打起十二分精神”。因为官员面对的，是一位曾经在政府体制中摸爬滚打了几十年的前高官，对香港情况了如指掌。作为香港新民党主席，叶刘淑仪曾称要推动香港发展优质民主，竭力为香港市民服务。繁忙的事务、频繁的曝光率，身兼数职的叶刘淑仪，仍然在政坛上，书写风云。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，对这位香港特区首位出掌纪律部门的女性，人们评价褒贬不一。支持她的人认为，她担任香港保安局局长期间，在《公安条例》争议、居港权问题、入境事务大楼纵火案等多起事件中处事果断、作风硬朗和建树良多，是不可多得的“香港铁娘子”。但也正是这种硬朗作风，引来不少反对的声音。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她还曾在2012年和2016年两次宣布参选香港特首。虽然都以惜败告终，但参选口号“赢返香港”依然让不少港人为之振奋。参选过程中，叶刘淑仪一再强调“如果当选，将率先处理香港核心管治问题”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她如何看待香港在海上丝绸之路上的独特作用，对香港的发展又有怎样的期待？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;串起&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;全球&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“朋友圈”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;香港作为海上丝绸之路联盟城市之一，具有地理优势。香港该如何利用海上丝绸之路促进香港经济的发展，串起“朋友圈”？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我创办的海上丝绸之路协会是在2015 年成立的，是共建“一带一路”倡议提出后最早回应倡议的香港组织。丝绸之路是中国很重要的品牌，也是个全球的品牌。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实中国是最早推动全球化，对外开放的。张骞通西域是一次伟大的远征，搭建起了连接世界的桥梁。香港的地理位置在南方，也是海上丝绸之路一个非常重要的节点。历史上，自中国出海的中国商船，或回航的蕃舶，多会待冬季东北风发之便，经香港屯门出海，南驶中南半岛及南洋群岛，再到印度及波斯湾等地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丝绸之路就是一个非常重要的文化符号，应该多利用软力量向年轻人推广。比如我们安排免费的电影如《大唐玄奘》给观众欣赏，讲述商人把中国的蚕桑带到西域，也把西域一些葡萄产品带到中国这种交流的历史。利用这种软力量，帮助香港年轻人理解中国伟大的发展历史，以及深厚的文化底蕴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港社会还有一个特色，就是很多华侨，包括很多东南亚的大家族在香港都有分支。香港跟东南亚的关系非常好。比如菲律宾大部分是福建人，新加坡有福建、潮州客家人，泰国也是很多潮州人，商业的来往非常频密。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以我觉得我们应该成立一个协会、联盟，连结海丝会沿岸的省市以及东南亚的国家。创办的时候，希望能在人心相通方面多做工夫，也希望能够教育香港年轻人多理解中国伟大的历史文化。所以协会部分重要的活动，都会安排一些年轻的大学生去海丝地区的国家走走。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这就是“张骞计划”吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，学习当年张骞勇敢的开创精神。我们成立的时候，荷兰商会的会长很感兴趣，“一带一路”的终点是欧洲的鹿特丹，所以他也有兴趣加入。我们还安排了大学生到内地的广西、广东，以及东南亚的国家，如泰国、马来西亚、新加坡。另外还去了东非吉布提、欧洲伦敦。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得一提的是，应希腊一个小岛的邀请，我们安排了负责中国文化的老师暑期到希腊宣传中国文化，教中文，也很受欢迎。但是疫情原因，停滞了三年，今年我们又重新启动，也得到很多企业的支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这个计划最高的时候派了一百个学生出去。今年大致有多少人？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;今年也起码有一百人了。因为陆陆续续有很多的中外企业参与支持，让大学生有机会去学习、实习，开阔眼界。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了“张骞计划”，海上丝绸之路协会还有什么样的工作思考？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们开展了很多论坛，包括不同的国家以及东南亚国家的论坛。我们的目的，是希望扩大朋友圈。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;软力量”推动中国文化&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如今，湾区的融合互动越来越大，作为海上丝绸之路的协会主席，你有什么相关的计划和设想？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;李特首已经举行了上任以后第一次的粤港研习会议，其中加强科技、金融，人才的交流，文化的加强和交流也非常重要。澳门是海上丝绸之路的一部分，我们也想跟澳门加强合作。同时，希望将来安排多点学生去大湾区学习考察、加深他们对岭南文化的理解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在香港学生对海上丝绸之路的文化，包括中国传统文化的熟悉程度和理解，达到什么样的程度?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得比较遗憾的，是香港的教改。 2009年推出的教改，我觉得走错了路，就好像台湾一样，把中国文化的元素大大减少。因为中史不是必修课，五万多个高考生只有五千人学习中史，学习世界史更少于五千人，学习中国文化典籍的考生只有两千人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我本身是念英国人的学校，但我小时候也念过很多的典籍，包括《经史子集》都读过一点点，现在的学生大部分都没有接触过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们安排了内地春节期间热映的《满江红》给年轻人免费观赏，但是他们不知道故事是发生在什么样的历史背景下，反响也一般。所以我觉得是教育出了问题，但现在已经加强中国历史典籍的教育传授，加强中史以及国情教育的传授，这些具有非常重要的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“香港未来的前途跟中国密不可分”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;作为汇贤智库的负责人，也是海上丝绸之路协会的负责人，同时还是立法委员，也曾担任保安局局长。通过综合身份，你怎么看香港的未来？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很多香港人都不明白，但也越来越多人在明白、觉醒。其实二十多年前，香港还没有回归祖国时，新加坡总理李光耀来香港考察时说，“香港未来的前途跟中国密不可分。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;确实，香港跟国家是风雨同路的。所以我们也很感谢国家不断地支持香港，香港今天稳定安全的局面得来不易。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，虽然《国安法》平息了2019年的骚乱，但是仍然有一些敌对的势力在香港蠢蠢欲动，所以还需要提高警惕。香港还没有为《基本法23条》立法，而澳门已经在2009年完成了这项工作。所以李特首已经表态，这是一个非常重要且需要优先的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你怎么看待香港的危机和机遇?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;中国有五千多年历史，国家有非常古老的一面，也有非常现代先进的一面。比如有部电影《流浪地球》，就充分地表现了中国在科技方面的发展，包括航天方面的不凡成就。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们要向香港年轻人多介绍中国各方面的成就。现在香港有故宫文化博物馆，是一个非常重要的传播载体。另外，香港也举办了如“三星堆”展览，我希望将来能有多一点中国现代化方面的成就在香港展示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实内地文化软力量很厉害。现在很多年轻人包括一些在外国留学的年轻人，也非常喜欢看内地的电视剧，内地的偶像顶流在香港也有市场，而且他们的水平很高。比较现代化的街舞等表演在香港很受年轻人的欢迎，我也希望香港的文化表演团体，能有机会到内地演出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我听说今年过春节时，有一部非常卖座的电影《毒舌律师》是律政片，在内地很受欢迎，所以期待将来香港与内地能在文化方面多点交流。香港是个中西文化交流的中心，我希望未来在这方面，无论是新民党、海上丝绸之路协会，都能为此多做一点贡献。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“超级联系人”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;新民党的主要成员基本上是精英阶层，而且是中产阶级偏上。作为新民党主席，你怎么看待新民党的作用？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;新民党于2011年1月9日在香港正式举行成立典礼，当时只有我一位议员。但在2021年的大选中，我们赢了3个议席，又在2022年的补选中多赢了一个议席。所以新民党现在已经有6位立法会议员，1位区议员。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同的政党都有不同的代表性。当年创党，是因为我觉得香港有一大部分的市民如中产阶级的市民、在国外接受教育的市民，以及思想比较西化的市民，他们都很爱国爱港，但没有党派为他们发声。所以新民党吸纳这些人员，教育水平也都比较高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我跟黎栋国（前保安局局长）是前官，所以我俩有很多公务员支持，包括纪律部队；容海恩议员是一位大律师；李梓敬在美国受过高等教育；陈家珮由地区直选。 2022年补选的、赢得一席的何敬康是澳门原特首何厚铧先生的侄儿，他可以协助我们加强跟澳门的联系，而且他也是留英留美的，非常理解西方的文化价值，有助香港发挥“中介人”“超级联络人”的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;香港特区政府成立以后，你是首位女性保安局局长，现任特首李家超也是保安局局长出身。你们之间有没有怎样的交流与合作？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;叶刘淑仪：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我跟李家超特首的交往很有趣。我当香港保安局局长时，李家超是有组织及严重罪案调查科的主管，当时他的外号就是“神探”，因为其心思非常缜密。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论他当保安局局长还是当特首，我也跟他合作得很好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在立法会发言前，我会询问李家超一些材料，形成工作默契，为现在的工作配合打下基础。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李特首有一个非常好的本领，他很愿意夸奖他的下属。工作表现好的时候，很愿意表扬他们，肯定其贡献。而且他能团结公务员、议员、行政会议成员。所以李特首上任之后，我们的氛围很好。我觉得2023 年真的是香港随着国家经济复苏，值得拼搏的一年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国内首部放生法规将生效：科学放生才是行善丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258752]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;国内第一部专门规范野生动物放生的地方性法规《广州市野生动物放生管理规定》，将自2023年11月1日起实施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;放生，在佛道两教中都是“善行”。佛教《梵网经》有言，“佛子应以慈心行放生之业……若见世人杀畜生时，应方便救护，解其苦难。”道教经典中也有《放生文》《杀生七戒》等劝人不杀生、放生的经文。中国佛道两教信徒众多，因此放生的事近年来也越来越多。但是，不科学的盲目放生，不仅不能给被放生的动物带来好处，还有可能造成生态灾难，有必要对放生活动进行规范。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州市人大制定的放生管理规定，首先规定禁止放生所有的外来物种，并列举了鳄雀鳝、豹纹翼甲鲶（即俗称的“清道夫鱼”）、齐氏罗非鱼、淡水白鲳、食蚊鱼、埃及塘鲺、泰国鲮鱼、大鳄龟、红耳彩龟（俗称巴西龟）、美洲牛蛙等重点物种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;放生这些外来野生动物，可能给本土生物带来严重的威胁。比如鳄雀鳝，这是一种凶猛的肉食鱼类，成体体型巨大，最大可达3米，号称一条就能吃掉一片湖里所有的鱼，甚至会咬人。鳄雀鳝原产于北美洲南部，但近年来国内不少地方都出现了它的身影。这种鱼在国内水域中几乎没有天敌，一旦在野外泛滥，后果不堪设想。河南汝州中央公园曾经排干了20万立方米的湖水，就为了捕捉一条鳄雀鳝。罗非鱼、清道夫等外来物种，也会严重挤压本土生物的生存空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;放生了一种动物，却给另外的动物甚至整个生态带来灾难，恐怕也不是“善”。事实上，擅自放生外来物种，已经被明确规定为违法甚至犯罪行为。 2021年4月15日生效的“生物安全法”规定，未经批准，擅自释放或者丢弃外来物种的，责令限期捕回、找回释放或者丢弃的外来物种，处一万元以上五万元以下的罚款。 2021年3月1日起生效的刑法修正案（十一）规定，非法引进、释放或者丢弃外来入侵物种，情节严重的，处三年以下有期徒刑或者拘役，并处或者单处罚金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而有些物种，虽然不是从境外来的，但是放生到不合适的地点，也可能适得其反。中国幅员辽阔，很多地方有自己独特的生态系统。某个地方的本土物种，到了其他地方，可能无法适应环境而死亡。比如适合在温暖水域生活的鱼类，到了北方的冬天就会被冻死。盲目放生，把动物放生到不适合其生存的环境中，这些动物不仅不能“生”，反而会加速死亡。甚至有些人把淡水鱼类拿到大海去放生，这不是放生，而是杀生。大批被放生的动物死亡，也会造成环境污染。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一种可能，就是一地的本土物种，到了另一地，可能成了“入侵物种”，破坏当地原生生态。这种来自境内其他生态系统的物种，对本土生态来说，本质上也是外来入侵物种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，广州放生管理规定要求，放生要选择适合放生地野外生存的野生动物，并严格控制放生数量，不得对生态系统造成危害。法规还要求管理部门制定公布适合放生的本土野生动物名录，公众可从名录中选择放生的物种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了物种的选择，放生地也很重要。不合适的放生地点，除了被放生的动物可能无法生存之外，还可能给人类带来危险，比如在靠近人类活动的区域放生凶猛有毒的动物。曾经有人在公园放生毒蛇、鳄鱼，在海滩放生电鳐、海鳗等，都严重威胁到游客的人身安全。为此，广州放生管理规定要求管理部门划定并公布适合放生的区域，禁止在放生区域以外的地方放生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法规还规定了违法放生的后果。放生野生动物外来物种的，按照野生动物保护法的规定处罚；在放生区域以外的其他地方放生的，处二千元以上一万元以下罚款；对生态环境可能造成损害的，责令限期捕回，已经造成损害的，并处一万元以上十万元以下罚款。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;放生，在宗教观念中是“善”。但盲目放生却未必是好事，甚至可能对被放生的动物本身、对其他生物和生态环境、对人带来严重的危害，那就不是行善，而是作恶了。对放生进行规范，很有必要。应加强宣传，普及科学放生知识，更要加大执法力度，对违法放生行为加以处罚，避免盲目放生造成严重损害。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一位34岁的也门人，在三亚开了两家“万亿级”公司]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258780]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/Wm2jjWukGfmx50lErAsIuDMgTiDL8oeQrW33PL1X.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/Wm2jjWukGfmx50lErAsIuDMgTiDL8oeQr W33PL1X. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254328&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sanya city scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four &quot;Big Mac&quot; companies have emerged in Sanya, with registered capitals of up to 950 billion euros (approximately 7 trillion yuan), far exceeding Hainan Province’s GDP in 2022 (681.822 billion yuan). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System, these four companies are: Brand New Concept (Sanya) Investment Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Brand New Concept), Wansheng Zhaoye (Sanya) Investment Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Brand New Concept) (referred to as Wansheng Zhaoye), Lianou Honghan (Hainan) Industrial Investment Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Lianou Honghan), and Minhong (Sanya) Technology Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Minhong Technology). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were incorporated between September 25, 2023 and October 8, 2023, and their registered addresses are on the same floor of the same building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These four companies have other similarities. For example, their shareholders are all overseas companies, but their registered capital is small. After the equity penetration, the controlling shareholder of the two companies is the same, a Yemeni living in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Main investment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the national enterprise credit information disclosure system, New Concept, Wansheng Zhaoye, Lianou Honghan, and Minhong Technology were established respectively On September 25, 2023, October 7, 2023, October 8, 2023, October 8, 2023. The business scope of the four companies includes &quot;investment activities with self-owned funds; asset management services for self-owned fund investment; venture capital investment (limited to investment in unlisted companies).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yuchen, director of Beijing Jinliu Law Firm, told Southern Weekend reporters that a company&#39;s high registered capital can improve the company&#39;s credibility to a certain extent and show that the company has relatively strong economic strength, which is conducive to attracting investment. investors and customers. Secondly, companies with high registered capital will have certain advantages when participating in some large-scale projects, bidding and other activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Yuchen also pointed out that if the registered capital is too high, there will be certain legal risks. First of all, if the registered capital is falsely high but the actual operating capabilities are not strong, it may cause the company&#39;s financial situation to be strained and affect the company&#39;s normal operations. Secondly, it will increase the risks for shareholders. For example, if the actual capital contribution is not made in accordance with the commitment of subscribed capital, the relevant shareholders may bear corresponding liabilities within the scope of subscribed capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that when a company sets its registered capital, it should take into account not only the need to improve the company&#39;s credibility, but also its own financial capacity according to its actual situation, and avoid falsely reporting registered capital. legal risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to having similar registration times, the four companies have the same registered addresses, all located on the 10th floor of the Glory Century Building, Yingbin Road, Jiyang District, Sanya City, Hainan Province. According to the Hainan Free Trade Port Investment and Talent Promotion Network, the Glory Century Building is a commercial office building with a total area of ​​20,000 square meters. Tianyancha shows that there are 95 companies with registered addresses in the Glory Century Building, including travel agencies, law firms, educational institutions, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, according to industrial and commercial information, the names of managers of Wansheng Zhaoye and Minhong Technology overlap. The general manager and financial person in charge of Wansheng Zhaoye is &quot;Jiang Tingting&quot;, and the legal representative and executive director of Minhong Technology are also named &quot;Jiang Tingting&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 10, 2023, Dejizhong (Hainan) Digital Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Dejizhong), a wholly-owned subsidiary of Lianou Honghan, was established. Dejizhong&#39;s registered address is also located in the Glory Century Building, and its registered capital is as high as 100 billion yuan. The general manager and financial person in charge of Dejizhong is also &quot;Jiang Tingting&quot;. The supervisor of Dejizhong is named &quot;Li Ping&quot;, which is the same name as the general manager and financial director of Minhong Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The legal representative and executive director of the new concept is Li Yuyu. On October 16, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter called Li Yuyu&#39;s phone number shown on Tianyancha. The other party hung up the phone after learning that the reporter wanted to know why the registered capital was so high. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A shareholder is from the Middle East&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the national enterprise credit information disclosure system, Brand New Concept, Wansheng Zhaoye, Lianou Honghan, and Minhong Technology The shareholders are all registered overseas and are NGC Global Holdings Limited, Wansheng Zhaoye Co., Ltd., PINWHEEL INTERNATIONAL INVESTMENT LTD and TALIYA HOLDINGS GROUP PTE.LTD. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Wansheng Zhaoye’s shareholders are registered in Hong Kong. Information from the Hong Kong Companies Registry shows that the English name of MILLIONS MEGA TRADE LIMITED is MILLIONS MEGA TRADE LIMITED. It was established on December 7, 2017, and its registered place is Des Voeux Road, Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paid-in share capital of Wansheng Zhaoye Co., Ltd. is only HK$1, and the shareholder and director is Taiwanese Cai Qinglong. Cai Qinglong also serves as the executive director of Wansheng Zhaoye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The registration date of NGC Global Holdings Limited is September 6, 2023, which was established in the same month as the new concept of the subsidiary. The registered address of this company is in Kwai Chung, Hong Kong, with a paid-in capital of HK$10,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shareholder and director of NGC Global Holdings Limited is BASSAM TAHER ALI AL-SALAFI. His nationality is the Republic of Yemen and he currently lives in China. His mailing address is School of International Education, China University of Geosciences, Wuhan City, Hubei Province. International Education, China University of Geosciences) faculty apartment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, according to the company registration documents of PINWHEEL INTERNATIONAL INVESTMENT LTD, the shareholders and directors of PINWHEEL are also Yemeni BASSAM TAHER ALI AL-SALAFI, and the mailing address he left is consistent with the above. Registration documents also revealed that the Yemeni was born in 1989. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, after the equity penetration, the controlling shareholders of Brand New Concept and Lianou Honghan are both Yemenis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yemen is located at the southwest end of the Arabian Peninsula, adjacent to Saudi Arabia and Oman. It is a typical resource-based country, with oil and natural gas being its most important natural resources. Since 2023, a lot of Middle Eastern funds have poured into China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PINWHEEL&#39;s registered address is in the UK, with a registered share capital of 1,000 pounds. It was established on September 10, 2023, only one month earlier than its subsidiary Lianou Honghan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shareholder company of Minhong Technology will also be established in September 2023. According to the Accounting and Corporate Regulatory Authority of Singapore (ACRA), the registration date of TALIYA HOLDINGS GROUP PTE.LTD. is September 20, 2023, which was established half a month before Minhong Technology. The registration place is at Paya Lebar Plaza in Singapore. As of October 16, 2023, TALIYA&#39;s registered capital is SGD 1,000/USD and its paid-in capital is 0. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;TALIYA’s shareholders are Taiwanese CHEN and CHIH-SHENG. In addition to CHEN and CHIH-SHENG, the company&#39;s management also includes a Malaysian LIEW SHAN YEE and a Chinese GUAN XU. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[上热搜的“支原体肺炎”，究竟是啥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258756]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, more patients with Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection have appeared in hospitals across the country, mostly children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is mycoplasma? At what age is it easy for a child to get it? Can adults get it too? Let me reveal the secrets of Mycoplasma pneumoniae one by one! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/bddf3c3d344dfbd96d0d82199ddeb4b5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;494&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/bddf3c3d344dfbd96d0d82199ddeb4b5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254305&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;What is Mycoplasma pneumoniae? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is the smallest microorganism known in the world that can survive independently, between bacteria and viruses. Mycoplasma pneumoniae has no cell wall structure, like bacteria without a &quot;coat&quot;. Both 75% alcohol and chlorine-containing disinfectant (such as 84 disinfectant) can kill Mycoplasma pneumoniae. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/477dce0e66baefc1fe83bdbeb2bd445b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;626&quot; height=&quot;358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/477dce0e66baefc1fe83bdbeb2bd445b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254303&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is an important pathogen of acute respiratory infections in Beijing. Mycoplasma pneumoniae is divided into two subtypes, type I and type II. Currently, type I is the main prevalent subtype in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The population is generally susceptible to Mycoplasma pneumoniae, but it is more common in children and adolescents over 5 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can occur throughout the year. The high incidence period of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in Beijing is from August to December every year, and usually reaches its peak around November every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;How is Mycoplasma pneumoniae spread? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Patients with Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection and asymptomatic infections are the main sources of infection. The incubation period is 1 to 3 weeks, and they are infectious during the incubation period until symptoms subside for several weeks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is mainly transmitted through droplets, and the pathogen can be carried in secretions during coughing, sneezing, and runny noses. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;What are the symptoms of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The main symptoms of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection are fever and cough. Generally, the cough is severe, and the cough may continue for 1-2 weeks after the fever subsides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can cause upper respiratory tract infections, lower respiratory tract infections such as pneumonia, and extrapulmonary complications, such as autoimmune hemolytic anemia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is one of the main pathogens causing the high incidence of pneumonia in autumn and winter in Beijing. Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia is generally an interstitial pneumonia, so the clinical signs are often lighter than the imaging examination results, and after the clinical symptoms disappear, lung imaging examinations may still show inflammation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Mycoplasma pneumoniae does not have a cell wall, the familiar penicillins and cephalosporins, which are antibiotics that target the cell wall, are completely ineffective against Mycoplasma pneumoniae. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Macrolide antibiotics, such as roxithromycin and azithromycin, are currently the first-choice treatments for Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if citizens have fever accompanied by severe cough, they should seek medical treatment in time, identify the cause as soon as possible, standardize treatment, and avoid blindly taking medication on their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;04&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;How to prevent Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There is currently no vaccine to prevent Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. The most important thing to prevent Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection is to develop good personal hygiene habits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Try to avoid going to public places with dense crowds and poor ventilation, and wear a mask to protect yourself when necessary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Cover your mouth and nose with a tissue when coughing or sneezing, or cover it with your elbow or upper sleeve, and throw the used tissue into a covered trash can. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Pay attention to hand hygiene, use soap and hand sanitizer to wash hands under running water. If there is no running water, you can use alcohol-based hand sanitizer to wipe and disinfect your hands&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/5fdc5214073f81a1b9a66cf32966e8bd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/5fdc5214073f81a1b9a66cf32966e8bd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254304 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;4. During the high epidemic season&lt;/span>;, pay attention to indoor ventilation and ventilate for no less than 30 minutes each time to keep the air fresh. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5. Develop healthy living habits, exercise moderately, increase body resistance, and keep warm to avoid catching cold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6. Schools, kindergartens and other key places should pay attention to ventilation and disinfection, do daily cleaning work, and strengthen health monitoring to avoid clusters of infectious &lt;span>; infections. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 08:25:57 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[纠正百年历史错误，美国宾大将追授林徽因建筑学学位]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258762]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/47b57ec8864febb24d3be047bded52e0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;754&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/17/47b57ec8864febb24d3be047bded52e0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254306&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 15, local time, the official website of the University of Pennsylvania announced that the school will open on May 18 next year At the graduation ceremony of the Weizman School of Design, Lin Huiyin, a graduate of the school and a pioneer in Chinese architecture, was awarded a belated Bachelor of Architecture degree to express her commemoration and recognition. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the exhibition &quot;Building in China: A Century of Dialogues on Modern Architecture&quot; currently on display at the Penn Wharton China Center in Beijing, a long The 15-foot display board is eye-catching. It shows 23 Chinese graduates who studied architecture at the University of Pennsylvania between 1918 and 1941. After returning to China, these students became pioneers in opening up China&#39;s construction industry and architectural education, and devoted themselves to building China&#39;s rapidly developing cities and towns. , so he is known as the &quot;first generation of Chinese modern architects&quot;. At the center of the panel is Lin Huiyin, the only female among these students, and the only one who was not awarded a degree in architecture from Penn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the chief curator of the exhibition, Professor Lin Zhongjie from the Department of Urban and Regional Planning at the Weitzman School of Design at the University of Pennsylvania, Lin Huiyin and Liang Sicheng entered the University of Pennsylvania in the fall of 1924. At that time, they both wanted to pursue a degree in architecture. However, at that time, due to the fact that the required art courses including male model sketching and construction courses teaching construction techniques were not suitable for girls, the Department of Architecture at the University of Pennsylvania did not recruit girls, so Lin Huiyin had to register in the Art Department. However, she not only took all the architectural design courses, studied design theory, painting and architectural history, but also served as a teaching assistant in architectural design. Her academic performance was better than that of most of her male classmates. On her transcript, many classes received &quot;Excellence&quot; ( Distinguished) rating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to China, Lin Huiyin and Liang Sicheng worked together and made great contributions to reshaping China&#39;s architectural history, education and practice. “When you come to the United States, everyone knows Frank Lloyd Wright. And when you go to China, everyone knows Lin Huiyin and Liang Sicheng.” Weizman School of Design City and Region said Genie Birch, professor of urban studies and education in the Department of Planning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1934, the University of Pennsylvania’s architecture major began to admit female students. Since then, the School of Fine Arts (the original name of the Weitzman School of Design in the 20th century) has awarded supplementary architecture degrees to women who had previously studied architecture at Penn, including Georgiana Pope, the first female director of the Philadelphia Department of City Building. Georgiana Pope Yeatman. But Lin Huiyin&#39;s case has been ignored, even though she completed more architecture courses than any other female student of her time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Judging from records at the time, it is clear that Lin Huiyin wanted to study architecture and become an architect, and she later achieved great success in this field.&quot; Dean of the Weizman School of Design Fritz Steiner, Paley Chair Professor, initiated an investigation and review process into Lin Huiyin’s degree starting in 2022. “As our research continues to deepen, it becomes clear why she was not awarded a degree. Her identity as a woman. This is a historical mistake and it’s time to correct it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/17/6297d1bb86516148ed8689a960d73cfd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/17/6297d1bb86516148ed8689a960d73cfd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After learning that the University of Pennsylvania decided to posthumously award Lin Huiyin a degree, her family expressed their pride, gratitude and joy. Feeling. &quot;For my mother to be recognized by the school a hundred years later, it reminds me of her bravery and determination in choosing this major. She identified architecture as a teenager and determined to become a new generation of female architects. She enthusiastically guided and encouraged her father Liang Sicheng fell in love with her and chose architecture together. From then on, she was loyal to her choice throughout her life and sacrificed everything for her choice.&quot; Lin Huiyin&#39;s daughter Liang Zaibing said with emotion that today, on Lin Huiyin&#39;s tombstone, her husband Liang Sicheng inscribed &quot;Architect Lin Huiyin&quot; can be said to be a high-level summary of her life. &quot;As her descendants, we admire and appreciate her fearless spirit in pursuing her artistic dreams.&quot; Lin Huiyin&#39;s granddaughter Yu Kui said that the University of Pennsylvania chose to honor Lin Huiyin on the occasion of the 120th anniversary of her birth and the 100th anniversary of her enrollment. Teaching a degree in architecture will inject more hope and strength into the pursuit of dreams for future generations, especially women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[既嫌弃又上头，霸总式微短剧正成为00后的电子榨菜？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257206]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;The President&#39;s Billionaire Imprisoned Wife&quot;, &quot;The Heaven-defying Princess Leaves Too Wild&quot;, &quot;Son-in-law Dominates the World&quot; and &quot;Security &quot;The President&#39;s Daughter and Little Beloved Wife&quot;... If you come across micro-short dramas like this on short video platforms or other social platforms, don&#39;t be surprised. These micro-short dramas are becoming a creative craze, with people complaining about tyrants. Young people who always follow the same old tricks quietly hide in bed at night and start practicing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Detawen&#39;s Micro Short Drama Market Report for the First Half of 2023&quot; shows that a total of 481 new micro short dramas were released in the first half of 2023, compared with only 454 new ones in the whole year of 2022. This year The number of micro-short dramas in the first half of the year has exceeded that of the whole of last year. In July alone, 361 online micro-short dramas were recorded and announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, micro-short dramas are becoming a creative trend, on the other hand, the roughness and vulgarity of micro-short dramas are also despised by many netizens - why are micro-short dramas so popular? Is the only way for micro-short dramas to break out of the circle is the &quot;three vulgarities&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/gKB1xSTLiZ9trVAlnaHNSx5FO0tI7vY3tA5mLdg7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;947&quot; height= &quot;627&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/gKB1xSTLiZ9trVAlnaHNSx5FO0tI7vY3tA5mLdg7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253986&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Short, flat, fast&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with previous long dramas or short dramas, the difference between micro-short dramas is the length. Each episode can be up to ten minutes, and the shortest can even be only A few dozen seconds is in sharp contrast to the average length of a long drama episode of 40 minutes. In the past two years, the creation of micro-short dramas has become a trend, mainly due to the &quot;short, flat, and fast&quot; nature of its creation form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Short&quot; means that the duration of micro-short dramas is very short, the shooting threshold is very low, and the shooting techniques are much simpler. It can be said that as long as you have a mobile phone and a story outline, you can shoot a short drama. A short drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Assuming 20 episodes, each episode is 1 minute, a short drama is only 20 minutes long, which is less than the length of one episode of a long drama. With such a low threshold for creation, everyone can enter. Various small film and television production companies have used micro-short plays as the starting point for creation, easily triggering a creative boom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Plain&quot;, micro-short dramas are generally not so particular in film and television arts, and can be plain and mediocre. This is because micro-short dramas are parasitic on short video platforms. They are not meant to be viewed on large screens such as TVs, and mobile phone screens have limited capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially for micro-short plays with a vertical screen, if you take a close-up shot and see the expressions of the characters clearly, you can probably only accommodate two characters. It is difficult to pay attention to the depth of field and the depth of field. Space layout and shot scheduling. Therefore, many micro-short dramas are just about filming the characters and the plot, and they are all about saving money on the art and scenery, the service, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fast&quot; means that the filming time of micro-short dramas is very fast, the broadcast cycle is very fast, and more importantly, the money comes in very quickly. The cost of many micro-short dramas is only a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan. You can shoot one in three to five days. After shooting one, you can directly launch a short video or small program. If it becomes popular, you can copy another one in ten days. It&#39;s a good money, you can quickly get a lot of traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many ways to make money from micro-short dramas. Although micro-short dramas with an episode length of one or two minutes are not available on long-form video platforms such as &quot;Youai Tengmang&quot;, they are very popular on short-video platforms. After micro-short dramas become popular, the protagonists of micro-short dramas can transform into Internet celebrities and carry out live broadcasts to promote products; some micro-short dramas are customized by advertisers, and the entire episode revolves around the advertising brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those micro-short dramas that are parasitic on small programs can also be watched on a paid basis. A drama usually has more than 100 episodes, and each episode is one minute. The first part can be watched for free, but the subsequent episodes require payment. Unlocked viewing, watching a mini-series is even more expensive than watching a movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creative threshold is very low, the creative techniques are simple, the shooting time is short, and the money comes in quickly... It is not surprising that micro-short dramas have become a new trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/KEwiaPCVhglej8e5wja668usJKahucGEiupeCjE4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/KEwiaPCVhglej8e5wja668usJKahucGEiupeCjE4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253984&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Vulgar, vulgar, kitsch&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, it is worth noting that on the one hand, micro-short dramas are very popular, and on the other hand, micro-short dramas have been criticized and criticized by many people. The root cause is that a large part of micro-short dramas on the market have strong &quot;three vulgarities&quot; characteristics: vulgarity, vulgarity, and kitsch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Swarmed are all micro-short dramas. There are too many content for the audience to choose from. If you don’t find it interesting, just flick it by in three or two seconds, and the micro-short dramas will not get traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to catch the attention of users at the first glance, the orientation of many micro-short dramas can only be very &quot;vulgar&quot;. As some netizens summarized, they are nothing more than &quot;The Domineering President Falls in Love with Me, The Hero&quot; Saving an American but being rescued, falling in love while playing hard to get, seeing the true love in a kidnapping case&quot;... It&#39;s just a &quot;picking up&quot;, &quot;picking up a boss as a girlfriend&quot;, &quot;picking up a boss as a boyfriend&quot;, &quot;picking up a boss as a husband&quot;, &quot;accidentally picking up a boss&quot; Contents such as “Get a CEO Husband” are flying all over the place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some micro-short dramas have further slipped into &quot;vulgarity&quot; and made a big fuss over the edges. In particular, some micro-short dramas in mini programs have not obtained online registration numbers. The content is very large, full of sexual innuendo, or has bloody and violent scenes. Moreover, because the broadcast channel is very hidden, it has repeatedly escaped supervision, which is quite bad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is vulgar or vulgar, it is all about pleasing and flattering the audience. It not only caters to the instinctive parts of human nature, but also tries its best to tease users&#39; emotions and create traffic by selling emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This emotion is composed of &quot;hate&quot; and &quot;pleasure&quot; - many micro-short dramas remind us of Mi Meng in the public account era - interestingly, after the transformation, Mi Meng has also become a micro-short drama The manipulator behind the show: The targets of the micro-short drama are &quot;bitches, low bitches, scumbags, scumbags, and vicious female supporting characters.&quot; These &quot;enemies&quot; combine all kinds of personality flaws that the audience is tired of. The method maximizes the various flaws of the &quot;enemy&quot; to arouse the audience&#39;s hatred, and then humiliates, criticizes and attacks these villains through the protagonist&#39;s counterattack, allowing the audience to gain a sense of emotional catharsis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the &quot;hate&quot; and &quot;happiness&quot; brought about by this kind of kitsch simplify human nature, breed intolerance between people, intensify estrangement, and have a subtle influence on social mentality. negative impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/HZf8qSQLY6dllV6303J3HB0mSaiUAleQfqMVMN0W.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/HZf8qSQLY6dllV6303J3HB0mSaiUAleQfqMVMN0W.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253985&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;The possibility of being &quot;micro&quot; but not &quot;vulgar&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The recklessness of micro-short dramas has attracted official attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially in May this year, the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television issued new rules for the broadcasting of online dramas. After June 1, 2023, online dramas, online mini-series, online movies, and online cartoons that have been planned and registered will be Adopt a management approach with full license coverage. Only broadcasts can be broadcast after obtaining the &quot;Online Drama Distribution License&quot; in accordance with the law. Those without a license are not allowed to be broadcast; for those that have previously passed the planning and filing, licenses or numbers will be issued based on the circumstances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, starting from June 1, 2023, newly launched online dramas, online micro-shorts, online movies, and online cartoons must be declared through the &quot;Key Online Film and Television Drama Information Filing System&quot; , and works that have obtained the &quot;Online Drama Distribution License&quot; or online registration number after passing the content review of the radio and television management department at or above the provincial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this, there was a brief regulatory blank period for micro-short dramas. That is, many micro-short dramas were filmed and released casually. Take whatever you can to catch people&#39;s attention. Some short dramas on mini programs have become a place for &quot;harboring evil and evil people and practices&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the new regulations are released, the creation and broadcast of micro-short dramas will also face strict review. Only those that pass the review can be broadcast online on the platform. This also means that it is difficult to follow the &quot;three customs&quot; path of micro-short dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Micro short plays can only be &quot;micro&quot; but not &quot;vulgar&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, micro-short dramas can also be &quot;high-quality&quot;. For example, &quot;Youai Tengmang&quot; is also entering the micro-short drama industry. Each episode of the micro-short dramas they produce is only ten minutes long, and they use regular techniques for filming film and television dramas to shoot micro-short dramas. This makes micro-short dramas have A certain aesthetic style makes it more meaningful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, in this year&#39;s popular &quot;Invitation&quot;, director Zeng Qingjie&#39;s camera language is very sophisticated, and he shoots a story in a pure and beautiful way. It has the simplicity of a short play and the texture of a long drama. The box office is divided into two. More than 16 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, for those micro-short dramas with a single episode of only tens of seconds or two or three minutes, the production team does not have the money to pay attention to quality, so they have to make a fuss about the theme expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;既然不能“俗”，那么就要另辟蹊径，要么就把“爽感”发挥得更极致，要么就通过创意让观众耳目一新。 Otherwise, the micro-short drama will either end up being filmed but not broadcast, or it will be passed over by the audience after it is broadcast. Even if the cost is not high, it will end up in the street. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>