<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[2023年中国电影总票房已突破500亿元，国产片票房占比创十年来新高]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260699]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 14, Nandu reporters learned from the real-time data of the Beacon Professional Edition that as of November 13, 2023 The country&#39;s annual total box office (including pre-sales) exceeded 50 billion, and the top ten box office in the current year are all domestic films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8c6dc98a22c63c0267096e71b85c2ba2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1652&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8c6dc98a22c63c0267096e71b85c2ba2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258491&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Data show that the top ten films at the box office are all domestic films, including &quot;A River in Red&quot;, &quot;The Wandering Earth 2&quot;, &quot;Desperate&quot;, &quot;The Disappearance of Her&quot;, &quot;Fengshen Part 1: Chaoge Fengyun&quot;, &quot;Eight Anise&quot; &quot;In the Cage&quot;, &quot;Thirty Thousand Miles from Chang&#39;an&quot;, &quot;Bear Infested·Stand with Me &quot;Bear Core&quot;&quot;, &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; and &quot;Unfamiliar Life&quot;, these ten films all have a box office of more than 1 billion yuan. It is reported that domestic films account for 83.4% of the current annual box office, the highest in the past 10 years; imported films account for 16.6%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/c76798310f775545d8fad770acd46742.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;944&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/c76798310f775545d8fad770acd46742.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258492&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说丨郑永流：学法律的自豪来自两部电影]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260690]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu, the first doctor of jurisprudence in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in 1957 in Macheng County, Hubei Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1963－1974&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;went to primary school and middle school in Macheng County and Huangpi County, Hubei Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978-1982, studied at the Law Department of Hubei University of Finance and Economics and received a bachelor&#39;s degree in law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1983-1986, studied at the Law Department of Central South University of Political Science and Law and received a Master of Laws degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1986-1989, studied at the Law Department of Peking University and received a doctorate in law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1989-1993, served as lecturer and associate professor of the Law Department of Central South University of Political Science and Law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1993-1996, he served as a visiting professor at the School of Law and Economics, Saarland University, Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2004, he served as Acting Professor at the Law School of the University of Freiburg, Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1998 to 2023, he worked at the University of Friborg in Switzerland, the University of Oslo in Norway, He has served as a short-term visiting scholar at the University of Frankfurt in Germany for many times. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 1997 to 2022, he served as professor at the Law School of China University of Political Science and Law and China Europe Law School. Professor, doctoral supervisor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Currently a distinguished doctoral supervisor at China University of Political Science and Law, legal philosophy and interdisciplinary legal research at China Europe Law School Director. He is a member of the International Association for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy (IVR) and the editor-in-chief of the journal &quot;Philosophy of Law and Sociology of Law&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In July 2023, Zheng Yongliu (first from the right) held a lecture at the University of Munich. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4b176532a1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;593&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/16/4b176532a1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258474&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In July 2023, Zheng Yongliu ( First from right) giving a lecture at the University of Munich. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For our generation, reform and opening up has brought a great turning point in our lives.” October 2023 is the most beautiful time of the year in Beijing. In the autumn season, in a teahouse near Xueyuan Road, Zheng Yongliu recalled his youthful years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 1978, Zheng Yongliu was admitted to Hubei University of Finance and Economics (now Zhongnan University of Economics and Law) and became a freshman in the law department. At this time, 4 years had passed since he graduated from high school. During those four years, Zheng Yongliu worked as an educated youth in the countryside and as a fisherman in the lake area. When he took the college entrance examination, he was a surveyor in the water conservancy engineering team of the Water Conservancy Bureau of Huangpi County, Hubei Province (now Huangpi District, Wuhan City). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Born in a county town, Zheng Yongliu’s hometown did not have a university. He had never seen a university before. “Everyone yearns for a university, but they have no concept of it. They only know that a university is an ‘ivory tower’. &#39;, it&#39;s a world that you can&#39;t concretely imagine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After completing undergraduate and master’s degrees at Hubei University of Finance and Economics and Central South University of Political Science and Law, Zheng Yongliu was admitted to the Law Department of Peking University in 1986, where he studied under Chen Shouyi, a legal educator and one of the founders of contemporary Chinese jurisprudence. professor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1989, Zheng Yongliu graduated and became the first doctor of jurisprudence after the founding of New China. His doctoral thesis &quot;The Status and Development Path of Law in Rural Reform&quot; began to explore rural legal issues more than 30 years ago, and proposed the &quot;three-dimensional adjustment method of rural development of human ethics-law-policy&quot; and &quot;legal localization&quot;. The idea is extremely groundbreaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from Peking University, Zheng Yongliu taught at Central South University of Political Science and Law, Saarland University in Germany, University of Freiburg in Germany, and China University of Political Science and Law. In Zheng Yongliu’s view, “the first PhD in jurisprudence after the founding of the People’s Republic of China” was the starting point of his academic career, but it is his subsequent academic research that determines his reputation and academic status. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;This college is worth it&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From graduating from high school in 1974 to taking the college entrance examination in 1978, what were you doing in the intervening years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I graduated from high school, I was 17 years old. My classmates and I all went to the countryside to become educated youth. There was great enthusiasm at that time, and the countryside was a &quot;vast land with a lot to offer.&quot; We have all stated that we want to take root, blossom and bear fruit in the countryside and do not think about anything else. There are many lakes in Hubei. I worked as a fisherman in the countryside for two years. When fishing every day in winter, we have to get up at 5 o&#39;clock in the morning and set the net before the fish wake up. Otherwise, when the sun comes out, the fish will scatter and go out to look for food. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I was transferred to the Water Conservancy Bureau of Huangpi County (now Huangpi District, Wuhan City) as a surveyor, carrying a ruler and doing measurements everywhere. For example, when building a reservoir, it is necessary to measure the rain-bearing area, which determines the height and thickness of the reservoir dam. If the dam is built too high, it will be wasteful. If it is built too low or too thin, it will be easily washed away, so the watershed must be measured. Because we have not gone through any special study, our job is to go over mountains and ridges to place measuring rulers, trace and post pictures and other auxiliary tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You took the college entrance examination just after it resumed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In August 1977, Deng Xiaoping chaired a symposium on science and education and decided to resume the college entrance examination, which had been suspended for 11 years. At the end of 1977, each province resumed the college entrance examination with its own questions. When the exam notice was sent out, I was at a water conservancy construction site. If you don’t have time to review, you will naturally fail in taking the exam. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I took the college entrance examination in the second year, I had time to review by chance. At that time, a river in the county needed to be renovated, and the engineering team sent me to a cement factory in another place to purchase cement. The production environment in the cement factory was very bad. Although everyone wore masks and took other protective measures, there was a lot of dust in the factory. In May 1978, I contracted acute pleurisy. At that time, the water accumulation in my right chest was very serious, and I could even hear a &quot;gurgling&quot; sound in my chest when I breathed. A female doctor surnamed Gong said that I should be hospitalized immediately. She would use a particularly thick needle to puncture my back to my chest every day and extract about 100 ml of accumulated water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After about a week of pumping, the fluid in the chest was gone, but the inflammation was still not gone, so I could no longer go to the cement factory to purchase cement. The doctor asked me to stay in the hospital, but I said no, I had to take the college entrance examination. At that time, there were many people living in one room in the hospital, and I couldn&#39;t review. The doctor also understood. She kept me in the hospital for another three days, and then asked me to go to the hospital for injections during the day and stay at home at night. So I went to the hospital twice a day, and rested at home during the rest of the time while reviewing. In the summer of 1978, I entered college. I am very grateful to Dr. Gong. After I was admitted to college, I made a special trip to visit her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you went to college, was law your first choice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, law is my second choice. When I was filling out my application form, I preferred literature. At that time, everyone had a literary dream and wanted to be a writer. At that time, the most popular liberal arts subject was what we called &quot;xianxue&quot; - &quot;literature, history and philosophy&quot;. Students with high scores were admitted to the Chinese Department, followed by the History Department and Philosophy. At that time, I applied for the History Department of Wuhan University. In 1978, the key score for liberal arts in Hubei Province was 340 points. I scored 332.3 points, which was a few points short. Later, the key line was lowered to 330 points, and my score was enough, but at that time I had been admitted to the Law Department of Hubei University of Finance and Economics, so I missed the history major. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How is college life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was particularly impressed. On the first day of college, the school arranged a movie reception and showed us movies. The movie is called &quot;The Black Triangle&quot; and it&#39;s about catching spies in the north. The plot of the movie is average, but there is a song in it that shocked us very much. It was &quot;The Spring Water in the Border is Clear and Pure&quot; sung by Li Guyi. She sang this song using a new so-called breath singing method, which was completely different from the heroic and aspirational singing method popular in that era. That was the first time I realized that the song could still be sung like this. At that time, I felt: I went to the right university. I have never been exposed to these before. If I had not gone to college and lived in a small county, I might not have heard this singing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;University opened up a new world for me. The end of 1978 to 1979 was a period of surging ideological trends. At that time, there were many lectures in the school, such as those of Peking University and the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. Many famous scholars came to Wuhan to give lectures and spread some new ideas, which made me even more determined: this university is worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 1987, Zheng Yongliu was at the Weiming Lake of Peking University. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/16/79bc830a15.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 79bc830a15.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1987, Zheng Yongliu was at the Weiming Lake of Peking University. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;What should we do when studying law&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;South Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After going to college, are you interested in law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the first half of college, I didn’t have much feelings about law. I really became interested in this major because of movies. At that time, every Saturday, the school would show movies in the playground, and we would all watch them for free. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, there was an Indian movie &quot;Wanderer&quot;, which tells the story of two young people. The woman&#39;s name is Lida. She is a lawyer who represents her friend in court. Raz defended, vehemently. Lida studied law, and we immediately felt that studying law was very impressive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, another movie was released, &quot;Tragedy on the Nile&quot;, which tells the story of a Belgian detective named Poirot who used reasoning to find the killer on the cruise ship. At that time, we felt that this was also related to the law, and we might have to do related work in the future. A classmate in the same class got the nickname &quot;Poirot&quot; because he often imitated the great detective, and his classmates still call him that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After watching the movie, we gained some pride in studying law and felt that we should eliminate violence and bring justice to everyone. At that time, some students from other departments watched these two movies and asked to transfer to our department to study law. Of course, the theory is obscure, but everyone still has a general understanding of &quot;what we should do when studying law&quot; through film and television works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After you have the pride of studying law, you are interested in jurisprudence Yet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In our freshman year, we mainly took public courses and also offered jurisprudence. At that time, I felt that jurisprudence was too abstract and difficult to understand, but the teacher Wang Yajin, who studied in the Soviet Union, asked me to be the class representative of jurisprudence, so I did. At that time, there were no subdivisions in the legal profession, but you might be interested in a certain subject. Some people are interested in criminal law, others are interested in civil law. I am very interested in international law. My graduation thesis is also in the direction of international law, discussing the subject status of international organizations in international law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduation, the school asked me to stay and teach in jurisprudence. At that time, I thought that if I wanted to stay in school to teach, I would definitely need a higher degree, so I enrolled in a graduate program at this school. Zhang Ruolong, the dean of our Central South University of Political Science and Law, is a professor of jurisprudence, so I studied jurisprudence with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still didn’t feel much about jurisprudence when I was in school, but I felt that since I was a graduate student, I should study hard. It was also at this time that I started to become interested in jurisprudence because I had invested a lot of time in it. But to truly understand and study jurisprudence, it is still at the doctoral level and beyond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you later go to Peking University to study for a PhD in Jurisprudence? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because I have entered the field of jurisprudence and want to continue my studies. At that time, only Peking University in the country was able to recruit doctors of jurisprudence. My supervisor is Chen Shouyi, who is also among the first batch of liberal arts and the first doctoral supervisors in jurisprudence in the country. According to research, in November 1981, the State Council approved four scholars from Peking University: Chen Shouyi, Rui Mu (International Economic Law), Wang Tieya (International Law) and Zhang Youyu (Constitutional Law) of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences as the first batch of law doctoral supervisors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1986, Teacher Chen was getting older, in his eighties, and needed someone to assist him. At that time, Liu Shengping was the director of the Jurisprudence Teaching and Research Office of Peking University Law Department. He was not yet sixty years old and was in the prime of life, so the specific daily work was managed by Teacher Liu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teacher Chen is not in good health. He asks us to come to his home from time to time to talk, mainly about what is happening in the courts and procuratorates and what new problems there are. Another thing is to listen to what we think in theory. What he said the most is that we need to start from China&#39;s reality and understand more about China&#39;s reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your doctoral thesis is &quot;The Status and Development of Law in Rural Changes&quot; &quot;Road&quot;, how did you pay attention to this topic? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I entered Peking University in 1986, the topic of reform was very hot and my thoughts were very diverse. There are many various academic seminars in Beijing. After I arrived in Beijing, I also participated in these academic seminars and met some people from the China Institute of Economic Structural Reform and the Rural Development Institute of the Rural Policy Research Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. At that time, they advocated legalizing reform measures, but they were all majoring in economics and did not know how to legislate or provide legal advice, so they needed some people who studied law, so I went there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two research institutes are think tanks for reform. The Institute of Structural Reform leads urban system reform, especially enterprise restructuring; the Institute of Agricultural Research studies rural issues, including township and village enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I went to the Physical Reform Institute first and then to the Agricultural Research Institute. At the Agricultural Research Institute, I followed them to the Fuyang Township Enterprise Reform Experimental Zone in Anhui Province for investigation and did some empirical research. At that time, there was almost no legal issue in rural areas, and there were only some policies promoted by the annual No. 1 Central Document. After conducting research with people from the Agricultural Research Institute, I felt that I had found a direction and wanted to write about rural legal construction. In 1989, I co-wrote &quot;Promoting the System through the System - An Experimental Report on the Bankruptcy System of Township Enterprises in Fuyang, Anhui Province&quot; with Qiu Chengyi of the Agricultural Research Institute, which was published in &quot;Unfinalized&quot;, an internal journal of &quot;Chinese Social Sciences&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did your experience at the Agricultural Research Institute help you write your thesis? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The experience at the Agricultural Research Institute allowed me to understand and use empirical research methods instead of just deducing from theory. Scholars at the institute start from the facts, then make judgments and propose countermeasures and theories for reform. This inspired me a lot, because we used to introduce other people&#39;s theories, from theory to theory, PK was also PK between this theory and that theory. The impression given to me by the Agricultural Research Institute is that it is refreshing, and its examples are all real-life. We went there for about more than a month. We visited township enterprises and factories every day and held discussions with township cadres. This was completely different from my previous experience in college. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I proposed in my paper at that time that human ethics, policies and laws should be mutually complementary and cooperative means of adjusting rural development. No one said this at that time. Everyone either only emphasized human ethics, or only emphasized policies or laws. I think these are biased, so I proposed the three-dimensional adjustment. &lt;p>; )&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6646620582.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;789&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6646620582.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu (back row, first from right) takes a photo with Chen Shouyi (front row, first from right), associate instructor Liu Shengping (front row, first from left) and classmates. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Propose a theory of practical legal philosophy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt; /strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After graduating from your Ph.D., will all your subsequent academic research be related to jurisprudence? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From the doctoral student stage in 1988 to before going abroad in 1993, I mainly focused on empirical research and also did some investigations, including my Several colleagues from the Central South University of Political Science and Law conducted research on farmers&#39; legal awareness in Hubei and published some articles, such as &quot;Realistic Changes in China&#39;s Farmers&#39; Legal Awareness&quot; published in &quot;Chinese Law&quot; in 1992. In terms of discipline, we call it legal sociology. It should be said that in China, I was one of the first scholars to do empirical research. Later I went abroad and did not do much research at that time. On the one hand, I did not have the conditions for empirical research. On the other hand, I had a teaching assignment at the University of Saarland in Germany. I also needed to understand German law and read their laws. Research is still in the accumulation stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to China in 1997, I continued to teach sociology of law courses, but my research direction has shifted to legal methods, that is, how to apply legal methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 2000, in addition to paying attention to legal methods, I began to study legal philosophy. Jurisprudence and legal philosophy are the same concept, which is to answer the question &quot;What is law?&quot; It not only solves the problem of how to apply and interpret the law, but also forms a new law in the process. Later I summarized it as: law in a static sense is the 1.0 state of the law; after interpretation, the law you create yourself is the 2.0 state of the law. Later, this became my own set of legal philosophy theories. I called it practical legal philosophy because it was created in the process of legal practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The legal philosophy I mentioned today is different from traditional legal philosophy. Traditional legal philosophy is divorced from empirical research, but I proposed a new legal philosophy theory based on empirical research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The theory of practical legal philosophy you proposed also partially compensated for the failure of Chinese scholars Are there any research gaps in this area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As we all know, modern legal science is the product of Western knowledge and came to China across the ocean. After more than a hundred years of &quot;apprenticeship&quot; career, Chinese legal scholars want to participate in the world&#39;s mainstream legal dialogue, and Practical Legal Philosophy is the result of such an attempt. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a theoretical origin point of view, practical legal philosophy continues the tradition of practical philosophy, and also absorbs practical theory, as well as the famous German legal philosopher Kaufman’s idea of ​​​​&quot;actual reality&quot;. Theoretical resources such as the &quot;Third Way&quot; opened up between &quot;should be&quot; and &quot;should be&quot; strive to integrate the wisdom of several major schools of modern Western legal philosophy. This is a theory that can dialogue with the mainstream of the West rather than talk to itself. It wants to provide an answer to the age-old question &quot;What is law?&quot; and make a Chinese scholar&#39;s own contribution to the world of legal philosophy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now let me explain, what do you think jurisprudence is? What kind of subject? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The core question of jurisprudence is to answer &quot;what is the law?&quot; This sounds simple to say, but is more complicated to actually study. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, doesn’t the National People’s Congress enact laws? What&#39;s so hard about this? But that&#39;s not the case. We call formulated and written laws statutory laws. In addition to statutory law, law also has other forms of expression. For example, we call the universal rules of society expressed in the form of concepts and thoughts natural law. Laws made by people do not necessarily contain these ideas, and statutory laws are not necessarily correct. For example, many laws in ancient China were autocratic and authoritarian laws; many laws enacted by Nazi Germany also contained many anti-human and unfair ideas. So natural law is needed to correct errors in statutory law, which is part of our answer to &quot;what is law?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also customary law, which is something that exists in real life and has been observed by us for generations. It also adjusts people&#39;s behavior, which also belongs to the scope of &quot;what is the law&quot;. So in terms of scope, statutory law, natural law, and customary law are all the content of our research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the most difficult part of studying jurisprudence is that statutory law, natural law, and customary law are all expressed in a static sense. When these concepts are related to facts, it will show Certain deficiencies and weaknesses. As Goethe said, &quot;Theory is gray, but the tree of life is evergreen.&quot; In other words, no matter what the rules are, they can never fully meet the needs of reality. In more professional terms, it is called &quot;there is an asymmetry between facts and norms.&quot; This requires us to constantly combine facts in the process of applying rules to propose our new theory about &quot;what the law is.&quot; This new theory will become binding law on specific cases, so the theory also needs to be constantly updated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We call the previous static law Law 1.0. After Law 1.0 is related to facts, it puts forward new understandings. We call it Law 2.0. Legislation and law amendment can also be regarded as this process, but the procedures for legislation and law amendment are slow and complicated. If a new type of case arises, we cannot wait for the law to be revised before deciding. Therefore, when the existing legal norms are not symmetrical to the facts, we need to judicially interpret the norms. On what basis do you base your explanation? You have to put forward your own theories and opinions in order to explain it reasonably. So at this time, jurisprudence plays a big role. In this sense, although jurisprudence sounds very theoretical, it is also highly practical, so jurisprudence is also a required course for law majors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zheng Yongliu during his study tour at the University of Oslo, Norway. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/b12ad55cd6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;732&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/b12ad55cd6 .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zheng Yongliu while visiting the University of Oslo, Norway. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The combination of &quot;accidental&quot; and &quot;inevitable&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Does the label &quot;the first doctor of jurisprudence after the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; have a big impact on your future life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Judging from the time I got my degree, I am the first doctor of jurisprudence in the country. But when we entered school, there were actually two of us. The other one was my junior sister, and she delayed her graduation by one year. For many years after I graduated, I would not consciously mention it. It’s only in the last five or six years that some people started posting this on social media, and more people followed it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tag does not bring me much added value. Of course, my doctoral thesis is the starting point of my academic work. It can also be said that it established my academic confidence. Later, more people paid attention to me, not just because of this paper, but because I later published a series of research results in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, I publish the magazine of the International Association for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy (IVR), which is also the top international publication in the field of legal philosophy, &quot;Transactions on Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy&quot; Three papers were published on Archives for Philosophy of Law and Social Philosophy, one of which was &quot;On the Practical Philosophy of Law&quot; published in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back at your study experience now, I feel that many important choices were An accidental result? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If it wasn’t because of illness, I wouldn’t have time to review, and maybe I wouldn’t be able to get into college; if I had successfully become a navy when I was a fisherman , I would not have been admitted to university; if I had studied history in university, I would not have become a doctor of jurisprudence. For example, when I graduated from college, I wanted to engage in practice. At that time, many of my classmates went to work in government agencies, but the school allowed me to stay in school. I originally liked international law, but was assigned to teach jurisprudence. Later, I went abroad, and my first choice was to go to the United States. The University of Wisconsin, a stronghold of legal sociology, accidentally ended up at Saarland University, which ranks among the top universities in legal philosophy in Germany. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So it is true that there are too many accidents, and there are also inevitable consequences among too many accidents. It is impossible to say for sure. But going to college really opened a window for me to see a bigger world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you were asked to send a message to current college students, what would you do? explain? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zheng Yongliu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Sometimes students come to ask me, and I say that I really can’t say anything good, so it’s better not to say it. I am also telling myself now not to educate students or ask them to do what they want. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If I have to say something, this is not a message. I always emphasize that everyone, not just students, must have their own independent thoughts and not blindly follow fads and mainstream trends. Freedom of thought is the most worthy pursuit. I usually don&#39;t write these things for students, but sometimes when I say goodbye to students, they insist on asking me to write something. I once wrote this sentence: &quot;Tranquility leads to freedom, and freedom leads to scholarship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[悔婚拒退彩礼引发血案：当从悲剧中吸取教训丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Surveillance video circulated online shows that at 13:38 on November 11, two people were killed in a mahjong parlor in Liangshan, Sichuan. A woman playing mahjong was killed by two men with knives. According to media reports, insiders revealed that a knife-wielding man and a woman who was hacked were originally lovers and had paid a bride price of 300,000 yuan, but the woman regretted the marriage and was only willing to return 150,000 yuan. The two men are father and son, and the other woman is related to the woman who regretted her marriage. The next day, local police stated that the two assailants were controlled by the police on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tragedy sparked a lot of discussion. A mother said: &quot;Ever since my daughter entered the society, I have taught her that it is OK to fall in love, but you cannot use other people&#39;s money. You are not allowed to accept money or transfers from others!&quot; Some netizens said: &quot;You can go to the court to sue and demand She would not go to this step to return the gift.&quot; However, someone immediately appeared to give their own testimony or quoted the news to prove how difficult it is to return the bride price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nature of betrothal gifts is different from the betrothal gifts in traditional society. There is a wedding ceremony of a scholar in &quot;Book of Rites&quot;. Scholars were the lowest class of nobles; there were six rites for marrying a wife, namely nacai, asking for a name, naji, nazheng, asking for a date and personally welcoming. Nazheng was the betrothal gift. This set of common people was imitated and integrated into traditional marriage customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Betrothal gift is a &quot;new custom&quot; that has emerged in recent years. What is worrying is that betrothal gifts are becoming more and more popular. Not only are the prices getting higher and higher, but there is also a trend of generalization. Betrothal gifts were not available in some places, but now they are beginning to be given. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current legal definition of bride price is &quot;a gift for the purpose of marriage.&quot; The biggest problem caused by this characterization is that it has given rise to the stereotype that &quot;getting married is starting a business and getting divorced is getting rich&quot;. Some women disappear immediately after taking the bride price, or after receiving the marriage certificate, they refuse to live with the man, and then ask for a divorce in order to keep the high-priced bride price as their own. When more such incidents occur, social problems arise, and the judicial system has no choice but to add some patches to this characterization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme People’s Court’s Interpretation on the Application of the Marriage and Family Section of the Civil Code of the People’s Republic of China (1) Article 5 stipulates: If a party requests the return of a betrothal gift paid in accordance with customs, if it is found that it falls under the following circumstances, the People’s Court It should be supported: (1) Both parties have not completed the marriage registration procedures; (2) Both parties have completed the marriage registration procedures but have not lived together; (3) Pre-marriage payments have caused difficulties in the payer&#39;s life. The application of the provisions of the second and third items of the preceding paragraph shall be conditional on the divorce of both parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In judicial practice, some courts will use their discretion to determine whether and how much the bride price should be refunded based on the length of the marriage. Mastering the stick, but aiming for the yard. Some women have come up with some tricks: maintain the marriage for one year and then file for divorce, so that the probability of the court ruling to return the bride price is very small; install cameras at home, refuse to live as a couple, and use various methods to anger the man and induce him to take action. Photographing it will be evidence of domestic violence, so that the court will justifiably support the woman&#39;s various claims. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, a man in Zhumadian, Henan Province released a video saying that his wife had domestically abused him and set a fire indoors. The incident occurred at around two o&#39;clock in the morning on June 16, 2023. The video shows: the man was robbed of his mobile phone and was slapped by the woman without fighting back; the woman set fires in many places in the house, and the flames were visible on the sofa, dining table and kitchen trash can, and the man followed and doused them one by one. The man said that he had spent all his parents’ savings in order to get married, spending a total of nearly 200,000 yuan including 100,000 yuan in betrothal gifts. Now, after only four months of marriage, the woman is about to get divorced. “Tell me to get out of here, just a penny of betrothal gifts.” Neither will retreat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Rule of Law Daily&quot; report, recently, the Henan Provincial High Court concluded a divorce dispute case. In March 2022, the man Xiao Yijing introduced him to the woman Xiaoshuang. In May of the same year, the two registered their marriage; in July of the same year, Xiaoshuang announced that she was pregnant and had an abortion that month due to fetal abnormalities. Subsequently, Xiaoshuang sued for divorce, and Xiaoya agreed to the divorce, but countersued for the return of the 186,000 yuan gift. In both the first instance and the second instance, the court ruled that the parties were divorced, but did not support the request for return of the bride price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoya was dissatisfied and applied for retrial. After the court retrial, it was found that in the original trial, Xiaoya advocated that Xiao Shuang asked for the name of the marriage, and said that after the lawsuit, he found that Xiao Shuang had married 6 men before marriage, and all were pregnant in the short term after marriage. , And all received expensive gifts. The court believes that Cai Li is paid for the purpose of forming a family for a marriage and a long -term common life, otherwise it will violate the true meaning of the Lottery Ceremony, and it should be returned, but only 100,000 will be returned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If you divorce after a short -term pregnancy after marriage, it may be true; such a routine of seven successively is really small. The woman is probably to deceive the gift, the purpose is to establish evidence of common life. But even so, the 186,000 gifts received in the seventh marriage can still retain 86,000, and the &quot;profit margin&quot; is too high; coupled with the first six collected gifts, I am afraid that it will easily make a million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In this context, it can more deeper analysis of how the Liangshan tragedy happened. Liangshan is a very poor place in Sichuan. After receiving 300,000 gifts, only 150,000 were received. For the father and son, it was equivalent to taking away their two. Moreover, if you really want to go to the court to prosecute, the court may not be retired; even if he retreats, the woman may not perform: At present, more than 10,000 people who have become dishonesty due to the dispute between colorful gifts. After the tragedy, the two murderers will also pay a heavy price for their actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cai Li is a thing with inherent contradictions: those who can afford colorful gifts often do not need to have colorful gifts; but people who can&#39;t afford colorful gifts or are very difficult, they need to give up the gift. And it is a high -priced gift. In order to afford colorful gifts, such families often save money, borrow or even borrow usury. If the latter encounters a &quot;divorce to get rich&quot; routine to deceive Cai Li, it is difficult to accept it, which may resort to extreme means, causing irreparable consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; When facing the dispute of colorful gifts, it is necessary to take a reasonable and legal approach to solve it to safeguard their rights and interests in accordance with the law. But while thinking about the aforementioned tragedy, it is also necessary to reflect on the legal characteristics of Cai Li, and judicialness cannot promote the &quot;divorce to get rich&quot; routine. Only when you have money to return money and property back to property can marriage be marry. If marriage becomes a tool for re -distribution of wealth, it will stimulate and encourage the evil of human nature. It will hurt the marriage and the property. The tragedy that will happen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山西永聚煤业发生火灾，已致11人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260696]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:25:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yongju Coal Industry Joint Construction in Lishi District, Luliang City, Shanxi Province A fire broke out in the building around 6:50 a.m. today (16th). As of press time, 11 people have been confirmed dead, and the specific casualties are still being counted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to on-site information, the building on fire has 4 floors. A total of 63 people have been evacuated so far, 51 of whom were sent to Luliang First People&#39;s Hospital for treatment. Rescue is still in progress and the cause of the fire is under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑猩猩没有“祖母假说”模式？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260599]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When talking about chimpanzees, our close relatives, we cannot fail to mention British biologists, animal behaviorists and famous animal conservationists. Jane Goodall is a person who studied chimpanzees, but the “grandmother hypothesis” in this article is not based on Goodall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The documentary film &quot;The Legendary Life of Jane Goodall&quot; shot by the BBC and Goodall&#39;s book &quot;The Book of Hope: Jane Goodall on Human Survival, Future and Action&quot; give people a deeper understanding of Learn about chimpanzees and how they live like humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his 38 years of living with chimpanzees, Goodall discovered that chimpanzees can use tools (putting plant stems into ant nests to detect, using tree sticks to reach into the water to retrieve food), and they can also Making tools (removing leaves from plant stems) breaks the long-held belief that only humans can make tools. At the same time, chimpanzees will also form teams to hunt other small mammals, and wars will occur between different groups of chimpanzees, and weapons will be used in the battles. There are also some chimpanzees that attack and kill their own kind, sometimes just for fun. Chimpanzee society also has a strict hierarchical system. Each chimpanzee has its own status in society. Their overt and covert fights for social status are no less than that of humans. These findings also break the previous belief that war and cannibalism are uniquely human behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in addition to Goodall, other researchers have studied chimpanzees and found that chimpanzees also have a &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model similar to humans, but this model in chimpanzees is much weaker. The &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; means that healthy and surviving grandmothers and grandfathers can help take care of their grandchildren, increase their survival rate, and thus help their children have more children. This health effect, in turn, ensures the inheritance of your grandmother’s longevity genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the University of California, Santa Barbara, compared three groups of chimpanzees, hunter-gatherers, and horticultural producers and found that people’s production contributions in old age also exist, and are far greater. Higher than chimpanzees. Chimpanzees can have a 20% food or material surplus in their gathering and production capacity at age 30, 7% at age 40, and only 2% at age 50. But hunter-gatherers have a production surplus of 66% at age 30, 45% at age 40, and 24% at age 50. A horticultural producer&#39;s production surplus is 64% at age 30, 40% at age 40, and 21% at age 50. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this comparison, we can know that after chimpanzees enter old age, their production capacity drops significantly, and their ability to help their families and grandchildren also drops off a cliff. Therefore, even if chimpanzees have the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model, its effect is limited. Not big. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, a new study completely rejects the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model in chimpanzees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A team composed of research institutions such as Arizona State University in the United States, the University of California, Los Angeles, and the Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology in Germany studied the Ngo in Kibale National Park in western Uganda. A 20-year study of the wild chimpanzee community in Ngogo found that female chimpanzees in the community will survive menopause and childbirth, but they will not help their daughters raise grandchildren when they enter old age, nor will they live in nearby. Therefore, chimpanzees do not have a social system supported by grandparents, that is, there is no &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model. But Ngogo&#39;s female chimpanzees still live beyond their reproductive years and beyond, even to old age alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no survival problem in old age for chimpanzees in captivity because humans will provide them with good food, nutrition and medical care. However, chimpanzees in the wild will not be so lucky. Survival mode is more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To study the lifestyle and survival patterns of chimpanzees in the wild, researchers from the joint research team studied 185 female chimpanzees from group statistics collected from 1995 to 2016. Mortality and fertility rates, the proportion of time the observed female chimpanzees spent in sterilization as adults was calculated, and hormone levels were measured in urine samples from 66 female chimpanzees. The female chimpanzees varied in reproductive and sterilization status, survival and age, ranging from 14 to 67 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This research process was very arduous, lasting decades and thousands of hours of fieldwork in Ngogo before collecting chimpanzee urine samples to study menopausal hormone levels. . Hormone studies in chimpanzee urine are similar to those in humans, monitoring changes in levels of follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) and luteinizing hormone (LH), as well as ovarian steroid hormones including estrogen and progesterone. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These hormonal changes can determine whether chimpanzees have entered menopause. The estrogen levels of human menopausal women are below 100pmol/L, and the progesterone levels are below 2.2nmol/L. By comparing them with female chimpanzees, we can know whether they are menopausal and have entered menopause (sterilization state). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers found that, like other groups of chimpanzees and humans, the chimpanzees they studied lost fertility after age 30 and became infertile after age 50. Meanwhile, some data collected on hormone levels in chimpanzees show that menopause in Ngogo female chimpanzees is similar to that in humans, starting around age 50. Female chimpanzees reach adulthood at the age of 14, and spend about one-fifth of their adult life in the sterilization period, which is about half of the sterilization period of humans. That is, the old age of chimpanzees after entering menopause is only half of that of humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Menopause for chimpanzees means the beginning of old age, but Ngogo female chimpanzees can live over 50 years old even if they do not take care of their grandchildren and do not live with their children. Chimpanzees are prone to death from diseases originating from humans and have little natural immunity to these diseases, so living over 50 years is considered a long life, and living to 67 years is considered a long life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can Ngogo&#39;s chimpanzees survive into old age without the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model? The answer suggested by the study is that their post-neuter lifespan may be a temporary response to extremely favorable ecological conditions, as the group enjoys a stable and abundant food supply and they are isolated from human-induced stress. Survive longer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some researchers such as primatologist Susan Alberts of Duke University in the United States doubt this result because not all chimpanzees will go through menopause. Alberts believes that in most chimpanzee populations outside the Ngogo group, adult females live to be around 30 years old because they are stressed by predators, disease or other factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Alberts admitted that the study&#39;s results were so solid that she couldn&#39;t refute them. But she believes the next step should be to conduct similar long-term studies in larger populations of wild chimpanzees to determine whether Ngogo chimpanzees are unique in that they survive longer beyond their reproductive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[螺蛳粉疯狂布局线下门店，能否成为下一个兰州拉面？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260351]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since this year, snail noodle restaurant stores have grown rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xiao Lu, a netizen who lives in Guangzhou, said that several snail noodle stores have recently opened in the business district near her home, many of which are chain stores of a certain snail noodle brand. ——This has aroused the curiosity of many netizens: Has snail noodles also begun to focus on offline stores? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the characteristics of &quot;smells bad, tastes delicious, and is very popular&quot;, snail noodles have become a popular Internet celebrity food in just a few years. The sales volume of the channel remains high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, compared with its popularity online, the offline development of snail noodles has obvious shortcomings. What kind of distinction does the online and offline development of snail noodles show? How can snail noodles achieve offline breakthrough? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258356&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot; >;&lt;strong>;Hot online sales&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Snail noodles originated from the Liuzhou Night Market in the 1970s. It gradually became popular in the 1980s, but it was mainly limited to the local area, and then slowly spread to all of Guangxi and the neighboring Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2012, &quot;A Bite of China&quot; brought snail fans more into the public eye, but for people outside the Guangdong and Guangxi regions, it is still only As the name suggests, Luosifeng’s offline stores have not expanded too much to other provinces, and there are no online sales channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2014, Liuzhou’s first prepackaged snail noodle company was registered, and industrially produced bagged snail noodle appeared. At the beginning of 2015, the Liuzhou Municipal Government proposed the development concept of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; of Liuzhou&#39;s snail noodles, and determined the road for Liuzhou&#39;s snail noodles industry to be packaged and industrialized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2016 is the first year of live broadcasting. Luosi fans have keenly grasped the trend of the times and jumped on the &quot;Internet +&quot; short video and live broadcast express. The characteristics of &quot;smellful and smelly&quot; are quite contagious and quickly spread out of the circle through online channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2019, the industry output value of Liuzhou&#39;s bagged snail noodles exceeded 6 billion yuan. The impact of the epidemic, the rise of the &quot;stay-at-home economy&quot;, and the booming live-streaming of goods have boosted the online popularity of snail noodles. In 2020, the annual output value of bagged snail noodles exceeded 10 billion. In 2022, the sales revenue of the entire industry chain of Liuzhou snail noodles will be 60.07 billion yuan, and the sales revenue of bagged snail noodles will be 18.18 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Naturally, the online sales of snail noodles account for half of the total. iiMedia Research’s research data shows that among the channels through which Chinese snail noodle consumers purchase products, online shopping malls rank first with a proportion of 78.70%. Other data show that in 2022, 113 million snail noodle packages were sent through express delivery channels, becoming the first single product in Guangxi with an annual delivery volume exceeding 100 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The popularity of snail noodles online is not only due to its close integration with &quot;Internet +&quot;, but also because it fits the &quot;fast food life&quot; of this generation of young people. The characteristics of the food require that the food should not only be convenient and efficient, but also sufficient and delicious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Other instant noodles have few ingredients. Snail noodles are rich in ingredients, including yuba, pickled bamboo shoots, pickled beans, fungus, peanuts, dried radish and other common accessories. Bao snail rice noodles have everything, and they are more attractive to young people’s stomachs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258357&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot; >;&lt;strong>;Offline stores have shortcomings&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, compared with the popularity of online stores, offline stores of snail noodles have obvious shortcomings. plate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, there are now more than 40,000 offline stores of snail noodles. Compared with the approximately 500,000 offline stores of Lanzhou Ramen, It&#39;s like a small witch can see a big witch. Not to mention, the annual sales of Lanzhou Ramen are roughly estimated to exceed 400 billion yuan, which is several times that of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, relevant data shows that the average offline catering chain rate of snail noodles is only 15%, compared with 45% for tea drinks. Coffee is 55%, which shows that there is no strong enough brand of snail noodles to go offline, and the risk of &quot;having a category but not a brand&quot; has intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only that, there are also some worrying aspects regarding the existing offline stores of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First, the offline stores of snail noodles are mainly concentrated in Guangxi and Guangdong, and the national penetration rate is still relatively low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, iiMedia Consulting data shows that from 2020 to February 2023, most of the new snail noodle companies are located in Guangdong and Guangxi, and the proportion of snail noodle companies in Guangxi is as high as 21.63% and 21.21% of snail noodle companies are located in Guangdong Province. This is much weaker than the national radiation intensity of Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, due to the low chain rate, many offline snail noodle stores are small &quot;mom-and-pop&quot;-style workshops with varying tastes and quality, and individual stores are hygienic. The worrying situation has lowered consumers’ trust in offline stores of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some time ago, rumors spread widely that &quot;there were many mice jumping up and down in the back kitchen of a snail noodle shop in Chongqing.&quot; Although the Municipal Supervision Bureau of Jiulongpo District, Chongqing made a report stating that law enforcement officers did an on-site inspection and found no traces of rats in the snail noodle shop; the video was taken in March this year, because the decoration of the shop next door damaged the flue outlet of the shop, causing rats to enter After discovering the situation in the back kitchen, the person in charge of the store immediately carried out disinfection and repairs and rectifications in the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Such rumors have done great harm to the offline stores of Luosi Fen, and also reflect the public&#39;s concerns about food safety issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thirdly, offline snail noodles stores only offer a single variety of food, and relying solely on snail noodles will limit the development of offline stores. For example, Lanzhou Ramen Shop not only offers ramen noodles, but also Northwest-style pasta products such as rice bowls, steamed buns, and cold noodles; Shaxian snacks include mixed noodles, steamed dumplings, flat dishes, duck leg rice, and other choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258355&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; color: #aaa; &quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot; >;&lt;strong>;The snail noodles&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;stand out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, compared with the offline stores of Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian Snacks, Sloan noodles are blooming everywhere, and offline stores of snail noodles still have broad room for expansion, but this does not mean that snail noodles should &quot;underestimate themselves&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, compared with Lanzhou Ramen, the development route of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; of snail noodles is earlier and more mature. There are many ramen noodle restaurants in Lanzhou, but they are also faced with the embarrassment of &quot;having categories but not brands&quot;. This is a shortcoming that Lanzhou ramen is now making great efforts to make up for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To successfully break through, snail powder offline stores must, on the one hand, give full play to the advantages of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; and transform the current few stores into The snail noodle brand continues to grow bigger and stronger, and the chain layout is accelerated. It is necessary to establish both the category and the brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, efforts should be made to industrialize the supply chain and build a professional, platform-based supply chain service provider to fill the gap in the snail noodle supply chain business. Blank, so that even small workshop-style snail noodle stores can obtain stable quality snail noodle raw materials, so that consumers can taste snail noodle with stable taste and stabilize the reputation of offline snail noodle stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Third, as a regional delicacy, if snail noodles want to conquer the stomachs of people across the country, in addition to making authentic snail noodles, we also need to enrich the line. The gourmet food category in the lower store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​way is to focus on snail noodles but also sell other local delicacies from Liuzhou and even Guangxi to enrich consumers&#39; choice space, such as some from Liuzhou Local delicacies, such as Yong Tau Foo Pao, Niu Xianzi, Yun Pian Cake, Miao Sour Pork, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another way is to combine it with local cuisine and move toward integration, launching cross-category meals, stir-fries, soups, etc. This kind of integration poses a very big challenge to the management of chain brands, which must not only ensure standardization, but also successfully &quot;do as the Romans do.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although snail noodles have fully opened up the online space, if snail noodles want to continue to break through the upper limit of the industry, they must walk both online and offline. Luosifen offline stores are accelerating the layout. Whether it can create miracles like online stores is worth waiting to see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么年轻人不愿意生孩子？社会学家山田昌弘谈日本低生育困境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260643]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6Ignwi5oPp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1039&quot; height=&quot;1559&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6I gnwi5oPp. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Japanese sociologist Yamada Masahiro, professor at Chuo University, specializes in family sociology and emotional society Xuexue, etc., are the authors of &quot;Society with a Few Births&quot;, &quot;The Era of Marriage&quot;, &quot;The Low-Birth Trap&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Masahiro Yamada, a professor at Chuo University in Japan, has been deeply involved in the field of family sociology for many years. Before high school, he once wanted to be a mathematician, but &quot;because I don&#39;t have a family of my own, I decided to explore what family love is&quot; and since then entered the &quot;world of studying messy families.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When teaching in school, he used a lot of family materials to tell the origin, current situation and whereabouts of modern Japanese families. The seminars he held with students were on cutting-edge topics and discussed issues such as: To what extent do people need to &quot;rent friends&quot; when they are lonely? Does &quot;cohabiting partnership marriage&quot; (note: only cohabitation without marriage) explore another possibility beyond the current marriage system? There are more and more single young people in Japan. Where can their emotional needs for intimacy be met? He finally found some answers in cabaret clubs (note: places that provide singing and dancing performances), real or virtual idols, and pets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the book &quot;The Low Fertility Trap&quot;, Masahiro Yamada tries to answer a question: Why are young people in Japan reluctant to have children in recent years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Low fertility rate has always been a dark cloud lingering over Japanese society. Since 1989, Japan&#39;s fertility rate has continued to be sluggish, with the total fertility rate remaining below 1.6 for more than 30 years. In 2022, it reached a historical low of 1.26. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Since 1989, Japan&#39;s fertility rate has continued to be sluggish, with the total fertility rate below 1.6 for more than 30 years, and it reached a historical low of 1.26 in 2022 . The picture shows a still from the Japanese drama &quot;Obstetrician Kotori&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past thirty years, Japanese society has tried to solve this &quot;stubborn disease&quot;, but with little success. Yamada Masahiro was a member of the Committee on Countermeasures against Birthrate Reduction. Once, a committee member proposed holding a publicity campaign titled &quot;Parenting is Wonderful&quot; to increase the public&#39;s enthusiasm for childbirth. &quot;Many insightful people and policy leaders in Japanese society have ignored for a long time two important factors directly related to the cause of Japan&#39;s declining birthrate, namely &#39;non-marriage&#39; and &#39;the widening gap in the economic level of young people&#39; .&quot; Yamada believes, &quot;For the majority of people who &#39;want to have children but do not have the conditions, so they do not have children&#39;, it is meaningless to carry out such publicity activities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yamada Masahiro&#39;s view , young people’s desire to have children is linked to the overall economic status of society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1955, the Japanese economy entered a period of rapid growth. The prosperous economic environment gave rise to young people&#39;s positive expectations for the future. They tended to believe that through personal efforts, they could join the &quot;middle class&quot; and live a better life than their parents. A better, richer life. &quot;From World War II to about 1980, people did not think about the great risks in their economic life after marriage. At that time, men could count on becoming full-time employees, and their income would be based on the &#39;seniority system&#39; (note: wages will vary according to merit). (increasing with age and length of service).&quot; In Yamada Masahiro&#39;s view, people of that generation firmly believed that their children would grow up in a better environment than themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, the situation reversed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Entering the Heisei Era (Note: January 8, 1989), Japan&#39;s economic structure was adjusted, and a large number of informal employees (referring to fixed-term employees, part-time employees, dispatched employees, etc.) appeared. Social gaps have arisen in terms of employment, which in turn has led to gaps between the rich and poor families and the educational environment of their children, and the polarization of society has further developed.&quot; Masahiro Yamada said in an interview with Japanese media, &quot;For most informal employees, regardless of whether No matter how hard I try, I can&#39;t earn the income that will allow me to live a prosperous life in the future, nor can I get married and start a family. In other words, my future has become hopeless.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yamada observed, The Japanese pay more attention to the significance of marriage from an economic perspective and will make a careful risk assessment before making a decision to get married. The evaluation often starts from two perspectives: first, whether the standard of living after marriage will be better than before marriage, or at least not worse; second, whether after marriage, the child can create a better growth environment than oneself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Behind this view on marriage and childbearing are the unique values ​​of modern Japanese society: the hope to avoid risks in future life. The Japanese regard maintaining a middle-class living standard as their highest goal and believe that in life design, The series of issues of &#39;men and women dating&#39;, &#39;marriage&#39;, &#39;childbirth&#39;, &#39;child rearing&#39; and &#39;children&#39;s education&#39; are not single and separated, but are intertwined.&quot; Yamada Masahiro in the paper &quot;East Asian Characteristics of the Low Birth Rate Problem&quot; wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This awareness of risk also extends to the relationship stage. Yamada found that in Japan, many young people are even losing their desire to fall in love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NHK Broadcasting Culture Research Institute once conducted a survey of Japanese middle and high school students and found that the proportions of middle and high school students who &quot;have a crush&quot; were 41% and 54% respectively in 1982. In 2012, this figure dropped sharply to 25% and 31%. In 2014, the Japanese Cabinet Office conducted a survey on young people and found that more than one-third of the respondents preferred to spend time on work and study, and 46.2% felt that &quot;love is troublesome.&quot; In Yamada Masahiro’s view, “trouble” may mean “not cost-effective”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, when the phenomenon of declining birthrate first appeared in Japanese society, demographers held a mainstream view: young people just postponed marriage to enjoy single life, and one day they would get married. . Masahiro Yamada believes that such a logical basis may not be established. Over the past few decades, as Japanese society has gradually developed into a &quot;high-consumption society&quot;, the anxiety and pressure of childcare has also hit young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In December 2022, on the streets of Tokyo, Japan, a couple took wedding photos on the streets decorated with Christmas lights. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China Map/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Japan’s National Institute of Social Security and Population Issues conducted a survey on 30 -Why married women in the 34-year-old age group fail to have the expected number of children? 81.1% of the survey respondents believe that the reason is that &quot;the raising and education of children is too expensive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yamada’s view, modern society’s expectations for the function of marriage and childbearing are different from pre-modern society. In a society centered on agricultural production, childbirth means supplementing the labor force. Parents place expectations on their children to inherit the family business and take care of their parents later in life. Children are a kind of &quot;productive property.&quot; But after the 1950s, Japan began to &quot;nuclear family&quot; with reference to the family system in Europe and the United States. A couple and their unmarried children became the basic family unit. In modern society, raising children requires a large amount of childcare money, and children have therefore become &quot;consumable property.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The significance of children as a labor force no longer exists, and when the nuclear family becomes a principle, it is difficult to expect children to provide support and care in their old age. In addition, parents who can let their children inherit the family business It has also become less.&quot; Yamada Masahiro wrote in &quot;The Low Birth Trap&quot; that unlike European and American parents who enjoy the joy and fun of parenting itself, many times, East Asian parents care about whether to have a &quot;high-value&quot; child—— In the social evaluation system established by external factors such as academic qualifications and work, whether children can take the top spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yamada believes that East Asian parents often have a &quot;protective feeling&quot; for their children and do not want their children to &quot;live a hard life&quot;. It is also part of the value of parents for children to receive help from their parents when they receive higher education and even become adults. . As a result, the age of responsibility of East Asian parents for their children has been extended indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, Japanese sociologist Masahiro Yamada accepted a written interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;East Asian parents take it for granted that they spend money on their children&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;China&#39;s total fertility rate fell to 1.09 in 2022, which is lower than Japan&#39;s 1.26 and higher than South Korea&#39;s 0.78. In 2022, the total fertility rate of the three East Asian countries dropped to historical lows. You have done a lot of research on fertility wishes in Japan. Why are young people reluctant to have children? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In East Asia (China, Japan and South Korea), marriage and childcare are first considered from an economic perspective. When people raise children, they will want to spend more money on their children than their parents raised themselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past (50 years ago in Japan and 30 years ago in China and South Korea), the lives of most young people’s parents and the lives of young people themselves were relatively poor. And since society as a whole is in a period of economic growth, young people&#39;s future income can be expected to increase. So, at that time, it would be easier, and in fact it was, to spend more money on your own children than your own parents had raised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, starting 30 years ago in Japan and 10 years ago in China and South Korea, the children of the previous generation whose parents spent more money to raise them now have to spend money to raise their own children. These young people often have parents who are wealthier than themselves. In China, due to the large number of only children, the cost of this generation of only children is estimated to be more than twice that of Japan and South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is very difficult to spend more money on children born in the future when economic growth is slowing down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The process of family modernization in East Asian society is to imitate and learn from the European and American nuclear family. Process and the same social model, why do East Asian countries currently face more severe fertility difficulties than European and American societies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;East Asian countries only imitate the nuclear family model, but due to different social environments and traditions, the feedback these models receive will naturally vary. different. For example, parents in East Asia believe that spending money on children is natural and can bring a lot of emotional value; they believe in the love between parents and children more than the love between husband and wife. This also leads to a significant reduction in the need for marriage if one does not plan to have children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Europe and the United States believe that it is necessary to raise children until adulthood, while East Asian countries believe that it is natural to bear the cost of higher education for children. In contrast, parents in East Asian countries have to shoulder more childcare responsibilities and often need help solving various problems their children encounter even after they become adults. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past few years, the Chinese government has introduced some policies to encourage childbirth. For example, the three-child policy and the establishment of a childcare subsidy system have been proposed in many places. You said in &quot;The Low Fertility Trap&quot; that the Japanese government failed to seize the best opportunity to intervene in low fertility, and Japan&#39;s low birthrate policy failed. What lessons and inspiration can Japan’s experience bring to other countries? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We must consider reducing the burden of children’s education fees. A quarter of young people feel uneasy about the future, which is the main reason for Japan&#39;s declining birthrate. Measures should be taken so that young people will not feel insecure about not being able to live a prosperous life in the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We must transform our society into a society where every young person has hope that his children will not suffer in the future. That is, building a society where jobs are re-startable, equally friendly to two-income families, and where social security can help us get back on our feet if things go wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can you combine your own with that of your previous and next generations? Experience, talk about the changes in the situation and concepts of marriage and childbirth among young people in Japan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yamada Masahiro: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The concept itself has not changed much. If there is an expectation of living a relatively good life, then it is natural to get married and have children. The difference may be that people of the previous generation would have thought that they could live a prosperous life on their husband&#39;s income alone (about 30 years ago). Even today, nearly three-quarters of young people who are able to meet expectations are already married and have children. The reason why the remaining one-quarter of young people do not choose to get married and have children is mostly because their income is unstable and they are unable to They expect to live a relatively good life after getting married and having children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Is marriage and childbirth a matter of decency? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You put forward a point: wait for the one that suits you The idea that a partner appears and then gets married was once generally accepted, but now it is difficult to bring people into marriage. If today&#39;s young people want to get married, they need to participate in &quot;marriage activities&quot; (note: various activities to find marriage partners, first proposed by Yamada Masahiro). Why is there such a change? Isn’t it possible to get married if you don’t participate in the wedding ceremony? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because there are fewer places where young people can meet each other naturally. Not to mention men, even women&#39;s so-called &quot;men will take the initiative to strike up a conversation even if they don&#39;t take the initiative&quot; has become less common. The community or enterprises have to provide some opportunities so that young men and women can have more contact. If you want to find a marriage partner, you should still take active action. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Marriage&quot; is called blind date in China. For people born in the 1970s and 1980s in China, free love and marriage were a common view on marriage and love when they were young, but among today&#39;s young people, the concept of being well-matched is being revived. Are there similar changes in the concept of marriage in Japanese society? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In Japan, the consciousness of “fall in love first and then get married” has not changed. Young people&#39;s longing for love and marriage and their distaste for parents interfering with free love are still relatively strong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although we don’t care so much about the target’s family background, the economic life after marriage, that is, the overall family income of the couple after marriage, is a very important reference factor. Today&#39;s young people have a very strong sense of being &quot;middle-class.&quot; Most of them feel that they were in a middle-class life when they were with their parents, so they really don&#39;t want to fall from the middle-class life after marriage. This is also a habit of &quot;avoiding risks&quot; and &quot;valuing respectability.&quot; reflection of Japanese social characteristics. However, Japan does not have the custom like China that the male family needs to contribute a lot of money when getting married. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You seem to place great emphasis on analyzing the motivations for marriage and childbirth at the economic level. . You mentioned that in European and American societies, people do not strongly associate building a family (getting married, having children) with economic status, but not in East Asian societies. Why do East Asian societies place so much emphasis on the correlation between the two? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;East Asians value decency more, which is “face” in Chinese. People don’t want to be seen as having an unhappy marriage or poor parenting. There is a strong sense of shame associated with living a poor life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Europe and the United States, love between husband and wife is the expression of happiness, and the awareness that living in poverty can also be happy is very popular; in East Asian societies, even without love between husband and wife, living A rich life can also be a happy one, and this awareness is very strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a view that in modern families, &quot;the male is the dominant one and the female is the dominant one.&quot; The division of labor within the family means that women have to devote more time and energy to childcare. What do you think of this practical problem? How does Japanese society respond to this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is gradually becoming a prerequisite for a wealthy family to have a certain income and continue working for women. Since there are only a limited number of high-income men who can do &quot;men take care of the outside world and women take care of the house&quot;, in order to raise children in affluent living conditions, it has become very necessary for women to work outside the home and for men to participate in housework. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, this ideal is gradually becoming a reality by popularizing maternity leave and improving the construction of kindergartens. However, the Japanese government&#39;s &quot;two-dimensional support&quot; for women&#39;s work and childcare is obviously far from enough. It is still necessary to continue to improve the working environment, eliminate gender discrimination, and allow more women to engage in meaningful work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Cultivating &quot;high-value&quot; children, a twisted expectation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You mentioned that young people in Japan have the idea that &quot;children cannot be allowed to suffer&quot;. This idea also exists among young people in China. Why do young people care about nurturing children? Has a generation developed such a strong sense of responsibility? Has the meaning of “suffering” changed with the development of the times? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In East Asian societies, it is the responsibility of parents to let their children receive a better education and find a better job than themselves. The meaning of life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the awareness of discrimination among children is also very strong. Today&#39;s young people are worried that their poverty will cause their children to be bullied. When children play together, they sometimes need external hardware like Switch game consoles. If I don’t buy these things, will my children feel pain? This idea among young parents is becoming more and more intense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, it was enough for parents to be able to stay with their children, but now more and more parents feel that it will be uncomfortable if they cannot spend enough money on their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In China, unmarried men and women of working age may be harassed by their parents and elders Those who urge marriage are called bachelors or leftover women, which has a certain derogatory meaning. Is there a similar situation in Japan? How do you understand this phenomenon? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Single = unpopular. This equation will indirectly remind people of whether the reason for not getting married is because men have low incomes. , or is it because there is something wrong with women’s appearance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, because the unmarried rate is very high, people who want to get married but can’t, and people who can but don’t want to get married are mixed together, so simply treating unmarried people Put downs are uncommon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also because the unmarried rate is very high, the pressure from parents is much less than before. Many parents will think that it is better for their children to stay at home alone than to let their children marry someone with a low income and then live a less than ideal life of poverty. In Japan, a growing number of parents believe it is better to keep their children single than to be hung up on strange marriage partners. The awareness of inheriting the family business is gradually declining in Japan (people over 70 years old still have a strong awareness of this awareness). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You mentioned that in pre-modern society, children were a kind of &quot; &quot;Producive property&quot; becomes &quot;consumer property&quot; in modern society, requiring a higher investment in childcare. Having a child with a &quot;high sense of value&quot; becomes the value pursued by parenting behavior, and the sense of high value is determined by the child&#39;s academic qualifications, Depends on factors such as the glamor of the job. Why do parents have such expectations for child care? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The status of children = the status of parents. In East Asian cultural circles, this awareness of face or vanity is very strong. From an emotional point of view, this stems from parents&#39; desire for their children to live a carefree life financially. Although the original intention is good, with the comparison psychology brought about by the consciousness of decency, raising high-value children has become a distorted expectation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;European and American traditions are very different. When children become adults, they no longer depend on their parents financially and have a strong sense of self-responsibility. For parents, children are cute during the upbringing process, but when they grow up, they only expect emotional communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It seems that parenting is gradually evolving into a kind of competition. Is there a &quot;school district housing&quot; and &quot;chicken baby&quot; phenomenon in Japan? Will a highly competitive society have an impact on fertility? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Japan’s job market has relatively loose requirements for academic qualifications, and the salary gap between high school graduates and college graduates is one of the largest in the world. small. In other words, it is possible to live a relatively good life even after graduating from high school or a junior college. Parents don’t need to be so enthusiastic, especially those who have only graduated from high school themselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Young people are becoming more risk-averse&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​possible reason for the decline in young people&#39;s desire to get married is that more and more people realize that marriage is a contractual relationship and that the contract is at risk of breaking. Why do more and more young people tend to make risk assessments about getting married? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For young people, whether they can live a middle-class life in the future is something they are very concerned about. In Japan, before 1990, most young people could expect to rely on the &quot;merit-based system&quot; to live a life with wages increasing every year. However, with the development of globalization, economic risks are increasing, and today&#39;s young people can no longer afford it. Be optimistic that &quot;there will always be a way in the future.&quot; For this reason, young people are becoming more risk-averse. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you live a relatively poor life from the beginning, you generally don’t feel that there is any risk, but many young people today live a quite fulfilling and wealthy life in their teenage years life. The awareness of not wanting to give up this life will be strong. Especially for the generation of Chinese young people who are only children, this awareness should be even stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You mentioned a phenomenon: today’s young people are not even willing to fall in love Desire is fading. South Korea has the &quot;Three Abandonments&quot; (giving up on love, marriage, and childbirth), Japan has &quot;herbivore men&quot; (passive and inactive in love), and some young people in China think falling in love is troublesome. Why do young people lose the desire to fall in love? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because modern young people feel that love relationships will always &quot;cool down.&quot; In Europe and the United States, &quot;being with the person you love&quot; is the meaning of life. However, this idea is not widespread in East Asian countries. In the eyes of many people, falling in love is actually a process of finding a marriage partner. Therefore, they also believe that dating someone who knows they cannot get married is a waste of time and money. More and more people believe that love itself is a matter of worrying about other people&#39;s unhappiness. Because of the expansion of the porn industry, especially in Japan, the sexual value of dating has also decreased. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people meet their love needs through virtual relationships, such as The popular AI boyfriends and girlfriends, or &quot;CP addicts&quot;, gain emotional satisfaction from watching others fall in love. How do you understand these phenomena? Some people also question that obtaining emotional satisfaction through data calculation and monetary payment weakens the complexity of love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yamada Masahiro:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Although I think this is a form of escape, for today&#39;s young people, there are more and more People think this is a more enjoyable time of communication than real love. If the satisfaction of real love decreases, the value of virtual love will increase. Maybe it can no longer be said that satisfaction in reality is superior. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1997 you named the &quot; In recent years, &quot;full-time children&quot; have also appeared in Chinese society, that is, children give up their jobs and go home to take care of housework and provide for their parents. Living expenses are borne by their parents, and some full-time children will also receive wages from their parents. You seem to be interested in emphasizing the connection between &quot;single parasites&quot; and the desire to marry and have children. Can you expand on this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yamada Masahiro:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Before meeting your ideal marriage partner, living a prosperous life with your parents, this kind of &quot;waiting&quot; is very likely There is no end. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Europe and the United States, because adults must be independent from their parents, it is more advantageous for two young people to live together. But in East Asian countries, independence from parents generally means that children can live a better life outside than at home with their parents. It’s okay to “wait” at your parents’ house before meeting the person you want to marry with whom you can live a better life together. Even your parents are looking forward to it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, we have never been able to wait for the ideal person to appear, and there is an endless stream of &quot;former&quot; young people who are slowly aging like this. In Japan, there are an increasing number of unmarried people who are still living with their parents even in middle age. Increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;People usually believe that young people have unlimited possibilities, and it is precisely by actively trying Wrong age group. But you raise the question &quot;Why is society so callous to young people?&quot; Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If, like Europe and the United States, most children leave their parents to become independent when they reach adulthood, then even if they fail in taking risks in society, they will have to start over again. It&#39;s really not that difficult to come here. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in East Asian countries, young people compare themselves with their parents. More and more young people believe that failure to reach the level of their parents is a failure. This is especially true for people who live a prosperous life under the care of their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in Japan, many young people believe that employment and marriage cannot be repeated, which is also one of the important influencing factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贫困生攒钱看演唱会惹争议，该不该限制助学对象高消费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[习近平同美国总统拜登举行中美元首会晤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260688]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:43:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011765296853&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Exclusive video丨Xi Jinping and US President Biden held the China-US Presidential Meeting.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/ 79e1b7263270835011765296853/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b726327083501176 5296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot; 360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b7263270835011765296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local time 11 On March 15, President Xi Jinping held a China-US Presidential Meeting with US President Joe Biden at Philori Estate in San Francisco, USA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the last time Mr. President and I met was in Bali, and it has been a year. A lot has happened in the past year. The world has emerged from the COVID-19 pandemic, but the huge impact of the epidemic remains. The world economy has begun to recover, but it lacks momentum, industrial and supply chains are disrupted, and protectionism is on the rise. These problems are very prominent. As the most important bilateral relationship in the world, China-U.S. relations must be thought and planned against the backdrop of the accelerating changes in the world over the past century, so as to bring benefits to the people of both countries and demonstrate responsibility for human progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that over the past 50 years, Sino-US relations have never been smooth sailing. There will always be problems of one kind or another, and they will always move forward amid twists and turns. It is impossible for such two big countries not to deal with each other. It is unrealistic to try to change each other. No one can bear the consequences of conflict and confrontation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still have the same view. Great power competition is not the background of this era and cannot solve the problems facing China, the United States and the world. This earth can accommodate China and the United States, and our respective successes are opportunities for each other. China and the United States have different histories, cultures, social systems, and development paths. This is an objective reality. However, as long as both sides adhere to mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation, they can transcend differences and find a way for the two major countries to get along correctly. I firmly believe that the future of Sino-US relations is bright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The President and I are at the helm of Sino-US relations and bear heavy responsibilities for the people, the world, and history. I look forward to having an in-depth exchange of views and reaching new consensus with Mr. President today on strategic, overall and directional issues related to China-US relations, as well as major issues related to world peace and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被摘牌的55个中华老字号：停产、换新店、准备重申]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260668]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Ministry of Commerce will review 1,128 time-honored brands in 2023. The picture shows citizens in Suzhou on October 29 At the Golden Autumn Consumer Carnival event for time-honored brands. Pictures and texts have nothing to do with each other. Visual China Pictures&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/14ca44a779.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/14ca44a779.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Ministry of Commerce will review 1,128 time-honored brands in 2023. The picture shows citizens attending the Suzhou Time-honored Brands Golden Autumn Consumption Carnival on October 29. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After being stripped of the &quot;hat&quot; of a time-honored Chinese brand, the inheritor Wu Zhiyong explained to a dozen old customers: Because he missed the time to submit information, he was removed according to regulations, but Wu&#39;s Bacon (brand treasure) Xingshan)&#39;s factories are producing normally and stores are operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 9, 2023, the Ministry of Commerce disclosed the results of the review of Chinese time-honored brands at a regular press conference. Those that have been operating poorly for a long time have even gone bankrupt, canceled, closed down, or have lost the ownership and use rights of registered trademarks of time-honored brands. 55 brands were removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands; 73 brands with poor operations and declining performance were required to be rectified within 6 months; 1,000 brands with standardized operations and good development were continued to be retained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wujia Bacon is one of the 55 brands. Chinese time-honored brands were first selected by the former Ministry of Domestic Trade, and more than 1,600 were rated in 1991. In 2006, the Ministry of Commerce re-certified 429 Chinese time-honored brands in the first batch; in 2010, the Ministry of Commerce recognized 699 in the second batch. As of the beginning of 2023, there are 1,128 Chinese time-honored brands across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2023, in order to promote the innovative development of time-honored brands, the Ministry of Commerce and other five departments issued the &quot;Measures for the Administration of the Demonstration Creation of Chinese Time-honored Brands&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Measures&quot;). In this &quot;Measures&quot;, the &quot;Measures&quot; were established The &quot;traffic light&quot; mechanism, that is, the dynamic management mechanism of &quot;in and out&quot;, takes rectification or removal measures for time-honored brands that do not meet the requirements. In February 2023, the Ministry of Commerce publicly stated that the &quot;honor&quot; of China&#39;s time-honored brands is not once and for all, let alone resting on the credit book to &quot;show off seniority&quot; or &quot;rest on one&#39;s laurels.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months after the &quot;Measures&quot; were issued, the Ministry of Commerce, together with the Ministry of Culture and Tourism and other ministries and commissions, decided to review the existing Chinese time-honored brands and carry out the certification of a new batch of Chinese time-honored brands, so that time-honored brands can &quot;come in and out&quot; . This is the first time that Chinese time-honored brands have been reviewed since they were recognized, but it is not the last time. The &quot;Measures&quot; stipulate that in principle, a new batch of Chinese time-honored brands will be recognized and published every three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;55 time-honored brands delisted&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As of this delisting, Wujia Bacon has been a time-honored brand in China for nearly 30 years. In the early 1990s, Wujia Bacon in Linfen City, Shanxi Province was rated as a Chinese time-honored brand by the former Ministry of Domestic Trade. At that time, Wu Zhiyong, who had just grown up, as the fifth generation successor, was learning the ancestral condiment formula and processing technology from the basics. Now he has reached the age where he knows his destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong told Southern Weekend reporters that because he was busy launching a new production line at the time, he did not pay enough attention to the review. At the same time, it took too much time to search and complete historical data, resulting in missing the time to submit materials. Wu Zhiyong speculated that the removal may be due to Article 20 of the &quot;Measures&quot;: Enterprises are bankrupt, liquidated, disbanded, canceled, have their business licenses revoked, or have not carried out business activities for more than three years. They will be removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands and the right to use the Chinese time-honored brand logo and plaque will be recovered. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company owned by Wujia Bacon is Wujiabaoxing Bacon Products Co., Ltd. in Yaodu District, Linfen City. The company was liquidated in 2017. Wu Zhiyong explained that the company was jointly run by his father Wu Baoshan and his second uncle. Due to their old age and poor health, and the original bacon processing factory was demolished due to urban expansion in 2014, the two &quot;retired&quot;, and the Wu family bacon business also hiatus for 6 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 55 brands that have been removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands, many are in a similar situation to Wu’s Bacon. Southern Weekend reporters found out that most of the brand companies that were removed from the directory were canceled, bankrupt, removed from the list, etc., and even seriously violated the law. Some legal representatives of the companies were also listed as dishonest persons subject to execution, and high consumption was restricted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact the 55 brands on the removal list, but most of them refused to be interviewed, except for some that could not be contacted. Among the few brands interviewed, the reasons for delisting varied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of Shanxi Yanhu brand told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;When the last order on the handle is completed, I will never do it again.&quot; The person in charge of Inner Mongolia Dashengkui brand said that the company is still open, but it is not Produced, just to maintain the brand. Anhui Shouchuntang said that it is in the process of changing its store and will wait until a new place is found. The person in charge of Shanxi Mingquanbao said that the company is still open, but it is no longer producing, &quot;because the national standards do not allow the use of current boilers, and production can be resumed after replacing new boilers.&quot; The person in charge of the Shandong Shi Toad brand said that he had no idea about being &quot;kicked out&quot; of a Chinese time-honored brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a businessman, a Southern Weekend reporter consulted a relevant person from the Circulation Development Department of the Ministry of Commerce. The other party replied: &quot;There are various reasons for being removed. It is not just bankruptcy or no longer operating that will be removed. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In real scenarios, the decline of some Chinese time-honored brands is more intuitive. Beijing Hua Nv Underwear, which was approved by the Ministry of Commerce in 2010 to become a time-honored brand in China, was founded in 1938. It was the first women&#39;s products store in Beijing. It once proposed that Chinese women wear &quot;Hua Nv&quot; underwear. There is no trace of the Chinese lingerie brand that once opened a store on Wangfujing Street. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Linlang Wedding Photography Shop, once located in Shangxiajiu Commercial Street, Guangzhou, was founded in 1947. At that time, it was the largest photography shop in Liwan District where it was located. Now the store has been occupied by sports brands. Granny Chen, who is nearly 80 years old, recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that the previous photo studio was a two-story arcade, which belonged to a high-end consumer brand. She had taken work photos at Linlang Photo Studio in the 1970s, but never wedding photos. One room is used for taking photos, and the outside is used as the lobby. It is relatively high-end and there are quite a lot of people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the eve of the Double Ninth Festival in 2023, citizens and tourists queue up to buy Double Ninth Cake from time-honored brands in Shanghai. According to data from the Ministry of Commerce, the operating income of time-honored enterprises will exceed 1.2 trillion yuan in 2022. Visual China Map &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ea6f938e95.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ea6f938e95.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the eve of the Double Ninth Festival in 2023, citizens and tourists lined up to buy Double Ninth Cake from a time-honored brand in Shanghai. According to data from the Ministry of Commerce, the operating income of time-honored enterprises will exceed 1.2 trillion yuan in 2022. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Plans to return to the time-honored brand list&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong regrets being removed from the time-honored brand list but is not discouraged: “We have learned from the experience and cannot let the brand stay on the family business model. We are confident that the next application (for Chinese time-honored brands) will be successful.&quot; According to the &quot;Measures&quot;, those who have been removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands are not allowed to apply again within two application cycles from the date of the decision. In other words, Wu Zhiyong cannot declare again until 2032. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wu’s bacon business does not seem to be affected. The Chinese Time-honored Brand plaque awarded by the Commerce Department has not yet been notified of its withdrawal. The packaging bags with the &quot;Chinese Time-honored Brand&quot; logo can no longer be used, and there are not many goods left. , the loss is not big. At the end of 2020, Wu Zhiyong and his brother Wu Zhijun raised funds to build a new factory in another location. Today, the factory covering an area of ​​6 acres can produce about 800 kilograms of bacon every day, which is sold by four local stores in a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the productivity of the fourth generation, the area of ​​the new factory has been reduced but the production capacity has been increased. According to Wu Zhiyong, his secret recipe was prepared by his ancestors who were doctors in the third year of Guangxu (1877). During this period, his grandfather improved it once, and it has been used ever since. There are about 22 Chinese herbal medicines in this secret recipe. Different ingredients are used in different seasons. Pork, beef, chicken, rabbit and other ingredients are also different, and even the ingredients used in different parts are different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong told Southern Weekend reporters that for many years, the Wu family’s secret recipe for bacon has been dictated. He recalled that he and his younger brother were taken to the batching room by his father. The batching room had no windows and only one door. His father taught them the recipe for cooking pig head meat in summer. They could only memorize it by rote. If they wrote it down on paper, they had to cook it before going out. Lose. Not only that, this recipe can be passed down to sons and daughters-in-law, but not to daughters-in-law. Wu Zhiyong said that all 7 brothers of his father&#39;s generation have completed the inheritance; there are 10 cousins ​​of his generation, and 5 of them are currently running the business; now, the baton is slowly being passed to the hands of the sixth generation. Among this generation, There are 10 males, 9 of whom are minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Wu Yazhou, the sixth generation inheritor, has begun to learn how to make ingredients, as well as washing, soaking, pickling, boiling, smoking, drying and other techniques. Wu Zhiyong revealed that Wu Yazhou, who is currently 25 years old, does not fully understand the ingredients of the secret recipe. He will not be able to teach all the secret recipes until he reaches the age of 35 and matures mentally. Another inheritor is Wu Zhiyong’s son Wu Yaxuan. He is still in his second year of high school and has not yet decided whether to inherit the family business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong feels that Wu’s bacon, which has lost the title of a time-honored Chinese brand, is not only a food, but also the hard work and bitterness of the older generation, and he wants to carry it forward. Now, the new factory is debugging a high-temperature sterilization flexible packaging production line. After debugging is completed, the products can be launched into foreign markets. Not only that, he plans to introduce live streaming to deliver goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 9, the day the Ministry of Commerce disclosed the results of the review of Chinese time-honored brands, Ministry of Commerce spokesperson He Yadong said that in 2022, Chinese time-honored brands will achieve operating income of more than 1.2 trillion yuan, and nearly 70% of them will be profitable. . In the first three quarters of 2023, operating income has exceeded the full-year level of 2022. The Ministry of Commerce will work with relevant departments to further establish and improve the long-term mechanism for the protection, inheritance and innovation and development of time-honored brands, promote time-honored brands to dig deep into their cultural heritage, benchmark against advanced concepts, adhere to integrity, innovate and develop, and better play a demonstration role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中山大学通报“贫困生炫富”：终止发放助学金]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260686]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 23:46:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 15, the Student Financial Aid Management Center of Sun Yat-sen University issued a briefing on the situation of students from financially disadvantaged families at the school. Zhao Moumou responded to reports of showing off his wealth and excessive consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice stated that after verification, the student was identified as a student from a family with financial difficulties. The identification procedures and materials were complete and in compliance with relevant regulations. However, during the verification, it was found that the man was not frugal in his life and had excessive consumption. According to the relevant regulations of the school, it was decided to terminate the grant of scholarships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, some netizens posted on the forum of Sun Yat-sen University that a poor student from the school’s Sino-French School of Nuclear Engineering and Technology who received a scholarship used an Apple series four-piece set (generally referring to Apple-branded mobile phones, computer, tablet and watch), and also bought Wang Jiaer’s concert tickets worth 1,517 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the post, the netizen who broke the news disclosed the student ID information of the student who received the scholarship, showing that this 2021 undergraduate student at Sun Yat-sen University belongs to the &quot;especially difficult&quot; category. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complete situation is reported as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 14, the Student Financial Aid Management Center of Sun Yat-sen University received a report about Zhao Moumou, a student from a financially disadvantaged family in our school, showing off his wealth and excessive consumption. , his college and our center quickly launched investigation procedures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After verification, the student was identified as a student from a family with financial difficulties. The identification procedures and materials were complete and in compliance with relevant regulations. However, during the verification, it was found that the man was not frugal in his life and had excessive consumption. According to the provisions of Article 21, Paragraph 3 of the &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Bursaries for Undergraduate Students of Sun Yat-sen University&quot;, it was decided to terminate the payment of its bursaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The school attaches great importance to student financial aid and provides all possible assistance to students from families with financial difficulties to help students grow and become talents. Next, the school will further strengthen the management and supervision of student financial aid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yat-sen University Student Financial Aid Management Center&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 15, 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>