<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“毛孩子”上幼儿园]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258991]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/V0LTOkR67vJedXXZb5clBZd8L6rjNgVAPLvRo1Tt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/V0LTOkR67vJedXXZb5clBZd8L6rjNgVA PLvRo1Tt. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Two &quot;students&quot; participated in the agility game course in kindergarten&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On an autumn afternoon, three pet dogs of different types participated in games under the guidance of their dog trainers. Balance boards, skateboards, number recognition, toy sorting...these adaptive and educational games are part of the Beijing Cute Pet Hotel (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as It is part of the pet kindergarten teaching system offered by &quot;Cute Beast School&quot;. In addition, there are courses such as swimming, sniffing and desensitization. Kindergarten care hours are from 8 am to 8 pm every day. In addition to classes, dogs can also enjoy services such as nutritious meals, lunch breaks, bathing, hair care and massage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/2wPb9QqtOnbVPZkOsdHUoZ5sjdlFX2Q1AjbzsXGP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/2wPb9QqtOnbVPZkOsdHUoZ5sjdlFX2Q1AjbzsXGP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Fat Tiger&quot; is two and a half years old this year. Its &quot;parents&quot; are a couple born in 1995. They love traveling and send &quot;Fat Tiger&quot; to a pet hotel for a few days every month &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three dogs participating in the game class entered the classroom one after another. They were the Shiba Inu, the Poodle and the Samoyed. At the beginning of the course, when they saw the stranger taking pictures with the camera, the three students immediately gave different feedback: the little Shiba Inu focused on the handler&#39;s commands; the poodle kept barking while tentatively approaching the stranger, and the course was unable to do so for a while. The Samoyed also noticed the presence of the camera and tried to get closer in a friendly manner. When the dog trainer gave the instruction, it immediately returned to the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/tO4JE0DuciA7OwPu0kt49VMpwuAlvYIgyGVyx3U4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/tO4JE0DuciA7OwPu0kt49VMpwuAlvYIgyGVyx3U4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Fat Tiger&quot; participates in the educational game class in kindergarten&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/kZ21UuvWMsdCj28jPMXKyxiita4EsHe9PMhCctsW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/kZ21UuvWMsdCj28jPMXKyxiita4EsHe9PMhCctsW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Fat Tiger&quot; experiences the cute beast theater in kindergarten&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Dogs also have their own personalities. You can see that the three of them are completely different. This has nothing to do with their body shape. It is determined by genes first and is related to their growth experience. Poodles are very vigilant. In fact, they are very vigilant. It&#39;s not to attack you, it&#39;s just to scare you - &#39;Don&#39;t come here, don&#39;t hurt me, I&#39;m very fierce, listen to how loud I scream&#39;, but in fact this just reflects its timidity and sensitivity. The other two They can only focus on their own things, which shows that they are well socialized, can regulate their own behavior, do not affect others, and are very confident and brave when facing new things.&quot; Li, the founder of Cute Beasts Chen analyzed the students&#39; performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has been almost five years since Mengzhupai opened its kindergarten, during which time it experienced the COVID-19 epidemic and its business almost stagnated. Starting from the beginning of 2023, Li Chen found that the demand for pet foster care and kindergarten attendance had “exploded.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/FC6KETtmuncBPDSPDhxTSAhX45uo5giBOXqwQhFk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/FC6KETtmuncBPDSPDhxTSAhX45uo5giBOXqwQhFk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sister Wang and 9-year-old &quot;Coffee Bean&quot; are in the cute animal party. This is the fifth year that Coffee Bean has come to kindergarten &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Young pet-raising groups are interested in The acceptance of kindergartens has suddenly increased. They will not sacrifice their lifestyle (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;socializing, business trips, travel, etc.&lt;/span>;) The price is to raise a dog - I have my life, you have your life. I do my best to make your life colorful, send you to school, and make you live a full and happy life every day. It does not need to be just Wait for me at home. I will be very calm when I go out and don’t have to feel guilty. I always feel that the dog has only one thing in his life, which is to wait for me at home.” Li Chen believes that with the progress of society and the changes in the thinking of pet owners, Nowadays, pet owners are no longer concerned about whether their pets are eating imported dog food, but also about the mental health of their pets - whether you are happy today. Dogs also need their own spiritual world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The slogan of the kindergarten is &quot;Let dogs be dogs again&quot;. Through many courses, training is provided to help them regain their instincts as animals, such as sniffing, hunting and swimming, and enhance the dogs&#39; confidence and physical fitness. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/u4ADV0FJUMQxzOuo358BIoMpSQ2kBW2owRMc26Xs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/u4ADV0FJUMQxzOuo358BIoMpSQ2kBW2owRMc26Xs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;San San’s mother took her 4 adopted elderly dogs to the cute animal party for a birthday party&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Li Chen, the current kindergarten parents are mainly those born in the 1980s and 1990s. They are not all middle-class or white-collar workers from well-off families, but they are very willing to give to &quot;hairy children&quot; Spend money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only young people, but some elderly people also spend a lot of money to create a healthy and comfortable life for their &quot;hairy children&quot;. Li Chen calls it &quot;a step-by-step relationship.&quot; She hosted a retired couple who regularly visited their daughter out of town every year. During the two or three months away from Beijing, they adopted two Chuan Chuan children (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Hybrid breed dog&lt;/span>;) and put it here with Li Chen. &quot;In their eyes, pets are the same as family members.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/HIhqM5okdFH3w15o1XUrPF20x55vH5IW5PIUdth0. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/HIhqM5okdFH3w15o1XUrPF20x55vH5IW5PIUdth0.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;254457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Three huskies are waiting in the restaurant&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coffee Bean is a teddy dog ​​who is 9 years old this year. Sister Wang remembers the first time after she went to kindergarten, the clerk dropped it off, turned around and left, with the coffee beans still chasing her. &quot;The dog&#39;s reaction was very real. From then on, I knew that they must be good to Doudou.&quot; This is the fifth year that Coffee Bean has come to the kindergarten. From the beginning, no one could touch him and he would bark when he saw people. Now he often pretends to be Doudou. Cuteness attracts the attention of those around you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sister Wang and her husband are from the DINK tribe. She “raises coffee beans as sons” and never hesitates to spend money on them. Whenever there is an event in the store, Sister Wang always thinks about renewing the fee. Li Chen saw the sufficient balance on her card and always advised her to spend rationally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Cheng used to love traveling and buying bags, but now she spends all the money she has saved on 90,000 yuan, which is about 4,000 to 5,000 yuan a month. Taking Jiuwan out for fun every week has turned Xiaocheng from a homebody into an outdoor expert who is familiar with pet-friendly places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ECkm98Du2wPcFJFTgUG11UqIWYNvulU7VsHxuvOQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ECkm98Du2wPcFJFTgUG11UqIWYNvulU7VsHxuvOQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;3-year-old &quot;Fifteen&quot; enjoys a pet birthday cake&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Three years ago, Xiao Cheng’s son was born. She felt that raising dogs and raising children each had their own advantages, but raising children was definitely more difficult, and 90,000 yuan brought her only happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding some news about uncivilized dog-raising circulating on the Internet, Xiao Cheng believes that it should not be a confrontation between dog-raising and non-dog-raising, but a confrontation between civilized dog-raising and uncivilized dog-raising. &quot;Dog owners must first do their best: leash, pick up poop, walk the dog at different times, and avoid pedestrians - especially the elderly and children. I also understand that some people are naturally afraid of dogs, so stay away from each other. We all understand each other about waiting for an extra elevator.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/q84SEeNxwenqXKYtBpLZjacHK3QJahHbIPpIorxD.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/q84SEeNxwenqXKYtBpLZjacHK3QJahHbIPpIorxD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 254455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Bottle&quot; (top) finishes swimming and enjoys a snack at the pet restaurant. More than three years ago, &quot;Milk Bottle&quot; was picked up from the road by its current owner &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;At the beginning of the creation of Cute Beasts, Li Chen designed a space of nearly 300 square meters on the second floor into an audio-visual room to meet the needs of owners and dogs to watch movies together, and it was open to members free of charge. This plan was questioned by some shareholders at the time, who believed that it was a waste in terms of profitability. But Li Chen had his own ideas. Although some pet-themed movies would be reserved, the speakers in the theater were designed for humans and were not suitable for dogs&#39; hearing systems. &quot;I hope to provide owners and pets with a diversified choice, even if it meets some very niche needs, but there is no way to experience it elsewhere.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fhNiWp9f8o5hBGPiBdk2Dwh4lEhelsNP5xoThX4Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fhNiWp9f8o5hBGPiBdk2Dwh4lEhelsNP5xoThX4Q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This The huskies are being frightened - screening out and weeding out dogs who tend to be overly fearful, aggressive or overly excited about running, screaming, overly enthusiastic people. This test simulates situations that therapy dogs may encounter in service facilities, minimizing safety hazards. Dogs that pass the assessment are trained and have the opportunity to come to serve special groups (the elderly, autistic children, etc.)&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In the past six years, Li Chen has been surrounded by some controversy, mainly questioning that she treats relatively high-end and niche services as a gimmick, and that the form is greater than the content. &quot;Actually, most of our services are very urgent, and some may be relatively advanced, but they are scientific and I believe they are also in line with future development trends. Pet services face the needs of different customers, so they must provide different services. There is no unified standard answer to the choice, and there is no need to have one,&quot; Li Chen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the 2022 COVID-19 epidemic, Cute Beasts assisted the Chaoyang District Government of Beijing in the centralized transportation of pets, and immediately converted the store into a pet shelter, which alleviated the problem of pet placement during the epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/CK4QvzWosGyhf8RGYpIHZLlOhsWpBZwUbL1xIkpH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/CK4QvzWosGyhf8RGYpIHZLlOhsWpBZwUbL1xIkpH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ninety Wan&quot; takes swimming lessons in kindergarten&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Li Chen still vividly remembers the large-scale transfer in Nanxinyuan Community. More than 120 pets, mostly dogs, but also cats, rabbits, turtles and chickens, were pulled back one by one for transfer. For two whole days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the normal operation, pets must be evaluated for foster care: age, underlying diseases, and whether they are aggressive... But that time there was no choice, time was tight, and the owner gave his contact information on the spot. The pet and the basic information are written on a piece of paper. The staff puts the paper and the pet together to take a photo, and the registration is completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3PlP1CX4XisMazaYlQYQd2NIRd0igmjLFJGTAAV9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3PlP1CX4XisMazaYlQYQd2NIRd0igmjLFJGTAAV9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The foster care rooms on the first floor of the Animal Pet Hotel all have independent yards. In order to avoid separation anxiety, some owners will bring their pets’ toys or cushions at home to help them adapt to the new environment as soon as possible &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Back in the store, Li Chen and the store staff managed different categories of pets, and tried their best to send the latest photos and videos of the pets to the owners to appease their emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Trust was not established at the beginning. Some owners saw the video and said that although they looked similar, they could tell from the expression that this was not my dog. It doesn&#39;t matter, we will take 10 more pictures of him. Video, let him look for feelings or expressions to judge whether it is his own dog. In the first three days, we received calls from owners every day, some questioning, some crying, and some cursing. On the fourth day, everyone I started to believe that you really placed my dog ​​with you, so I started to buy food and supplies for us online to express my gratitude.&quot; This experience gave Li Chen a deeper understanding and understanding of human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/oxBwRwuqqXdMtN0VLrKbh46vWylDWBWByWq02nwR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/oxBwRwuqqXdMtN0VLrKbh46vWylDWBWByWq02nwR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kindergarten photo wall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Isolation At the end of the period, these more than 120 pets returned to their owners intact after undergoing nucleic acid tests one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since starting a pet hotel, Li Chen has seen countless dogs and witnessed many touching stories: During the swimming class, the dog did not dare to go into the water, but when its owner &quot;fell&quot; into the pool, it jumped into the water to save him regardless of his own safety. ; If there are pregnant women or children at home, the dog would rather not go to the toilet by itself when walking the dog, but also make sure that the owner is within his sight and not let strangers approach...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[烈犬伤童事件后，“失焦”的多地捕狗风波]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259173]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A Guangzhou resident is walking his dog. There is a sign on the side of the road &quot;Walking your dog on a leash&quot; , civilization will not lose its link.&quot; Pictures and texts have nothing to do with it. Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5aa90d6adb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5aa90d6adb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255050&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A Guangzhou resident was walking his dog. There was a sign on the roadside, &quot;Walking your dog on a leash, being civilized and keeping the leash on&quot;. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You can’t say that we beat dogs, we really have never beaten them.” On October 20, 2023, Zhang Yong was a little nervous when talking about the recent public opinion about dog hunting, and emphasized that they were civilized law enforcement. , the entire process was recorded with a law enforcement recorder and recorded in the ledger. &quot;It must be ensured that they are all alive and cannot be damaged.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director of the Publicity Unit of the Urban Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau of Saihan District, Hohhot City is worried about the public opinion that a Rottweiler dog bit a 4-year-old girl in Chongzhou The chain reaction of events. A video of a ferocious dog biting a person swept the entire Internet, and dog hunting operations took place in many places. It was reported on the Internet that a residential property management team had set up a &quot;dog fighting team&quot;, and security guards patrolled with sticks and nets; Bozhou in Anhui, Zhengzhou in Henan, Taixing in Jiangsu, Urban management departments in Qingdao, Shandong and other places have successively released videos of catching stray dogs, and netizens have begun heated discussions about whether stray dogs should be culled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Controversial cases also emerged. A stray dog ​​living in Chongqing University of International Business and Economics was driven to death by security guards. On October 20, the school reported that a student was chased by a stray dog ​​on his way back to bed. The school security guard had engaged in inappropriate behavior during the chase and the security guard involved had been suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that after this incident, many places carried out special rectifications on the behavior of ownerless dogs, aggressive dogs, and not wearing leashes. But at the same time, various rumors are also circulating on online platforms. In fact, in many places, catching stray dogs is a regular task. The captured stray dogs will be sent to stray animal rescue centers for shelter and will not be killed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What responsibilities should the property owner bear?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the Rottweiler dog biting incident, slogans were hung in many places in the Xichen Oasis Community of Hengda where the girl lived: &quot;Walking dogs in a civilized manner and keeping the leash on them&quot; &quot;, keep your mouth shut and don&#39;t hurt others&quot; &quot;Tighten the &#39;civilized rope&#39; and be a civilized dog owner&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, a mother who lived above the victim girl told a Southern Weekend reporter , the day the girl was bitten, the angry owners were already discussing in the owner group: &quot;If such a big thing happened, where is the security guard?&quot; &quot;Why don&#39;t they know when an outside dog comes in?&quot; Under pressure, the property began patrolling daily to catch off-leash dogs. These tasks will be posted to the group one by one and reported to the owner, with arrest videos and photos attached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tense atmosphere quickly spread to other communities. On October 17, the media reported that a &quot;dog fighting team&quot; was set up in Fuhe Yujing Community in Chengdu City. In the video, security guards were patrolling with sticks and nets. The property staff said: &quot;All stray dogs are left unattended and without leashes.&quot; Yes, the whole community needs to be rectified.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 18, the Sanduhui Chaowai Community in Chengdu hung a banner in the name of the property saying &quot;The community will hunt and kill unleashed cats and dogs.&quot; The word &quot;hunt and kill&quot; immediately caused worries and accusations from pet owners in the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Li Ming, a resident of the community, the idea of ​​&quot;hunting and killing&quot; actually came from the community&#39;s mother group. Out of concern, the mothers suggested in the group &quot;methods to deal with stray dogs: first, kill or capture them as much as possible, second, drive them out of the community and then call the police to notify the community.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, those who opposed the culling called the government service hotline 12345 to complain one after another on the evening of the 18th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next morning, the property management company stated that the banner was inappropriate and had been removed. &quot;The property management company no longer dares to answer the phone. The street refused to allow them to kill the people by force and warned them in the morning.&quot; Li Ming said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters called the property and street office of the community many times, but none of them got through. On the 20th, the Property Affairs Service Center of the Chengdu Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau responded to the media saying that the center had not received a notice that a dog hunting team was set up in a community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chang Sha, a lawyer at Beijing Jingdu Law Firm, has been involved in cases of dog injuries. She believes that the community property has a safety obligation to the owners. Therefore, if there is an ownerless dog in the community, the property owner must be responsible for evicting it. Or management responsibility, otherwise you will have to bear fault liability for stray dogs hurting people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the other hand, the property management company does not have the power to enforce the law, so for dogs with owners, the property management cannot take mandatory management measures, such as directly arresting them. In non-emergency situations, property management can only be handled by persuasion or handed over to urban management and public security agencies with law enforcement powers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Remediation in many places, rumors go hand in hand&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the evening of the 18th, when the owners of a Chengdu community were arguing about whether to cull stray dogs, the urban management department of Jinshui District, Zhengzhou City, Henan Province targeted dogs without leashes. The act was enforced overnight and broadcast live. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dog-catching controversy began to spread to many places across the country, resulting in law enforcement actions. In this live broadcast in Zhengzhou, a young man holding a French bulldog was chased for a long distance. According to the live video, although the urban management personnel repeatedly emphasized that they would not harm the dog and would only take it back for registration and investigation, the young man tried to escape with the black dog after some unsuccessful negotiations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This video has become another spreading point of this Internet storm. Xiao Zhen, a citizen who also raises French bulldogs in Zhengzhou, told Southern Weekend reporters that it is indeed prohibited to raise French bulldogs in Zhengzhou. Dog licenses are usually not allowed, but the law enforcement is not strict and &quot;we would check occasionally in the past.&quot; At the same time, many cities across the country allow the breeding of French bulldogs, including Beijing, Shanghai, Xi&#39;an, Dalian, Harbin, Nanjing, Hangzhou, Changsha, etc. After learning that the young man needed to pay a fine of 5,000 yuan, the group of French bullfighting enthusiasts sent him red envelopes one after another, saying that they would help him get his dog back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Fan, president of the Wuhan Small Animal Protection Association, said that the current management of dogs in cities is mainly based on regulations formulated by each locality. Such administrative regulations are not very effective, so many people do not apply for dog licenses. Nor do they keep dogs according to regulations. (For details, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/258846&quot;>;&quot;Many experts talk about the Rottweiler dog biting a girl: &quot;The key is to manage people, followed by managing dogs&quot;&quot;&lt;/ a>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the division of powers for dog management in cities is not clear. Most cities are currently in charge of public security, and some are under the charge of urban management. Dog management also involves industry and commerce, food safety, and public security. Management and other departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident of Rottweiler dogs injuring children, many places issued special management actions. Bozhou in Anhui, Taixing in Jiangsu, Shenqiu in Henan, Shehong in Sichuan and other places targeted ownerless dogs, aggressive dogs, and unprotected dogs. The behavior of traction ropes will be specially rectified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In it, rumors and facts are mixed. Southern Weekend reporters found that in videos calling for not killing stray dogs, photos of dozens of dog corpses and scenes of being thrown to death often appear, but there is no time stamp. Just looking at the background of the picture, buses and buildings should be numbers. years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the hot topic on Weibo &quot;Puppies don&#39;t feel like they are wandering&quot;, many netizens identified a photo of a puppy that was still grinning after being arrested as the one involved in the Chongqing University of International Business and Economics. It was a yellow dog, with the caption &quot;It was still laughing when it was caught, it thought it was going to have a home&quot;, and expressed condolences. However, the author of the original picture refuted the rumors and said that the smiling puppy was taken in April and is not the same dog as the one in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s a bit out of focus.” Zhou Wei, director of the Jiangsu Provincial Zoological Society, found that as the situation developed, netizens’ discussions gradually turned into opposing issues such as loving dogs or not, and culling or not culling. , without going into details. For example, many video titles say &quot;catching&quot; stray dogs, but most of the current videos only show &quot;catching&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Normalization of Urban Management&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found through searches that many dog-catching videos were released by the official accounts of urban management and public security agencies in various places, such as Qingdao West Coast New District Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau. It released three videos in a row, introducing that catching stray dogs is a regular task. The captured stray dogs will be sent to the stray animal rescue center for shelter and will not be killed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The distribution of dog leashes and dog muzzles has attracted attention. The Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau of Shehong City, Sichuan Province, which is considered by netizens to be a model of civilized law enforcement, told Southern Weekend reporters that they will set up dog leashes starting in 2021. The management office is equipped with professional dog-catching equipment and vehicles, and has 5 staff members daily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Saihan District, Hohhot City, according to the City Comprehensive Law Enforcement Bureau, the bureau took over the work of catching stray dogs in 2020. In 2023 alone, it received more than 1,100 related reports and has captured stray dogs. There are more than 300 dogs, and most of the reports are about barking dogs disturbing people, especially in the early morning and early morning. Zhang Yong, head of the bureau&#39;s publicity department, said that when team members receive a reporting call, they must contact the person involved in a timely manner and respond to the person after handling the case. If they cannot catch the person, the team members will have to go there at least three times within a week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This does not sound like an easy job. Zhang Yong said that they have specially formulated a long-term mechanism for this purpose, which is divided into day shift and night shift. &quot;There are 38 people in the mobile squadron participating in dog hunting.&quot; They have to patrol the 1,025 square kilometers under the jurisdiction of Saihan District. When the dog climbs over the fence and enters the bush, it is difficult for law enforcement officers to catch up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, stray dogs have a keen sense of smell. As soon as the law enforcement vehicles that carry stray dogs all the year round stop in a place, &quot;no dogs will come out of this area.&quot; Zhang Yong said that one of their team members saw a stray dog ​​while driving around in his car and called for a law enforcement vehicle. Before the vehicle arrived, the stray dog ​​started to get restless. &quot;It could smell the smell of the car.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every dog-catching team member in Saihan District has been bitten by a dog, and some have broken their legs while catching dogs. The tool they use is a fishing net. Dogs of different sizes use different types of fishing nets. The largest ones use fiber rope nets as thick as their thumbs. &quot;They have very good teeth and can bite through thin ropes in one bite.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sichuan Province Shehong City Comprehensive Administrative Law Enforcement Bureau and Qingdao West Coast New District Comprehensive Law Enforcement Administration both responded to Southern Weekend reporters that the tools used to catch dogs are mainly fishing nets. In most of the dog-catching videos circulated on the Internet, law enforcement officers used fishing nets. Only one video showed a dog-catching video with a license plate number from Taizhou, Zhejiang, using curved clamps. Zhou Wei believes that the fishing net is currently a more suitable tool for catching dogs. It has a soft texture and can trap dogs without causing too much harm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yong said that after the stray dogs are caught, they will be sent to the detention center managed by the public security department for adoption. After the dog is inspected, the detention center will give the urban management team member a receipt, which will clearly indicate the receipt. Quantity and condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from Southern Weekend called the Hohhot Public Security Bureau Dog Inspection Station, and the other party replied that the institute has 50 acres of kennels and is currently able to raise stray cats and dogs until they die of natural causes. In addition, the center is open to the public for adoption, and you can visit, adopt or donate materials during the open day. As for the number of stray cats and dogs currently detained in the inspection center, the staff member said that detailed data could not be provided for the time being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Bodhi Nursing Home for Stray Fur Children in Shehong, Sichuan is a privately run base for stray cats and dogs. It occupies a hilltop in the mountains and feeds stray cats and dogs in different areas. In 2021, the base began to receive stray cats and dogs caught by the urban management department, 20-30 every year. &quot;They are sent here sporadically, and they are all caught after being complained about disturbing the residents.&quot; Ms. Ren, the person in charge of the base, said that the urban management department Part of the cost of dog food is provided. Cats and dogs will be checked for infectious diseases in advance before delivery. If there are injuries or illnesses, they will go to the pet hospital for treatment first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Ren said that Shehong has launched a special operation to capture stray cats and dogs since October 20, and 11 stray dogs were delivered in just one day. She was a little worried that too many cats and dogs would be sent in a short period of time and that the base would not be able to handle the load. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;More sophisticated, professional and scientific&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 20, the French Dou who was captured in Zhengzhou has been brought back to his hometown for adoption , and the Zhengzhou Urban Management Bureau told the media that the case is still going through the process and the fine has not yet been determined. The topic of why French bulldogs are banned has been hotly discussed in the dog breeding circle. Mao Jing, who has raised French bulldogs for many years, saw from this the management problems of dog breeding in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mao Jing said that French bulldogs are not clearly marked on Shanghai’s prohibited list, but French bulldogs have long been regarded as a type of bulldog and face different management methods in various districts of Shanghai. In 2014, she raised her first French bulldog, and she successfully applied for a dog license in Siping Street, Yangpu District. In 2016, Mao Jing was planning to raise a second French bulldog, but when she applied for a dog license in Jiangpu Street, the same district, her dog license was rejected. It was approved after a phone appeal. &quot;The handler didn&#39;t know much about this dog breed.&quot; In 2019, Shanghai stated that legal fighting is allowed in the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the French Bulldog incident in Zhengzhou, she specially compared the lists of banned dogs in Zhengzhou and Shanghai, and found that Shanghai clearly prohibited the breeding of British bulldogs, but French Bulldogs were not allowed; while Zhengzhou clearly prohibited the breeding of French Bulldogs, But I can&#39;t help but raise heroes to fight. Mao Jing said that the two types of dogs have different body shapes and agility. In comparison, Yingdou can grow to 60-80 pounds. &quot;Even if it doesn&#39;t bite, hitting someone may be more serious.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There is actually no common standard for dog breeds in our country.” Zhou Wei said that when foreign dog breeds were introduced in the early stages, there may be a lack of understanding of the dog breed’s habits or translation problems. &quot;This reflects management lag.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China&#39;s pet industry has developed by leaps and bounds in more than ten years, and the problem of how people and animals coexist in cities has continued to become highlighted. The &quot;2021 China Pet Industry White Paper&quot; shows that the total number of pet dogs and pet cats in cities and towns nationwide in 2021 will exceed 112 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Wei believes that in terms of dog management, a more refined, professional and scientific management mechanism is needed starting from the source. For example, when breeding, attention should be paid to the breed genes and how to train them. The problem is that there is currently a lack of supervision in the upstream breeding stage, and it is only at the pet raising stage that it starts to get tight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Fan also holds a similar view. He believes that many incidents of dog injuries can be traced back to the source: &quot;Why are banned violent dogs still sold on the market?&quot; From this, he suggested that dogs are born from Establish a series of supervision mechanisms for sales and breeding, and clarify departmental responsibilities and management rights and responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Wei suggested that solving the current problem can start with popular science education, such as providing professional training services to campuses and real estate properties: how to deal with fierce dogs in the community, how to correctly place and capture them; People provide training: how to scientifically understand and control their pet dogs, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Wuhan Small Animal Association, where Du Fan works, has reached a cooperation with the local public security department. Around the 25th of each month, some captured stray dogs from the inspection center are open to the public for adoption, calling for &quot;adopting instead of purchasing&quot; &quot;. Du Fan said that the previous two adoption events were successfully held, and all the dogs kept for inspection were successfully adopted. &quot;We are currently preparing for the third one.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ Southern Weekend reporter Gao Yichen also contributed to this article (Li Ming and Mao Jing are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中美经济工作组举行第一次会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259175]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to He Lifeng, Vice Premier of the State Council and Chinese leader of China-US Economic and Trade, and Janet. Following the consensus reached by Yellen during her talks in Beijing in July, the China-US Economic Working Group held its first meeting via video on October 24. The meeting was chaired by officials at the deputy ministerial level of finance from the two countries. The two sides had in-depth, candid and constructive communication on issues such as the macroeconomic situation and policies of the two countries and the world, bilateral economic relations, and cooperation in responding to global challenges. China expressed its concerns. Both parties will continue to maintain communication. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“第一学历歧视”？别用这样的观念轻易否定企业丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259163]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, many media launched reports related to &quot;first degree discrimination&quot;. It is worth noting that on September 29, the Ministry of Education responded to a netizen’s question about “Whether the first degree after graduation is a junior college or a bachelor’s degree?” The concept of “first degree” is not used in the relevant policies and documents of the national education administration department regarding the learning experience of scientific and cultural education and skills training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, from an objective point of view, graduates with master&#39;s and doctoral degrees from prestigious schools generally have some advantages in the job market. Needless to say, this may be &quot;first degree discrimination&quot; The realistic background in which relevant issues have received attention. But is similar recruitment behavior “merit-based” or “discriminatory”? It may not be possible to generalize, but the issues of corporate operational autonomy and employment autonomy that run through it are also important aspects worthy of analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, for graduate students from 985 universities, does the recruiting unit or human resources specialist make a clear employment choice based on the prerequisite of &quot;undergraduate degree from a prestigious school&quot;? This is actually hard to say. Especially as a for-profit organization, the company will ultimately look at whether the applicant&#39;s abilities and talents match the company&#39;s employment needs. It may also be that the company&#39;s interviewer confirms the match between the applicant&#39;s abilities and the company&#39;s needs through a comprehensive, complete and systematic assessment. . And graduates with master&#39;s and doctoral degrees who have been blessed by famous schools may have shown certain advantages in this link and finally got the opportunity, but it may not necessarily be simple and crude academic qualifications that win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, the recruitment process of the employer is that the human resources specialist will screen the resume before the interview. Only after passing the preliminary screening will he be qualified to participate in the initial interview hosted by the human resources department and even the professional interview hosted by the leader of the hiring department. interview. If some companies clearly stipulate in black and white that they will not recruit students with &quot;double bachelor&#39;s degrees&quot; or are suspected of academic discrimination, if graduates with &quot;double bachelor&#39;s degrees&quot; and master&#39;s degrees can pass the resume screening, in this sense, 985 As a stepping stone, colleges and universities have already been used in the preliminary screening stage. The stepping stone is just a stepping stone. Next, it depends on whether the job seeker has real ability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时应该说明的是，社会也没有必要过分放大所谓“第一学历”的光环加持。如今，本科毕业于985的学子何其多也。在严峻的就业形势下，北大物理博士去争城管编制的有之，上海交大医学院博士去中学当校医的有之。本科985真的没有一些人想象的那样有多耀眼的光环与多有力的加持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，客观地讲，本科985院校学子相对于非985，在就业市场上总体上多多少少是有些优势的。这本身也有合理的一面。如果这个优势不存在，那学子们秋雨寒灯努力考上好大学的动力或许就不存在了，也就无所谓好大学与一般大学的差异了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更进一步，表面上是学子得到了985院校文凭的加持，获得了一些优势，但实际逻辑是反过来的：高考考分排序及名校与非名校的分际，是对学子智力、能力的排序。在这个意义上，总体上是优秀的学子成就了985院校，而不是反过来。所以985文凭就具有了重要的信号功能，对用人单位筛选简历构成了一个重要的参考。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，高分低能是有的，低分高能也是有的；高考失误是有的，高考超常发挥也是有的，不过，一要看是大概率还是小概率；二是大家最终都要接受市场与用人单位的检验，要看真才实干的，是骡子是马拉出来遛遛就知道了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;企业是营利机构，最终会看应聘者的能力才干与企业用人需求是否匹配，能否为企业创造更高的价值。人事与用人部门对985本科的求职者可能会高看一眼，但也就仅此而已，接下来要看求职者在面试中的表现能否符合他们对人才的期待。尤其是自由竞争行业，企业没有任何动机放着更能干的非985本科就职者不用，反而用不能干的985本科求职者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果两个人，一个非985本+985研，另一个985本+985研，企业没有录取前者而录取了后者，是不是就成了“第一学历歧视”？恐怕并非如此。求职者与用人单位是双向选择，达成合意才是对双方权利的尊重与市场效率的提升。推而广之，求职者本身很能干，想去高薪单位不想去低薪单位，是否构成对后者的歧视呢？就算是，也是效率歧视，应属正当。正如大家婚嫁时愿意找个人、家庭条件好的而不愿找条件差的，也不能说是对后者的歧视。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后，在严峻就业形势之下，让学子有更多更好的工作机会可选择，关键在于激发企业家的信心与对未来的预期，让他们敢于用真金白银下注，扩大投资，创造更多更好的就业岗位。这就要尊重企业家的经营自主权与用人自主权，而不能动辄否定企业“择优”的权利，削弱企业家投资下注的动力与信心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不让企业显示自己的招聘偏好，结果无非有二：一是短期内企业把自己的偏好隐藏起来但写在心里，无非是让求职者做更多的无用功，对求职者真的好吗？二是长期看企业会觉得营商环境与观念环境不好，会更加谨慎投资下注，创造就业岗位的过程就会受到影响，对求职者又有什么好处呢？总之，社会应给企业家创造一个宽松、理性的观念环境，让他们用自己的聪明才智与真金白银推动我们的经济，最终也会有利于每一个求职者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 10:01:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[触碰寻亲直播间里的伤痛 | 记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259121]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e505f7e258.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e505f7e258.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254952&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年7月14日，贵州贵阳，四个寻亲家长开车从云南昆明出发，奔波上千公里寻子。 （南方周末记者刘怡仙/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;采访杨妞花被拐案（详见《&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/253854&quot;>;人贩余华英被判死刑：拐卖11名儿童，还卖过亲儿子&lt;/a>;》），是我第一次接近寻亲家长们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年7月14日早晨，拐卖杨妞花的人贩子余华英在贵州省贵阳市中级人民法院受审，法院外站满了寻亲家长。他们大多穿着白色衬衫，上面印着宝贝的照片，手里还举着红底黄字的寻人牌子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“寻找儿子李先芳”“寻儿子安旭和安彪”“棉花糖爸爸寻找女儿陈杨梅”……每张寻人牌子上都标注着孩子的出生年月日、走失时间、走失时的身体特征等等。牌子后面，大多是愁苦的面容，仿佛五官都耷拉了下来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;等待的过程中，也有寻亲家长在做直播，给网友介绍庭审进展，法院外现场是什么情况，中间穿插&lt;span>;着&lt;/span>;说自己的孩子是如何丢的，为了找孩子去过哪些地方，又是怎么来到这儿的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我和其中的几位家长打招呼，告知记者身份，在旁边录采访视频。此后，只要我举起手机录像，旁边的家长马上凑上来，抱着寻人牌子转悠一圈，偶尔搭腔说话。他们知道如何“蹭流量”，在任何可能的机会里，露一次脸，增加一点曝光度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这种急切在杨妞花出现后更为明显。寻亲家长们几乎一窝蜂地涌了上去，前后包围着，一个挨着一个举着牌子。好几次，杨妞花被淹没在寻亲牌子中，记者根本找不到她。混乱中，有家长把自己的寻人牌塞到杨妞花手中，还有家长将写有寻亲信息的背包挂在了她身上。杨妞花理解这些寻亲家长的心情，也不拒绝。这些家长常年奔波于各地，出现在各种热点场景里，争取让孩子看到自己，看到“爸爸妈妈一直在找你”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;结束庭审的那天下午，我敲开杨妞花的房门，却惊讶地发现房间里挤满了寻亲家长，床上、椅子上、地板上，每个角落都坐满了人。他们都在排队等着上杨妞花的直播间，介绍自己寻亲情况。杨妞花在2021年网络寻亲成功后，引发了诸多关注，在短视频平台也积累了30余万粉丝。在庭审这样的重要日子，她也乐意利用自己的流量，让家长们上直播间扩散寻亲信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我在一个50多岁的阿姨身边坐下来，看着房间里人来人往上直播。那时还是7月盛夏，这位阿姨穿着印有孩子信息的套头长袖衫，里头还叠加了几件衣服。一番攀谈后，她说自己是贵州布依族人，左脚天生&lt;span>;残&lt;/span>;疾，难以走远路。可丈夫生病卧床，无奈她只能独自出来找孩子。说着她脱下左脚的短靴，露出的足面是畸形的，看起来难以受力。难以想象这些天她是如何跟着寻亲队伍辗转福建、贵州多地的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我印象比较深的还有一位“棉花糖爸爸”，他的女儿2003年出生，3岁时在云南昆明失踪。杨妞花庭审后接受采访时，他就站在杨妞花身后，突然无法控制地哭出了声，声音一点点变大，最后蹲在地上痛哭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;多年来，“棉花糖爸爸”一直用小面包车四处做生意，一边卖棉花糖一边找孩子，妻子则在家里卖气球支撑生活。在“棉花糖爸爸”的视频号主页里，他去过多个寻亲成功的认亲现场。那些天贵州榕江村超正是热点，他接连赶路，到村超现场找孩子。为了节约用费，4个寻亲家长一路上都是自己做饭吃，露天支起灶台架子炒菜，4个人一天花费二十多元就够了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;寻亲艰难，寻亲家长们都痛恨人贩子。但对于收养家庭，他们有着不同的看法。有人支持买卖同罪，认为应该追究养家的责任。但更多的家长，则会强调自己只是想见见孩子，不求孩子回到亲生家庭，也不追究养家责任。一个很重要的原因是，许多被拐孩子担心伤害养父母感情，不愿主动站出来寻亲，这将增加寻亲的难度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;余华英拐卖儿童案件里，仍有几位被拐孩子不愿正式认亲，他们陷于复杂的家庭关系里，不知如何是好。也有已经认亲的被拐孩子与父母并不亲近，亲子关系空荡荡的，不知从何建起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在寻亲直播间里，家长们呼吁对自己身世有怀疑的孩子前往公安局采血，录入寻亲数据库，将来有一天认亲成功，“你想回来就回来，你要是不想回来，也可以留在养家生活”&lt;span>;。 &lt;/span>;这句话大概饱含苦楚与伤痛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;祝愿他们与亲人早日团聚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[睡眠保单规模有多大？如何常态化唤醒？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259165]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;睡眠保单正被要求限期清理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家金融监督管理总局近期发布限期清理人身保险“睡眠保单”的专项通知。根据通知，针对2013年1月1日至2023年6月30日期间产生的“睡眠保单”，专项清理工作从2023年10月起持续为期一年。南方周末新金融研究中心研究员调研获悉，各寿险公司开始为“睡眠保单”寻找“主人”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国内为何会有睡眠保单？投保人的权益又将如何获得保证？海外在处理睡眠保单时有何经验？南方周末新金融研究中心研究员研究海外经验后认为，睡眠保单清理不能仅仅依靠监管机构不定期的督促，而应建立易得易查全国性系统，且保险公司应主动披露睡眠保单情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;何为&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“睡眠保单”？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;何为“睡眠保单”？中国社会科学院金融研究所保险与社会保障研究室副主任王向楠对南方周末新金融研究中心研究员称，“睡眠保单”并没有明确定义，一般是指保险事故发生或保险合同到期但尚未领取赔偿或满期给付保险金，以及保险合同效力中止或效力终止但尚未领取现金价值的保单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员查询发现，国外与之相类似的概念为“未领取保单（unclaimed life insurance）”。美国好事达保险公司（Allstate）将其特指为保险人过世，受益人未申领保险赔偿的情况。根据美国政府网站，美国把未申领的保险收益与未支付的工资、养老金、退税、基金收益、债券收益等统一纳入未申领资金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通俗而言，国家金融监督管理总局这次要求限期清理的“睡眠保单”即是保单主人“失联”导致保单“应领而未领”，最终被保险公司“束之高阁”的保单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“睡眠保单”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;何以产生&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;睡眠保单为何产生呢？北京大童保险销售公司一位合伙人告诉南方周末新金融研究中心研究员，保单主人“失联”的原因有很多。比如，有的家里长辈买了年金，没有知会家人，还没等到领取的时候，长辈去世了。这将导致无人申请理赔；也有消费者购买保险后，因更换联系方式、缴费中断等，导致保单失效，而自己也忘记了这件事，没去退现金；很多家庭没有好好保存和管理保单，家庭成员互相之间不了解保单持有情况。保险公司一般很难对这类保单进行处理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员还了解到，孤儿保单也是导致睡眠保单产生的原因之一。 &lt;span>;孤儿&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保&lt;/span>;单指因为原营销人员离职而无人主动跟进服务的&lt;span>;保单&lt;/span>;。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与国内睡眠保单产生的原因类似，国外睡眠保单也多由投保人各种原因的“失联”导致。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于投保人而言，“睡眠保单”意味着一笔“睡眠资金”或一段“保险空窗期”。前者对应的是投保人名下有到期生存金和满期金未领取的情况；而后者发生在保单因“失联”欠费而中止时。这意味着保险公司有权解除保险合同。基于此，国家金融监督管理总局组织的这次专项清理行动，既能盘活社会沉睡的“闲置资金”，也维护了消费者权益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;睡眠保单规模有多大&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;监管机构专门发通知限期清理“睡眠保单”。这意味着“睡眠保单”不可忽视。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“睡眠保单”规模究竟有多大？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员梳理发现，截至目前，监管部门并没有公布全国范围内的统计数据。可参考的一项数据是，2014年8月，原中国保监会曾对“1999年6月10日以后签发生效、截至2014年6月30日24时，所有缴费期为一年以上的人身保险失效保单”开展专项清理，共排查出人身保险失效保单1857.93万件，现金价值350.83亿元。该专项清理行动针对的“人身保险失效保单”特指因保险缴费中断导致合同效力中止的保单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“睡眠保单”不仅仅包括“人身保险失效保单”。据此可见，睡眠保单涉及金额也应该更大。各地数据可做例证。安徽省保险业协会披露的数据显示，截至2023年6月30日，安徽省人身险公司应领未领取生存金保单件数为7.79万件，涉及金额9.2亿元；据中国银行保险报报道，2022年，浙江40家人身险公司开展“寻找保险生存金领取人”活动，截至2020年12月31日，浙江（不含宁波）到期未领取人身险保单共计12.13万件，金额7.79亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同保险公司的数据亦显示，睡眠保单不是小事。平安养老保险浙江分公司2022年4月至8月为客户找回了“满期生存金”1.4亿元。新华人寿官方称，&amp;nbsp;2021年到目前，新华保险浙江分公司开展寻找生存金领取人活动，通过走访村委、社区，寻求出单银行、派出所、户籍中心等寻找“失联”客户，共找回“失联”客户2193人，协助客户办理领取手续，支付生存金9046万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;财报未单独披露&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;险企清理睡眠保单的动力有多大？躺在账上的“睡眠资金”对保险公司而言是一笔意外之财？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员查询各上市险企财报发现，各公司对此没有单独披露。这意味着各公司在财报上将此作为正常保单处理了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一家上市险企的一位资深士在接受南方周末新金融研究中心研究员调研时确认，从保险业务端来看，保险公司在财务报表中并不区分“睡眠保单”和正常保单。 “睡眠保单”同其余保单一样，执行相同的会计准则，如保费收入计入资产类账目，保险责任准备金依据精算确定金额计入“提取保险责任准备金”科目等。准备金提取比例，按照保险种类和准备金种类，规则较多，各家保险公司情况存在差异。加上受保险期限长和保单状态多样等因素，“睡眠保单”清理是一项复杂的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一家保险销售公司一位合伙人更称，保险公司不一定有动力清理睡眠保单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;如何唤醒“睡眠保单”？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;海外如何唤醒睡眠保单？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;证券时报2020年5月报道，美国每年数百万美元的人寿保险权益无人申请索赔。英国保险公司协会网站2023年援引消息人士保守估计，英国各地被遗忘和无人认领的保单预计共涉及2亿英镑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员梳理发现，在美国，消费者既可以登录美国保险监督协会（NAIC）的系统查询，也可以找第三方机构帮助查询。根据美国家庭人寿保险公司（Aflac）网站介绍，美国不同州对于未领取保单有不同的法律规定。在许多案例中，受益人可追溯的保单没有时间限制，一旦受益人提交保单，保险公司会用几周到一个月的时间来处理并赔付。受益人除了可以领取保险赔付外，还可以领取部分利息收入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，为配合“睡眠保单”清理工作，国家金融监督管理总局这次也指导相关机构研究建立统一的“睡眠保单”信息查询平台，供消费者自主查询。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末新金融研究中心研究员认为，睡眠保单的清理不能仅仅依靠监管机构不定期的催促监督，除了尽快建立全国统一的保单查询系统，监管部门和行业协会应要求保险公司把提醒投保人工作前置。与此同时，各保险公司应利用金融科技赋能睡眠保单的追踪，甚至可以利用大数据系统对所有保单每年进行一次检查，实现常态化唤醒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新任中国足协主席宋凯：不能再出台“奇葩”政策]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259155]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;22日，新任中国足协主席宋凯来到山东潍坊观看第二届中国青少年足球联赛男子U15组决赛，并与青训和媒体代表座谈，这是他首次以足协主席身份公开亮相。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于新一届中国足协的工作思路，宋凯表示，中国足球未来要下定决心走“长征路”，把青训当成头等大事来抓，还要通过扩大开放来提升中国足球竞争力，并且确保中国足协各项政策合理稳定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/4c31a52c7e5b9847bbfb84f41cf49701.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/4c31a52c7e5b9847bbfb84f41cf49701.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255015&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;中国足协主席宋凯（中）和中国足协副主席袁永清（右）、许基仁在媒体座谈会上&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“把青训当成头等大事来抓”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;上任后首站选择考察青少年比赛，宋凯想传达的信号非常明确：“足球想振兴，首要是抓青训。未来中国足协要把青训当成头等大事来抓。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宋凯表示，一方面要鼓励高水平教练从事青训工作。“竞技成绩不好，首先说明训练不行。我们没有好教练去做青训，青训教练待遇确实和职业队差距很大，这是个现实问题，需要逐步去改变。中国足协要力争通过政策规定和导向，引导最好的教练去抓青训。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，要建立高水平、稳定的青少年竞赛体系。“12岁时中国球员和日韩球员水平相当，但到16岁差距就很大，这主要是竞赛体系的差距。只有多参加高水平比赛，球员才能不断成长。我们的竞赛体系问题是不稳定，青少年竞赛体系一定要保持稳定，可以进行合理的改进，但总体框架要保持不变。”宋凯说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/c238d83b720e76683a63f3053a1db926.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/c238d83b720e76683a63f3053a1db926.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255014&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（资料图）小球员在球场上比赛。新华社记者周密摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈及中国足球究竟应该采用怎样的青训模式，宋凯说：“现在中国足球青训主要有职业俱乐部、专业体工队、社会机构和校园足球等不同路线，中国足协首先要巩固根据地，守住基本盘。中国足球完全重回体工队模式不现实，但可以通过全运会的政策导向来提高各省市的积极性，加大各省市对足球的支持力度。”宋凯说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在坚持修炼内功的基础上，宋凯认为青训的发展也需要借助外力。“借助外力包括请进来、走出去和归化球员，这都可以探讨。我们对青训的理解和足球发达国家有差距，那就要虚心学习。青训的国际化很重要，据统计中国现在有137名注册外教，未来要继续提升青训教练的国际化程度。青少年联赛也可以考虑放宽国籍限制，增加交流机会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/1f2957ee55bb560399fe419d8ecd75e9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;725&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/1f2957ee55bb560399fe419d8ecd75e9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255016&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月8日，东亚足联U15男足锦标赛，中国队在颁奖仪式上庆祝胜利。新华社记者李紫恒摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在今年9月举行的东亚足联U15男足锦标赛中，中国队击败日本队夺冠。宋凯表示：“U15的球员确实让我们看到一些希望，到2034年世界杯他们正好是当打之年，我们得把这个年龄段抓好。各方都建议申办世少赛、世青赛，中国足协目前正在考虑，我们也在和国际足联探讨此事。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“中国足球不开放不行”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在16日的就职演讲中，宋凯提到“更开放”“对接亚足联，放开外援限制”等话题。本次媒体座谈会上，宋凯解释这是希望通过扩大开放来倒逼中国足球提升竞争力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宋凯认为，中国足球长期处在相对封闭的环境中，球员缺乏竞争。“很多行业都证明了，只有在开放的市场中充分竞争，才能生产出价廉物美的产品。现在亚足联正在放宽外援限制，沙特联赛计划将每支球队外援名额增加到10人，别人都在开放，中国足球不开放不行。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国足球的长征，需要球员们一起走。如何让球员们走长征？仅仅靠教育不够，还要靠竞争和高淘汰率。通过扩大开放，来倒逼中国球员在竞争中提高水平。”宋凯说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/2f5472dd47520d8bf451e2f807ca9892.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/2f5472dd47520d8bf451e2f807ca9892.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于扩大开放可能导致国内球员踢不上球，进而影响国家队的问题，宋凯坦言：“包括西班牙在内很多国家联赛放宽外援政策，当时都在国内引发了很大的争议。中国足球扩大开放的过程中，肯定会有阵痛，中国足协一定要保持定力。国内球员在中超踢不上球，可以去低级别联赛。政策只能更开放，不能往回走。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宋凯同时表示，中国足协扩大开放的步子要稳。“我们一定不能着急出台政策，要用一年时间让各方充分讨论，要把事情想清楚说清楚，然后再来一步步实施。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“中国足协不能再出台&#39;奇葩&#39;政策”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;宋凯坦言，此前中国足协很多政策制定比较随意，给中国足球发展造成伤害。“中国足协以后不能再出台类似&#39;国家队打联赛&#39;&#39;U23球员政策&#39;这样的&#39;奇葩&#39;政策。中国足协要出新政策，必须要符合社会预期，这是我任内的第一个底线。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“新一届的中国足协会跟媒体建立更通畅的沟通渠道和沟通机制。真理越辩越明，未来中国足协的政策希望媒体能带头讨论，我们不会出台所有人都不同意的政策。”宋凯说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/0630b7d37b470fe1489dbc794328769d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/0630b7d37b470fe1489dbc794328769d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255018&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月18日，中国女足在设于澳大利亚阿德莱德克罗地亚人体育中心的2023年女足世界杯中国女足大本营训练，图为中国女足球员王霜（左）和张馨在训练中。新华社记者李一博摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于国家队发展，宋凯表示中国足协将坚持“久久为功”和“只争朝夕”相结合，在立足长远发展的同时，尽可能提升球队管理建设水平。“虽然国家队的事情着急也没用，但是我们要在现有的水平上，把国家队建设好。球队管理好了可能能发挥出120%的水平，管理不好就只能发挥出60%的水平。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国女足在本月底将迎来巴黎奥运会预选赛，中国男足将在11月中旬参加2026美加墨世界杯亚洲区预选赛。对于这两项关键比赛任务，宋凯表示：“我们近期强化了中国女足队内的管理，海外留洋球员也都召回来。中国女足在亚洲是有竞争力的，我们一定要把奥运会预选赛打好。中国男足的近况大家都不是太满意，虽然赢了越南队但技术含量不高，然后输给了乌兹别克斯坦队。我认为扬科维奇是个很好的教练，教练组需要总结一下经验教训。我们必须要更努力。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[视频小作文与泛道德批判：真的有助于社会道德风尚的提升吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259108]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;前段时间，“网友发视频举报女子多次陪领导喝酒醉卧街头”，引发大量围观与热议，许多人都刷到过，不少人马上建立起这样的“心智占位”：这事儿看来假不了，并顿时涌起鄙视或愤怒之类的情感，然后他们把此事抛到一边，又去赶下一个实锤或看起来实锤的热点，同样的正义感爆棚或义愤填膺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，在10月6日，山东省泰安高新技术产业开发区针对此事发布了调查情况通报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;令人啼笑皆非的是，所谓的“举报视频”中，视频拍摄者声称与该女子存在不正当男女关系的泰安新区党工委委员、管委会副主任张某，实际上与该女子（许某）不存在此类关系，而与许某存在男女关系的，恰恰是视频的拍摄和发布者孟某，已婚男子孟某在与未婚女子许某交往的过程中产生了情感纠纷，遂通过移花接木、恶意剪辑的手段制造了相关视频并在某平台发布，以此向对方进行“报复”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孟某发布包含不实信息的视频，对他人进行侮辱诽谤，显然是公然侵犯他人名誉权的违法行为，如果将此视为一种举报，那么毫无疑问属恶意诬告。而事情远没有这么简单，调查显示，同在高新技术开发区工作的张某和许某虽不存在“举报视频”中所说的不正当男女关系，但存在违规接受企业宴请的问题。正是这一情况，在一直关注事件的网友中引发了意见分歧。一些网民认为，尽管张某、许某二人存在其他问题，但“一码归一码”，并不能改变孟某侵犯他人名誉权的违法事实。另一些网友则认为，尽管视频发布者孟某的和“举报”不实，却歪打正着挖出了其他问题，如果对孟某进行追责，会让类似、的潜在举报者望而却步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场争论实际上包含着一个相当深刻的社会道德问题，即对“泛道德批判”和“低成本举报”的鼓励，真的有助于形成风清气正的社会环境吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;泛道德批判&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“泛道德批评”是网络时代相当流行的一种批判方式，批判者往往将一切私人恩怨和社会现象道德化，并借助“民意”之名获得“正义”的道德高地，居高临下地对攻击对象进行绝对化的道德挞伐。批判者往往借助“群体标签”，将公众对群体的某种刻板印象投射到具体的事件当事人身上，刻意扰乱公众对事件基本事实的判断，进而引导公众对当事人进行攻击，以实现当事人在道德层面上的“社会性死亡”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正因为“泛道德批判”往往能够借助民意之名占据道德高地，因此在成功挑动起公众情绪之后，批判者本人就获得了某种“道德金身”，即使其本身存在较大的道德瑕疵，也往往能在“正义”的大旗下豁免于质疑和责问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在前述事件中，视频发布者孟某显然利用“领导”“官员”等身份标签对当事人许某和张某进行了“标注”，进而引导公众将“糜烂贪腐”这一印象投射到许某和张某身上，扰乱了公众对事实本身“张某和许某是否存在不正当男女关系”的关注和分辨，最终达到使张某和许某“身败名裂”的目的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以说，孟某自导自演的这一出“曝光”和“举报”的闹剧是标准的“泛道德批判”，孟某自身存在道德问题，却又敢于肆无忌惮地虚构事实，对他人进行“泛道德批判”，就是认为自己一旦占据“正义”高地，就拥有了对他人进行单方面泛道德批判而自身不受任何道德质疑的特权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;道德感是一种社会意识形态，体现了公众对社会公平正义的追求，道德批判的目的在于在道德层面上褒美贬丑，惩恶扬善，进而推动对社会道德风尚的提升。然而“泛道德批判”则不然，道德败坏者站在“正义”的高地上抨击他人道德沦丧的怪相和闹剧比比皆是。“泛道德批判”不但不能助推社会道德风尚的提升，反而使得拉大旗作虎皮的投机小人得以横行网络，不但造成舆论监督失焦，还形成“以无德治有德”的社会道德退步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以毫不客气地说，“泛道德批判”是“道德批判”的异化与畸变。因此一个社会中，如果公众普遍热衷于“泛道德批判”不能自拔，则不仅不能令社会道德趋于进步，反而导致社会道德的退步和崩塌。而认为孟某非正义的行为歪打正着产生了“正义”的结果，因此不该受罚，或应该从轻处罚的网友，实际上也在潜移默化中受到了孟某“泛道德批判”的圈套的影响，而不自觉地接受了这样一种异化的网络道德观。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;低成本举报&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;除了“泛道德批判”外，“网友发视频举报女子多次陪领导喝酒醉卧街头”这一事件中存在另一个问题：我们的社会是否接受“视频曝光”这种低成本的“举报”方式，这种“举报”方式如果成立，是否应当和其他举报途径一样，需要举报者承担举报内容不实而产生的相应责任和后果？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;界定“视频曝光”行为是否符合“举报”定义的难点在于，它并不像传统的举报方式那样，是举报人—受理机构之间点对点的单向传递关系。而是往往以“泛道德批判”的开局在网络平台发酵成为舆情之后，倒逼相关部门进行调查。最终回应问题的，往往并不是传统的信访和纪检监察机制，而是舆情处置机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这导致了一系列的问题。首先，因为这种“举报”方式并非传统渠道，因此也很难受到种种规定的约束和限制，即使产生了法律后果，也往往是因“发布不实信息扰乱社会公共秩序”而受到惩处，而其“诬告”的行为则难以得到追究，这使得种种避重就轻、九真一假小作文、小视频得以以“擦边球”的方式大钻制度漏洞，败坏社会风气。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，这种利用舆情处置机制的“倒逼式举报”在有关部门调查前，就提前对当事人进行了道德审判，形成了无形的舆论压力对调查进行干扰，一旦调查结果与道德审判的结果不一致，极易引起公众对调查部门的质疑和攻讦，损害相关部门的公信力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，一旦别有用心者发现这种举报方式比传统的渠道更为“有效”，那么“先把事情闹大自然有人出来管”的心态必然泛滥，先将各种鸡毛蒜皮的生活琐事和个人恩怨上升到道德层面，再发布炒作形成网络舆情，进而倒逼相关部门出面“解决”问题的现象必然越来越多，大量的社会资源被迫投入无穷无尽无意义的调查中，本身就是一种对社会巨大的内耗。孟某的诬告最终“歪打正着”只是一个偶然，我们对社会公平正义孜孜不倦的追求，决不能依赖于网络诬告者的“歪打正着”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 22:25:17 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大账高企小账不绝  银保业务何以常年畸形？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259167]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As the channel business that contributes the largest premium to insurance companies, bancassurance is facing a new round of high pressure from regulations and new policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, 2023, Liu Sheng, the person in charge of the personal insurance supervision work of the State Administration of Financial Supervision, said that the regulatory authorities will consistently do a good job in the work of &quot;unifying reporting and banking&quot;; insist on catching up early and small , grasp the typical cases, continue to strictly supervise and strengthen accountability, rectify industry chaos, and effectively safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of insurance consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 22, the Personal Insurance Department of the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration issued the &quot;Notice on Regulating Insurance Products through Bank Agency Channels&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Notice&quot;) to all personal insurance companies, requiring all When filing products, insurance companies should clearly state the cost assumptions and fee structure in the product actuarial report, and list the commission ceiling; each insurance company should truthfully list the commission rates paid to the bank, and the actual fees such as commissions should be compared with the filing materials. Stay consistent, that is, &quot;unity of reward and action.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the issuance of the &quot;Notice&quot;, the Shanghai Insurance Association has issued an industry self-discipline convention. Following the Notice, insurance industry associations in Guangdong and other places also issued a self-discipline convention for bancassurance business. Self-regulatory conventions in various places target stubborn problems such as high fees and disorderly competition in bancassurance channels, and strictly prohibit vicious price competition, commercial bribery and other illegal activities that disrupt the order of the bancassurance market. We promise not to covertly increase bancassurance business fees through other channels and methods, and resolutely put an end to small accounts in bancassurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the pressure of supervision, it is imperative to reduce bank insurance fees. But why does the bancassurance business always suffer from the chronic industry problem of high large accounts and constant small accounts? It seems to be getting more and more popular as it becomes more banned. As early as August 27, 2019, the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission had clearly stipulated in the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; that commercial banks &quot;may not collect or demand any benefits other than those agreed in the agreement in any way from insurance companies and their personnel.&quot; Under this round of high pressure, will the chaos in the banking and insurance channels end? Will the bank insurance premium rate difference that plagues insurance companies turn into a fee difference from now on? How do bancassurance alliances develop internationally? What are some lessons worth learning from? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center reviewed the development history of bancassurance at home and abroad, and used horizontal comparative research methods to find that the root cause of the &quot;big and small account problem&quot; lies in the profit distribution mechanism caused by the loose cooperation between insurance and banks. imbalance. Under this cooperation model, banks are driven by unilateral profits, and the overall business falls into a dilemma of incremental growth but no efficiency gain. Researchers from Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center also visited different bank outlets as policyholders and conducted unannounced visits and found that the professionalism of bancassurance sales staff needs to be improved. Only when banks and bank employees transfer their focus on sales fees to professionalism will bank cooperation enter a new stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The stubborn problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bank insurance refers to a business model in which banks mainly sell insurance on their behalf. Together with personal agents and group insurance, it constitutes the main sales channel of insurance companies. Bancassurance is the core business of life insurance companies and the leading business of many small and medium-sized companies. In order to compete for premiums,&amp;nbsp;many small and medium-sized insurance companies have always maintained high-priced large accounts and various forms of small accounts, and many large companies have been passively involved in price wars. This is what the industry calls &quot;big and small accounts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot;big and small accounts&quot;? The &quot;big account&quot; refers to the handling fee agreed in the written contract between the insurance company and the bank, which is the bank&#39;s official income from the agency sales of insurance; the &quot;small account&quot; refers to the sales incentives privately given by the insurance company to bank staff, in various forms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2019, when talking about strict management of violations of regulations and disciplines at an internal meeting, the president of a joint-stock bank said that the one thing he could not tolerate the most was employees receiving kickbacks from insurance companies. In fact, regulatory agencies have also cracked down on small accounting issues many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as August 27, 2019, the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission had clearly stipulated in the &quot;Administrative Measures for the Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; that commercial banks &quot;may not collect or demand from insurance companies and their personnel in any way other than what is agreed in the agreement.&quot; any benefit”. Over the past few years, rectification has continued, but no significant results have been achieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/OuOgJkoLFPDWFMaDwkIxlbWLwDEYesUm9fthHglI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1509&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/OuOgJkoLFPDWFMaDwkIxlbWLwDEYesUm9fthHglI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Big accounts are high, small accounts are endless&quot; Why does it become a chronic disease? On the surface, the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is due to the strong position of banks and bancassurance cooperation due to their huge channels and strong customer resources. However, the root cause is that the interest distribution mechanism under the short-term and loose cooperation model between banks and insurance companies is insufficient. Reasonably caused. Banking and insurance are independent entities and there is no basis for equal cooperation between them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reasons for the strong position of banks are complicated, but in the financial market structure dominated by banks, it does not necessarily lead to the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot;. For example, in Europe, where the bancassurance business originated, in countries such as France and Italy, the bancassurance business not only accounts for a high proportion, but also makes a large contribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this is related to my country’s bancassurance cooperation model. Except for bank insurance companies and some giant insurance companies, the cooperation model between most banks and insurance companies is a &quot;many-to-many&quot; distribution agency model, that is, banks sign distribution agreements with insurance companies, and banks sell insurance through agency insurance companies. Products earn fees and commission income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this model, the determination of business philosophy, development of bancassurance products and insurance claims settlement are all undertaken by the insurance company, and both bancassurance and bancassurance parties only carry out superficial cooperation based on channel-level factors such as marketing channels and customer resources. cooperation. From the perspective of contract theory, it is essentially a simple principal-agent relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, outside the bank, the insurance company serves as the principal and the bank acts as the agent. The two define each other&#39;s rights, obligations and interest distribution methods by signing a cooperation agreement. The main incentive mechanism of the contract is that the bank earns handling fees from the bancassurance agency business, while the insurer transfers part of the benefits in exchange for rapid expansion of premium income, thus forming the first level of entrustment-agency between the bank and the insurance company. relation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within the bank, sales tasks are distributed layer by layer in the order of head office - branch branches - outlets, and the products are ultimately sold directly by bancassurance specialists at each outlet. According to the &quot;About Further Strengthening the Compliance of Commercial Banks&#39; Agency Insurance Business&quot; &quot;Notice on Sales and Risk Management&quot; stipulates that commercial banks shall not allow insurance company personnel to be stationed in bank branches. Therefore, relevant personnel of the insurance company can only supervise and assist bancassurance sales in the form of patrol points. A second principal-agent relationship is formed between the bank and its employees based on the sales of bancassurance products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, the sales intensity of sinking channels determines the amount of premiums to a large extent. Moreover, because of the existence of a double principal-agent relationship, the two parties have conflicting goals. Specifically, banks tend to sell single payment or short-term regular payment insurance products with high commission rates, simple terms and simple benefit demonstrations. As for the compatibility between customers and products, agents are not particularly concerned. However, regular payment insurance with long payment period and comprehensive protection functions is the type of insurance that insurance companies hope to sell because of its high intrinsic value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, insurance companies compete fiercely for banking channels. The &quot;Measures for the Administration of Insurance Agency Business of Commercial Banks&quot; promulgated in 2019 (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Measures&quot;) stipulates that each branch of a commercial bank can only cooperate with no more than 3 insurance companies in the insurance agency business in the same fiscal year, that is, &quot;1+ 3&quot; mode. The quality and configuration of banks’ sinking channels have become the focus of competition among insurance companies. Therefore, the Measures have to a certain extent intensified competition among insurance companies for banks’ high-quality channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the context of serious product homogeneity, large accounts and small accounts have become an alternative competitive weapon. Liu Sheng commented that in recent years, the personal insurance industry has experienced severe homogeneous competition, and insurance companies generally have extensive expense management, resulting in actual expenses exceeding the level at the time of product filing, resulting in &quot;inconsistent reporting&quot;. High fees not only disrupt the market order, but are also the root cause of problems such as false fees, false insurance applications, and false surrenders. They are also the breeding ground for &quot;black agency products&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To what extent are bancassurance channel fees exaggerated? Liu Sheng revealed that as of October 20, the vast majority of banks carrying out bancassurance business have re-signed contracts with insurance companies in accordance with the requirements of &quot;unification of banks and banks&quot;. Preliminary estimates show that the commission rate for the bancassurance channel has dropped by about 30% compared with the previous average level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the results of the competition between &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is the fragmentation of market share. According to statistics from Guolian Securities, judging from the scale of bancassurance channel premiums of personal insurance companies, the market share of the top ten companies in bancassurance channel premiums has dropped from 59.9% in 2017 to 52.1% in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Due to the intertwining of various reasons, the bancassurance channel has formed a status quo of &quot;high cost and low value&quot;. The bancassurance channel is also one of the channels where policyholders complain more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the problem of &quot;big and small accounts&quot; is the intersection of history and reality, and is the product of the extensive development of the insurance industry in the past. In recent years, the insurance industry has received great attention in supporting economic and social development, and regulatory authorities have promoted deepening reforms in multiple key areas, including comprehensive system construction and core areas such as corporate governance, solvency, capital utilization, and consumer rights protection. The &quot;Notice&quot; releases a signal of reform, which will curb the industry&#39;s &quot;big and small accounts&quot; problem to a certain extent. However, whether the stubborn problem of &quot;big accounts, high prices, small accounts, and constant supply&quot; can be completely eradicated still depends on industry self-discipline, deepening cooperation between banks and insurance companies, and improving long-term incentive mechanisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Change&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Window period&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Why are the temporary management agencies stepping up their efforts to rectify the bancassurance business at this time? A researcher at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that the insurance industry has undergone major changes under the new situation, and this is a window period for reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the insurance industry is concerned, the agent team continues to shrink, and the growth rate of original premium income of the personal insurance industry is hovering at a low level. In 2022, the personal insurance industry will continue to be under pressure and enter a period of deep adjustment. That year, the original premium income of life insurance was 2.45 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of only 4%, accounting for 71.6% of personal insurance premiums. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/Ted4LW6uHu6upX9Pr6OsFDZHhV2Uc5wiKBxoBr6h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1509&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/Ted4LW6uHu6upX9Pr6OsFDZHhV2Uc5wiKBxoBr6h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the public’s awareness of social security is gradually increasing The trend of aging and social aging still creates demand space for the development of the personal insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of consumer behavior, insurance consumption has changed from &quot;should I buy it&quot; to &quot;is it good or not.&quot; The &quot;2022 China Internet Insurance Consumer Insight Report&quot; shows that consumers aged 31-40, mainly those born in the 1980s, spend more on insurance, and 75% of households spend more than 5,000 yuan on annual insurance. It can be seen that young consumers’ awareness of insurance and willingness to pay have increased significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From an operational perspective, some small and medium-sized insurance companies have relatively aggressive product pricing strategies, and some products have risks of long-term insurance and short-term insurance. At the same time, in the context of declining long-term interest rates and declining corporate investment yields, incremental whole life insurance with the function of locking long-term interest rates will expose insurance companies to the risk of spread losses. Data from China Chengxin International shows that in 2022, the insurance industry&#39;s investment return rate will drop to 3.8%, a decrease of 0.6 percentage points from 2021, which is significantly lower than the industry&#39;s average investment return rate of 5.3% in the past ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the life insurance version of “interest rate cuts” has been implemented. Supervision has clearly provided window guidance. Before the end of July 2023, the predetermined interest rates for new personal insurance products will be adjusted. After dealing with the interest rate loss in the short term, how to solve the fee difference loss has become increasingly urgent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform of bancassurance channels is a key measure to alleviate fee differences. What conditions are met for channel purification at this time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found through statistics and comparison that as of the end of 2022, the total number of agents of Ping An, China Life, China Pacific Insurance and New China Insurance was 1.59 million, down from 1.64 million in 2010 Thousands of people. The efficiency-improving reform of personal agency channels continues to show no significant results. At the same time, since 2020, major domestic listed insurance companies have been actively developing bancassurance channels, promoting the strategic transformation of &quot;new bancassurance&quot;, and have introduced a series of measures to strengthen the depth of cooperation with banks, hoping to achieve Growth in scale and value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/YNoRagCWoyIZy6owM3Nsbl1ehNwhFJkW3z4NSEkC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/YNoRagCWoyIZy6owM3Nsbl1ehNwhFJkW3z4NSEkC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take Ping An Life as an example, financial report data shows that, From 2019 to 2022, the growth rate of new policy premiums in the bancassurance channel was as high as 19.1%, significantly ahead of the individual insurance channel and other channels. The premium growth rates of the two during the same period were -10.1% and -7.5% respectively. The proportion of the company&#39;s new premiums increased from 4.2% in 2019 to 9.2% in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This also shows that the agent channel that can best bring high intrinsic value policies to life insurance companies is still being adjusted. However, small and medium-sized insurance companies are basically unable to cultivate a large-scale agent team. In other words, the importance of the bancassurance channel has increased, highlighting the need for reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banks are also facing performance pressure. In a situation where interest spreads have shrunk, wealth management products have been depleted and trust products have become scarce, the agency insurance business has become a performance highlight. Take China Merchants Bank as an example. In 2022, China Merchants Bank&#39;s fund agency business revenue dropped by 46.4% year-on-year, and its proportion of non-interest income also dropped from the highest value of 13.0% in 2015 to 6.6%, while insurance agency sales revenue has remained at around 50% for two consecutive years. positive growth, and its proportion in non-interest income also increased significantly to 11.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/G9GBKprgogUlHMExIlVxAUdWI5O1QjROYAJ7tms1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;974&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/G9GBKprgogUlHMExIlVxAUdWI5O1QjROYAJ7tms1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the depth of both banks and insurance companies The window period for cooperation has arrived, and regulatory agencies and associations have the “right time, favorable location, and harmonious relationship” to crack down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that from the perspective of insurance companies’ profit models, among the “three differences”, death and fee differences account for relatively small proportions. The &quot;Notice&quot; aims to standardize sales expenses and prevent unfair competition. It is one of the important measures to standardize insurance sales behavior in a multi-dimensional and systematic manner. Following the &quot;Notice&quot;, the &quot;Insurance Sales Behavior Management Measures&quot; recently issued by the State Administration of Financial Supervision will be implemented from March 1, 2024. The &quot;Measures&quot; echo the &quot;Plan for the Construction of the Sales Ability Qualification Grading System for Insurance Sales Practitioners&quot; previously issued by the Insurance Industry Association, and aim to guide insurance companies to establish a product grading and channel grading system that matches customer needs. With the combined efforts of multiple measures, the results of this round of bancassurance channel rectification are worth looking forward to. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Overseas Bancassurance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Close&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Type&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bank Insurance It has existed abroad for more than 60 years. What can we learn from it? Researchers from Southern Weekend&#39;s New Finance Research Center found out that there are two theories about the origin of bancassurance: one is Britain in the 1960s; the other is France in the 1970s. However, the development of bancassurance business in Britain and France is quite different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;New Bancassurance Era: The Beginning of Value&quot; released by Deloitte in 2023 shows that bancassurance channels in France, Italy and Spain account for 64%, 74% and 60% of all premiums respectively. %. Among Asian countries, South Korea accounts for 50%, Indonesia accounts for 48%, Singapore accounts for 30%, and India accounts for 25%. The UK bancassurance business has developed slowly and mainly relies on insurance broker channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the evolution of cooperation models in various countries, four bancassurance business cooperation models, namely agreement agency, strategic alliance, capital cooperation and financial group, have proven to be quite successful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/XyLiWZmPSs8wjHkxV4pG5kt5zLfSUZwE5GzmMaBW.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1535&quot; height= &quot;3358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/XyLiWZmPSs8wjHkxV4pG5kt5zLfSUZwE5GzmMaBW.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take France as an example. Banks enter the bancassurance field mainly by controlling insurance companies. Banks control insurance companies in two ways: establishing self-owned subsidiaries and acquiring other insurance companies, with the former being the main form. In terms of products, simplified and standardized life insurance or savings products are the main products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banking and insurance in Hong Kong, China also implement mixed operations, and large banks build their own insurance companies to achieve bancassurance synergy. The same is true for Taiwan, China. Bancassurance is mostly carried out in the form of a financial holding company. Its insurance product sales channels mainly include joint marketing through financial holding companies and strategic alliances, that is, business cooperation promotion through financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overseas experience shows that the development process of bancassurance is a process of banks and insurance companies jointly exploring consumer needs. It is a common choice for banks and insurance companies to choose the path of bancassurance cooperation and provide bancassurance products that meet the diverse needs of consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of development experience, the global bancassurance industry has experienced three stages: bancassurance, insurance banking and universal finance. They are essentially the cross-penetration, mutual integration, mutual complementation and common development of banks and insurance companies in many aspects such as product research and development, sales channels, organizational forms and business strategies, that is, the mixed operation of banks and insurance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the development models of bancassurance vary in different countries and regions. In other words, there is no universally applicable bancassurance development model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that my country’s bancassurance started relatively late but is developing rapidly. Data from the &quot;Insurance Yearbook&quot; show that in 2010, China&#39;s bancassurance channel premium income accounted for 50% of life insurance premium income, which was the highest in history. However, the cooperation between banks and insurance companies has always been based on the sales agreement model, and the cooperative relationship between banks and insurance companies is relatively loose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This model has obvious shortcomings. First, bancassurance cooperation is limited to the sales level, and there is a lack of motivation to jointly develop products; second, banks only act as agents for insurance products to obtain agency fees, and the cooperation between the two parties is short-term and unstable. Third, driven by short-term financial goals, both parties lacked enthusiasm in cultivating bancassurance professionals, resulting in low bancassurance service levels and frequent misleading sales problems. Therefore, my country’s banking and insurance cooperation model needs to be further deepened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Explore new ways of bancassurance cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to establish a healthy and win-win bancassurance ecosystem? The development experience of overseas banking and insurance shows that the financial legal environment and the form of organizational cooperation are crucial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the banking and insurance industries are under the unified supervision of the State Administration of Financial Supervision, and the regulatory coordination of the two industries will be smoother. At the same time, banks’ huge channels and strong customer resources are excellent channels for bancassurance to acquire customers. In addition, after years of market education, people generally have insurance awareness. Bank customers are naturally aware of financial management, and the question has changed from &quot;whether to buy&quot; to &quot;which product to buy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, for insurance companies and banks, the customer acquisition cost advantage of the bancassurance channel will exist for a long time, and it will still be the main channel for insurance companies, especially small and medium-sized insurance companies, and it is not to be underestimated in banks’ collection business. field of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to build a new cooperation method for banks and insurance? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that judging from overseas experience, the four models each have their own merits. At this stage, we can appropriately promote the development of in-depth bancassurance cooperation models. Those who have the conditions can try it at a higher level. my country&#39;s bancassurance development model has transformed from a sales agreement model to a strategic alliance model. In the future cooperation between bancassurance and insurance, the following points should be implemented: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. In terms of business philosophy, both bancassurance and bancassurance parties should completely transform the extensive operation that puts scale first, and truly shift from &quot;sales-centered&quot; to &quot;sales-centered&quot; Customer-centric&quot;. This will help both banks and insurance companies reach a consensus and shift to long-term business goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. In terms of cooperation methods, promote the transformation and upgrading of bancassurance cooperation. On the one hand, through strategic alliances between banks and insurance companies, &quot;capital integration&quot; and other methods, the constraint mechanism for the distribution of interests between banks and insurance companies will be reconstructed, and the &quot;discourse power&quot; of insurers in bank-insurance cooperation will be enhanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of laws and regulations, it is recommended to further optimize relevant laws and regulations. Objectively speaking, under the &quot;1+3&quot; model, the collaborative business relationship between banks and insurance is not stable, which increases the coordination costs between the two parties and exacerbates the inequality between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[科技之手点燃梦想之火——访杭州亚残运会主火炬手徐佳玲]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259159]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the lighting ceremony of the opening ceremony of the 4th Asian Para Games in Hangzhou on the evening of the 22nd, the last torch bearer , disabled swimmer Xu Jialing stepped onto the main torch stand and changed the torch &quot;laurel crown&quot; from her right hand to her left hand in front of everyone&#39;s attention - her smart bionic hand lit the main torch of this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/520dfc8ee375d7df0f42c77b3263bbd2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1014&quot; height= &quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/520dfc8ee375d7df0f42c77b3263bbd2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255022&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wu Zhizun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, I only found out through the news that I was the last one.” Before the rehearsal of the opening ceremony, Xu Jialing had already worked with Intelligent Bionics with the help of the research and development company Zhejiang Qiannao Technology. It took me a while to get my hands on it and I can control it pretty well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“A staff member previously informed me that I was the infield torchbearer for the opening ceremony, but I didn’t know which torchbearer I was.” Until I saw Sha Xiao, the chief director of the opening ceremony, in the news. Lan revealed how to light the main torch, and Xu Jialing realized that she, who had been working with the intelligent bionic hand, would bear the final blow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;At that time, I felt that I was very honored to be given such an important task.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/397cd0ba6f42ec45937985f88916b756.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1016&quot; height= &quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/397cd0ba6f42ec45937985f88916b756.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255023&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Beh In Chinese language, this is called &quot;controlling with thoughts.&quot; &quot;Actually, I am already accustomed to life after amputation, but the smart bionic hand allows me to hold the torch with both hands and light the sacred flame. It is also very convenient in life. I can hold a water cup and twist the bottle cap.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smart bionic hand that looked very technological at the opening ceremony has actually undergone improvements in appearance design. &quot;At the beginning, we made a skin-colored version of the hand and socket for Xu Jialing. In order to make the overall visual presentation more technological, the team replaced her with a space gray hand and a carbon fiber socket. She also said she liked it very much. .&quot; revealed the intelligent bionic hand engineer team of Zhejiang Qiannao Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My prosthesis is very cool!” Xu Jialing’s tone revealed happiness and pride. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fdebe0f9d70f3c09452d5e3a338293e6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;729&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/fdebe0f9d70f3c09452d5e3a338293e6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255025&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, was at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Bei He&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, Xu Jialing’s cheerful and optimistic words often make people forget that the “cool” high-tech product we are discussing is being worn on her slightly defective left arm. superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2006, 4-year-old Xu Jialing was involved in a car accident and her left arm was no longer intact. By chance two years later, her mother discovered that Xu Jialing liked to play in the swimming pool, so she considered sending her to learn how to swim. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The coach thought that Xu Jialing might be good at swimming. Coupled with the recommendation of the local Disabled Persons&#39; Federation, Xu Jialing trained in her hometown of Ningbo for 6 years, successfully entered the Zhejiang Provincial Disabled Swimming Team, and went on an expedition with the national team. Rio 2016 Paralympic Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/07a4a3c6953404a1d8d8bc098f0726b7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1019&quot; height= &quot;755&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/07a4a3c6953404a1d8d8bc098f0726b7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255027&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 15, 2016, at the Rio Paralympic Games, Xu Jialing (middle) won the S9 championship in the women&#39;s 100-meter butterfly. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yang Lei&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Rio, 14-year-old Xu Jialing, as the youngest competitor of the Chinese delegation at the time, won 1 gold and 2 bronze medals, which can be said to be &quot;the peak at her debut.&quot; After that, she won 7 gold medals and 2 silver medals at the 2018 Jakarta Asian Para Games. Although she experienced a trough in the subsequent Tokyo Paralympics, Xu Jialing&#39;s mentality is now very calm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When I won the gold medal in Rio, the journey may have been too smooth. At that time, I felt that it was not too difficult to stand on the podium. In Tokyo, I was not able to get on the podium even once. There will be disappointment, but it is also expected, because the state was not very good at that time.&quot; Xu Jialing said, &quot;The mentality now is more about training well and letting nature take its course.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only cheerful Optimistic, Xu Jialing often shows maturity beyond her years in conversations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the Rio Paralympics, 14-year-old Xu Jialing said in an interview: &quot;I think my life is very exciting, no worse than my able-bodied peers.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/70ae3dfa16f7209dc6e5dc2f72cbc3fa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1015&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/70ae3dfa16f7209dc6e5dc2f72cbc3fa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255024&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 2, in the women&#39;s 100-meter butterfly S9 final of the Para Swimming World Championships held in Manchester, England, Chinese athlete Xu Jialing won the championship with a time of 1 minute, 08 seconds and 34 seconds. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Photo by Jon Hupper)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven years have passed, looking back on the growth process, Xu Jialing’s youth can indeed be described as “wonderful”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to her dazzling competition results, Xu Jialing also likes to travel during her limited holidays. In addition, she trains and competes with the team overseas, allowing her to leave precious memories around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jialing is currently a student in the &quot;Championship Class&quot; of Beijing Sport University. Her major is sports training. &quot;I&#39;m very happy to be back in school.&quot; Xu Jialing, who has been training for swimming for most of the past ten years, said, &quot;Studying in college can not only learn knowledge, but also better understand the major you are engaged in. I think this is The chances are good.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/86f546b15442a09ba566768e51702cbf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;1014&quot; height=&quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/86f546b15442a09ba566768e51702cbf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255026&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 22, Xu Jialing, the last torchbearer, lit the main torch at the opening ceremony. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wu Zhizun&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Xu Jialing has become the main torchbearer of the Asian Paralympic Games. With the help of technology, she lit the main torch in the spotlight and illuminated her youth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the development of science and technology, more and more devices and equipment such as smart bionic hands help people with disabilities make up for their physical deficiencies, igniting their belief in pursuing their dreams. But in Xu Jialing&#39;s view, the word &quot;equality&quot; may be as important as technological assistance to the disabled group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Personally, I don’t want everyone to look at us with a pity and want to cry. Our ability to stand on the Asian Paralympic Games, just like any athlete, is a result of hard work. The result of training. Maybe our training will be harder and it will be more difficult at the beginning, but we still hope that everyone can treat us with a normal mind.&quot; Xu Jialing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网传“前台实名制”将落地：能有效改善网络空间的现实生态吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259112]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, it has been reported online that the &quot;real-name system at the front desk&quot; is about to be implemented, causing concern and discussion. &quot;Come and Go&quot; (Wang Gaofei, CEO of Sina Weibo) quoted a media comment &quot;&quot;Real-name system at the front desk&quot;, big V should have taken off his vest long ago&quot;, which showed that the rumors were true. He also stated in a reply: The real-name system at the front desk is aimed at It is a self-media account with 1 million fans, which will be reduced to 500,000 fans in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the Central Cyberspace Administration of China issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening the Management of &quot;Self-Media&quot;&quot;. Among the 13 articles, there is a requirement to &quot;standardize account operation behavior&quot;: website platforms should strictly implement the &quot;one-person According to the regulations on the number of account registrations for &quot;One Number, One Enterprise and Two Numbers&quot;, individuals or companies are strictly prohibited from manipulating the &quot;self-media&quot; account matrix to publish and disseminate illegal and harmful information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current network platform implements a &quot;backend real-name system&quot;, and the front-end real-name and pseudonym are decided by oneself. If you really commit a crime on the Internet, you cannot go unpunished. The police will find you very quickly. Because the phone number used for registration itself is a real-name one; the IP addresses of Internet users are recorded in the background. However, even if real names are used in the background, as long as the person does not actively expose his or her information, the anonymity of online accounts is still quite strong, and online moral constraints are far inferior to offline ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, for some people, if they want to maintain the quiet handsome man/demure lady personality that the large account has established, or if the large account exposes private information, they can just create another small account, go there Say something that the big one won&#39;t say. In this way, a person&#39;s personality can be divided into three: the offline one, a normal person in the eyes of colleagues and family members; the large one, an image with an ideal personality; the small one, another one, All kinds of darkness and nastiness appear. Seamless switching between ego, superego and id. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bigger problem with anonymity is that some self-media, in order to create topics and traffic, have no bottom line at all, and use all kinds of opposition to mobilize, engage in &quot;team building&quot;, and brush up comments and hot searches. Using a small power to create a huge voice in an organized manner to create public opinion and influence the legislative and judicial process; the same party opposes dissent, and organized super-saturated attacks, harassment, and threats against individuals and institutions that disagree with their actions and values. This is It has become a public nuisance, constantly dissolving the consensus and values ​​on which society relies for survival, and greatly deteriorating the ecology of public spaces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, can these problems be solved by allowing self-media accounts with 1 million or even 500,000 fans to have real names at the front desk? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We might as well do a model analysis. There is a group of people, each of whom has a voting right. So which one is better, anonymous voting or real-name voting, so that everyone can express their true opinions and make the results more fair? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people think it is better to vote anonymously: this way everyone can express their true opinions without pressure. But the disadvantages of anonymity are also obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, some people may be bribed or asked privately, because the final result is anonymous. Except for people who are colluding with each other, others have no way of knowing how they voted and no moral pressure can be exerted on them. , in this case, the vote he cast probably cannot be called &quot;expressing his true thoughts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, even if some people have not been bribed or accepted private requests, their voting tendency may not be fair. For example, they may not want to let others go because they have personal grudges. Or maybe it&#39;s purely because of the &quot;Prisoner&#39;s Dilemma&quot;: No matter you vote for or against my favorite, I will always vote against it, at least without losing money. In this way, unanimously opposing it becomes an advantageous strategy. Having a significant number of people think this way can significantly skew the overall voting results. Although these voters &quot;expressed their true thoughts,&quot; they had nothing to do with fairness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, it is not ruled out that there are some people who are pure in nature and will not be bribed or accept private requests under any circumstances. They will put aside their personal grudges during the voting process and do not bother to conduct sophisticated calculations of interests. There are some people who objectively judge candidates based on their own merits, but they are probably few. In addition, it does not rule out that the above two types of people will vote fairly under certain circumstances. If the candidate is too good/bad, they cannot resist their conscience by insisting on voting against/for voting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people also think that real-name voting is good and can effectively reduce the above two unfair situations of anonymous voting. Everyone&#39;s voting results will be seen by others, thus making it easier to vote for favors and vote for personal grudges. Exposing the behavior of calculated votes to the public will significantly constrain such behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But real-name voting is not without problems. First, some weak-minded people are afraid of offending others and do not dare to truly express their wishes and cast a fair vote when voting with real names; second, voting with real names will make the differentiation of factions from vague to clear. After factions or cliques are formed, conflicts will become apparent and may intensify. These two points are also the main reasons for implementing anonymous voting: to allow everyone to vote without pressure, thereby limiting the intensity of conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To sum up, whether to vote anonymously or with a real name ultimately depends on which values ​​the institutions involved prefer and which issues need to be urgently resolved. How to apply this model analysis to whether the real-name system at the front desk should be implemented and the scope of implementation? If we want to solve the two problems of organized public opinion creation and organized over-limit attacks and harassment of individuals and institutions, we should undoubtedly implement a real-name system at the front desk to expose these organized and dark behaviors of self-media to the public and accept them. The scorching heat of the moral sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if only self-media accounts with 1 million or even 500,000 fans require front-end real names, it may not be enough to curb the organized and dark behavior of self-media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there is the question of how far the front desk needs to be real-named. Is it the real person in charge or the editor of the operation? How to solve the problem of letting people without decision-making power to top the tank and deal with the real-name front desk? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, organized public opinion creation and organized over-limit attacks and nuisance have become highly evolved. The main account with hundreds of thousands or millions of fans will not be left alone at first, allowing some peripherals or fans to send malicious messages or mobilization messages through small accounts, and then instigate or patiently wait for some accounts with fewer fans to forward them, in addition to layer upon layer of forwarding. , the main account will then follow up and forward, thus minimizing the risk of the main account. This method of &quot;wearing multiple layers of cover&quot; is difficult to break the real-name system at the front desk of some self-media accounts with many fans, because small accounts and accounts with fewer fans can still do their own thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>