<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“互换住房”有没有风险？理解年轻人对人性的乐观、对陌生人的善意丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258028]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The long holiday is long and it’s time to travel. According to the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, domestic tourism trips nationwide are expected to reach 896 million during this year&#39;s long holiday, a year-on-year increase of 86%. During the seven-day long holiday in 2019, the country received a total of 782 million domestic tourists. There is one more day this year, which means that the average number of domestic travelers during this year’s long holiday has returned to the level of 2019. It seems that the recovery of the tourism industry is real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data shows that during the long holiday, the cultural tourism market in popular tourist cities such as Shanghai and Suzhou in the Yangtze River Delta and Pearl River Delta regions is extremely hot. Orders for hotels, air tickets, etc. have increased at least five times compared with the same period last year. Prices have also generally risen significantly. On the eve of the long holiday, many netizens posted &quot;travel housing exchange&quot; posts on social platforms, looking for netizens with travel destinations opposite to their own to exchange housing and save money. This is in line with the original intention of tourism: traveling is nothing more than going from a place you are tired of playing to a place others are tired of playing, escaping from daily life and looking for a sense of alienation and freshness that is different from daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When exchanging houses, each party will go to the other party&#39;s city and live in the other party&#39;s house at the same time. The risk should be controllable, because each party at least knows the other party&#39;s real information such as address and contact information. &quot;Reciprocity&quot; is originally an effective means to establish a &quot;balance of power&quot; and control risks such as breach of trust. However, if the housing exchange agreement reached by both parties is that one party will first go to the other party&#39;s city during this holiday and live in the other party&#39;s house, and the other party will claim his own consideration after a period of time, there will inevitably be some risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is security risk. Even if there is an agreement, the person who comes to check in is a stranger to you, and you cannot verify his or her identity. He may use a fake name and ID card. Even if you do not reveal your true identity, your address, contact information and other information will always be with you. Really, this creates asymmetry and asymmetry. If the other party has a serious disease, it will harm the health of the family; if the other party has bad hygiene habits, the living environment will be very poor, which will inevitably cause headaches. If the other party intentionally or unintentionally damages the facilities in the house, it will also be troublesome. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, there is the risk of breach of trust. As long as it is not a transaction or agreement where the money is paid and the goods are delivered, there is such a risk. After you have fulfilled the agreement and entertained them with good intentions, but when you go to the city where they are located, they directly break the contract and breach of trust. There is nothing you can do. To protect your own rights and interests, or if the living conditions provided by the other party are far from what they claim, and they take advantage of you, you will most likely have to hold your nose and endure it. Physical exchanges are not delivered at the same time, and it is common for the goods to be incorrect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are complaints about &quot;specialty exchange&quot; everywhere on the platform: being taken advantage of and deceived by the other party. In the final analysis, there is still an underestimation of human nature. The ancients had a saying of &quot;Be cautious of independence&quot;, which is very reasonable as a criterion for judging whether a person is truly moral. Many people&#39;s morals are flexible: they speak morally in front of acquaintances, because failure to speak up will have consequences and will affect their reputation; they don&#39;t speak morally in front of strangers, and even do evil on the spur of the moment, because they feel that no one knows them. It is difficult to be held accountable even if someone is willful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, in order to avoid the above two risks, you insist on verifying the other party&#39;s identity, such as finding a trusted third party to guarantee, or collecting the other party&#39;s accommodation fee in advance? In this case, what&#39;s the difference between doing a B&amp;B? If you want to stay in a B&amp;B, wouldn&#39;t it be easier to list the available rooms for sale on the OTA platform? After being screened by the platform, the security risks are controllable and there is no risk of breach of trust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you insist on doing it yourself, you are actually following the old path of Airbnb’s evolution: At first, everyone just wanted to save money than staying in a hotel and build a platform to build a bridge. But after a period of brutal growth and After the chaos, it was discovered that the grass-roots team was not good enough, and it still needed specialization and standardization, so that professional people could do professional things. It was difficult to use amorphous &quot;non-standard&quot; services for a long time. In the end, Airbnb had not returned to the hotel model. The so-called B&amp;Bs that are aggregated are just numerous small-scale hotels run by private individuals. In large-scale talent shows, the final winners are often those who major in music or dance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having said that, exchanging housing is actually &quot;sofa living&quot; with a different name, and it also has its own ecological niche. People with families can&#39;t help but frown when they think of the above risks. When going out, they would rather spend money to stay in a hotel than get into trouble just to save money. This is indeed good. But for young people who have just started working, they rent a house that they can just live in. There are no valuables or facilities in it, they have no long-term possessions, and in short, they have no money. Because they are relatively young and fresh when they first enter the society, they have no understanding of human nature. With optimism and kindness towards strangers, the above-mentioned risks are not a problem. Isn’t it appropriate to let netizens from other places come and stay for a few nights, and do the same when I go to other places? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both are young people, both are poor, both understand the need to save money, and have a common topic. A stranger may be able to bring him a world that he has never been exposed to or even imagined before, fully exposing himself to Through randomness, you can interact with more people and discover a larger and broader world. If you go out on your own, you can &quot;travel thousands of miles&quot;, and when others walk in, you can &quot;travel thousands of miles to you.&quot; Movement is relative, and changing the frame of reference is the same thing. Your own experience and the experience of others can increase your knowledge. See. Although you may meet some bad people and weirdos, you will also get to know some good friends who can become lifelong friends. The risks are controllable, so why not? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of openness and sharing spirit among young people is commendable. To a certain extent, if all you think about when encountering problems are risks, and then you are hesitant and hesitant to do anything, it is actually a sign that your heart is getting older. Therefore, we can warn young people of risks in good faith, but there is no need to intimidate young people with various risks. We should be happy to see young people make full use of this youthful time. This beautiful and wanton time is short. Our body will age, but our mentality should try to stay young, energetic and courageous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[布克奖得主弗兰纳根：活下去，比时代活得更久]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257969]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/1VGcttsOmOq3e7DgDoZVaHIbBgiTj3sGId82ZeAd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/1VGcttsOmOq3e7DgDoZVaHIbBgiTj3 sGId82ZeAd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Joel Saget/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The world is becoming more and more uncertain and disorderly. Since no one knows what will happen tomorrow, this story may remind them that in an uncertain world In this world, we still have each other&#39;s love, which is probably the only thing we can be sure of in this life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, the Australian writer Richard Flanagan (Richard Flanagan) wrote the novel The novel &quot;The Way North&quot; won the Booker Prize. The novel is based on his father&#39;s experience of being captured by the Japanese during World War II and building the &quot;Death Railway&quot; in Thailand and Burma. It tells the life of Australian military doctor Dorigo Evans in two lines: he tried his best to save lives in a prisoner of war camp and was on the verge of death. companion, when he is lonely and hopeless, he will continue to recall the only unforgettable love in his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Flanagan&#39;s writing, &quot;Dorigo Evans will live a long time and witness all the changes&quot; - he feels that something is withering, but he will live on and be better than himself Live longer...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a masterpiece about love and war,&quot; the Booker Prize citation stated. &quot;Flanagan&#39;s elegant narrative tells a story of the coexistence of sin and heroism.&quot; The story connects the East and the West, the past and the present.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flanagan was born in Tasmania, southeastern Australia, in 1961. For generations, people have lived in this &quot;end of the world&quot; &quot;The logging life on a desert island. Both his grandparents were illiterate, and his father was the only one in the family who received a basic education. &quot;My father had a strong feeling for the beauty and magic of words. He lamented until his death that people can use these 26 letters to glimpse the universe. Reading can enjoy freedom and transcendent power. The magic carpet of literature has lifted me from this world. Take a small island far away.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1994, Flanagan published his debut novel &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot;. He tells the story of the river guide Aliyah in a language that is freehand, dreamy, and full of original tension. Even through his experience of capsizing a boat and drowning in Tasmania&#39;s Franklin River, through the torrent-like confessions of the dead, Flanagan closely tied his personal experience to the mythical history of Tasmania&#39;s ancestors. &quot;I could write about the mud, the smell, the heat and the blood, but it was the readers who brought the emotion, the sympathy, the sorrow and the pity. The book didn&#39;t get many reviews at the time, but it gained readers, which is enough to give a book life .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the late summer and early autumn of 2023, the new translation of Flanagan&#39;s &quot;The Road to the North&quot; and the Chinese translation of his new work &quot;The Surging Sea in Dreams&quot; were published in China. Hobart, the capital of Nigeria, accepted an online interview with Southern People Weekly. “Literature opened my eyes to the depth and breadth of each person, and the possibilities that are within each of us, both evil and good. When you realize that people can be everything, they can be murderers and When you are a saint, you can learn to look at the world with humility and understand that anything that happens has nothing to do with you, but is a way of our existence as human beings.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The lower world is more real, The universe of literature points directly to human nature&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I heard that before becoming a professional writer, you worked as a construction worker and gardener, and you also considered going to northern Australia for mining. How have your past work experiences inspired you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Indeed, I have done a lot of work, and these experiences have made me realize that most people&#39;s lives are so difficult. In order to have food to eat and a house to live in, people struggle to survive. They don&#39;t like their bosses, and their jobs are very menial and extremely hard. This is actually the daily life situation of most people in the world. I always tell myself that if I’m lucky enough to be a full-time writer, I’ll never forget those hard times and I’ll never complain about the difficulties of writing, because you’ve been given the extraordinary privilege of having the opportunity to do what you love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Various experiences in the past have also made me discover that when you are close to those powerful and famous people, their world is not real, but when you are at the bottom, people are often very honest, and they are Tell the truth to each other, so you&#39;ll find plenty of truth. My grandparents were both illiterate, and I was lucky enough to become a writer. When I was with them and their friends, I could see a real world, but when I was with people who had achieved great things, I found that understanding The truth is much more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your debut novel &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot;, the protagonist Aliash fell in love with a girl of Chinese descent, Kota He. You also wrote about the history of the He family. What original material was there? You also visited China in 2018, can you share your impressions? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, I have some Chinese cousins. In the 19th century, many Chinese came to Australia and they intermarried with the locals, so many Australians Everyone has Chinese relatives. I wrote about China in my novel because I grew up in such an environment and I am no stranger to the Chinese. There was a period in Australia&#39;s history when racism was high and many Chinese were forced to leave, but thankfully that has changed again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I visited China last time, I talked with the Chinese writer Yu Hua. His experience was very different from mine, but we shared our thoughts on reading and writing. His literature The hero is also William Faulkner like me, and I find that our creative philosophies are also very similar. When you become a writer, you may enter forbidden areas, but you also belong to a literary universe, and that universe speaks directly to human nature. I was deeply moved by the fact that you meet a friend from far away, who writes a book from another far away country, but you share similar sources of inspiration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned your hero Faulkner. Faulkner believed that experience, observation and imagination are three necessary conditions for a writer. Which one is the most important in your writing? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think Faulkner is not completely telling the truth here, because his experience is not rich, and mine is not. not much. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Laugh)&lt;/span>; I visited Faulkner&#39;s former home in Oxford, Mississippi, and he created that world out of his imagination, a kind of To a certain extent, this is also his observation of that world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Writing is a craft that requires long-term polishing, just like making furniture. Many times it is just the continuous improvement of ordinary labor, which is what Maupassant said: writing black words on white paper. But there is also a mysterious part to writing. The great jazz musician Duke Ellington once talked about his composition. People said that the piano music was so great. He said, no, it was a dream. I completely agree that all great creations are like a dream. When you dream, you will find that, for example, you are in Shanghai and I am in Tasmania, but we are connected, talking about the absent Yu Hua and the late Faulkner. You find that you are not just one person and one person. You are connected to everyone, even beyond time, space and life and death. All of this is you and not you. It is important to find this in imagination. This points to the highest realm of creation. When we reach there, we know that we are not you. No longer alone. Writing reminds me to share with others, and just as people can relate to a work of art, I think creators must bravely break into that place. Observation and description alone are not enough. We need to rely on imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;We are constantly corrupting as we move forward, and we are lost in the theater of emotions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Why is there always light at the beginning of all things?&quot; &quot;The Path to the North&quot; opens with this philosophical question. How did this beginning come about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Parts of this novel touch on the dark side of the world. I think that if your creation involves darkness, it must be balanced with light. If all readers see is the dark side, they will not believe it, and they have reason to choose not to believe it, because it is not in line with our knowledge and understanding of ourselves as human beings. . If there is only darkness in the end, then it does not truly tell the whole story of human nature. The core of the human spirit lies in having hope. Without hope, we are just zombies. So, I chose to balance the whole story with light and hope. Therefore, this work is about war, but it also depicts love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, my first memory of light is actually in that church, my grandmother and mother hugged me, and I saw a beam of light coming over me, and it was the woman who loved me. running in their arms. As we age, we lose our sight, our hair... but I think the saddest thing is that we lose that sense of wonder. As a child, you retained this extraordinary and wonderful feeling that as long as you could see the light, you were content. I wanted to commemorate this flash of memory by placing it at the beginning of the novel, because it tells a truth that we have long forgotten. As we grow up, we lose this sense of wonder, awe and joy, but this was once It’s a great truth that we learn as children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/evGuPm3gQAw3depowqukV3cC38KbhoPhgnsoHleY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;697&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/evGuPm3gQAw3depowqukV3cC38KbhoPhgnsoHleY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/wXQKHKqGQ9Jv9FhxHiozDTJvFvGsuPyia3Z9XQ81.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;214&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/wXQKHKqGQ9Jv9FhxHiozDTJvFvGsuPyia3Z9XQ81.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/XfHFyriUFmTJqw3kO2YZiU4zYpZjS0a6n2iBjsrT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/XfHFyriUFmTJqw3kO2YZiU4zYpZjS0a6n2iBjsrT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The novel opens with a description of a little boy’s fear after his finger was injured and being bullied by his peers while playing ball. Have these details about a boy’s growth also happened in your life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Actually, these are more based on stories my father told me. Tasmania is not like other places. It is the poorest region in Australia. People here not only live in poor areas, but also live in older eras. I tried to write that feeling in the story. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the football story, once again, he ran into the light and felt the light. This moment embodies the profound feelings we had when we were young, and we can never go back to them. There&#39;s this misconception in the West that we&#39;re constantly moving forward and shedding innocence, and I don&#39;t buy that. We are constantly corrupting as we move forward. In fact, innocence is a treasure we once had, but we are too forgetful and have discarded many of the most basic things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Later, crying became a simple confirmation of emotion... Emotions have become fashionable, emotions have become theater, and as actors, people have no way of knowing who they are after getting off the stage.&quot; Can you give some interpretation to this passage in the book? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The world is undergoing tremendous changes. People now express their emotions more, but sometimes, the emotions they express are not Not sincere. It&#39;s not good to suppress emotions, but I think sometimes expressions in public spaces have gone too far. Whether people agree with it or not, this is one of the biggest changes in the past 100 years. I think a novel could reflect these kinds of changes that we talk less about. I wanted a character who understood these strange changes and documented them. For the protagonist Dorigo, this change is shocking because he has been playing a certain role his whole life. He is not a hero but has to pretend to be one because this is what the other prisoners of war demand of him. After the war, he had to continue playing this role, he had to wear this mask, and he knew it was a lie, but it had become a necessity in life for other people, so he agreed, partly because he avoided it. own emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What interests me is that when a person becomes a leader or a celebrity, we often think that they created this identity themselves, but in fact we &quot;created&quot; them, we decided to let them Becoming a celebrity or a hero, sometimes these roles are a kind of imprisonment for people. Celebrity and fame are some manifestations of misunderstanding and trouble. Behind this is loneliness. The fact is that the more famous you are, the lonelier you are. This is not a paradox. But the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Life is alive, walking on the roof of hell, gazing at flowers&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The title and the first part of the quotation of &quot;The Path Deep into the North&quot; are all quoted from haiku by Matsuo Basho. The last four parts of the novel are opened with haiku by Kobayashi Icha. Please tell me your considerations in choosing these haiku. ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This book was difficult for me to write. At first I didn’t think I could do it. I didn’t want to offend my father by writing something that he felt was incompatible with his experience and seemed like a betrayal. It took me 12 years to write this work, and it also took me that long to find the most suitable way of expression. Finally, I finished this writing with love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t want to judge anyone, I just want to show what humans do to each other. I wanted to organize the book in a form that I learned from Japanese literature. I could use the most beautiful things in Japanese culture to present the worst atrocities in the same society. Writing it like this might be a way for me to liberate myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The structure of this book is a bit like &quot;Rashomon&quot;, looking at crimes from multiple perspectives, presenting different perspectives on the same crime, interspersed with Japanese poetry. I long to strip away all the trappings, and in fact, the more you strip away, the more you allow readers to discover the true meaning. When I write, I try to keep taking things away, cutting and cutting, so that what is left is something that the reader can find meaning and purpose in, rather than me telling him what it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Two of the haiku of Kobayashi Icha you quoted involve &quot; &quot;The World of Dew&quot;, how do you understand &quot;The World of Dew&quot;? What do you think of Eastern Zen thought? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Japanese militarism was deeply influenced by Zen thought&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;(Note: The theory of Zen is one of the ideological weapons used in Japanese militarism&#39;s war mobilization. For relevant discussions, see &quot;Japanese Zen and Militarism&quot;, &quot;Misunderstandings of Modern Japanese Zen and Its Beyond&quot; and other papers)&lt;/span>;, There is a strange ecstasy in the latter, but the same ideas can also manifest themselves as evil when they advocate Japanese militarism. At the end of the book, I quoted a haiku: &quot;While I&#39;m alive/Walking on the rooftops of hell/Looking at the flowers,&quot; for me, that&#39;s the haiku that sums up the book. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6iP1uFXMrQiBtPDCvjDW1CqReQ8mqJ2opPjBphOt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;594&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/6iP1uFXMrQiBtPDCvjDW1CqReQ8mqJ2opPjBphOt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2014, Australian writer Richard Flanagan (right) won the Booker Prize for his novel &quot;The Passage to the North&quot;&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;In the novel, you inserted the &quot;circle&quot; made with one stroke of the brush into the text. Could you tell us about your understanding and conception of this pattern? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is a famous death poem by the 18th-century haiku poet Zomizu. Death poems are one of the traditions of Japanese literature. Before, Zhishui grabbed a brush and &quot;drawed&quot; the poem. People found that he just used the brush to draw a circle on the paper. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To me, the void, mystery, and reincarnation contained in this circle fit the theme of the story, and also fit the novel’s repetitive structure, echoing from beginning to end, “the magnificent wheel, the eternal return.” &quot;: The Opposite of a Circle and a Thin Line.&quot; At the end of the book, we don&#39;t know whether Dorigo is dead or alive. In fact, he never left the prisoner of war camp. Some ghosts trapped him in a special place forever: there is love and hell. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tasmania, we have a different concept of time: it often feels like time goes back and forth and never moves forward. I think this is a broader concept of time. We often move from this year to next year, and then to the year after that. What happened 10 years ago is in the past, but the aboriginal people here believe that what happened a thousand years ago It is happening today and it will happen again tomorrow. I think this more truly reflects our self-perception. The idea that what happened in the past is the past is actually an illusion. Nothing has ever passed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When people suffer from dementia, we say they have lost consciousness, but they have only lost their memory. Once you lose your memory, you cannot control your current life because people rely on their memory to understand everything. So this Australian Aboriginal concept of time plays a role in my work, and my novels are often presented in a cyclical structure, rather than being linear in a one-dimensional space like most English novels. Narrative. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The past can be forgiven, but cannot be forgotten&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;From &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot; to &quot;The Path Deep into the North&quot;, your writings have all explored the secrets of memory. You once mentioned, &quot;I have witnessed how people who have lost their memory fall into panic. .&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I&#39;m fascinated by the way people remember the past. We usually think of memory as a kind of witness. I tell you what happened 50 years ago, just like I have a camera. But in fact, memory is more likely to be an act of creation, capable of spinning lies as well as truth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father gradually lost the memory of the violence and pain he suffered, but in the end, he left behind the idea of ​​love. Although what he experienced was not love, what he finally had Memory was something he himself discovered to be valuable. I thought a lot about this, trying to capture the way people think through memory. Memory is thought to represent some kind of statement of justice, which it may or may not be. There is a paradox here: when people experience major trauma and you and your compatriots suffer great pain, the first thing people want to do is forget. I think the reason why humans survive is the ability to forget; but with At the same time, in order to free yourself, you must retreat into your memory and face the shadows in order to understand what happened and free your soul. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to war, we are fed a lot of lies about villains and heroes. When something terrible happens, it doesn&#39;t just affect the individual, a terrible war or social unrest, the trauma affects my family as well. and friends, will eventually slowly poison the surrounding community, and even the entire society. Because war is a black hole of horror, and those huge traumas are difficult to describe and spread. Those who have experienced it sometimes erase part of their memories. The responsibility falls on novelists, who try to piece together the past to better understand what happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your father once said: &quot;You can forgive the past. , but you can’t forget.” You just mentioned releasing your soul. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I just said that people survive by forgetting, but they have to remember something, and people will hate it. You want to live because hate is a strong emotion, but ultimately, you can&#39;t move forward in your hate and you have to put it aside and find another way out. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father experienced a very touching thing during his lifetime. About twenty years ago, three middle-aged Japanese women showed up at my house. They were incredibly brave and dedicated their lives to documenting Japan’s war crimes. One of them wrote a book about Unit 731, a horrific crime committed by the Japanese in your country. She suffered a lot in Japan for writing this book. She herself is actually a survivor of the Tokyo bombing, a horrific crime committed by the Allies against Japan that killed more than 100,000 innocent civilians. But she came to my house with two other ladies. They wanted to apologize to my father. They did not represent the government or the Japanese people. I was very surprised. I never thought that someone from another country would come to my house and apologize to us. It meant a lot to our family to apologize and it was such a release for all of us. The feats of these three women taught me that there is a way out, and that it is not about dividing people into opposing sides, but that we can rise above it all and live a better outcome. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Salute to the open and free world&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; You often mention your father, can you tell us about your mother and siblings? I know you are the fifth of six children, have they all read your work? Any feedback? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You did your homework! We were all very close as brothers and sisters, and everyone was surprised that I became a writer. No one expected a writer from Tasmania. They read my books and liked my novels. Being a writer and winning the Booker Prize are honors, but in any family, you are ultimately a son or a daughter, a brother or a sister, and what your family means to each other is the most important thing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My mother was a lovely woman, full of stories. Tasmania was once the golden bag of the British Empire and a huge prison. Over the centuries, the British exiled felons here. Political prisoners, slave owners and slaves... all kinds of people came here. here. My ancestors are Irish, and there are many Catholics in Ireland. They gathered, intermarried, and settled here, forming a unique culture. Ireland is rich in stories and has produced many writers. I talk about my father because of &quot;The Road to the North&quot;, but I am very close to my mother. I have listened to her telling stories passed down from generation to generation since I was a child. Many of my writings come from my mother. Like women of her time, life was restricted and unlike Women today have all kinds of opportunities, but she was an amazing woman and I loved her so much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How has Irish literature influenced you? Are there any Irish writers that you particularly admire? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I admire many Irish writers, but the ones who really influence me are Borges, Neruda, and Marquez , Cortázar and other South American writers, because their world is more like the world of Tasmania. We have people here who do comedy, trying to find their own experience, their own reality and escape the colonial influence of the British, while they were trying to escape the colonial influence of Spain in South America. The beauty of Faulkner is that he was both an American writer and not, he was from the South but was never really accepted into the United States, but he had an important influence on French and South American literature, and in my opinion he really was the 20th century The central figure who achieved breakthroughs in novel writing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot; Aliash was not born in Tasmania, but in Trieste. Why did he choose this small European city as his birthplace? Joyce lived in Trieste, does this have anything to do with where he wrote &quot;Ulysses&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Flanagan:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That’s right! As you can imagine, Death of the River Guide was my debut novel, and I wanted my first &quot;child&quot; to be born in Trieste. Trieste is different from many places in the world. It is a mixture. It is freer and more open. It is not really Italy, it is not really Slovenia, and it is not really Germany, but it is all, all kinds of ideas. and culture meet there. What interests me is that Joyce wrote his great novel not in Paris, not in Dublin, but in this dilapidated, disintegrating old port. His writing was influenced by all these peoples, and he was deeply inspired by &quot;The Consciousness of Zeno&quot;, but the author Italo Svevo only used a pseudonym. He was an Italian Jew, and his real name was Ettore Schmitz. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is another reason why Aliash was born in Trieste. My wife is from Slovenia. When I wrote &quot;The Death of the River Guide&quot;, Yugoslavia had just disintegrated and Slovenia had just Birth. I am very interested in multi-ethnic countries where different ethnic groups live together and often have frictions and conflicts, but sometimes they are full of creativity. You just asked me which writers I am influenced by. I mentioned South American writers, but I am also influenced by Central European writers. Before World War II, especially before the 1940s, those great &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Central European)&lt;/span>; writers did not represent their own countries; Greater ideas at the time, but after ethnic cleansing many places became small enclaves. Australia, which was a very racist country for most of the 20th century, now opens its doors and welcomes everyone in and is a richer place because of its cultural and spiritual tolerance. Central Europe at the beginning of the 20th century allowed me to see a world full of hope. I made the protagonist in my novel live in Trieste to pay tribute to that open and free world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Hometown pain&quot;: I have never left home, but I feel vaguely separated from my hometown and feel deeply lost&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;关于2020年出版的新作《幻梦中涌动的海》，你曾提到，这部作品和“乡痛”&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（solastalgia）&lt;/span>;这个新词的意境相关。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这是一位澳大利亚哲学家提出的新词：当人所处环境遭到破坏，心底失落，隐隐觉得自己与故土剥离，从未离家、却有种异乡人思乡心切的痛感。澳大利亚经历了可怕的丛林大火后，这个词开始被大量使用。家乡经历一些重创后，意识到昔日美好一去不返，人就会有这种感觉。我认为，许多宝贵的东西以发展和进步的名义被夺走了，这种发展只让少数人受益，却剥夺了其他所有人的利益，这种创痛会以非常真实的方式影响我们，对我们的身心造成毁灭性打击。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ChimdINzerF1E9e4aSYlKuu6POdH2vTuv4HJnZsq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ChimdINzerF1E9e4aSYlKuu6POdH2vTuv4HJnZsq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2018年3月17日，北京单向空间，中国作家余华（右）对话澳大利亚作家理查德·弗兰纳根&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《幻梦中涌动的海》中，面临灾难，女主人公安娜不停查看手机上的新闻更新，但恐惧和焦虑只增无减。从丢失一根无名指开始，她身体各个部分逐渐消失，但她对此并无痛感也无知觉，这种构想是如何产生的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们生活在一个奇怪的时代，身上发生许多事，但我们选择不去察看。小说开头，我引用了英国浪漫主义诗人约翰·克莱尔的《纪念》：“破坏者和私欲的利斧砍倒了猎物；／我再也见不到这里的水莲木路和圆橡树窄街／还有像教堂讲坛般的中空大树：／圈地运动像拿破仑一样，把一切都铲除……”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;19世纪的圈地运动是欧洲历史上非常悲惨可怕的事情，但我认为，现在世界上出现了一种新的圈地运动，正从我们手中夺走那些精神上锚定我们的东西。人们开始失去四肢、眼睛、膝盖……没人注意到，与此同时，我们每天越来越多查看手机，而不是关注真实世界发生的一切。随着社交软件的兴起，许多人的灵魂被占领了。每个人都有公共生活和私人生活，还有自己的秘密生活，伟大的文学塑造冲突中的人物，他们做的是一件事，想的却相反，此外还有第三面，他们也不明白自己为何如此矛盾，这就是我们人类。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，这些高科技让我们公开展示自己的私生活，还能解读我们的生活，并将其转化为利益取悦他人。无论在哪国，这对我们都构成威胁，对大多数人来说，我认为，最终，它们的存在不是帮助我们，而是在剥削我们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得自己是个悲观主义者还是个乐观主义者？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;弗兰纳根：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;两者都不是。在《幻梦中涌动的海》里，安娜的母亲临终前说，世界如此美丽，但很少有人看见。我认为当我发现那些可爱的人时，世界是美的，但我们常常选择视而不见。我们让自己看得越多，希望就越大。所以我并不悲观，我试着每天去发现人身上朴素的美好，我相信这种点滴的喜乐会滋养你，让你活下去。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“助农”靠假货，走红靠演技？野生MCN怎么成了“凉山制造”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258014]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-02 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访《人世间》导演李路：“任何时代都是以小人物为分母构成的”丨影视大咖谈③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257479]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/mzmGTNwphgKGgaj8DF3clEEGx4gUPgwnkEr4HE63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/mzmGTNwphgKGgaj8DF3clEEGx4gUPgwnkEr4HE63.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;185579&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电视剧《人世间》中周家一家之主周志刚退休后从大三线回到老家、城乡结合部的“光字片”。即便如此，一家人过年也很难团圆包饺子。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（剧组供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电视剧《人世间》展现的是“沉默的一代”，也演活了“沉默的一代”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一开场，是1969年的中国。东北某省会城市吉春市的城乡接合部“光字片”，一个叫周秉昆的年轻人经历了两件大事：一是目睹了死刑犯游街和被枪决，其中一个是自己在工厂车间里一起干活儿的好哥们儿，深受震撼；二是父亲周志刚要去“三线”当泥瓦工，支援三线建设，哥哥周秉义和姐姐周蓉，也响应号召“上山下乡”，成了知青，家里只剩下“老疙瘩”周秉昆和母亲相依为命。一家人的生活轨迹从此发生巨变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;故事由此铺展开来，跨越五十年。“光字片”的常住户、工人阶层出身的周家五口人是故事的圆心，由此辐射出枝枝蔓蔓。周家人之外，《人世间》里出场的人物多达百人，勾勒出一代人的“大江大河”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该剧改编自作家梁晓声茅盾文学奖同名获奖小说《人世间》。导演李路拿到这本小说的时候，《人世间》还没有获奖，李路看完大为感动，决定改编拍成电视剧。他之前的两部代表作分别是反腐剧《人民的名义》和法治剧《巡回检察组》。更早之前，他是南京电影制片厂生产副厂长、江苏电视台电视剧制作中心主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李路拍电视剧有野心，要拍就要拍伟大的作品，《人世间》里的小人物，符合他心里对“伟大”的定义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;项目定下来，李路约梁晓声见面，见面第一句话，他问梁晓声：为什么要写这部小说？梁晓声告诉他，最初只是一些个人情愫。梁晓声的父亲是“大三线”的建设工人，1950年代中期就离开家，每隔几年才回一次。好不容易回家探亲一次，“知青”梁晓声又下乡了，总是和父亲错过，见面次数少之又少。梁晓声写《人世间》，其中一个原因就是想弥补感情上的缺失，尤其是父亲去世后，他觉得要用文字致敬那一代工人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁晓声一家的情况，和《人世间》的周家很像，“文革”期间，父亲去三线，梁晓声和大弟弟下乡了，家里剩下母亲、哥哥、妹妹和一个小弟弟。哥哥患有精神疾病，小弟承担了照顾全家的重担。剧中的周秉昆，就有小弟弟的影子。“这些留在城市普通劳动家庭的青年，在我们的文学、戏剧、影视剧中几乎是缺失的，他们被表现得非常少，是沉默的一代，那么我就为他们写本书吧。”梁晓声在采访中说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁晓声对李路也有问题，他反问李路：为什么要把这样一部小说拍成电视剧？李路回答：“我对工人题材有感情”。七年前，李路就自掏腰包，拿下了一部工业题材小说，却找不到编剧。和梁晓声一样，李路也是东北人，成长过程中，他目睹过东北重工业的繁盛和兴衰，也见证过工人群体在面对下岗时的阵痛和坚忍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《人世间》自2022年1月28日上线后，在网络形成热议，讨论的角度涉及方方面面，溢出了剧作本身——有讨论成功学、讨论孝道的：上北大的哥哥姐姐，学成归来当副省长，和没上过大学、全心全意照顾家的弟弟，谁更成功、谁更孝顺？有讨论爱情的：周家老两口，几年不见一面，他们之间有没有爱情？姐姐周蓉当年为爱不顾一切，跑到大山沟里陪诗人过苦日子、当知青，多年后却要面对爱人的出轨和背叛，她当年的付出到底值不值得？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《人世间》播出后，李路经常收到朋友发来的微信，一个医生朋友发来微信，反复向他确认，“秉昆和秉义，他俩后面没事吧？没出什么问题吧？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可能这种类型剧这些年少了一些，所以真是牵动大家的心。”李路告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李路记得2017年《人民的名义》播出时，“有来自各个阶层的反馈，包括好多省的领导中午吃饭看，坐在那儿拿着盒饭看《人民的名义》，还有部队的、社会基层群众，那真是破圈。这次我们也在密切关注，是否真正意义上的真破圈，是你在喊，还是更多人茶余饭后地喜欢。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“一定是温暖作为底色”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;梁晓声的原著《人世间》被称为“平民的史诗”，你决定拍摄《人世间》时，怎么理解和梳理这个作品？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李路：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我拿到《人世间》的时候是2018年6月，那时候它还没有获得茅盾文学奖，也没有被称为“平民的史诗”，只是一套小说刚刚出版。《人民的名义》之后，我拿了一些项目，觉得都没有超过《人民的名义》和《巡回检察组》的，这让合作团队也很为难。他们说那你要选一个什么样的题材呢，我就说，伟大的，就三个字。后来有一个文学编辑跟我说，梁晓声刚出了一部小说你看看，不过长一点，有115万字。我把这个小说读了，很感兴趣。但文字和视觉还是有巨大的区别，阅读层和收视群也是完全不一样的，所以从小说文字体到剧本要有一个提升，从剧本再到视觉化有另外一段路要走。现在呈现给观众的58集电视剧是我们紧凑到不能再紧凑的一个版本了，因为我们粗剪是88集，精剪是72集，送审是66集，最后压缩到58集。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你希望拍一部伟大的作品，《人世间》讲的是一群小人物的故事，这两者之间是否有关联？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李路：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;要看清楚《人世间》小说文字背后巨大的力量，这可能是很多人看不到的。写这么小的一个家庭、一条胡同、一个片区的青春史，怎么就折射出中国这五十年的巨大变迁呢？怎么能有巨大的感染力和影响力呢？说良心话是要眼光的。甚至也有人质疑网感，还有一些质疑受众的年龄层次，这么一个讲述苦难的故事，有没有人看，等等。我是这个戏的总负责、实操人，从选材到孕育、布局这个戏，我一直就像《人民的名义》一样（我是拿个人身份证跟最高检影视中心签的约）。我知道这种戏该怎么弄，该找谁演，在什么平台播出，是很清晰的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《人世间》拍摄定下来之后，我就跟梁晓声老师见面了。见面之后想听一听梁老师的创作初衷，就像当时我找周梅森一样，周梅森一句话就把我打动了，他说要做什么样的《人民的名义》，怎么样做。这次也是，梁老师来了之后，我觉得大家切合点是一样的，有一种使命感，想为百姓、想为平民，想为这个时代，中国历史上剧变的这五十年的人和事给予视觉、文字证明，大家还是有家国情怀的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;七年前，我个人掏腰包拿下了一部写工厂工业题材的小说，可是找不到编剧，没人来写。我认为这也是必然情况，因为七年前我们还在绝对娱乐中行走，拍出来可能也没有人静下来看，所以说好多事情生逢其时才是最重要的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《人世间》的开场就是“文革”期间的知青岁月，对这段特殊历史时期的展现，你的想法是怎样的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李路：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;梁晓声的“伤痕文学”是“好人文学”，这是在文学界深深盖上烙印的。但这次在电视剧里，我们没有在“文革”、知青问题上加更多的笔墨，用寥寥数笔代表了一个群落。像那个弹钢琴的女知青就是，她是从上海来的南方知青，来到大东北那么冷，用她的话讲，我这手就是为弹钢琴留着的，干不了粗活。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那个时候类似这样的知青故事很多，但咱们也没渲染，也没扩大，只把剧情如实地拍出来。她为了返城，付出很多，但即使这样一个小人物，我们也没有把她写一笔就没了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“伤痕文学”在一段历史时期是非常火的，后来渐渐淡出大众视野。你怎么看伤痕文学，尤其是把它改编成能被当下接受的影视作品，你面临的最大挑战是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李路：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;“伤痕文学”是改革开放之后特定一段历史时期的一种提法，现在提“伤痕文学”已经不合适了。《人世间》写的不是伤痕，而是人间烟火，它没有以批判的眼光去嘲讽什么，就是生活的点滴映射出时代的变迁。能够喜欢这个作品一定是价值观认同的，有激情才去做这件事，没激情犯不着做这件事，那就拍别的了，我对《人世间》小说主题和价值观是认同的。我所做的就是从视觉化这块进行一些归拢。我做总体把握的时候，确定了温暖是底色，改编都要围绕这个来。当时拍《人民的名义》的时候，用当时（国家新闻出版广电总局）电视剧司的评价，叫做光明hold住黑暗，正义hold住邪恶，这个比例一定要用得对。我们这个剧的比例，用的是温暖作为底色。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/ssiVQVSPSZbhaj8VuyMPrrmwlwkRwr3BAfiE7VFp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;598&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/03/03/ssiVQVSPSZbhaj8VuyMPrrmwlwkRwr3BAfiE7VFp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;185586&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;李路认为，《人世间》写的不是伤痕，而是人间烟火，是生活的点滴映射出时代的变迁。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（剧组供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;“任何时代都有蓝天，每天太阳都要升起”&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;从小说到电视剧，你们做了怎样的改动？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李路：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们改词、改景，像这样的例子比比皆是，有的时候改行动线。编剧在二度创作上对原小说进行了凝练，因为你不可能像小说那样太娓娓道来，毕竟集数在这儿、人物在这儿。拍起来又是另外一个概念上的事，现场演员有一些即兴的东西、导演有一些即兴的东西，甚至有一些案头需要去调整。我们这次演员的配置是比较高规格的，他们基本上一个底色是都会演戏。这种情况下，导演的责任是鉴定、辨认，这样是可以的，那样是不可以的，并不需要过多让他们完全按我的意思来演。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如丁勇岱老师，他演的是周秉昆的父亲。他进入剧组的时候，刚拍完《跨过鸭绿江》，演彭德怀。来了以后，他两个手天天插着，像个大将军，我就着急了，“老丁、丁哥，你把手拿下去，你现在是老工人，你把腰驼点儿，憨点儿来，咱这儿没有千军万马！”他真的是好演员，过了几天就回来了，把身段放低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些需要演员的功力，同时也需要剧组营造创作氛围。很多人来探班都惊呆了，我们有房车休息室，大家基本上换光、换镜头的时候没人往外跑，都坐在那儿聊天，看对方表演，都很安静。摆POSE的、跑来跑去的没有，都是很安静地准备下一场戏、下一个镜头。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《人世间》里的主角是“光字片”的周家人，以及与他们相关联的各色人物，加起来有一百多号人，你们是怎么安排这些人物的呢？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李路：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我找了编剧王海鸰，请了她来之后，没多久，新冠疫情暴发，我从外地回到北京，看了十几集剧本，从晚上一直看到天大亮，热泪盈眶，非常激动，给王海鸰发了一个长微信，表示这个方向是对的，成了。海鸰老师对题目的提炼描摹和小说是相近的，但也有区别。比如像骆士宾这个角色，就是我的命题，我说要有这么一个人，他是商人，是改革开放后起来的一代商人，原小说里没有，骆士宾提供了比色板。像周秉昆，他就是小人物，他没有世俗意义上的成功，但是你看现在网上的发酵都是“笨儿子得济父母”“家里的老疙瘩反倒是父母的暖宝宝”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们没想到社会的讨论会延伸到这么多地方，但是像光字片里体现出的仁义礼智信、孝道、人与人的温暖，这是我们更看重的，或者说这些年所缺失、人内心的某个角落尚存的。你看韩剧里经常出现的画面，是一家人吃饭香喷喷的，咱们确实这么多年都是家里人口越来越稀少，年味越来越少，人情味越来越淡薄，邻里不相来往，独生子女没有家庭群落。但是，虽然稀薄，你不能说每个人的心里没这块，都是有，只是没被唤醒。这部戏有一个唤醒功能，就是把中国人这几千年来人情、家、国，小的和大的温暖的勾连在这里好好编织出来。按这个方向走，我们把一些边边角角的东西去掉了，把温暖作为该剧的主旋律之一，让大家更多感受到这五十年中国大的变迁，由官员、工人、各个阶层的努力和付出，加上隐忍捏合在一起的产物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;殷桃饰演的郑娟（周秉昆妻子）的出场让人印象深刻。明明是一个破破烂烂的茅草屋，一个没有棉裤穿的落魄女子，她坐在炕上串糖葫芦糊口的场景却让人眼前一亮。类似这样的场景，你们在拍摄时的考虑是怎样的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李路：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;拍殷桃出场这一段我们花了很长时间，如果按电视剧的节奏是非常贵的了，我们花大量时间布光、布景，如果按有些剧那样，三天一集、四天一集这种速度，是不可能拍这场戏的。从我们的理念上来讲，任何时代都有蓝天，每天太阳都要升起，再灰暗的角落也有美丽的人，只不过你从什么视角去看。郑娟的家虽然家徒四壁，就剩点破柜子、烂棉花被子，但是她的美是挡不住的，要不然周秉昆也不会一见到郑娟就马上怦然心动。所以说任何年代都有它挡不住的美，尤其咱们这个戏，开拍一个月之后就被迪士尼买走了版权，要在全球播放，所以我们时时刻刻都有这种意识，不光是自己过家家，这个戏会漂洋出海的。你破可以，不能脏，你的窗花，可能很穷、很清贫，但还是要干干净净的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;剧中主角，周家父子，尤其是秉昆和他父亲的关系，你觉得是典型的中国式父子关系吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李路：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，周秉昆和他的父亲，是我们呼唤的或者曾经拥有的这种父子关系。周父在“大三线”做瓦工，他是八级瓦工，当年收入不低的，相当于高干的收入。台词也讲到了，他自打结婚，就和李素华，也就是他老伴儿没见过多少次面，三年探亲假，有的时候回不来就攒着，甚至有一年春节是时隔八年才回来，你想想，人一辈子有几个八年？周秉昆当仁不让顶着这个剧最大的男主角光环，全剧讲人物命运最多的就是秉昆这个人物。小说以一个低俯视角，一个世俗意义上没有成功的人，一辈子命运的起伏作为叙事点，我觉得这也是梁晓声这部小说能获茅盾文学奖最主要的原因——小人物、大英雄。任何时代都是以这些人为分母而构成的，不可能人人都成功、成为大人物，生活就是由无数的周秉昆累积而成的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《人民的名义》是你的另一部代表作，当时不被大家看好，没想到后来一部主旋律片变成了爆款，这次《人世间》也是这样，你的秘诀是什么呢？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李路：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;如果爆款能有公式的话，那人人都可以做爆款了。《人民的名义》也好，《人世间》也好，是两种完全不同的类型和剧情。《人民的名义》有强情节，有当时反腐热背景下的这种时间性。但《人世间》是没有这两项的，既没有强情节，也没有反腐的强力的时效性，而是娓娓道来的，（它们）完全是两种手法、两种样式的爆款。爆款是结果，平时如果没有这方面的激情和思考，是不可能来做这种东西的，肯定是有感而发，有热血，还要有担当。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[玉树光影澜湄源丨指尖华夏③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257583]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Yushu Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture, Qinghai Province, the birthplace of the Lancang-Mekong River has a pleasant scenery, with landscapes in the morning light and sea of ​​clouds The light and shadow change against the background, and the scenery is picturesque. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/RlzDQx7NvpojuNouZ0ztdJPnZ8IS22u26kQeez8S.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;499&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/RlzDQx7NvpojuNouZ0ztdJPnZ8IS22u26kQeez8S.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252012&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Angsai Grand Canyon in Yushu Zaduo County, Qinghai Province, a sea of ​​clouds appears over the Lancang River. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/bPFbRCdO8Z7Iv79YcyJTn5KOBjxlkuWOiBsYMhGm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;511&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/bPFbRCdO8Z7Iv79YcyJTn5KOBjxlkuWOiBsYMhGm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Taken at Angsai Grand Canyon, Zaduo County, Yushu, Qinghai golden peaks surrounded by the Lancang River. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/4RL755WwRcEwxGEGyeVmzzr0I6hvkQFAWBYcQgdA.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/4RL755WwRcEwxGEGyeVmzzr0I6hvkQFAWBYcQgdA.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chadan Wetland, the source of the Lancang River, photographed in Yushu, Qinghai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Xie Chunjin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/Uvkusq4zef6GEMOITbmEhUhD8kmcvrpkpBwlcFK5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/Uvkusq4zef6GEMOITbmEhUhD8kmcvrpkpBwlcFK5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;White clouds over the vast grassland in Nangqian County, Yushu, Qinghai Stretch out and enjoy the picturesque scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/8berhKyFTX5ykjV3e0lZlBU81K0WfR1BYFGxplJQ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;825&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/8berhKyFTX5ykjV3e0lZlBU81K0WfR1BYFGxplJQ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;White clouds over the vast grassland in Nangqian County, Yushu, Qinghai Stretch out and enjoy the picturesque scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Zhiqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/HaXEiIIIAPsC4CwHlbpdGOKNjVfvJ2R9QVl5D9HM1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/HaXEiIIIAPsC4CwHlbpdGOKNjVfvJ2R9QVl5D9HM1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Angsai Grand Canyon, Zaduo County, Yushu, Qinghai, Lancang River A sea of ​​clouds appears in the sky. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/CICPHOTO/周博/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[红河梯田上，那些逆流的追乡者丨月是故乡明③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257354]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;Hani Village, the spring of the cattle herding class&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Yuanyang Hani Rice Terraces Airport Connection Line Construction has made the road conditions in the already extremely isolated mountain villages of Honghe County even worse. Most of the short 8-kilometer mountain road has turned into mud. It took more than half an hour to reach the destination of Qielongzhong Village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/s223DyoKGhAH9HgEQMPovK7JAk2OrbNVCC45vB0f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/s223DyoKGhAH9HgEQMPovK7JAk2OrbNVCC45vB0f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170797&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Farmers resting among the terraces of Qielong Zhongzhai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;39 The 20-year-old Che Zhixiong picked me up at the door of my house and helped me carry my luggage up to the Datongbu room on the third floor of my old house. This is for investigators from all over the world doing ethnoanthropological research. Different from the village youths, he went to Gejiu, a major town in southern Yunnan, to work for two years before he was 20 years old. He then returned to the village and worked as a team leader and veterinarian. Six years ago, he began to organize nearby left-behind children and teach them to sing and dance traditional Hani. Song and dance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puchun, the administrative village to which Qielong Zhongzhai belongs, is the birthplace of Hani multi-part folk songs, a national intangible cultural heritage, and Che Zhixiong’s father, Che Kesan, is the provincial inheritor. . In 2018, after attending the one-week village imaging training class of &quot;Village Eyes&quot; in the county seat, Che Zhixiong excitedly set up a Canon DV distributed by a charity organization, shot and recorded the life and festivals of Qielongzhong Village, and then recorded his The edited materials are saved to the hard drive for researchers from Kunming to take away when they come over. &quot;In the past three years, two 4T hard drives have been filled up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another house opposite the residence is Che Zhixiong&#39;s new home. . Last summer, with the help of 40,000 yuan in project start-up funds donated by a caring fan of Wang Yibo, Brother Che emptied the first floor and repainted it, turning it into a &quot;local imaging and cultural transmission hall.&quot; On the wall between the load-bearing columns, two LCD TVs are hung. The station at the door was broadcasting a CCTV set of the rice-planting gate opening ceremony filmed and produced in the village. When the rice-planting girl marries the young man from the field in early spring, the villagers who plant the rice-planting are all the bridesmaids and best men. Planting the rice-planting in a good field means marrying into a good family. Che Kesan frequently appears in the camera. As the ditch leader, he has to strictly measure the proportion of each ditch dug to ensure that the water from the forest reservoir flows fairly and accurately into the field ridges of each household. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The TV inside is Che Zhixiong&#39;s own &quot;Personal Film Exhibition&quot;. The sudden heavy hailstorm, the city children who came here for study tours, and the slaughter of cattle to worship the gods during the &quot;June Year&quot;, each section is an anthropological documentary with a complete narrative and clear rhythm. &quot;Most of my peers don&#39;t understand so many Hani rituals, let alone children. I only have a third-grade elementary school education, and all I can do is film and edit all the festivals here,&quot; Village Eyes &#39;People then use it to add subtitles. As for Kuaishou Douyin, it may occasionally attract attention, but it is not complete and even the surface is not captured.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New documentary director Che Zhixiong, Talk about your creative passion. He then pointed to the &quot;One Year&#39;s Festival Ritual&quot; display board on the wall between the two LCD TVs. For example, in the first month of the lunar calendar, the Hani people hold Lazuozuo and Angmatu successively, both of which are sacrificial ceremonies for the dead. &quot;Our ancestors will turn into little gods after they die, and they may come back to harass us. After death, the little gods will turn into great gods, and only then will they bless us. We kill cows for sacrifice to ensure that they can turn into great gods. . When the great god dies, it turns into dew, which drips down at night to irrigate the terraced fields and breed new life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It happened that an old man in the village was about to leave, so the driver took me to where the villagers kept watch. room. All the middle-aged and elderly people who stayed behind gathered here. The woman was in the back room, and the man was on the terrace, drinking pot-stewing wine just scooped out of a sealed earthen vat, chewing green chili peppers dipped in chili oil, and chatting in Hani dialect. The old man who smoked hookah encouraged me to be more generous, &quot;Go inside with your phone and take pictures.&quot; The daughter of the deceased man came back and told me, &quot;She is 80 years old, there is no need to stay in the hospital and suffer, let everyone have fun It&#39;s our tradition to stay with you.&quot; Later, most people would go home and sleep, but there would always be someone staying with them to wait for the final moments. Che Zhixiong carried the old man on his back, and while watching him the documentary he shot on TV, he told me, &quot;The bema (shaman) in the village will calculate the exact day to leave, and the funeral will begin three days before.&quot; . The posthumous affairs are more grand, and one or twenty cows may have to be killed and raised in the underworld for the deceased. This is not an exaggeration. Each of the children will have one, and if the spouse and family members have others, the beef will be taken back to their respective villages to be divided. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KMYD8TnYTGxWjDJ86KztQRUsymuqNaITsvoEvg58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KMYD8TnYTGxWjDJ86KztQRUsymuqNaITsvoEvg58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170799&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Che Longzhong Village keeps vigil at night. Che Zhixiong carries the departing old man on his back and watches the documentary he shot. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puchun Village, where the village primary school is located, is only a 20-minute walk from the village. Less than ten children would go to the village every night to learn Hani dance from Che Zhixiong. The popular song &quot;Honey Baby&quot; with a hip-hop style has become a &quot;county dance&quot; vigorously promoted by Honghe primary and secondary schools, and children never tire of dancing it. The &quot;Music and Dance&quot; that has been passed down from our ancestors in production and life is more popular among energetic children because of its rich routines of squatting, jumping, lining up and circling. Accompanied by the cheerful beats and high-fives, I also followed the Hani cattle herding class and entered a selfless state of joy with nature and heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/XmocXYbwdYdsfRySlzFt7Cj6I1znT2WNT8ANQcNk.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/XmocXYbwdYdsfRySlzFt7Cj6I1znT2WNT8ANQcNk.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Che Zhixiong teaches children music and dance in the village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;The young people of Yisa Town dedicated their entire youth to musical instruments&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Honghe County Government The town of Yisa is located at the top of a hill where two winding asphalt roads meet. At the highest edge of the ancient city, starting from the east gate with three floors and three rooms, a large and majestic ancient castle that combines Chinese and Western styles spreads out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a masonry town brought on horseback by local business gangs 90 years ago, and the primitive tribes who practiced slash-and-burn farming, carved wood and knotted ropes were upgraded into &quot;Little Shanghai outside the Yangtze River&quot;. Jiang refers to the Red River that flows to Vietnam and divides Red River Prefecture into two. Places such as Jianshui and Mengzi, which have many Han immigrants and are economically developed, are in the north and are called inside the river; while counties such as Yuanyang, Honghe and Luchun, which have developed world heritage terraced landscapes, are outside the river, which is backward. Yisa means &quot;drought and water shortage&quot; in the dialect of the Yi people who first came here to open up wasteland. During the Qianlong period, copper mines were discovered in the mountains, and immigrants followed the mining industry. These ancestors also experienced a history of prosperity and decline with the Qing Dynasty. At the end of the Qing Dynasty, the copper mines dried up and the new mountain people had no land to cultivate. They had to drag horses and go deep into the mountains and forests of Southeast Asia to do trade. They gradually developed from traditional caravans to tobacco gangs. In the early years of the Republic of China, the government&#39;s vigorous crackdown on opium led to a sharp increase in black market profits. Cigarette gangs organized and strengthened private militia to safeguard their vested interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/QislqJmk9cSDUoAKbbAG0tgxBY4Qsgb2olkGz6R6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/QislqJmk9cSDUoAKbbAG0tgxBY4Qsgb2olkGz6R6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170802&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; The French designers I knew drew drawings and hired Jiangnan craftsmen to build various stone mansions with European-style exteriors and Chinese-style interiors, row upon row on the hills. Since then, more men have dispersed overseas and reorganized their families, making Honghe County the second largest hometown of overseas Chinese in Yunnan, with more than 10,000 overseas Chinese distributed in 18 countries and regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wave of overseas immigrants on horseback has long been replaced by the wave of designated labor exports. But there are always people who insist on staying behind, such as Awen, the traditional musical instrument maker and inheritor I met at the east gate. &quot;Do you understand Honghe dialect? I can&#39;t speak Mandarin.&quot; Awen confessed in advance on WeChat. The craftsman who doesn’t speak Mandarin must be an old man with a white beard smoking a hookah, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the bluestone road, the roaring Aprilia 150 motorcycle turned off its engine. The &quot;white vest&quot; on the car took off the helmet with the three colors of the Italian flag. The cool guy with a ponytail stepped forward and said, &quot;I That’s Ah Wen.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I went from the village to the county cultural center to work when I was sixteen or seventeen years old. Now I am 35 years old, and I have dedicated all my youth to musical instruments.” In the restaurant next to Daguangtang in the center of the ancient town, Ah Wen Wen continued to introduce himself. &quot;I quit my job last year. I know nothing but making musical instruments. I&#39;m so hurt by music!&quot; Although he was a little sad, when he was flipping through the various beautiful instruments on his phone, Awen became excited again, &quot;I ride a motorcycle. When I visited various villages in Hani, I couldn&#39;t put it down when I saw these treasures. Every sanxian and every straw have different materials, appearance and sound quality. They can&#39;t be made in factories. They will be gone when the older generation leaves. I can only Take photos and videos, listen to the sounds, and restore them all.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dinner, we walked through the lush Xishan Park and walked to the musical instrument workshop next to the County Cultural Center. Master Wu Zhiming was lying on a bamboo chair. When he heard me say that he had just come from Qielong Zhongzhai, memories of his life came back to him, &quot;It can be said that it was them who started my career, and I played a role as a link between past and future.&quot; 1986 In May, when Wu Zhiming, who was employed by the County Culture and Sports Bureau, went to Puchun to collect folk music, he heard the eight-part chorus of rice-planting girls coming from a distance, and followed the sound to find it... Later, he changed from a county actor to a song and dance creator. and music theory researchers, and brought Hani singing and dancing to the world. Ah Wen and Che Zhixiong have traveled as far as Shandong and Beijing respectively, but their master and father have already traveled to Taiwan, Singapore, Japan and the Netherlands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/tVMULXeHWW8OLcd8NgjmsJDwCvNAXOyQAPZFErVa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/tVMULXeHWW8OLcd8NgjmsJDwCvNAXOyQAPZFErVa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170798&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Awen from Yisa Town Musical Instrument Making Workshop&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Like those young and middle-aged people in the city who are separated from their work units and pursue personal values, Awen also worries about how to monetize his hobbies. &quot;Many scholars and teachers can only provide spiritual support, but &#39;Village Eyes&#39; has raised 10,000 to 20,000 yuan for me.&quot; . But there are many others, but even a small business loan of 50,000 yuan cannot be approved.&quot; With the capital, Awen can build his own studio and improve the efficiency of working all night and three days to make two sanxian. One piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You still have to be realistic and start with a wind instrument that saves time and materials. Although it is not as good as the cucurbit flutes in the pedestrian streets of ancient cities, you should try to reduce the production cost first, and then put it into Go to the Samaba Visitor Center to try out the sales.&quot; Xu Tianming, an old colleague who still works at the County Cultural Center, reminded him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Tianming is from the Yi ethnic group. In June 2021, under the guidance of the state song and dance troupe, he and other colleagues rehearsed the first courtyard drama &quot;Caravan Women&quot; in Honghe Prefecture. The Wanxing Courtyard was staged by relying on money. As the name of the play suggests, it tells the stories of chaste women displayed in this mansion. The dancers, from the image of disgraced grooms at the beginning, jumped to become a men&#39;s team in suits returning home joyfully, and the girls who looked through the love finally became the old mothers holding a revolving door, looking forward to the return of their husbands. Although the over-an-hour play is in a very complete musical format, it is not an original performance and is reduced to a series of popular Han-style compositions. Moreover, because the fee is not enough, embarrassing copyright information often comes out of the soundtrack. . Everything is difficult at the beginning. The ticket agent told me that starting with their play, all the counties and cities in Honghe Prefecture will create their own courtyard dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Hollowed Village, a Holiday Paradise for City People&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Xu Tianming suggested that Awen go to Samaba, which sells bamboo flutes. It is located at the end of the gently undulating hillside and is the most famous place in Honghe County. The scenic area has more than 14,000 acres of the world&#39;s largest concentrated contiguous terraces with more than 4,300 levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/zSqER3Vy9QkygwFuAaj3LctdJc5PEjeLIwS8jiab.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/zSqER3Vy9QkygwFuAaj3LctdJc5PEjeLIwS8jiab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170801&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Samaba Terraces&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A on the other side of the landscape terraces Although Yinxiang is the birthplace of the 600-year-old Hani Street Festival, the most beautiful historical and cultural village &quot;Zuofu&quot; failed to retain a few mushroom houses with ethnic characteristics and was replaced by reinforced concrete. house. Of course, there is nothing wrong with pursuing a once-and-for-all residence, but &quot;it is good to leave many old things in the village and tidy them up. For example, at the east gate of the county, the two mansions of Yao and Qian were used as public prosecutors and detention centers respectively before they became museums. It has always been used as a reservation.&quot; Liu Zhigang, who manages Kangteng·Honghehe Valley Tent Camp deep in Jiayin Township, as an outside operator, has a relatively objective and neutral voice on rural protection and development issues, &quot;and it is not far from Jiayin Township. There is a Tusi Mansion, and it is very grandiose. It could not have been so grand before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Conten Company, which creates high-end vacation products, chose the project outside the scenic area because it had to find convenience for renovation. of hollowed out villages. &quot;Shitou Village has been empty for more than ten years. There are only one or two families who have owned houses in the new village. They use the old houses to store farm tools. It is not difficult for us to use them as campsites.&quot; Liu Zhigang is now busy developing another hollow village. , Suhong Village in the core area of ​​Samaba Rice Terraces. To this end, a tourism investment company has been established with the county government, and famous architect Zhang Yonghe has been hired as the chief planner to create timeshare real estate based on the &quot;low-involvement&quot; concept to allow urbanites to live in rural areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the heavy rain, the county road from the camp to Suhong Village was completely cut off by mudslides, and we had to climb down the narrow village road with hundreds of turns. The landscape along the road gradually changes from the rain-watered mulberry trees and red chrysanthemums at high altitudes to the steaming dense banana forest with broad leaves covering the sky. In the past, the smoke-traveling gang probably often did this, shuttling back and forth between alpine mountains and tropical dense forests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KYbublnB4r6wgP8I0WqZ0Dbqr5qVHJX5SbkP4LJZ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/KYbublnB4r6wgP8I0WqZ0Dbqr5qVHJX5SbkP4LJZ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170804&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A corner of Suhong Village&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Hani people’s hoes are But the enemy&#39;s iron gun. Seven thousand women have become widows, seven thousand children can&#39;t see their parents, the high swings have been knocked down, and the three-story mushroom houses have been burned down.&quot; An ancient Hani song once lamented the ancestors The fate of being defeated all the way and moving southward. After finally settling in the &quot;two mountains and three rivers&quot; area consisting of Ailao Mountain, Wuliang Mountain, Lancang River, Yuanjiang River and Honghe River, with the help of my good friend Old Buffalo, we dug out magnificent terraces with hoe after hoe. Nowadays, except for a few local people who work in the camp due to the demand for original ecological services, for more Honghe youths like Awen who stay in their hometown, city people come to experience the terraced life of transplanting rice seedlings, harvesting in autumn, and setting up tents. It&#39;s so familiar that it won&#39;t be rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;People chasing hometown&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The NAS system of the computer in the Kunming office of &quot;Village Eyes&quot; stores a large number of documentaries shot by Che Zhixiong. This is a public welfare organization that helps farmers and herdsmen in western rural areas record the ecological and cultural changes in their hometown through their own ethnic perspective and using cameras as tools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person who introduced Che Zhixiong to me was Li Xudong, a young man from his hometown who had just graduated more than a year ago. &quot;I studied hotel management at a private university. After graduation, I worked as a housekeeper in a high-end B&amp;B in Dali for two months. In August last year, I saw someone posting the official account &#39;Village Eyes&#39; in one of my most active groups. I was attracted to this charity organization after reading an article about Hani’s cattle herding class.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the male classmates in the village who went out to work and the female classmates who married early, Adong, who was born in 1996, They are very few young people who have a conscious sense of national identity early on. “Since my sophomore year, from January to April every year, I have taken leave, hitchhiked home from Kunming, participated in organizing the grand Silhouette Festival, written event planning, served as host, worked as a financial accountant, and dressed in national costumes , followed the horn team, taking the children who no longer have contact with the seedlings, to play in the terraced fields. This festival is a rest and entertainment time for the Hani people after planting the spring seedlings, and they also look forward to the rich autumn harvest in a few months.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;A Dong also cooperates with four friends to operate a public account - People Chasing Hometown. Share the Hani branch, costumes, rituals, music, poetry and other content mainly in Honghe County at any time, publish essays by fellow villagers, and launch an essay collection activity for primary and secondary school students in your hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/w8EG1KxDR8z0IMux79rUBnZqvaRkFFjGcFFCQ16a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/12/w8EG1KxDR8z0IMux79rUBnZqvaRkFFjGcFFCQ16a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;170803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meet Hani villagers on the road&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Hailu/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Honghe Hani Rice Terraces were successfully applied for World Heritage status It has been 8 years, and it has given local people cultural confidence. &quot;The current situation should be said to be &#39;what goes in and what goes out&#39;. The return flow has increased. Young people go out to work, but when they are over 40 years old, more people come back. At the same time, the part-time status of half-farmers, half-workers also makes the villagers&#39; The enthusiasm for farming is back.&quot; Zhang Hongzhen, director of the Hani Terraces Protection and Development Research Center at Honghe University, recounted his observations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我所理解的五千年中华文明之精华]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257944]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;China is a giant country in terms of population, land area, and history and culture. The late well-known archaeologist Su Bingqi, who proposed the &quot;starry sky&quot; theory about the origin of Chinese civilization, once said that what we want to build is a modernization with Chinese characteristics commensurate with the ancient country of five thousand years of civilization. This naturally puts forward the idea of ​​five thousand years of civilization. What is the essence, what is the national soul, and what is the spiritual pillar? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concept of &quot;Chinese nation&quot; was proposed by Liang Qichao a hundred years ago, but even starting from the Liangzhu Culture characterized by jade culture, the civilization creation of our ancestors on the land of China has exceeded 5000 years. The Liangzhu ancestors’ divine and animal facial patterns, head-up and head-down dragons, and tomb forms with obvious ritual connotations, all clearly show that they are an important source of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese civilization naturally has more than one origin. In addition to the Liangzhu Culture in the Taihu Lake area, there are also the Hongshan Culture in western Liaoning, the Yangshao Culture in the Central Plains, the Pengtoushan-Chengbeixi Culture in the Yangtze River Basin, the Longshan Culture that is a fusion of various cultures in China, and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The basic spirit of Chinese civilization has gradually formed in the historical development, including the invention of square characters, the &quot;work&quot; of the &quot;system&quot; of the previous kings in the actual social development form, and the &quot;narration&quot; of the previous teachers, as well as The &quot;interpretation&quot; of scholars and intellectuals of all dynasties. Whether it is the &quot;new underground materials&quot; that are advancing rapidly in the modern era or the rich ancient documents dating back to Oracle Bone Inscriptions and Bronze Inscriptions, they can all help us today understand more deeply what the &quot;Chinese national spirit&quot; is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And this understanding cannot only be directed towards the past. Although Zhou is an old state, its destiny is renewed. It is facing the future and participating in the present. Here, I try to summarize what I understand about Chinese civilization from five aspects: society, politics, faith, economy, and culture and education. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Society: Family Orientation and Individuality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From a social perspective, we attach great importance to the value of a small community such as &quot;family&quot;, which leads to the spirit of benevolence and individual personality. growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Benevolent people are the most important to people who are close to each other. To be close means to be filial to one&#39;s parents, to be kind to one&#39;s children, and to be friendly to one&#39;s brothers and sisters based on human blood and nature. And &quot;Old people are like the old people, young people are like the young people&quot;, and this kind of love is extended to everyone. Different from Mohism’s proposition of universal love, as the mainstream of Han culture, Confucianism admits that “there are differences in love”, but it still has a feeling of universal love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern people tend to value individualism first. Does this kind of &quot;familism&quot; conflict with respect for individual personality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a motivational point of view, parents raising their children comes from their own nature and is the best natural mechanism to help individuals grow. Family love provides relatively pure love and good emotions between parents and children. In terms of children&#39;s growth, the family structure can provide more support. From the perspective of ethnic continuity, this culture is obviously beneficial to increasing fertility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dear love does not advocate unconditional submission. If parents are at fault, the &quot;Book of Filial Piety&quot; advocates that &quot;there are faults in the family&quot;, but it only advises parents to pay attention to their attitude and methods. Mencius encouraged everyone to &quot;nurture my awe-inspiring spirit&quot; and &quot;even if there are thousands of people, I will go there&quot;. It is a kind of personalism with abundant independent consciousness and free spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although in reality there are overbearing and irresponsible parents and rebellious children, this is precisely because they have betrayed the love of their relatives and cannot be blamed on this kind of balancing of family structure and individual personality. The social structure and value form of development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Family, a small community, constitutes a social unit, and the independent individuals with community and public care bred in it have become the foundation of the country. The laws promulgated by the governor should encourage this kind of love, but not destroy it. If conditions are created to make it easier for parents to raise their children and for children to get closer to their parents, it is care that nourishes this spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Political ideal: The world is for the common good&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the mainstream of our culture, individuals not only live within the family structure, but also naturally extend to the country and the world. To cultivate oneself, manage one&#39;s family, govern the country, and bring peace to the world, in &quot;The Great Learning&quot;, individuals need to constantly study things to gain knowledge, be sincere and righteous, and expand their areas of concern and efforts to the vast areas of the country and the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When someone asked Confucius why he did not engage in politics, Confucius quoted &quot;Shangshu&quot; and replied: &quot;Filial piety is only filial piety, and friendship is with brothers.&quot; Politics? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a social structure and cultural spirit, &quot;keeping the family together&quot; is already a part of public affairs. Expanding this spirit to a wider social space is also &quot;for government&quot; rather than for government. You must &quot;serve as an official in the government&quot; to enter politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern families are families of three or four, but in Chinese history, unless official laws deliberately required &quot;family separation&quot; to weaken the organizational strength of small communities, our culture often praised &quot;multi-generational families&quot;. &quot;Together under the same roof&quot; encourages large families to live together and help each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of large family living together combines the principles of &quot;kinship&quot;, &quot;respect for respect&quot; and &quot;virtue&quot; to form the social autonomy of a small community. From this, the tradition of gentry autonomy was derived. This made it possible to create a &quot;small government, big society&quot; where the imperial power did not extend to the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhou system of feudalism and founding of the country directly used family as a link to establish the basic political order of the entire Chinese world: on the one hand, the eldest son inheritance system was implemented to ensure the institutionalization and stability of the inheritance of power; On the one hand, talented people are selected to govern. Of course, the Zhou system still embodies moral governance in the family and the world, and the degree of openness of power is still limited. In the political field, the value that best embodies the spirit of the Chinese nation is the spirit of &quot;the world is for the common good.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original text of &quot;Book of Rites&quot; is: In the journey of the great road, the world is for the common good, selecting talents and talents, adhering to trust and cultivating harmony, old friends do not only kiss their relatives, do not only give birth to their children, so that the old will die well. The strong have their uses, the young have their talents, and those who are modest, widowed, lonely, and lonely are all supported... Another example is &quot;The king and his ministers are united by righteousness.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s not all about the same surname&quot;... These political thoughts, which exude eternal brilliance, have broken through the &quot;kinship&quot; principle of the family and become a concrete manifestation of the commonwealth of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, since selfish desires are difficult to eliminate, it is extremely difficult to achieve the goal of serving the world for the common good. Needless to say, the Qin system, from the Han and Tang dynasties to the Song, Ming and Qing dynasties, the separation of imperial power and prime ministerial power, the system of admonishing officials and historians, the feudal system throughout the Han, Tang, and Song dynasties, the education of princes, and the system of co-governance of scholar-bureaucrats, etc., are only partial and It plays a certain role in the short term. Royal power is never truly under the law. The Chinese nation’s political spirit of “the world is for the common good” is so premature and yet so immature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the famous &quot;Debate between Righteousness, Benefit and Overlord&quot; with Chen Liang, Zhu Xi lamented decisively: For fifteen hundred years, he was just sitting on this, so it was just a matter of time to make up for it. Although there may have been some moderate prosperity during this period, the Tao taught by the three kings Yao and Shun, Zhou Gong and Confucius, has not yet been practiced in heaven and earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the political standard of the world for the common good continues to exist. Whether to put the interests and happiness of the people first in governance, and whether to keep the economic, social and spiritual life vigorous and prosperous? These political requirements for governors are also an important dimension of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Economy: People have permanent property&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the economy, how does &quot;the world is for the common good&quot; be reflected? For the government, it is &quot;the king, why should he call it profit&quot;. From the emperor, princes to officials, managers at all levels should not compete with the people for profit; for the common people, it is &quot;those who have permanent property have perseverance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to do this specifically? What the government wants to do is to &quot;benefit the people according to their interests&quot; and naturally carry out production, trade and consumption activities based on the needs of the people in the world. Therefore, in the choice between cannon and butter, butter obviously takes precedence. This only requires the establishment of a service-oriented government that provides &quot;benefits at no cost&quot; and cannot compete with the people for profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Benevolent government must start from the borders.” The basis for the interests of the people is to ensure that citizens have their own three-acre land, and they can use their own land according to their personal and family interests. Judgment, to produce and trade. Although Mencius&#39;s proposition mainly focused on delimiting the boundaries of mine fields, its essence pointed to the determination of property rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only that, Mencius also advocated encouraging commerce and protecting travelers by providing warehouses for merchants and requisitioning them in accordance with the law to avoid stagnant goods, only registering and inspecting but not collecting taxes, only doing labor service but not collecting land rent, etc. Let it be beneficial to farmers, so that all merchants in the world will be happy and willing to hide in their markets, all travelers in the world will be happy and willing to go out on their own roads, and all farmers in the world will be happy and willing to plow their fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the current economic reform is concerned, the confirmation and long-term stability of agricultural land rights, as well as deepening the reform of state-owned enterprises, protecting the investment and property rights of the private economy in various fields, tax laws, etc., all fall into this category. economic issues. This also determines whether entrepreneurs have long-term confidence in the Chinese economy and whether they dare to make large investments. In short, the essence of the economic spirit of an ideal Chinese community is to achieve economic prosperity, prosperity and prosperity for the people, and ensure the material life of the people through the property rights, production and trade system of &quot;big public ownership and private ownership&quot; and the fiscal and taxation system that is light on corvee and light on taxes. of plenty. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Belief: The unity of nature and man&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For families, why should fathers be kind and sons should be filial? For rulers, why should the world be for the common good? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do ordinary people have perseverance only if they have perseverance? For a person like Yan Hui, why can he achieve &quot;a basket of food and a ladle of drink, and he cannot bear the worries, but his joy will not change even after he returns&quot;? How can he have perseverance without permanent income? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This involves the fourth dimension of Chinese civilization, faith. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Businessmen believed in the personified &quot;Emperor&quot; and were biased toward the dominating heaven; Zhou people believed in &quot;the destiny of heaven is constant, only virtue is the supplementary one&quot;, and in the dominating heaven there was a profound meaning of the heaven of righteousness; although Confucius &quot;revered &quot;Keep the ghosts and gods at a distance&quot;, but still &quot;offer sacrifices to the gods as if they were present&quot;, reminding the disciples to realize the sincere spirit of life from the great popularity of &quot;Heaven can say nothing&quot;, and firmly believe that they carry &quot;Heaven will not lose the grace&quot;, which deepened the Zhou people&#39;s The concept of destiny; in the Han Dynasty, Dong Zhongshu believed that humans are copies of heaven, that heaven and humans can sense each other, and can warn the king of his misconduct and mismanagement with &quot;disasters&quot;; by the Song and Ming dynasties, heaven mainly became the heaven of justice, tending to one an inner transcendence and infinity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For heaven, most of the most outstanding kings and sages of the Chinese nation had a strong and heartfelt awe, and regarded the unity of heaven and man as their ultimate pursuit, thus giving integrity to daily life and political life. sense of meaning, certainty and direction. Mencius has a very vivid description of this realm of belief that is both ordinary and holy: what is desirable is called good, what is called self-belief is called faith, what is full is called beauty, what is full and glorious is called great, what is great is called transformation. Holy, what is holy but unknowable is called God. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Father&#39;s kindness and son&#39;s filial piety originate from the &quot;nature of destiny&quot; and from &quot;the child is free from the arms of his parents for three years&quot;. If this kind of human nature is brought into full play like Shun in &quot;Yao Canon&quot;, we can A saint who acquires a set of abilities including avoiding disasters, harmonizing the family, and governing the country is a saint who unites nature and man;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Emperor&quot; regards himself as the eldest son of Heaven to gain legitimacy and even sanctity, and must serve Heaven To carry on, we must nourish all people, and the world is for the common good;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ordinary people don’t understand this enough, and they don’t have the time to cultivate themselves. They need a constant income to have perseverance. This is normal, but it has a family “kissing” mechanism. With nourishment, there is still benevolence and righteousness in the heart. As long as you don&#39;t cut it off, you can also see the virtuous and considerate people; The obsession with external objects returns to the state of life where meaning flows. March is not contrary to benevolence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is extremely difficult to truly practice faith. For ordinary people, if they have permanent property and perseverance, maintain a comfortable life and common sense rooted in the meaning of family, they can become qualified members of the Chinese community; for people in high positions, if they cannot &quot;devour their heart and soul to understand heaven, &quot;If you cultivate your mind and cultivate your nature to serve Heaven&quot;, you will begin to pollute a large area from the source of law, politics, culture and education, and spread evil to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While Mencius affirmed that all people have the four ideals, he also clearly realized that &quot;human beings are somewhat different from beasts.&quot; He quoted from &quot;Shang Shu·Tai Oath&quot; that &quot;Heaven sees me and the people see me, and God listens to me and the people listen&quot;, and gave a principled explanation of the relationship between heaven and the people. God’s will is unpredictable and manifests itself through public opinion. A holy king who unites nature and man is rare to find in five hundred or even a thousand years, but secular kings who are holy because of their kings are everywhere. The reverence for heaven and the people is not empty talk, so it is necessary to establish a technical system to restrict the royal power, so that public opinion can be fully reflected, and governance can fully reflect public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public opinion may be divided and antagonistic, what should we do? Will it bring about the disadvantages of &quot;welfarism&quot;? Will the &quot;public opinion&quot; of this generation harm the &quot;public opinion&quot; of future generations? These challenges have entered the field of building a modern republic and legal system. In addition to drawing on the more mature modern governance system, we also need to give full play to the spirit of &quot;Spring of the First Year, King Zhengyue&quot; in &quot;Spring and Autumn&quot;. In the era of great changes, we should constantly return to the origin of politics and beliefs, consider profits and losses, and &quot;make&quot; new systems. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Literature and education: Respecting teachers, respecting morality, and vigorous spirit&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From Liangzhu, Hongshan, Yangshao to Longshan, from Xia, Shang and Zhou to Qin, Han, Tang, Song, Ming and Qing, the Chinese community gradually formed and split frequently And it can be continuously unified, and the culture whose roots were formed over five thousand years will never be destroyed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have a unified square character that has basically not changed since ancient times. Even though &quot;the winds are different in hundreds of miles, and the customs are different in thousands of miles&quot;, a county may have several dialects, but we can still recognize and identify with each other. There is also the ideological system from Zhou Confucius, Mencius, Xun, Lao and Zhuang. They have governed themselves and made history, and they have also learned from history and classics, providing rich resources for spiritual inspiration and institutional reconstruction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no insurmountable rivers or mountains in the land of China. Whether it is divided into feudal states or prefectures and counties, the gradually formed Zhou Wen and Han systems, Tang style and Song style are diverse but capable of unification, and have strong agglomeration effect. For thousands of years, no matter what force entered China, it would be transformed by Chinese culture to a large extent. They inherited Chinese culture and therefore gained basic recognition from the scholars in this tradition. This is the attraction and centripetal force of the Chinese national spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this cultural spirit faces not only the debate between China and the West, but also the changes in ancient and modern times. How to inherit and update our cultural spirit has been a major issue that several generations of intellectuals in modern times have struggled with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the Han Dynasty to the Tang and Song Dynasties, we spent thousands of years absorbing Buddhist culture, which not only gave birth to Chinese Zen Buddhism, but also gave birth to Taoism in the Song and Ming Dynasties. Since the late Qing Dynasty and the early Republic of China, in the face of the strong Western learning and Western politics, scholars from both sides of the Taiwan Strait and three places have translated a large number of translations, digested them quickly, practiced them politically, and compared and absorbed them academically, which has initially opened up a new situation for Chinese culture. The process is far from over. To return to the roots and create new things requires a free and powerful cultural and educational system that represents the fifth dimension of the Chinese national spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A teacher is someone who teaches, teaches and resolves doubts. China has a tradition of scholarship. The Jixia Academy, which flourished 2,400 years ago, was once an international academic center in China, even though it was officially run by the Qi State. Scholars from Taoism, Confucianism, Legalism, Ming Dynasty, Ming Dynasty, Agriculture, Yin and Yang, Mencius, Xunzi, Shen Buhai, Lu Zhonglian, Shen Dao and other scholars whose names were important for a time and even influenced thousands of years are here to &quot;discuss without ruling&quot;, &quot; &quot;Discussing state affairs without holding office&quot;, the ideological power derived from this has surged forward with the source of living water, and its influence continues to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Confucius broke away from &quot;learning in the government&quot; and gave private lectures, to the &quot;Jingshe&quot; in the Han Dynasty, from the &quot;academy&quot; where individuals studied and lectured in the Tang Dynasty, to the Yuelu Academy in the Southern Song Dynasty, where Zhang Shi lectured , the Bailudong Academy restored by Zhu Xi... The folk academy system is well-established, with independent subject-based teaching systems, autonomous methods for students to participate in management, and relatively independent funding sources, finally forming a mature private school system. By the Ming Dynasty, academies such as Longgang, Guiyang, and Kuaiji, which were founded or presided over by Wang Yangming and promoted the purpose of Xinxue, changed to Donglin Academy, which criticized the shortcomings of Xinxue and advocated practical learning. This has never ceased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These academies have the character of pursuing the Tao rather than seeking official positions, the style of study of free debate, the aura of making friends to help others, and the worldly sentiments of &quot;the sound of wind and rain, the sound of reading, family affairs, state affairs, and world affairs.&quot; In &quot;Records of Visits to the Ming Yi&quot;, Huang Zongxi even put forward the view that &quot;what the emperor is right may not necessarily be right, and what the emperor is wrong may not be wrong, so the emperor will not dare to be wrong for himself and publicize his right and wrong to the school.&quot; Right and wrong and truth were elevated to a higher status than the emperor, restoring the traditional essence of discussing politics based on Tao, and inspiring people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern intellectuals need to inherit the spirit of scholars, not only to interpret and continue the great ancient Chinese civilization, but also to &quot;work&quot; according to the times and explore new philosophical, institutional and scientific principles. In short, the foundation of this cultural and educational system is the guarantee of the institutionalization and legalization of &quot;teachers&quot; and &quot;scholars&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conclusion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The final conclusion: This article believes that heaven (the belief system in which heaven and man are unified), earth (the economic system in which people have permanent property), and the country (the political system in which the world is for the common good) System), relatives (kinship is the most important, a personality development system nurtured in the family structure), and teachers (a cultural and educational system full of dynamic research, preaching and civilized dialogue), the above five constitute the main content of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国跳水队包揽亚运会跳水项目首个比赛日的两枚金牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258022]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 19:38:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese group Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yu Xi in the competition. They won the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving gold medal at the Hangzhou Asian Games with 375.30 points.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/67c81a7599. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;758&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/67c81a7599.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;252916&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yuxi competed. They won the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving gold medal at the Hangzhou Asian Games with 375.30 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 30, 2023, the diving competition of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou officially began. The first competition day was the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform final and the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard final. In the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving competition, Chinese combination Quan Hongchan/Chen Yuxi won the gold medal with a huge advantage. The Chinese team achieved six consecutive titles in the women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform diving at the Asian Games. In the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard final, although the Chinese team Yan Siyu/He Chao made varying degrees of errors in the fourth and sixth jumps, it did not affect their overall success in winning the gold medal with a 29.55-point lead over the runner-up South Korea. The Chinese diving team won two gold medals on the first competition day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (right)/Chen Yuxi competed.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/01/78b2ea88b8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/01/78b2ea88b8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252917&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the Chinese group will be all red Chan (right)/Chen Yuxi during the competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao competed. They won the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard championship with 422.55 points.&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/d740081fa7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/d740081fa7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252918&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 30, the Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao was in the competition. They won the men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard championship with 422.55 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform is the first completed event in the Hangzhou Asian Games diving competition. As Olympic champions, this is the first time for the gold medal team of Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan to participate in the Asian Games. The women&#39;s synchronized 10-meter platform competition does not have preliminaries and will go directly to the finals. In this project, Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan are the only ones in the world in terms of strength, while the strong players in the second tier are mainly from Europe and the United States. During the competition, Chen Yuxi and Quan Hongchan led the way from the first jump, with a total score of 375.30 points in 5 jumps, leading the runner-up Japanese team by 85.26 points, and won the first gold medal in diving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Chinese combination Yan Siyu (Part 2)/He Chao was in the competition.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/01/e34a8dcbde.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1558&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/ 01/e34a8dcbde.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252919&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, Chinese group Yan Siyu (Part 2)/ He Chao is in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The men&#39;s synchronized 3-meter springboard also has no preliminary schedule and goes directly to the finals. The Chinese combination Yan Siyu/He Chao ranked fifth in the order of appearance. During the competition, He Chao and Yan Siyu demonstrated their extremely high technical level and tacit cooperation ability. Taking off, turning, and entering the water, the entire set of movements of the two people is very smooth. Although he successfully won the men&#39;s synchronized three-meter springboard championship, He Chao was not very satisfied with himself because of his mistake in the last jump. &quot;The result was good, but all the movements were not perfect in the process. This is the first time for Yan Siyu to participate in an international competition. I am also participating in an international competition again after six years, which is a test for both of us. But winning this gold medal is our best gift for National Day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023 On September 30, 2019, Quan Hongchan (left) and Chen Yuxi showed their gold medals to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/58e7bffb79 .jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/58e7bffb79.jpg&quot; data-key =&quot;252920&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Quan Hongchan (left) and Chen Yuxi showed the gold medal in their hands to the audience . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, Yan Siyu (right) and He Chao showed their gold medals to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/01/ab9db6dd5c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /01/ab9db6dd5c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252921&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Yan Siyu (right) and He Chao shows the audience the gold medal in his hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is reported that the Hangzhou Asian Games diving event will be held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Natatorium from September 30 to October 4, 2023. A total of 10 gold medals will be produced. gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (third from right)/Chen Yuxi (third from left), and the runner-up Japanese combination Itabashi Minami (second from left)/Arai Jili (first from the left) and the third runner-up Malaysian combination Pandelela Linong Anak Pamg (first from the right)/Nur Dabita Binti Sabri at the award ceremony.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/5ccaddf8a8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;785&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/5ccaddf8a8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Quan Hongchan (third from right)/Chen Yuxi (third from left), the runner-up Japanese combination Itabashi Minami (second from left)/Arai Matsuri (first left), the third runner-up Malaysian combination Pandelela Rinon Anak Pamg (first from right)/Nur Dabita Binti Sabri at the award ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 30, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Yan Siyu (third from left)/He Chao (third from right), the runner-up Korean combination Lee Jae-kyung (first from left)/Yu Helan ( Second from left) and the third runner-up Malaysian combination Mohammad Siafik bin Put (second from right)/Huang Ziliang at the award ceremony.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/01/53741cc3d0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;793&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/ 53741cc3d0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252923&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, champion Chinese group Yan Siyu (third from left)/ He Chao (third from right), runner-up Korean combination Lee Jae Kyung (first from left)/Yu Helan (second from left) and third runner-up Malaysian combination Mohammad Siafik Bin Put (second from right)/Huang Ziliang at the award ceremony superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[易水悲风：追寻燕国往事丨古国多少事③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257352]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The wind is coming again. The imaginary group of people gradually disappeared on the other side of the misty water, but the imaginary wine and food still exuded steam, as if chasing the sound of construction and singing that had just disappeared... More than two thousand years passed by in a blink of an eye, and this road from North China The rivers flowing across the plains brought me closer to those people and things that were far away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The river is named Yishui, and it is famous in history because of that famous farewell. ——That year, they sang softly by the river:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The wind rustles and the water becomes cold,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strong man will never return once he is gone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/qHq4WGuD8LlEMzMFhaZ0nMRZjeTLpZxv9oW0uzru.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/qHq4WGuD8LlEMzMFhaZ0nMRZjeTLpZxv9oW0uzru.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yishuihan, Yixian County&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Yandu&lt;/span>; h4>; &lt;p>;The North China Great Plain extends to Yixian County, Hebei Province, and has reached its western edge. In the county town, looking to the west from a high altitude, a line of dark mountains stretches across the end of the plain, which is the Taihang Mountains that separate the North China Plain and the Shanxi Plateau. The Yishui that gives Yixian County its name originates from the eastern foothills of Taihang Mountain. In fact, the Yishui is not one river, but divided into three: North Yishui, Zhongyishui and Nanyishui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are various signs that that famous farewell should be on the shore of Zhongyi River. The man named Jing Ke, when he finished singing generously amidst the sound of Gao Jianli&#39;s construction, and everyone&#39;s eyes were splitting with anger, he had already jumped on the carriage and headed to Xianyang, the capital of Qin, two thousand miles away. In order to repay Prince Dan for his kindness, he is going to perform an almost impossible task. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the traffic conditions at that time, there were two roads for him to choose. One was to go south, along the Great Plains to today&#39;s Kaifeng, Henan, and then turn west; the other was to follow the Yishui River, Passing through Puyinxing and Feihuxing among the eight hidden tunnels in the Taihang Mountains, they entered today&#39;s Shanxi, then traveled southwest, crossed the Yellow River from Pujin, and entered Guanzhong. For no reason, I think Jing Ke would probably choose the latter. Although the latter journey is more difficult, the mileage is shorter. What is particularly important is that perhaps, only when he slowly climbed from the flat plain to the majestic mountain - at that time, the wind was also blowing, blowing Jing Ke&#39;s white robe - he stood at the mountain pass, and then turned back to take one last look at the sad scene under the sunset. The windy home is more in line with Jing Ke’s character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Jing Ke appeared on the scene, the life of Yan State had entered a countdown. And Jing Ke, a native of Wei, is undoubtedly a colorful part of the historical drama of Yan. The 800-year history of the Yan Kingdom came to a desolate and tragic end with Jing Ke&#39;s stubbornness and despair in attacking Qin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The history of Yan State must start from three hundred miles north of Yishui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is also a river, a river that is shallower and thinner than Yi Shui: Liuli River. The Liuli River is an insignificant tributary of the Haihe River Basin. When it flows into Fangshan District, Beijing, a small town surrounded by the Liuli River is named after the Liuli River. To the east of the town, a number of Shang and Zhou cultural relics and sites have been excavated since the 1940s. Now, relying on the ruins, the Western Zhou Yandu Ruins Museum has been built. There are eight big characters on one wall of the museum: Ding Tian Ge Di, appointed to the Northern Territory. These eight characters illustrate that the purpose of establishing the Yan State was to ensure the security of the northern frontier of the Zhou Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/WyrxAP660ttx9yxBFzMnYaAIAjLh6TYFswiKhog4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1449&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/WyrxAP660ttx9yxBFzMnYaAIAjLh6TYFswiKhog4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Territory tiles with Taotie patterns from the Yan State, collected by the Yandu Museum of the Western Zhou Dynasty. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Shang Dynasty in the Zhou Dynasty, the princes were granted great titles. The first person to be ennobled in the Yan Kingdom was the eldest concubine of King Wen of Zhou, who was also the half-brother of King Wu of Zhou, Ji Shi. Since Ji Shi wanted to stay in the royal city to assist the emperor, he did not go to the fief to govern, but sent his son Ji Ke there. He himself was called Zhao Gong because of his fiefdom, so he was called Zhao Gong in history. This means that the nominal first monarch of the Yan Kingdom was Zhao Gong, but the actual first monarch was Zhao Gong&#39;s son Ji Ke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The territory of Yan State is roughly equivalent to today&#39;s northern part of Hebei plus Beijing. Among all the princes, Yan State is located in the north, and bordering it is the ethnic tribe called Rong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first capital of the Yan Kingdom - for the sake of narrative convenience, let&#39;s call it the first capital of Yan - is near the museum. Of course, the capital city of a feudal state more than two thousand years ago was just a larger market town. When the Yan Kingdom was first established, it was adjacent to another smaller country: Ji. Soon, Yan State annexed Ji State and moved its capital to Ji. The location of thistle is located in the Guang&#39;anmen area of ​​today&#39;s Beijing city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/U9CatV5KXO1N1LSRngz9uAyuINPajP8hVdy0UiOT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/U9CatV5KXO1N1LSRngz9uAyuINPajP8hVdy0UiOT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Outside Guang&#39;an Gate in Beijing, there is a Liao Dynasty Buddhist temple - Tianning Temple. The Tianning Temple Tower is the oldest above-ground building in Beijing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yan Kingdom lasted for more than 800 years, and it can be said that it had little sense of existence for the first 700 years. In other words, the only time it had a sense of existence was when this small country in the north encountered big trouble - Shanrong invaded and almost destroyed the country. Fortunately, the Central Plains region was in the era of Duke Huan of Qi, the leader of the Five Hegemons in the Spring and Autumn Period. Under the banner of Zun Wang and Expelling the Barbarians, Duke Huan of Qi contacted the princes to form a coalition. He personally led his troops deep into the hinterland of the Shanrong and fought several battles with the Shanrong until the Shanrong came far away. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From then on, the Yan Kingdom was just like ordinary passers-by A and B, living and multiplying in the northern country in obscurity. By the time the princes turned their attention to it again, it was already three hundred years later. At this time, a major event occurred in the Yan Kingdom that shocked the princes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, the important difference between the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period is that although the Spring and Autumn Period also had frequent wars, they generally only beat their opponents until they surrendered and admitted their mistakes, while the Warring States Period focused on occupying the opponent&#39;s territory or even annexing the opponent. Purpose. During the bloody Warring States Period, with wars and wars raging, ancient countries perished one after another, and the remote Yan State also felt great pressure to survive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 321 BC, the first king of the Yan Kingdom, King Yan Yi, died. His son Ji Kuai ascended the throne and was known as King Kuai of Yan in history. Faced with the great powers surrounding the country and the weak state of Yan, King Kuai of Yan was worried. He wanted to work hard to make the backward Yan state invincible. He sincerely believes that as long as it can make the Yan country strong, he will not hesitate even if he and his family are not in power. Various signs show that King Yan is a simple and open-minded person. Only in this way can his dream be used with ulterior motives. The traitor took advantage of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The treacherous minister was his son, who was the Prime Minister of Yan State at that time and was highly regarded by King Kuai of Yan State. Zi Zhi was indeed quite talented, so much so that King Kuai of Yan mistakenly believed that Yan must rely on him in order to revitalize the country. Zizhi fully grasped the eagerness of King Kuai of Yan to seek governance. His two confidants Su Dai and Lu Maoshou often gave advice to King Kuai of Yan, praising Zizhi&#39;s ability to govern the country, and urging King Kuai of Yan to follow the example of Yao and Shun and cede the world to the throne. Son of. In this way, Zi Zhi can not only govern the Yan Kingdom well and realize the rise of the Yan Kingdom, but at the same time, King Kuai of Yan will also become a saint like Yao and Shun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Kuai of Yan deeply believed in these deceptions, &quot;because the whole country belongs to the son, and the son is of great importance&quot; - King Kuai of Yan handed over all the important affairs of the country to the son, so the power of the son was extremely popular. ——Of course, I also want to sit on the throne. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon after, under the continued instigation of Zi Zhi and his associates, King Kuai of Yan &quot;received the seals from his son who was an official of three hundred stone&quot;, that is, he took all the seals of middle and high-level officials with more than three hundred stone in the country. Leave it to Zi, and let Zi control it. So, &quot;the son went to the south to do the king&#39;s business.&quot; The throne of the King of Yan passed from King Kuai to his son, who became the King of Yan. King Kuai instead became a minister. He no longer interfered with political affairs on the grounds of old age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confucianism has always beautified the three generations and believed that the abdication of Yao, Shun and Yu was a symbol of the great unity of the world. Later, there were many abdication events, including Emperor Xian of the Han Dynasty, whose throne was Cao Pi, Emperor Gong of the Jin Dynasty, Liu Yu, Emperor Gong of the Sui Dynasty, Li Yuan, Emperor Ai of the Tang Dynasty, Zhu Wen, and Emperor Gong of the Zhou Dynasty, Zhao Kuangyin. However, the concessions between these foreign surnames were backed by force by the recipients, and the monarch had no choice but to give in. In contrast, King Kuai of Yan&#39;s true and heartfelt surrender was unprecedented, if not unprecedented, in thousands of years of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the sage-like abdication of King Yan brought a catastrophe to the Yan country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the three years of Zi Zhi’s reign, the State of Yan did not revitalize as King Kuai of Yan had hoped. Instead, it got worse. “The State of Yan was in chaos and the people complained.” Prince Kuai&#39;s son, Tai Ziping, was originally supposed to inherit the throne, but his father&#39;s abdication made him a minister. Of course, he wanted to regain the throne that belonged to him. Therefore, with Jiangjun City&#39;s support, Tai Ziping and his supporters plotted to overthrow Zi Zhi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qi State, which is adjacent to Yan State, saw an excellent opportunity to get involved in Yan State. King Xuan of Qi sent an envoy to contact Tai Ziping and expressed his willingness to help Tai Ziping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With Qi&#39;s promise, Prince Ping felt that great things were about to happen, so he and the city attacked the palace. However, Qi did not send troops in time as promised. The prince Pingji was defeated and died, and the Yan country was in chaos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking this opportunity, King Xuan of Qi sent troops to attack Yan. The Yan soldiers were disheartened and fled one after another. King Kuai and Zizhi of Yan were both killed by the Qi army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Qi army invaded Yan, and the Yan state suffered heavy losses. A large number of heavy weapons were transported away, the ancestral temples were burned, and tens of thousands of Yan people died. Direct evidence of the massacre of the Yan people by the Qi army has been revealed more than two thousand years after the incident: in 1966, fourteen skulls of Warring States people were discovered in Yanxiadu, Yixian County, Hebei Province. Archaeologists examined Tomb No. 5 among them. A rescue excavation was carried out. Under the loess, a large number of white human skulls were randomly buried together without any burial objects. The excavation report stated that &quot;almost all of these human bones are male adults&quot;; &quot;the largest number of skulls belong to young adults aged 18-35, accounting for about 80% of the observations&quot;; and, archaeologists also found that some of them Either part of the skull had been chopped off, or the arrowhead remained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The State of Zhao is adjacent to the State of Yan. With the help of King Wuling of Zhao, another son of King Kuai of Yan, Gongzi Shi, was escorted back to the country to inherit the throne. This is King Yan Zhao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What King Yan Zhao inherited was a mess. Ji was looted and destroyed by the Qi army and could no longer serve as the capital. So, he built a new city further south on the banks of the Yishui River. This was the lower capital of Yan; correspondingly, Ji was the upper capital of Yan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yanchu Capital ruins are located in the suburbs of Beijing. A railway is close to the ruins. Occasionally, trains pass by, making earth-shattering sounds. A little further away is the densely populated Liulihe Town. As for the ruins of Yanshangdu, it is located in a bustling metropolis with busy traffic, with cars coming and going, noisy day and night. In sharp contrast to Yanchu Capital and Yanshangdu, Yanxiadu is the largest capital among the excavated capitals of the Spring and Autumn and Warring States princes. At its peak, Yanxiadu had an estimated population of about 300,000. ——And the population of the entire Yan State will most likely not exceed three million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/ZhSm7PMYgSDX8kFNUfE1Sf8p5oaRTFom9Ew5nWYE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/ZhSm7PMYgSDX8kFNUfE1Sf8p5oaRTFom9Ew5nWYE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216769&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Liuli River Ancient Bridge in Liulihe Town, Fangshan District, Beijing. The ancient bridge was built during the Jiajing period of the Ming Dynasty. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, what I see in Yanxiadu are patches of green cornfields. In the cornfield, there are occasional mounds of soil rising suddenly. The unique mounds of soil vaguely indicate that this is no ordinary crop field. This was one of the most important metropolises in China two thousand years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the cornfield, tall black poplar trees cover a small river, which flows toward Yi Shui. That year, white clothes were fluttering and the crown looked like snow. Prince Dan and a group of Yan people gathered around Jing Ke, got into the carriage, and drove slowly out of the capital of Yanxia to the banks of the Yishui River not far outside the city. There is a pavilion there; in the pavilion, wine and food have been laid out. They are about to raise a toast together for the last time...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/vj9FASfXSnIgbCDNOWacLiNo7rW2ju9r8w2zdQ2l.jpeg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1507&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/vj9FASfXSnIgbCDNOWacLiNo7rW2ju9r8w2zdQ2l.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216775&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yixian County Yanxiadu Ancient City Ruins&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Dead Time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Yan State when the capital of Yanxia was being built was undoubtedly the weakest among the seven heroes. How to rectify this mess and how to magically revitalize the sluggish Yan State were the urgent issues faced by King Yan Zhao when he came to the throne. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;King Yan Zhao realized the importance of talents. Only by absorbing the best talents to serve the State of Yan, could the State of Yan become rich and powerful in a short period of time. The news that King Yan Zhao was thirsty for talents quickly spread throughout the world, and many scholars with weapons in their possession went to the Kingdom of Yan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before visiting the ruins of Yanxiadu, I first went to Luoyang, Henan. In a field on one side of the road outside Luoyang, there is an extraordinary tomb. Next to the tomb is a key cultural relic protection monument in Henan Province: Su Qin&#39;s tomb. On the square at the head of the tomb, there are several tall stone tablets, one of which is inscribed with the inscription &quot;The Tombstone of Su Qin, a Co-conspirator of the Warring States Period&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the scholars who defected to the Yan Kingdom, the most famous and influential was Su Qin, a native of Luoyi who was directly under the Emperor of Zhou. Su Qin&#39;s deeds are mainly recorded in &quot;Historical Records&quot; and &quot;Warring States Policy&quot;, but there are many contradictions in the two books. This is because both Sima Qian and Liu Xiang suffered from the lack of authentic and reliable first-hand information. It was not until the end of 1973 that a batch of silk books were unearthed from Han Tomb No. 3 in Mawangdui, Changsha, and Su Qin&#39;s true identity gradually became clear. This batch of silk books was compiled by experts into &quot;Books from the Warring States Strategists and Family&quot;. Among the twenty-seven chapters, sixteen are long-lost books that Sima Qian and Liu Xiangwei have never seen. The content of the lost book happens to be related to Su Qin - so, more than two thousand years later, through these words, we can finally restore a lurker who paid the price with his life: the spy Su Qin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before defecting to King Yan Zhao, Su Qin traveled around the country, looking for opportunities. However, he was arrogant and spent all his money, but no monarch took him seriously. When he returned home, his family ignored him. Therefore, when King Yan Zhao respected him, treated him politely, and regarded him as a national scholar, Su Qin decided that the scholar would die for his confidant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Qin believed that Yan was the weakest among the seven kingdoms. Qin and Qi are powerful countries, and Zhao is a sub-powerful country. The State of Yan could not compete with any of them. If you want to defeat Qi and take revenge, you must weaken Qi. The best way to weaken Qi is to encourage and support Qi to annex Song. In this way, Qi will inevitably become the target of public criticism. In order to make Qi State implement the wrong line and achieve the purpose of weakening it, Su Qin was willing to go to Qi State for internal response. He made an agreement with King Zhao of Yan: &quot;If you don&#39;t fight against internal invaders, you can&#39;t keep away from external enemies. The king governs the outside world, and the ministers report to the inside. This is the trend of destruction.&quot; - If internal strife does not arise, the outside world cannot act easily. The king is planning to deal with Qi State while he is away, while I invade Qi State and create chaos. In this way, the situation of destroying Qi was created. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Qin came to Qi State as an envoy from Yan State. Later, with his outstanding talent and eloquence, he won the trust of King Qi Min and was appointed as the Prime Minister-his status even exceeded In the state of Yan. As Su Qin was favored by King Qi Min, people around King Yan Zhao began to suspect that Su Qin might not keep his promise, and King Yan Zhao was shaken for a time. For this reason, Su Qin wrote a letter to King Yan Zhao, swearing that he would be &quot;as trustworthy as Wei Sheng, as honest as Boyi, and as filial as Zeng Shen&quot; - these top-secret communications at the time were passed down through the transmission of silk books in the early Han Dynasty, more than two thousand years later. See the light of day again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than ten years in Qi State, despite the changing international situation, Su Qin consistently implemented his agreement with King Yan Zhao, that is, when formulating foreign policies for Qi State, he always tried every means to weaken Qi State. During this period, he not only dissuaded the King of Qin from asking the King of Qi to jointly proclaim the emperor, but also successfully alienated the relationship between Qin and Qi, formed a five-nation coalition to attack Qin, and made Zhao, Chu and other countries have tense relations with Qi. Especially important, he prompted the King of Qi to invade and finally annex the Song Dynasty three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to paralyze the monarchs and ministers of Qi State, King Yan Zhao, who hated Qi State deeply, only followed King Qi&#39;s lead. When Qi State attacked Song Dynasty, Yan State sent troops to help. Even King Qi Min executed a general of the Yan army for a trivial matter. Although King Yan Zhao shed tears of grief and anger, he sent an envoy to admit his mistake to King Qi Min...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 286 BC, Qi destroyed the Song Dynasty. The Song Kingdom, located in the fertile land of the Central Plains, was established by enfeoffing the survivors of the Yin and Shang Dynasties in the early Zhou Dynasty. It had a very high level: Duke. This noble and wealthy country was annexed by Qi, which aroused strong dissatisfaction among other princes. At this time, under the painstaking management of King Yan Zhao, the Yan State had become strong and strong. The state of Qi has long been strong on the outside but weak on the inside. So, more than a year later, King Zhao of Yan poured out all his troops, led by general Le Yi, across the border of Qi and Yan like a tide, and entered Qi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the Yan army attacked Qi State, Su Qin was named the Prime Minister of Qi State, but his identity as a spy of Yan State was exposed. He was tortured by the furious King Min of Qi and was tortured by breaking a car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fury of King Qi could not withstand the revengeful Yan army. The Yan army attacked Linzi, the capital of Qi. King Qi Min fled and was later killed by the Chu army general Nao Chi - his death was very tragic: &quot;Shoot the king&#39;s stock, pull out the king&#39;s tendon, hang it on the temple beam, and die in the past.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Yan army captured more than 70 cities in Qi, and only Jimo and Ju were still trapped and fighting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, during the siege of Jimo, King Yan Zhao died. The current situation suddenly took a turn for the worse: King Hui of Yan had a rift with Le Yi when he was crown prince. Under the instigation of the State of Qi, he dismissed Le Yi, and Le Yi had to defect to the State of Zhao - the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period. , this kind of voting with feet is not uncommon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Qi State, which was originally in an absolutely weak position, came back to life under the strategizing of the famous general Tian Dan - the Yan army was driven out of the country, and the lost cities of the Qi State were recovered one by one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The short-lived prosperity of the Yan Kingdom ends here. It is like a meteor streaking across the sky. While people are still looking up at it and surprised by its brilliance, it has extinguished and fallen. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Later&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is interesting is that the two most exciting historical events of the Yan Kingdom, which has been in the country for more than 800 years, namely Su Qin’s relationship with Qi and Jing Ke’s assassination of Qin, both had protagonists. He is a foreigner; whether he is a spy or an assassin, trying to defeat a country or save a country by such extraordinary means is full of wild imagination and thrilling legend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of seniority, Prince Dan is the sixth grandson of King Yan Zhao, and there is more than fifty years between them. In the half century from the death of King Yan Zhao to the reign of Crown Prince Dan&#39;s father, King Yan Xi, the national fortunes of the Yan country deteriorated from bad to worse. Four generations of Yan kings made mistakes one after another. They fought nine foreign wars and only won one small victory. Among them, when King Xi of Yan was on the throne, the State of Zhao suffered a disastrous defeat in the Battle of Changping. As a neighbor of the State of Zhao, the State of Yan not only did not suffer a loss, but instead took advantage of the situation and robbed it. However, it was severely attacked by the State of Zhao after the defeat, so that the capital of Yan was trapped. He had to pay a lot of money for peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The snipe and the clam fight, and the fisherman gains. The Qin State, which fought for the unification war after the sixth generation, was the ultimate beneficiary of the war between the princes. After Qin destroyed Han and then Zhao, Qin&#39;s forces entered Nanyishui. Previously, Yan State had built the Great Wall along the Nanyi River. However, Prince Dan knew that the simple Great Wall could not withstand Qin&#39;s tiger and wolf troops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He hopes there is a way to quickly and once and for all remove the threat from the Qin State and save the precarious Yan State.于是，便有了众所周知的荆轲刺秦；便有了两千多年前，易水河边那场风萧萧兮的饯别宴……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/J2zZt3V7ZcZwjVHayueRKgRLKKn6oXdk4WNJIC8L.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1850&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/J2zZt3V7ZcZwjVHayueRKgRLKKn6oXdk4WNJIC8L.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;荆轲拜别&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末资料/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;昔时人已没，今日水犹寒。夏秋之交的易水，有风，却不寒冷，大多数河段水流平缓，沙洲上生长着诸多水草，鸟儿轻飞，看上去更像湿地。距燕下都遗址数公里的河畔，平原上隆起一座土堆，土堆上矗着一座塔，建于辽代，名为荆轲塔。据说，土堆附近有荆轲衣冠冢。那个衣冠似雪的男儿，掷下手中的酒樽，头也不回地朝着夕阳沉落的方向远去。从此，再也没有回来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从远处看，荆轲塔的形状像一柄短剑，直刺蓝得空洞的苍穹。它让我想起了荆轲藏在地图中的匕首。图穷匕现，如果那把淬过剧毒的匕首刺死了嬴政；又或者，燕昭王的寿命再延续十年；历史，一定不是我们后来看到的那样。只是，世界上有苹果有芒果有开心果，却没有如果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/OeWlz0cgwTsfzJQ2BWrovDOIpEAWW1gcEapnM3C4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1445&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/11/25/OeWlz0cgwTsfzJQ2BWrovDOIpEAWW1gcEapnM3C4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;216770&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;易县荆轲塔&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC Photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辽阔的燕下都遗址，大部分是庄稼地，小部分是林子，更小部分是村落。玉米长势良好，野花漫不经心。沟渠里，蹲伏着青蛙，向天空睁大了警惕的双眼。风来，杨树发出夸张的声响。高树多悲风，萧萧愁杀人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夕阳西下时，如血的残阳斜射在一座座隆起的土堆上，它们，要么是从前的宫殿台基，要么是埋葬死者的封土。厚重潮湿的黄土下面，杨树扎根的大地深处，还残留着一个逝去时代，渐行渐远的血泪，呼喊和挣扎……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[陈冠锋：苏炳添接班人？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258020]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/01/y73V4w4TYwPKIDQPxAik5Um8apKla4o6ORuxKabk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;715&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/y73V4w4TYwPKIDQPxAik5Um8apKla4o6ORuxK abk. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252911&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 30, 2023, men&#39;s 100m final of track and field events at the Hangzhou Asian Games, China Contestant Chen Guanfeng after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 21:55 on September 30, 2023, men&#39;s 100 track and field at the Hangzhou Asian Games In the meter final, Chinese player and 30-year-old veteran Xie Zhenye won the championship in 9.97 seconds, tying his personal best. 23-year-old Chen Guanfeng ranked seventh in 10.34 seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Xie Zhen focused on the men’s 200 meters and won the men’s 200 meters championship at the 2010 Youth Olympic Games, the men’s 4×100 meter relay championship at the 2014 Incheon Asian Games, and the 2017 Tianjin National Games. Men&#39;s 100m and 200m champions, men&#39;s 200m champion at the 2018 Athletics World Cup in London, UK, and men&#39;s 200m champion at the 2019 IAAF Diamond League London Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/9nNgnfPUKFqnPWv30kAhzyWE8r45pAJLJpEWn6YM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/9nNgnfPUKFqnPWv30kAhzyWE8r45pAJLJpEWn6YM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252912&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, in the men&#39;s 100-meter final of the track and field event in Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese player Chen Guanfeng (middle) competed&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2019 Doha World Athletics Championships, Xie Zhenye broke into the men&#39;s 200m final with a time of 20.03 seconds, creating Chinese sprint history and becoming the first Chinese to enter this event. Athletes in the World Championship finals. On August 6, 2021, in the men&#39;s 4×100m relay final of the Tokyo Olympics, Tang Xingqiang, Xie Zhenye, Su Bingtian, and Wu Zhiqiang represented the Chinese team and won the bronze medal, creating the best result in history. In September of the same year, at the 14th National Games, Xie Zhenye won the men&#39;s 100m and 200m runner-up, and the men&#39;s 4×100m relay championship. He is the Asian record holder in the men&#39;s 200 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the Asian record for men&#39;s 100 meters is 9.83 seconds set by Chinese player Su Bingtian at the 2021 Tokyo Olympics; the Asian Games record also belongs to Su Bingtian, who ran 9.92 seconds at the 2018 Jakarta Asian Games. . During the finals, he appeared in the live broadcast room to give commentary, saying that their group of old athletes had completed their tasks, and now it was time to look at the young athletes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/M0tl7nFcaGJ8O3SwQZtNyW14KQCmuGmUMoemIxRs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;653&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/M0tl7nFcaGJ8O3SwQZtNyW14KQCmuGmUMoemIxRs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252913&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 6, 2023, in the men&#39;s 4x100m relay final of the track and field event at the 31st Summer Universiade held in Chengdu, the Chinese team won the championship with a time of 38.80 seconds. Chinese players Chen Guanfeng (first from left) and Yan Haibin (second from right) hand over the baton during the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Guanfeng He is one of the young athletes Su Bingtian is optimistic about. He has repeatedly praised Chen Guanfeng in public as the best among domestic post-00 players. In an interview, he mentioned: &quot;Based on my progress that year, he should be able to take over the job in three years.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of August 2, Chen Guanfeng stood at the Chengdu Universiade Summer Games On the second lane of the men&#39;s 100-meter final, he leaned down and waited for the starting gun to sound. Twelve years ago, the 23-year-old Su Bingtian also stood on the second track of the men&#39;s 100-meter final of the Shenzhen Universiade. That time, he won the bronze medal. The media called him &quot;China&#39;s sprint hope.&quot; Later, Su Bingtian became famous all the way on the 100-meter track, collecting many records to his name, carving a place in the world of track and field, and becoming the undisputed leader of Chinese sprints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 23-year-old Chen Guanfeng almost replicated Su Bingtian’s medal-winning journey. This is the first time in his career that he has appeared in a real world competition, and it is also the first time that he has set foot in a world-class men’s competition. The track for the 100-meter final. He ran a personal season-best time of 10.16 seconds in the semifinals, and two hours later in the final, he crossed the finish line third in 10.17 seconds. After the game, Chen Guanfeng, draped in the national flag, ran around the track and field to express his gratitude to the audience. Four days later, he and his teammates won the gold medal in the 4×100m relay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yH5ivwbDM5RXIIwH8iggUHNRB2xjkgApagUuq9Gf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;578&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yH5ivwbDM5RXIIwH8iggUHNRB2xjkgApagUuq9Gf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252914&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the men&#39;s 100-meter final of the track and field event in Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese players Chen Guanfeng (front) and Xie Zhenye (first from right) competed in the competition&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The similarity in winning the medal in the 100-meter final made the media and audiences associate him with Su Bingtian. Chen Guanfeng is 1.80 meters tall, 8 centimeters taller than Su Bingtian. In 2020, his time in the 100-meter event was about 10.40 seconds, and his personal best in 2021 was 10.19 seconds. In the National Championships of the same year, Chen Guanfeng won the championship in 10.06 seconds against two famous players of the national team, Wu Zhiqiang and Xu Zhouzheng, in nearly zero wind speed. He was only 0.01 seconds away from the Olympic standard. He surpassed Ho Yuhong&#39;s 10.19 seconds in one fell swoop and became China&#39;s &quot;post-2000&quot; 100-meter sprinter. one person. He also became the fourth-best player in the history of the Chinese team after Su Bingtian, Xie Zhenye and Zhang Peimeng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Guanfeng said: &quot;I will try my best to attack the Olympic podium. Although I don&#39;t know whether I can succeed, I will also help the young people behind me like Su Bingtian. , set a good example for them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Chen Guanfeng is still a fresh face in the national track and field competition, he has long been known as the &quot;Xiguan Flying Man&quot; in Guangzhou. Before the age of 17, Chen Guanfeng had been a campus player and did not enter a sports school to receive systematic professional training. He has represented Guangzhou No. 1 Middle School in inter-school competitions many times, and his running speed is much faster than that of ordinary students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have always been active since I was a child and like to run and jump. I seem to have always had better sports scores in elementary school, so the physical education teachers recommended me to practice in the school track and field team. I did not sacrifice a lot of study time to practice track and field. Like other students, they also have to do homework and take exams,&quot; Chen Guanfeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He ranked first in competitions in Liwan District many times and was discovered by Gu Yanqiang, the former coach of the West Village Youth Amateur Sports School. In 2015, Gu Yanqiang took up his new position at Guangzhou Sports Vocational and Technical College. He did long-term ideological work with Chen Guanfeng&#39;s parents and himself, and recruited Chen Guanfeng into the school after the high school entrance examination. &quot;My parents are very supportive of me and have always told me that doing what you like to do and being happy is the most important thing.&quot; Chen Guanfeng recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Yanqiang commented on him: &quot;It was a bit late to receive professional training, but he is talented in sprinting, has a good figure and good jumping ability. He is a rare talent.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yJAMO94NiPbDa8jm3UteqAMOOKu73TlP0Hi54Vhd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/01/yJAMO94NiPbDa8jm3UteqAMOOKu73TlP0Hi54Vhd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252915&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 2, 2023, in the men&#39;s 100-meter final of the track and field event at the 31st Summer Universiade in Chengdu, China&#39;s Chen Guanfeng won the third place with a time of 10.17 seconds&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first entered the sports school, Chen Guanfeng’s foundation was relatively weak, and his best 100-meter time was 11.03 seconds. As he grows older and his coach slowly guides him, Chen Guanfeng&#39;s training gradually gets on the right track. In Gu Yanqiang&#39;s plan, he will spend two years laying the foundation, training explosive power, coordination, balance, and sensitivity, and gradually improving strength and frequency. At the end of 2017, Chen Guanfeng joined the Guangdong Provincial Team. In 2018, he became a regular from the provincial team and was selected for the Chinese national track and field team. He became the main member of the men&#39;s 4×100 meter relay event and began to launch an impact on larger competitions. He constantly refreshed his original speed and emerged in the track and field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, Chen Guanfeng joined Su Bingtian’s team for training. After Su Bingtian created the &quot;myth&quot; of 9.83 seconds in the Tokyo Olympics, the Su Bingtian Speed ​​Research and Training Center, jointly built by Jinan University, Guangdong Provincial Sports Bureau, and the Chinese Athletics Association, was established to explore cutting-edge technology, discipline construction and technology in track and field training. Innovation to support the cultivation and selection of track and field reserve talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The technical team filmed Chen Guanfeng’s daily training and analyzed his technical movements. He improved his starts and runs as a result. &quot;My advantage at the start was pretty good, but my running was very bad on the way. I often led in the first 60 to 70 meters, but overtook me in the last 20 to 30 meters.&quot; Chen Guanfeng analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reviewing his performance on the 100-meter track at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chen Guanfeng said that his performance in the first half of the race was normal, but after adjusting his technique, the old problem of serious slowdown in the second half still existed. He admitted that his legs were slightly uncomfortable during the second half of the final, so he chose a relatively conservative finishing strategy. After all, there were relay tasks ahead. &quot;I am still in the process of adapting and running in with new technologies, but I have achieved my goal of advancing to the finals. With my current hard power, I am not particularly outstanding in Asia, so the finals are a process of learning and enjoying.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Watching his senior Xie Zhenye break the 10-second mark in Hangzhou, Chen Guanfeng excitedly said that this is a historic moment for Chinese sprinting. Regarding the question about whether he has the chance to become the fourth Chinese athlete to break the 10-second barrier for 100 meters, Chen Guanfeng said that he will go all out and be ready to take over at all times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I think there are too many talented people. You must train hard and maintain your best condition every day in order to not fall behind in the arena.&quot; Chen Jianfeng said, &quot;This is my first time. Participating in the Asian Games, with the current sprint level of Asian countries, I can&#39;t say that I will definitely get a ranking, but the goal I set for myself is to advance to the finals.&quot; Judging from his performance in this Asian Games, he achieved his goal. We have There are reasons to believe that this post-2000 athlete will bring us more surprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中小学流行“萝卜刀”惹争议：让孩子没有害人之心，比严防死守害人之物重要得多丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257942]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a children&#39;s toy has caused heated discussion in public opinion. According to media reports, almost all primary school students have a &quot;carrot knife&quot;, which is a colorful plastic imitation knife toy that uses its own gravity to slide the knife body. The &quot;Carrot Knife&quot; is available in different colors and sizes, with prices ranging from 5 yuan to 25 yuan. There are also different styles such as &quot;printed flash radish knife&quot; and &quot;luminous gravity radish knife&quot;, which have already sold &quot;400,000&quot; online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media reports said that some parents reported to the Chongqing Online Political Questioning Platform that primary and secondary school students brought &quot;carrot knives&quot; into school to play together, which posed safety risks. Some parents are worried that if their children imitate actions such as stabbing and poking, it will have a negative impact on their psychology. When interviewed, some experts and scholars said that the &quot;carrot knife&quot; has safety hazards and &quot;subconsciously inspires children to be violent and do the same thing with a real knife.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first glance, it seems that the carrot knife is a kind of &quot;knife&quot; just like its name, and there is a danger of cutting, scratching and stabbing children. If the carrot knife is really a sharp-edged tool that can easily hurt people, not to mention that minors should not possess it, it should also be classified as a controlled knife in the adult world. However, judging from the actual situation of this toy, I am afraid that its danger is not as serious as that reported by parents and experts. Words such as &quot;danger&quot;, &quot;warning&quot; and &quot;warning&quot; are also exaggerated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, judging from the appearance and material of the carrot knife, its &quot;edge&quot; is an obtuse angle and it is also a plastic product. How much harm it can do to humans can only be achieved by piercing white paper and apples with a few pieces. The photos are not convincing, and pencils and ballpoint pens can also be used to pierce them. Are they also banned because they are dangerous? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is the innate nature of human beings to play with objects in their hands. Even for common stationery such as rulers and ballpoint pens, children have developed recreational uses for turning pens and placing rulers. If we have to talk about the degree of danger, any of these commonly used stationery items, such as a 30-degree triangle, a thin steel ruler, and a sharp ballpoint pen tip, is probably much more dangerous than a carrot knife. Even long fingernails can scratch the skin. A book page can also cut your finger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if it is just to prevent the possible harm caused by such &quot;blunt plastic knives&quot;, it is obvious that measures such as &quot;playing under parental supervision&quot; and &quot;not allowing children to bring it to school&quot; should be adopted. is to exaggerate the power of a plastic blunt knife toy and devote a disproportionate amount of attention to it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the rhetoric of “stimulating children’s violent tendencies” when interviewed by experts and scholars is also worthy of analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the long years before the advent of the carrot knife, generations of minors would also imitate &quot;stabbing, poking, poking and other actions&quot; because this is something written in human genes. Human ancestors jumped from hunting activities to becoming the spiritual beings and then ruling the earth. It is the nature of every child to imitate and use weapons. A simple wooden sword or a delicate toy sword is almost everyone’s childhood memory. Who hasn&#39;t fantasized as a child about being a superhero, or more or less a general and a vigilante? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Playing is a way for children to understand the world. Role-playing and imitating martial arts movements are their irrepressible nature. Advertising slogans such as &quot;Show me my carrot knife and defeat the enemy with one strike&quot; In fact, there is no big problem. If children&#39;s behavior of imitating the use of weapons is denigrated as &quot;violent tendencies&quot;, this is definitely inconsistent with formal logic and goes against common sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference between small plastic toys and real sharp controlled knives, the difference between simulated games and wounding with a knife, and even the difference between legal violence and illegal violence, children with a little ability to discern After receiving education, they can be easily distinguished. The statement of &quot;stimulating violent tendencies&quot; goes too far, and it also denies children&#39;s cognitive and discerning abilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, from the perspective of healthy growth of minors, it is actually unrealistic to over-protect them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Minors will always encounter various risks in their growth process. This is not only the inevitable path of life, but also the price that cannot be avoided. Traffic rules cannot yet eliminate all traffic accidents, sports competitions cannot eliminate all injuries, and even adult society cannot eliminate all risks. On campus, stationery, tree branches, tables, chairs, and benches can all injure people. Should the campus be like a prison, free of sharp objects and hard walls, and tightly controlled? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, &quot;Don&#39;t underestimate children&quot; has long been a consensus in education. Neither parents nor schools should over-protect minors or completely deny their ability to self-manage. Minors will grow up one day, and it is impossible to keep them strictly guarded in a sterile environment and worry about every possible safety risk. The correct approach should be to guide them to correctly assess risks and teach them the ability to fight risks independently. Otherwise, there would not be such a famous saying in the Chinese world as “civilized in spirit, barbaric in body.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in the face of the popularity of &quot;Carrot Knife&quot; toys, the right thing for adults to do is to provide reasonable guidance and teach children correct values. It is much more important to prevent children from harming others than to strictly guard against harmful things. After all, if you have an evil intention, you can harm others and yourself with your bare hands; if you have the right views and knowledge, you can use sharp weapons to defend yourself and protect others. Not only does a small dull plastic knife pose no safety risks, it can actually become an &quot;experience package&quot; for children to view violence correctly and learn to face risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>