<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[鼠头还是鸭脖？不该成为一个问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259115]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On October 23, in response to campus food safety incidents such as &quot;rat head duck neck&quot;, the Food Safety Office of the State Council interviewed Nanchang, The main person in charge of the people&#39;s governments of Tangshan and two places. The interview required that various risks and hidden dangers should be prevented and resolved, and the bottom line of campus food safety should be firmly maintained. In the face of the storm of public opinion, &quot;drawing lessons from the past&quot; should become &quot;teachers for the future.&quot;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 14:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蒋寅：一张联系着青春记忆的唱片]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259077]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/22/SFRvTEx0DIb4NtFGgJmlZm1sXRPPnlt3XjagYdvS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/SFRvTEx0DIb4NtFGgJmlZm1sXRPPnlt3Xja gYdvS. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Japanese violinist Atsuko Tenma and her CD &quot;Elegy&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this era of emphasis on appearance, ATSUKO TEMMA compares with Akiko Sowauchi, Ikuko Kawai, and Sa Sa Beautiful violinists like Yaka can only be said to be talented individuals who rely on their skills. I didn&#39;t know her name until I saw this record. It was because this CD included &quot;&lt;span>;Balada&quot; (&lt;span>;balada&lt;/span>;) by Romanian composer Ciprián Polombescu that it caught my attention. I believe that many people had seen the biographical film of Romanian composer Polombescu and were deeply impressed by the recurring melody in the film. I&#39;ve been looking for recordings of this song everywhere, but I&#39;ve only seen one or two online audios, never a record. Therefore, as soon as I saw Atsuko Tenma’s CD online, I bought it immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/seOeZa1pWjlISOkgTEZ4ck30tIShYuEY9LMYrdJA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1061&quot; height= &quot;475&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/seOeZa1pWjlISOkgTEZ4ck30tIShYuEY9LMYrdJA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254822&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Romanian music biopic &quot;Ciprian Polombescu&quot;, a poster when it was released in China in 1978. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I got the record and browsed through the instructions. I was surprised to see that it also included two other pieces of music by Polombescu, &quot;Elegy.&quot; and &quot;BERTHA Nocturne&quot; were both music score manuscripts that Atsuko Tenma obtained when she visited the Polombescu Memorial Hall in Romania. They were arranged by composer Yasei Kobayashi and performed by Atsuko Tenma for the first time in 1993, becoming the world of these two pieces of music. Premiere. This CD is a live recording of her 1995 recital at the Shinjuku Bunka Center in Tokyo, produced and released by CONCERT IMAGINE the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Temma Atsuko graduated from Tokyo Gakugei University and won the Special Silver Medal at the Ron Thibault International Music Competition in 1975. She also won the Grand Prize at the San Diego International Violin Competition in 1975 and made her debut. I know that the records she has released include the complete collection of Bach&#39;s unaccompanied violin sonatas and Partitas, the sonatas of Beethoven, Franck, and Fry, as well as some thematically popular music albums &quot;Prayer&quot;, &quot;Song of a Traveler&quot;, &quot;Love&#39;s &quot;Greetings&quot;, &quot;Dream Queen&quot;, &quot;Song of Hometown&quot;, &quot;Silk Road&quot;, &quot;Silent Pavilion&quot;, &quot;Summer Sky Dance&quot;, &quot;Poetry&quot;, etc. The most popular one is the &quot;Nostalgia&quot; album featuring the Japanese popular name &quot;Looking Home BALADA&quot; , there have been multiple versions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sound effect of this live recording selection is not the best, but inspired by the warm atmosphere of the scene, Atsuko Tenma was very emotional. Massenet&#39;s &quot;Meditation&quot; is completely different from the ordinary soft and graceful music. A deep passion actually made me cry. When the familiar melody of &quot;BALADA&quot; sounded, all my senses were immediately conquered by it and I was immersed in the music. Although I feel it&#39;s a little less expressive, I still want to say it&#39;s touching. After all, this tune later almost became Atsuko Tenma’s calling card. There are twelve songs in the album, from Bach&#39;s &quot;Aria on the G String&quot; to &quot;This Road: Rain on the Castle Island&quot; written for her by Japanese composer Takeuchi Kunimitsu, and &quot;Seaside Sound Poetry&quot; by Chinese composer Qin Yongcheng, spanning a lot of times. It is big and has various styles. It is indeed very difficult to master each one in a concert. This shows that she has unusual expressive power. To some extent, I even think it surpasses those international female violinists. Of course, Yuko Komoriya’s piano accompaniment also added a lot to the performance. The only shortcoming is that in the last song &quot;Chaldash Dance&quot;, it seems that the fingertips touching the strings are not short and clear enough, and the technique is not enough. Most of her recordings focus on sketches, not any major works, and she seems to be using her strengths to avoid her weaknesses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Time flies, but music is eternal. The memory of the movie flows along with the melody, as if the hero of &quot;Cinema Paradiso&quot; is revisiting his hometown and pursuing his past youth. I have always wondered why so many people play such beautiful music. With Atsuko Tenma’s record, I don’t have any regrets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[针对校园食品安全事件，国务院食安办约谈河北唐山、江西南昌人民政府主要负责人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259114]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In response to the food safety incidents that occurred at North China University of Technology and Jiangxi Industrial Vocational and Technical College, the Food Safety Office of the State Council today (23 Japan) interviewed the main persons in charge of the People’s Government of Tangshan, Hebei and Nanchang, Jiangxi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to the food safety incident at North China University of Science and Technology, the Food Safety Office of the State Council interviewed the main person in charge of the Tangshan Municipal People&#39;s Government today (23rd). The interview pointed out that the Party Central Committee and the State Council attach great importance to food safety work. Ensuring food safety is a people&#39;s livelihood project and a public support project, and it is an unshirkable responsibility of party committees and governments at all levels. The campus food safety incident that occurred at North China University of Science and Technology exposed the school involved&#39;s weak food safety awareness, serious lack of main body responsibilities, lack of industry management responsibilities of the competent department, insufficient fulfillment of food safety territorial management responsibilities, and failure to effectively implement supervision and management responsibilities. , causing adverse social impacts. The interview requested that Tangshan City should benchmark and implement the &quot;four most stringent&quot; requirements, strictly implement the responsibilities of the &quot;first person responsible for food safety&quot; in the region, effectively strengthen organizational leadership, and tighten the responsibilities of all parties; it is necessary to learn deeply Learn lessons from one example and make rectifications quickly, prevent and resolve various risks and hidden dangers, and resolutely maintain the bottom line of campus food safety. The Food Safety Office of the State Council will conduct on-site inspections and supervise the entire implementation of rectifications in Tangshan City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to the &quot;rat head and duck neck&quot; food safety incident that occurred at Jiangxi Industrial Vocational and Technical College, the Food Safety Office of the State Council interviewed the main person in charge of the Nanchang Municipal People&#39;s Government today (23rd). The interview pointed out that the Party Central Committee and the State Council attach great importance to food safety work. Ensuring food safety is a people&#39;s livelihood project and a public support project, and it is an unshirkable responsibility of party committees and governments at all levels. The food safety incident that occurred at Jiangxi Industrial Vocational and Technical College exposed the weakening of local food safety management responsibilities in Nanchang, the vacant responsibility of the school involved, the absence of industry management responsibilities of the competent department, the failure to implement supervision and management responsibilities, and improper emergency response work. problems, causing bad social impact, and the lessons are extremely profound. The interview requested that Nanchang City should strictly abide by the &quot;four most stringent&quot; requirements for food safety, fully implement territorial management responsibilities, and conscientiously do a good job in food safety work in the region; it should conduct a profound analysis of the food safety incidents that occurred at Jiangxi Industrial Vocational and Technical College, and draw inferences from one example to other cases. Pay close attention to comprehensive rectification; we must tighten the responsibilities of all parties and resolutely maintain the bottom line of campus food safety. The Food Safety Office of the State Council will conduct on-site inspections and supervise the entire implementation of Nanchang City’s rectifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 13:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[球鞋与郁金香的炒作动力学：从共识形成到泡沫破灭要多久？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259075]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;With the reversal of market expectations, the &quot;shoe speculation&quot; that was popular in the past few years has begun to ebb. At present, has declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shoe speculation is not a rare game in human history. There have been various objects of speculation in human history, such as tulips, cotton, copper, and tin. In China, Pu&#39;er tea, precious Chinese medicinal materials, famous wines, walnuts, Tibetan mastiffs, and even green onions and garlic are all fried. All speculation and speculation activities have a similar process: consensus formation, professional market formation, financialization, bubbles, loss of rationality, and then, the bubble bursts and the last batch of entrants go bankrupt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, basketball fans bought the same sneakers of their favorite stars, and sneaker collection only developed in a small basketball circle. Driven by celebrities and hungry marketing by shoe factories, the price of shoes is getting higher and higher. This is how the sneaker consensus came to be. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tulip speculation also shows characteristics very similar to shoe speculation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1593, a botany professor from Vienna brought tulips from Turkey to the Netherlands. This exotic and beautiful plant became the talk of high society. In the 17th century, the Netherlands was known as the &quot;Sea Coachman.&quot; Many Dutch people made their fortune through navigation and trade. At that time, the Netherlands was the richest place in Europe, and its assets were also expanding. When you have money, you will have some spiritual needs, and this need points to tulips. The price of tulips slowly increased as demand for tulips increased as dignitaries sought after them. This is also a process of forming social consensus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A very important link in forming a consensus is the proliferation of wealth myths. When some people make a lot of money through initial production, sales, and reselling speculation. The story will spread far and wide, attracting envy and followers. In the current information age, this process will be even more intense, and within a short period of time, everyone will know the story of wealth. This is the spread and explosion of consensus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The consensus among shoe speculators is that there is another important driving force, and that is the brand. The second-hand market for sneakers can be compared to the secondary market for stocks. The secondary market will have an impact on the primary market. Similarly, the second-hand hype of sneakers will also affect the primary market to a certain extent. The higher the price of a certain brand of shoes, the stronger the brand power is and the better the stock will be. Relevant analysis shows that there is a significant positive correlation between the transaction volume of sneakers in the second-hand market and the stock price. Therefore, the price of fried shoes is high. Although the brand side does not get the premium of fried shoes, it can gain profits from the stock market and the brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This will cause the company to change its business strategy to a certain extent. For collectibles, it will implement hunger marketing in terms of production and pricing, and launch limited editions and co-branded shoes, making these styles the object of speculation. But the paradox here is that the objects of hype are always increasing. As a modern industrial product, the quantity of shoes can easily increase. For a financial product, this is very dangerous. As a large-volume industrial product, shoes do not have the trust mechanism or proof-of-work mechanism of Bitcoin. The marginal cost is very small and depends entirely on the manufacturer&#39;s limit. However, there is competition between manufacturers. In the end, it will form a tragedy of the commons effect. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the consensus expanded, a professional market emerged, turning shoes into a financial product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second-hand sneaker trade began to develop in 2012 and experienced explosive growth in the following years. In 2015, StockX, a second-hand sneaker trading market, was established in the United States. The platform built a &quot;stock market&quot; for trading items, allowing users to trade sneakers like stocks. Users can see the index of each sneaker on the platform and check the price of sneakers at all times. In China, there were also multiple trading platforms for &quot;shoe speculation&quot; at that time, which were very similar to the trading model of the securities market. Not only did they derive K-line charts and &quot;shoe futures&quot;, but also derived from the Internet &quot;Cloud Shoe Speculation&quot;, showing a sense of participation. It has characteristics such as large number of investors, large trading volume, and violent price fluctuations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some third-party payment institutions are also providing leveraged services such as installment payments for shoe speculation platforms, and some people use this to gain high profits with high leverage. However, these leverages amplify risks. Not only do borrowers bear huge debts, but also the lending platform faces the risk of a break in the capital chain, creating a chain reaction and leading to financial risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process of tulip speculation, the formation of a professional market also played an important role. At the end of 1634, Dutch tulip merchants formed an organization similar to an industrial guild (College), which basically controlled the tulip trading market. The role of this industry organization is to formulate rules and facilitate the exchange of information. In essence, this means that tulips were formed as a professional market for financial product trading, and then financialization also appeared, and tulip futures began to appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Market formation and financialization will greatly stimulate bubbles. At that time, on a certain shoe speculation platform, the average selling price of Air Jordan 1 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this madness pales in comparison to tulips. Between December 1636 and January 1637, the prices of all varieties of tulips rose across the board, and speculators entered the Dutch tulip market. At that time, a rare bulb could be sold for 5,500 Dutch guilders, which was equivalent to 184 pigs or 46 cows at the time, and the equivalent of $140,000 today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After high prices, there is collapse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As more funds enter, the price of shoes is raised, but in the end, the excessive price will cause the consensus to break down, and the person who finally takes over will suffer losses. In 2021, the price of a pair of sneakers dropped from 1,659 to 700. A shoe dealer bought shoes for 40,000 to 50,000 yuan, but the original price dropped to more than 1,000 yuan. After the tide receded, countless people died on the shallows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same goes for tulips. By February 1637, people began to wonder how much the tulip bulbs bought at a high price were worth after they bloomed. The collapse happened, and no one bought the tulips that cost 5,000 guilders each and sold them for 50 guilders each. Essentially, this is a consensus bust, and the reason for the consensus bust is that the price goes beyond common sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relatively stable financial products either have use value or can be stored for a long time to go through cycles. The tulip bubble lasted for 27 years, starting in 1610 until prices collapsed in early February 1637. But the rapid rise and fall only lasted for just over 3 years. The most direct reason is: tulips cannot be preserved. Shoes also have a similar feature. Rubber and leather cannot be stored for a long time and will oxidize in the air. This is destined to make it impossible for shoe speculators to survive the cycle. Once there is any trouble in the economy, this type of speculators will be the first to be hit. Relatively speaking, Bitcoin has a consensus mechanism, proof of production, and black market uses, while tea and gold can be stored for a long time, and the consensus will be stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hypework has distinct characteristics of the times. The economic, technological, and cultural conditions of each era are different, and different consensuses will naturally be formed. But in the end, all hype will lead to the same result: the bubble bursts, and the last batch of entrants go bankrupt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[高邮：一座普通县城的工业逆袭丨县城故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258985]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/XCAZKCi8YlXGa7eJp8NEOyFbk7GBVjxcLESYdXhr.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;601&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/XCAZKCi8YlXGa7eJp8NEOyFbk7GBVjxc LESYdXhr. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254639&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Gaoyou, Zhenguo Temple on the Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Zhuhu People&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking for Gaoyou on the map, the first thing you see is a large blue water swamp - Gaoyou lake. The east bank of the lake forms an unnatural straight line, which was formed after the Beijing-Hangzhou Canal was dug. The old town of Gaoyou is right on the edge of the canal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zengqi described his hometown and mentioned the relationship between the canal and the old city, &quot;The canal is almost a &#39;hanging river&#39; as high as the river, while the county&#39;s terrain is low... Standing on the river embankment, you can overlook On the roofs of people below. Children in the city fly kites, and the kites float under the feet of people on the embankment.&quot; The water system shapes the appearance of the city and people&#39;s character. Wang Zengqi called it &quot;calm as water, flowing as water, and clear as water.&quot; He once Carve yourself a seal of &quot;Zhuhu People&quot;. Zhuhu is the nickname of Gaoyou Lake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going down the steep slope along the road on the river embankment and entering the old city, the driving speed becomes slower. The speed limit on the road is 20 kilometers, but the actual speed can only be this. Pedestrians and electric motorcycles are constantly passing through the narrow single lane, which is full of lively life. The architectural style facing the street is old, and many shops retain memories from the last century. For example, the Gaoyou Food Factory store near Fu Gongqiao Road has a long counter across the entrance with traditional mooncakes on an iron plate. They have been sold out all morning. Out of half. The specialty of the store is a kind of halva called Dongtang, which is wrapped in maltose with wheat flour mixed with sesame seeds. It is stacked on top of each other and has &quot;Handmade&quot; printed on the old-fashioned wrapping paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The vehicles stopped at Zhongshan South Road. A stretch of lane further south was designated as a historical and cultural district. It used to be the residences of officials and wealthy families. Local scholars believe that Qin Shaoyou’s former residence is in Jiaojia Lane. Nowadays, most of the houses here have been renovated into self-built rural houses. Only the shops on the main road have been uniformly decorated in the style of ancient buildings. Most of the shops are open, running snack bars, cotton shops, shrouds and longevity materials shops, and some people set up stalls to sell freshly caught fish and shrimps. The operators and customers are elderly. The old people on the street will wave their hands and say to passers-by, &quot;Go to Nanmen Street, it&#39;s beautiful there.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the Nanmen Street archway to Yucheng Station, it is an ancient city built in the style of a scenic spot, with black tiles and white walls. The rebuilt Qin Post Pavilion is also in this area. According to historical records, the history of Gaoyou began with the &quot;Public Post Pavilion&quot; in the Qin Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most modern building in the old city is the Wang Zengqi Memorial Hall. It looks like seven irregularly arranged thick books and is surrounded by narrow alleys densely packed with bungalows. Opposite the memorial hall, there is a &quot;Er Zi Cattail Meat&quot; shop. Two display boards indicate the inextricable relationship between the shop owner and Wang Zengqi - the grandson-in-law of the prototype of the character in Wang Zengqi&#39;s novel. But it is difficult to find the Gaoyou described by Wang Zengqi. The Zhenguo Temple was rebuilt on the river island where the Ximen Pagoda is located. Tianwang Temple and Chengtian Temple are no longer there. Naturally, there is no midnight bell ringing on the canal. The sound of the boat crossing is not a whistle. But it is a short and intensive motor sound. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s Gaoyou is far from being a small place with backward economy and famous only for its double-yellow duck eggs at Wang Zengqi&#39;s time. It has become a county-level city under the jurisdiction of Jiangsu Province and is managed by Yangzhou City. It is changing rapidly and changing with each passing day. Gaoyou has become a famous down clothing manufacturing city in China and a street lamp manufacturing base in China. It is famous throughout the country for many industries. Its GDP in 2022 will exceed 100 billion yuan, and industrial invoice sales will exceed 130 billion yuan. In the &quot;Research on China&#39;s Top 100 County Economies in 2023&quot; released by CCID, Gaoyou ranked 66th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new generation of Zhuhu people are as diligent, lively and tolerant as water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Sxovroi8pdRTXFDwZghj82sP592P3gwNzRuhiCgd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Sxovroi8pdRTXFDwZghj82sP592P3gwNzRuhiCgd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the garment workshop of a garment factory in Yangzhou, Jiangsu, employees are rushing to make down jackets for export&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Duck, duck down, new energy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the 1970s and 1980s, the textile and clothing industry in Gaoyou emerged, with township factories and family workshops blooming everywhere. In the impression of old Gaoyou people, Most people are making clothes. This is of course an exaggeration. Survey data since the 21st century shows that the number of employees in Gaoyou&#39;s textile and garment industry is around 40,000-60,000, accounting for nearly half of the city&#39;s industrial employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, Bosideng Chairman Gao Dekang once said that 70% of China&#39;s down clothing is processed and produced in Jiangsu, and 70% of Jiangsu&#39;s down clothing is processed and produced in Gaoyou. In the same year, Bosideng invested 450 million yuan to build an industrial park in Gaoyou Economic Development Zone, becoming the largest investment and largest construction project in Gaoyou at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, when He Qixin, a local entrepreneur from Gaoyou, proposed cooperation to Bosideng for the first time, Bosideng did not agree. Their focus was on establishing a wholly-owned production base. At that time, Yangzhou Salon Garment Co., Ltd., which was so new, was already the garment factory with the largest number of employees in Gaoyou, with more than 1,700 people. It manufactured for many well-known brands, including Bosideng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Why did Bosideng make a 180-degree turn after 8 years?” He Qixin later recalled in an interview with Yangzhou Evening News, “First, because of the quality of our products and the ability to deliver them on time. Ability, and more importantly, we have a large number of skilled garment workers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director of the Gaoyou Economic Development Zone Management Committee also attributed the diligence and dexterity of Gaoyou workers to one of the reasons, &quot;Bosideng was The factory in Huai&#39;an is larger than Gaoyou, but workers in Huai&#39;an can only process 5.5 down jackets a day, while workers in Gaoyou can process 8 pieces a day.&quot; But the director of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee believes that He Qi&#39;s new business vision is more important , &quot;Without He Qixin, there would be no Bosideng (in Gaoyou).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Qixin&#39;s entrepreneurial experience started with a village-run factory built with funds raised by village cadres, making simple clothing such as shorts and headgear, and undertaking the surplus work of other factories. of orders. Before that, he worked as a temporary worker in various factories for more than three years, such as knocking carbon blocks in the carbon instrument workshop of the fertilizer factory and working as a spray paint inspector in the electric fan factory. When he first entered the factory, He Qixin had just graduated from junior high school. He had to make a living early because of his poor family. When he was younger, he started raising ducks to support his family. Later, the duck down filling of down jackets often reminded He Qixin of his childhood as a &quot;Duck Commander&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years after setting up the factory, He Qixin found a new production direction. In the mid-1980s, gabardine Chinese tunic suits were popular. Although the cost of clothing materials was high and it was difficult to purchase, He Qixin did some calculations and felt that the profits were considerable. At that time, the price of gabardine was more than 10 yuan per meter of fabric, and a roll of fabric cost 450 meters. The factory needed to consume three or four rolls a week. Due to lack of money, He Qixin only bought three or four rolls of cloth at a time and had to restock every week. He traveled between Gaoyou, Zhenjiang, Suzhou, Wujiang, and Shengze, carrying heavy cloths alone. Relying on such resilience, He Qixin gradually grew the 80-person factory to a level that Bosideng could not ignore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first year of production in Gaoyou, Bosideng achieved sales of 300 million yuan, and in the second year it was 1 billion yuan... The director of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee thinks that what is new and valuable is that, &quot;In cooperating with Bosideng, he continues to improve his voice and keep up with the development of the industry.&quot; After the textile and clothing industry found it difficult to expand its scale, He Qixin began to deploy in new industries. In addition to the textile industry, He Qixin has also cooperated with Bosideng to invest in new materials, logistics, real estate, hotels and other industries in Gaoyou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the work report of the Gaoyou Municipal Government, the industrial advantages of textiles and clothing as the four basic industries were still emphasized until 2014. When looking back in 2015, the industrial achievements became &quot;continuous transformation.&quot; Gaoyou Economic and Technological Development Zone lists the optical storage and charging industry as a characteristic leading industry. In 2023, He Qixin integrated its subsidiaries to establish Xinlinfei Group. The total investment in the optical storage and charging industry exceeds more than 20 billion, accounting for the largest share of Gaoyou Economic and Technological Development Zone. half of the district. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The entrepreneurs led by He Qixin have promoted the development process of the entire Economic Development Zone. The director of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee concluded: &quot;It is because of such a group of entrepreneurs in our park that we dare to do things and dare to try. , the park develops faster.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/XbogCvFM6Gx5mTWo6W5a7Amo8Ob5pE8IZMyu14eK.jpg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/XbogCvFM6Gx5mTWo6W5a7Amo8Ob5pE8IZMyu14eK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254441&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Workers work in the intelligent workshop of a semiconductor manufacturing company in Gaoyou Economic Development Zone&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Qianyi Park&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Gaoyou Economic Development Zone is a provincial development zone established in November 1993. The initial planned area was 6.43 square meters Kilometers, 30 years later, the total area of ​​the park today is 101 square kilometers, with an average annual GDP growth rate of 32%. In 2022, GDP growth will be close to 20.5 billion yuan, and industrial invoices will be 55.6 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gaoyou Economic Development Zone, which started from farmland, has no obvious geographical and resource advantages, making it difficult to attract foreign capital through investment promotion. The director of the Economic and Technological Development Zone Management Committee said, “The time when other regions will really invest here will be in 2019.” Before that, like Heqixin’s introduction of Bosideng, it was through joint ventures and cooperation between local companies and foreign companies. way to attract customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The local advantages are not obvious, so leading cadres began to find new ways to study the economic policies and situations of surrounding areas and build Gaoyou&#39;s location advantages. The director of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee recalled: &quot;In 2019, attracting enterprises from Shenzhen to invest was actually discussed around the strategic steps of the Yangtze River Delta region, not just the development zone. For electronic information companies in Shenzhen, the supporting radius is only Half an hour, and we had not yet started the entire industry, why do people come to you? So we talk about the Yangtze River Delta - a high-end cluster area for the electronic information industry. Nanjing has Jiangbei New District, Wuxi is an integrated circuit design center, and Shanghai has the most talents. Kunshan and Suzhou are the earliest industrial bases - Gaoyou, right in the middle of the Yangtze River Delta.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to attracting investment in Gaoyou lies in the cadres&#39; cognition, &quot;Many companies that come to invest will I found that it would be more difficult to go to other places to socialize, but we are very professional here. We can help you with which end of the industry your product is in and which equipment you use is better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let The director of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee was most impressed by Sanfu Xinke, which settled in Gaoyou Economic Development Zone in 2023. Originally, this company had its eye on another economic development zone in Jiangsu, but after visiting Gaoyou and communicating with city leaders, it finally Gaoyou was chosen. &quot;They are engaged in surface treatment technology. After arriving, we found that we could not only communicate with them about the industry, but also put forward countermeasures for problems that may be involved in the entire production process.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;May 2023 , Gaoyou Economic and Technological Development Zone has completed its annual investment promotion tasks, and the next big goal is to achieve a RMB 100 billion park in 2025. In addition to introducing new enterprises, the management committee&#39;s focus is to serve existing enterprises well. Every Monday morning, the management committee holds a regular weekly meeting to discuss how to help enterprises solve problems. &quot;There are three biggest pain points for enterprises: the first is funding issues, the second is employment issues, and the third is market issues.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;New strategies were released for these three issues at the weekly meeting in September. The park guarantee studio solves the problem of mutual guarantee loans between enterprises, and the government can provide credit guarantees for loans within 5 million; establishes a central kitchen and talent apartments to improve the living conditions of enterprise employees; establishes an integrated development platform to integrate the services of enterprises in the zone Products, recommendations and connections between upstream and downstream. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes the strategy is very detailed. A decision passed at the weekly meeting on September 18 was to help companies delay paying import duties on equipment. The director of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee explained: &quot;Imported equipment has a 13% value-added tax. Tens of millions of units of equipment will have to pay millions of tariffs at a time. Our supply chain finance company will help pay it first, and then the money will be transferred back from the subsidy. Extend the payment cycle and reduce the financial pressure on enterprises.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to pay attention to each enterprise, the Management Committee divided all enterprises into 21 grids, and each grid was divided into 21 grids by the work of the Management Committee. Personnel serve as &quot;grid members&quot;. They must be familiar with the industrial chains they are responsible for and regularly conduct economic analysis for the enterprise. &quot;What are the advantages, what are the difficulties, and which direction should we work in the future?&quot; The director of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee asked all staff to work in the economic and technological development zone, and they should understand the economy. &quot;Even if some problems are not solved for the time being, We can find a solution, and the company can feel that we are paying attention and not ignoring it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to its original advantageous industries of textiles, clothing and metallurgical machinery, the Economic Development Zone has set its future development direction in light. storage and charging industry, electronic information and life and health industries, and actively negotiates cooperation with listed companies. Regarding the goal of the 100-billion-dollar park, the director of the Economic Development Zone Management Committee is very confident, &quot;Judging from the investments that have been signed so far, the goal of the 100-billion-dollar park in 2025 is achievable.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/34l6OhN1MS0xJUqHEuW4SvsPAPabaL7eZ0b2s4q2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/34l6OhN1MS0xJUqHEuW4SvsPAPabaL7eZ0b2s4q2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Workers are processing signal signs. Although modern factories have been established in the street lighting industry in the new district, the workmanship of small workshops still exists&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Nie Yangxin/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Growing street lamp factories&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Another major traditional industry in Gaoyou is the lighting industry, which is known as the &quot;Hometown of Street Lamps&quot;. Most of the factories are concentrated in Guoji Town, Sendong Qiao Town and Tianshan Town are now included in Gaoyou Huxi New District. In the new district, factories of all sizes can be seen everywhere. Chen Guoqing is the deputy secretary-general of the Gaoyou Lighting Association. According to him, there are currently about 1,000 lighting companies in Huxi New District, with fixed sites. There are about 500 slightly larger ones. Home, a popular slogan here is &quot;Entrepreneurship for All&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The large number of lighting factories has created employment for 40,000 people. Chen Guoqing is a native of Guoji Town. His relatives and friends are all in this industry. They either work in factories or set up their own factories. The restaurants and other small shops offering daily life services are all run by outsiders. The annual income of an ordinary worker in a lighting factory can reach 100,000 yuan, but local housing prices are not high, more than 4,000 yuan per square meter, because many people choose to buy houses in Gaoyou urban area or Yangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Time goes back 40 years. Guoji is a well-known poor township. It is located to the west of Gaoyou Lake, surrounded by water on three sides. The terrain is low-lying and the transportation is very inconvenient. There is only one road to Yangzhou, to Gaoyou County. You have to take a boat. At that time, people&#39;s income depended on farming, but due to the low terrain, the fields would be flooded whenever it rained heavily. &quot;If the fields are flooded, there will be no food, and food and clothing cannot be guaranteed. Girls from neighboring towns are not willing to marry to Guo Ji,&quot; Chen Guoqing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because survival is difficult, people here will seize every possible opportunity. In 1976, Yao Peishan, secretary of the Pantang Brigade of Guoji Commune, heard about a man who secretly made ballasts (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;lamp accessories&lt;/span>;). A young man, Chen Jingchun, invited him to set up a factory. The start-up capital was the money earned by the production team from selling two pigs. Once the products were made, they were carried in sacks to find buyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Kl76Mo8nwDAHAnciicxDSLtsB8dXZ3lH8frtUOKs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/Kl76Mo8nwDAHAnciicxDSLtsB8dXZ3lH8frtUOKs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Howell Transportation’s simulation showroom&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Nie Yangxin/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Ji’s successful entrepreneurial story seems to have an element of luck. The first pot of gold that Chen Jingchun&#39;s village-run factory got came from the news he accidentally learned: A radio factory in Shandong that was on the verge of bankruptcy had thousands of ballasts to be processed. Chen Jingchun bought them at a price of 5 yuan each. After inspection and After packaging, they were sold for 16 yuan each, making a total profit of 30,000 to 40,000 yuan. Using this money as a basis, the factory gradually developed other products such as light poles, lamps, and light sources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Jingchun&#39;s factory continued to grow and trained a large number of production staff and salespeople. In the 1980s and 1990s, all local farmers, bricklayers, and workers wanted to do sales. Zhao Jinyin, the founder of Noel Lighting, was a salesman. “Because of the lack of information, people who go out basically gain something, and it is possible to pass a Orders amount to 10,000 yuan per household.&quot; After the restructuring of state-owned enterprises, these people became the mainstream of independent factories. In Gaoyou, a city with highly concentrated industries and specialized factories for each subdivision, it is not difficult to set up a factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Zhao Jinyin left school in 2002, he began to run out, holding one or two pages of paper to sell to people. &quot;There is no strong purpose, and I don’t know where to go.&quot; His first big order was also based on As luck would have it, I randomly got on a bus heading to Wuhan. After entering Hubei, I found that there were no street lights in a county I was passing through, so I got out of the car and approached the road administration bureau. The two parties hit it off immediately. In less than ten years, Zhao Jinyin saved a fortune and founded Noer Lighting in 2011. It took another ten years to expand the factory from a dozen acres to the current 100 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The outdoor lighting fixtures in Huxi New District account for 40% of the national market, and light poles account for 70%. Most factories still produce ordinary lighting products with low thresholds. Larger companies like Knoll Lighting have begun to upgrade equipment and transform into &quot;multi-pole-in-one&quot; smart street lights that are supporting transportation. &quot;The main reason is that the price competition of traditional street lights is fierce and the involution is serious.&quot; In the era of accessible information, Large manufacturers may not have an advantage in a price war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, talents and funds restrict the industrial upgrading of Gaoyou lamps. &quot;We are basically in rural areas. It is difficult to recruit outstanding college students. Even if the salary level is high, they may not want to come.&quot; Zhao Jinyin said, Noel The current smart street lighting team relies on hiring and cultivating internal talents with high salaries. Howell Transportation directly set up its R&amp;D team in Jiangbei New District, Nanjing. Chairman Hao Binghe thought about leaving Gaoyou, but quickly gave up the idea, &quot;The industrial chain is here, the reputation is here, and only here can we develop well.&quot; ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about transformation in Huxi New District, the bosses of many companies recommended Hao Binghe of Haowei. &quot;I am a technical person, and I have lived in an atmosphere where everyone is determined to make progress since I was a child.&quot; Hao Binghe is from Guoji. He said, &quot;Innovation is very painful, and the losses caused by unsuccessful research and development are very scary. In the first two years, Because there was a problem with the investment direction, tens of millions were lost. Innovation cannot be immediate, otherwise everyone would innovate.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The risk of transformation makes Knoll and Howell tend to cooperate with state-owned enterprises, but local Lamp companies have never thought about cooperating with each other. Hao Binghe believes that the manager system is unrealistic. &quot;We all work alone here. Our structure is not that good. When you reach a certain age, it will definitely be passed on to the family.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;The lighting industry, which originated from Chen Jingchun, is like a tree that continuously branches and grows from a single trunk. The branches are dense but independent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WQFt4sfbUNb3e26RItq51IEmqpfagApUfOlkVgoo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/WQFt4sfbUNb3e26RItq51IEmqpfagApUfOlkVgoo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254447&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the historical and cultural district beside the canal, the houses here will not be demolished, but most residents have built rural self-built houses&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Nie Yangxin/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the Gaoyou Economic Development Zone is a joint effort between the government and enterprises to move toward scale and intensification, Huxi New District is more of a support for small enterprises. The industrial chain is highly concentrated, and the two development trajectories present different industrial forms. In Gaoyou, a county with no advantage in natural resources, no special policy support, and little foreign capital, both models have opened up a vital path from spontaneous growth to outward progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the top 100 counties, Gaoyou is not particularly eye-catching, but if we take double yellow duck eggs as the starting point, the history of Gaoyou industry is a revelation of the rise of industry in ordinary counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从0到1，“一带一路”倡议下中国社会组织的国际化之路]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259096]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-22 19:59:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In October 2023, the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum was held in Beijing, which is also a commemoration of Special event for the 10th anniversary of the Belt and Road Initiative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The “One Belt, One Road” initiative is not just business exchanges, but also emphasizes cultural exchanges and people-to-people connections, which opens a window for Chinese social organizations to “go global”. In March 2015, the &quot;Vision and Actions on Promoting the Joint Construction of the Silk Road Economic Belt and the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot; issued by the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, and the Ministry of Commerce with the authorization of the State Council pointed out that people-to-people bonds are the key to the construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; It is necessary to strengthen exchanges and cooperation among non-governmental organizations in countries along the route, focusing on grassroots people, and extensively carry out various charity activities such as education and medical care, poverty reduction and development, biodiversity and ecological environmental protection, so as to promote the improvement of production and living conditions in poverty-stricken areas along the route. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, the General Office of the Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Notice on Promoting the Participation of Social Organizations in the Activities of International Non-Governmental Organizations&quot; and &quot;Opinions on Further Strengthening the Training and Promotion of Talents for International Organizations&quot;, actively advocating the participation of social organizations. International exchanges and strengthening international talent cultivation. In 2016, the &quot;Opinions on Reforming the Management System of Social Organizations to Promote the Healthy and Orderly Development of Social Organizations&quot; was released, further encouraging social organizations to &quot;carry out external exchanges in an orderly manner&quot; and &quot;give full play to the important platform role of social organizations in non-governmental external exchanges.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first “Belt and Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum in 2017 officially launched the “Chinese Social Organizations Action Plan to Promote People-to-People Connectivity along the Belt and Road (2017-2020)” and the cooperation network of civil society organizations along the Silk Road. More than 160 Chinese and foreign non-governmental organizations have joined the cooperation network, and more than 90 Chinese organizations have joined the action plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many organizations stated that the “One Belt, One Road” initiative has a significant impact on their internationalization journey. &quot;In the past, social organizations carried out international business independently based on their own business development. Now there are policies to clearly support and encourage going global. This difference is still very big.&quot; Secretary-General of China Rural Development Foundation (formerly China Poverty Alleviation and Development Foundation) Chen Hongtao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from the Ministry of Civil Affairs, my country currently has 51 registered international social organizations; since 2013, relevant work has been further accelerated, with a total of 24 international social organizations registered, accounting for 47% of the total. Chinese social organizations are not only going global, but also increasingly participating in the international governance system. In 2015, Professor Deng Guosheng of the School of Public Policy and Management at Tsinghua University conducted research on the “going global” strategy of Chinese social organizations. At that time, there were &lt;span>;48&lt;/span>; social organizations in China (including Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan) that had consultative status with the United Nations Economic and Social Council. This number has now grown to 103. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Sail to the sea&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Chinese social organizations &quot;go global&quot;, and the China Rural Development Foundation can be regarded as one of the &quot;first batch of institutions to eat crabs&quot;. The China Rural Development Foundation carried out de-administrative reforms in the late 1990s. In 2005, it began to explore international development. In 2007, it proposed an internationalization strategy for institutional development and began to go abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Our internationalization can basically be divided into three stages: internationalization without going abroad, internationalization on a business trip, and resident internationalization.” Chen Hongtao introduced that internationalization without going abroad, For example, if you participated in international actions or international assistance before 2009, you would mainly donate money and materials through cooperation with other international organizations. In 2009, the International Development Department was established, with a dedicated team to carry out special projects. At this time, the domestic team was mainly responsible for traveling overseas to implement. In 2015, the China Rural Development Foundation officially registered and established offices in Myanmar and Nepal, marking the transformation from a local social organization in China to an international public welfare organization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the China Rural Development Foundation has 3 country offices and is carrying out projects in 7 other countries in a relatively stable and sustainable manner. Internationalization is written into the organization&#39;s vision, &quot;to build an international public welfare platform that is more trustworthy, more worthy of expectation, and more worthy of respect.&quot; &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; has also been included in the organization&#39;s charter, &quot;responding to the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; initiative and participating in international poverty reduction cooperation.&quot; and humanitarian aid”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Amity Foundation, established in 1985, has been active in the field of international exchange and development. From &quot;bringing in&quot;, such as introducing foreign teachers and introducing advanced concepts in the field of international development, to &quot;going out&quot; in 2009 and launching a series of international projects. From 2015 to 2019, the Amity Foundation successively set up African offices, international offices and Kenya offices in Ethiopia, Geneva, Switzerland, and Nairobi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the early institutions that were trying to cross the river by feeling their way through the river to explore “going out”, the pace of Chinese social organizations’ “going out” has accelerated since the “One Belt, One Road” initiative was proposed. The Red Cross Foundation of China closely follows the overall requirements of the country&#39;s &quot;Belt and Road&quot; construction and in accordance with the foreign aid work deployment of the Red Cross Society of China, and established the &quot;Silk Road Fraternity Fund&quot; in 2017. This fund is a &quot;Belt and Road&quot; public welfare fund, covering China&#39;s international humanitarian aid, state-supported private foreign aid, Chinese enterprises&#39; &quot;going global strategy&quot;, international volunteer services, etc. Relying on the partners of the International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement around the world, after the establishment of the special fund, the Chinese Red Cross Foundation quickly established an international working network to carry out projects along the “Belt and Road”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The “One Belt, One Road” initiative has also inspired more organizations that have been focusing on global issues since their establishment. The Beijing Pinglan Charity Foundation was established in April 2018. Since its establishment, it has actively participated in responding to domestic and foreign humanitarian crises, environmental crises and other emergencies. In 2019, the Beijing Pinglan Charity Foundation conducted preliminary research on the situation of Syrian refugees in Lebanon, set up a local office, and sent a working group to carry out humanitarian assistance work. &lt;span>;In 2021&lt;/span>; the Beijing Pinglan Charity Foundation’s Geneva office was established, with staff stationed there to carry out international exchanges and cooperation in the fields of humanitarian assistance and environmental protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Promoting &quot;people-to-people connectivity&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Chinese social organizations face far more complex situations and more severe tests than at home. However, as the world&#39;s No. 1 China, the two largest economies, is both a developing country, and its governance experience seems to be more &quot;resonant&quot; with that of less developed countries. &quot;Compared with Western developed countries, China&#39;s social organizations&#39; going global still has our own characteristics. &quot;Professor Huang Haoming, Executive Director of the Hainan Asia Philanthropy Research Institute and Honorary Chairman of the China Association for the Promotion of International Non-Governmental Organization Cooperation, introduced. One of these characteristics is reflected in our culture of gratitude. &quot;In the past, China was more of a recipient of foreign aid. Now we As we develop, we begin to go out and help other countries. As Mozi said, &#39;love universally&#39; and &#39;not attack&#39;, and go out in a peaceful way. &quot;The second is the awareness of equality and respect. &quot;Because we ourselves are also developing countries, when we go to other less developed countries, we are not condescending or asking them to listen to us, but more of equality and respect. &quot;The third is to focus on problem-oriented and results-oriented. &quot;Our non-mechanical transportation when going abroad is more based on the needs of the recipient countries, such as solving the problem of children&#39;s schooling and cataract surgery, which are all real solutions to the urgent needs in people&#39;s lives. problem. &quot;As a result, the poverty reduction experience and brand projects that have achieved good results in China have gradually formed international influence overseas.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Love Package Project, launched in 2009, is the largest domestic project of the China Rural Development Foundation. One of the most popular and influential projects. The project builds a public welfare platform and distributes packages to children in underdeveloped areas to provide one-on-one care and inspire children&#39;s childhood dreams. From the launch of the project to the end of 2022, the Love Package Project A total of 869 million yuan of social donations have been received in China, benefiting nearly 8 million students in 31 provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) across the country.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to the “Belt and Road” initiative, in February 2019 The China Rural Development Foundation and Alibaba Philanthropy jointly launched the Panda&amp;nbsp;Pack&amp;nbsp;Project, which brought the PandaPack Project from China to countries along the “Belt and Road”. As of the end of 2022, the international PandaPack Project has raised more than 139 million yuan, benefiting 14 countries including Myanmar, Nepal, Ethiopia, Cambodia, Laos, Pakistan, Namibia, Uganda, Mongolia, Philippines, Zimbabwe, South Sudan, Burundi, Chad, etc., with more than 1.184 million beneficiaries. International Love Package The project has also become one of the largest overseas public welfare projects implemented by Chinese social organizations, and has become a representative of the people-to-people bonds of the &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&quot;. The project won the Best Reduction Award in the &quot;Second Global Poverty Reduction Case Collection&quot; awarded by the United Nations system in 2021. &quot;Poverty Cases&quot;.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2017, the Red Cross Foundation of China, relying on the Silk Road Philanthropy Fund, has also begun to optimize the supply of humanitarian services in countries along the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and provide humanitarian assistance to people in urgent humanitarian needs along the routes. As of the end of June 2023, a total of nearly 70 million yuan has been invested to fund international humanitarian assistance projects in 26 countries in Asia and Africa. The funding areas include medical assistance, health intervention, community development, relief and disaster relief, volunteer services, etc. The number of beneficiaries 62,669 people. Among them, the international free lunch project has benefited 7,197 students in 6 countries: Kenya, Uganda, Malawi, Nigeria, Tanzania and Ethiopia, helped 1,105 children return to school, and created employment for hundreds of African women. Nemy Matinde, one of the students who was once aided, returned to a community school to become a teacher after graduating from university. He said: &quot;Chinese public welfare organizations helped me, so I also want to use my own power to help more children here, so that They have access to education. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of global biodiversity and ecological environmental protection, more and more Chinese organizations are gradually practicing. The Global Environmental Institute (GEI), founded in 2004, is one of the strongest in the country. , a large-scale grassroots environmental non-governmental organization, committed to using market mechanisms and policy suggestions to solve environmental problems. Since its establishment, GEI has focused on promoting international cooperation on environment, energy and other issues from a local perspective, especially South-South cooperation. As early as In 2005, GEI brought China&#39;s mature and reliable biogas technology to Sri Lanka and to Laos five years later. GEI has been carrying out projects in the fields of biodiversity protection, global climate change, energy efficiency and other fields for many years. In 2011, all projects were completed &quot;Going Global&quot;. From 2012 to 2019, its projects have covered Myanmar, Mongolia, Laos, Vietnam, Cambodia, Indonesia, Ghana, Cameroon, the Republic of Congo and many other countries.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Walk on a tightrope. OK&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;The “Belt and Road” initiative has led more Chinese social organizations to go global, but this decade is only the first step. Professor Huang Haoming said that Chinese social organizations still have to go global. Faced with many challenges, the legal basis is insufficient from a macro perspective and policy support is relatively lagging behind.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the “Belt and Road” initiative was proposed in 2013, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council successively issued a series of opinions and notices to encourage social organizations to participate in international Non-governmental organization activities and international exchanges. The promulgation of the Charity Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China in 2016 ushered in the era of &quot;good&quot; governance in accordance with the law. There are some provisions related to overseas donations, but there are no provisions related to the &quot;going global&quot; of charitable public welfare organizations. In the same year, the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on the Administration of Activities of Overseas Non-Governmental Organizations in the Territory&quot; was passed and implemented, regulating and guiding the exchanges and cooperation of overseas non-governmental organizations in China. There are laws to follow for overseas non-governmental organizations to carry out activities in China, and Chinese non-governmental organizations Organizations have gone global but are still wandering in the legal void.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2023, the National People’s Congress website of China announced the Charity Law &lt;span>;(&lt;/span>;Revised Draft&lt;span>;)&lt;/span>;, facing the society The public is soliciting opinions. An article has been added to the revised draft: “The state encourages international charitable exchanges. Charitable organizations that accept overseas charitable donations or cooperate with overseas organizations or individuals to carry out charitable activities must go through approval or filing procedures in accordance with relevant national regulations. &quot;Although international exchange terms have been added, there are no specific provisions on international cooperation and overseas project development.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Funding is another major factor that restricts Chinese public welfare organizations from going global. Take the China Rural Development Foundation as an example For example, in 2022, the total donation income will be 1.159 billion yuan, and international projects will be 31.0095 million yuan, accounting for less than 3%. International project funds come from the public, enterprises, foundations and government departments, of which public donations account for the bulk, accounting for 70%, and others Foundations and enterprises each account for 10%. Government donations include grants from Chinese embassies and consulates abroad and grants from the Global Development and South-South Cooperation Fund, accounting for only about &lt;span>;5%&lt;/span>;.&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; Judging from the experience of other countries, when international non-governmental organizations carry out projects overseas, government overseas aid funds are an important source. &quot;Compared with other countries, our government&#39;s purchase funds for social organizations are still relatively small,&quot; Professor Huang Haoming said, “For example, about 20% of the U.S.’s annual foreign aid funds are implemented through their non-governmental organizations, which is a huge amount. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2021, the China International Development Cooperation Agency, the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, and the Ministry of Commerce issued the &quot;Foreign Aid Management Measures&quot;, which pointed out that South-South Cooperation Assistance Fund projects should be carried out, that is, using the South-South Cooperation Assistance Fund to support Projects implemented by international organizations, social organizations, think tanks, etc. This sends a positive signal for the government to implement foreign aid through social organizations, but it is only the beginning.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talent is also a challenge for Chinese social organizations to go global. A 2021 study on &quot;Chinese Social Organizations&#39; Participation in the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; Construction&quot; conducted by Yang Li, Director of the International NGO and Foundation Research Center of Beijing Normal University, showed that social organizations generally lack talents with rich foreign-related work experience. 124 companies participated in the survey Institutions, 50% of institutions have no relevant foreign-related talents, and less than 13% of institutions have 7 or more foreign-related talents.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Professor Huang Haoming’s view, international talents are not only foreign language skills, but also more important It is comprehensive quality. There are four key and difficult points, one is to have an international vision, the other is to understand international rules, the third is to have the ability to resist risks, and the fourth is to have strong negotiation skills. &quot;When carrying out projects overseas, you need to deal with local people. , the working environment is also full of uncertainty and requires strong adaptability. &quot; Professor Huang Haoming said.&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Steady the first step and help peers take the first step&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Earlier, the China Rural Development Foundation &quot;went global&quot; &quot;We encountered various challenges and problems. For example, when we were working as the first hospital in Sudan, there was a problem with customs clearance of materials, which ultimately resulted in demurrage fees. Later, looking back, the reason was mainly because we were not familiar with the customs, laws and regulations of the other country. . Accordingly, with the funding of the Asia Foundation, the China Rural Development Foundation compiled an &quot;Operation Manual for Chinese Non-Governmental Organizations Going Global&quot; to share the key points of going global with other organizations to help them go global more smoothly. At the same time, the China Rural Development Foundation actively organizes and participates in various &quot;going global&quot; activities, such as the Chinese Social Organizations Going Abroad Symposium, the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; Chinese Enterprises Overseas Philanthropy Road Seminar, the China-Egypt Non-Governmental Organization Webinar, and the China Rural Development Foundation. non-forums, etc., to share the challenges and experiences of going global and build a collaborative network.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As China’s first non-governmental organization in the environmental field to “go global” to carry out overseas projects, the Global Environment Institute (GEI), at the Ford Foundation In 2016, with the funding of &quot;Going Global&quot;, the experience, challenges and thinking of &quot;Going Global&quot; were also researched, and the report &quot;Chinese Non-Governmental Organizations &quot;Going Global&quot;: Current Situation, Challenges and Policy Recommendations&quot; was released, which focused on the relationship between Chinese and foreign non-governmental organizations and the government, Case references for enterprises to carry out cooperation projects provide reference for peers. Then, in 2017, GEI joined hands with experts from different fields to hold a &quot;Going Global&quot; symposium for Chinese non-governmental organizations to discuss and share experiences in participating in international affairs.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In May 2021, Amity Foundation Secretary-General Ling Chunxiang was successfully elected as a director of the International Confederation of Voluntary Agencies (ICVA). This marks that Amity has further accumulated experience in deeply participating in international governance. To this end, Amity actively cooperates with the International Relations of Renmin University of China Associate Professor Xu Ying of the college co-wrote the article &quot;Seizing International Political Opportunities - The Path of Internationalization of Chinese Social Organizations&quot;, introducing Amity&#39;s participation in the United Nations humanitarian aid system by joining ICVA and its significance to the internationalization of Chinese social organizations. Other peers provide reference.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everything is still in its infancy, and mutual help and teamwork are particularly important. Chen Hongtao, Secretary-General of the China Rural Development Foundation, said: &quot;Although the international construction of the China Rural Development Foundation is currently Some progress and results have been achieved, but compared with some mature international institutions, there is a relatively large gap in the number of countries covered overseas, project scale, team capabilities, international influence, etc. In the future, we hope to strengthen learning and exchanges , while linking more social forces and joining hands with more social organizations to go global. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to large institutions that have explored internationalization earlier, Professor Huang Haoming has also observed in recent years that some local institutions have begun to take the first step. Their exploration may provide reference for other places and even the country. “Yunnan takes advantage of its border, and the Yunnan Provincial Foreign Affairs Office, Yunnan Provincial Department of Commerce, Yunnan Provincial Promotion Association and other departments and social organizations have collaborated to form a very good communication mechanism. This is rare in the country. &quot;Professor Huang Haoming said, &quot;When talking about &#39;going out&#39; in the past, most people talked about institutions in Beijing. In recent years, institutions such as Shenzhen International Exchange and Cooperation Foundation, Shanghai Fosun Foundation, Sichuan Haihui Poverty Alleviation Center, Tibet Charity Yuan Foundation, Zhejiang Gongyang Association, etc. are also doing very distinctive things. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The “14th Five-Year Plan for the Development of Social Organizations” issued by the Ministry of Civil Affairs in 2021 pointed out that it is necessary to steadily implement the “going out” of social organizations, carry out overseas cooperation in an orderly manner, and enhance the participation of our country’s social organizations in global governance. ability to improve the influence of Chinese culture and China&#39;s &quot;soft power.&quot; The word &quot;stable&quot; may be the current attitude of China&#39;s public welfare institutions in &quot;going out&quot;. Only by stabilizing the first step can we take a more stable step in the future. next step.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[演唱会吸金能力超越黄金周，“周杰伦”经济能拯救地方文旅吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259080]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“小便事件”冲击青岛啤酒？全链条管控能力或存疏漏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259088]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;How much impact will a video of more than ten seconds have on a 100-billion-dollar listed company? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many investors in Tsingtao Beer (600600.SH) have been worried about this throughout the weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A video posted online showed a male employee wearing blue overalls and a safety helmet digging into a suspected raw material warehouse to urinate. The video said it happened at Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 Factory. After the market closed on October 20, this video was widely circulated on the Internet and became a hot search topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Market Supervision and Administration Bureau of Pingdu City, where Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 is located, confirmed to the 21st Century Business Herald reporter that the malt involved has been sealed and the investigation of the incident is still ongoing. A person from Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 responded to a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald that the incident in the online video was not in the warehouse of No. 3 Beer, and the person involved was not an employee of No. 3 Beer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This statement has not been officially confirmed by Tsingtao Beer. A reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald noticed that the clothes of the person involved in the online video were similar to the work clothes of Tsingtao Brewery No. 3. Regarding the progress of the investigation of the incident, a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald contacted the Tsingtao Brewery Board Secretary Office several times over the weekend, but was unable to get through as of press time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Food safety is a top priority in the beverage industry. Domestic beer giants have rarely encountered such major public opinion in recent years. Many investors have questioned on platforms such as Stock Bar: How can the production safety control capabilities of large wine companies be weak? Could this be some kind of business war &quot;script&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The final investigation results will lead to different directions. If it is confirmed that the incident is related to the Tsingtao Brewery factory or employees, it means that there are major problems with the internal control system of this century-old beer giant. If it is confirmed that the incident was committed by a third-party supplier and did not occur within the Tsingtao Brewery factory, Tsingtao Brewery&#39;s responsibility will be relatively reduced, but it will still expose its omissions in the entire chain of supplier control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coinciding with the weakening growth momentum of domestic beer since the third quarter, Tsingtao Beer’s stock price has continued to fall recently. How to characterize this incident and how to deal with it later will test the wisdom of the parties involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pingdu Municipal Supervision Bureau: The malt involved has been sealed&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 said: It is not in the warehouse and is not a Tsingtao Brewery employee&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the video, The urination incident occurred at Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 Factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 is located in Pingdu City, a subsidiary of Qingdao City, more than 100 kilometers away from Qingdao City. It was formerly known as Beihai Brewery. It was founded in 1986 and had a production capacity of less than 10,000 when it was built. However, after years of capacity transformation, especially in recent years, the scale has continued to increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An article on Tsingtao Beer’s official WeChat ID earlier this year mentioned: In the past five years, Tsingtao Beer Plant No. 3 has undergone multiple upgrades, with annual production capacity jumping from 750,000 kiloliters in 2018 to 2022. 1.2 million kiloliters, making it a world-class factory. Not only that, Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 is also the leader of Tsingtao Beer Intelligent Industrial Park, which gathers 11 industrial chain supporting enterprises and is the largest clustered, intelligent, garden-style industrial park in the global industrial chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do such very elementary production safety incidents occur in a world-class factory? Some investors pointed out that in a factory of this size, the bathroom must be standard and not far from the workplace. Why would employees go to all the trouble to go into the raw material warehouse to urinate, and even be caught on video? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 22, a person from the Third Tsingtao Brewery Factory responded to a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald that the video of an employee urinating online was not at the raw material warehouse of the Third Factory, and the person involved was not an employee of Tsingtao Brewery. , the specific circumstances of the incident are still under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald contacted the Pingdu Municipal Market Supervision Bureau on October 21. A person from the Pingdu Municipal Supervision Bureau told the reporter that it was certain that the malt involved had been sealed, but the specifics of the incident The results of the investigation are yet to be officially announced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People from the Municipal Supervision Bureau did not respond to whether the incident was committed by employees of Tsingtao Brewery No. 3. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;21st Century Business Herald compared the photos on the official account of Tsingtao Brewery Plant 3 and noticed that the work clothes of employees at Tsingtao Brewery Plant 3 are dark blue, with yellow hats, and there are light-colored striped designs on the back of the work clothes, which is consistent with The people involved in the video posted online were wearing similar clothes. However, due to insufficient clarity, it is difficult to determine whether the person involved in the video was wearing work clothes from Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 Factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/981cc1a404f50dd891c7f657a05c0533.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height= &quot;635&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/981cc1a404f50dd891c7f657a05c0533.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254839&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/401a211480df23b912e12a6b4096f4fd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;671&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/401a211480df23b912e12a6b4096f4fd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254840&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;(Comparison of the work clothes of Tsingtao Beer Factory No. 3 and the clothing of the person involved in the online video)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tsingtao Beer officials issued a situation statement on the evening of October 20: In response to the Tsingtao Beer Factory No. 3 that appeared online on October 19 Our company attaches great importance to the relevant video and immediately reported it to the public security organs, who have intervened in the investigation. At present, this batch of malt has been completely sealed. Our company continues to increase management efforts to ensure product quality, and welcomes consumer supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 produces main brand products&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Consumption intention will be affected in the short term&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What netizens are worried about is: has similar incidents happened before? Budweiser has twice made false alarms due to similar news. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2017, a video of female workers manually pouring Budweiser beer was widely circulated. &amp;nbsp;After Budweiser reported the case, an investigation found that the video was fake wine made from recycled Budweiser beer cans from a domestic copycat brewery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2020, news circulated on the domestic Internet that &quot;an employee of Budweiser beer has peed in it for many years.&quot; It was later discovered that the news was &quot;fake news&quot; from an external spoof website. Budweiser quickly refuted the rumors on its domestic platform, saying that the rumors were &quot;malicious slander of the company&#39;s products&quot; and &quot;this matter is purely fabricated.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have strict production procedures. After the malt enters our production line, it will go through various processes such as cleaning, sterilization, disinfection, and fermentation. Consumers should rest assured.” The aforementioned person from the third Tsingtao Brewery Factory said 21st Century Business Herald reporter emphasized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some industry insiders also told reporters that malt is generally cleaned to remove impurities before brewing, and industrial canned beer is also sterilized, which will most likely not affect the drinking safety of the beer. However, there are also draft beer products on the market that are not sterilized and only fermented at low temperatures. The purpose is to retain more flavor. Such products are difficult to preserve and have a short shelf life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is widely circulated on the Internet that Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 mainly produces non-Tsingtao beer brands such as Guoli and Red Snow Dragon. They are not major brands on the market. Most locals in Qingdao do not drink them and they mainly sell them to other places. , some of which brands have been discontinued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald learned that Tsingtao Brewery No. 3 also produces main brand products such as Classic 1903. Classic 1903 is one of the representative products of Tsingtao Beer’s product upgrade in recent years. It has a shelf life of 365 days and theoretically also requires sterilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the overwhelming news will still have an impact on some consumers&#39; willingness to consume. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald noticed that a netizen posted a post saying that he habitually purchased an extra box of Tsingtao beer, but after thinking of the news, he finally chose to delete it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some consumers asked the customer service of Tsingtao Beer flagship store whether the products come from the third factory? Customer service responded that it was not clear which factory the product came from. Since the product is shipped randomly from the warehouse, it cannot be designated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of press time on the afternoon of the 22nd, Tsingtao Brewery and the Pingdu Municipal Supervision Bureau have not disclosed the results of their investigation into the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If it is finally confirmed that he is an employee of Tsingtao Beer or that the incident occurred in a Tsingtao Beer factory, it means that Tsingtao Beer’s internal control system will face torture. If the incident is confirmed to be the behavior of a third party, Tsingtao Beer&#39;s responsibility can be reduced, but there are still omissions in Tsingtao Beer&#39;s full-chain production control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the incident is true, then this incident is a very low-level mistake. As a listed company and the oldest leading beer company in China, Tsingtao Beer reflects the internal management and quality control of Tsingtao Beer The lack of the system will definitely have some impact on the entire image of Tsingtao Beer and its performance in the capital market.&quot; Zhu Danpeng, vice president of the Guangdong Provincial Food Safety Promotion Association, told the 21st Century Business Herald reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The third quarter performance is the focus&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As the relevant video was widely circulated after the market closed on October 20, Tsingtao Beer’s stock price was not affected and closed with a slight increase on the 20th. official. Investors are watching how the market will react after the market opens on Monday, the 23rd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with this unexpected incident, the impact of the recent weakening of beer consumption sentiment on major beer stocks deserves more attention from investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After offline opening this year, the beer industry ushered in a year of recovery. The beer output of designated enterprises across the country increased by 7% year-on-year in the first half of the year, especially in March and April, based on a low base in the same period last year, the year-on-year growth was as high as 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the industry leaders, Tsingtao Beer has enjoyed the dividends of recovery. In the first half of this year, Tsingtao Brewery achieved operating income of 21.59 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 12%; net profit attributable to shareholders of listed companies was 3.43 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 20.1%. Tsingtao Beer&#39;s stock price hit a record high in April, exceeding 123 yuan per share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, starting from June, the consumption enthusiasm in the beer market began to decline. First, in June, the beer production of designated enterprises across the country increased by only 1.6% year-on-year. In the summer of July and August, under the dual influence of heavy rains in the north and typhoons in the south, beer consumption during the peak season was not as expected. Coupled with the impact of the high base in the same period last year, The beer output of designated enterprises across the country has declined, with year-on-year declines of 3.4% and 5.8% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September, beer consumption became even weaker. According to data from the National Bureau of Statistics, the beer output of designated enterprises across the country in September was 2.866 million liters, a year-on-year decrease of 8%. The cumulative output in the first nine months was 29.933 million liters, a year-on-year increase of 2.1%. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tsingtao Beer’s stock price has been declining since April. As of last week, the stock price was as low as just over 80 yuan. It has fallen by more than 30% in less than half a year, which is a new low in the past year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tsingtao Beer will disclose its third quarter report on the evening of October 27. As of the close of trading on the 20th, Tsingtao Beer’s market value was approximately 110.6 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家烟草专卖局原党组书记、局长凌成兴被查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259102]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 10:09:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ling Chengxing, former Party Secretary and Director of the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration, is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently under investigation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection Disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the National Supervisory Commission. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“22万美元降至1美元”？美国防部长陷入降薪风波]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259090]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Austin has been in &quot;trouble&quot; recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It has been more than a thousand days since Austin took office as Defense Secretary on January 20, 2021. The Republican Party is quite dissatisfied with Austin&#39;s &quot;political performance&quot; so far, and recently even publicly proposed to reduce his annual salary from US$220,000 to US$1. The U.S. House of Representatives recently passed amendments to the relevant bill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Republican Representative Marjorie Taylor Greene, who proposed this amendment, said fiercely in the House of Representatives: &quot;Austin did not perform his job responsibilities. In fact, he is destroying our military.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is going on? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/52d93b7d33.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/22/52d93b7d33.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Republican Party is quite dissatisfied with Austin&#39;s &quot;political performance&quot; so far. (Yao Yijiang/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Annual salary&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;cut to US$1&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;As the top civilian military leader in the Biden administration, Austin came under fire from Republican lawmakers in the House. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 27, the U.S. House of Representatives voted to approve an amendment proposed by Georgia Representative Marjorie Taylor Greene to replace Defense Secretary Austin’s Annual salary cut to $1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Secretary Austin botched the U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan, resulting in the deaths of thirteen U.S. soldiers while abandoning U.S. civilians and military equipment.&quot; Green on social media上写道，“在奥斯汀任职期间，没有招募新兵，而是集中精力通过所谓的权力来清洗军队。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据众议院规则委员会的说法，格林在修正案中表示，她使用了霍尔曼规则，该规则“允许修改拨款立法，以减少特定联邦雇员的工资或解雇特定联邦雇员，或削减特定计划”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;议员们以口头投票方式通过了她的修正案，民主党人没有要求进行唱名投票，因为他们预计减薪措施将失败，因为民主党控制了参议院，而且民主党人反对众议院共和党制定的国防预算法案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“共和党仅仅是借助一些问题和少数士兵的死亡来打击拜登总统而已。”国际问题研究专家周圆曦向南方周末记者表示，征兵困难是美国的社会问题，不能完全责怪一个国防部长所发挥的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;奥斯汀是美国首位非裔防长，年薪超过221,000 美元。奥斯汀的养老金估计价值180万美元起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;即使奥斯汀降薪至1美元，对他的影响也“不太大”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;奥斯汀与拜登相识多年，深受后者信赖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;外界普遍认为，奥斯汀拥有“AB面”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A面，是当奥斯汀还是一个上校时，就被任命为第82空降师的指挥官。更因为出色的表现，奥斯汀的履历里出现了很多次“第一”。例如第一位非裔美国国防部防长；第一位非裔陆军副参谋长；第一位非裔中央司令部指挥官……&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;奥斯汀军事履历的中东色彩浓厚，曾任美国中央司令部司令。指挥美军撤离伊拉克和打击极端组织“伊斯兰国”，是奥斯汀职业生涯中的高光时刻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;拜登曾撰文强调，奥斯汀不仅有作为士兵的丰富经验、技巧和策略，还拥有外交能力。称奥斯汀是“经过考验的士兵和领导人”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“拜登并非将国防部长的能力作为首要考虑要素。”上海政法学院东北亚研究中心副主任杨震认为，而这往往为其处理内政外交事务“埋雷”。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;奥斯汀的“B面”，则被外界认为是共和党要求他降薪的“三宗罪”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“奥斯汀部长没有履行他的工作职责。事实上，他正在摧毁我们的军队。”格林批评奥斯汀，目前征兵人数处于“危机水平”，如果继续为乌克兰冲突提供援助，“这无疑将导致我们走向第三次世界大战”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“罪状”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前，征兵难是美军面临的“老大难”问题之一。征兵人数减少，自杀率上升，军队的凝聚力正在急剧下降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在国防部五个军种中，只有海军陆战队和太空军实现了2023财年的现役部队征兵目标，陆军、空军和海军等军种都没能达到目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;尽管美军方采取了许多创新方式，鼓励年轻人参军，包括陆军重新使用上世纪80年代的口号“尽你所能”，空军放宽此前的文身和药检政策，海军推出最高可达14万美元的创纪录的经济鼓励。但最终这三个军种还是没有实现征兵目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“美国在征兵、阿富汗撤军以及乌克兰的应对方面，都遇到了各种各样的难题和困境，这些难题和困境中，很大一部分空耗美国国力，也降低美国的国际威望。”杨震表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在征兵困难之际，美国陆军将裁减约3000人，即特种作战部队人数的约10%。包括在心理战、民政事务、情报人员、通信部队、后勤及其他辅助部门。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但奥斯汀尚未签署最终文件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;威斯康星州众议员德里克·范·奥登表示支持格林的修正案，指出现役军人和退伍军人的自杀率很高，并且在2021年从阿富汗撤军期间有13名士兵死亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;外界许多人认为，阿富汗撤军行动成为美国军事史上的“笑话”。美军的仓皇撤退，以及喀布尔机场的混乱场面，导致十三名美国军人在喀布尔的袭击中丧生。这场撤军，奥斯汀被舆论指责为未能妥善处理这一重大军事行动，导致美军陷入困境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“奥斯汀将数千名美国公民和盟友抛弃给阿富汗的恐怖分子，他对这件事情应该负有直接责任。”美军前海豹突击队员范奥登公开表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“美国当前面临的主要矛盾，即日趋上升的霸权护持成本与逐渐衰退的综合国力之间的矛盾。”杨震认为，“从这一点来说，奥斯汀缺乏该岗位所需要的政治智慧和战略眼光。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;值得关注的是，美众议院还指出，美国对乌克兰投入巨额的资金，却未能为国家带来实质性的战略利益。奥斯汀在这一问题上未能有效领导，让美国军事政策备受质疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自2022年2月俄罗斯对乌克兰发动冲突以来，拜登政府在国会的支持下，已向乌克兰提供了近750亿美元的援助，包括人道主义、经济和军事支持。但经过各种民意调查显示，美国国内越来越怀疑继续向乌克兰提供额外援助的必要性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;周圆曦则认为，奥斯汀执政以后，在援助乌克兰过程当中，组成了由54个国家组成的联盟，共同支援乌克兰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“枪打出头鸟”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一边是共和党人的弹劾，另一边是民主党人的力挺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“奥斯汀在帮助乌克兰和加强世界各地的防务伙伴关系方面，发挥了重要作用。”明尼苏达州民主党众议员贝蒂·麦科勒姆对奥斯汀的表现进行辩护并表示，民主党将共和党对奥斯汀的降薪提议视为“政治噱头”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;作为&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.militarytimes.com/news/pentagon-congress/2023/09/21/house-gop-plans-to-pass-defense-budget-fail-again-as-shutdown-looms/&quot;>;关于2024财年国防拨款法案&lt;/a>;辩论的一部分，共和党立法者批准了多项类似的提案，以削减他们不喜欢的国防部职位的工资。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不少受访专家学者告诉南方周末记者，由于该法案还必须通过民主党控制的参议院并由拜登签署，不太可能获得通过。但它标志着共和党对美国现任军事领导层的又一次谴责，也反映了美国党派分歧的加剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;周圆曦认为，给国防部长降薪，是共和党对拜登执政持反对意见的一种情绪表达。主要的目的是为了“恶心”拜登，为特朗普大选铺路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“这次众议院采取的就是剪除羽翼的战术。目标直指拜登，几乎挑明指责其用人不当。”杨震认为，众议院认为奥斯汀不能胜任工作，且摧毁美国武装力量也并非全然夸大其词，这才是拜登面临的最大问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年8月，民意调查机构美国盖洛普咨询公司的一项民调结果显示，民主党和共和党之间，意见不断分化，双方在大多数问题上都难以达成共识，美国政治分裂现象越来越严重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;周圆曦认为，美国共和党与民主党之间的斗争，通过找国防部长这样一个敏感职位的人的弱点，来打击拜登总统和民主党，实际上这是两党斗争的结果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月28日晚上，美国国会众议院就四项单独的拨款法案进行投票，四项拨款法案分别涉及国防、国土安全、农业、国务院和对外事务。其中涉及国防、国土安全以及国务院和对外事务的三项法案通过，涉及农业的法案被否决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;值得关注的是，此次预算案之争，不仅体现了民主党、共和党的长久矛盾，也让共和党内部“矛盾叠加”，局面复杂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“两党纷争已经没了底线。”杨震分析，在美国政坛上，两党纷争是主旋律，当前安全形势对美国来说并不乐观，反对党要求将国防部长降薪至1美元，其实是将党派利益凌驾于国家利益之上。 “这是非常危险的信号”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“对一些共和党人来说，所有的民主党人都是坏人，反之亦然。”美国知名社会学者托德·格兰德博士曾公开表示，“这是一种非常简单而且相当危险的看待世界的方式。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月3日，美国众议院就罢免共和党籍众议长麦卡锡的动议进行表决，结果以216票赞成、210票反对的微弱差距通过罢免麦卡锡的动议，这也标志着麦卡锡成为美国历史上首位被投票罢免的众议院议长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这场罢免事件，令美国舆论认为，两党的政治斗争会更加剧烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杨震则分析，此次事件为选民留下几个印象：一是拜登用人失察，其自身行使权力的能力值得怀疑；二是拜登政府的高官不能胜任其工作，这一届政府必须下台；三是美国当今面临的所有安全问题都是拜登政府所赐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随着美国政治撕裂的程度与矛盾的激化，2024年的大选年注定将充满不确定性，美国的政局未来，到底何去何从，仍然有待观察。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末实习生林曦对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[怀化乡村：拨开云雾，宛若仙境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258935]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>