<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[温州实现数据资产“入表”第一单，万亿市场仍藏水面下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259268]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/dhrnvgaSoWKV9eICfGEagpNKL5CAyvz5SdzrTtK2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/dhrnvgaSoWKV9eICfGEagpNKL5CAyvz5SdzrT tK2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Data exchanges are springing up like mushrooms after a rain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Shi Xuan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The capitalization of data is ushering in new progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early October 2023, the data product &quot;Credit Data Treasure&quot; of Wenzhou Big Data Operation Co., Ltd. completed the data asset confirmation registration. The Wenzhou Municipal Finance Bureau stated in the announcement that this is the first order to confirm the registration of data assets in Wenzhou, and it is also the first order to list the data assets of a financial guidance enterprise in China that has been publicly reported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Incorporating data resources into the balance sheet refers to recognizing data resources as an &quot;asset&quot; in the company&#39;s balance sheet, and reflecting its value in financial statements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Credit Data Treasure is developed based on the Wenzhou Government Blockchain &quot;Data Asset Cloud Voucher&quot; system. After authorization by individuals or enterprises, it provides financial institutions with data services related to credit business, simplifying loan application materials and process to improve credit approval efficiency and bank verification accuracy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2020, data was upgraded to the fifth major factor of production alongside land, labor, capital and technology, and a series of policies related to the capitalization of data were closely introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If you had asked me two years ago, I would have told you that most enterprises knew nothing about data capitalization.” Today, data capitalization has become a hot topic, but according to UFIDA Group Data Governance Expert Shi Xiufeng observed that most companies have not yet truly touched upon their essence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the difficulties in capitalizing data? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The trillion-dollar market under the water&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“First of all, it must be clear that not all data is data assets.” Deputy Director of the Price Monitoring Center of the National Development and Reform Commission Director Wang Jiandong told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the definition of China Academy of Information and Communications Technology (hereinafter referred to as the Academy of Information and Communications Technology), data assets refer to data legally owned or controlled by organizations (government agencies, enterprises and institutions, etc.), recorded electronically or by other means , such as structured or unstructured data such as texts, videos, databases, and sensor signals, can be measured or traded, and can directly or indirectly bring economic and social benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, only data that can bring value to the organization is a data asset, and its formation requires active management and effective control of data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tang Hanlin, chairman of Guizhou Databao Network Technology Co., Ltd. and general manager of East China Jiangsu Big Data Trading Center, explained to Southern Weekend reporters that data capitalization is to transform data resources into data assets, and its core is to fully release data value of resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the development, use and market operation of public data are still being explored. In December 2022, the &quot;Opinions on Building a Data Basic System to Better Play the Role of Data Elements&quot; (also known as the Twenty Data Articles) was issued and proposed to &quot;promote the paid use of public data used for digital development in accordance with government guidance and pricing, and enterprises and A price formation mechanism that combines independent pricing in the personal information data market.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Xiufeng analyzed from the perspective of enterprise development that enterprises have accumulated a large amount of data in the informatization process over the past 20 years. Nowadays, these data can generate greater value, thus pushing enterprises to start data governance, realize the utilization and value maximization of data assets, and ultimately realize the digital transformation of enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Informatization refers to the realization of enterprise business process management and data recording through network, computer, database and other information technologies, such as financial computerization, OA collaborative office, etc. Digitalization is the use of digital technologies such as cloud computing and blockchain to achieve innovation in enterprise business and management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Xiufeng has more than 16 years of working experience in the data field. His business involves consulting and delivery in the fields of enterprise data governance, data asset management, data applications and other fields. He has led many companies in traditional manufacturing, energy and other industries. Planning and implementation of large-scale data projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Xiufeng believes that currently 80% of enterprises are still in the process of forming data assets. Wang Jiandong said that in the short term, the data infrastructure system will give rise to a data trading market of 300 billion to 500 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This 100-billion-dollar transaction will leverage the trillion-level market behind it.” Wang Jiandong said that by further considering the derivative markets such as the evaluation, pledge, and financing of data assets, the potential scale of the entire data asset market will be More than 10 trillion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that, like production factors such as land, data elements can also be explored using hierarchical governance. The primary data market is the transfer of ownership rights and open usage rights of data resources, while the secondary data market is the market for data products and services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The main part of enterprise data capitalization is still hidden under the water.” Wang Jiandong explained that currently, only a small part of the data owned by social institutions has entered the circulation and transaction process, and most of the other data They are all circulated in the zero-level market in various forms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The zero-level data market refers to the market behavior that does not enter the transaction link, but data sharing, exchange and equity transfer occur, such as within an enterprise and between enterprises with certain business or equity relationships. Another example is that data sharing and exchange occurs every moment within Internet companies, but no external transactions are conducted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jiandong said that according to preliminary calculations, the potential scale of data assets and their pledge, financing and other derivative markets in the current zero-level data market is 30 times to 60 times that of the primary and secondary markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Obtain a position first&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“It’s hot at the top and cold at the bottom.” Senior data Industry insider Cheng Guo described the current data capitalization process to Southern Weekend reporters. He has participated in corporate research and the formulation of industry rules for many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Guo’s view, the only newly established deputy ministerial-level national bureau in this round of institutional reform of the State Council is the National Data Bureau. The bureau is affiliated with the National Development and Reform Commission, alongside the National Grain Administration and the National Energy Administration, which shows that senior officials regard data as a core strategic resource. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 25, 2023, the National Data Administration was officially launched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The introduction of a number of relevant policies has also prompted a new wave of enthusiasm in the preparation and construction of data exchanges. After the fourth quarter of 2020, data exchanges have sprung up like mushrooms after a rain, including Shanxi, Shanghai, Shenzhen, Fujian and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;White Paper on Data Elements&quot; released by the Academy of Information and Communications Technology shows that as of August 2023, 53 data trading institutions have been established across the country. From January to August 2023 alone, 5 new data trading institutions have been established in the country. Home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, generally speaking, most of the data trading institutions established in the early stage have not found successful business models. Most of them have stopped operations or changed their business direction, and their development has not been as expected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The East China Jiangsu Big Data Trading Center (hereinafter referred to as the East China Data Trading Center) where Tang Hanlin works was established in 2015 and is one of the earliest data trading institutions in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said frankly that in the past, there was no clear requirement that data transactions must be conducted on exchanges. The East China Digital Exchange serves more as an announcement platform - allowing both supply and demand parties to better understand each other, in order to promote Both parties mainly conduct offline transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Guo’s view, the importance of data capitalization has been emphasized at the national level, but local governments are still relatively confused. &quot;Their (local government) idea is that although I can&#39;t understand this new thing yet, I will take a position first.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, Shenzhen Data Trading Co., Ltd. was established, and then based on The Shenzhen Data Exchange (hereinafter referred to as the Shenzhen Data Exchange) was established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The focus of Shenzhen Data Institute in the past few years has not been to increase transaction volume, but to cultivate market ecology.&quot; At the end of September 2022, Wang Guan, deputy general manager of Shenzhen Data Institute, revealed in a meeting that Shenzhen Data The trading market has led the country in both transaction volume and transaction activity. However, the market supply and demand are not balanced. There are relatively few suppliers and many demand sides. At the same time, the number of third-party service organizations and data providers is not abundant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The supply of high-quality data products is the most critical.” Wei Zhilin, deputy general manager of the Shanghai Data Exchange (hereinafter referred to as Shanghai Data Exchange), emphasized to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of November 2021, the Shanghai Institute of Technology was established almost at the same time as the Shenzhen Institute of Technology. Its goal is clear and its mission is to “build a data element market and promote the process of data assetization”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Zhilin revealed that as of now, there are more than 1,600 data products listed on the exchanges, and the monthly transaction volume has exceeded 100 million yuan. It is expected that the annual transaction volume in 2023 will exceed 1 billion yuan. SSI currently focuses on providing data products in the fields of finance, shipping, transportation and trade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the financial industry data trading market has existed for a long time, and its delivery products and financial methods are more mature. It is a data-intensive industry. In the past five years, the compound annual growth rate of the number of data element procurement projects in the financial industry has reached 40%, far exceeding the compound annual growth rate of 26% in the number of total financial industry procurement projects, showing that the scale of the financial industry data trading market is developing rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wei Zhilin also admitted that the current scale of on-site transactions in the entire data element market is relatively small. &quot;The construction of on-site trading is crucial, and its role in compliance, credibility, efficiency and capitalization is irreplaceable.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/25/PFsqMbL5vp0h984ZrkC24QdhDi3uzJfkpiLUxnNx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;896&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/25/PFsqMbL5vp0h984ZrkC24QdhDi3uzJfkpiLUxnNx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;May 6, 2022 A pedestrian walks past the Northern Big Data Trading Center under preparation in Tianjin Binhai New Area. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jiandong said that one of the future directions of data capitalization is to encourage enterprises to enter the market for transactions as much as possible and realize the confirmation of the value of their data assets through on-site transactions, so that The price formed in the exchange becomes the &quot;anchor&quot; for the valuation of data assets, so the exchange will become active. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It is equivalent to companies entering the market not just to earn money from transactions, but to gain opportunities for asset appreciation through transactions.” Wang Jiandong explained that the value of corporate data assets has been recognized by the market and will be capitalized in the future. Only through operation can enterprises have greater enthusiasm to participate in on-site transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tang Hanlin believes that the requirement for enterprise data assets to be included in the table will promote great improvements in the data trading market. In the future, both supply and demand parties will hope to form a fair price system for data assets through on-site transactions. This will make it easier to incorporate the valuation into the table. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Problems in confirming rights&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August and September 2023, the Ministry of Finance and the China Assessment Association successively issued reports on the entry of data resources into the table and the evaluation of data assets. The relevant documents are the &quot;Interim Provisions on Accounting Treatment Related to Enterprise Data Resources&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Interim Provisions&quot;) and the &quot;Guidance Opinions on Data Asset Assessment&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Guidance Opinions&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the two sets of documents came out, Yuan Lizhi, a partner at Jingtian &amp; Gongcheng Law Firm and an expert in data law, immediately received inquiries from clients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Accountants, auditors and appraisers all hope that our lawyers can issue a legal opinion first as a basis for the inclusion of corporate data assets in the balance sheet or asset valuation.” Yuan Lizhi told the Southern Weekend reporter that they were worried The fundamental reason is that the ownership of data assets cannot be confirmed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The industry generally believes that there are three major links and three major challenges in realizing data capitalization, namely the confirmation of data asset ownership from a legal perspective, the valuation and trading of data assets from a market perspective, and the inclusion of data assets in the accounting perspective. . Among them, the confirmation of data assets is the prerequisite for everything. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process of data production, circulation, use, etc., relevant entities such as individuals, enterprises, society, and countries have different interests and demands for data, which are characterized by complex symbiosis, interdependence, and dynamic changes. Traditional rights It is difficult for the institutional framework to break through the data property rights dilemma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Twenty Data Articles propose to establish a data property rights system framework of &quot;separation of three rights&quot;: data resource holding rights, data processing and use rights, and data product operation rights, downplaying ownership and emphasizing use rights. To a certain extent, the problem of data asset confirmation has been solved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jiandong said that the &quot;separation of three powers&quot; provides a basic idea for solving problems. At present, there are no fundamental technical obstacles to the registration and confirmation of data assets, but the difficulty in specific implementation lies in the lack of support from higher-level laws. Just like the securities law is to securities registration, the property law is to real estate registration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 127 of the &quot;Civil Code of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates, &quot;Where the law has provisions on the protection of data and network virtual property, those provisions shall prevail.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current laws and regulations related to it, such as the Personal Information Protection Law, Data Security Law and Network Security Law, etc., are more focused from the perspective of data security and privacy protection, and do not make clear the confirmation of data rights. Regulation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuan Lizhi introduced that in actual cases, due to the large number of stakeholders involved, companies may encounter interest demands from various angles when developing and utilizing data assets, such as personal information protection. , unfair competition, trade secrets, intellectual property rights, contractual claims, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the investigation, Cheng Guo found that under this situation, some companies also expressed concerns about the inclusion of their data assets in the table. Being included in the table means that companies must undergo strict audits, but currently it is difficult for many companies to clarify the true ownership of their data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the above-mentioned &quot;Interim Provisions&quot; and &quot;Guidance Opinions&quot; are only detailed specifications of existing relevant rules and &quot;do not break through the existing financial accounting system.&quot; In Yuan Lizhi&#39;s view, the property rights system is the prerequisite for market transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yuan Lizhi said that when formal legal documents are issued, lawyers are relatively mature in judging the legality of data assets and will be more cautious in determining their ownership. &quot;Especially when it comes to third-party rights and interests, we will make judgments based on general legal principles, but we will reserve our opinions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant departments were obviously aware of the difficulties when they issued the regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Guo called the &quot;Interim Provisions&quot; a &quot;small entry&quot; of data assets. The reason is that this document does not target all data assets. Instead, it divides data resources into those that meet the conditions and can be &quot;entered into the table&quot; and those that do not, based on whether they meet the recognition conditions of assets in the &quot;Accounting Standards for Business Enterprises - Basic Standards&quot;. Conditional &quot;not included in the table&quot; data resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the &quot;Interim Provisions&quot; are future applicable laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Guo said that some enterprises mainly invest in data capitalization in the early stage, and then only make a small amount of investment regularly every year. The data assets entered into the table are only calculated based on the new investment, not It will have a great impact on the asset size of the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Looking for another way&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In a short period of time, the problem of confirming rights cannot be solved, and market entities have begun to find another way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wei Zhilin’s view, the operating rights of data products among the “three rights” of data property rights solve the so-called difficulty in confirming rights and pricing, including the supervision of data. On this basis, Shangshu Institute proposed the concept of “data products”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Zhilin said that only by organizing and processing data into data products according to certain needs and application scenarios can a market with demand and supply be formed. Only in this way can corresponding trading rules, standard systems, technology, ecology and supervision and other circulation and trading systems be established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He explained that if original data is circulated and traded, it will involve issues such as data security and confirmation of rights that are currently difficult to crack, and the concept of &quot;data products&quot; has solved the problem of data well. Ownership issues. Data products formed by processing the original data held by an enterprise give the enterprise the right to determine the data product. Based on the data product, the enterprise can enjoy the right to operate the data product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, media reported that in terms of building a specific data property rights system, the intellectual property system is the only system currently being piloted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Yang, a lecturer at the Law School of Shanghai University of International Business and Economics, once publicly stated that intellectual property rights, as a system for protecting the property rights of intangible assets, are legitimate when applied to data. Data can obtain higher economic value only through human creative intellectual labor, which is in line with the scope of intellectual property protection for intellectual achievements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Yang said in the above interview that by granting intellectual property rights to data that meets the conditions, clear guidance is provided to data transaction subjects, which improves the security and efficiency of data transactions, thereby stimulating enterprise data product innovation, so as to Solve the problem of insufficient supply of data products in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tang Hanlin also recognized the application of the intellectual property system in data rights confirmation. In April 2023, the Jiangsu Provincial Intellectual Property Office issued the &quot;Jiangsu Province Data Intellectual Property Registration and Management Rules (Trial)&quot;, and East China Digital Communications is a pilot unit for data intellectual property in Jiangsu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to him, East China Digital Communications has directly connected with the Jiangsu Provincial Intellectual Property Office. &quot;After our data traders submit data products to the exchange, they can be directly reviewed by the Jiangsu Provincial Intellectual Property Bureau and confirmed online, thereby completing a closed-loop service for confirmation of rights.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Xinhua Daily” reported that in mid-October 2023, a data product “Enterprise Batch Query” developed by Jiangsu Lianhe Credit Information Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Lianhe Credit Information) obtained pledge financing of 12 million yuan from the Jiangsu Branch of the Bank of Communications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;United Credit Information is a financial technology company approved by the Jiangsu Provincial Government and is a credit information agency registered with the Central Bank. &quot;Enterprise Batch Inquiry&quot; is an enterprise information inquiry data product formed by United Credit Information on the basis of data cleaning and processing, and through the construction of a model with more than 40 dimensional indicators. It is mainly used to reflect the credit status of enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above report stated that as a local pilot for national data intellectual property work, Jiangsu Province will issue the first batch of data intellectual property registration certificates in May 2023. As of October 11, there have been 125 data intellectual property registrations in Jiangsu Province, and more than 50 million yuan of data intellectual property pledge financing has been achieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of value assessment of data assets, Wang Jiandong has always called for the data traceability function to be included in the country’s future data asset registration platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that enterprises need to explain the data sources at every step in the formation process of their data assets. In this way, the future value potential of the data asset can be more fairly assessed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As data assets are entered into the statement and effective evaluation is achieved, the enterprise has expressions in the accounting statements and has the support of real economic activities.” Wei Zhilin believes that the process of data assetization begins when the data is entered into the statement. Based on this, greater breakthroughs and innovations will surely be achieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He concluded that there are six main directions for the innovative application of data assets, including adding data assets to the balance sheet, credit enhancement of data assets, pledge financing of data assets, factoring of data assets, pricing shares of data assets and securitization of data assets. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters made an interview with the Wenzhou Municipal Finance Bureau over the phone and sent an interview letter, but the other party declined the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Cheng Guo is a pseudonym at the request of the interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京长峰医院重大火灾事故调查报告公布]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259282]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:08:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 12:50 on April 18, 2023, Beijing Changfeng, No. 291, Indochang New Village, Fengtai District, Beijing A major fire accident occurred in the hospital, causing 29 deaths, 42 injuries, and direct economic losses of 38.3182 million yuan. Recently, the State Council executive meeting reviewed and approved the investigation report on the &quot;4·18&quot; major fire accident of Beijing Fengtai Changfeng Hospital. The accident investigation team of the State Council determined that this was an incident due to the hospital&#39;s illegal implementation of renovation projects, poor construction safety management, chaotic daily management, long-term fire hazards, illegal operations by the construction unit, lack of on-site safety management, and poor emergency response. Major production safety accidents caused by the failure of local party committees, governments and relevant departments to fulfill their duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the accident, the Party Central Committee and the State Council attached great importance to it. General Secretary Xi Jinping immediately issued important instructions, requiring all efforts to treat the injured, properly handling the aftermath of the victims and comforting their families, identifying the cause of the fire accident as soon as possible, and strictly pursuing responsibility in accordance with the law. It is emphasized that all regions and relevant departments must always tighten the string of safety production, earnestly implement safety production responsibilities, strengthen safety management, thoroughly investigate various risks and hidden dangers, and resolutely prevent and contain major safety accidents. Premier Li Qiang and other leading comrades issued important instructions and put forward clear requirements for aftermath handling, accident investigation, special rectification and other work. Beijing immediately organized emergency rescue, casualty treatment and aftermath disposal. The Ministry of Emergency Management, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the National Health Commission, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau and other departments immediately dispatched and deployed, and sent working groups to the scene to guide emergency response work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 21, the Beijing Municipal People&#39;s Government established an accident investigation team to carry out investigation work, and the State Council Safety Committee supervised the investigation and handling of the accident. In view of the serious nature and bad impact of the accident, in accordance with relevant laws and regulations and with the approval of the State Council, the establishment was led by the Ministry of Emergency Management, the Ministry of Public Security, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the National Health Commission, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, the All-China Federation of Trade Unions and Beijing The &quot;4·18&quot; fire accident investigation team of the State Council Beijing Fengtai Changfeng Hospital, which the Municipal People&#39;s Government participated in, conducted a detailed investigation into the accident based on the previous work of Beijing Municipality. The accident investigation team followed the principles of scientific rigor, compliance with laws and regulations, seeking truth from facts, and focusing on effectiveness, and through on-site inspection, investigation and evidence collection, video analysis, detection and identification, simulation experiments, expert argumentation, etc., they found out the course of the accident, the cause of the occurrence, and the casualties , direct economic losses and the situation of relevant units, identified the problems and responsibilities of the local party committee, government, relevant departments and units, summarized and analyzed the main lessons of the accident, and put forward suggestions for rectification and preventive measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The accident investigation team found that the direct cause of the accident was the construction site of the Beijing Changfeng Hospital renovation project. The construction unit illegally carried out self-leveling ground construction and door frame installation and cutting cross-cutting operations. The easy-to-use epoxy resin primer materials The combustible and explosive components volatilize and form an explosive gas mixture. When encountering the sparks generated by the angle grinder cutting the metal purification board, it deflagrates. It ignites combustible materials near the site. The open flame and high-temperature smoke generated ignite the wooden decoration materials in the building and partially fireproof partitions. The fixed fire-fighting facilities failed to function, causing the fire to expand and a large amount of smoke to spread. In addition, the initial handling was not effective, and the evacuation and transfer of patients on high floors failed to be effectively organized, resulting in heavy casualties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investigation revealed that the main problems exposed in the accident were the serious failure of the hospital to fulfill its main responsibilities, the construction unit&#39;s illegal and hot work, the local party committee and government&#39;s weak awareness of preventing and resolving major risks, and the shortcomings in administrative approval and safety management of medical and health institutions. There are obvious flaws, there are loopholes in the safety supervision and management of construction projects, and the fire safety risk prevention and control network is not tight, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to regulations, the accident investigation team will hand over clues and relevant materials found during the investigation on problems in the performance of duties of local party committees, governments and public officials of relevant departments to the accountability review and investigation team of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the problems exposed in the accident, the accident investigation team summarized the main lessons in five aspects: weak awareness of preventing and resolving major risks, lax administrative approval and safety management in the medical and health industry, construction project planning and construction safety There are shortcomings and loopholes in supervision, fire supervision and inspection and special rectification are not in-depth, and initial emergency response capabilities are insufficient. At the same time, five suggestions for rectification and preventive measures are put forward: earnestly shoulder the political responsibility for preventing and resolving major risks, strive to make up for the shortcomings of safety management of medical and health institutions, resolutely plug the loopholes in safety supervision and management of construction projects, and comprehensively implement fire safety risk prevention Control the network and accelerate the improvement of front-line emergency response capabilities and levels at the grassroots level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院事故调查组相关负责人就北京长峰医院重大火灾事故调查工作答记者问]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259284]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:16:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, the State Council executive meeting reviewed and approved the &quot;4·18&quot; major fire accident investigation report of Beijing Fengtai Changfeng Hospital . The reporter interviewed the relevant person in charge of the accident investigation team on the hot issues of social concern during the investigation of the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Reporter: How is the State Council accident investigation team composed? What was the investigation process like? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer:&lt;/strong>;After the accident, the Party Central Committee and the State Council attached great importance to it. On April 21, the Beijing Municipal People&#39;s Government established an accident investigation team to carry out investigation work, and the State Council Safety Committee supervised the investigation and handling of the accident. In view of the serious nature and bad impact of the accident, in accordance with relevant laws and regulations and with the approval of the State Council, the establishment was led by the Ministry of Emergency Management, the Ministry of Public Security, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the National Health Commission, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, the All-China Federation of Trade Unions and Beijing The &quot;4·18&quot; fire accident investigation team of the State Council Beijing Fengtai Changfeng Hospital, which the Municipal People&#39;s Government participated in, conducted a detailed investigation into the accident based on the previous work of Beijing Municipality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The accident investigation team conscientiously implemented the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions and instructions and the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, and followed the principles of scientific rigor, compliance with laws and regulations, seeking truth from facts, and focusing on results, through on-site inspections, investigation and evidence collection , video analysis, inspection and identification, simulation experiments, expert demonstrations, etc., to find out the accident, causes, casualties, direct economic losses and the situation of relevant units, and to identify the problems and responsibilities of the local party committee, government, relevant departments and units , summarized and analyzed the main lessons from the accident, and put forward suggestions for rectification and preventive measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investigation determined that this was a case of illegal implementation of renovation projects by the hospital, poor construction safety management, chaotic daily management, long-term fire hazards, illegal operations by the construction unit, lack of on-site safety management, and emergency response Major production safety accidents caused by failure of local party committees, governments and relevant departments to fulfill their duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Reporter: What was the main reason for the accident? Why did it cause a large number of casualties? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;Through video analysis, on-site inspection, testing and identification, and simulation experiment analysis, the accident investigation team determined that the direct cause of the accident was the construction of the renovation project of Beijing Changfeng Hospital On site, the construction unit illegally carried out self-leveling floor construction and door frame installation and cutting cross-cutting operations. The flammable and explosive components in the epoxy resin primer material volatilized and formed an explosive gas mixture. When encountering the sparks generated by the angle grinder cutting the metal purification plate, a deflagration occurred. ; ignited combustible materials near the site, and the open flame and high-temperature smoke generated ignited the wooden decoration materials in the building. Some fire prevention partitions did not work, and the fixed fire-fighting facilities failed, causing the fire to expand and a large amount of smoke to spread; coupled with poor initial treatment, the fire was not It can effectively organize the evacuation and transfer of patients on high floors, causing heavy casualties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The accident investigation team analyzed the cause of the fire, the cause of the fire spread, and the cause of casualties one by one. In terms of the cause of the fire, at the construction site of the ICU renovation project on the third floor of the south annex building of Beijing Changfeng Hospital, when the workers were carrying out self-leveling floor construction and purification door frame installation and cutting, they illegally crossed the work; the epoxy resin painted on the self-leveling floor construction The flammable and explosive components in the primer material volatilize, and effective ventilation is not maintained at the site, forming an explosive gas mixture, and the concentration reaches the lower explosion limit; the sparks generated by the angle grinder cutting the metal purification plate will cause deflagration and ignite when encountering the explosive gas mixture. Combustibles piled under the ramp outside the northwest gate. In terms of the reasons for the spread of the fire, after the deflagration occurred, the workers did not put out all the fire spots that formed on the scene and did not call the police immediately. The staff of the hospital where the incident occurred did not call the police immediately after discovering the fire, and did not effectively organize the initial fire. Firefighting, fixed firefighting facilities failed, automatic sprinkler system and fire hydrant system pipe network had no water, and the fire could not be effectively controlled; wooden decoration materials were used on the walls of ramps and hospital passages, and non-combustible materials were not used in construction areas and non-construction areas as required Fire prevention separation was carried out, causing the open fire to spread into the main building of the east building; some pipe shafts were not fireproof sealed and no fire doors were installed; the door closers of some stairwell fire doors were damaged and could not be closed normally; the stairwell on the east side of the fifth floor of the north passage often The closed fire door was not kept closed, and the gypsum board partition wall above the fire door in the west stairwell on the sixth floor of the south passage was burned through, causing the smoke to spread. In terms of causes of casualties, failure to evacuate in time and inhalation of smoke containing carbon monoxide are the main reasons for a large number of casualties. In the early stages of the fire, the hospital where the fire occurred did not activate an emergency plan and failed to effectively organize the evacuation and transfer of trapped people; the ward setting was unreasonable, and the hospital where the incident occurred concentrated patients who were unable to take care of themselves or had difficulty moving in high-rise floors such as the seventh and eighth floors. Some patients do not have the ability to escape independently; it is difficult for critically ill patients to move, the passages in the building are narrow, and the transfer conditions are poor, making rescue and transfer difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Reporter: What illegal behaviors did the hospital and related units involved have? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer:&lt;/strong>;The investigation found that the hospital and construction unit involved had many violations of laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main aspects are as follows: First, the main responsibility of the hospital is seriously not implemented. Changfeng Hospital Company violated medical institution management regulations and failed to register changes in the number of beds as required, and the ratio of medical and nursing staff did not meet regulations. The width of the public walkway in the inpatient department was 1.4 meters, which was significantly smaller than the minimum 2.1 meters required by the regulations; it failed to fulfill its legal obligations in construction construction and Construction site safety management responsibilities. The 38 renovation and renovation construction projects that have been carried out since 2017 have not applied for construction permits from relevant departments or applied for construction start registration procedures to streets and towns as required. No illegal activities at the ICU renovation project site have been discovered and stopped. Fire and cross-operation behaviors; failure to perform the main responsibility for fire safety as required, meeting the defined standards but failing to declare a key fire safety unit, failing to organize regular maintenance of fire protection facilities and equipment, automatic fire alarm systems, automatic sprinkler systems, and indoor fire hydrants The system is not kept intact and efficient. The second is that the construction unit violated the regulations and engaged in cross-fire operations. Zhongyuan Xincheng Company&#39;s construction site safety management was lacking. Workers illegally carried out open fire work without going through the fire approval procedures, without supervision on site, and without cleaning up combustible materials on site. They used angle grinders for cutting operations; Establish fire safety measures for flammable and explosive items, and season ingredients in the workplace in violation of regulations; epoxy resin self-leveling floor construction and purification door installation are cross-cutting operations; construction industry enterprise qualification license conditions are not maintained, and safety production management institutions are not established as required and Equipped with full-time safety production management personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Reporter: What problems did the local party committee, government and relevant departments have in this accident? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer:&lt;/strong>;The accident investigation team identified problems in the implementation of the responsibilities of the local party committee, government and relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, local party committees and governments have weak awareness of preventing and resolving major risks. Fengtai District in Beijing has not conscientiously fulfilled its territorial management responsibilities for production safety, and has not paid enough attention to the construction of safety supervision capabilities at the grassroots level in streets and towns. In 2022, the city&#39;s safety production and fire protection work assessment ranked first from the bottom, and it has not effectively organized and carried out special inspections of fire safety at the construction site of construction projects. , accident information is not reported in time, and reports of casualties are slow. Beijing&#39;s safety development concept is not strong enough, and it has neglected to observe the problem that relevant departments have not conscientiously implemented the safety production and fire safety management responsibilities of local medical institutions, construction sites and other key places, and has not effectively urged and guided the Fengtai District Committee and District Government to strictly implement local safety production management. responsibility. Second, there are obvious shortcomings in the administrative approval and safety management of medical and health institutions. The Fengtai District Health Commission failed to strictly perform its medical institution verification and management responsibilities. It failed to supervise the Beijing Changfeng Hospital&#39;s long-term failure to apply for bed number change registration and staffing failure to meet the requirements. It also failed to perform the ICU renovation project of Beijing Changfeng Hospital. It has no industry supervision and management responsibilities for construction permits, failed to inspect and discover hidden fire hazards in the project, and failed to report accident casualty information to the Fengtai District Party Committee, District Government and District Emergency Office through formal channels. The Beijing Municipal Health Commission failed to conscientiously perform the safety supervision duty of &quot;managing the industry must manage safety&quot;, and neglected to supervise the Fengtai District Health Commission&#39;s inability to perform industry safety supervision duties and other issues; guide the implementation of group inspections of fire safety groups in Beijing medical institutions, The special inspection requirements for fire safety at the construction site of construction projects were insufficient, and the rectification of hidden dangers was not effectively promoted. Third, there are loopholes in the safety supervision and management of construction projects. The Fengtai District Housing and Urban-Rural Development Committee failed to conscientiously perform its industry safety supervision responsibilities and failed to supervise construction projects that did not have construction permits; it failed to provide effective business guidance and service cooperation for construction projects below the quota that were transferred to the management of streets and towns; The failure to obtain a construction permit for the ICU renovation project of Changfeng Hospital was investigated and punished in accordance with laws and regulations. The Beijing Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Commission failed to implement special inspection requirements for fire safety at construction project construction sites; it failed to dynamically supervise the qualifications of construction industry enterprises as required, and neglected to supervise the issue of construction units failing to maintain the second-level qualification licensing conditions for the construction industry.四是消防安全风险防控网不严密。当地消防部门未认真履行消防监督管理职责，日常消防监督检查和消防安全专项整治不扎实。丰台区消防救援支队（原丰台区公安消防支队）2012年对北京长峰医院东楼内部装修工程进行消防验收时，在未检查管道竖井封堵完整性、未对建筑内部装修防火等进行评定，以及在消防用电设备未采用专用供电回路的情况下，违规出具验收合格评定结论；长期以来未将北京长峰医院确定为消防安全重点单位。北京市消防救援总队指导落实北京市医疗机构消防安全组团体检式检查、建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查工作不力，未有效推进隐患整改工作。此外，国务院事故调查组还查明，北京市规划和自然资源委员会丰台分局未认真履行制止和查处违法建设职责，未及时发现并查处北京长峰医院部分建筑未办理建设工程规划许可证违法行为；丰台区应急办在首次获知事故信息后4小时24分才正式报告，违反北京市应急值守工作有关规定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：这起事故暴露出哪些深层次的教训？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;这起事故教训十分深刻，暴露出当地消防安全存在诸多突出问题和明显短板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是防范化解重大风险意识薄弱。一些领导干部对本地区存在的重大风险认识不足，没有及时发现并有效防控重大风险，也没有把他人的教训当作自己的教训，对相关重特大火灾事故暴露出的违规动火或电焊作业问题没有引起足够重视。这些问题根本原因在于，学习贯彻习近平总书记关于防范化解重大风险的重要论述不认真不深刻，没有结合实际认真研究和排查本地区风险隐患。二是医疗卫生行业行政审批和安全管理不严格。丰台区卫生健康部门工作作风不实不细，审批许可流于形式，1998年以来先后对事发医院校验18次，在病床数量成倍增加却未变更登记、医护配比不符合要求等情况下，每次校验结果均为合格；对安全生产工作面上重视，实际却撤销安全生产科；没有定期开展医疗卫生机构消防安全检查，也没有对事发医院近3年消防检测发现的重大问题进行督促整改。三是建设工程规划、施工安全监管存在短板漏洞。北京市住房城乡建设部门对建筑业企业资质条件保持情况疏于监管，动态排查清理不符合条件企业工作滞后。北京市建设工程施工管理自我设“限”，对限额以上未办理施工许可证的建设工程未主动开展监督管理，把不具备申请办理施工许可条件的建设工程排除在监管范围外，“只管合法、不管非法”；对限额以下工程施工安全疏于管理，对属地培训指导、协调督促又没跟上，导致基层接不住、管不好。北京市城乡规划部门履行制止和查处违法建设职责不到位，未能有效指导属地政府及其相关部门违法建设查处工作，对辖区内无规划手续即新建、扩建的行为查不出、管不住。四是消防监督检查和专项整治不深入。当地消防部门未认真履行消防安全监管职责，2009年事发医院已符合消防安全重点单位界定标准，至2022年才将其确定为重点单位进行监管；确定为重点单位后，消防监督检查质效依然不高，未及时发现和督促整改消防设施、消防供电等问题隐患。北京市消防救援总队在全市部署开展的建设工程施工现场消防安全专项检查中，未能有效指导丰台区消防救援支队严格落实消防监督检查职责。五是初期应急处置能力不足。这次事故中，自流平地面和净化工程作业人员均为临时雇佣人员，未经任何施工交底和安全教育培训直接上岗，违规交叉作业导致发生火灾，之后作业人员均未第一时间报警。医院值班人员、管理人员和医护人员，在发现火情后均未第一时间报警，医院未有效组织初期火灾扑救和人员疏散。同时，这次事故也暴露出一些政府部门和单位存在事故信息报送特别是伤亡人员信息报送不及时不规范等问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;记者：这起事故性质严重、影响恶劣，为进一步汲取教训，防止此类事故再次发生，有哪些整改和防范措施建议？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;答：&lt;/strong>;为深刻汲取事故教训，举一反三，坚决防范遏制重特大事故发生，事故调查组提出了五个方面的整改和防范措施建议：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一是切实扛起防范化解重大风险政治责任。各级领导干部要结合学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想主题教育，全面深入学习领会习近平总书记关于安全生产重要论述，坚持人民至上、生命至上，牢固树立安全发展理念，进一步增强防范化解重大风险的政治自觉、思想自觉和行动自觉。各地区、各部门、各单位要切实提高风险隐患排查整改质量，切实提升发现问题解决问题的强烈意愿和能力水平，进一步压紧压实企业主体责任、部门监管责任、地方领导责任，建立安全风险防范长效机制，坚决守牢安全红线底线。二是着力补齐医疗卫生机构安全管理短板。各级卫生健康部门要加强医疗卫生行业安全管理，督促各类医疗卫生机构严格执行安全生产和消防安全管理规定，加强安全风险分级管控和隐患排查治理，组织开展医疗卫生机构安全生产和消防安全专项排查整治。严格医疗卫生机构登记校验、行政审批等，组织开展医疗卫生机构依法执业情况核查，严查不如实申报情况、超许可范围执业、违规开展医养结合服务等行为。督促医疗卫生机构统筹考虑院感防治和病患应急疏散转移，指导各类医疗卫生机构制定专项灭火预案和应急疏散预案。三是坚决堵塞建设工程安全监督管理漏洞。各级住房城乡建设部门要加大资质审批后动态监管力度，严格建设工程施工许可管理，加强施工现场特别是施工动火作业安全管理，及时发现并消除事故隐患。城乡规划等部门要加大对违法建设的巡查和处置力度，对新增违建实行“零容忍”。四是全面织牢织密消防安全风险防控网。各地区要按照“三管三必须”要求，进一步压实行业部门消防安全管理责任，推行行业消防安全标准化管理；对职能交叉和新业态新风险，及时明确监管责任。推动街道乡镇建设应急站、消防所，发挥公安派出所、社区、网格等群防群治力量，切实加强对小场所小单位的消防安全管理。各级消防部门要严格履行消防监督管理职责，推动公共消防安全治理模式向事前预防转型，切实提升消防监督检查质效。五是加快提升基层一线应急处置能力和水平。各地区要进一步强化对各类企事业单位应急预案、演练、培训等应急准备的组织指导、监督检查。加强基层一线作业人员安全教育和应急培训，深入开展实操实训应急演练，确保熟悉作业场所现场处置方案。加强应急文化建设，强化应急科普宣传，切实增强社会公众安全意识，做到人人讲安全、个个会应急。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[聚焦北京长峰医院火灾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/247513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:18:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;2023年4月18日12时50分，北京市丰台区靛厂新村291号北京长峰医院发生重大火灾事故，造成29人死亡、42人受伤，直接经济损失3831.82万元。 日前，国务院常务会议审议通过了北京丰台长峰医院“4·18”重大火灾事故调查报告。</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李佳琦陷“二选一”风波：是否触发反垄断调查值得关切丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259275]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 16:17:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;关于李佳琦，一波未平一波又起。2023年10月24日上午，京东采销在朋友圈公开喊话李佳琦“二选一”。该工作人员表示，京东收到了品牌商海氏的律师函，被品牌投诉由于某款海氏烤箱的京东价格低于李佳琦直播售价，违反了他们与李佳琦签署的“底价协议”，会导致要求赔偿巨额违约金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，李佳琦所在公司美ONE回应称：李佳琦直播间和海氏没有签订所谓的“底价协议”；李佳琦直播间从未要求品牌进行任何的二选一；李佳琦直播间商品的定价权在于品牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海氏则发布声明称：海氏品牌没有签订任何“底价协议”，京东采销发布的信息不实。海氏称保证价格是为了将最低销售价全网拉齐，京东采销无权擅自修改价格，在己方拒绝后，京东仍选择降价。且京东调低价格出售的烤箱每一台的损失都由海氏品牌承担，并非京东采销声称的由平台补贴费用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如何看待这一次电商平台同电商直播的对线，双方乃至三方（加上品牌方）所争论的实质是什么？值得条分缕析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，有一个事实问题不能回避：海氏与李佳琦或其所在公司到底有没有签署“底价协议”？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据新浪科技披露的一份“美ONE直播推广服务合同”，合同中写道：……品牌需保证赠品的价值为保证期限内在保证范围内的同等条件下价值最高；在保证期限内，品牌需要保证其通过指定达人在本合同框架下双方约定的所有推广服务下提供的促销力度为保证期限内在保证范围内的同等条件下最大力度。如若违约，品牌需要向消费者退还五倍差价，并向美ONE赔偿违约金人民币200万元，并承担由于退还差价发生的一切费用和损失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;合同附件三为特别保证条款。规定最优惠价格的范围为甲方（品牌方）可控制的淘系平台(包括但不限于淘宝/天猫店铺、主播直播等淘系内容渠道)、其他电商平台和线下渠道。最优惠价格保证期限为该场直播推广服务实际发生日前后各60日内（共121天）。有三条特别保证内容，第一条为：在保证期限内，品牌还需保证其通过指定达人的所有推广服务下所对应计划售货量内的推广对象的最终成交价为保证期限内在保证范围内的最低价格。第二、第三条同合同正文中对赠品与促销力度的规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;显然，将合同正文与附件三对照，美ONE直播对品牌方要求是：在前后共四个月内，直播推广对象的最终成交价格必须是相对于所有电商平台与线下渠道的最低价格，并且对赠品价值与促销力度也进行了规定，以免品牌方与其他平台通过这两个方式绕开最低价格条款。这就是从正品价格、赠品价值与促销力度全方位规定的“全网最低价协议”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在的问题就成了海氏与李佳琦有没有签署有“底价协议”的合同。如果京东采销所说是真的，那就是签署了。当然，京东采销同海氏与美ONE，到底哪一方说的是实话，我们可以看双方进一步披露硬证据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，京东采销在朋友圈公开指控李佳琦“二选一”、搞“底价协议”，李佳琦所在公司予以否认。显然，前者或在召唤达摩克里斯之剑：《中华人民共和国反垄断法》（以下简称《反垄断法》）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《反垄断法》有针对“滥用市场支配地位”（第22条）的法条。2021年《国务院反垄断委员会关于平台经济领域的反垄断指南》规定：具有市场支配地位的平台经济领域经营者，可能滥用市场支配地位，无正当理由对交易相对人进行限定交易，排除、限制市场竞争。分析是否构成限定交易行为，可以考虑以下因素：要求平台内经营者在竞争性平台间进行“二选一”，或者限定交易相对人与其进行独家交易的其他行为……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也就是说，平台要求商家“二选一”可能被视为“滥用市场支配地位”“排除、限制市场竞争”，从而触发反垄断调查，这就是李佳琦所在公司为什么否认“二选一”。但现在谁能否认李佳琦一人就是一个平台呢？ “二选一”实质上是逼着商家只能选自己。至于海氏这次为什么站“强势”的李佳琦，应是其权衡自身利弊得失的结果。所以，这场对线会不会导致监管机构与反垄断执法机构下场，也是值得关切的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后，现在头部主播要求商家签“全网最低价协议”，依然是一个行业惯例。所谓“李佳琦直播间商品的定价权在于品牌”显然难以让人信服，只是一种话术或规避法律风险的辞令。对此有两点进一步的解读。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一，在经济进入中低增长及存量时代，所有平台间的内卷在加剧。从电商平台到头部主播，其实所有互联网平台的打法都在简化，以价格取胜成为趋势，因为现在消费者最关心的就是价格。你头部主播要搞全网最低价，我电商平台凭什么不可以搞比你更低的价格？也就是说，这是一场对“全网最低价”头衔与人设的争夺，诸多电商平台的目标就是把这个头衔与人设夺回来，在广大消费者那里建立“心智占位”。这才是这场对线背后的商业逻辑与实质。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，2022年中修订的《反垄断法》，并没有明确针对头部主播“全网最低价”打法的条款。但按照《反垄断法》的逻辑，要求几个月内商家必须给直播平台保证必须是相对于其他所有平台与渠道的全网最低价，可能被视为滥用市场支配地位，其22条有兜底条款：“国务院反垄断执法机构认定的其他滥用市场支配地位的行为”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;故而，围绕本次对线，我们也要密切关注监管者对长时间全领域“底价协议”的态度与看法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[国家发改委解读2024年放假安排：史上最长春节假期]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259264]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;【2024年放假安排的五大突出亮点】每年一度的全年放假安排一直是社会公众高度关注和翘首以盼的焦点话题。经过统筹协调和综合考虑，国务院办公厅适时发布了2024年的部分节假日安排。这一放假安排主要呈现出五大亮点：&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;亮点一：9天，史上最长春节假期&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;2024年春节至少放假8天，从初一放到初八，如果配合带薪休假可以放假9天，堪称新年第一份大礼包。虽然除夕当天名义上不放假，但鼓励各单位和机构根据实际情况来灵活安排。同时高速公路已经免费了，实质上就是创造条件给老百姓多放一天假。春节假期的延长，能够满足广大群众有更多时间用于亲人团聚的心愿，还可以实现一个假期先团聚、后旅游的小目标。这是在依据《全国年节及纪念日放假办法》规定的基础上的创新之举、暖心之举，充分体现出政策制定者的用心良苦和精心设计。&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;亮点二：不得不调，但更加人性化更具灵活性&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;调休是放假安排中社会公众普遍关心的话题，是否调休以及如何调休，目前社会公众的观点差异比较大。总体而言，调休比不调休好，而且是不得不调。因为7个法定节假日中，春节、端午节和中秋节是按照农历来确定的，元旦节、劳动节和国庆节是按照公历来确定的，清明节又是按照节气来确定的，与公历历法中的双休日不够衔接，如果不做调休，基本上每年都会出现部分节假日与双休日之间间隔1个工作日、造成节假日“碎片化”等情况，形成很多“单蹦”，那就不是“累觉不爱”，而是“累且不爱”啦。调休就是在节假日总量固定的前提下，为避免节假日“碎片化”所做出的有效政策安排。2024年通过调休，形成了“9573”的放假时间安排，展现出较强的人性化和灵活性。&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;亮点三：最小干预，尽量不打乱人们的正常生活节奏&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;2024年全年假期比较均衡，通过调借临近周末，春节至少8天、国庆7天、劳动节5天，元旦、清明、端午、中秋都是3天，长假后最长工作日也只有6天，调整的幅度比较小，避免出现长假过后工作时间长的局面，较好地满足了人们劳逸结合的实际需要。&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;亮点四：长短结合，更好满足群众出游要求和休假期盼&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;我国法定节假日具有时间分布“上半年多、下半年少”、日期间隔“上半年短、下半年长”等特点，5个集中在上半年。此次放假安排充分考虑到这些法定节假日的日期特点，形成了四个3天短假、一个5天小长假、一个7天长假、一个9天超长假的假期分布，较好地实现了长假与短假相互交错的局面。通过长假、短假的合理搭配，人们可以提前做好全年的出行计划与安排，在探亲、休闲、旅游等方面拥有更多更好的日期选择，避免“一窝蜂”出行和“扎堆”旅游。&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;亮点五：鼓励落实带薪年休假，更好保障群众休息权益&lt;/span>;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;国办发文中首次提出了鼓励结合落实带薪年休假等制度来落实，实质上就是倡导企事业单位在保障基本运行的前提下，能放则放。我国现行法定节假日总天数为11天，周末休息104天，带薪休假5-15天，总假期天数在国际上处于中等偏上水平。之所以大家仍然觉得假期不够、获得感不强，主要还是带薪年休假制度落实不到位，大家不能错怪法定节假日安排和调休了。此次放假安排，通过鼓励用人单位将除夕放假纳入带薪年休假安排，就是一次非常巧妙的探索。相对而言，带薪年休假的假期时间更长，安排更加灵活，更加适合人们错峰出行、分散安排的客观需要。只有将带薪年休假与法定节假日统筹协调安排好，劳动者的休息权利才会更有保障，保障得更为充分&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[吸食除尘罐的女孩]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259260]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;吸食除尘罐后，女孩们出现了幻觉。（农健/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c2d95c294a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1152&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c2d95c294a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255330&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吸食除尘罐后，女孩们出现了幻觉。（农健/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;陈敏茹被大火烧伤那晚，出现过一次幻觉：一个披头散发的妖怪，拎着滚动的电锯缓缓靠近，一对红眼睛死死盯着陈敏茹的闺蜜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我赶紧护住闺蜜，把我都吓哭了。”半夜清醒过来，什么事都没有发生。陈敏茹环视一周，房间里的人大都已经睡着。3张床挤了8个不到20岁的年轻人，7女1男，其中4人未成年。满地散落着他们刚吸食过的高压气体除尘罐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高压气体除尘罐，一种用于清洁电脑键盘、相机或车内缝隙死角灰尘的液态喷雾装置，主要成分是HFC清洁气体，喷射瞬间液体会变成强气流，其宣传语写道：气流大到能轻松吹动一个132克重的鼠标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年6月17日傍晚，陕西省商洛市，包括陈敏茹在内的8人在如澜酒店501房间吸食除尘罐。“吸那个东西，能出现幻觉。”17岁的陈敏茹告诉南方周末记者，除尘罐喷出的气体味道涩涩的，并不好吸。“那天开始吸的时候，脸还有点疼，然后出幻觉了，醒来想抽烟。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;陈敏茹没有注意，除尘罐瓶身的注意事项写明：勿暴露在40摄氏度以上环境中，勿投入火中。该产品说明中还标注：需远离热源，防止爆罐。当天，房间里有四五十瓶除尘罐，有的还没有吸完。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;18日凌晨3时许，陈敏茹按下了打火机，邻床19岁的郭桢睡得正香，两个女孩的命运自此彻底扭转，背后的两个家庭一并坠入深渊。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我忘了我吸多少罐”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;先是天花板上的灯“砰”的一声，爆了。陈敏茹的脸离打火机最近，先着起了火，哭嚎着在地上滚来滚去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几个女孩陆续惊醒，身上也亮起火星子，急得在房间里乱窜。门拉不开，她们跑进卫生间打开花洒，“但水是热的，烫，我们又跑出去。”陈敏茹回忆。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭桢还在熟睡，她的反应慢许多。事后她回忆，当被好朋友拽起时，她还迷迷糊糊，看到眼前的大火失了神。靠墙的窗帘、被罩全是火，越烧越旺。直到约10分钟后，郭桢打开从内反锁的门，才注意到自己的双手已经皮肉外翻，指关节清晰可见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这一幕，被酒店对面楼的居民拍下来。一段当晚拍摄的视频显示，501室的窗户冒出熊熊大火，噼里啪啦的声音里夹杂着女孩们的呼救。8人从5楼顺着楼梯跑下去，在大马路上拦住一辆巡视的警车，救护车和消防车后续赶到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年6月18日凌晨，事发现场附近居民拍到火势。（受访者供图/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/851fb0350f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/851fb0350f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255331&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年6月18日凌晨，事发现场附近居民拍到火势。（受访者供图/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;早晨6点多，陈帅还没进商洛市中心医院急诊室的门，远远&lt;span>;就&lt;/span>;闻到一股皮肤烧焦的味道，“头发炸炸，都认不出来谁是谁”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;8个烧得焦黑的孩子躺在担架上，一排摆开。陈帅看到一个红头发的女孩，确定那是妹妹陈敏茹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭桢的母亲贺玮莉来得更早。郭父回忆，6月18日凌晨4点，妻子接到警察电话说女儿在医院，扑进来就抱住一个姑娘哭。旁边的郭桢发出颤颤的声音，“妈，我在这儿”，随即晕了过去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;经医生诊断，8人中属陈敏茹和郭桢烧伤最严重，被建议送到西安的大医院治疗。她们烧伤创面分布于头面部、前后躯干和四肢，等级均在Ⅱ-Ⅲ度。陈敏茹体表烧伤面积高达75%，郭桢在60%-69%，均属于特重烧伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;其余6人为轻伤。其中最轻的只伤及小腿皮肤，第二天就可以下地活动。5人烧伤面遍布四肢，至今都在家敷药自愈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位四肢烧伤的女孩总结道，“罪魁祸首”有两个人，一个是点烟的，另一个就是组织大家吸除尘罐的徐可欣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;徐可欣，一个出身于商洛农村的15岁女孩。跟她一起玩的圈里人说，徐可欣家境贫苦，但早早出来混社会的她却从不差钱，吃穿用的档次，都高出圈子里一大截。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“她说，吸了&#39;爽太太&#39;，让我试一下。”2023年年初，郭桢在西安和徐可欣玩时，第一次碰高压除尘罐，“吸了一口，感觉味道特别恶心，吸不进去，后来就能接受了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她还见过徐可欣捧着另一种叫不上名字的铝罐吸食，“特别大的罐子，她说吸完之后，比除尘罐爽多了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;陕西商洛，除尘罐爆炸事发地。（南方周末记者郑丹/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6743675af5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;808&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6743675af5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255332&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;陕西商洛，除尘罐爆炸事发地。（南方周末记者郑丹/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭桢回忆，事发当晚，徐可欣“等不及了，特别想吸”，便在如澜酒店开好房，招呼朋友们过来一起吸除尘罐，前后两次下单，以一罐80元的高价购买同城现货，很快送到酒店房间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“在网上买一瓶十来块钱，从别人手上买是80块钱。”10月9日晚，徐可欣在电话里告诉南方周末记者，自己当晚买的除尘罐数量有四五十罐，“那个东西一打就想睡觉，我忘了我吸多少罐”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“管不住，没办法”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月9日下午，南方周末记者走进陈敏茹的病房，一股浓浓的烧伤膏味扑面而来。她正靠两个胳膊肘和脚后跟支撑起身板，轮流抬起缠满绷带的双腿，缓缓横向挪动到靠窗的病床上，她要离阳光更近一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这是陈敏茹烧伤后第4个月，身体已经植皮2次，面部遍布坑坑洼洼的疤痕，&lt;span>;皮肤&lt;/span>;凝似塑面，甚至反光。这与她朋友圈、短视频账号里那个眼神灵动的女孩，判若两人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;视频里，陈敏茹皮肤白皙，大眼睛，嘟嘟唇。她有周边朋友都羡慕的身材，165cm的身高，喜欢穿超短裤和JK制服。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;陈敏茹在烧伤前的照片。（受访者供图/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/93b62d9453.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;756&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/93b62d9453.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255333&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;陈敏茹在烧伤前的照片。（受访者供图/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;郭桢躺在距离陈敏茹两个病房的30号病床上，全身上下裹满纱布，除了胳膊和手能小幅度活动，其他部位完全动弹不得。和陈敏茹一样，昔日短视频里的她打扮精致，丝毫看不出家境普通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“这就是混社会、不学好的人才发的。”2022年，陈帅第一次加妹妹微信，刷了一遍朋友圈，觉得她变化很大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;陈敏茹有两个哥哥，23岁的陈帅是老大，但陈敏茹与哥哥们从小到大没见过几次面。2009年，陈敏茹3岁，父亲因罪入狱服刑，母亲潘娅芳因此受了刺激，精神失常，这个家分崩离析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我奶奶把两个哥哥接到老家，他们重男轻女，不要我。”跟着潘娅芳流浪的生活，让陈敏茹时常恨自己的出身，她盯着病房的天花板掉眼泪，“家里人都讨厌我，我就不该出生在这个家”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;陈敏茹的奶奶听说后，哭着解释，“家里条件不好，养不起啊。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈敏茹在五岁时，跟着潘娅芳坐火车前往西安混生计。西安太大，潘娅芳只知道老火车站，母女俩就在火车站&lt;span>;旁&lt;/span>;的城墙根流浪，每天靠着帮扶流浪汉的救助站给食物填饱肚子。流浪一段时间，潘娅芳会带女儿回商洛，寄宿在姐姐或哥哥家。她没有钱，也舍不得花钱，陈敏茹自称学会了偷亲戚的钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;潘娅芳始终是一副头发蓬乱的样子，印堂一抹鸡血，手腕和脖子戴了三串五颜六色的塑料珠，这都是她从庙里求来辟邪的法宝。陈敏茹说，母亲不会做饭，也不着家，时常在外面跳舞，以至于陈敏茹曾走丢过十多天，失足掉进水池里，差点呛死。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“这根本就不叫一个家，感觉都像陌生人一样。”日子稀里糊涂的过着，陈敏茹成为一个典型的叛逆女孩，她形容自己“有点混社会”，通过亲戚的人脉进了一所职业中学，不想上学，经常去朋友家过夜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年，在外打工的陈帅回到商洛，在一家汽车厂打工赚钱。他主动联系到陈敏茹，认真地聊过一次天，如果陈敏茹愿意的话，他可以承担父亲的角色。陈敏茹毫不犹豫地答应了，“我哥说，他会尽他的能力，管我到18岁。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;陈帅约束妹妹的第一个条件，就是不要再跟混社会的人玩。陈敏茹显然没有听，她还是会逃课去找朋友，也曾在醉酒后，把一个十四五岁的小孩打得鼻青脸肿，以至于警察打电话给陈帅。他用陕西话形容，妹妹就是个“二杆子”，没有脑子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭增虎称也接过不少派出所的电话，全是因为女儿郭桢。不是郭桢叫一帮朋友把别人打了，就是有人叫一帮朋友打了郭桢，“整天都是那样，也不念书”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如果没有发生这场事故，郭桢和郭增虎仍然形同陌路，他们早就口头断绝了父女关系，两年没有联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我管不住她，她是男孩子性格，野得很。”贺玮莉说，对于这个女儿，夫妻俩没有一点办法。郭增虎也无奈，他已经57岁了，还要为女儿操心。“管不住，都叫不到跟前来，一年半载的不回来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自打17岁，郭桢就离家出走，换过几份工作，最后跟着两个朋友在酒吧做服务员。对于郭桢早早就抽烟喝酒这件事，郭增虎不知情，但听到也不惊讶，“咱农村说，啥人交啥样的朋友，她们那圈都是这样，跟着那帮娃耍，没啥好习惯”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月9日，陕西商洛，贺玮莉照顾郭桢吃晚饭。（ 南方周末记者郑丹/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6a2dc04b8c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/6a2dc04b8c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255334&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月9日，陕西商洛，贺玮莉照顾郭桢吃晚饭。（ 南方周末记者郑丹/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“就是不想回家”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;最开始不是这样的。郭增虎怀念小时候的郭桢，“乖得很，特别乖。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;郭桢六七岁时，就会收拾屋子。郭增虎夫妻下地种玉米回来，这个小女儿会将洗脸水端到跟前。一次，小郭桢在帮忙烧水时，胳膊不小心伸进了煮沸水的铁锅里，臂膀烫伤一大片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我最重视的，就是这个女儿。”郭家有三个女儿，以前家庭条件不好，老大念书到半路辍学；老二生下来就被送到亲戚家寄养。最后是老三郭桢，郭增虎下决心要培养好小女儿，不留遗憾，“我让她好好念书，能学到啥地步，屋里想尽一切办法都会供出来”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭桢也算争气，小学后考上了商洛最好的私立初中。郭增虎便从农村举家搬到城里生活。中考时，郭桢又考上了当地最好的商洛中学，只是没到一年，就因打架被学校开除了。郭增虎恨铁不成钢，“那两女子常说我偏心，嫌我最重视郭桢，没想到最后成了这样子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“就是老家下来到城里念书，变坏了。”在郭增虎的印象里，初中的老师几次通知他去学校，建议郭桢转学，别在城里头了，尽交些不三不四的朋友。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在郭桢看来，这件事情成了心结，因为她害怕郭增虎。自小学开始，她就不敢让爸爸去参加家长会，怕他听到不好的评价又发脾气。但凡一道题不会做，郭增虎就当着很多人的面，拾起扫帚追打&lt;span>;她&lt;/span>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;初中老师反映问题后，郭增虎的态度更严厉了。“我爸开始骂我，我必须天天盯着书看。我那时候还特别乖，但老师说我和外面社会上的二流子混到一起，不让我的好朋友跟我玩，一直针对我。”郭桢说，她心里憋屈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那段时间，老师布置作业多，郭桢压力逐渐变大，“我学习本来也不好，他们就不理解，考不好会说我，考好了也不夸，没有动力，感觉家里待不住，再加上我在班上谈了个对象，吵架，就整晚哭。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;她开始经常失眠，半夜被噩梦吓得胡喊，主动给贺玮莉看手腕上自残留下的疤痕，“妈，我要是跳到水库里，鱼咬我怎么办？”“我要是爬到房顶上，摔不死但摔残疾了怎么办？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;贺玮莉没念过书，她不懂这些，就带女儿去西安的大医院看病，花了八九千元，也没看出来问题。“医生说，娃压力太大，家里管得太严了，给娃些时间和空间，放松些，或许还能好。”贺玮莉猜测，娃从小一直被她爸连打带骂，搞抑郁了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;而那个小时候臂膀上烫伤的疤痕，被郭桢悄悄&lt;span>;文&lt;/span>;上一个非主流风格的图案，盖住了。图案是一只伤痕累累的双头玩偶熊，一个头面无表情，另一个头睁大空洞的双眼，露出一嘴獠牙。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;郭桢在胳膊伤疤上文的图案。（南方周末记者郑丹/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/be5077424b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/be5077424b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255335&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;郭桢在胳膊伤疤上文的图案。（南方周末记者郑丹/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;郭桢情绪出问题后，郭增虎也头疼，“我嘴笨，娃是女娃，我不知道咋沟通。”就这样，郭桢被“放松了”。他发现，女儿的脾气越来越大。“我轻轻打她一下，她恨不得把楼都吼塌，又要跳楼，最后根本不到屋里来，一说她，她就出去住。打电话不接，信息不回，你说这最后能咋弄？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;直到郭桢念到高一时，被商洛中学开除，郭增虎再一次动手打了她，提出断绝父女关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“他不仅自己打，还打电话叫我姐回来打我，我姐一个台灯砸我头上。”打那以后，郭桢搬出了家，每次贺玮莉叫她回家，她都会先问一句，爸爸在不在家。“他只会骂人，一直打我，扇巴掌，拿棍在身上打，反正就是不想回家。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;有一天，郭增虎在路上碰到了失联许久的郭桢，又在大庭广众之下扇了她几记耳光。郭桢第一次有了还手的想法，她打电话报警了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;提起这件事，郭桢哭得喘不过气。一旁的&lt;span>;贺&lt;/span>;玮莉&lt;span>;很&lt;/span>;惊讶，除尘罐爆炸事故后，她没见过女儿掉过一滴泪。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;被拖垮的家庭&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;郭桢看到一向板着脸的郭增虎哭了，天天哭。“他每天趴我旁边看着我，看着看着就哭了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“医院开始说，希望不是很大。”郭增虎回忆，刚去西安的医院时，医生就通知他做好心理准备，因为郭桢肺部烧伤严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在西安住院五十多天，郭增虎看女儿植皮4次，身上的伤烂了，好了，又烂了，反反复复，后背取皮后始终糜烂，“越看越没希望，最坏的打算是，我想跳楼，我支撑不起了”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;郭桢主动提出放弃治疗，“不想治了，你们回去吧，不用管我”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我真的不想管她了，但&lt;span>;她&lt;/span>;毕竟是我女子，舍不得。”郭增虎的确没钱继续治疗了，他只是一名在工地干活的工人，到了打板栗的季节，到处收板栗，这么多年积攒了不到10万元，又跟亲戚筹了30多万，全搭进去还不够。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;陈帅经历着与郭增虎一模一样的煎熬。陈敏茹出事后，他将认识的不认识的亲戚都借遍，凑够40万元，在西安住了40天院就耗不住了，只得将妹妹拉回商洛市中心医院继续治疗。后期，又欠了商洛市中心医院4万多，被医院一遍遍催缴费后，他不再去医院，陈敏茹被迫停了药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“她要是学好，我把命给她都行，但她不听话。”陈帅把头缩&lt;span>;进&lt;/span>;领口，声音低沉。起初，这个23岁的男孩几次拒绝采访，他想狠下心来，远离关于妹妹的一切。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这些年，陈帅过&lt;span>;得&lt;/span>;其实不比陈敏茹好多少。虽然被爷爷奶奶接管，但也处于散养状态。8岁就跟着二流子们进超市偷零食充饥，长大后整日泡在网吧，只为混个住处，13岁开始在外面打杂，自己赚钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;走近这个陌生的妹妹，让他原本紧巴巴的日子雪上加霜。短短一年间，陈敏茹先是骑电动车，掉沟里摔得严重；又三番五次因为身子弱，晕倒住进医院；有一次陈敏茹阑尾炎发作，做手术需要两三万，都是陈帅处理的。尤其让他心凉的是，陈敏茹瞒着他旷课。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“她说她上学去了，我问老师，老师说她没去，她也不回家，就在外面混。”这件事让陈帅火大，“只要你一句话，说不要我管你了，我以后绝对不管”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;陈敏茹态度也坚决，回了一句，“你不要管我了。”自此，两人断了联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;直到事发前一天，临近端午节。陈帅已经两个月没有见过陈敏茹，他主动发消息过去，说家里包了粽子。陈敏茹也希望兄妹关系能缓和，答应过两天就回老家吃粽子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;兄妹俩再见，就是在医院了，陈帅对这个妹妹又恨又心疼，“那时候，我真想不管她了，这都是她自己造成的”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除尘罐引发的这场大火彻底压垮了陈帅。他辞去工作，卖了价值一万三的摩托车，几近身无分文，还背上了40多万的债务。即使不去医院，母亲和妹妹吃饭钱也只能依赖他。他无心再找工作，白天睡觉，晚上胡思乱想，觉得生活浑浑噩噩，“我现在不知道我该做什么，做什么都没有动力了”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;悔恨与怀念&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;有那么一刻，郭增虎以为，离经叛道的女儿即将回到正轨，“要有个人样儿了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“出事那天下午，她叫的货拉拉，把大箱小箱的东西全都搬回来了。”郭增虎听女儿说，自己以后在家里住。“我一看，她也不在外头住了，像是回心转意了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;郭桢没有告诉郭增虎的是，她是被房东赶出来的，因为徐可欣总带朋友去出租屋里玩。这晚，郭桢出门后，贺玮莉打了几个电话，想叫她回家，郭桢还是没有接。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;真正的回心转意，是在病床上。郭桢跟父亲一次次说，她真的知道错了。但当得知郭桢还是会跟徐可欣保持联系时，郭增虎气得一次次骂郭桢死不悔改。“她到现在都没悔改自己，还跟那些人联系。我现在就是想尽最大努力把娃看好，治好以后，她爱干啥干啥，我就不管她了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但对于郭桢而言，她只有这些朋友，大家都来自农村，有差不多的家庭背景和喜好，“我跟她们在一起是快乐的，想说啥说啥，想干啥干啥”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“她没听我的话。”郭增虎想想都害怕，医院说郭桢恢复之后也不能变回正常的皮肤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“对女孩子来说，最重要的就是脸。”出事后，原本话多的陈敏茹变&lt;span>;得&lt;/span>;沉默寡言。她尤其对毁容耿耿于怀，脑子里一直回旋着过去的一幕幕，自己明明有很多个机会避免这场灾难。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我不知道吸那个东西，不能打火。”陈敏茹说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“如果时间能回到以前，我就不会从江苏回来。”事发前一天，陈敏茹刚从江苏实习回到商洛。说是实习，实际是职校安排的暑假劳务派遣工作。她被学校派到一个电视&lt;span>;机&lt;/span>;厂，每天穿着防尘服在车间的流水线上站12个小时，从早晨7:00站到傍晚7:30，两个月下来，赚了5000多元。对她来说，这是一笔不菲的数目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那段打工的日子虽然辛苦，但员工宿舍宽敞，过得也顺心。想来想去，陈敏茹也懊悔，为什么当初没有听哥哥的话，“当时太混了，那种状态，时间长都习惯了”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从西安转回商洛住院以后，陈敏茹听说了一起发生在商洛的类似事故。一群孩子聚在一起吸除尘罐，其中一个13岁的男生，为了寻求快乐的感觉，还吞下了40片药，“据说他出现的幻觉特别恐怖，全是绿色的，又快乐又痛苦”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;网购平台上，疑似吸食者对除尘罐商品的评论。网络截图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b4fc584eb0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;975&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/b4fc584eb0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;网购平台上，疑似吸食者对除尘罐商品的评论。（网络截图/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;最后，男孩缩在地上浑身抽搐，口吐白沫，叫伙伴们赶紧打120。“另外几个人不敢报警，最后他们敢叫救护车的时候，人拉到医院已经死了。”陈敏茹叹了口气，“至少我还活着，算幸运了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但她很快就不这么认为了。每到夜晚来临，身体的每一寸皮肤和骨头缝都是疼的。让她更难受的是，没有独立生活能力的母亲并不会照顾人，她神神叨叨，自顾自地滔滔不绝，还会突然情绪失控，指着陈敏茹大骂她没有良心，病房里争吵不断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我还不如死了算了。”陈敏茹别过头，眼泪溢出来，她用力吼，“你能不能看我这可怜，再不要说我了。”可冷静下来，看潘娅芳吃发霉的剩饭，陈敏茹又心疼，“流浪这些年，我恨过她，但她能把我拉扯这么大，很不容易”&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;10月21日晚，陈敏茹发了一条朋友圈，那是一段以前与闺蜜的合拍，视频中的她鼓着腮，鼻尖加了萌宠滤镜，摇头晃脑，扮相可爱。她写下三个字：“很怀念。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（文中陈敏茹、郭桢、徐可欣、潘娅芳为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“不出奇葩政策”：搞好中国足球，“不做什么”比“要做什么”更重要丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259252]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;10月22日，中国足协新任主席宋凯在一次座谈会上明确表示，“中国足协绝不能再出奇葩政策，这是底线，所出台的政策要符合社会预期”，这一表态引发广泛关注与热议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次宋凯履新面临的情况是，足坛反腐的风暴余波荡漾，社会各界对中国足球啧有烦言、物议不少，中国足球仍然处在低谷期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次宋凯“不能出奇葩政策”的发言，为他赢得不少肯定之声。原因无他，中国足协在过往几年推出了不少事倍功半乃至适得其反的奇葩政策。以前几年足协推出的“U23（23岁以下）球员新政”为例，这项政策初衷是让年轻球员在联赛中得到更多的出场时间，培养更多优秀国内球员。但从政策制定到执行的过程中，外界目睹了一场场“奇葩无下限”的闹剧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017赛季职业联赛，中国足协的规定是，报名的18人名单中必须有两名U23球员，其中必须有一人首发。结果各个球队为了优先保证成绩，搞出了“换上年轻球员就换下”“补时阶段再换上来刷数据”的操作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在2018赛季，足协将这项政策升级为“U23球员上场人数不可少于外援登场人数”。这项政策最终事与愿违，各个球队宁肯不上外援，也不敢给U23球员机会，如何安排U23球员登场“刷数据”，甚至成了各队教练的“算术题”。 2023年，U23政策只得取消。在六七年的时间里，这项政策成了典型的“任务蠕变”，目标与手段完全脱节，还虚耗大量资源。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;U23政策的奇葩之处，在于违背足球运动的根本规律，也违背职业联赛的市场规律。年轻球员如果有实力，不需要政策帮助也能抢到出场时间；没能力的年轻球员即便强行给他们时间，也不会赢得首发位置。强行要求“给机会”，看似在锻炼年轻球员，最终却伤害了所有人的利益。这番强行倒果为因的操作不但惹来外界嗤笑，揠苗助长的过程也收获一地鸡毛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;U23政策也仅仅是中国足协不少奇葩政策中的一种。因此，如果想让中国足协的工作“符合社会预期”的话，如果想搞好中国足球的话，应当考虑的未必是“中国足协应当做什么”，反而是“中国足协不应做什么”，这恐怕才是新一届足协领导班子应当记取的教训。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从宋凯的发言看，“不能出奇葩政策”是立论的基调，也有“青少年竞赛体系一定要保持稳定”的愿景，表现出拨乱反正的雄心。其实顺着这个思路延展下去，还可以深入思考，“中国足协”与“中国足球”究竟应该呈现什么样的二元关系，才能更好地满足社会期待。或者说得更直接一些，搞好中国足球，难道就真的只能靠中国足协吗？答案恐怕并非如此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;评价一国足球是否繁荣，同样不能单纯以国家队的比赛成绩作为标准，在此之外还有联赛体系、足球产业、足球文化等多个领域。而在这些领域，一国足协是没有能力大包大揽，也没有权力去发号施令的。指望以行政之手就可以振兴一国足球，是完全说不通的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;足球是一门非常科学的运动，回归客观规律才能真正搞好足球，而这需要全社会的共同努力。中国足协还是不应太高估自身的能力，更不能人为扩张自身权力，指望以一己之力可以从根本上改进“中国足球”这么一个庞大的复合概念。与其说中国足协的目标是做好中国足球的管理者，倒不如说应该朝着一个好的服务者努力，做好行政服务的工作，让民间足球机构自己做主，让市场来判断选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，中国足球并不缺乏民间基础。中超联赛的高上座率，“村超”的火爆满场，都在显示中国足球文化的潜力与足球产业的可能。中国足协应当做的是尊重民间足球体系的自治与自建，至少不去用“奇葩政策”破坏仍在繁育生长的足球土壤。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿根廷名宿巴尔达诺曾表示，“足球不属于任何一个人，所有人都要对这项奇妙的运动有一点主人翁意识，足球亦需要所有人都对它有一点掌控。否则的话，权力过度集中必然产生腐败，即便是足球这个行业，也没有人能超越这个规律。”从管办分离到“做好服务”，中国足协“不出奇葩政策”的表态只是迈出了第一步，是时候把足球这项奇妙的运动，交给每一个爱好足球的人了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿科爆满，耐药棘手，肺炎支原体流行何时休？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259242]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[与熊猫为邻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259248]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ZYWGGcKQBM7O1YhwAkAkp75RvRfakwsD4D6GD7Xe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1259&quot; height=&quot;916&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ZYWGGcKQBM7O1YhwAkAkp75RvRfakwsD4D6GD7Xe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;红外相机拍摄到野生大熊猫路过&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不用怀疑我的技术。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四川绵阳平武县的传奇猎人钟俊德眯着眼睛指向对面的山坡。他头发花白，干瘦的身体看起来十分灵活，讲话讲到得意处，便是这样眯起眼睛，从椅背直起身，翘起二郎腿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那里有一只野猪。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山坡上风平浪静。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你如果多待一天，我马上就给你把野猪打下来吃了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个老头又在开玩笑了。如今这山里若还有什么人打猎，都必然躲着他走。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当年的传奇猎人钟俊德在因倒卖熊猫皮而锒铛入狱之前，猎杀过林麝、毛冠鹿、“四不像”，以及数量无法统计的麂子和野猪。猎人职业的巅峰期，他和同伙们曾在3天里让9头羚牛倒地不起，收获总重量超过3吨的肉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而如今，他是新驿村巡护队队长，带着一队昔日的猎人们巡山，林子里什么东西该有，什么东西不该有，他们再明了不过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“什么季节下猎套，什么季节该去反盗猎，我们是绝对有把握的。”他说，“像了解自己一样了解他（它）们。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/FIC7PnPtR8FgnJQroVD5UH03ETwB22IMLxvHaCPf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/FIC7PnPtR8FgnJQroVD5UH03ETwB22IMLxvHaCPf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255304&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;钟俊德展示自己以前打猎的弩。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（刘辉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;猎人、村庄和山林&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“靠山吃山”，在山区，狩猎有着悠久的历史，平武也不例外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;猎人拥有独特的自然知识。他们掌握72种咒语，会根据太阳的运动轨迹，将山脉分作阴、阳、公、母，在他们眼中，山不是由泥土和草木而是由不同动物的活动轨迹拼接在一起的，泥土滚落、草木摆动，仅仅是为了显露出动物的移动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“藏族人吃糌粑，我们汉族就爱吃干饭。动物也是一样。”老猎人用理解人类的方式理解野生动物：羚牛爱吃树梢上的叶、悬崖上毛茸茸的草，所以它们得待在阴山；可麂子和毛冠鹿，就喜欢阳山。大熊猫要复杂一些，它们会相时而动：5月至7月间，它们遍山跑，四处寻着新鲜的笋子；热天呢，它们就喜坐高山；冬天因为要产子，它们就找半阴半阳之所，有水源、有食物，也要晒得着太阳。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/KLZ7vbgwAk3tMr0RFpHxZuL4ZxSuEpPyk8U0yvVq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/KLZ7vbgwAk3tMr0RFpHxZuL4ZxSuEpPyk8U0yvVq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255308&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;出现在老河沟自然保护中心的毛冠鹿。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（吴雨辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1961年出生的钟俊德，7岁那年和父亲打到一只熊猫后，认为这种肉质棉柴、滂臭的动物难下咽。那时的猎人也因此并不喜打熊猫，有时只是碰上了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;羚牛通常最受狩猎者欢迎。14岁那年，得知忙着回村报到挣工分的父亲没能把一头羚牛打死，钟俊德约了朋友，拿上猎枪，朝它前腿和胸部相连的位置开了一枪，便让那头羚牛陷入永恒的沉睡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;饥饿和贫穷能让猎人们驮上比他们自己还重的羚牛尸体。尸体装在一种棕树纤维制成的镂空双肩袋里，那股近似山羊的膻味，会在扛肉者的身体上停留很长时间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20世纪80年代，市场上忽然涌现出对熊猫皮和麝香的追捧，有人曾相信，麝香有“起死回生”的功效，而睡在熊猫皮上，能交到好运。男人们拿上土炮和用牙膏铅皮熔炼出的子弹，踏遍每一处竹林和灌木丛。当地人回忆，曾有熊猫皮被炒到50万元一张的天价。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接下来是持续多年的严打。1987年，最高法出台司法解释，指出倒卖、走私熊猫皮最高可判处死刑。然而严打并没有让盗猎行为锐减，新驿村就是盗猎熊猫的重灾区。全村一百六十多户人，就有四十多户的户主被捕入狱，村子成了所谓的“寡妇村”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多老猎人在追忆往事时，都会提到没日没夜踏入丛林前的人生经历：结婚、生子、再生子。在贫困的生活和养家的压力面前，男人们不会轻易放弃打猎——大山是他们近乎唯一的依靠。一斤玉米几毛钱，到省城打工每天几块钱，而麝香呢？克价直接等同于黄金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在离新驿村不远的福寿村，猎人强清贵因曾在一个冬天连续捕获了13只林麝而名声大噪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WjRgUuinuvnQDoULJOJMmetEbPVUM0RKpqgZuzEb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/WjRgUuinuvnQDoULJOJMmetEbPVUM0RKpqgZuzEb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255305&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;绵阳市平武县福寿村，强清贵展示自己已经废弃的捕猎工具。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孙晓晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些村庄的日常生活与狩猎紧密勾连，大部分村民，即便没有参与过，也都知道剥开熊猫皮需要从熊猫的腋窝下开刀，才能让皮草完整无缺；2000年之前出生的人，多半在村里红白事的筵席上吃过羚牛肉，煮的或是红烧，“拿不出羚牛肉的人家，面上无光”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在所有男孩都要进丛林寻找猎物的村庄，甘明东从小自视为一个猎手。他1994年出生在平武县的高村，乡镇上只有一条一眼能望到头的街道。他的父母找不到其他活路，在他6岁之后就外出务工。他爷爷，一位老兵，能给予他的教育是，零花钱每天两块钱，“如果打了架，就给五块”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;男孩们一起打猎时，兴奋支配着所有人的行动。打下猎物，荷尔蒙分泌达到顶点，并在一次次相互比试中循环强化。但甘明东隐约感到一丝异样，在他拿到动物尸体的瞬间，会莫名涌起悲伤。但到“下一次捕猎时，又是更加凶猛的亢奋”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他也讨厌那些打猎只为取乐或精进枪法的做法。信佛的长辈虽然递给他猎枪，但也会叮嘱：你不得不吃肉的时候，才去打它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了捕猎，剩下只有谈恋爱和打架，后者这种人与人之间激烈的对抗是他最主要的生活内容。他每周最少打三次架，收保护费，然后把这些钱连同母亲的工资一起，再交给那些被他打碎骨头的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;甘明东的顽劣远近闻名。一次爸妈不在家，他进不去家门，在街上睡了一夜，乡上数不清的沾亲带故，没人施舍他一餐饭吃。早晨被不住前来骚扰的野狗咬醒，他去河坝洗了脸，用弹弓打了一只褐河乌，烤着吃了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村庄就像“一个死角”，“世界的尽头”。人们向山林求生存，以猎杀为自我存在的保证和凭据。而猎物们，就像散落在山脉里的小小金矿，分布之密，让人不会想到它们会有消失的一天。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“熊猫和黑熊，你更喜欢哪个？”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在世界上另外一群人眼里，“猎物”的生命跟自己一样平等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1996年，四川农业大学学生刘小庚毕业，来到唐家河国家级自然保护区工作。他的想法很单纯，这么成熟的保护区，对外交流也多，可以跟外国同行学到先进的东西，为我所用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;27年了，如今回忆起来，他印象最深的“一课”，来自一个在明尼苏达做过黑熊保护的美国小伙子。对方提问：你更喜欢熊猫，还是黑熊？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘小庚一时语塞，潦草地做出了选择：熊猫吧，更可爱一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国小伙子说，我更喜欢亚洲黑熊，因为它身上月牙形的斑，很好看，比明尼苏达的黑熊的月牙斑好看得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘小庚第一次发现，一个人保护动物的初衷可以这么简单：喜欢它。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1997年，北京大学环境生物学与生态学专业大三的学生王德智到秦岭实习。离驻地不到200米的山坡上，一只野生大熊猫正在吃竹子。这是导师潘文石教授研究的熊猫家庭的二女儿。潘教授轻声唤它的名字：“希望。”“希望”一边咀嚼，一边回过头来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时隔26年，王德智还记得那个时刻：“一种野生动物，一种非常平静的眼神，在我心里产生了巨大的冲击。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原本志向研究微观生物学的林场子弟王德智，在那一刻做出一个决定：“要做野生动物研究。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中国生物学泰斗潘文石那里，野生动物“研究”，其实就意味着“保护”。 他常在学生面前说的一句话是，“我们做很多研究，发表很多论文，但要是这个动物没有了，这些研究又有多大用？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;念研究生时，王德智跟着潘教授在广西崇左研究白头叶猴，长达8年，他和他的同学守着一片甘蔗地，用望远镜观察喀斯特山上的猴群。一只从出生起就被他观察的小猴子，王德智叫它“一一”。有一阵子一一不见了，直到村人送来一只被捕兽夹夹断了右臂的小猴。大家用火淬过的砍刀斩断了一一的残臂，它全程躺在王德智的怀里，安安静静。后来给它喂最爱的树叶，一一习惯性地伸出了右手。那又是王德智刻骨铭心的一刻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这种猴子是在岩壁上生活的，这是它躲避敌害最主要的方式。岩壁上，必须得四足攀爬——三点抓住成一个平面，另外一只（手脚）去够第四点（来移动）。”王德智说，“丢了那一只手，意味着它没有办法再在岩壁上生活。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一一变成了在陆地上行走的生物。没过多久，它走失，再也没有了踪迹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地人设置陷阱、捕获这种珍稀动物，可能抱有着某种“药”的寄托。这令王德智感到愤怒。但8年守着甘蔗地的日子让他逐渐意识到，“单纯去责备任何人都没有什么价值。真正应该做的，是找到一些机会，让（人和动物）两者都能生活得更好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2011年，刘小庚被邀请来平武县的老河沟林场做本底调查，一个新保护区正在筹划中。这里是传奇猎人们的家包围的区域，钟俊德、强清贵都生活在老河沟周边。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GFdGBGJRQkytLIvjdn0WsHE9HWzVh2kPRcXtTjFG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/GFdGBGJRQkytLIvjdn0WsHE9HWzVh2kPRcXtTjFG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255309&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;老河沟保护中心主任马剑。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孙晓晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平武素有“天下熊猫第一县”美誉，其辖内已建有多个保护区，根据全国第四次大熊猫资源调查结果，平武有野生大熊猫335只。老河沟国有林场位于平武县高村乡，连接了唐家河（川）和白水江（甘）两个国家级自然保护区，相当于两省几大保护区的大熊猫走廊。红外相机曾拍摄到大熊猫妈妈带着熊猫宝宝穿行林场的影像；2011年底，这里还拍摄到了野生大熊猫夜晚大啖羚牛肉的影像。老河沟是大熊猫的交通要道，生态系统复杂多样，但其时并不在任一保护区辖内，也就成了盗猎盛行之地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在王德智看来，老河沟具有保护价值不言而喻，这里有望被建成保护区的核心要点在于，历史条件给予了这里天然的保护机会。1970年代起，这里就是老林场，其中没有农户居住及放牧牲畜，环境纯粹，对生态的核心威胁，就是盗猎。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两年的本底调查结束后，刘小庚留了下来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年，四川西部自然保护基金会（四川桃花源生态保护基金会）与平武县签订为期50年的委托管理协议，由桃花源基金会筹集资金全面负责公益保护地的生态保护工作，老河沟成为中国第一个由政府把保护地委托给民间机构管理的试点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桃花源基金会由中国知名的企业家、艺术家、慈善家发起，专注于自然保护地的非营利环境保护。截至2023年，基金会在五个省管理着六个保护地，总面积527平方公里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年，桃花源基金会注册成立平武县老河沟自然保护中心，刘小庚任主任。王德智也加入了，任首席科学家，成为老河沟保护区的筹划者之一，他希望在这里抓住让人和动物都能生活得更好的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“乌托邦”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;陈二哥好像半辈子都在看护老河沟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈祥辉，1971年生人，土生土长的当地人，大家都叫他“二哥”。青年时，二哥子承父业，进入老河沟林场。1990年代，他看着一棵棵粗壮的桦树在他面前倒下，以每立方米500元的价格销往各地。这样的平淡生活过了几年后，二哥忽然发现，自己原本要和父亲一样，看护一辈子的林场，已经空无一物了，“树都是新栽种的，动物一只都看不到”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1998年，中国开始实施天然林保护工程，叫停区内采伐经营活动，林场职工面临巨大压力。陈二哥也曾试图外出打工，去了广东，后来退回到平武县城，最终回到林场：“你本身就是这个地方的，你得赶回去。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;21世纪头几年，二哥守着空荡荡的林场，一日三餐，与电视机相伴，日子过得比林场还空荡。路边冒出羊肚菌，山上长出了鲜嫩的笋子，他都懒得去弄一弄。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;故事在一通电话后转了弯。2011年，陈二哥接到电话，说有组织想在林场落地保护区，他立刻答应加入。他见过王朗保护区（也在平武县）的人，冲锋衣、户外鞋，“好大气，让人羡慕”，而且，有点燃生活希望的收入。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/M1vqZ1rYecs1vcIoqzZQ1Yek6NcAYTixQ2HaDLZS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/M1vqZ1rYecs1vcIoqzZQ1Yek6NcAYTixQ2HaDLZS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255306&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;天黑后，巡护员陈祥辉带队夜观野生动物。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孙晓晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一拨来调研的是成都中科院的两爬（两栖动物和爬行动物）专家，第二拨是武汉水生所的……他跟在这些老师的身后转，帮忙开车，帮忙做陷阱标记动物，称量之后再帮助放归，生活有了真实的内容，日子转得飞快。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我就死心塌地地跟着保护中心。”二哥说。2013年3月底，与保护中心的人一同翻山时，二哥发现了一种以前没见过的动物粪便，旋即打电话跟专家咨询。几天后，他带人背了12台红外相机进山，布设好；一个月后查看照片，当场给县林业局领导打电话：我们这里拍到老虎了！对方回：老虎个锤子哦！陕西的“周老虎”你晓得伐？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我知道是金猫，我就逗他开心。”沉默寡言的二哥少见地开起了玩笑。他记事起，偶尔从老人的口中听闻过，山中有“豹子”，“实际上就是金猫”。这是他第一次见到这个物种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘小庚及各路专家陆续进行了两年的本底调查，最高峰时，有四五十位学者聚在这里研究13个不同门类的动物。调查识别出以大熊猫及其栖息地为代表的7类主要保护对象，以及对生态产生威胁的最大原因盗猎，其根源“就在于保护区外村民生活和发展的压力”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为桃花源保护地蓝图的勾画者之一，王德智回忆，创设团队为老河沟构想了一个完全基于科学主义的保护计划。“一方面，保护区应该用最科学的方式来管理；另一方面，这么牛的保护规划，最主要提倡的不仅是关注保护地内部，还要关注保护地外面的村庄（福寿村、新驿村都包含其中），它们是保护的扩展。这个设计还拿了一个英国的奖，”王德智说，“那时候我觉得设计得简直就是一个乌托邦，太美好了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;热闹中，科学主义者们还没察觉，在村民们眼中，他们的工作却是另外一番意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;成为邻居&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;早在学生时代，王德智就在与保护区农户一次次的沟通中，感受过独属于生态保护者的惆怅和失落。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在广西崇左的8年，对猴子来说，王德智他们是观察者；对原住民来说，保护者与他们之间那堵墙，始终没有打破。王德智认为，当时保护生态只会从“表象”出发——当地人捕猎猴子，是为了用它的骨头泡酒医治关节病，因此潘文石推动当地卫生院升级改造；为了留住山上的树，团队又推动沼气池的建造；另外，还帮助当地修建了一所小学，从教育入手，希望改变人思考问题的方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;倾注资源的好处立竿见影，当地人变得“配合”——当着保护者的面。一旦保护者离开，他们会立刻抛弃沼气池，回到习惯的砍柴烧火上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在老河沟，为了让保护区周边的村民放弃狩猎，保护中心也想了不少办法，试图为村民寻找新的经济来源。却都在表面看起来大获成功之后急转直下，比如鼓励村民标准化养猪，保护中心承诺以高于市场价20%收购，但到了收购时，村民才得知不收下水，更不要说碰上非洲猪瘟等突发因素，回收不成。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“老百姓一肚子意见，说你们这帮人骗我们。”保护中心也很委屈，“大家都是处在一个摸索的阶段。我们哪会做生意啊！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保护中心还曾帮助保护区周边社区建蜂蜜酒厂，桃花源的理事们出了高价购买产品高价卖给理事，第一年蜂蜜酒厂便获得630万元的收益，一半覆盖成本，一半投入到保护工作，成绩喜人。结果第二年，生意又转不动了：“理事们反馈，那个酒太难喝”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生意做不成，老河沟也不好看。沟里，设计了26条巡护线路遍布全区，布设八十多个红外相机位点。但沟外村民的眼里，老河沟是自家的后山，去那里的土地庙祭拜，不需要经过任何人允许，不论杀鸡还是焚香，都是他们千百年来的传统与自由，他们包上一辆辆面包车，成群结队地来去，这给保护区的管理、防火等工作都造成了压力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保护中心尝试用当地人的思维来打破隔阂。祭祀时，他们也凑钱捐一只鸡，“专门交代这是保护区的鸡”，还说，同一块土地上做事，该着敬奉同一个神仙。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“成为邻居”，这是一套仍在探索的思路。保护中心的巡护员，除了在保护区里反盗猎，每年要花超过400小时做社区工作。在基金会看来，保护地的人为威胁大多来自周边社区，和居民交朋友才是发现、阻止、排除人为干扰的长久之道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;保护中心里，人人都要“下乡”走社区。基金会副总裁马剑家住深圳，现任老河沟保护中心主任的他，在老河沟时更像是村主任：走在村道上，向村民们点头问好，打着招呼熟络地推开农户家的门，一屁股坐到板凳上，边嗑瓜子，边问主人家手上的伤好点没，儿子、女儿过年有没有回家。“你做厨师的儿子长胖没？没有啊，人家可都说厨师不胖不是好厨子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/q3Y5jOg1k7ipvMT2v5NLCt8ovucLbTabvxqV2hpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/q3Y5jOg1k7ipvMT2v5NLCt8ovucLbTabvxqV2hpD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255310&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;马剑到平武县福寿村下乡走访。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孙晓晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;聊天不是唯一目的。已经是保护中心副主任的陈二哥有时仅绕屋一圈，就能知道谁家偷偷打猎。一次，他就在新驿村某农户的屋后石缝里，发现斑羚的毛发，又在灌木丛中找到雉鸡的羽毛。当晚他拉着村书记到农户屋里。第二天一早，这位农户又从森林里取回两副兽夹上交。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;既然是“邻居”，保护中心与周围村庄的关系，也应该是互相帮助。“以前老百姓都怀疑，你们把地围起来，钱都被你们挣走了。”马剑认为，巡护员要了解村民，村民也得知道，老河沟里的人究竟在干什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年，保护中心开设生态导赏员培训，首期有115位村民报名，培训成绩合格后，村民成为导赏员，只要遵守国家公园的管理规定，即可带游客进入保护区体验，不需要给保护区交钱，导赏费归属村民个人。如果违反规定，就像驾照管理一样，扣到6分重新参加培训，扣完12分就暂停导赏员资格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蜂蜜酒怎么酿，也已经不再是保护中心的职责，他们只做生态规划，明确可以养蜂的区域、数量，在遵守保护区规定的情况下，农户怎么做，就看他们自身的能力和心愿了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农忙时，保护中心会抽时间帮农户收玉米；村民采了野菜、摘了梨子、柿子，也随手扎两把给保护中心送来。有时，几个村子要联合办一次宴会，老河沟也必须和其他村子一样，出一个节目，尽管它并不是一个自然村的行政区划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种互利互助的邻里关系的成效，还在日常的细微之处。嗜好烟草的强清贵，抽完烟后，会熟练地用手指掐灭烟头，顺手揣进口袋里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不得乱扔垃圾，这是马老师教的。”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;还是要“靠山吃山”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;成为邻居的关键结果，是联合原住民，共同保护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年，在桃花源基金会的支持下，平武的新驿村、福寿村等相继成立了自己的巡护队。每年，这些老猎人都能从山上收获数十个猎套。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新驿村的巡护队，自然是钟俊德拉起来的。这个亦正亦邪的老头，组织了八个老猎人，开始了反盗猎。旁人问他为什么搞这个，他回答：不给钱我也要搞。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我当时起了一点私心。”他坦白，“我们这个沟沟里没有几个人，就是几个老年人在屋头。外面的人跑到我这个沟沟里，打猎也好，挖药也好，把我们的资源全弄跑了。组了巡护队，不管外来的人是打我沟沟里的动物，还是挖我沟沟里的草药，我把你逮着了，不准你拿起走。”但这种事，得“有个单位来给我撑腰”才行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UwtejEavJeswwrbiYclSQclkBXsUTQJvZXIIm5oU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1270&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/UwtejEavJeswwrbiYclSQclkBXsUTQJvZXIIm5oU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255312&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;钟俊德的家在山林间，旁边的山上，曾经是钟俊德猎杀的主阵地之一。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张蕾/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村书记坚决支持。在书记眼里，这是一雪“寡妇村”前耻的机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;桃花源这个“媒人”也来得正好。桃花源还给社区巡护队提供了装备，包括红外相机、电池等，为巡护员购买保险，以及配发统一的服装，每年工作做得好，基金会还会给与一定的奖励。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地人言，桃花源这样“保媒”，让钟俊德“把以前&#39;邪&#39;的做成了&#39;正&#39;的”。在福寿村也是如此，因打林麝而出名的强清贵，成了村里巡护队的队长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾经的矛，变成了如今的盾，猎人角色的转变改变着山林的面貌，但时间也过去了。他们都老了。强清贵如同一只步入老年的猎豹，他健硕的肌肉开始松弛，走路时步态谨慎，一颗眼球因为受伤而显露灰色。钟俊德的队伍，平均年龄将近六十。他们都在寻找继任者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/nikG5oZe3oCOhIuQSocfEGW2DKrxPZCzmFQrYNwL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/nikG5oZe3oCOhIuQSocfEGW2DKrxPZCzmFQrYNwL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255313&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;青年巡护员组成一队上山巡护。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孙晓晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小猎人长大了。在保护区内，桃花源招聘专职山林巡护员，曾经的顽劣小子甘明东以自己唯一的特长和热爱——爬山——应聘成功。他身形灵巧，在山林间，就如藤蔓间穿梭的猴子一样自如。刚成为巡护员的那一年，甘明东巡山的里程就达到了1700多公里，相当于绵阳到北京的距离。熊猫走过哪些路，会在什么地方出现，已经在他心里画出了路线图。在山林里行走的每一步，拆除的每一个猎套、兽夹，根据行踪判断红外相机的安装位置、捕捉到每一个稀有动物的身影，都使得天生的猎手成了天生的巡护员，“感受到自己还是有那么一点价值”。亲戚们眼中“肯定要吃牢饭”的青年人，如今“在做一件正事”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;村庄里的人们都渐渐看到保护的好处，不单是赶走了来自家地盘掠夺资源的外来人，还引入了愿意花钱来看山林里动物的游客。“金山银山就是这么变出来的。”钟俊德看懂了这当中的名堂，“就是过去说的&#39;靠山吃山&#39;。这个就是靠了山、吃了山。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在村里，人们如今因为钟俊德能够保护动物而不是伤害动物而对他倍加尊敬，这种尊重甚至比1980年代盗猎盛行时更加强烈。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;观念的转变是何时，以何种方式发生的？法律的健全、全民生活水平的提高，或许都是必要条件。而在王德智看来，更重要的是“看见”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“大家越来越相信这件事情，就是环境如果再破坏下去，我们的后代可能是没有未来的。”王德智说，“任何一种生命都没有办法单独在地球上生活，因为我们不可能自己吃自己。如果把每一种生命看作一个点，点和点之间都会有这样的连线，你总能够找到一条连线，是外界把能量传递到自己身上。但是当这样的一个物种消失的时候，那就意味着跟它相关的这些连线全部都消失。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在老河沟工作10年后，刘小庚到了桃花源在吉林的向海公益保护地，那里生态保护的主要威胁是过度放牧。以前，向海的保护主要依赖执法，但客观上讲，保护和发展的矛盾并不会因为执法有效而得到解决，冲突反而在逐年累积。况且，公益机构并没有执法权，这更需要他们走入当地人的生活。引导老百姓合理放牧，刘小庚主要靠“劝”，508户养牛羊，跟刘小庚“谈过心”的就超过398户。老百姓为躲着刘主任放牛，只好下半夜出动，结果刘主任就跟着凌晨3点去赶牛。因“碍于情面”，2022年下半年，向海保护地的过度放牧减少了70%——先成为“邻居”，再共同找到破局之道，外来者、原住民、自然，大家都在一条连线上。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;连接的时刻&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;或许在老河沟的每个人都感受过那种（重新）连接的时刻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那位让林麝闻风丧胆的猎人，在一次修公路时，撞见一只意外滚落的熊猫。现场所有30岁甚至年纪更大的工人们，把这坨圆滚滚的动物围住，每个男人都想去摸一摸它。熊猫被来自男人们的抚摸吓跑了。强清贵说，“野外的大熊猫，那个毛发，比所有的黑色更黑，也比所有的白色更白。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做巡护员越久，甘明东越喜欢看动物的眼睛，从中读解它们的心思，他见过刚出生的小羚牛纯洁的眼神，也见过第二天就死亡的老羚牛，在寻找自己的安息之地时，眼神中流出的迟暮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王德智的这个时刻来自成群的羚牛堵着他的车，不让路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/h8TWfWk1kPIoAZnKroUMYJ3lvf4bdnhhw3kZ9J54.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1658&quot; height=&quot;1106&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/h8TWfWk1kPIoAZnKroUMYJ3lvf4bdnhhw3kZ9J54.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255311&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在老河沟自然保护中心，巡护员夜观野生动物的途中，与羚牛相遇。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孙晓晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那个时候我真的感觉（老河沟）这个地方已经变得是野生动物的家了，这是我们最希望达到的，还自然以自然。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅从动物的遇见率上看，老河沟及其扩展区的保护工作取得的成绩斐然。原有的盗猎、滥伐活动基本杜绝，十多年来布设的红外相机累计拍摄到一百多万张照片，记录了12万分钟的动物活动影像。其中，红外相机拍到的一段亚洲金猫进食视频，在网上的观看量达到5亿——姑且可以看做亿万网友也与这只敏捷而凶猛的大猫建立了连接吧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/KjLXAN1LNWCu9GGSgjHEfIPmlpdx7qAQBwDomn2c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;845&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/KjLXAN1LNWCu9GGSgjHEfIPmlpdx7qAQBwDomn2c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255314&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;上山巡护期间，巡护员甘明东检查野外红外相机。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（孙晓晨/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于工作安排，刘小庚调离老河沟。那年开春，他遇到了三只毛冠鹿，其中一只正在生产。当巡护人员经过，两只行动自便的毛冠鹿没有本能地逃跑，而是选择守护在生产的母鹿身旁。刘小庚将这视作十年山林工作的馈赠，心满意足，超过了离别的伤感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在已经荒了的二楼茶亭，传奇猎人钟俊德俯瞰着自家小院，说过年时，这里就是花果山——他的孩子，他兄弟过世后被他领来养的孩子，他的孙子孙女，以及姊妹家的后生，都聚在这。他们衣食足、仓廪实，生活无虞。这个时刻，他的桀骜完全褪去，一张历经山林沧桑的脸上，闪烁着母性的柔光。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们在夜观时看到了林麝，这是马剑来老河沟保护中心当主任三年来一直想偶遇而不得的运气。但我们始终未得见溪边饮水的熊猫，据说那时的它们最是憨憨。但那种连接时刻也是有的：趟过布满史前白色巨蛋的河流后，走上坡，微风吹过，粉白色的四川杜鹃从空中纷纷落在我的肩膀上，腰身下方的灌木丛布满浆果。如果低头细细寻找，还能看到披针形的重楼。在接近溪流的地方，石头缝中冒出蓝紫色的川东紫堇，它花蕊的位置，有着玫瑰色的染晕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老师被挖走、学生招不满，崩塌的县中何去何从？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259202]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;两千多个县是中国基础的存在，它一头连接城市，一头连接乡村。它是小镇做题家的避风港，它蕴藏着最深沉、最厚重的感情。县中，是其中的稳定器。当城乡教育差距逐渐扩大，面对老师被挖走、学生招不满以及“超级中学”的上门挑战，县中该何去何从？</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 10:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>