<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[李佳琦直播间卖假和田玉？谈谈玉的文化、国标及科学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After online anchor Li Jiaqi was accused by JD.com’s purchasing staff of forcing him to “choose one from two” and questioned the alleged monopoly, he went on a professional crackdown on counterfeiting Wang Hai also questioned whether the Hetian jade sold in Li Jiaqi&#39;s live broadcast room was fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jade is a unique culture in China. The Chinese ancestors selected the &quot;beautiful stones&quot; from various stones. Jade is warm, shiny, meticulous and tough, so it is also considered by the Chinese to be benevolent and benevolent. Justice, wisdom, courage, and purity are the five moral qualities. Wearing jade has the effect of preventing evil spirits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese ancestors’ understanding of jade can be traced back to the Neolithic Age. Humans ground stone tools as tools for chopping and scraping, hunting, and cutting meat. Some ground stone tools showed a smooth and beautiful appearance, and humans began to have a preliminary understanding of jade. This also marks the beginning of the transition of human beings from material needs to spiritual needs. Archaeological research has found that in the late Neolithic Age, many jade products and jade ornaments appeared. At this time, the ancients had realized that jade and stone had completely different functions and aesthetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 3000 BC, jade craftsmanship was separated from stone tool processing technology and became an independent craft category. Based on the production traces left on the jades unearthed from the Hongshan Cultural Site and the Liangzhu Cultural Site, experts have inferred that a rotating jade processing tool - a weight machine - had appeared at that time. This is no different in principle from the jade processing machines we see now. The Shang and Zhou dynasties were the growth stage of Chinese jade art. The scope of use of jade expanded, and the number and types increased significantly. However, the shapes were still very simple, with only sporadic decorations. Hotan jade also appeared in this era for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Spring and Autumn Period and the Warring States Period, the art of jade carving developed. At that time, scholar-bureaucrats wore a series of jade ornaments all over their bodies. What reflected the spirit of the times at that time were a large number of jade pendants in the shapes of dragons, phoenixes and tigers, with complex and beautiful shapes and strong Chinese style and national characteristics. The jade pieces of the Tang Dynasty are all treasures. The craftsmanship was further developed and refined. The texture is warm and the luster is soft. Gold and jade complement each other, making them rich and elegant. In the Song Dynasty, jade gradually entered people&#39;s lives. Influenced by calligraphy and painting at that time, the style became more realistic and full of life. During the Ming and Qing Dynasties, jade art reached its peak, and various types of exquisite jade articles emerged in endlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The definition of real jade and non-real jade has long been reflected in the system of jade use in Chinese history. Hotan jade is the highest level of jade, it is real jade, and is used by emperors. After countless years, Hotan jade has just entered the folk world. The one that caused the controversy this time was Hetian jade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing Wang Hai’s doubts, Yuanyang Jinlou, the owner of the cargo in Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room, posted the appraisal certificates, including the National Jewelry and Jade Quality Supervision and Inspection Center (NGTC), Guangdong Gold and Silver Jewelry Testing Center Co., Ltd., National Gold and Silver Products Quality Inspection and Testing Center (Nanjing) Organization, Shenzhen Zhongdi Jewelry Testing Co., Ltd. These institutions are not without authority. So, what is the problem? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the question of whether it is fake. According to Wang Hai, GB/T38821-2020 stipulates that the appraisal certificate must have total mass and physical photos, and consumers received 18 appraisal certificates attached to the necklace. Not only are each 40g, but they are also photos of a shared necklace. , then it is suspected of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the problem of counterfeiting is easy to solve, but what is difficult to solve is the second level problem, which is the standard issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The standards used by these institutions are the national Hetian jade testing standards GB/T16552-2017 and GB/T16553-2017. This 2017 standard does not clearly stipulate the specific content of tremolite. As long as the main component is tremolite, it can be named &quot;Hetian Jade&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Hai adopts another standard, namely GB/T 38831-2020. The GB/T38821-2020 &quot;Hetian Jade Identification and Classification&quot; launched in 2020 was developed by the State Administration for Market Regulation and China Released by the National Standardization Administration Committee, it is the latest national standard for the Hetian jade industry. The mineral composition of Hetian jade is described as: &quot;Mainly composed of tremolite, the secondary mineral can be actinolite, and can contain a small amount of calcite, diopside, pyrite, pyrite, chromite, and magnetite. , quartz, serpentine, chlorite, epidote, wollastonite, apatite and garnet, etc.&quot; According to this standard, the naming rule is: when the percentage of other minerals in the same piece of jade is less than 5%, Hetian jade can be named directly. When the percentage of other minerals is more than 5% (except black jade), if the other minerals contained are evenly distributed and the boundaries of the mineral particles are clear, use &quot;tremolite jade&quot; with a note indicating that it contains other minerals. For example: tremolite jade (including tremolite jade) carbonates). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, things are clear. Both standards are used in the industry. The 2017 standard is more relaxed, while the 2020 standard is more stringent. However, this standard is not mandatory and is only a recommended standard. Jade sellers adopted the loose standards introduced in 2017, saying that their items were Hetian jade; while Wang Hai, who fights against counterfeiters, adopted a stricter standard in 2020, saying that the jade sold by Li Jiaqi was fake and did not meet the standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Objectively speaking, jade has been difficult to identify clearly since ancient times. What exactly is jade? In fact, many people don&#39;t understand. When we talk about what a thing is, it is actually a chemical question. Chemistry is the study of the composition of matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a chemical perspective, jade is actually a mixture. When we talk about gold, we refer to the material composed of gold atoms; when we talk about quartz, we refer to silicon dioxide; when we talk about ice, we refer to dihydrogen monoxide. Of course, minerals are mixed with other impurities, but in an abstract sense, these things are composed of single atoms or single compound molecules. But jade, in an abstract sense, is a mixture. For example, just like when we talk about Chinese medicinal soup and borscht soup, even in an abstract sense, it must be a mixture of multiple ingredients. Therefore, jade is a mixture, which is a mixture of two or more compounds and elements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this concept, it is easier to understand jade. Jade has different chemical compositions, different colors, and different types. The chemical composition of jadeite is sodium aluminum silicate, the most representative of which is jadeite. The chemical composition of nephrite is hydrous calcium magnesium silicate, the most representative of which is Hetian jade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, Hetian jade has four main mineral components: silicon, aluminum, iron and magnesium. Silicon accounts for a large proportion of Hetian jade, and its main forms are calcium silicate (CaSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;), magnesium silicate (MgSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;), and sodium disilicate (Na&lt; sub>;2&lt;/sub>;Si&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>;5&lt;/sub>;), etc.; the aluminum element is mainly albite (NaAlSi&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>; 8&lt;/sub>;), and also contains a small amount of aluminum silicate; iron mainly exists in the form of potassium ferroaluminate and iron silicate. It can be seen that Hetian jade has many ingredients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The charm of jade, its appeal to people in terms of look and feel, stems from this characteristic of jade&#39;s chemical composition. This has also caused various confusions in the naming, identification, and even price of jade. Some people say that the wholesale price of jade sold by Li Jiaqi is only a few dozen yuan. But then again, the wholesale price of tens of thousands of jade in those tourist attractions and jewelry stores may only be a few hundred yuan or less. This is the characteristic of the jade industry. As the old saying goes, &quot;Gold has a price, jade is priceless.&quot; This does not mean that gold is not as valuable as jade, and jade is a priceless treasure. It means that the price of jade has been confusing and confusing since ancient times, and the profits are often abnormally high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiaqi’s live broadcast room is said to have the lowest price on the entire Internet. Consumers believe it, but there is a gap between their expectations and reality. In fact, if you really want to buy cost-effective jade, the live broadcast room is not a good place. Only knowledgeable people with instruments can identify, and only with the ability to identify can we negotiate a good price. Obviously, most consumers cannot do this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[过度加工食物可能成瘾并严重影响健康]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCyJ69RpVgzEp0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCy J69RpVgzEp0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256141&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over-processing of food refers to industrial production and the addition of at least 5 or more ingredients, additives (usually sugar, stabilizers, preservatives, preservatives, pigments), etc., in this way Processed foods are called ultra-processed foods. Their purpose is to make them delicious and convenient, and more importantly, manufacturers can earn higher profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excessively processed foods include soft drinks such as cola, bread, cakes, potato chips, pizza, biscuits, candies, burgers, instant noodles, ice cream, spicy sticks, etc. More and more research results show that the intake of overly processed foods may be harmful to human health and increase the risk of various diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A recent study by Brazilian researchers suggests that overly processed foods may harm brain function. The reason is that overly processed foods contain many added and unhealthy ingredients such as sugar, salt, fat, artificial colors and preservatives. Past research has shown that overly processed foods are directly linked to an increased risk of heart disease, metabolic syndrome, and obesity, and now research is linking overly processed foods to a risk of decreased brain function. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers collected data on nearly 11,000 men and women in Brazil with an average age of 52 who participated in the Brazilian Longitudinal Study of Adult Health. The researchers followed them for a long time, with a median follow-up time of 8 years. The results found that participants who consumed more than 20% of their daily calories from ultra-processed foods experienced a 28% faster decline in overall cognitive function and a 25% faster decline in executive function compared to adults over 59 years old. In other words, the decline in cognitive function and executive function is more obvious among adults aged 35-59. Overall, overall cognitive functions include learning ability and memory, while executive functions include language fluency and behavioral agility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the researchers admit that they cannot yet explain the mechanism by which excessively processed foods lead to reduced brain function, and there is no neuroimaging to confirm their results. Therefore, future research is to explore which overly processed foods lead to cognitive decline in the body and the molecular mechanisms behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One possible explanation, however, is that when people regularly consume overly processed foods, they are less likely to get the fiber, microbes, minerals, and plants they need to stay healthy, fight off disease, and reduce inflammation. Nutrients. Ultimately, this may affect a person&#39;s brain function and functioning, as the brain requires a steady supply of these nutrients to function properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed foods have also been linked to cancer. Researchers from Imperial College London have found that high intakes of ultra-processed foods may increase an individual&#39;s risk of developing cancer and dying from cancer. Previously, a large number of studies have revealed that consuming large amounts of overly processed food will increase the incidence of obesity, type 2 diabetes, and cardiovascular disease. Now, British researchers have used the British Biobank to collect dietary information from 200,000 young people to study the relationship between body health and diet. This is the first such study to be conducted in the UK. The researchers monitored the people&#39;s health for 10 years, analyzing their risk of developing any cancer and 34 types of cancer, as well as the participants&#39; risk of dying from cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers conducted the most comprehensive assessment to date of the link between overly processed foods and people’s risk of developing cancer, including soda, industrially produced bread, and more. Ready-to-eat meals and most breakfast cereals. These foods often contain high levels of salt, sugar, fat, and artificial additives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that people who eat a lot of overly processed foods are at a greater risk of developing cancer. Overly processed foods are particularly related to ovarian cancer and brain cancer. They also increase an individual&#39;s risk of death from cancer, most obviously. of ovarian and breast cancer. For every 10% increase in a person&#39;s intake of overly processed foods in a person&#39;s diet, the overall risk of cancer increases by 2%, and the risk of ovarian cancer in particular increases by 19%. It is associated with a 6% increase in overall cancer mortality, a 16% increase in the risk of death from breast cancer, and a 30% increase in the risk of death from ovarian cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The association between excessively processed food intake and cancer remained after adjusting for social, economic, behavioral and dietary factors such as smoking, physical activity and body mass index (BMI). Furthermore, previous research has shown that British adults and children consume the highest amounts of ultra-processed food in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the study by British researchers cannot explain the causal relationship and mechanism between over-processed foods and cancer, they believe that existing research evidence shows that reducing the intake of over-processed foods in the daily diet may avoid Higher cancer rates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed food has become widespread around the world and is addictive. A research report published in the British Medical Journal on October 9, 2023 by researchers from the United States, Brazil, and Spain pointed out that an analysis of 281 studies in 36 different countries found that 14% of adults and adults worldwide 12% of children are addicted to over-processed foods, and 1/7 adults and 1/8 children may be addicted to over-processed foods. These foods include ice cream, carbonated drinks and convenience foods, which can lead to cancer, obesity and Increased risk of heart disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the consumption of ultra-processed foods is soaring around the world, and now more than half of the daily energy intake in the UK comes from ultra-processed foods. In the United States, ultra-processed foods account for 58% of Americans’ energy intake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fact that so many people eat over-processed foods suggests that they are addictive. Researchers explain the addiction to over-processed foods as higher levels of dopamine secretion may lead to over-processed foods. of addiction. Extracellular dopamine levels in the brain&#39;s striatum caused by refined carbohydrates or fats are similar to those of addictive substances such as nicotine and alcohol, thus creating a craving similar to alcoholism. Therefore, foods that contain high amounts of refined carbohydrates or added fats are likely to be addictive substances. The speed at which these overly processed foods deliver carbohydrates and fats to the intestines may also play a role in their addictive nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Symptoms of addiction to over-processed foods include: strong desire to eat, withdrawal symptoms, difficulty controlling food intake, and obesity, overeating, poor physical and mental health, and reduced quality of life. Despite this, he continued to eat without restraint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All of this suggests that the relationship between overly processed foods and health, as well as the addictive nature of such foods, should be further studied, and appropriate measures should be taken to protect people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京香山论坛：大国小国，平等对话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 10:06:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;&#39;Ten&#39; means maturity, perfection, harvest, and also indicates a new starting point and renewal. Let’s go.” On the morning of October 30, 2023, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, told officials from the defense departments of many countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held from October 29th to 31st, reaching the highest level and largest scale in history - more than 90 official delegations from countries and international organizations participated, including 19 defense ministers , 14 military commander-level representatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the podium at the opening ceremony, the &quot;ten&quot; in &quot;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum&quot; was painted in red. In the audience, foreign defense ministers, representatives of international institutions and experts are looking forward to an &quot;international security event&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. (Photo by Lu Huiqian/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/01/7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01 /7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256571&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Great powers play a more important role”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At nine o’clock in the morning on October 30, the main venue on the second floor of the Beijing International Convention Center was packed with seats. Dozens of defense ministers and senior representatives from various countries in military uniforms sat in the front row of the auditorium; the back row was divided into two floors and filled with nearly a thousand experts, observers or media members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Common Security, Lasting Peace&quot; is marked with white letters on a blue background inside and outside the venue - this is the theme of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum and the core idea of ​​the Global Security Initiative in February 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Youxia pointed out that without mutual respect, it will be difficult to coexist peacefully, and common security will be out of the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 19 defense ministers participating in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu was the first speaker. Before the opening ceremony, Shaoyigu and Zhang Youxia walked into the main venue side by side and sat in the center of the first row. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Russia-China relations are exemplary and are increasingly attractive to other countries.” Shoigu mentioned, “The circle of friends between Russia and China who do not want to be involved in the Western confrontation agenda is constantly expanding.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a country involved in the Russia-Ukraine conflict, Shoigu’s attendance attracted much attention. He mentioned that after Russia countered NATO&#39;s eastward expansion, the United States was using Ukraine to attack Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Russia will only use nuclear weapons when it is attacked by a nuclear attack or when its national survival is threatened.&quot; Shoigu said in his speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the second time that Shaoyigu has attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and delivered a keynote speech. The last time was in 2019. After the meeting, Zhang Youxia held talks with Shaoyigu at the Bayi Building in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/c2f75269a6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/c2f75269a6.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;256572&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The speeches of the guests at the first plenary session all closely followed the theme of &quot;Responsibility of Major Powers and Global Security Cooperation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is important to strive for peace. In promoting global peace and security, major powers play a more important role.&quot; ASEAN Secretary-General Gao Jinhong said in the second half of the first half that major powers promote peace and make war a Obsolete things. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“From Asia-Pacific to the Global”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A few days before the opening ceremony, defense ministers and representatives from various countries arrived in Beijing one after another. As the organizer, Zhao Xiaozhuo, deputy director of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum Secretariat, is extremely busy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 21:00 on the evening of October 29, when Southern Weekend reporters met Zhao Xiaozhuo, he had just finished the welcome dinner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recalling the first forum, Zhao Xiaozhuo still has fresh memories. &quot;At that time, most of the participants were scholars, and the total number of participants was only a few dozen, so it was very small.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Beijing Xiangshan Forum was founded in 2006 and is hosted by two think tanks from the Chinese military, the China Society of Military Science and the China Society for International Strategic Studies. In 2014, the forum was upgraded from track two (private) to track one and a half (semi-official, semi-private). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since then, military and political leaders and national leaders will appear every year, and the conference has been adjusted from once every two years to once a year.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Farewell to online meetings during the epidemic, the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum attracted official delegations from more than 90 countries and international organizations including Russia, the United States, Saudi Arabia, and Iran, with more than 1,800 participants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 9 forums, there have been as many as 6 forums with the theme of &quot;Asia-Pacific&quot;. With the major changes in the nature of the forum, the scope of topics has also expanded from Asia-Pacific affairs to global issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xinbo, Dean of the Institute of International Studies at Fudan University, is a frequent visitor to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. Since the first forum in 2006, he has attended the forum almost every year. He said, &quot;The theme of the forum is increasingly consistent with China&#39;s core concepts and basic principles of international security, and the topics of the sub-forums are also increasingly consistent with the current actual international security situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; On October 30, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 256573&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 30 On the same day, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 30, ten small closed-door seminars were held simultaneously, covering topics such as global security governance, artificial intelligence security, and Sino-US crisis management and control. &quot;It has never happened before that ten meetings can be held at the same time.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said, &quot;It is up to the participating representatives to choose which forum they want to go to, who they want to talk to, and how much they want to talk.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shi Chande, a researcher at the Institute for Defense Analyses and former deputy assistant secretary of defense, is an &quot;old friend&quot; of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and a well-known &quot;China expert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I pay attention to China every day, and my understanding here may be deeper than that of the United States.” He told Southern Weekend reporters with a smile before the “Northeast Asian Order” sub-forum. The United States first sent official representatives to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum in 2015. Four years later, in 2019, then-U.S. Assistant Secretary of Defense Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense Shi Chande led a team to attend the meeting. It was the first time that a current senior U.S. military official appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the early days, the U.S. delegation’s participation in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum was relatively low, and basically only the military attache from the embassy in China was sent to participate.” Wu Xinbo recalled that as the importance and influence of the forum increased, the United States began to start from domestic Send some mid-level delegations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Similar to the Shangri-La Summit and the Munich Security Conference, an official’s rank determines his stage. This is a common international practice.” Zhao Xiaozhuo said, “After lower-level officials arrive, they are often only responsible for collecting information. Various opinions and information.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the U.S. military delegation was led by Owen Lewis, dean of the Joint Forces Staff College of the U.S. National Defense University; previously, the president of the U.S. National Defense University also led a delegation to Beijing Xiangshan Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Carles, senior director for China affairs in the Office of the Deputy Secretary of Defense of the United States, took over the &quot;baton&quot; from the head of the delegation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The levels of Carles and Shi Chande are similar, but in terms of specific ranking, Shi Chande is higher.&quot; During the welcome dinner, Zhao Xiaozhuo specially analyzed the level setting of U.S. officials to the U.S. Navy Feng Dewei, vice president of the center, asked for advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Calles, the official leader of the US delegation at this forum, kept a low profile and rarely appeared in public. On the evening of October 30, she appeared at a small seminar on &quot;China-U.S. Crisis Management&quot;, but did not speak. She only briefly communicated with the participants after the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, &quot;the level of the participants in the forum is not the most important matter. The communication between the two parties focuses on the substantive content.&quot; Wu Qian, spokesperson of the Ministry of National Defense, pointed out at a press conference held before the opening of the forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;International Issues &quot;Desktop Collision&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 15:00 on October 29, half an hour before the official start of the meeting, the conference room with less than 100 people was packed with people from all over the world. Representatives, experts and media, etc. This is a dialogue titled &quot;China&#39;s Role in Maintaining Asia-Pacific Security.&quot; Under the chairmanship of Wu Xinbo, experts from China, the United States, Russia and South Korea took their seats in turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why can the Asia-Pacific maintain stability for thirty years?&quot; The host first asked the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying, a former Chinese diplomat, shared &quot;the reasons for the Asia-Pacific economic miracle&quot;: peace and stability, focus on regional cooperation and dialogue, and economic globalization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She gave data from the Bank of Asia, &quot;In the past 42 years, Asia&#39;s GDP has grown seven times. Nearly half of it was created by China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And the United States&#39; GDP has grown seven times. Michael Swan, chief director of the East Asia Project at the Western Institute of National Affairs, believes that &quot;the change of power between China and the United States will bring huge uncertainty to Asia. In the next 10 to 15 years, the process of peace and stability in Asia may be disrupted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen&#39;s view was refuted by Fu Ying: &quot;Today, China is the driving force of the development miracle in the Asia-Pacific region, and the United States has also benefited greatly from it, but now this has become a problem?&quot; Fu Ying said, The United States has launched a &quot;China-US trade war&quot; that has more gains than losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen during the celebrity dialogue on October 29. (Photo by Yao Yijiang/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256574&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the celebrity dialogue on October 29, Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen. (Photo by Yao Yijiang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Russian expert Karaganov mentioned that &quot;Russia wants to create a peaceful and stable Eurasia and Asia-Pacific.&quot; Karaganov is the dean of the School of World Economics and International Affairs at the Russian State Higher University of Economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This scene better reflects the current international security situation.” After listening to the whole process, Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the &quot;Northeast Asia Security Trends and Shaping&quot; parallel forum on the afternoon of the 30th, explosive scenes took place one after another. American scholar Shi Wen and Director of the Asian and African Studies Department of the Japanese Defense Research Institute Masuda Masayuki were criticized by Chinese scholars one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The Northeast Asian issue depends on the interaction of multinational relations between China, Japan, the United States, and South Korea.” Shi Wen said. He was the third speaker at this forum, and there were also scholars from China, Russia, South Korea and the UK. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen flicked the tablet on the armrest of his seat, trying to regard the North Korean nuclear issue and the Taiwan issue as the same type of regional conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the moderator of the sub-forum, Vice President of the China Institute of International Strategic Studies, and retired major general Du Nongyi made his point clear, &quot;The core of the Taiwan issue is China&#39;s sovereignty and territorial integrity. It has nothing to do with North Korea.&quot; Nuclear issues and other issues cannot be compared with each other.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half, Japanese scholar Masuda Masayuki became the target of public criticism because he blamed China for regional security problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xuguang, senior adviser to the China Institute for International Strategic Studies, took the microphone and changed his original speech. He said that Masuda Masayuki was trying to teach the Chinese people &quot;a lesson&quot;. &quot;It is true that I am a little speechless.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xuguang pointed out that the crux of the problem between China and Japan is rooted in Japan&#39;s psychological imbalance, trying to regard the Sino-US game as a &quot;rare opportunity&quot; to take action, and constantly pointing fingers at the Taiwan issue. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the rebuttal, Masuda Masayuki sat on the stage and smiled awkwardly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let developing countries have a voice&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the international public opinion field dominated by European and American countries, the voices of developing countries are rarely heard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although it is a global village, every country has its own goals.&quot; At the &quot;Chinese and Foreign Young Officers and Scholars Seminar&quot; on October 29, Chief Executive Officer of the Pakistan Balochistan Research and Development Think Tank Official Jawariya Tareen said frankly. The young American scholar next to her had a serious expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than seventy years, the India-Pakistan border issue has remained unresolved, and Kashmir has always been like a thorn in the relationship between the two countries. Jawariya mentioned that every time Pakistan wanted to have dialogue, India did not respond positively, and the relationship between the two sides only stopped at the think tank level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Developing countries face two major problems, one is development and the other is security.&quot; Lieutenant General He Lei of the Chinese Academy of Military Sciences told Southern Weekend reporters that in a sense, developing countries are the most important problems in today&#39;s world. The security demands of the &quot;vulnerable groups&quot; should receive more attention and reasonable concerns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, internationally renowned security forums include the Shangri-La Dialogue, the Halifax International Security Forum, the Munich Security Conference and the Seoul Defense Dialogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;These forums have obvious &#39;circle&#39; attributes, and developing countries do not have much room to express themselves.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo mentioned that only the Beijing Xiangshan Forum clearly provides a stage for developing countries to fully express themselves safety concerns and demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Representatives from various countries at the main venue (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;645&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;256575&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Main venue representatives of various countries. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters observed that among the parallel group meetings and seminars, 5 of them were themed on developing countries and the &quot;Global South&quot;, and more than half of the speakers were from the development community. Chinese home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Global South&quot; is not a new concept. The term was first used by American political activist Carl Oglesby as early as 1969. &quot;European and American countries are using the Global South to exclude China from developing countries and isolate China to the maximum extent.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo believes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;China occupies a very critical or even core position in the global South. China&#39;s success has become the most important driving force for the global South at the international level...China has been promoting peaceful development through the &#39;One Belt, One Road&#39; initiative, which can What is the United States doing?&quot; Zheng Yongnian, President&#39;s Chair Professor of the Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen), asked on the morning of October 29. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With concerns about the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, Selchuk Chorakkoglu, the founding director of the Asia-Pacific Research Center of Turkey, came to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Palestinian-Israeli conflict has caused nearly 10,000 deaths on both sides, and there are also hidden dangers of spillover.&quot; Selchuk told Southern Weekend reporters that he hopes to discuss how to discuss the &quot;new Middle East security architecture&quot; Providing new solutions to Palestine and Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alessio Patalano has participated in the Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore and the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing for many times. He believes that the Beijing Xiangshan Forum is more &quot;pragmatic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This professor at the Department of War Studies at King&#39;s College London is very talkative. As soon as the forum began, Alessio was interviewed for an hour by the media who came to ask for advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told Southern Weekend reporters that providing a platform for developing countries to speak out is one of the greatest advantages of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Defense ministers and representatives from various countries came to Beijing Xiangshan Forum with the vision of seeking peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Common security and lasting peace are the basis for the common development of all countries.” Itizal Khadim, director of the Afghanistan Development and Peace Research Center, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Afghanistan, Itizal is a former government official who is now a professor of modern political history. He joked to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;I came to the meeting wearing two &#39;hats.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;36 million people in Afghanistan are suffering from extreme poverty and hunger. &quot;Only by creating jobs for the people, they will not turn to war.&quot; Itizal hopes that China can participate in the reconstruction of Afghanistan. &quot;China can help developing countries promote economic and social development instead of distributing gunpowder.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend interns Liu Yaqi, Lin Xi, Jiang Lai, Xu Ziyi, Feng Jiayi, and Zhang Xinyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target =&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx .best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[地理学家段义孚的终生追问：我是谁？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4P4YXsf2grzoKpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4 P4YXsf2grzoKpD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (third from right) in his later years with friends. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu ended his autobiography &quot;Who Am I?&quot; with an encounter in middle age. 》. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At night, he was driving on a narrow highway with only one car in front of him. He lacks confidence in his driving skills, so he uses the taillights of the car in front of him as a guide to gain a sense of safety and comfort. Suddenly the car flashed its right turn signal and turned into a country road. Visible to the naked eye, he was the only one driving on the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;So, only my own headlights are left to guide the way. This light can only illuminate a very small area. It is a short road, but this road, farther away, is swallowed up in darkness.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Tuan is a famous geographer and the founder of humanistic geography. One of the people. He intellectually understands the relationship between people and place and considers himself a cosmopolitan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot; was written in 1999, when Duan Yifu was 69 years old, and mankind was about to enter the new millennium. He sees &quot;Who am I&quot; as the fashionable question at the dawn of the new millennium. This issue actually received increasing attention as early as the 1960s, &quot;In order to generate a solid sense of self, a person needs the past, not just the present and the future.&quot; It is worth mentioning that &quot;Silent Spring&quot; combined poetry and science in the 1960s to jointly examine the relationship between man and the environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu continued to think about it and wrote important works in the next twenty years. &quot;who I am? 》 is a good stage summary, showing sincere self-examination. He seems to be getting closer and closer to a location, but he is not sure when he will arrive, or even further away. The ideal position always changes with time, space and thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;657&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the early 1940s, Duan Yifu and his family were preparing to move from Chongqing to Australia. During the group photo, Yifu Duan (third from left) tried to squeeze away from his younger brother and stay close to his mother to gain more attention. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The world in his eyes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; is shrinking inward &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, Yifu Tuan quoted the words of Socrates: An unexamined life is not worth living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before middle age, Duan Yifu had never lived in any city for more than five years. After leaving China, he continued to move around until he moved to Minneapolis at the age of 38 and stopped to engage in academic work. Migration is inseparable from both my father&#39;s work and historical events. He believed he was rootless and &quot;born to examine himself.&quot; He never married and could not fully integrate into American society, and the issue of identity was always there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He considers himself an optimist and &quot;often places the golden age in the future.&quot; He knows that he gained his confidence early, having been relatively unscathed by racism while living abroad, and that later in life he began to question its source. His various ways of dealing with the world are closely related to the events he has experienced and the environment in which he lives. The book reveals his own “sense of place”—emotions and judgments about specific places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his first interview at Indiana University in 1956, an Asian history professor was surprised by his family background. Duan Yifu recalled his childhood memories and was sure that the other party was not joking. According to what he heard, the Duan family was divided into two branches in modern times, both in Anhui. Duan Yifu&#39;s family belonged to the poor branch, and his father Duan Maolan relied on his uncle Duan Qirui from the Hefei branch to fully fund his studies at Nankai Middle School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu was born in Tianjin. From the age of 7 to 10, he lived in a village on the outskirts of Chongqing due to the war. His family was financially distressed. The school is a single room belonging to a power station. The place smelled sour and rancid, and the fetid mud dragged at his shoes. He was disgusted and horrified. Occasionally he encountered a funeral procession, with the bodies of the guards wrapped in bamboo mats. There is a rooster tied to it, which will crow if the corpse is found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;765&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256473&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1954, Yifu Duan conducted field research in Arizona, USA. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Small schools are different places, where students learn about the history, Culture and Technology. Wilde&#39;s work &quot;The Happy Prince&quot; left an indelible mark on him, and he knew: &quot;&#39;Good&#39; can no longer be limited to fulfilling social obligations.&quot; These realizations inspired Duan Yifu to think, and he was always exploring how to determine a person&#39;s position in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu mentioned some important historical figures in his narrative. Duan Maolan and his alumnus Zhou Enlai wrestled with each other&#39;s arms to test whether the other&#39;s injured arm was healed. Zhang Boling, the principal of Nankai Middle School, had a rare refrigerator and distributed trays of ice cubes to everyone. In order to keep them for him, his father used the folk remedy of spreading salt to delay melting. The adults are still thinking about how to treat their distant relative Wang Jingwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu has conflicting emotions about his father. He longs for love, but is disappointed by his father&#39;s preference for his brothers; he remembers the tenderness of the difficult times, but is also traumatized by his father&#39;s severity or anger. The most profound memory of my father is even just a childhood nightmare, and the scene in the dream has remained for many years:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; &quot;I opened my arms and wanted to hug him... What happened? But a ghost stood in front of me. It could be seen that it was my father, but he was covered in mourning clothes. This ghost was in the ever-changing airflow It was moving in the middle, weightless. It was an evil ghost, a corpse, with yellow light in its empty eyes.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The impression his mother left on him was warm and tough. , it’s a pity that she passed away prematurely. At the same time, Duan Yifu became increasingly sensitive due to his physical condition, and he became very ill for a time. He confessed his cowardice and unwillingness to participate in social change activities. Even in the face of racism and rude boys who treat him as a &quot;little girl,&quot; he has no motivation to actively fight back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world in Duan Yifu&#39;s eyes is shrinking inward. When he was a child, he was exposed to all kinds of extraordinary events. When he grew up, the war ended and he had to face many personal problems. He summed up this growth experience as moving from the universe to the stove, and used beautiful writing to integrate life and academia. He quoted the words of the poet TS Eliot:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;All of us, in our lifetime, have heard and seen , why does everything you feel (a bird singing, a fish leaping, an old woman walking on a mountain road) be reproduced with emotion, but other things are not?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;935&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256474&quot;>;Youth Yifu Tuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Are you willing to be a lonely captain&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Poetry can break through the barriers or boundaries of language logic.” Liu Su told Southern Weekend. He used this to describe the beautiful words written by Tuan Yifu. He translated &quot;Love Land Complex&quot; and &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;Two books by Yifu Tuan, and I am currently translating &quot;The Divided World and Self&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was a graduate student around 2010, Liu Su often suffered from having no books to read. Many times he was attracted by the ideas mentioned in the book, but could not find relevant Chinese or even English translations. He tried his best to find the original work, went to Douban to ask Douban friends who had read the book, and also went to the library, but he might only be able to make half a copy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I might as well translate it myself!&quot; Those experiences inspired Liu Su&#39;s enthusiasm. He thus embarked on the path of academic translation, and future college students will no longer face the dilemma of reading. At the same time, many scholars have also participated in the translation and introduction of geography classics. The Chinese translations of scholars such as Tuan Yifu and David Harvey are enough to be compiled into a collection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2021, in the crowded Chongqing subway, Liu Su received a WeChat message from another translator Zhicheng, asking him if he was willing to translate &quot;Who Am I?&quot; 》. Even though the air conditioning was sufficient, he still broke out in a hot sweat: &quot;This book will finally be translated into Chinese!&quot; He had seriously considered that he was not willing to live a lonely life as a &quot;foreigner&quot; in a foreign country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; ” resonated with Liu Su’s heart. He experienced a long single life. When he got married, the children of his classmates were almost in junior high school. He may have experienced Duan Yifu&#39;s loneliness and his self-statement: &quot;I spent a lot of time in poems and essays about the sadness of spring and autumn, and spent them in places like libraries and coffee shops.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su finished class, said goodbye to the students, and went to the library for a while after walking out of the teaching building. Even if I don’t write anything, I would still like to sit in the corner and experience what Yifu Duan said: “Living on campus almost all my life, surrounded by young people, makes me feel happy physically and mentally.” He sometimes goes to a nearby coffee shop and sits by the window, looking at the pedestrians, vehicles and street lights, feeling that loneliness is far away. The sensibility of exquisite language gathers together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-Fu Tuan in 1998, that is, &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;The previous year&#39;s work &quot;Escapism&quot; asked: What is the greatest escape? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When you lower your head and manage the environment around you with a heart that loves your neighbor, you can also look up at the vast starry sky.&quot; Liu Su talked about his understanding of this sentence and added a more realistic side, &quot;As a scholar, like him, I often look up at the starry sky of metaphysical thoughts and theories. However, whenever I look down at my single life, I often feel like I&#39;m in a mess.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot; 1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (1930-2022), an internationally renowned Chinese geographer, was born in Tianjin and graduated from Oxford University. He returned to China in his later years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su is looking for descriptions of single life in books. Yifu Tuan made his apartment simple and warm, dressed modestly and appropriately, maintained good health and longevity, had good interpersonal relationships, and gained precious friendships. However, &quot;he once dreamed that he died alone at home, and no one found his rotting body.&quot; Duan Yifu always writes about his loneliness, a complicated feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Perhaps the reason is that loneliness is the most authentic way of human existence. The state of not being lonely is actually the product of escape.&quot; Liu Su quoted the saying of &quot;Escapism&quot;. There are three questions surrounding Yifu Duan&#39;s life: &quot;I am mortal&quot; that has lingered since childhood; &quot;Who am I&quot; related to individual consciousness; and &quot;What is a good life&quot;. Yifu Tuan wrote &quot;Geography saved me&quot;. Geography was like a road that led him to understand himself and the problems of human life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Translation of &quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot; also allowed Liu Su to gain &quot;a friendship worth cherishing.&quot; After the book launch, he, Zhi Cheng, editors and readers friends braved the heavy rain and went into a noodle shop to chat. Five people each signed five books and kept them. He also wanted to write his feelings into a longer email and share it with Duan Yifu. Before the email was finished, Duan Yifu passed away in August 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tuan Yifu published a new book that year, and finally wrote: &quot;I would like to advise you again, young traveler! You must be full of courage to operate your own ship like a captain, even though it is only Life&#39;s puzzling clues and stars serve as your guide.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su was devastated by his mistake, but would continue to translate classics of humanistic geography. He also asked himself if he was willing to be a lonely captain and walk on a narrow road. No matter what the answer is, Tuan Yifu&#39;s book &quot;will always be projected into the heart of every reader.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Where is the real home&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu recalled in the preface of &quot;Going Home&quot; that people often asked him where he thought the real hometown was. . He answered lightly: &quot;In general, it&#39;s the earth.&quot; &quot;Where on earth is it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, the meaning of the question is probably: there must be a place where he is most comfortable, The most yearning, can form the deepest sense of belonging. &quot;Some specific landscapes do have great appeal to me, such as a landscape that transcends aesthetics - the desert. I feel that I am very close to the desert psychologically, and I can even regard it as my home.&quot; Yifu Duan again and again Once I wrote about my love for the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in the winter of 1954, Yifu Tuan was conducting field research for his doctoral thesis in southeastern Arizona. The research object was the desert terrain called the foothill erosion surface. When optimistic British student David Harris joins the group, the physical and spiritual hardships of the wilderness thin out and are gradually replaced by friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This relationship brings me satisfaction, but it also causes insecurity—almost all relationships of any depth involve both. Why? Is there something wrong with me? ?&quot; Duan Yifu asked in the book. In 1962, they collaborated again. He remained single and became a teacher; David married and had two daughters. &quot;The David today is a broader, more elusive personality than I knew before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following description is sensitive and stinging, and such feelings appear repeatedly in the book . They each drove to Chaco Canyon to investigate, with Yifu Duan leading the way and David&#39;s family following behind. At dusk, maybe David knew the route, maybe the children needed care, David&#39;s car honked, kicked up dust and drove ahead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The distance between us became wider and wider, and soon, all that was left in front of my eyes was the raised The dust was gone, and in the end, even the dust was gone. I fell into a lonely shadow... When I tried to catch up with the Harris family, I felt lonely and painful for the first time. What&#39;s worse, I I even feel ridiculous. What on earth was I doing on a dirt road in New Mexico? Chasing a young family in a car?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yifu Tuan&#39;s eyes, friendship must meet two basic requirements: The conditions—like-mindedness and sympathy—should be balanced in an ideal friendship. &quot;If overly oriented toward shared interests and interests, these two people may become more like colleagues than friends; conversely, they may be more like lovers, staring into each other&#39;s eyes rather than into the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Shy people, unsociable people, or people like me who have their social needs suppressed by eccentric pursuits, perhaps should devote themselves to Nature...maybe only by staying in an inorganic environment, such as deserts and icebergs, can people feel relaxed and happy, and forget the good and the bad.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Duan also wrote about the German Alexander von Humboldt. Humboldt was the founder of modern physical geography. He “made outstanding contributions to the development of geodesy and was the first to use painting and poetry to develop human geographical experience-feelings, emotions and concepts, which are the core of humanities. The starting point of socialist geography”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humboldt lived to be 90 years old and was full of energy throughout his life. In his sixties, he could still travel through Siberia and Central Asia. He enjoys socializing, but has never been married, and has been trapped in emotional entanglements with men three times. He wrote in a letter to the married soldier Reinhard von Haften: &quot;Even if you reject me and look at me coldly, like a stain, I still want to be with you. ...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If I leave the universe, or to be precise, leave the harmony of nature and the joy brought by human beings&#39; ultimate achievements, my life will become miserable and I will not be able to survive.&quot; Yifu Duan listed He felt all kinds of human misery, &quot;But, I don&#39;t want to stay in those shadows for a long time...&quot; He believed in the light, the beauty of the universe, and the beauty and kindness of events. The next chapter is &quot;Geography Saved Me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, taking the opportunity of attending an architectural conference, Yi-Fu Tuan returned to China after 60 years of absence and deliberately stayed for a while. He wrote a book called &quot;Going Home&quot;, which was translated into Chinese by Zhicheng. During the trip to Chongqing, he once again mentioned the nightmare that had plagued him throughout his life. When his father passed away in Taipei in 1980, he did not go back to see him for the last time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The end of the autobiography is the contrast between the dim light of the car lights and the vast darkness. That is not despair. Duan Yifu is still looking at himself. He asked the translator to attach his speech notes in 2012 as an updated understanding of &quot;who I am.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are no so-called ordinary people in the world. The people you talk to every day are actually people with immortal souls... They joke with us, work together, and get married, but they are also ignored and exploited by us. All people are actually people with immortal souls. Among these people, some are immortal and terrifying, and some are immortal and brilliant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Maybe it has been too long, he I really forgot&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot;Yu Shiyi, the editor of &quot;WeChat,&quot; appeared somewhat silent - just like when communicating with text on WeChat - but soon opened up the situation, became talkative and humorous. His daily schedule was very regular and he even added a short period of time that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later he added that he should not talk too much about his own story, and autobiographers should be given more space. So, this part is an extra chapter of this article. People are always faced with questions such as &quot;Who am I?&quot; The questions and answers constantly change with the situation, each covered with attractive colors. For example, the great director Bergman claimed that he knew less about himself than he did ten years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi has unique feelings about discrete events. In early 1949, the Taiping shipwreck occurred in the waters west of Daishan Island where he was born. When he was a child, he had no idea about this tragedy. He only learned about it through documentaries when he left his hometown to attend college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1950, approximately 125,000 young men, soldiers, and 25,000 civilian personnel and civilians moved to Taiwan from Zhoushan, later forming the first generation of Zhoushan people of 20,000 to 30,000 people. The initiators of Taiwan’s Veterans Return Movement in 1987 were Zhoushan people. Before the “Three Direct Links”, it was very difficult for them to contact their homeland. The local historical materials exhibition hall uses an entire wall to display letters forwarded by the Red Cross at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Islands shape cognition. Yu Shiyi left Zhoushan for Ningbo ten years ago, and then went to Shanghai to study. When I was growing up, there was no cross-sea bridge in Zhoushan. When a typhoon came, the island became an isolated island, physically and psychologically isolated from the rest of the world. Compared to county towns, provincial towns, and cities, visitors from small islands seem to be “small” and marginal. At first he longed to merge from the margins into the mainstream, but now he wants to have subjectivity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As an immigrant, your regional identity is the first thing that is mentioned when you arrive in a new environment.” Yu Shiyi has a friend who was born in Hubei and grew up in Shenzhen, and later moved to Shanghai. He asked: What is the local accent of “other”? In 1973, 43-year-old Yifu Duan officially became a U.S. citizen. He has been living in the United States for nearly two decades, debugging himself as a &quot;cosmopolitan and a thinker writing about discrete subjects.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also the little grandpa - my grandfather&#39;s younger brother - talking about the past during the Chinese New Year. He claimed that he once drove a simple diesel-powered boat from Qushan Island to Dongjiadu, Shanghai, in one night. Alone, without a GPS, all I have is experience and a compass. Yu Shiyi could not imagine the plight of the fishermen. Wouldn&#39;t they be scared if they were wandering around without land? He wrote down his boundless imagination in his notes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The lanky man drove a small sampan from the island Set off and drive northwest, through night and day, to Dongjiadu. The lighting system at that time was not perfect, and there was no positioning system. Some waterways were almost dark at night, but he arrived at his destination safely without saying a word about the wind and waves he encountered. I think maybe too much time has passed and he has long forgotten the ups and downs along the way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I remember that there is a famous lighthouse on Flower and Bird Island. I wonder if he passed by it. Under certain conditions, There will also be the wonder of the fluorescent sea. I always feel that the waterway from my hometown to Shanghai is full of mysterious powers. I once took a ferry from the island to Shanghai. I landed ashore at dusk and landed at dawn. That was the first time I saw the waves gurgling like spring water and seagulls soaring in the sky. Looking out from the small round glass of the third-class cabin, there are faint lights. Maybe I have seen the lighthouse of Flower and Bird Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I asked the tribesmen, have you gone ashore? He said he had unloaded the goods but did not go up. I was so sorry. I wanted to get the secrets of Shanghai in the 1980s from him, but he said, it’s nothing. The Bund is just across the Dongjia Ferry Road. I can’t understand those Western things. At that time, everything could be bought by ticket, and the people were people on the water. , naturally cannot be obtained. He drove the sampan up the Huangpu River and finally reached Jiangyin. This was undoubtedly an adventure. As for what to do there and how to get back to the island, he stopped talking without saying a few words. Maybe it&#39;s been too long and he really forgot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Memories and narratives form fragments one after another, embedded in life. More than thirty years after my grandfather left Shanghai, Yu Shiyi also arrived in Shanghai. During the National Day holiday in 2022, he took a boat to the island with his father. The father was hesitant at first, after all, the house was no longer theirs. Many places are different. Old houses and new ones are popping up one after another. Fortunately, the road remains where it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi returned to the lane where he was born. The commercial house he bought more than 20 years ago was still there, but it was older. The back door was open, he went in and saw the washboard from many years ago. After all these years, it&#39;s still there, like a miracle. There was someone living nearby, and he was too embarrassed to disturb him, so he just wanted to go to the front door to take a look. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the resident saw the stranger, he became alert and asked: &quot;Who are you?&quot; Yu Shiyi was stunned, silent for a few seconds, and instinctively replied: &quot;This is my home.&quot; He walked to the front door and took a photo Teru then left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You have become the &#39;other&#39;.&quot; He recalled, &quot;There are physical things, and it used to be my home.&quot; He didn&#39;t know how many hands the house had changed. I felt relieved that I could finally say goodbye. For almost twenty years, he always thought of this home, worried about it, and was afraid it would be demolished. Now all the playmates and neighbors have left, leaving only photos and washboards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The recognition and memory of your hometown, in turn, become the means for others to identify you. Not long after being asked &quot;Who are you?&quot;, in December 2022, Yu Shiyi took over &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;, the book will be launched at the Shanghai Book Fair in August 2023. The above is always a bit of an unexpected fate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[天安门下半旗悼念李克强同志]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259779]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:28:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKjlN5UvkjG6D.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/cJf35kinfSqDJ9neqoAwAKA7BWIEKj lN5UvkjG6D. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ju Huanzong&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;On November 2, in memory of Comrade Li Keqiang, flags were flown at half-mast at Tiananmen Square in the capital. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃得苦中苦，方为人上人”：是一种可鄙的价值观吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259580]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;There are many serious and serious rumors circulating on the Internet. Some are old and constantly updated versions, and some are new. of. A relatively recent one is: The Chinese student&#39;s thesis &quot;You have to endure hardships to become a superior person&quot;. As a result, the New Zealand professor gave a zero point and asked the soul question, &quot;Why should you become a superior person while others are inferior?&quot; What do people do? Why do you divide your compatriots into three, six or nine grades? Shouldn’t everyone be equal?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you do some Internet archeology, it is not difficult to find that this is A piece of Sanwu news concocted by a certain self-media, with no specific time, university or person. The motive of the fabricator is to use the words of foreigners who regard them as authoritative to show how low some Chinese people&#39;s words, deeds, and values ​​are, and how high their own preferred values ​​are. However, there are still many people who believe in this rumor that &quot;foreign monks like to chant sutras&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original version of &quot;Only when you have to endure hardships can you become the best among people.&quot; The original version should be &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the most hardships, you can become the best among people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chapter 32 of &quot;Journey to the West&quot;. Tang Monk said: &quot;Disciples, be careful. If you encounter a high mountain ahead, you may be blocked by tigers and wolves.&quot; Sun Wukong said: &quot;Master, as a monk, don&#39;t talk at home. Do you remember the &quot;Heart Sutra&quot; written by Monk Wuchao, which says, &#39;If you have no worries, you will be free from worries.&#39; No fear, stay away from words that confuse dreams? But it is just to sweep away the dirt on the heart and wash the dirt on the ears. If you don&#39;t suffer in the suffering, it is difficult to be a good person. You should not worry, but there is an old man, even if the sky falls, you can Be safe. What are you afraid of?&quot; This was an education for the master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also from &quot;Warning Words to the World&quot;, &quot;It&#39;s Hard to Meet Your Husband after Spring Falls in the Yutang&quot;. I saw a couplet hanging on the door: &quot;After ten years of suffering in front of the window, he became famous all over the world.&quot; &quot;This is the couplet written by my father-in-law. He passed the national examination and became a minister: Later, our father was When I study here, I will become a minister. I am studying here now, and I also want to climb the dragon and the phoenix to carry forward the ambitions of my predecessors.&quot; I also saw a couplet on the second door: &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the hardships, it is difficult to become a master.&quot; The young master hurriedly returned. Study room...with my mind turned around and my determination to study diligently. This is a lot of self-motivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference between the two versions is: &quot;Only when you endure hardships can you become the best among people.&quot; The first sentence is a necessary condition for the latter sentence; &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer the most hardships, you can become the best among people&quot; is the probability. Expression. The latter seems more rigorous and allows exceptions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What do you think of this kind of saying? If you take &quot;You must endure hardships to become the best&quot; as a full judgment, then it is not difficult to find counterexamples. In a logical sense, this proposition has been refuted. However, after that, everyone thought this was wrong and discarded it? Obviously not, everyone will just think you are making excuses, because this is not the correct way to open the proverb. The use of proverbs is inherently situational: only when specific preconditions are added or placed in a specific context can the proverb be established and can be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are a large number of sayings in various languages ​​with completely opposite meanings. Here is an example of Chinese: &quot;A powerful man cannot bend&quot; vs &quot;A man can bend and stretch&quot;; &quot;I will not offend others unless they attack me&quot; vs &quot;Strike first to gain strength, but to attack later will suffer&quot;; &quot;It is better to be broken into pieces than to be left intact&quot; vs &quot;to stay intact&quot; If the green mountains are there, you will not be afraid of running out of firewood&quot;; &quot;Take a step back and the sky will be brighter&quot; Vs &quot;The brave will win when you meet on a narrow road&quot;; &quot;To endure a moment of calm&quot; Vs &quot;It is tolerable, but what is intolerable&quot;; &quot;Everything is inferior, only reading is good&quot; Vs &quot; Three hundred and sixty lines, he will be the number one scholar&quot;; &quot;The blue is better than the blue&quot; vs &quot;The hair on the lips is weak, and the work is not solid&quot;; &quot;Three cobblers are better than Zhuge Liang&quot; vs &quot;Three monks have no water to drink&quot; ...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tell me, which sentence before and after is right, which sentence is wrong, or are they both wrong? In fact, as long as they are put into the appropriate context, these common sayings with opposite meanings can be used correctly. This is the correct way to use common sayings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, &quot;Only when you have to endure hardships can you become a superior person&quot; or &quot;If you don&#39;t suffer a lot of hardships, can you become a superior person&quot;, there are also common sayings with opposite meanings or different emphasis, such as &quot;One life. &quot;Second Movement and Three Feng Shui&quot;, &quot;Choice is more important than effort&quot;, &quot;Don&#39;t use tactical diligence to cover up strategic laziness&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my opinion, success is determined by many innate and acquired factors. 1. Fate: when you were born in which country and family, this constitutes your initial conditions and boundary conditions; 2. Wisdom: intellectual endowment, the computing power and algorithm of the brain, which are also innate; 3. God: you Your knowledge system and values, as well as your vitality, motivation, courage and patience, have both innate and acquired components, but the acquired component is greater, because you can always choose your values ​​and choose to be a courageous person; 4. Luck: Factors you have no way of knowing or controlling because you are in a complex random system. In a specific process, &quot;god, wisdom, fate, luck&quot;, which factors are more important cannot be generalized. A person&#39;s success always resonates with the trend of history and personal destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, among the many factors that determine success, hardship, diligence or patience are certainly important, especially for people without background. Other statements such as &quot;The sharp edge of a sword comes from sharpening, and the plum blossoms bloom from the bitter cold&quot;, &quot;There are roads in the mountains of books, and diligence is the path, and there is no limit to the sea of ​​learning, and the boat is made by hard work.&quot; Do they sound more pleasing to the ear? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What many people don’t like is “people superior to others”. This needs to be looked at twice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, from the perspective of rights or rules, of course everyone should be equal. No one is above anyone else, and no one is subordinate to anyone. It is against anyone&#39;s privileges or slavery. , which is the basic principle of civilized society. In this sense, there should be no &quot;people superior to others&quot; and &quot;people inferior to others&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, there are always certain professions that are more respected in society and have higher social evaluation or reputation. For example, professionals such as surgeons enjoy a higher social status and are not considered &quot;human beings&quot;. What about &quot;Master&quot;? Also, some people are respected and admired by everyone because of their ability, knowledge or virtue, and they even have many followers. For example, people like Xinxiang Xian are the core of society. If neighbors come to him to resolve disputes, does he count? What about &quot;people superior to people&quot;? In a company or organization, whether it has a strict hierarchy or a relatively &quot;flat&quot; management, there is a chain of command and a superior-subordinate relationship. The subordinates must obey the instructions of the superiors to do things. Can senior executives and superiors be considered &quot;superiors&quot;? &quot;Woolen cloth? In a nutshell, from the perspective of power or influence, elites or those with higher social status are often called &quot;dragons and phoenixes&quot;, and there is nothing wrong with being considered &quot;superior&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, if you want to be &quot;superior&quot; and pursue the privilege of overpowering others or trampling others under your feet, it is naturally a despicable value; What&#39;s the problem if you deepen your field, improve your talents and virtues, become popular, and gain a higher social status? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[书城伏案的侧影：写在刘世南先生百年诞辰之际]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259765]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3AasqhT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;916&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/gJOH0MA1fEMOll8Ren0VMWx1Krulso5uG3Aasq hT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256565&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Shinan took a photo in front of the Chongshao Library of Jiangxi Normal University. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of Li Taosheng)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;People who long for friends who fear friends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Liu Shinan Mr. (1923-2021) was a fighter. This is the first impression of him by people who are familiar with him and those who are not familiar with him. He dared to criticize various scholars, including those older than him, those of his generation, and those younger than him. His articles were scattered in various books and periodicals from the late 1970s to the new century, making readers People who feel the enthusiasm and persistence of his criticism are of course embarrassed by the critics, but they do learn from him, and many criticized scholars express their gratitude to him and respect him even more. His criticisms are actually aimed at problems, especially the style of study. His crisp and refreshing writing style contains a profound call for a sincere, simple, serious and down-to-earth style of study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not many people know that he is very eager to be criticized. He criticized Mr. Liu Mengfu (&quot;Outside the Academic Hall&quot; page 301), and Mr. Mengfu also criticized him. He invited Mr. Mengfu to write a preface to his &quot;Da Luo Ju Shi Cun&quot;. Mr. Mengfu wrote a long preface in which he included his own critical opinions. He criticized it with real swords and guns. Mr. Shinan did not think that Sorry, let it remain in the preface as it is. This is the style of sincerity and magnanimity. He said in a letter to me on July 26, 2005: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Mr. Liu Mengfu is in middle age and a poet. Learn the art of poetry and achieve the best of both worlds. He looks down upon him as a servant, looks down upon his followers, and is sincerely afraid of his friends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He respects and looks forward to his &quot;fearful friends&quot;. When he heard Mr. Tao Wenpeng mention that some parts of his &quot;History of Qing Poetry Schools&quot; were a bit &quot;old&quot;, he wrote a letter asking Mr. Tao to point out his shortcomings in detail. Mr. Tao replied, and Mr. Shinan made a copy of the letter. Send me a copy and write:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Send me a copy of Mr. Tao Wenpeng’s letter, to be compared with Mr. Tao Wenpeng’s book review Although Mr. Yun and Mr. Tao made many mistakes in their compliments, Mr. Tao was able to correct their flaws. I hope Mr. Yun can do the same. In the past, Chen Si once said: &quot;The writings of the world cannot be without disease. I always have good people ridiculing my writings, and if there are bad ones, I should correct them in due course.&quot; He also quoted Ding Jingli and said: &quot;Who in future generations will know that my writings are evil?&quot;走甚望先生以《清诗流派史》责编身份，能抉吾书之失，以告后世治清诗者知所戒避，此即学术公器之意也。 （2005年1月12日）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可见他对于陶先生的批评，仍不满足，希望得到更多更真实的批评，他是把批评当作了“学术公器”来看待的。这让我们更加明白他之所以一往无前地开展学术批评，真的是毫无私心杂念，只不过一心一意地为了学术更加健康、成熟地发展壮大。他对于批评的态度，不是只针对他人，还希望针对自己，这样有利于自己的改进，有利于学界清晰的认知。他身先示范，有着清风朗月的美好胸襟，令人感佩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;866&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/A2lmlAB2WbWNF9rofeqfKqiPLtvwopiAQGhCByuu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘世南教授和他的《清诗三百首详注》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他对于别人对于他的指正，非常感动，并再三致意。我社断代文选陆续规划推出，当时的古典部主任周绚隆编审考虑到世南先生对清代文学熟悉，就诚邀他来选注《清文选》，他考虑到时间紧迫，便请他的学生刘松来教授协助，书稿到来之后，由实习生北京师范大学研究生文丽琛女士在我指导下初审，然后我再复审，写好两份修改意见之后，寄呈世南先生过目。他2005年10月1日在省图书馆写的信中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;9月22日手示及审稿意见、书评复印件，俱收到，请释念。捧读之下，既惭且感！ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由匡正与补苴各条，亦可见先生与文丽琛女史之学富功深矣，钦服之忱，何可言罄！窃谓《清文选》他日苟能略有裨于斯世，实吾四人合作之力，非松来与我区区棉薄所致也。拟于此书前言补缀数语，以明斯义，聊以示吾两人不敢掠美之意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他后来坚持在该书前言中，加入了表彰我和小文的文字，可见他闻过则喜、虚怀若谷的贤者胸怀，令人如沐春风。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/9ICJwEasJaiGQCkwpKLheTnuNb0kMpOpfGgmCBxe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256566&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘世南教授著作两种。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“生死书丛一蠹虫”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;世南先生的斗志主要体现在他自己勤奋读书和写作上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他藏书不多，主要因为特殊时期把他两代人的藏书都销毁了，使他极度伤心，他一般就不再买书（《师友偶录》117页）。他主要是跑图书馆，省图书馆、校图书馆里，他是常客。当1994年，历经十四年的艰苦卓绝的阅读、研究、撰写，终于完成了《清诗流派史》，在次年夏日校对书稿时，他欣喜地回顾了这段历程：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;忆昔每岁除，书城犹弄翰。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;万家庆团栾，独坐一笑粲。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;卡片漫盈箱，有得逾美膳。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;心劳十四载，书成瘁笔砚。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（《清诗流派史》附录《甲戌岁盛夏校对〈清诗流派史〉书稿……》）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自注：“每当春节除夕，余犹坐图书馆，与管理员一人遥遥相对。”我社预备出版简体版，我有幸担任责任编辑，在编辑过程中，向他问候，提到这个给人印象深刻的场景，他在2003年12月30日晚和次日在样书库给我写回信说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;谢谢您的关注，还记得我除夕仍坐图书馆的事。如果校图仍开放，我的确会那样干。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“生死书丛一蠹虫”，一辈子就是这样过来的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;的确，他仍放不过每一天，有年除夕，馆长跟他“遥遥相对”，倒是一景了。他写信给他的学生郭丹教授说：“现在是除夕下午近4点钟，图书馆阅览厅里只剩我和张馆长两人；张馆长亲自值班，微笑着陪我到4点钟关门。”（郭丹《治学的境界&amp;nbsp;人格的风范——记刘世南先生》，《师友偶记》237页）这样的馆长真是好馆长，这样的读者真是好读者，这称得上当代阅读界的佳话。他在2006年12月31日寄给我的明信片上写着：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;书城伏案茧丝怜，忘却匆匆岁月迁。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;不是华筵此宵醉，谁知后日是新年。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除夕仍在读书，的确是读书种子的风范。当然他不是只瞅准了除夕，其实每一天对他来讲都是宝贵的。 2004年6月4日的来信讲：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《清文选》忙得很，我从未如此紧张过，因为一放暑假，校图就要闭馆，我必须赶在放假前做完这事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是在与松来教授一起赶着选注《清文选》时的情景。而后来没有要紧的工作时，仍坚持不懈地去图书馆。过去革命者有句豪言壮语“把牢底坐穿”，世南先生耄耋之年，不顾病体，仍执著前往，真是有要把图书馆坐穿的气概。 2013年1月10日的信里说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;匆匆又一年，我近住院切除鼻疣，医言为基底细胞癌，已切除干净。我已实龄九十，齐生死久矣，故出院后，仍坐图书馆。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当郭丹教授在2015年乙未年春节正月初一上午给世南先生电话拜年时，听到的回答是“已在省图书馆看书了”！ （《师友偶记》再版后记）李陶生先生多年陪护世南先生，他在《自我肺腑出未尝只字篡》一文讲：“书本是他所有的精神寄托。”“无论风霜雨雪，他都会像工作人员一样准时出现在图书馆。他说他希望自己将来能死在书桌旁。”（《师友偶记》249页）可见他痴迷于书到了何等地步。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“自万卷书中来”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;世南先生泛览群籍，对经史尤其精熟，因此他能对许多论著存在的误解、误断、误改，比较敏感，并能给予指正。他除了助人刊谬，主要的精力用在《清诗流派史》的研究、撰写上了。此外用功甚多的是《清文选》的选注。在承担这项工作之后，他全身心地投入到选文当中去。尽管邀请了松来教授参与注释工作，但是他仍是处处亲历亲为：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;由选文到标点到注释，我将全部通读并改定。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这些时候，我正忙于选定篇目，主要是从《四库全书》《续修四库全书》以及《存目丛书》中选择，少数还要另从线装书库去找。例如蒋士铨，《续修》中无文，而《鸣机夜课图》等必须选入。其他可以类推。选文之事颇费时间，选定之后，要先复印，再手抄成简化体字。 （2003年12月16日）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了集中全力做好《清文选》工作，他把几年来担任的江西省高校《豫章丛书》整理工作的首席学术顾问（即最后把关）一职也辞去了。可见他对《清文选》工作的全身心投入的决心。因为他对清代文集比较熟悉，加上昼夜兼程地翻阅，到2003年12月30日，他“逐页翻阅《续修四库全书》清人别集，188册中，已翻到154册，尚余30册，寒假前可翻完”,并说“然后看《四库全书》，文集不多。《存目》未看，不知多少”。在选文上“一定别出手眼，不因人热”（2003年12月30日来信）。在这封信里，他仍难以掩饰自己挑剔的眼光，对于几种书表达了自己的意见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;今天看曾国藩文集，顺便找了四本今人选注的，以《原才》一篇为例，涂小马本、来新夏本、郭预衡本，对“谓之不诬可乎否也”，都断为：“谓之不诬，可乎？否也。”倒是郑振铎《晚清文选》断为：“谓之不诬，可乎否也？”断对了。涂、来、郭三人……不知“可乎否也”的“也”其实是“耶”，《经传释词》等书说得很明白，而韩愈、欧阳修所作古文，摇曳多姿，常有这种咏叹句。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，对“众人君之而受命焉”之“君”的被误解，《召诲》“播为声气”的被误解，“虽圣人不免”“不”误改作“必”，也予以辨析。他没有否定诸位的贡献，他只是为了说明自己会借鉴他们的成果，但绝对不会简单地抄袭：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;即使我们参考这类选注本，也一定辨析毫厘，决不作模糊影响之谈，而是力求明白准确。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;类似的著作可以依傍的其实很少，即便参考，也一定是有鉴别地采用，这符合世南先生向来提倡的“自我肺腑出，未尝只字篡”的治学精神。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到2004年6月26日，已是《清文选》收尾的阶段，他向我写信介绍该书前言的撰写情况：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;前言可以证明，我们两人对清文的认识略有新意，并不人云亦云看，正是因为对作品注释下了一番功夫。例如“流派单一，风格多样”，我们不仅指出了“其然”，也说明了“其所以然”。这是我们做学问的特点。也是针对中国传统文学批评来的。传统手法是即兴式的、感悟式的，只指出了“然”，而不分析“其所以然”。我们接受了西方学术的影响，总喜欢追究一个“为什么”。因此，对桐城派（包含后来的阳湖派、湘乡派）的出现，以及“天下文章，其在桐城乎”的赞辞，我们企图透过这一现象找出它的逻辑的必然性，历史现象从来都是有规律可循的，其中的因果律最值得玩味，玩味的结果也最发人深省。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陶文鹏先生听说了这篇前言的情况，立即请世南先生先期发表在《文学遗产》上。世南先生于2005年1月12日的来信中讲：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;陶君嘱改写《清文选》前言为论文，已与松来君合作，然画眉未必入时，朱衣未必点头，而可自信者，则此文字字句句自我二人肺腑出，自万卷书中来，无剿说，无雷同。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里所体现的自信，来自他踏实的阅读、长期的深耕。这在他的著作中和批评文章里，都体现了这样的精神。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;选本这种文化普及方式，是传统的，但却是千百年来行之有效的一种文化传播方式，但当下较少有人愿意承担这样的工作，因为它需要投入大量精力，需要有较高的鉴赏水平，需要具备广博的知识储备和深厚的文化底蕴。注释这门学问极其难做，动辄露出马脚。而世南先生却毅然决然地答应做《清文选》这一工作，可以看出他的自信和担当。此书出版之后，读者反映很好，世南先生非常高兴，并来信讲：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;贵社明年如有新课题，适合松来与我棉力者，尚希玉成。盖仆虽已耄耋，而神明未衰，时复技痒，不乐措手无为也。 （2005年10月1日写于省图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可见他“老骥伏枥，志在千里”的雄心。因为考虑到他年事已高，不能过于劳累，所以我们没有邀请他再做一种。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“年轻的思想者”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;世南先生稳坐图书馆，似乎是个书呆子，但是他实则是个“年轻的思想者”（陈骥《永远年轻的先生》，《师友偶记》）。除了《清诗流派史》《大螺居诗文集》之外，世南先生另有《在学术殿堂外》修订再版，还有《师友偶记》，这两本书不是“纯粹”的书，收录比较杂，形式很随意，但是主题鲜明，都是论学文字，都是“干货”，其中保存了大量来往论学信笺，汇集了一些书评，讲治学方法，更讲治学精神，有意思的是还收集了与世南先生有分歧的一些观点。他在《师友偶记》前言中讲：“&#39;其争也君子&#39;，绝非意气之争，在我是&#39;吾爱吾师，吾尤爱真理&#39;。”他再一次称道梦芙先生，赞他是“诤友”，“佩服他坚持真理的勇气”。关于这部以“我和我所理解的知识人”为主题的书，世南先生说：“这本书的性质，近似《国朝汉学师承记》，是学术性的，它可做现当代学术史、思想史的资料。”的确如此，它的内容超过了一篇篇独立的论文，它包含了当代学者思想交流甚至交锋的丰富材料，学术价值非常大，在形式上无疑也是一种突破和开创。 2004年7月18日来信中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您会觉得这是一幅时代风云画卷，它反映出心灵搏击的轰轰烈烈。可以给后代留下一份宝贵的遗产，让后人知道我们这时代知识分子在怎样上下求索。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此书“外编”有一篇《当代知识分子是怎样继承和发扬中国古代士的优良传统的？ 》便体现了他在思想精神层面的探索，让人知道他并非书呆子，而他活跃的思想像他的身体超过了不少年轻人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在学术研究上，他有直接深入的讨论。在诗歌创作上，也寄托遥深，值得体味。 2005年1月12日他来信谈他的《大螺居诗存》：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;先生细加披览，便知拙诗迥非批风抹月之作，而皆痛哭太息之言。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他在《诗存》序里说：“凡为诗，必有为而作，决不叹老嗟卑，而惟生民邦国天下之忧。”他的不少诗作直录现实，让人不胜感叹，也让人感动他胸怀的宽广。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有感于先生用了十四年撰成《清诗流派史》，我在该书编辑出版后，写了一篇书评，发表在《海南日报》上，后来修改发表在《光明日报》上。寄呈先生过目，他在2004年6月4日的信中说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;忙于《清文选》工作，一般信我都搁下以后回。没想到今天得到您的信，更没想到读到您的书评。仔细读了书评以后，我竟感极而泣。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您也许会奇怪：我怎么这样容易激动？关于《清诗流派史》的书评，大约有七八篇，我并没这样激动过。而您，显然是由于身为责编，认真看了《清诗流派史》，因此又细看了《在学术殿堂外》，加上您的高超的鉴赏力和丰富的人生经历，正确的思想认识，才能写出这样一篇使我激动的书评。大作并不长，可都说到了点子上，尤其人文关怀这点，只有您敢于指出。坦白说，我写《清诗流派史》实在是抱着孔子作《春秋》、马迁作《史记》的心态。这一点，只有本校王琦珍教授一篇书评指出了，但该文似尚未问世。而您却与王先生不谋而合，这是我最快慰的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;云波先生，请让我说一句衷心感谢的话：“君为鲍叔能知管，我傲虞卿不客蝇。”这是随手凑成的一联，俱用《史记》，自觉很切。也许有人会质疑：怎么可以人对物呢？那我要大言不惭说：就算自我作古吧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;先生对我写的书评加以肯定，我有这个自信，但是却想不到引他到了“感极而泣”的地步，还写“君为鲍叔能知管”云云的感谢话来；他径直吐露自己的抱负和追求，可见没有见外。先生2011年录制超星学术视频，讲“我与《清诗流派史》”（后收入《师友偶记》），提到“葛云波先生真是我的知音”。这些都让我非常感动，让我倍感前辈对后辈鼓舞的力量，让我感到踏实做编辑的荣光。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以上的经历，无疑增加了我们的亲近。当2018年10月6日，我们全家到南昌第一次拜访世南先生，宾主欢然，他有力地握着我的手，久久不放，根本不像96岁老者的手，他能自食其力，还常去图书馆，我们都相信他能轻松度过期颐之年，我们盼望再一次拜望先生。但不成想，2021年8月2日收到了松来教授的短信，获悉世南先生于前一日晚仙逝。我本想痛定思痛之后，写篇感念的文章，然而为出版项目所累，未能如愿。今年是世南先生百年诞辰，我下定决心要写，略表对他老人家的敬仰和感怀，便有了以上不够成熟的追念文字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[娄底7岁女孩遭性霸凌疑云：到底是夸大其词还是轻描淡写？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259761]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，湖南娄底一网民称自己7岁的女儿在学校午休时被同班十几名女同学霸凌，甚至伤及下体，引起网络极大关注。而当地通报称经调查确认有女学生短暂打闹，但未发现存在故意伤害的情形。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月28日，湖南娄底一家长在社交媒体发帖，称女儿7岁，在湖南娄底某乡镇小学二年级读书，10月20日午休时间，被同班十六七个女同学在操场上霸凌，这些女同学不仅殴打其女，还对其进行性霸凌，导致女儿下体受伤，疼痛难忍。而校方和霸凌方同学家长都对解决问题态度消极。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二年级的小女孩就集体对女同学实施霸凌，尤其是涉及性霸凌，骇人听闻。让人不禁想起几个月之前曝光的山西大同某双语学校9岁小学生性霸凌事件。因此，事件很快成为网络热点，引起了极大的关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月30日，事发地冷水江市（娄底市代管县级市）以联合调查组名义发布情况说明，称发现相关视频后第一时间成立了由市教育局、公安局等部门组成的联合调查组，经公安部门初查，当事女生张某与其他六名女同学为该市某小学二年级同班同学；10月20日中午，因为在操场跳绳时发生争执，发生“相互打闹”约1分钟，其间张某被其他几名同学“短暂围住拍打”；经过调取监控，“保护性”询问涉事女生，调查目击老师和学生，未发现存在故意伤害的情形。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一官方通报对事件的定性与受害人母亲的指控天差地别，对事发过程的描述也用词模糊、语焉不详，没有对所指控的关键问题作出澄清。官方如果确有充分证据是女孩家长夸大事实，就应该公开证据反驳，否则，不仅无法消除公众的疑虑，反而会引起更大的质疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是女生张某下体有没有受伤。根据张某母亲发布的信息，张某身体有多处软组织损伤，下体也受到伤害，小便时疼痛难忍，为此被迫憋尿。但官方通报虽然确认发生了“相互打闹”，但对张某是否受伤只字未提。这也是此事中最受网民关注，也是让人最为气愤的一点。官方不应回避，应该对此进行调查并公布结果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果张某下体确实受伤，那这是非常严重的侵害未成年人事件，必须查明受伤的原因，如果涉及犯罪行为，要严惩不贷。如果张某并没有受伤，那也要拿出有足够公信力的证据，反驳女孩家长的指控。比如可以在家长陪同下带张某到娄底市以外的三甲医院进行检查，并公布检查结果。如果张某母亲夸大其词或撒谎，也不应回避。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，对当时在操场上发生的事件经过，有必要公布相关视频，以正视听。张某母亲称，张某在操场上被十六七个同班女生殴打。而官方的情况说明则称除张某外只有6名学生涉事，而且多名女生“相互打闹”只有约一分钟时间，而张某只是被几名同学“短暂围住”“拍打”。双方的说法，不仅参与人数相差巨大，而且“殴打”与“相互打闹”之间也存在着性质的巨大差别。既然官方说明中提及警方调取了学校的监控录像，那就是说事发经过是有录像的，并不是张某母亲帖子中校方所说的“监控老化”。既然有录像，那就应该完整地公之于众，让公众自己判断到底是“殴打”还是“相互打闹”，到底持续了多长时间，有没有“故意伤害”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，出于保护未成年人的考虑，对录像中能够辨认的未成年人可以进行保护性技术处理，比如打马赛克、模糊面部等，但应该保证能看出有几个人参与了事件，以及“打闹”的程度到底是怎样。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;才7岁的小女孩就会霸凌同学，而且还涉性，似乎有些不可思议。但也并非不可能。在山西大同某双语学校霸凌事件中，霸凌者也不过才9岁，而霸凌并非第一次发生，也是从二年级就开始了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一种刻板印象，好像学校中霸凌别人的就是男生。其实不然，校园暴力事件中，女性施暴的比例并不低。 2023年3月，海南曾爆出一名13岁女孩被一群同性同龄人殴打侮辱的霸凌事件。在大同事件引发极大关注时，刑法学教师蔡某也曾收到爆料，一位女同学被宿舍的其他女同学欺凌，同样有涉性行为，施害者还拍下了视频。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早年，央视曾报道过一份研究，发现网络上爆出的校园霸凌视频中，八成以上的施暴者是女性。当然这可能和女性霸凌者更倾向于拍下视频并上传到网上羞辱被害人有关，但也说明，校园暴力中女性施暴者绝不少见。而且在女性实施的校园霸凌中，不少是一群人霸凌一个人，而她们霸凌的对象，也是女性居多。还有，女性实施的霸凌中，涉性侮辱的比例不低，比如强制脱光衣服拍照之类。这或许是因为这样会给受害人带来更强烈的耻辱感。这些女性霸凌的特征，与娄底事件中受害人母亲所指控的十几名女生一起殴打、性霸凌其女儿相符。这也是网民更愿意相信受害人指控的原因之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此事在网络上引起极大的关注，而官方目前轻描淡写的情况说明，显然难以服众。这不禁让人想起，在山西大同某双语学校性霸凌事件中，学校和主管部门也曾试图大事化小小事化了，但最终，霸凌事件被坐实。这次的娄底疑似霸凌事件也是如此。如果官方有足够的证据支持其情况说明，就应该及时公开，驳斥女孩家长的指控。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[舒徐礼乐自圆融：礼学宗师沈文倬先生小记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTpOzxQVWlMy0o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/E4iGWSPPxsQh8e00gO9ijH5s3ebTpOzxQVWlMy0o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;沈文倬(1917-2009)，当代礼学宗师、著名经学家，一生潜心研习三礼之学，在礼学、经学史、文献学、甲骨金石学、版本目录学、古籍整理等诸多领域都有卓越建树，尤其是“三礼”研究，解决了礼学和经学史上许多悬而未决的难题，受到顾颉刚的高度评价。图片摄于1986年5月。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈文倬先生（1917-2009）在杭州大学是个“隐身人”。 1978年10月，我进中文系读本科，他曾在“古代汉语”课时，给我们讲过几节“古代文化常识”，但大家对他没有什么印象。读研究生时，他是导师组成员，我才开始有所了解。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上世纪八十年代初的杭大校本部（今浙大西溪校区），面积不大，高大的法国梧桐树舒展地伸向林荫道，构成一道道穹窿，展示着这个校园所经历的岁月。东南角是几排青灰色砖块砌成的四层楼房，教师集体宿舍和研究生宿舍前后相望。两楼之间是锅炉房，早晨炉火轰然作响，我们每天都要去那里打开水。秋冬时分，梧桐叶已经灰败，锅炉房的行道上撒满了细碎煤灰，映衬着青灰色的砖墙，眼前一片灰蒙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时沈先生就住在一号楼第一单元一楼的一间房子里，大约十五六个平方米，对面是公共厕所，春季潮湿,夏日闷热，冬天阴冷。没有厨房，只能在走道生火，所以二十多年间，他一直吃食堂，偶尔才煮个蹄膀之类改善一下生活。直到1986年分到两居室的房子，搬离此处（那年7月他被国务院学科评议组批准为博导）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我从未进过他的住处，只是每次路过时，会有片刻的伫视。后来多次在梦中到过他门外，从门上方的玻璃透过去，仿佛看到了墙上的条幅，却总看不清内里，就像他的为人与为学，十分神秘，望不真切。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我经常在去食堂的路上遇见他。那时他年过花甲，宽广的额头，稀疏的头发，花白的胡子，脸色却十分红润。他个子不高，但很壮实。冬天时，他在老棉袄上套一件陈旧的灰色罩衣，左手挎着一个很浅的竹篮子，也像是个簸箕，那双大手，有着粗壮的指节。他总是面带笑容，仿佛挪动似的走在路上，口中略有“呼哧呼哧”的声音。若是遇到旁人注视的目光，他用眼中的笑意作回应，嘴巴似有牵动，并不说出话来。他看起来是温和平静，又如海似渊。他微笑时身上洋溢出能量，让路人也不禁受到鼓舞。所以我觉得那个时候他的心情很不错。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们这些“新晋”的研究生，那时经常谈论的便是自己的导师和对方的导师：主要做哪个领域，出版过什么著作，在哪里发表了论文，听闻有怎样的评价，对学生有哪些要求，有什么口头禅，在课堂讲了什么新鲜事……自豪地介绍对导师的发现，互相分享，并认真地听别人的补充与议论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;室友陈剩勇是沈文倬先生所带的第一个研究生。我对沈先生的了解，便是通过剩勇同学充满崇拜的解说和大家的议论，慢慢地丰富起来的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;999&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kTlWhOwgCv9rDWA37zbDLtgi7iIhLLAXRfIVGRBC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256136&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;左起：方建新、沈先生、李解民、王云路(摄于1997年)。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈文倬先生，字凤笙，号菿闇，江苏吴江人。幼入私塾，长则自习，未获任何文凭。他早年从沈昌直学读古文辞，从金天翮、姚廷杰受文史之学。 1940年代初，从曹元弼专攻“三礼”之学，为其关门弟子，耳提面命达九年之久。曹元弼（1867-1954），人称清代最后一位杰出的经学家，时已年逾古稀，故寄厚望于沈文倬：“善守可望有成。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1946年，他发表了《说高禖》《“蜡”与“腊”》等文章，引起顾颉刚的注意，破格聘其为国立编译馆副编审，主要负责校点经籍、编撰提要、草拟经学词典。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1950年，被派往北京华北人民革命大学政治学院学习。次年6月，分配至上海图书馆，任编目部副主任。我们经常查阅的《中国丛书综录》，极厚的三册，叠起来有一尺多高，就是由他主持编成的。 1960年，《综录》编辑组被评为上海市先进集体，身为组长的他，作为代表出席了上海市群英会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1963年2月，应姜亮夫教授的邀请，调入中国科学院浙江分院的语言文学研究室（设在杭州大学，夏承焘为主任），为专职研究人员，只身赴杭州。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3月，甫抵杭，即往谒马一浮先生；4月下旬，再往。 “以后学求谒前辈学者之礼相见，主亲客敬，融洽无间”。有所悟，也有所思，撰有《蒋庄问学记》以记之。秋后到长春东北文史研究所讲《仪礼》，入冬回杭。欲再谒，未成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;次年，“谈论古学的风气戛然而止，而情趣也大减”。不久，即下乡参加“社教运动”，到了我的家乡诸暨县的某公社，驻留有时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之前，他有多篇论文在《考古》上发表（1961，1963），传言时任中国科学院院长的郭沫若先生见后，评价颇高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“文革”发生后，研究室解散，他转入杭大中文系，在系资料室做资料员。因博闻强记，同事惊为“活字典”。他则独自默处，但从未停止礼学研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1974年，被安排赴安吉参加杭大最后一期“五七”干校“农林班”，白天做“鸭司令”，晚间仍探礼学之奥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1975年3月，将《武威出土&amp;lt;礼&amp;gt;汉简考辨》等四种，寄请顾颉刚先生审阅。顾复信称“台端实为今世治礼经者之第一人也”，同时又叹息，这些成果不知何时才能面世。以上这些话语，当时只是在一个很小的圈子内流传，并不为外界知闻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/jHofSRDsIAXS1YQGGmUlO06aJt08qBm9Z1fpUvxx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;顾颉刚复沈文倬函。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到“文革”结束, 情况又有了变化。 1979年，他转到教师岗位。次年，评为副研究员，时已64岁。我们82级研究生，是他第一次招生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时杭大对中华书局的《文史》和上海古籍的《中华文史论丛》最为推崇，视为古代文史领域的顶刊，沈先生则是其中的常客。其中如《略论礼典的实行和〈仪礼〉书本的撰作》(《文史》15、16辑，1983)，提出“礼典的实践早于文字记录而存在”，由以阐明礼典与礼书的关系，后来杨向奎先生称此文是“鸿文巨制，成绩空前”。又如《黄龙十二博士的定员和太学郡国学校的设置》（1983）一文,对汉代建立经学博士的复杂史实条分缕析，正皮锡瑞《经学历史》之误，纠王国维《汉魏博士考》之偏，从而详判武、昭、宣三代各经博士官的兴废增缺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有后学称，沈先生的文章视野非常开阔，既有宏观的关照，贯通古今，又有微观的考证，心细如发。同时运用各种方法容纳材料，信息量极大。他对传统礼学中的任何问题，几乎都有独到的见解，文中的每一句话，几乎都凝聚着思考的结果。他的叙述语言非常典雅，几乎与引用文献可以无缝对接，是一种很难达到的境界。对此，我也深表赞同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，我那时并没有认真拜读过沈先生的著作与论文，也怕读，因为太深奥了。我只是读过他在《中华文史论丛》上的专栏，名为“菿闇述礼”，有时一期刊发数则，所占篇幅，不过一两页，所释则为一字或一物，都属疑难问题之解说，于文史研究关系颇大，而文字典雅凝练，令我叹服不已。这类短文，他从1946年就开始写作了,采山之铜，累积甚丰。很多年后，他汇集成书，仍取栏目之名，不过薄薄一册，十余万字，但甚得好评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;801&quot; height=&quot;564&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/48zsNz45py5GAydBqZLHrzAwV4pvbvSzSSnFdV4w.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;沈文倬先生在书斋中。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我开始学写论文时，就知道短论文是最难写的，因为数百字、千余字，要提出一个真问题，罗列材料并且讲清楚，是多么的困难呵！据说沈先生的另一本著作《〈礼〉汉简异文释》，写成时有四十余万字，他并不急于发表，反复压缩，最后出版时，只有十六万字。在我们读研究生时（1982.9-1985.6），他除了一些论文，尚无著作出版。他的第一部专著《宗周礼乐文明考论》,其实是他的论文集，在1999年才问世，写作跨度逾40年，总数也才14篇。那时他已经是耄耋之年了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生一生淡于名利。他说：“治经治礼不易，只有心除&#39;魔障&#39;，胸臆如水，方能专注向学，趋于会通。”他一生的著述其实不多，学者却推许他为“礼学大师”，因为他的文章不靠量的堆积，而是以质取胜。他的每一篇文章都解决了历史上悬而未决的问题，累积起来，便令人叹为观止，且是仰之弥高了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;非常幸运的是，沈先生专门为我们开了课。当时我们五名研究生，由五位导师指导，他们每人讲授三堂课，构成了一个学期的研究生课程。他的三堂课，连郭在贻老师也来听了，就坐在后排。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生从小患有严重的口吃，连讲一句完整的话，对他而言，都是很吃力的事情。这也是他很少上课的原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时老师们所讲的内容是自选的，也都是多年深思所得。印象中，沈文倬先生讲到了先秦诸子流派和古文今文有关问题。在我当时有限的知识里，《论》《孟》《老》《庄》作为独立的著述，稍有涉猎，《墨子》未曾读过，《礼》《书》则不敢碰，至于各家之间的关系，则全无了解。沈先生的课，却讲出了各派思想之间错综复杂的关系，特别是稷下学派、名家，这些几无著述传世的学派，原来也曾在与各家的角逐中占得大势，令其他各家不得不作回应与调整；某些消失的流派，其学说则为他家所融合而流传于后世。这让我忽然明白，原来每一家说法都不是在对某种理论来作完整系统的阐释，而是针对对手发表自己的观点，如果不知道这个论辩的背景，便会觉得其论极偏，像是对着空气作战，不知其所以然。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这很像我在篮球场上打中锋，每一次强打，都必须用力把背后顶着我的那个人靠开，才能翻身把球打进。你必须知道那“顶”的力量有多大，才能明白我这一“靠”要花多少的气力。若是将我身后的人物虚化，人们在镜头中只见我对着空气用力地先靠后转，必然会嘲笑我过度使用了蛮力，即所谓“失之偏颇”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我们的课室里，沈先生“哧哧”地把一个个字从口中用力地迸出来，有些词花了两三次方才说得完整，就用手绢擦一擦汗水，口中依然不停。讲到开心处，他也会带着吃吃的笑声。他先用他自己的考证与解说，重新厘定了旧有概念，然后再作延伸，对一连串的问题提出新的界说，于是相关的人物事件、流派学说，被拂去久积的尘垢，露出了完全不同的容貌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们所有人都肃然聆听，唯恐错过了一个音节。因为那一个个迸出来的字，如同一个个阵符在空中翻飞，构成了一个奇妙的阵法，从中显现出历史的真相。那阵势如此波诡云谲，力与力你来我往，波与波争相角逐，声与理相互呼应，这端的是百家争鸣的时代啊！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四十多年过去了，沈先生的具体解说，我只留下了若干印象，例如“礼书”晚于“礼典”；“古文”最初是指六国文字，“今文”则指汉隶，他从文本书写所用文字的角度，解释各经诸文本在汉代的传承情况；某人的解说，被立于学官，即是“师法”，未立之时，则是“家法”……其他具体的知识，如今大都已经忘记，只有他“哧哧”的声音，偶然还在我的耳边响起，于是他的讲解所引发的那种感触，再次如潮水般漫过我的脑回路，让我感受到一种莫名的震荡。更为重要的是，通过这些讲解，我懂得必须透过文献的表象，去感受时代背后那一道道的“力”及其相互作用，才能依稀看见上帝那只“无形之手”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈先生在谒见马一浮先生后，撰有一诗：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;儒经释典一炉熔，&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;证得心同理亦同。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;善美深微容别解，&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;舒徐礼乐自圆融。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并记云：“（马）先生知予治姬旦之礼，颇申礼善乐美之旨，为之赞叹不已。予亦进&#39;舒徐&#39;一义，先生颔之者再，不以别解见摒焉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今我回忆沈先生的三堂课，记录当时所见所闻的点点滴滴，敬取他的末句为题，以表怀念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[解聘247名自聘科级干部：萍乡经开区“瘦身”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259704]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPAzbx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/aRbzoDBFvweqUXSNpmmpnQkAxjFfXOcZzgoPAzbx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256318&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;萍乡经开区成立于1992年， 2010年升格为国家级经济技术开发区。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者翟星理/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是我人生中的一次重大选择。”2023年4月，张世春选择放弃体制内身份，留在江西省萍乡经济技术开发区某大型国企工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，他已经在这家国企工作了4年，但保留着事业单位编制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月，萍乡经开区根据萍乡市委市政府通过的人事制度改革方案，宣布撤销19个自设机构，并解聘247名自聘科级干部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被解聘人员中有相当一部分原本就是在编人员，经开区自聘的职务被解除后，他们可以选择保留编制、由经开区统筹安排新的工作岗位，也可以放弃编制到企业工作。原本就是编外人员的被解聘者，则可以参加全员竞聘上岗，也可以选择辞职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张世春就是一位由萍乡经开区自聘的科级干部，面对改革，他有两个选择，“想保留编内身份就要回机关，想留在企业就必须放弃编制”。召开一场家庭会议后，他决定留在企业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张世春成为自聘干部的成因并不复杂。作为中国最早设立的经开区之一，萍乡经开区经过31年发展，人口从最初的1万人增加到现在的约25万人，职能也由单一的经济开发拓展到兼顾社会管理和公共服务等，发展过程中自设管理机构、自设岗位、自聘人员，这其中既有客观原因，也有以前机构编制管理不规范、用人随意性较大等主观原因。而这也是国内开发区普遍存在的现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月，中共中央、国务院印发《党和国家机构改革方案》，明确中央和地方都要进行编制精简。在此基础上，多地开始清理编外人员，黑龙江省哈尔滨市、湖北省十堰市、云南省楚雄州、广东省惠州市、湖南省株洲市等地纷纷出台清理编外人员的方案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萍乡经开区全面规范人事管理，在解聘的247名干部中，包含清退违规借用人员63人，辞退17人，另有8人放弃事业编制到企业工作。改革后全员推行“主办制管理”（一种人员管理方式，将在编人员和编外人员统一聘为各级主办），而非简单将编外人员“扫地出门”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;被解聘的副部长&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;生于1970年的张世春，参加工作后先当了10年教师，本来的身份就是事业编制。离开学校后，张世春进入教育局工作，1997年又调到萍乡经开区，后来当上了经开区党工委党群工作部副部长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，因工作需要，张世春被调整到经开区一家大型国资企业担任党委副书记、纪委书记，编制还保留在经开区党群工作部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时像世春这样的情况还是比较多的。”党群工作部副部长喻志峰解释，即从经开区机关到企业任职，仍然保留着机关编制的这类人员，一共有七八位。国有企业都没有事业编制，但他们仍然保留着事业编制身份，属于经开区自聘的科级干部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自聘，就是自行聘任，未经上级组织部门备案，上级组织部门并不认可。如果一个公务员或事业编人员经正常组织流程被任命为副科级干部，需要上级组织部门为其备案，但经开区根据工作需要，未经上级组织部门备案就聘为正科级，那么实际上他的级别仍然是副科级。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年和2022年，江西省委巡视组两次巡视萍乡都指出这个问题。以2022年为例，当年4月省委第四巡视组巡视萍乡，7月28日，第四巡视组向萍乡经开区党工委反馈巡视情况，4条主要意见中第三条就是针对经开区的组织工作，“完善上下贯通、执行有力的组织体系差距较大”。巡视组提出整改意见建议，“聚焦解决好机构人事领域重点突出问题”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;喻志峰介绍，经开区人事领域比较突出的问题就是自设机构过多、自聘干部过多：经过多年发展，经开区自聘的科级干部达到247人，主要有三类：经开区在编人员、上级机关或兄弟区县调入的干部、经开区自聘的编外人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人事改革工作启动后，经开区组织相关领导干部对这247名自聘干部进行一对一谈话，由经开区党工委主要领导牵头。喻志峰说，一对一谈话持续了几个月，主要是阐释政策和改革的紧迫性，“耐心细致地做解聘对象的思想工作”。对于原本就在编内的自聘干部，给他们选择权，可以放弃编制选择在企业工作或保留编制在机关任职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张世春更倾向于放弃编制留在企业任职，但他也对家人讲明了在企业任职的风险：一旦企业发展遇到困难，他的收入也会随之下降，甚至可能失业，“我们商量之后最终决定我留在企业，也是相信经开区改革后企业会发展得更好”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，执行解聘工作的喻志峰本人也是自聘干部。被解聘前，他的职务是党群工作部党支部书记、副部长。解聘后，他还是事业编，但只保留了党群部副部长的职务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“小马拉大车”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;解聘247名自聘干部的同时，萍乡经开区还撤并了19个自设机构，包括区政法委、区国资委、区信访局等。喻志峰解释，“在多年经开区发展的历程中，随着不断增加的社会事务和服务人口，经开区在未取得上级同意的情况下违规自设了机构、聘任了大量干部。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萍乡经开区成立于1992年，1995年升格为省级开发区，2010年升格为国家级经济技术开发区，2021年12月底调区扩容后辖区总面积119平方公里，常住人口约25万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;截至2021年6月，国家级经济技术开发区有230个。萍乡经开区GDP已连续5年稳居全国百强经开区行列，2022年全国排名第62位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和全国其他经开区一样，萍乡经开区也是市政府的派出机关，为功能区而非行政区。 “设置之初，经开区的职能单一，主要是经济发展任务，因此上级部门给经开区核定的编制数不多。”萍乡经开区党工委党群部部长朱敏告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经开区提供给南方周末记者的材料显示，经开区设置之初并未划定具体区域范围，1995年升为省级开发区后，萍乡市政府决定将6个行政村划作直接开发范围，开发面积10平方公里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“按照这样的面积和人口，当时经开区也确实不需要太多编制。”朱敏说，但在发展过程中，萍乡经开区的面积逐渐扩大，而且伴随产业聚集、萍乡市老城区人口纾解等因素，导致经开区人口剧增。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按萍乡市官方发布的数据，经开区常住人口从2011年的11万人增长至2021年的25万人。同年，萍乡市下辖的芦溪县常住人口为26万人，莲花县常住人口为21万人。这意味着，经开区管理的人口与萍乡市的普通县城相当。在经济规模上，萍乡经开区2022年新年贺词显示，2021年前三季度经开区完成地区生产总值223.159亿元，总量列萍乡市第1位。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;管理25万人口的萍乡经开区有多少编制？朱敏介绍，2022年，上级编制部门对经开区管委会编制进行了重新核定，现有参公编102名，事业编138名，合计编制240名。而南方周末记者从权威渠道了解到，周边地市某区公务员编制有700多名，事业编有1000多名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为应对随着人口和区域面积不断增加而增加的社会管理职能，萍乡经开区开始自设机构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者了解到，经开区自设机构基本分为两种情况：人口增长产生社会管理需求，必须自设机构提供公共服务；市级职能部门出于垂直管理需要，要求经开区设立相应机构以进行工作对接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，经开区自设5个社会工作管理局，每个局管理几个行政村，实际上履行的是乡镇政府或城市街道办职能；经开区的城管局、园林管理局的设立，则是因为萍乡市城管局、园林管理局要求经开区也设立管理机构，便于城管、园林工作在萍乡全市统一规划和开展工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一些自设机构是经开区为统筹条线工作而设置的。经开区公安机关是萍乡市公安局设立的开发区分局，检察职能由萍乡市检察院设立的驻开发区检察室履行，审判机构由安源区法院托管，设立了开发区法庭。为了统筹公检法和信访、巡访、综治工作，经开区又自设了政法委。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过31年开发建设，经开区已成为一个高度产城融合的功能区，经开区管委会的职能从单一转向综合，事实上在履行类似区县政府的职能。南方周末记者采访期间，经开区一位主要领导分析，以现有编制和人员数，经开区要履行好所有管理职能有点像“小马拉大车”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“锁死入口，畅通出口”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;自设机构、自聘干部过多虽然有实际工作的需要，但也是机构人事管理不够规范造成的，机构、干部过多也产生了很多不良后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在干部队伍建设上，上级组织部门不认可经开区自聘干部，对干部成长造成了不利影响，这客观上是不利于干部的培养的。”喻志峰解释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朱敏调任经开区任党群工作部部长之前在萍乡市委组织部任职。 2019年，朱敏到萍乡市委组织部干部一科工作，负责联系经开区，“当时我就提过经开区组织工作不规范的问题，自设机构太多”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，萍乡市委、市政府大力推进萍乡经开区人事制度改革，市委组织部、市委编办、市发改委等部门牵头组织外出学习其他地区经开区人事改革的经验。到2022年，人事改革推进的力度明显加大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年第11期《中国机构改革与管理》杂志刊发了萍乡市委编办的署名文章《萍乡推动编外人员规范化管理》。文章总结萍乡市对于编外聘用人员进行清理的工作经验，总体原则是把编外聘用人员和在编人员统一纳入总量管理，机构编制部门根据部门的职能和编制情况核定编外聘用人员员额，对超出核定员额的编外聘用人员坚决清理，对员额内的编外聘用人员规范化管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文章还总结了使用编外人员的方向，对行政审批、行政执法、档案管理、政工人事、信访以及涉密等岗位禁止使用编外聘用人员；坚持“管事不聘人”的原则，用人单位的物业管理、安保、绿化养护、食堂服务、信息网络服务、公共建筑设施和设备维护等工作，除中小学、幼儿园食堂外，一律不得使用编外聘用人员，全部采取市场服务外包、政府购买服务的方式予以解决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，经开区此次清理编外聘用人员也在上述原则框定的范围内进行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月人事制度改革后，经开区根据萍乡市委、市政府批复的人事制度改革方案实行了员额总控。在这个基础上，经开区进一步规定，按照员额总控的要求，未来不再新增编外人员，只在编制限额内招录人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“锁死编外人员进入经开区的入口，同时强化对现有人员的考核管理，推行末位淘汰制，畅通出口。”朱敏说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;绝不是“扫地出门”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在解聘自聘干部时，经开区主要担心的是引起解聘对象的过度反应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朱敏就改革方案向萍乡市委主要领导进行过汇报，“领导强调了大方向：改革的目的不是把你们经开区改没了，经开区仍然是萍乡经济发展的引擎。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;撤并19个自设机构后，重新调整工作归口，将撤并掉的机构职能分别并入经开区党政办公室、经济发展局、社会发展局等8个内设机构和园区企业服务中心、社会治理中心等8个事业单位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，经开区打破身份界限，对在编人员和编外人员统一实行“主办制管理”，不区分是否在编，只看岗位，主办共分为12级，每个级别对应不同的薪酬。主办有晋级机制也有降级机制，并且设置了每年5%的考核不合格率，明确连续两年考核不合格的直接予以淘汰，实现主办级别能上能下，薪酬绩效能升能降。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在朱敏看来，经开区逐步消化编外人员绝不是简单的“扫地出门”，而是通过主办制让留下来的编内编外人员在同一个赛道竞争，“不管是体制内的还是体制外的，都要给这些年轻人留机会”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者采访期间，经开区正在进行一项调研，主题是探索干部队伍激励的新机制，通过竞岗、转岗、待岗、降岗、解聘等方式，构建具有竞争性的选拔机制。南方周末记者向经开区几位主办求证，他们表示在机构改革之后，工作节奏更快、工作强度更高、工作压力更大。 2023年国庆假期后，不少主办连续工作至今，周末基本也只能休息半天。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而另一个原因是，机构撤并、清退人员后，原有机构的社会管理职能并未完全剥离，各项职能被划分至新成立的事业单位中，因此工作总量并未减少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，随着下一轮改革的到来，全国的经济技术开发区或许将迎来一次职能上的“瘦身”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年3月发布的《安徽省“十四五”开发区高质量发展规划》，有专门章节论述开发区体制机制改革，重点提到&amp;nbsp;合理划分开发区管理机构、属地政府、开发运营公司实权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，《河南省开发区高质量发展促进条例（草案）》提请河南省人大常委会第一次审议，草案明确管委会主要承担政策制定、发展规划、行政审批、招商引资、企业服务等行政管理职能，未提及社会管理职能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两地的表述都释放出一个信号：省级层面对开发区的职能定位也许仍然是经济发展。那么，在各地开发区发展过程中逐渐增加的社会管理职能如何处理？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者了解到，国家层面针对全国开发区下一轮体制机制改革的总体规划中，理顺开发区与行政区的关系，逐渐剥离社会事务管理职能是趋势之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 21:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国际足联：沙特是2034年足球世界杯唯一申办方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259759]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 19:55:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;FIFA announced on October 31 that the Saudi Arabian Football Association was the only one to submit a proposal to host the 2034 Football World Cup before the deadline. Apply to the Football Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;FIFA confirmed that it has received Saudi Arabia’s application to host the 2034 World Cup, and Saudi Arabia is currently the only country that has expressed interest in hosting the 2034 World Cup to FIFA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/eac5aaef239e99ff9fdabaecf7cf7f55.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256476&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, FIFA announced that the only application for hosting the 2030 World Cup was jointly submitted by the football federations of Morocco, Portugal and Spain. Currently, these three countries have confirmed their intention to bid. Since the centenary celebration of the World Cup will be held in 2030, FIFA plans to hold a World Cup match in Uruguay, Argentina and Paraguay. These three countries have also confirmed their intention to host FIFA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Saudi Arabia, like Morocco, Portugal and Spain, still needs to pass the review of FIFA. If these bidding countries can meet the requirements put forward by FIFA, complete the entire bidding process and pass, then FIFA will determine its hosting rights at the FIFA Congress at the end of 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>