<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[白客：像水一样的演员]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Most of the time, Baike doesn&#39;t know where the boundaries of his abilities are and relies on his feelings. Taking on a role is not that particular about rules and regulations, it’s about getting along well. In the past few years, he has acted in many movies and dramas that focus on reality, and appeared in &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; and &quot;The Gentle Shell&quot;. He said, &quot;The abilities contained in my body were discovered by the producer and director. Thank them.&quot; And he quietly does his job as an actor, using his skills, emotions, and talents to be responsible for every performance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/vsBMgnmHeYijo0WGszOvBYMoRoFft3vyR6cl1cIK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/vsBMgnmHeYijo0WGszOvBYMoRoFft3vyR6cl1cIK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/254252&quot; title=&quot;Baike: A &quot;cowarded and frustrated&quot; &quot;The actor&#39;s way of survival&quot;>;Bake: The way of survival of a &quot;cowardly and frustrated&quot; actor&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 9, 2023, the Shanghai International Film Festival opened On the red carpet, actor Bai Ke appeared three times. In the screenings that lasted for 10 days, he was Gan Yaozu in &quot;Looking for Her&quot; and &quot;The Annual Party Can&#39;t Stop!&quot; &quot;Ma Jie&quot; and Pan Congcong in &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot;, whether he is the protagonist or supporting role, comedy or drama, he has appropriately expressed the character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Baike, becoming an actor was unexpected. On the eve of his graduation from college, he became famous for his dubbing work. In 2010, after graduating from Nanguang College of Communication University of China, he briefly worked in a television station, and then quickly went north to join the film and television company Wanhetianyi. When the company was on the verge of collapse and everyone was planning to go their separate ways, they filmed the short play &quot;Unexpectedly&quot;, which saved the company and made the director and actors an instant hit. The male protagonist of &quot;Unexpectedly&quot;, the narcissistic, self-deprecating, grassroots Wang Dachui, was played by Bai Gugu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experience of becoming popular in his early years was intertwined with the family teaching of &quot;live your own little life&quot;, and finally derived a happy-go-lucky character. He has his own comfort zone and feels good staying there. After work, I play football with my friends, watch football, read comics and TV shows, and spend time with my parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only time he experienced stepping out of his comfort zone since he was a child was when he decided to apply for the broadcasting major because he liked football and wanted to be a football commentator. After studying media for four years, although he failed to become a commentator, he became sensitive to the matter of &quot;recording&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also related to this that Baike liked the script of &quot;Looking for Her&quot;, a female self-awareness exploration in a traditional village. He said: &quot;This kind of thing is very meaningful to me. I think the topic needs to be recorded.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The filming of &quot;Looking for Her&quot; was not easy for Baike because he had to memorize Cantonese lines and play opposite Shu Qi. There was a scene where he and Shu Qi quarreled, and there was a lot of Cantonese dialogue, which was originally going to be filmed after the actors got used to each other. However, the crew encountered a typhoon as soon as they arrived in Huizhou, the filming location. In order to avoid the bad weather, director Chen Shizhong planned to shoot the quarrel scene indoors first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He would not say that I was scared before the shooting, nor would he say that I would definitely be able to do it, and then he would complete it very well. He is very relaxed, but has strong energy inside.&quot; Later Chen Shizhong said Then I realized that Bai Ke was nervous, but he hid it. Chen Shizhong had seen a journalist role he played, and on the day after watching it, he posted on WeChat Moments: Bai Ke can give the director a great sense of security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He is an actor like water. He can be matched with any actor. He is very malleable.&quot; Chen Shizhong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会主媒体中心里有什么？南周记者带你去探营]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257322]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[张家界一景区多名身着警察制服人员殴打游客？警方回应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257326]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Police Information Report&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 12:49 on September 20, 2023, the Yongding Public Security Bureau received a call from a tourist claiming to have been injured. After receiving the alarm, the Yongding Public Security Bureau quickly dispatched police to deal with the incident. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After investigation, tourist Feng had a dispute with Yang Mouyi and Qin &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; when he was buying rain gear at a shop near the parking lot of Tianmen Mountain. Feng&#39;s husband Liu was beaten and suffered eye injuries. At the time of the incident, Yang Mouyi was wearing a blue uniform, and another person, Zou Moukang, was illegally wearing a police armband. There were no public security police officers or auxiliary police officers at the scene of the incident. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Currently, the public security organs have detained Yang Mouyi and Qin for beating others, and Zou Moukang for illegally wearing police armbands and uniforms. , the case is under further processing. The police will handle the case strictly in accordance with the law, resolutely safeguard&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; the legitimate rights and interests of the victims, and investigate and correct the illegal wearing of imitation police uniforms in accordance with the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yongding Public Security Bureau&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span >;September 21, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冲着漫改来，意外被他圈粉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257320]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Recently, there are two comic dramas that attract people Pay attention to: One is the live-action version of &quot;One Piece&quot; on Netflix, and the other is &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; on Youku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, compared to &quot;One Piece&quot;, the broadcast process of &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; has been full of twists and turns. It first premiered on August 4 with 4 episodes, and then stopped airing the next day due to &quot;media reasons&quot;, setting a record for the &quot;fastest offline&quot; of a domestic drama. It did not resume broadcast until September 6, dispelling the audience&#39;s doubts that it disappeared out of thin air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/5a25a4a369827783352e693c7158d38e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/5a25a4a369827783352e693c7158d38e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251571&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Stranger&quot; &quot;Under&quot; is adapted from the well-known Chinese comic &quot;Under One Person&quot; created by Mi Er. The original work is not only well-received but also extremely popular. Since the animated version came out in 2016, it has been broadcast for a total of five seasons, with an average score of 8.4 on Douban. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;qi (qi) warrior&quot; in traditional fairy tale novels was fictionalized by Mi Er into a &quot;stranger&quot; hidden in the real world in the original work. &quot;Extraordinary people&quot; are gifted with special abilities and can skillfully control their own &quot;qi&quot;, thus possessing special abilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that during the Jiashen period (1944), several strangers discovered the &quot;Eight Wonderful Skills&quot; such as the Origin of Qi Ti, Ju Ling Qian Jiang, Fenghou Qimen, and the Tongtian Rui, which caused the strangers to People in the world fought for it, which triggered a bloody storm, known in history as the &quot;Jiashen Rebellion.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/0c12eb18e51067c31c3f414d93f0f34f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;638&quot; height= &quot;270&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/0c12eb18e51067c31c3f414d93f0f34f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251573&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The comic is adapted into Dramas have a natural barrier, which is mainly reflected in the degree of casting and adaptation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to the live-action version of &quot;One Piece&quot;, &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; also experienced a difficult casting controversy when it first aired. Zhang Chulan, played by Peng Yuchang, was questioned for her poor appearance and lacked the ruffian spirit in the original work; Feng Baobao, played by Wang Yinglu, was questioned for her dull acting skills, like a humanoid AI; Zhang Lingyu, played by Bi Wenjun, had inconsistent appearance and temperament , was criticized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/3e397c0a9ab9647b08e98a436e959af9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;736&quot; height= &quot;308&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/3e397c0a9ab9647b08e98a436e959af9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251570&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although these doubts It&#39;s not unreasonable, but it&#39;s also common for people to have difficulty in choosing the right characters for comic book adaptations. Since the audience watches the original work first, they are bound to have preconceptions and view the comic-adapted drama with resistance. When the domestic comic drama &quot;Soul of Chess&quot; came out, it was labeled as &quot;ruining childhood&quot; due to casting and styling issues. It was not until the story got better in the later years that the reputation changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/36a6d71ccad0a47b673eee745a80a5f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/36a6d71ccad0a47b673eee745a80a5f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251572&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, select Whether the corner sticks to the face or not is very important, but one move will not determine life or death. Because there is still a plot, and a good storyline can also turn the tide. And this involves the &quot;degree&quot; of adaptation: too few adaptations, and it is suspected of copying and pasting; too many adaptations, and the characters and famous scenes are not restored enough, and it is easy to fall into the misunderstanding of &quot;magic modification&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the comic drama &quot;Under the Stranger&quot;, the male protagonist Zhang Chulan accidentally got involved in the world of strangers because his grandfather Zhang Huaiyi&#39;s bones were stolen. In the process of searching for his grandfather&#39;s body, he first met Feng Baobao, a girl who behaved strangely, and then was recruited by the mysterious organization Nadu Tong. He passed the trial of the Tianshi Mansion in Longhu Mountain and got the opportunity to participate in the Alien Martial Arts Competition. Opportunity...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the descendant of the &quot;Eight Skills&quot; Qi Ti lineage, Zhang Chulan quickly became a popular star in the alien world, attracting the attention of all forces. In the process of wrestling with various forces, he gradually came to face the various alien abilities that his grandfather had taught him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e74900efbaca076c702130cdaa78d40b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;727&quot; height= &quot;311&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e74900efbaca076c702130cdaa78d40b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251574&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Original author Mi Secondly, &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; has restored the rich world view constructed with imaginative settings to a greater extent, including various sects, families and stunts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Disguised as a logistics company, &quot;Everywhere Connect&quot; has employees who are all composed of aliens. They are responsible for maintaining the balance and stability of the alien world and ensuring that ordinary people will not be aware of the existence of aliens. It is a bit like a cartoon. S.H.I.E.L.D. in the Marvel Universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the alien world, the ten men with the highest say are from the Tianshi Mansion, the Lu Family, the Lu Family, the Tianxiahui, the Wang Family, the Mu Family, and the Chen Family. Zhang Zhiwei, the Celestial Master of Longhu Mountain, is the leader of the ten men. He has a very high level of cultivation and is over a hundred years old. He is the ceiling of combat power in the alien world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/bb791c56359d86ea510d67e0cf69b036.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;302&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/bb791c56359d86ea510d67e0cf69b036.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251575&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Don&#39;t talk about it &quot;Quan Xing&quot;, who has no principles and no rules, is an alien organization that does all kinds of evil. &quot;Complete nature&quot; has been around for thousands of years. It was founded by Yang Zhu, one of the hundreds of scholars in the Warring States period. It originally emphasized &quot;preserving integrity and not burdening the body with things&quot;. Unfortunately, it gradually went astray in the later period and became an evil spirit in the alien world. group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the number of episodes currently aired, the overall quality of &quot;Under the Strangers&quot; is still good. First of all, director Xu Hongyu set a clear main line for the whole play, changing the unit-style narrative habit of the original work, using the male protagonist Zhang Chulan as the entry point, allowing him to lead the audience into the world of strangers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, as the plot progresses, several suspense points in the original work become clear and intriguing, such as the reasons for the &quot;Jiashen Rebellion&quot; and the mystery of Feng Baobao&#39;s life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, in addition to restoring the characters and famous scenes, the main creator also showed good subjective initiative, such as rationalizing the popular character Wang Ye in advance. Under the interpretation of actor Hou Minghao, this The charm of the character continues in the play. Many viewers said that they came for the comic adaptation and eventually became fans of Wang Ye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, the entire plot is dense and fast-paced. The plot has advanced to the 20th episode, and the content of the first two seasons and extra chapters of the animated version has been completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e1f0d2c3443b5dc9a4c30ec286e96262.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;455&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e1f0d2c3443b5dc9a4c30ec286e96262.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251577&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the core idea It seems that &quot;Under the Stranger&quot; has firmly captured the essence of the original work, that is, &quot;What is a Stranger&quot;. Mi Er once mentioned in an interview that this story began with the word &quot;foreigner&quot;. He wanted to express the theme of &quot;if one day you find that you are different from others, how should you deal with yourself and how should you get along with the world?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone will encounter such torture when growing up. Some people choose to stick to themselves, while others choose to blend in with others. There is no right or wrong way to do this. No matter what choice you make, the ultimate goal is to find your own place in this world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/cba1cf717be21996e7db64fffed47ee5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;789&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/cba1cf717be21996e7db64fffed47ee5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251576&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; Stranger &quot;The word itself has two meanings, one is a person with special powers, and the other is a rejected alien. The male protagonist Zhang Chulan happens to possess these two characteristics. But what he yearned for wholeheartedly was to be an ordinary person and live an ordinary life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this reason, he endured it for 12 years, in order not to expose his strength and to survive. But the tree wanted to be still but the wind didn&#39;t stop. The more he wanted to be calm, the more he couldn&#39;t be calm. When things finally came to a head, he gave up his patience and began to explore the truth about the alien world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e75c9fa1134fb62283f569f81e90c661.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;597&quot; height= &quot;248&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/e75c9fa1134fb62283f569f81e90c661.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251578&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you say before In 22 years, being a stranger but being willing to be ordinary is a kind of strength. After that, it is another kind of strength to face one&#39;s own abilities and choose to live a life with dignity and confidence. What the play emphasizes is not &quot;strangers&quot;, but &quot;people&quot; - people&#39;s choices, people&#39;s confrontation with fate, and people&#39;s pursuit of the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, this is not an impeccable drama. If you are repulsive to the &quot;secondary sense&quot; itself, you will probably accept incompetence. But if you like this style and the passion of teenagers, then it will most likely provide you with happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李硕：直面历史深渊，再现惊心动魄的华夏新生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256821]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;The book &quot;Jian Shang&quot; has caused waves in the circles of archeology, history and literature and history enthusiasts, making the author Li Shuo the best performer in 2023 The most dazzling academic newcomer. Li Shuo uses his extremely talented imagination, powerful analysis and reasoning, and based on fragmented archaeological information and sporadic ancient documents, reasoning, imagination, and connections, he paints a possible full picture of the early days of Chinese civilization for us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jBfKO2fDHmO3El3jxoPilMbISTLgrpdP1esrH0bD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jBfKO2fDHmO3El3jxoPilMbISTLgrpdP1esrH0bD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250538&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 March At about 4 pm on the 15th, it was dull and windless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was hanging in an online work meeting, and I casually swiped my finger through WeChat on my phone, and a shocking &quot;last words&quot; jumped into my eyes - it was Li Shuo, a young scholar I met two months ago. He said that because there were no groups in his circle of friends, he sent a message to inform his friends: If you have any debts, please contact him. As for other messages, he will not reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person who has been looking forward to meeting each other for months may suddenly never have the chance to meet again. For the next week, I was in a state of trance, savoring the extremely plain words of the Japanese tea ceremony - &quot;One period, one moment, should be cherished in this life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shuo&#39;s &quot;last words of life and death&quot; were screenshotted and forwarded by good people, and added The media followed up, and public attention surged. This also made his new work &quot;Jian Shang&quot; unexpectedly &quot;break the circle&quot; and sold out within a few days. For a time, &quot;Jian Shang&quot; and several past books by Li Shuo were marked with the word &quot;pre-sale&quot; on major book websites. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A wonderful book of genius&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since the beginning of 2023, Li Shuo has been listed as a scholar of our focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if there was no last words incident that attracted public attention, the book &quot;Jian Shang&quot; was enough to make Li Shuo the most outstanding academic rookie in 2023. Since its publication at the end of 2022, the book has caused waves in the circles of archeology, history and literature and history enthusiasts. According to data provided by the publisher, the print run had reached 100,000 copies by the end of February. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Hong, the former captain of the Erlitou archaeological team and archaeologist, used &quot;shock&quot; to describe his feelings after reading the manuscript. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a strange book with a bloody atmosphere, in which Li Shuo reveals a dark past in the early days of Chinese civilization. After examining the archaeological excavation results from the end of the Neolithic Age to the Shang and Zhou Dynasties, he found that: during the Yin and Shang Dynasties, there was a nationwide, large-scale, and normalized phenomenon of human blood sacrifice, and various methods of cruelty and sacrifice were very mature; But starting from the Zhou Dynasty, this phenomenon suddenly almost completely disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After analyzing the oracle bone inscriptions and bronze inscriptions of this period and re-interpreting the &quot;Book of Changes&quot;, Li Shuo believed that the disappearance of human sacrifice was directly related to the Zhou Dynasty&#39;s destruction of the Shang Dynasty. After King Wu destroyed the merchants and died of illness, Zhou Gongdan, who was assisting the government, banned the merchants&#39; custom of human sacrifice, almost completely erasing the records and historical memories of blood sacrifices, and replaced them with &quot;virtue&quot; and &quot;the concept of destiny&quot; centered on etiquette and music. ”, thus recreating a new Chinese civilization characterized by peace and tolerance, which continues to this day. Since then, the history of human sacrifice has been blank in the Central Plains for more than three thousand years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The insight and understanding of the &quot;Shang and Zhou Dynasties&quot; began with Wang Guowei in the late Qing Dynasty and the early Republic of China. In &quot;On the Institutions of the Yin and Zhou Dynasties&quot;, he put forward the view that &quot;the changes in Chinese politics and culture did not occur during the Yin and Zhou Dynasties&quot;, and from the perspective of his eldest son ( ;&quot;>;This paper discusses the differences between the Yin and Zhou Dynasties in three aspects: the patriarchal system, mourning clothes, enfeoffment, etc.&lt;/span>;), the number of temples, and the non-marriage of the same surname, which opened the prelude to the study of the &quot;Shang and Zhou Dynasties&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Jian Shang&quot; is a further development of Mr. Jing&#39;an&#39;s views. Li Shuo focuses on &quot;blood sacrifice of human animals&quot; to explain why the theocracy of merchants was so drastically transformed into the secular moral-political system of the Zhou Dynasty centered on &quot;morality&quot; during the Shang and Zhou Dynasties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shuo, who has always been a talented writer, also showed his outstanding writing talent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to calmly and calmly restoring the large-scale killings at human sacrifice sites during archaeological excavations, he also carved out dramatic story lines in the Shang and Zhou Dynasties - for example, the Zhou people hunted for the Shang king The &quot;black history&quot; of human sacrifice, the love and marriage between Boyikao, the eldest son of King Wen, and Yijiang, the daughter of Jiang Taigong, the dark memories and pain caused by the blood sacrifice to King Wen&#39;s family, and the care King Wen took with tortoise bones in the dark cellar Deducing and plotting the great cause of destroying business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, &quot;Jian Shang&quot; re-understood and reshaped King Wen of Zhou, King Wu of Zhou, Gongdan of Zhou and others. In particular, Zhou Gongdan, the seemingly broad-minded &quot;moral incarnation&quot; in the Confucian classics, presents a rich and complex appearance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shuo wrote &quot;The Great History of Confucius&quot; in his early years. He connected the two Confucian saints who were five hundred years apart and speculated that Confucius may have discovered the bloody history that Duke Zhou deliberately erased and the The intention behind it. This explains quite convincingly why a scholar from the Spring and Autumn Period paid homage to the Duke of Zhou, as well as the sadness and heaviness that he felt in his old age: &quot;I no longer dream of seeing the Duke of Zhou.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/KQOWYvUQtlpFaN27HtwaRxiP225au4c8TbRLnN0J.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/KQOWYvUQtlpFaN27HtwaRxiP225au4c8TbRLnN0J.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250537&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Shuo at the Badshahi Mosque in Lahore, Pakistan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;Puzzle game super player&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first time I learned the name Li Shuo was 10 years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2012, an article of tens of thousands of words, &quot;Zhou&#39;s Destruction of Shang and the Rebirth of Chinese Civilization,&quot; has been circulating in the online community of literature and history enthusiasts. The author is Li Shuo. Its novel and unique viewpoints, strange imagination, and vivid narrative have left an unforgettable impression on many people. The article has also become a long-lasting hot topic in the literary and historical circles. Because it was too strange and strange, I regarded it more as an imaginative &quot;historical possibility novel&quot;, similar to &quot;The History of the Mayan Conquest of the Yin Shang Fleet&quot; by the best-selling author Ma Boyong in his early years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following more than ten years, Li Shuo continued his exploration, thoroughly delved into the professional fields of Neolithic Age and Xia and Shang archaeology, visited archaeological sites, and reinterpreted the &quot;Book of Changes&quot;, and finally wrote this inspiring article He Chuangjian&#39;s &quot;wonderful articles&quot; have developed into a work of nearly 500,000 words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Jian Shang&quot; has not only been highly praised and recommended by academic authorities, but also caused considerable controversy in the field of classics and history - mainly questioning Li Shuo&#39;s logic and arguments in constructing the entire book. Excessive use of reasoning and imagination is the so-called &quot;too much imagination&quot;. Some conservative academics even believe that &quot;Jian Shang&quot; should not be classified as a serious academic work, but more like a wonderful novel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This reminds one of what a famous Qin and Han historian said: It is a blessing that less than 10% of historical records have survived. In the ancient times when civilization itself was still in its infancy, historical reconstruction relied almost entirely on sporadic archaeological excavation results, leaving a huge blank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the leaders of all spirits, we are so eager to understand our ancestors and past. When faced with the reality of a long history, lack of records, and limited cultural relics that make it difficult to form a complete and convincing narrative, how should we find and restore our past? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shuo provides a new research and writing method full of personal color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Jian Shang&quot;, he is like a super player playing jigsaw puzzles: with extremely talented imagination, powerful analysis and reasoning, based on fragmented archaeological information, sporadic Ancient documents, reasoning, imagination, and connections provide us with a possible overall picture of the early days of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is no exaggeration to say that for the formation and transformation of early Chinese civilization, Li Shuo came up with a complete and logically consistent explanation model that is currently the most convincing. As archaeologist Xu Hong pointed out: Li Shuo&#39;s research and writing are certainly not &quot;perfect&quot;; but in comparison, many current studies of ancient times are mediocre works of little value and significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the interview, many young scholars agreed on one point: &quot;Jian Shang&quot; is a true milestone in the research and writing of ancient history. If there are more archaeological discoveries and research in the future, many of his inferences and imaginations will be tested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Whether it is confirmation, supplement, or partial falsification, it is very valuable.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/13/iBkO5ZxbWsP0L4wnSODOV8lMvFDYULlf5ApSlkLR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/13/iBkO5ZxbWsP0L4wnSODOV8lMvFDYULlf5ApSlkLR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Born to Death&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Li Shuo and I met in January 2023, for The book &quot;Jian Shang&quot; made an interview with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That winter, Li Shuo was collecting and conducting research in Pakistan. The signal on the road was sometimes good or bad. I suggested that we meet and chat after he returns to China: in addition to communication issues, the main reason is because I have a lot of things I want to communicate with him outside of &quot;Jian Shang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more I learn about Li Shuo and his writings, the more curious I become: a young scholar who was originally from a mainstream elite and possesses talents can definitely have a more comfortable and leisurely life, and it is easier to achieve success and fame. , why did he choose such a marginal, difficult, and dangerous path? He also laughed at himself as a &quot;homeless scoundrel&quot; who wandered around all year round. He was forty years old, had no house, no car, no money, and was sometimes burdened with making ends meet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shuo was born in 1977. He studied in the liberal arts experimental class of Peking University for his undergraduate degree. He worked as a reporter for several years and later entered the History Department of Tsinghua University to study for a master&#39;s and doctoral degree. When he graduated with a doctorate, he had every chance of getting a teaching position in a university in a major mainland city, but he went to a border area to find a job. In his spare time, he travels to the Himalayas and South Asia all year round, which are geopolitically sensitive areas where ethnic, religious and military conflicts occur frequently. During the trip, he was questioned and &quot;clinged&quot; by the local military and police as a suspicious person, but he also made some interesting new friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Spring Festival of 2023, a crisis broke out in Pakistan and the situation suddenly became tense. Friends were all worried about his safety on the road. Every day, he recorded his &quot;awkward&quot; encounters with the military and police along the way, and talked and laughed with them without taking it seriously, until he suddenly lost contact and disappeared for more than ten days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I had a very bad premonition at the time, thinking that his life was in danger.&quot; One of his friends recalled - later I learned that Li Shuo suddenly fell ill and fell into a coma on the road. After being rescued locally, Was rushed back to the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shiping, a young scholar who has a close relationship with him, said: Li Shuo is not a simple adventurer. The reason why he travels in seemingly unstable areas all year round is out of his interest in the historical Silk Road and the history of the Silk Road. Interests and passions in a multicultural and ethnic intersection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In fact, his research and writing path has inherited the historical writing tradition of the East and the West since ancient times. Whether it is Herodotus, the &#39;father of history&#39; in the West, or Sima Qian in China, In ancient times when transportation was inconvenient and travel was full of dangers, they traveled around and conducted field surveys.&quot; &quot;Today, when transportation and communication are so convenient, many historical researchers and writers have abandoned this tradition.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shuo has a wild heart and great feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than ten years, he has been walking, thinking and writing with his life. In the few years when he was writing &quot;Jian Shang&quot;, Li Shuo fell into a state of depression because he faced that extremely bloody and violent dark history for a long time. His friend and travel writer Suishui believed that this was probably the main factor that caused him to suffer from the dangerous disease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 is an extraordinary year for Li Shuo. In this personal disaster, his calmness and indifference in the face of life and death made many people who knew him or did not know him respect him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a brush with death, his physical and mental state improved significantly after the operation. He is currently receiving treatment while starting to write a new book that he has been preparing for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“《诗经•彼阳》”引人爆笑之余：伪诗伪文何以走红网络？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257308]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a &quot;fake poem incident&quot; has attracted attention. The official account of the School of History and Culture of Central China Normal University published a promotional article, which published a student&#39;s reflections when participating in military training. &quot;During the interview, he used &quot;The Book of Songs·Beyond the Sun&quot; to express his feelings.&quot; The full text was immediately published. I wrote this poem &quot;The Book of Songs·Beyond the Sun&quot;: &quot;If the sun comes, the eastern sun rises. The crimson mist covers it, like silk curtains. The sun is green, the mist is rippling. The red stone winter stream is like an agate pond. . The sun is setting in the evening, and warm dreams are like joy. I swim in the floating bath, like a pheasant flying.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the article was published, it triggered hilarious ridicule across the Internet: The so-called &quot;Book of Songs·Beyond the Sun&quot; is simply not It does not exist. This poem is simply a forgery written by modern people and has been circulated on the Internet for a long time. The interviewed students &quot;quoted&quot; the song &quot;Bi Yang&quot; with the intention of complaining about it as a &quot;homonym&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the public opinion fermented, the official account of the School of History and Culture of Central China Normal University quickly deleted the article. On September 19, the college stated in the &quot;Situation Statement&quot; that &quot;the control was not strict and a tweet caused a negative impact, and we deeply apologize&quot;, &quot;the college has conducted a profound review and has criticized and educated relevant personnel&quot; and will &quot;in-depth &quot;Problem rectification&quot;, &quot;drawing inferences from one example&quot;, &quot;strengthening student education guidance&quot; and &quot;strengthening public account management&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While making people laugh, this incident also raises a question, that is, the inner mechanism and past and present life of such &quot;pseudo-poetry and pseudo-essays&quot;: why do they appear, and how do they become popular? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, pseudo-poems and pseudo-texts have appeared since the beginning of the Internet, and have been &quot;carried forward&quot; in the new media era. For example, the song mentioned by Han Han in the novel &quot;Three Gates&quot; &quot;I can smell the flowers when I lie down, I know how to paint the sky. The fish kisses the water on the stone, and the stone answers the spring green&quot;, which has caused a lot of jokes and many &quot;adaptations&quot; &quot;Re-creation&quot;, the person who forwarded it inadvertently hit the target. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Originated from the Internet, the author is unknown” is often a major feature of these pseudo-poems and pseudo-articles. Most pseudo-poems and pseudo-texts are spread quickly on the Internet, and the author cannot be found at all. The reason is also very simple, because these &quot;poems&quot; were originally written by pretending to be based on the ancients, and the real author naturally had to hide his identity. The natural &quot;anonymity&quot; at the beginning of the Internet was the natural soil for pseudo-poems and pseudo-texts to flourish. The Internet has given birth to a large number of pseudo-poems and pseudo-articles, and pseudo-poems and pseudo-articles have also been widely spread due to the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It spreads like wildfire without realizing it is fake. This is another major characteristic of fake poems and fake prose. In particular, fake poems and fake articles can inadvertently deceive highly educated people into confusion. In the &quot;Warring States Policy&quot; incident in 2009, a doctor in Shanghai blurted out during an interview, &quot;&#39;What the hell? The word &quot;comes from &quot;Warring States Policy&quot; and describes those who show off their appearance and seize fame and status,&quot; which also caused an uproar on the Internet. In fact, the so-called &quot;&quot;Warring States Policy·Chu Ce&quot;&quot; from which this sentence comes is purely a joke made by netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having existed since ancient times, pseudo-poems and pseudo-texts write about real things at this moment, but they must be deliberately wrapped in a layer of classical Chinese, with homophony, puns, anonymity, and hidden meanings. The final rhetorical method is completed. In other words, although the object of its projection is contemporary, its grammar and rhetoric are &quot;ancient&quot; to the letter, and its &quot;pseudo-submission technique&quot; is a technique that the ancients have long used. &quot;The Book of Songs: Biyang&quot; is also in line with the true meaning of the &quot;Book of Songs&quot; in terms of effect, &quot;The Book of Songs can be used to inspire, to observe, to group, and to complain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the famous &quot;Full Score Essay on the College Entrance Examination&quot; &quot;The Death of Red Rabbit&quot;, the author cleverly uses the &quot;character design&quot; of &quot;The Romance of the Three Kingdoms&quot; to describe the great meaning of &quot;integrity&quot;, which is essentially an essay. It is an excellent &quot;pseudo-poem and pseudo-article&quot;, and its technique of fake substantiation is undoubtedly much better than the above-mentioned cases. There is even an allusion made up by Su Shi: &quot;Gaotao is a scholar, and he will kill people. Gao Tao said to kill three, Yao said to forgive him. The charm of &quot;three&quot;: There is no such allusion in ancient times, but Su Shi&#39;s fabrication is undoubtedly in line with Yao&#39;s &quot;personality&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pseudo-poetry and pseudo-articles became popular due to the boom of the Internet, but they will eventually be destined to decline due to technological iteration. For example, there are endless fake poems by Li Bai on the Internet. There are many well-known literature professors in the society who personally identify the poems based on the level and rhyme. There are also many netizens who &quot;look through the complete works of Li Taibai&quot; to verify the authenticity; &quot;Warring States Policy&quot; Incident&quot; also alerted literature professors to falsify this false article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, various large language models have emerged. The powerful computing power of artificial intelligence can not only produce pseudo-poems and pseudo-texts on a large scale, but also easily crawl ancient documents and identify authentic texts. Fake. &quot;The Book of Songs: Biyang&quot; has been circulating for many years, and senior netizens have also developed the ability to identify fakes at a glance. This time the editor of the public account was deceived into a fog. He can only say that his own network &quot;rank&quot; needs to be improved, and he did not make good use of the rich network resources to do the identification work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Shishuo Xinyu·Pai Diao&quot; records, &quot;Xi Chizhi and Sun Xinggong were not acquainted, so they sat together with Duke Huan. Huan said to Sun: &#39;We can talk to Xi in the army.&#39; Sun Yun: &#39;Stupid You, a barbarian Jing, dare to enmity with a big country?&#39; Xi Yun said: &#39;Severely cutting down the yong and yellow, as for Taiyuan.&#39;&quot; Sun Chuo mocked Xi Chuo Chi for being a &quot;barbarian Jing&quot; who was born in the Chu region, and Xi Chuo retorted that his native place was In Taiyuan, a place where the Huns were infested, two people here each quoted a poem from &quot;The Book of Songs·Xiaoya&quot;, which was just right and clever, which shows the eternal charm of the &quot;Book of Songs&quot;. After all, pseudo-poems and pseudo-texts will no longer be as easy for people to take the bait as before, but the cultural interest derived from classical poetry will continue, whether it is a simple homophonic curse, or a higher-level &quot;playing with poetry&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[20家银行净利占A股1/3强，“利润王”对抗息差压力分化加剧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257314]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-22 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Major commercial banks, the “profit kings” of China’s A-share market, are facing unprecedented profit pressure because overall interest rates The gap has fallen to historic lows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the People&#39;s Bank of China will implement the second reserve requirement ratio cut in 2023 starting from September 15, 2023, which has eased the liability costs of commercial banks to a certain extent, and the previous two asymmetric interest rate cuts have also moderately protected businesses. The interest rate spread of banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite the central bank&#39;s protective mentality, under the complex and special economic situation in 2023, the profitability of commercial banks is being tested. Which banks are more resilient? Which banks are under pressure? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the 2023 mid-term reports of commercial banks, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center analyzed the 20 major domestic banks with assets of 2 trillion yuan and above (18 of which were rated as domestic banks in 2022). Systemically important banks) conduct vertical and horizontal comparative studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This research refers to 20 large domestic commercial banks (referred to as &quot;20 banks&quot; in this article), including 6 major state-owned commercial banks (Industrial, Agricultural, China, Construction, Communications, and Postal Savings Bank), 9 national joint-stock commercial banks (China Merchants, Industrial Bank, CITIC, Everbright, Pudong Development Bank, Ping An, Huaxia, Minsheng, Zheshang) and 5 city commercial banks (Bank of Beijing, Bank of Ningbo, Bank of Shanghai, Bank of Jiangsu, Bank of Nanjing), Their asset scale exceeds 2 trillion yuan. (Since it did not disclose its semi-annual report, China Guangfa Bank was not included in this statistical analysis.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the above comparative research, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also surveyed the research teams of large domestic securities firms and banks, and Combined with each bank&#39;s interim results press conference (including both media press conferences and investor exchange meetings), an in-depth analysis of changes in the core operating indicators of the above banks was conducted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The study found that against the background of prudent but loose monetary policy in the first half of the year, the overall revenue of the 20 major banks fell by 3.9% year-on-year, and individual banks faced capital pressure. From the perspective of influencing factors, the narrowing of interest spreads is the main drag, but the margin of decline in net interest margins has narrowed. However, the net profits of 20 banks increased by 3.3% year-on-year, mainly due to the decline in non-performing ratios and provisions that fed back profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the three echelons of state-owned banks, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks, the competitiveness of each bank against the cycle has shown obvious differentiation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Scale and provisions&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;VS&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Interest spread&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Net profit of city commercial banks increased The fastest&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center counted the mid-term report data of 20 banks and learned that in the first half of 2023, the operating income of the 20 banks totaled 2.92 trillion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 3.8% , but net profit rose instead of falling, with net profit attributable to the parent company reaching 1.03 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 2.9%. The total net profit attributable to parent companies of all companies in the A-share market during the same period was 2.95 trillion, and the net profits of 20 banks accounted for more than one-third of the net profits of all listed companies in the A-share market. They can be described as the &quot;profit kings&quot; in the true sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/h6rabkaDOJa8s94SO41VwKdKJeAyVlPlmwxcY0mw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;577&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/h6rabkaDOJa8s94SO41VwKdKJeAyVlPlmwxcY0mw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of scale, state-owned banks have an absolute advantage. In the first half of the year, the average revenue of the six major state-owned banks was about 307.8 billion yuan, and the average net profit attributable to the parent company was 115 billion yuan; the average revenue of the nine joint-stock banks was 89.4 billion yuan, and the average net profit attributable to the parent company was 30 billion yuan; the average operating income of the five city commercial banks Revenue was 31 billion yuan, with an average net profit attributable to the parent company of 13.5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;State-owned banks, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks all show an obvious trend of differentiation. For example, among the state-owned banks, the net profit of ICBC was 174.720 billion, while that of Bank of Communications was 46.555 billion; among the joint-stock banks, the net profit of China Merchants Bank was 76.437 billion, while that of Zheshang Bank was 7.965 billion; among the city commercial banks, the net profit of Bank of Jiangsu was as high as 17.626 billion, exceeding Many joint-stock companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of growth rate alone, city commercial banks performed better. In the first half of the year, the revenue of the five city commercial banks increased by 3.4% year-on-year, and the net profit attributable to the parent company increased by 10.9% year-on-year. However, the revenue of the six major state-owned banks and nine joint-stock banks declined year-on-year, while profits increased slightly year-on-year. Among them, the revenue of the six major state-owned banks decreased by 4.8% year-on-year, and the net profit attributable to the parent company increased by 2.5% year-on-year; the revenue of 9 joint-stock banks decreased by 2.7% year-on-year, and the net profit attributable to the parent company increased by 2.0% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center surveyed the research teams of major securities firms and banks and found that in terms of factors affecting performance, scale is the main driving force, followed by provisions, and interest spreads are the main drag, followed by is the cost. According to calculations by CITIC Securities, growth in scale has contributed positively to net profit by 12.2%, and provision and other non-interest have contributed positively to net profit by 4.4% and 2.2% respectively; while narrowing of interest spreads and increasing operating expenses are the main drags. items, dragging down profits by 13.2% and 2.5% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of particular note is Bank of Jiangsu. The bank&#39;s net profit attributable to the parent company in the first half of 2023 increased by 27.2% year-on-year, and revenue growth reached 10.6%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/2g1Shb7xfx5xkjvO84lmRoEouIspBIYAzur2KeL0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/2g1Shb7xfx5xkjvO84lmRoEouIspBIYAzur2KeL0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251549&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is in line with Jiangsu Bank’s focus on small and micro business operations strategy is closely related. The bank&#39;s interim report showed that the balance of small and micro loans was 625 billion yuan, accounting for 35.80% of total loans. At the same time, the non-performing loan ratio of Bank of Jiangsu was 0.91%, a decrease of 0.03 percentage points from the end of the previous year; the provision coverage ratio was 378.09%, an increase of 6.43 percentage points from the end of the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can Bank of Jiangsu maintain a declining NPL ratio while growing rapidly? From an internal perspective, firstly, Bank of Jiangsu attaches great importance to financial technology and proposes the strategy of building “the bank with the most Internet big data genes”, with the president also serving as the chief information officer. Second, the channel outlets are widely distributed. Bank of Jiangsu has 460 business outlets spread across counties in Jiangsu Province and is familiar with the local economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the external ecosystem, Jiangsu’s strong private economy is the foundation for the bank’s development. As of the end of 2022, there were a total of 13.608 million private enterprises and individual industrial and commercial households in Jiangsu Province, accounting for 96.4% of the province&#39;s business entities. In 2022, the added value of the province&#39;s private economy will reach 7.1 trillion yuan, accounting for 57.7% of Jiangsu Province&#39;s GDP, and its contribution to the province&#39;s GDP growth will increase from 63.1% in the previous year to 72.2%. This can also be confirmed in the &quot;Suzhou Financial Ecosystem In-depth Survey&quot; series by the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The expansion of commercial banks is often accompanied by capital consumption. Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that, overall, the core tier one capital adequacy ratio of commercial banks is still relatively high, but a few banks are facing certain capital pressure. For example, joint-stock banks CITIC, Hua Xia and Zheshang Bank have their core tier 1 capital adequacy ratio approaching the regulatory red line. However, according to the &lt;span>;China Securities Regulatory Commission&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&#39;s recently released &quot;Rescue&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Combination Punch&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>; the China Securities Regulatory Commission Recently, they have been cautious about financing from commercial banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The proportion of corporate loans has increased&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Business loans have become new&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Personal loans&lt;/strong>; strong>;&lt;strong>;Increase&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Main force&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The deposit and loan business is the basic business of the bank, and the expansion of the asset balance sheet is the core business of the bank. important growth strategy. In the first half of 2023, the total assets of the 20 banks were 260.04 trillion, a year-on-year increase of 11.9%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/RyZrGgDlIodsSjTWd8XENxoij9sZk8IT0zjwnKvY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/RyZrGgDlIodsSjTWd8XENxoij9sZk8IT0zjwnKvY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251550&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of asset structure, the six major state-owned banks as a whole Relatively stable; 9 joint-stock banks have increased their financial investment proportions, slightly decreased loans, and differentiated assets among peers; 5 city commercial banks have relatively large differences. The proportion of assets of Bank of Ningbo and Bank of Nanjing increased by 1.95% and 1.39% respectively year-on-year. The proportion of financial investment of Bank of Beijing increased by 5.4% year-on-year. The proportion of deposits from banks of Shanghai Bank increased by 28.8% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the loan structure, the proportion of retail loans has declined while the proportion of corporate loans has increased. In the first half of 2023, the corporate loans of the 20 banks accounted for 57.89%, a year-on-year increase of 3.8%, and the retail loans accounted for 37.60%, a year-on-year decrease of 6.0%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that the main reason is that driven by policies, credit demand for large infrastructure and core manufacturing industries is the first to recover, while retail loans are dragged down by residents’ income levels and consumption willingness, and effective demand not tall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among retail loans, the proportion of mortgage loans decreased, and operating loans became the main source of loan growth. Judging from the banks that disclosed operating loan data, in the first half of 2023, among state-owned banks, China Construction Bank, ICBC and Bank of Communications increased by 98.2%, 44.8% and 39.1% respectively year-on-year; among joint-stock banks, Industrial Bank increased by 26.4% year-on-year; city commercial banks Among them, Bank of Shanghai and Bank of Jiangsu increased by 60.8% and 53.7% respectively year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The low interest rate of operating loans is one of the reasons for its rapid growth. Whether business loans are diverted to other uses in violation of regulations has always attracted much attention. The Central Bank and the State Administration of Financial Supervision jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Adjusting and Optimizing Differentiated Housing Credit Policies&quot; and &quot;Notice on Matters Related to Reducing the Interest Rates of Existing First Home Loans&quot; jointly issued on August 31. &quot;It can also reduce the space for illegal use of business loans and consumer loans to replace existing housing loans.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the current operating loan interest rate is still lower than the housing loan interest rate, and borrowers still have room for replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Term deposits will continue&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;International competitiveness needs to be improved&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In high-quality assets In less cases, banks have an urgent and realistic task of managing liability costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparative research by the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that the regularization of liability-side deposits continues, mainly due to the increase in the proportion of regular personal deposits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2023, corporate time deposits among the 20 major banks have diverged. In terms of growth rate, Agricultural Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and China Construction Bank grew faster. However, the proportion of personal time deposits has generally increased. Among them, Industrial Bank had the largest year-on-year increase, reaching 45.4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/kmKuJtGFXhLoifcQne7694knOWVsg7jXlc1s8rSS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/kmKuJtGFXhLoifcQne7694knOWVsg7jXlc1s8rSS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that in the short term Judging from the above, the expansion of bank asset balance sheets is related to the prudent and loose monetary policy in the first half of the year. Measures to stabilize growth continued to be introduced, and the real economic sector began to increase leverage. Data show that the leverage ratio has increased significantly by 10.8pcts from the end of 2022, and commercial banks have overall accelerated their balance sheet expansion. But in the long term, China&#39;s banking industry needs to improve its income structure. Compared with overseas, the revenue of China&#39;s banking industry is mainly realized by the expansion of asset business, and the proportion of non-interest income of light capital is still not high. China&#39;s banking industry needs to further strengthen its product innovation, talent training and business development capabilities in financial markets, wealth management, investment banking, transaction banking, etc., further enhance the level of non-interest business income generation, and increase return on capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Large banks also need to improve their international business capabilities. Take ICBC as an example. The financial report shows that ICBC has ranked first among the top 1000 global banks in the British &quot;The Banker&quot; list for eleven consecutive years, ranked first among the global commercial banks in the U.S. Fortune 500 list for eleven consecutive years, and ranked first in the British Brand Finance list for seven consecutive years. Ranked first among the top 500 most valuable global bank brands. However, ICBC mainly relies on the support of the domestic business market, and its degree of internationalization and international business competitiveness lag behind the top-ranked large European, American and Japanese banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that as of the end of June, ICBC had established 415 overseas institutions in 49 countries and regions. However, the total assets of ICBC’s overseas institutions only account for 7.3% of the group’s total assets. Among them, assets in Hong Kong and Macao accounted for 46.41% of the assets of overseas institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The decline in net interest margin narrowed&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Under the double attack of the scarcity of high-quality assets and the regularization of deposits, bank interest margins fell to a record low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Research by the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that in the first half of 2023, among the 20 banks, Agricultural Bank of China had the largest year-on-year decrease in interest margins, a decrease of 36BP, while Bank of Nanjing had the smallest decrease, with a decrease of only 2BP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/5xSlElZOjPJajX05FgPbOhhrSycH1ooUOr7BvJqs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;583&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/5xSlElZOjPJajX05FgPbOhhrSycH1ooUOr7BvJqs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251551&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the central bank show that in 2022, China’s commercial banks will The net interest margin was 1.91%, and was even as low as 1.74% in the first half of 2023, which was lower than the baseline for two consecutive quarters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the narrowing trend of net interest margin is slowing down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the short term, it mainly benefits from the policy-driven easing of pressure on both assets and liabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The downward pressure on asset-side interest rates is expected to ease. The central bank&#39;s second quarter monetary execution report pointed out that &quot;commercial banks need to maintain reasonable profits and net interest margins to maintain sound operations and prevent financial risks. This will also help enhance the sustainability of commercial banks in supporting the real economy.&quot; Newly issued in the second quarter of 2023 The corporate loan interest rate remained unchanged at 3.95% month-on-month, and the new mortgage interest rate fell slightly by 3 BP to 4.11% month-on-month. The decline has gradually narrowed. On August 31, the existing first-home loan interest rate policy was officially implemented, stipulating that the adjusted home loan interest rate shall not be lower than the lower limit of the first-home loan interest rate policy in the &quot;city where the original loan is issued&quot;. This reflects the central bank&#39;s care for commercial banks&#39; interest rate spreads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bank liability-side costs have also been reduced. On September 1, state-owned banks and most joint-stock banks took the initiative to lower the listed interest rates of RMB deposits for the third time this year. The interest rates for medium and long-term deposits were lowered by a larger margin, which will effectively offset the impact of the lower interest rates on existing first-home mortgages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that banks’ setting of net interest margin targets should be reasonably planned within the scope of their own risk preferences, because credit risk preferences have a direct impact on the level of net interest margins of commercial banks. Influence. In the environment of interest rate liberalization and financial disintermediation, the cost of liabilities is relatively rigid. At the same time, the demand for on-balance sheet credit from traditional large corporate customers has shrunk. Banks urgently need to find new credit growth points, such as small business loans, small and micro loans, and consumer loans. wait. Although such loans are priced at a high level, their credit risks are also relatively high. Therefore, banks cannot increase their risk appetite in pursuit of short-term improvement in net interest margin. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The non-performing ratio improved and provisions rebounded&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the interim results conferences or investor exchange meetings of commercial banks, all sectors of society expressed their concern for the development of real estate companies. There are widespread concerns about the possible increase in non-performing ratios caused by loans and local platform loans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the overall non-performing ratio of banks has improved and the provision coverage ratio has been stable. In the first half of 2023, the non-performing loan ratios of 20 banks have almost all dropped, and only Ping An Bank’s non-performing loan ratio has increased by 1BP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The provision coverage ratios of the 20 banks are generally healthy. Only the Postal Savings Bank, Bank of Ningbo and Bank of Shanghai experienced larger year-on-year declines, but the base was still high, which was due to banks taking the initiative to feed back profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/hEBOcg8EYODEm1gDCDMAufgCOiO6z7piSlZLzGPU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;656&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/hEBOcg8EYODEm1gDCDMAufgCOiO6z7piSlZLzGPU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251552&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The real estate non-performing rate continues to rise from the beginning of the year. Among them, the average real estate non-performing rate of the six major state-owned banks is 4.46%, the highest among all types of banks; joint-stock banks have the most obvious increase; while city commercial banks are less affected, mainly because they have little involvement in real estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, banks’ demand for index management and balance sheet adjustment through the issuance of non-performing asset securitization products tends to increase. According to Wind statistics, a total of 47 non-performing loan asset-backed securities were issued in the first half of 2023, with a total issuance size of 20.098 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 67.86% and 89.07% respectively. During the same period, the number and scale of credit asset securitization products issued in the inter-bank market were 86 and 153.848 billion yuan respectively, and the proportion of non-performing loan asset-backed securities rose to 54.65% and 13.06% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that the decline in non-performing loan ratio is due to active management of banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Middle income&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Continuation&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Negative growth&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Insurance becomes popular&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to interest income, commercial banks have been focusing on non-interest intermediary business income as a strategic focus in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this revenue in the first half of the year was unsatisfactory. The main reason is that residents’ willingness to invest is low. Banks&#39; business income from fund sales and financial management income declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the &quot;China Banking Industry Financial Management Market Semi-Annual Report (First 2023)&quot; released by the Banking Industry Financial Management Registration and Custody Center show that the existing scale of banking industry wealth management products in the first half of 2023 decreased by 2.4 trillion to 25.3 trillion from the beginning of the year. trillion, still in a declining stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of revenue structure, Bank of Communications, China Merchants Bank, Bank of Ningbo and Industrial Bank have a relatively high proportion of non-interest income in revenue, all exceeding 35%. Among them, the non-interest income of Bank of Communications and China Merchants Bank mainly comes from handling fees, while the non-interest income of Industrial Bank and Bank of Ningbo is mainly contributed by investment income from trading assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/NfhzU102CgEo6B3y4VDXZsTj5qGqM3962B5NwVxB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;596&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/NfhzU102CgEo6B3y4VDXZsTj5qGqM3962B5NwVxB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of growth rate, China Merchants Bank’s handling fees and Commission income fell 11.8% year-on-year, but agency insurance income increased 3.07% year-on-year to 9.260 billion yuan. This reflects residents’ tendency to allocate funds in insurance products. Among them, the year-on-year growth in agency insurance income of Industrial Bank and Ping An Bank in the first half of the year was 123.47% and 107.2% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is related to the fact that the incremental whole life insurance with a predetermined interest rate of 3.5% was required to be removed from the shelves at the end of June. Products with high predetermined interest rates are highly attractive under the current circumstances. However, as life insurance products with high predetermined interest rates are removed from the shelves and regulators continue to crack down on bancassurance channel fees, banks&#39; agency insurance fee income in the second half of the year may be lower than in the first half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that residents’ asset allocation shows a certain procyclicality. When the prospects of the stock market and real estate market are sluggish or strict supervision suppresses a certain type of existing assets with considerable returns, the scale of residents’ investment in insurance will rise significantly. However, the proportion of real estate in the asset allocation of Chinese households is still relatively high, and financial assets are mainly capital-guaranteed deposits and fixed-income financial products. Judging from the development history of overseas residents&#39; asset allocation, the financial asset allocation structure of domestic residents will be more diversified in the future, and the proportion of asset types such as equity, industrial funds and alternative assets will gradually increase. On the one hand, real estate investment demand will gradually return to rationality; on the other hand, the rigid redemption of financial management is broken, deposit interest rates are reduced, and residents are in urgent need of high-quality financial products. Commercial banks should increase innovation efforts and develop better financial products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡安焉：打工人的共鸣与文学的安慰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256785]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;&quot;I Deliver Express in Beijing&quot; is the most watched non-fiction work in 2023. Behind this echo of the times is the process of the author Huan Yan shaping his heart and building his life through writing for more than ten years. When he fell in love with literature, he knew how to spend his life; when he took literature as his ambition, the ups and downs of working could not really hurt him. Fortunately, we still have literature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678020838991949&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;People Weekly 766th issue of Huan Yan video.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/uSgBreF3VnE53aQjdEQyJVP1LWGoEaeZMPJqgmMq.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507 .vod2.myqCloud.com/02F2B5C2VODCQ1251434507/ABF0243F55766780208991949/5nc6t8jbriqa.mp4 &quot;Poster =&quot; Controls &quot;width =&quot; 64 0 &quot;Height =&quot; 360 &quot;>; &lt;Source src =&quot; http: //1251434507.vod2.myqCloud. com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/abf0243f5576678020838991949/5NC6T8jBrIQA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In WeChat Reading, the most tagged passage of &quot;I Deliver Express in Beijing&quot; is as follows: &quot;In short, if despicable people are dissatisfied, they will only bully other despicable people, because resisting power will lead to suffering. If you can&#39;t bully anyone, then you can only abuse animals... Hatred is what Blind.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/576B8ZZf8aVZ3NWhEruAjHKjRLVxHGVU6eQWeLuw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/576B8ZZf8aVZ3NWhEruAjHKjRLVxHGVU6eQWeLuw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250530&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Hua Xiaofeng/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a paragraph of Juan Yan&#39;s memories of working at a gas station, about the driver&#39;s sarcastic remarks to him, as if he, as a gas station worker, was an accomplice to the rise in oil prices. &quot;When they suffered and were angry at work, they vented their resentment on us. Because they couldn&#39;t afford to offend those who made them angry,&quot; Huan Yan wrote, &quot;and our way and attitude towards them also changed. Almost.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most attractive thing about &quot;I Deliver Express in Beijing&quot; is that in its sincere self-awareness and introspection, it uses a simple and prudent style to show how a person constantly collides with the outside world. Shaping the consciousness and contours of self. He experienced avoidance and cowardice, but in the end he worked hard to move towards a life he considered normal and separated himself from &quot;unreasonable&quot; things. For migrant workers from all walks of life, this book is not a leafy tree, but a seed sown into the heart. Whether blue-collar or white-collar, in a cubicle or on a construction site, there is no essential difference in the feelings between work and freedom, life and self. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huan Yan is introverted. For him, campus life is the happiest time in life. At that time, he had not yet entered society, no one was looking at him, there was no pressure, and there were no complicated relationships. What&#39;s more, his introversion, sensitivity, and shyness didn&#39;t hold him back. Ever since he entered society, he has suffered many setbacks due to his introversion and timidity, but he has been unable to change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He started working in 1999 and moved around. In 2003, he joined a comic club and came into contact with some self-confident non-mainstream values: opposing everything and smashing everything. This conscious and confident act of self-marginalization resolved Huan Yan’s fear of being marginalized by the social system. &quot;They told me that my immature qualities in society are valuable. In fact, they are a process of disenchantment with this society. This &#39;doubt&#39; allowed me to open a door in my numb and drifting life. At least it made me no longer blindly adhere to social standards or mainstream values, and then gradually began to reflect, allowing me to re-examine the value and meaning of all aspects of life: what is important and what is not important.&quot; Huan Yan recalled road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, after working for 10 years, he started writing. Initially, it was to prove the emptiness and ugliness of life with the sublimity of writing, but the childish worry about gains and losses permeated his writing. Two years later, Huan Yan, who fled to writing because of a setback in his life, fled back to life and continued to work because of frustration in his writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 20 years, Huan Yan has changed 19 jobs in Guangdong, Guangxi, Yunnan, Shanghai, Beijing and other places. He has worked as a convenience store clerk, bicycle salesman, logistics picker, courier, etc. . These experiences are often full of frustration and pain, but when he returns to reading or writing - even writing that achieves nothing - he can always find some comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He knows that he is a screw, and writing is a creative act that distinguishes him from others. &quot;What I want to write and how to write is a process that is completely controlled by myself.&quot; Huan Yan said, &quot;After a few years, along with reading, thinking, and communicating, I have matured a little. I have gradually seen the &#39;truth&#39; of writing. , I no longer hope to change my life through writing, and I have abandoned the idea of ​​the sublimity of writing. I no longer think that cooking a dish is easier than writing an article.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He did not expect that, Because the article I published on the Internet about the night shift life in Deppon Logistics attracted the attention of literary editors, I did not expect that &quot;I Deliver Express in Beijing&quot; would arouse such a warm response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is like an old-school literary young man: he loves literature, takes literature as his career, is saved by literature, is changed by literature, and meets his life partner through literature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;But in fact, outside this writing circle, it is difficult for me to meet the opposite sex who accepts people like me. I don’t know if you understand? My situation is that I am old, have no money, and have very few career prospects. Too bad I&#39;m not willing to work on it yet. Most people wouldn&#39;t consider being with me after hearing my situation.&quot; He said, &quot;Thanks to literature.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大哥溥伒、五哥溥僩……溥仪的弟弟为什么叫溥杰？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257220]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/n9vnHe7gMbbKz39vzXngf5CNgOcufScH4M9oQc6A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;735&quot; height=&quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/n9vnHe7gMbbKz39vzXngf5CNgOcufScH 4M9oQc6A. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251310&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;From left: Song Xilian, Du Yuming, Pu Jie and Pu Yi in the Office of the Cultural and Historical Commissioner of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was a child, because I read some stories about the last emperor, I not only knew about Puyi, but also knew that he had A younger brother named Pujie has a very close relationship with him. Later, I came to Beijing and lived in Dongcheng all year round. In my spare time, I would stroll in the alleys. I often saw Mr. Pujie&#39;s inscriptions and I admired them very much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pu Yi is of the same generation as Pu, and his younger brother is named Pu Jie. There is no doubt about this. However, when I re-read &quot;The First Half of My Life&quot; written by Pu Yi, I saw a few passages that made me have a small question. The first paragraph is in the section &quot;Studying at Yuqing Palace&quot; in Chapter 2 &quot;My Childhood&quot;. Puyi mentioned some scenes of his studying at that time:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three people have received this honor, namely Puyi Jie, Yu Chong (son of Pu Lun, who has been reading Chinese with me), and Pu Jia (son of my seventh uncle Zaitao, who has been reading English with me since I was fourteen). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other two paragraphs are in Chapter 10. At this time, Puyi had returned to Beijing after ten years of transformation in the Northeast:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I heard Brother Brother&#39;s guqin and saw the words he wrote for me. His calligraphy attainments have indeed reached a new level. I also admired Brother Wu Wu’s new paintings of flowers and birds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My fifth sister, sixth brother Jian and I walked westward slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you hear these affectionate titles: eldest brother, fifth brother, and sixth brother; when you see their names: Pulun, Pujia, Puyi, Puyi, and Pujian, you know their relationship with Puyi. It is extraordinary because since Emperor Kangxi, it has been stipulated that the descendants of the royal family should be named with two characters. The first character indicates seniority, and the second character has the same radical, indicating brotherhood. Pu Lun&#39;s father&#39;s original name was Zai Zhong. In December of the fourth year of Xianfeng, he was adopted by Emperor Daoguang Emperor&#39;s eldest son Yiwei as his heir. He became the eldest grandson of Emperor Dao Guang and was renamed Zai Zhi. Pu Lun was the eldest son of Zai Zhi and the great-eldest grandson of Emperor Daoguang. Pujia is the eldest son of Puyi&#39;s seventh uncle Zaitao. Zaitao is the younger brother of Puyi&#39;s father and regent Zaifeng. They are both the half-brothers of Emperor Guangxu Zaiyan. Therefore, Puyi and Pujia were cousins. The eldest brother Puyi, the fifth brother Punu, and the sixth brother Pujian are all the grandsons of the fifth son of Emperor Daoguang, Yigui. Specifically, Puyi is the eldest son of Yigui’s fourth son, Zaiying, and the fifth brother Punu is his younger brother. ; The sixth brother Pujian is the sixth son of Zaiying&#39;s third brother Zailan. Therefore, they are all very close to Puyi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WpeIDbimA1gUDZWzcEnsdRZ6e3nbYe3bHR40s26U.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;557&quot; height= &quot;728&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WpeIDbimA1gUDZWzcEnsdRZ6e3nbYe3bHR40s26U.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251309&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1910, Puyi (right) took a photo with his father, the regent Zaifeng, and his brother Pujie. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the above-mentioned cousins, Puyi also has two half-brothers, three The younger brother Pu Bo and the fourth younger brother Pu Ren also have the second character of their names next to the character &quot;任&quot;. Pujie is Puyi&#39;s younger brother. The two have the closest relationship and get along most harmoniously. When he was young, Pujie was not only qualified to be Puyi&#39;s companion, he could also enter the palace and play with Puyi. When he grew up, he also helped Puyi plan his plans to go abroad. Logically speaking, Pujie&#39;s name should also include the word &quot;任&quot; next to it! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person&#39;s name seems to be just a symbol, but from the moment the person is born, this name carries rich cultural information and cultural connotations. It can be a human recognition of new life; it can also express parents&#39; expectations for everlasting love; at the same time, it is also full of the ancestors&#39; hope for the prosperity of future generations, and individuals must flourish in this branch. He found his place in Mao&#39;s genealogy, and all his family glory and family missions came from this. What cannot be ignored is that a person&#39;s name also contains various historical factors, which are related to the destiny of the times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, when choosing which words to name children and grandchildren, elders must not only consider the pronunciation of the word, whether the word and the surname are read harmoniously, and try to avoid misunderstandings caused by certain homophonics; You must consider the meaning contained in this word, whether the word itself is positive or negative, and whether there is any taboo. In a traditional clan society, the relationship between this word and the family genealogy will definitely be considered. Sometimes, this relationship is expressed through phonology, such as Xu Shichang and his younger brother Xu Shiguang, and his younger brothers Xu Shigang, Xu Shiliang, Xu Shifang, Xu Shiyang, Xu Shixiang, Xu Shizhang, etc. The last characters all rhyme with Jiangyang. More often, it is expressed through glyphs. For example, Zeng Guofan, a famous official of the Zhongxing Dynasty in the Qing Dynasty, his younger brothers Zeng Guohuang, Zeng Guobao, Zeng Guoquan, etc. all have the name &quot;艹&quot;; another example is Mr. Zhou Shaoliang, a famous contemporary scholar, who named his daughters respectively Qixiu, Qizhang, and Qiyu all follow this tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, where did the word &quot;任&quot; in Mr. Pujie&#39;s name go? If you read the traditional Chinese version of the family genealogy, the problem will be easily solved, because there is another traditional Chinese character for &quot;Jie&quot; in the ancient books, written as &quot;Jie&quot;. As a calligrapher and painter, Mr. Pu Jie used the inscription &quot;Pu Jie&quot; on some of his paintings and calligraphy works, and also wrote &quot;Pu Jie&quot; on his seal. In this way, it can be understood that Mr. Pujie did not change his name, nor was he adopted by other royal families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/l1HBRsfJHAWvJvNvkIlpuxdo2NqRJRFAnKtDKuOE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;440&quot; height= &quot;646&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/l1HBRsfJHAWvJvNvkIlpuxdo2NqRJRFAnKtDKuOE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251311&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The title, title and seal on the title page of &quot;The Autobiography of Pujie&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be pointed out that &quot;Jie&quot; and &quot;Jie&quot; are not simply related in traditional and simplified Chinese. In ancient books, the words &quot;Jie&quot; and &quot;Jie&quot; coexist. They have the same pronunciation and most of the time the same meaning. They both mean towering, outstanding and full of praise, such as &quot;outstanding&quot; and &quot;masterpiece&quot;, so although the two The glyphs of the characters are different, so they can usually be read together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/TBskXM88DDttCrtkWjC4J5P0m2bEYDMWVvAa65I7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1044&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/TBskXM88DDttCrtkWjC4J5P0m2bEYDMWVvAa65I7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251312&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Jie, the first number one scholar from Shaanxi in the Qing Dynasty, and his seven-character couplet in running script (now in the Shenyang Palace Museum). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, precisely because the glyphs of the two characters are different, there are also special circumstances that cannot be used universally, especially When using it as a person&#39;s name, be very careful. For example, during the Qianjia period of the Qing Dynasty, there was a famous figure named Wang Jie. Even in ancient books, his name cannot be written as &quot;Wang Jie&quot;. First let’s talk about why he is famous. He was the number one scholar appointed by Emperor Qianlong and the first number one scholar in Shaanxi since the founding of the Qing Dynasty. When Emperor Jiaqing came to the throne, he, as the first assistant, participated in the impeachment case of He Shen. It can be said that he is the pride of Shaanxi people. Wang Jie is good at poetry and writing, and is good at calligraphy. His seven-character couplet in running script is collected in the Shenyang Palace Museum: &quot;In the rainy night, I leisurely chant Zuo Si&#39;s sentence, and when the weather is clear, I quickly imitate Youjun&#39;s calligraphy.&quot; Why does his name have to be written as &quot;Wang Jie&quot; in ancient books? There are two reasons: on the one hand, based on the signature of Wang Jie’s inscriptions and calligraphy works. On his inscription or signature, there are two characters &quot;Wang Jie&quot;. On the other hand, according to the names of brothers Wang Jie. Wang Jie has two older brothers, one named Wang Rong and the other named Wang Che. On the surface, Wang Jie&#39;s names have nothing to do with his brother&#39;s names. Their radicals are not consistent. One is &quot;氵&quot; and the other is &quot;灬&quot;. But those who have practiced calligraphy can understand the kinship between the two at a glance. The right part of his brother&#39;s name &quot;Rong&quot; and &quot;Che&quot; has a dot on the right side, both of which are four dots. By the way, it can be mentioned that due to the same cultural tradition, the name of Emperor Qianlong Hongli should be written as &quot;Hongli&quot; rather than &quot;Hongli&quot; in ancient books, because Emperor Qianlong&#39;s brothers in descending order were named respectively The names Honghui, Honghan, Hongyun, Hongshi, Hongzhou and Hongluo all use the word &quot;日&quot; as the radical, indicating that they are from the same family genealogy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Should the name of Puyi&#39;s brother be written as &quot;Pu Jie&quot; or &quot;Pu Jie&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If we talk about cultural traditions, it should undoubtedly be written as &quot;Pu Jie&quot;, so that we can see at a glance his relationship with Pu Yi and Pu Lun. However, with the strong call for writing reform, if you want to simplify it, just simplify it. Writing &quot;Jie&quot; is not bad either. Therefore, we see that Mr. Pu Jie often made &quot;outstanding&quot; remarks when he signed his signature. If this is his personal wish, we should respect it. However, if we think about people and the world, he will probably be lucky that the seal can still protect his true name intact, and he will stamp this seal firmly at the signature every time. This kind of cultural psychology is probably not easy for modern people to understand or feel. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbSP; bsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 22:25:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国际奥委会成立电子竞技委员会：电竞会成为奥运项目吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257312]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 6, 2023, International Olympic Committee President Thomas Bach announced that a new e-sports will be established committee. The establishment of the E-Sports Committee is the latest move by the International Olympic Committee to support the development of virtual Olympic sports. From an organizational perspective, this is an organizational-level upgrade of the e-sports contact group established by the International Olympic Committee in 2018, highlighting the IOC’s recognition of the huge development potential of e-sports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is still controversial, in recent years, e-sports has become a formal &quot;sport&quot;. In June 2023, Singapore held its first &quot;Olympic Esports Week&quot; and &quot;Olympic Esports Series&quot;, inviting professional and amateur players from around the world to participate in the competition. At the upcoming Asian Games in Hangzhou, e-sports will become an official event of the Asian Games for the first time and will be included in the national medal list. It is an &quot;intellectual event&quot; like chess events, covering 5 PC-side events and two mobile game-side events. Generate 7 gold medals. On July 8, the Asian Olympic Council announced that e-sports will be included in the 2026 Nagoya Asian Games again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The establishment of the International Olympic Committee’s E-Sports Committee indicates that e-Sports is one step closer to officially entering the Olympic Games and becoming a permanent project. It reflects the International Olympic Committee’s further awareness of the value of esports to the Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;E-sports can bring huge benefits to the Olympic Games. In 2023, the global e-sports audience is expected to reach 574 million, with global e-sports revenue approaching US$1.8 billion. The entry of e-sports into the Olympic Games will further expand this revenue. The International Olympic Committee also values ​​this. After all, any organization needs money to survive and develop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The foundation of e-sports is the video game industry. Video games originated in the United States in the 1950s. In the 1980s, with the popularization of televisions and the development of computer hardware, they became popular. By the mid-1990s, with the rise of multimedia technology, games entered a period of rapid development. With the advent of the digital age and the popularization of smartphones, the game industry has grown explosively, from the earliest home computer games to today&#39;s multi-platform, multi-user online games. Video games have become the largest industry in entertainment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The revenue of the game industry now far exceeds the movie box office. Affected by the epidemic, the global movie box office has just exceeded 21.4 billion US dollars in 2022. Before the epidemic, the global movie box office in 2019 was 42.5 billion US dollars. It&#39;s the highest record. Looking back at the gaming industry, according to a report released by market research organization Newzoo, the global gaming market revenue is estimated to be US$187.7 billion in 2023. Among them, the mobile market is expected to reach US$92.6 billion, which also reflects the status of mobile games in the gaming industry. From an audience perspective, globally, the number of game players will grow from 2.9 billion in 2020 to 3.5 billion in 2025, with a five-year compound annual growth rate of 4.2%. There is a view that the huge market size and audience size make games the ninth art after the eight major art forms such as painting, sculpture, architecture, music, poetry (literature), dance, drama, and film (film and television). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of the game industry gave birth to e-sports. More and more players not only play games, but also watch game competitions. To a certain extent, this is the “sport” with the largest number of participants and the best mass base in the world. Whether it is traditional client games or emerging mobile games, they all play an important role in e-sports events. For example, the Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports projects include League of Legends, Honor of Kings Asian Games version, Peace Elite Asian Games version, and FIFA Online 4. These games are the games with the largest audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of the broad base of video games, e-sports has become a bridge between the Olympic Games and young groups. Thomas Bach, President of the International Olympic Committee, said, &quot;Virtual sports can supplement and strengthen the potential of traditional Olympic sports, and it will provide new opportunities for athletes and spectators to participate in the Olympic movement.&quot; “We believe that virtual sports can help promote the values ​​of excellence, friendship and respect that are at the heart of the Olympic Games and can inspire young people around the world to participate in sport and develop active and healthy lifestyles.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it should be noted that the interest game of e-sports entering the Olympics is more complicated than traditional projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Traditional sports are often born out of sports with a long history. They are not themselves a commercial product, and there are no intellectual property rights or controllers. Therefore, the International Olympic Committee can control them relatively independently and completely. . But video games are different. They were born out of business from the beginning. As a sports industry that integrates entertainment, technology, competition, live broadcasting, and social networking, e-sports has achieved mature operations and formed a relatively complete industrial chain. This means that e-sports itself is &quot;owned&quot;. In addition to game manufacturers, each link in the industry chain itself has a mature business model to undertake a series of benefits generated by being an Olympic project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, to a certain extent, when e-sports enters the Olympics, there is a complicated game of interests and a battle for control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While establishing the e-sports committee, the International Olympic Committee also reiterated their definition of e-sports: e-sports is virtual sports (Esports based on Traditional Sports), not gaming e-sports (Gaming) Esports). &quot;Virtual sports&quot; are a supplement and enhancement of &quot;traditional Olympic events&quot;, a supporting role of traditional sports, and will still accept the all-round leadership of traditional sports forces. Judging from the member structure of the Olympic Esports Committee, the same is true. Most of them come from individual sports federations and senior marketing and media personnel in the traditional sports industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the International Olympic Committee insists on two points and will not give in. First, traditional sports must lead e-sports; second, competition content must comply with Olympic standards, and manufacturers must compromise on the red line of game content review. Based on these two points, the International Olympic Committee may require the selection of games or even customize games with its own intellectual property rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But at the same time, Olympic projects must also be selected from games on the market, otherwise there will be no audience. This dependence not only refers to game manufacturers, but also includes sales networks, marketing, live broadcasts, and video platforms. Therefore, the Olympic Committee cannot do without the e-sports industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a completely new situation. The tug-of-war over the inclusion of e-sports in the Olympics will continue for a long time, which will also affect the schedule for e-sports to eventually enter the Olympics as an official event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[开幕前夕，南周记者探访亚运主媒体中心，打卡亚运灯光秀]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257306]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/feZ3faeodBYoUOUsBHkXT2KsjB0x8PG0LdHR2pps.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/feZ3faeodBYoUOUsBHkXT2KsjB0x8PG0Ld HR2pps. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251534&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a young man raised his mobile phone to take pictures Light show in Qianjiang New Town. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ TvkAafdG4SSIvpvXbdhqUs7bz10NG4OrecmTMy4s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/TvkAafdG4SSIvpvXbdhqUs7bz10NG4OrecmTMy4s. jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;251535&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a franchise store in the main media center of the Asian Games, a A customer is selecting Asian Games souvenirs. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 19th Asian Games will open in Hangzhou, Zhejiang on September 23, 2023. On September 20, Southern Weekend visited the Hangzhou Asian Games Main Media Center (MMC). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/AWaZ21XYMnASMAPGh6J96kHP7mywYm75JGu19P84.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/AWaZ21XYMnASMAPGh6J96kHP7mywYm75JGu19P84.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251536&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, volunteers were working at the reception desk of the main press center of the Asian Games in Hangzhou, Zhejiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ lkmHUo0l2VekD1qhdhM1rDXqCVKjViGLxuhwJqyX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/lkmHUo0l2VekD1qhdhM1rDXqCVKjViGLxuhwJqyX.jpg &quot;data- key=&quot;251537&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a volunteer showed the Southern Weekend reporter what he had purchased Asian Games commemorative badge. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main media center with a total area of ​​nearly 50,000 square meters is located in the Hangzhou International Expo Center, close to the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center venue group, and is divided into Main news center, international broadcast center, main broadcaster operation center and other different areas. The center also has supporting service areas such as a medical station, a bookstore, an official licensed merchandise retail store for the Hangzhou Asian Games, and a post office. This is the &quot;home base&quot; for media reporters and the &quot;general hub&quot; for information dissemination. It is also the headquarters for media operations and the media operations of the Olympic Council of Asia. It is an important window to display the image of the host country and host city to Chinese and foreign media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/t2JLTfSadhOFf7tftI6c0jmi0iqDsrGjgUJVWQU7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/t2JLTfSadhOFf7tftI6c0jmi0iqDsrGjgUJVWQU7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251538&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, volunteers were working at the reception desk of the main press center of the Asian Games in Hangzhou, Zhejiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ dkBEEqMrt7Jo9UTtyrBgglHRXLb2UPs4xe8Ayzkt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/dkBEEqMrt7Jo9UTtyrBgglHRXLb2UPs4xe8Ayzkt.j pg&quot; data- key=&quot;251529&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 20, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, three days away from the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games. Citizens and tourists who came to enjoy the light show picked up their mobile phones to take pictures of the main Asian Games venue across the river. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ onzsDtHbp6O1PahdcIimco95ggvfvT0LR77Yk5gu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/onzsDtHbp6O1PahdcIimco95ggvfvT0LR77Yk5gu.jp g&quot; data- key=&quot;251530&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, although it was raining lightly, it could not stop people from coming to enjoy the Asian Games. The enthusiasm of the people for the light show. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ l23Gq3H2tOEk9oaOpxth6xOo1YOZiPWtmU4Nxsbx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/l23Gq3H2tOEk9oaOpxth6xOo1YOZiPWtmU4 Nxsbx.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;251531&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 20, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, three days away from the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games. Citizens and tourists who came to enjoy the light show picked up their mobile phones to take pictures of the main Asian Games venue across the river. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After nightfall, the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center ushered in a dazzling Asian Games-themed light show. Many citizens and tourists came to the Qiantang River to check out the light show and experience the atmosphere of the Asian Games in advance. The lights of the iconic building &quot;Big Lotus&quot; light up the night sky, forming a spectacular city landscape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/r9fI4Gf7Tk7ExU1ZXGsF0pKemZ8G6VWttOkTg0Jd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;676&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/r9fI4Gf7Tk7ExU1ZXGsF0pKemZ8G6VWttOkTg0Jd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251532&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, reporters from various media successively entered the main media center of the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ TRXuy5yzfbepzGYHyMJO3k3EjJXScCi9bniZEvrz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;602&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/TRXuy5yzfbepzGYHyMJO3k3EjJXScCi9bni ZEvrz.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;251533&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 20, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, although it was raining lightly, it could not stop people from coming to enjoy the Asian Games. The enthusiasm of the people for the light show. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the Asian Games themed light show is divided into &quot;running a conference to improve a city&quot; and &quot;strengthening the new era and working together towards the future&quot; The three chapters of &quot;I love Hangzhou and contribute to the Asian Games&quot; illuminate the passion with lights and create a strong Asian Games atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>