<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[雪国芭蕉——松尾芭蕉“奥之细道”行迹（五）丨最深之水]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260812]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/17/fXpujkHdDpeuAavi8nL2NRJEO5JawNmDWrcTl3NZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/fXpujkHdDpeuAavi8nL2NRJEO5JawNmDWrcTl 3NZ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258619&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Matsuo Basho Monument at Inari Shrine in Niigata Prefecture, left picture taken in April 2023 month, the picture on the right was taken in September 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After walking several points on Matsuo Basho’s “Oku no Homichi” in the fall of 2019, Then came three years of COVID. It&#39;s like a big dream. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early April and early September 2023, in early spring and early autumn, I went to Niigata Prefecture in northern Japan twice, the Echigo country that often appears in ancient Japanese literature. Echigo Kingdom, one of the ancient &lt;span>;Reiji Kingdom&lt;/span>; in Japan, faces the &lt;span>;Sea of ​​Japan&lt;/span>; and is long and narrow from north to south. &lt;span>;Meiji&lt;/span>; Four years later, the feudal domain was abolished and a prefecture was established, named Niigata. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Niigata in April, the car was driving among the continuous farmland. The brown rice fields in early spring have just been plowed and are waiting for a new round of sowing. The September trip is already in my plan, so I started imagining the scene of autumn. For large areas of solid color scenes, yellow is the most suitable, and the combination with the blue sky is pure and gorgeous. In the Chengdu Plain where I live, there is a spectacular scene every day in March. The spread of rapeseed flowers is spectacular, and the atmosphere of early spring is quite exciting. Chengdu people who stay at home will basically go out for spring outings at this time, not to let down nature or themselves. Fortunately, I visited Niigata again in early September and enjoyed the sight of golden rice fields and blue sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many swans in Niigata’s deserted fields in April. They are pecking at the grain that falls in the soil. After being fed and fattened, they will fly back to Siberia. It migrates like this every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look at these beautiful big white birds from a distance. Has Basho seen them? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Probably not. Matsuo Basho and his disciple Soryo Kawai arrived in Echigo in the summer of 1689. Echigo is a stop on the &quot;Oku no Hosomido&quot;. The entire &quot;Oku no Homichi&quot; journey is a total of 2,400 kilometers of hiking. Starting from Edo, go north, then turn west. It is said that the most magnificent journey is the monk Kukai’s tour of the eighty-eight temples in Shikoku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the trip to Japan in the spring of 2023, the excitement and yearning were mixed with a different state of mind from the trips in previous years. During the three years of the epidemic, except for a few short trips within the country, I have not traveled abroad. Three years of isolation has had a psychological effect on me, leaving me with a faint uneasiness, but I don’t know where this uneasiness comes from. When applied to the body, the hands and feet feel sluggish and sluggish. Having been separated from the same rhythm for three years, the effect is really powerful. The body is heavy and the state of mind is also sinking. I asked myself, what would happen if I never went out again? It seems to be possible. For middle-aged people, three years makes them look older. This is probably an important reason. By September, after a trip to Japan in April, a self-driving trip to Yunnan in May, and several short trips, I felt that my mind and body were beginning to adapt to the journey again, which was very gratifying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My friend Ding Yuan settled in the village of &lt;span>;Niigata Prefecture&lt;/span>; and ran a B&amp;B called &quot;Four Seasons Inn&quot; with her husband, Mr. Nakamura Tatsuo. The couple also ran a local hotel. Various contents of travel. Regarding Basho, what Ding Yuan helped me find out is that Basho and Zeng Liang stayed in Murakami for two nights and three days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Basho accommodation in Murakami can be checked and determined based on local literature, but it has lost its former appearance and has become a salmon restaurant, so the curtain at the door is very interesting. This is a two-story Japanese-style house on Murakami Street. Three Japanese-style curtains are hung side by side at the door. They are written in black on a white background and &quot;Izutsuya&quot; is written in the middle. This is the name of the restaurant. The one on the right is written &quot;Murakami&quot;. &quot;Salmon Cuisine&quot; and a book on the left reads &quot;Basho&#39;s Staying Place&quot;. There is a wooden sign at the door stating, &quot;In June of the second year of Genroku (1689), Basho and Zeng Liang arrived at Murakami during their journey on the &#39;Ok no Homichi&#39;. They stayed here for two nights and three days. , it was called &#39;Sukuzaemon&#39; at the time.&quot; In order to show that the brand was not the store&#39;s own words, the signature was &quot;Mura City Education Committee.&quot; Murakami&#39;s salmon industry is very famous. Every year, many salmon migrate here, and the output and quality are of high quality. Therefore, Murakami has a considerable number of salmon restaurants and processing workshops for curing and drying salmon. I asked Nakamura, is &quot;Izutsuya&quot; the most famous salmon shop in Murakami? Nakamura smiled and said, that&#39;s not necessarily true. It&#39;s because of the influence of bananas, but most people don&#39;t care about this, and only you cultural people care about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/MQzAIBoCpFBy1l4BFMplWcHVyGjQuJFUl4plJrQa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/MQzAIBoCpFBy1l4BFMplWcHVyGjQuJFUl4plJrQa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258620&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsuo Basho and his disciple Kawai Sora went to the accommodation in the village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Basho wrote in &quot;The Thirty-Five Echigo Road&quot; in &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot; , &quot;As soon as we passed the Mouse Pass, we entered the territory of Echigo from Dewa, and then we rushed to Shizhen Pass in Etchu. We walked for nine days in total. During this period, sometimes the heat was unbearable, and sometimes the cold rain poured down on us, which made us physically and mentally exhausted. Even getting sick was really miserable. So I didn’t record much of my journey.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps because Basho was ill during Echigo, there are very few records about Echigo in &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;. Based on the results that Ding Yuan helped me check, I followed the traces in Murakami in early spring and early autumn. However, it is no longer possible to determine the location of this trace. We can only search for it based on the location of the Basho Sentence Monument. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jizo-do Hall in Kamikata Town has the Basho sentence monument &quot;けふはかり人も年よれ&amp;nbsp;First Time Rain&quot;. It can be translated as: Only today do you know that you are old, this is the first shower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inari Shrine has a Basho motto stone, &quot;Cloud folds 々人をやすむる月见かな&quot;. The general meaning I understand is that the shadow of the cloud covers the moon, and the shadow of the moon covers the person. The latter is a sentence from Basho&#39;s seven-part collection &quot;Spring Day&quot;, written in 1685. Basho visited Murakami in August 1689. He probably left no works due to poor health. Next to the Bajiao Monument Monument, there is a haiku poet Su Xian&#39;s Monument Stone. The handwriting is blurry. The general idea I read is: Under the moonlight, the shore of the water is covered with pine leaves like umbrellas (I don&#39;t know if it is correct or not). According to the introduction on the standing plaque next to it, these two stone sentences were erected in October 1843, during the 150th anniversary of Basho and the 17th anniversary of Susen. The introduction also specifically said that there are two important remains of Basho in Murakami, one is the Inari Shrine where this place is located, and the other is the Iwafune Shrine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Iwafune Shrine built on the seaside is much larger in scale and momentum than the Inari Shrine. It has a red torii gate and a white torii gate. In front of the red torii gate, there is a Basho sentence stone, which is engraved with the sentence &quot;On the seventh day of Hanasaki, Tsurumi will see Tsuruga&quot;, which can be understood as &quot;The cherry blossoms are in full bloom in seven days, and only Tsurumi can see such a beautiful scenery.&quot; The Basho stone in front of the white torii gate is engraved with &quot;Bunzuki や六日も常の夜には思ず&quot;, which means that the night of Bunzuki (July), when I am anxiously waiting for the letter, is also different from the ordinary night. The former Basho haiku has nothing to do with &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;, and the latter line is taken from a line written in the Hokuriku section of &quot;Oku no Hosomichi&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April, the day before Basho’s tour in &lt;span>;Niigata Prefecture&lt;/span>;, we went to Kameoka Monju-in, the Daishoji Temple in Yamagata Prefecture. In the drizzle, there was still residual snow on the mountain col in the distance and on the roofs nearby. When I was going down the mountain, I suddenly found a Basho sentence monument standing on the roadside, which read &quot;春の夜は桜に明けてしまひけり&quot; (Spring night, cherry blossoms are in full bloom). Tateishiji Temple (Mountain Temple) in Yamagata Prefecture is an important place to visit on the &quot;Oku no Hosōdo&quot; tour of Master Basho and his apprentice. I visited in 2019. I don’t know if they have been to the Great Holy Temple, and it is not mentioned in the book. Someone may have studied the details of these travels, and the results of these studies must be carefully explored to know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I used to read a lot of haiku in Chinese translation, but over the years I slowly started to read the original haiku. It is true that poetry cannot be translated. Because my Japanese foundation is still shallow, and it also involves issues of ancient and modern Japanese, I can only read these haiku at a loss. But maybe it was in this confusion, after leaking some clear information, that I finally understood the extremely concise and complex semantics of haiku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The highlight of Basho&#39;s activities in this area of ​​​​Murakami is Otohoji Temple. During my two trips to Murakami in early spring and early autumn, I went to Otohoji Temple twice. The cherry blossom scenery in early spring is obviously much more beautiful than the scenery in early autumn before the red leaves appear. It is said to be Murakami, but Otohoji Temple is actually located in Tainai City next to Murakami. This temple was built in the 8th century AD under the order of Emperor Shomu who was in office at the time. The temple covers a vast area of ​​more than 80,000 square meters. There is a &quot;three-story pagoda&quot; built in 1620 in the temple, which is designated as a national important cultural property of Japan. This temple is the only ancient temple in Shinji that is included in &quot;The Story of Konsai&quot;, and it is also the temple where Matsuo Basho once visited when he wandered the &quot;Oku no Hosho Road&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/vg13uYiV1rkOS05OOYFWHKCIRA8y6dKAOdlxPhPL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/vg13uYiV1rkOS05OOYFWHKCIRA8y6dKAOdlxPhPL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258621&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matsuo Basho Monument in Otohoji Temple. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the author)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the topic, let me say a few words. It was almost noon after visiting Otohoji Temple in early autumn. Mr. Nakamura said that there was a steamed bun shop next to it that was very delicious and he hadn’t eaten there in a long time. We decided to leave it at that for lunch. When I arrived at the door, I looked at the description and found that it was founded in the first year of culture, which was 1804, and has a history of more than 200 years. The shop is really small, with a few stools and two or three tables. When the steamed buns arrived, they turned out to be red bean paste buns. Later, I looked up information and learned that in Japan, the so-called steamed buns are bean paste buns, and the outer shell can vary. There are white steamed buns made of commonly used flour, brown tea steamed buns made of wheat flour, and sweet potato flour, yam flour, and japonica rice flour. There are sweet potato steamed buns and wine steamed buns made from fermented rice flour, etc., but they are filled with red bean paste. Yiboji Steamed Buns are delicious, and I am even more impressed that such a snack shop has a history of more than 200 years. In Japan, I often come across various small shops that are hundreds of years old. I once ate at a ramen shop in Kyoto. When I came to the door after eating, I was shocked to see the signboard. It has a history of more than 400 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I posted photos of my visit to Yibao Temple in WeChat Moments, and a friend asked: Is it the Yibao Temple in &quot;The Story of the Past&quot;? It seems that its name first came from &quot;The Story of the Past&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Story of the Past&quot; is a collection of folklore stories from the late Heian period in Japan, with a total of thirty-one volumes and more than a thousand stories. It is divided into Tianzhu (India) (volumes one to five), Cathay (China) (volumes six to ten), and Honchao (Japan) (volumes eleven to thirty-one). The current Chinese version of this Dynasty was edited by Zhou Zuoren. The stories in &quot;The Tale of the Past&quot; are all-encompassing, with Buddhist stories and secular stories mixed together. There are also many stories of gods and supernatural beings. Many creations of later generations come from this book, which is one of the source treasures of Japanese literature. It is similar to Chinese books such as San Yan Er Pai and Strange Stories from a Chinese Studio. Because each volume contains the word &quot;present and past&quot; at the beginning, it is called &quot;The Story of Present and Past&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Japanese writers, Ryunosuke Akutagawa made full use of &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot;. It is said that about one-fifth of the material in the historical novels he created came from &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot;, including &quot;Rason&quot; Door&quot; and &quot;In the Jungle&quot;. Ryunosuke Akutagawa called &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot; a &quot;human comedy&quot; in ancient Japan. He said that &quot;The Story of Konsai Monogatari&quot; is full of &quot;wild beauty&quot; and is &quot;a kind of beauty that has nothing to do with elegance and luxury.&quot; Many of the common Onmyodo and Onmyoji content in Japanese animations also come from &quot;Kanagi Monogatari&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spacious garden of Uhoji Temple, there is a Basho Sentence Monument, a round stone monument, the handwriting has been blurred. There is a wooden sign next to the stele, which records the content of this stele: &quot;In the second year of Genroku (1689), Matsuo Basho paid homage to the Ukiyo no Kita no Mountain Sakura Basho&quot; (The cherry blossoms of Kitayama, this floating world scenery makes I envy). Surrounding the Basho Sentence Monument are many echoing sentences from &lt;span>;Niigata&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;local&lt;/span>; haiku celebrities at that time. Otohoji Temple has been a famous place for cherry blossom viewing since ancient times. Basho admired the beauty of the northern cherry blossoms here, even though it was not during the cherry blossom season when he visited. Looking at Sakura Leaves, he also expressed his envious mood in his imagination. Two of the echoing haiku of other haiku writers were singled out and written in the description of the stele. They were probably the most famous haiku poets in the area at that time. One of them is not jade, &quot;Mitsukoshi Road や一の Temple の花ざかり&quot;, Mitsukoshi The road and Yi&#39;s Temple are filled with flowers. One song is by Yasuda Izabo, &quot;Different gods and Buddhas&quot;. Different gods and Buddhas all have the beauty of cherry blossoms. They are all sentences praising cherry blossoms. In Japan, the word flower, if not specifically mentioned, is cherry blossom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Niigata in early April, the cherry blossoms are in full bloom in previous years, but the spring of 2023 is coming fiercely, and when we arrived, the cherry blossoms were already a little overdue. In the garden of Otohoji Temple, on the round stone monument of Basho, there are several branches of cherry blossoms hanging down, on the eve of their withering. Behind the stele is a small hill, and on the steps are several red curtains from the temple, with the words &quot;Namo Guanyin Bodhisattva&quot; enshrined. The curtains fluttered gently in the sunshine and breeze. This sentiment and scene complement each other perfectly with the haikus tablet with unclear handwriting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Othoji Temple, like other Niigata landscapes, has very few tourists. I stood on the terrace outside the main hall, watching the yin and yang scene cut by the sun with the Buddha statues in the garden below. I have done this twice. Although the weather seems to be the same, there are obvious differences in the dividing lines between sunlight and shadow in early spring and early autumn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I visited Otohoji Temple again in September and suddenly discovered Kobo Daishi (Kukai) here. I didn’t notice it at all on that trip in April. There is a stone statue of Kobo Daishi Gozun here, which is a common standard shape of Kukai wearing a hat and leaning on a staff during his journey. This stone statue of Kukai is a bit cute, shaped into a pudgy little boy. I turned to the back of the base of the stone statue to read the description. The handwriting was a bit blurry, but I could clearly see the words &quot;Pursuing the eighty-eight sacred sites of Shikoku...to commemorate...&quot; and other words. It is estimated that someone went there before and erected a statue in Otohoji Temple after returning to Niigata. Benji was the monk Kukai&#39;s practice route. It later gradually became the most famous hiking route in the world, with a total length of more than 1,400 kilometers and 88 temples in Shikoku. Currently, more than half a million people from all over the world walk this road every year. This is also a strange fate for us. After seeing Kukai at Otohoji Temple, my friend Dr. Tan Weidong and I left Niigata the next day, flew to Osaka for a short stay, and then headed to Shikoku to start our plan Three years of preparation for the trip. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[格力电器：董明珠“绯闻”是造谣，已向公安机关报案]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260839]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 17, Gree Electric responded to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News: &quot;Regarding the recent efforts of many self-media To obtain traffic, maliciously edit relevant videos, and use vulgar and filthy words to insult and slander company executives, Gree Electric has reported the case to the public security organs, which have accepted and filed the case.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanduwan Financial News reporter learned that recently There are rumors on social platforms that Dong Mingzhu, chairman and president of Gree Electric Appliances, is in love with Wang Ziru, the &quot;channel reform project leader&quot; of Gree Electric Appliances. In a recent TV program, Dong Mingzhu responded, &quot;I don&#39;t even watch it. I don&#39;t think it matters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the same program, Wang Ziru said: &quot;I didn&#39;t watch it.&quot; &quot;I passed the salary slip issued to me by Gree&quot; and &quot;asked for an office close to the Dong Zong to facilitate reporting&quot;, etc., which have attracted much attention and controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Cheetah Mobile CEO Fu Sheng expressed his views on Wang Ziru in WeChat Moments. Fu Sheng said, &quot;I can only say that Wang Ziru is not only a freeloader, but also a gangster.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public information, Wang Ziru is the founder of ZEALER (ZEALER Network Technology). Tianyancha shows that ZEALAR was established in June 2012. It is a technology information website focusing on electronic product evaluation and Q&amp;A, and then expanded its mobile phone repair business, mobile device hardware laboratory, etc. Wang Ziru is not only the executive director and general manager of ZEALER, but also a digital review blogger with 1.97 million fans. He once became popular because of his public debate with Smartisan CEO Luo Yonghao over the review controversy of the Smartisan T1 mobile phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258706&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The picture comes from Wang Ziru&#39;s personal Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from public information, Wang Ziru and Dong Mingzhu met in 2016. In an entrepreneurial program &quot;I Am the Founder&quot; broadcast that year, Dong Mingzhu served as the mentor of Wang Ziru&#39;s team. Afterwards, Wang Ziru posted a photo of herself and Dong Mingzhu on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258707&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258708&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The picture comes from Wang Ziru&#39;s personal Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, Dong Mingzhu held a nationwide tour of live broadcast to bring goods. Wang Ziru appeared as the host many times, and together with Dong Mingzhu, they won 703 million yuan in sales. That year, Dong Mingzhu&#39;s 13 live broadcasts totaled 47.6 billion yuan, accounting for nearly 30% of Gree Electric&#39;s total revenue in 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2021, Gree Electric confirmed the news of Wang Ziru joining Gree Electric. At that time, industry insiders said that Wang Ziru’s department was affiliated with Gree’s President Office and Cultural Training and Communication Center. During the same period, Wang Ziru resigned from his position at ZEALER, the media he founded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are rumors that Wang Ziru’s rank in Gree is equivalent to that of vice president, with an annual salary of more than 3 million yuan. However, judging from Gree Electric’s financial reports in the past two years, Wang Ziru has never appeared in the executive compensation table middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After joining Gree Electric, Wang Ziru rarely appeared on public platforms. Gree Electric did not disclose his specific work content. However, it is known from some public reports that he is currently in charge of the Gree channel reform project. In late May this year, Wang Ziru, who had been with Gree for two years but had not yet appeared, appeared publicly in Nanchang for the first time as the &quot;channel reform project leader&quot; and spoke at the 2023 Gree Electric (Jiangxi) new marketing model presentation conference. In October and November, Gree Electric Shandong and Hebei Sales Companies also issued documents, and Wang Ziru gave a speech at a new marketing model conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that at the beginning of this year, news appeared on social platforms that Gree Electric Chairman and President Dong Mingzhu was in love with his company’s post-85s male executive. The news originated from the big V Gong A screenshot posted by Wen Xiang on the Internet. In February this year, Dong Mingzhu took the initiative to mention and denounced in an interview with reporters from Nanduwan Financial News and other media: &quot;Vulgar, obscene, and boring! It is not an exaggeration to use these words to describe it.&quot; She clearly denied the love scandal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March this year, big V Gong Wenxiang apologized to Dong Mingzhu, chairman and president of Gree Electric Appliances, for his previous remarks in the Southern Metropolis Daily. Gong Wenxiang said in his apology statement that he made distorted remarks about Ms. Dong Mingzhu’s private life on Toutiao on February 26, which were widely disseminated and objectively damaged Ms. Dong’s reputation. &quot;I deeply regret and am deeply sorry to Ms. Dong. The special newspaper expresses my public apology and sincere remorse to Ms. Dong, and hopes to obtain Ms. Dong&#39;s forgiveness. I will use this as a lesson in the future to be a self-media person with three upright views.&quot; .&quot; Gong Wenxiang said in the statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 17, Gree Electric responded to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News: It is worth mentioning that the Internet is not a place outside the law. The company will take legal measures to resolutely safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of the company and employees. We maintain a zero-tolerance attitude towards any malicious slander and rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the TV program mentioned above, Wang Ziru said that no company is drowned in saliva. As a business operator and manager, you should spend more time focusing on what you should do. things to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[跨越45年，披头士乐队的最后一首歌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260778]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/ugwAYHhpApNoKEoTS7occJos7QvHMSE4qPCs2MW0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ugwAYHhpApNoKEoTS7occJos7QvHMSE4qPCs2MW0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258571&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Beatles were founded in 1960, a milestone in the history of pop music band. In 1980, lead singer John Lennon was shot and killed. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 30, 1969, on the rooftop of Apple Records headquarters at 3 Savile Row, England , the Beatles held a 42-minute impromptu concert. It was almost at the last moment that the idea was settled - they discussed it and then fell silent until John Lennon said, &quot;...let&#39;s do it!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Noon Around 12:30, the four people arrived on the rooftop. As word spread, people began to gather in the surrounding streets and on the rooftops of nearby buildings. That day, Lennon wore a fur coat, and Ringo put on his wife&#39;s red coat. In the biting cold wind of January, the members sang a total of five songs in a loop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concert finally came to an end with the melody of &quot;Get&amp;nbsp;Back&quot;. Lennon said humorously to the audience: &quot;On behalf of the band and ourselves, I want to say thank you. I hope we have passed the audition.&quot; However, the public at the time may not have expected that this would be the last of the Beatles. A public performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 2, 2023, after a span of 45 years, a new Beatles collaboration called &quot;Now And Then&quot; finally came to the public. After the familiar &quot;one, two, three&quot; timer, the accompaniment sounded, and Lennon&#39;s voice slowly flowed out:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;&quot;&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;I know it&#39;s true / It&#39;s all because of you / And if I make it through / It&#39;s all because of you&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;……&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lennon in the MV The faces of George and George were still young, wearing bright costumes from that time, playing in the same space as Paul and Ringo. Different from their youthful and fresh appearance, the wrinkles on Paul and Ringo&#39;s faces are clearly visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It was incredibly touching to hear that they were still working together after all these years,” Lennon’s son Sean said. “It was my dad and Paul and George. , the last song we made together with Ringo.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;We&#39;ve been waiting almost a quarter of a century&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now And Then&quot; The story begins in 1978. Lennon recorded this vocal demo with accompaniment while playing the piano in his apartment in New York. By that time, he had focused on his family and had all but put his music career on hold, not touring or fulfilling any major label obligations. However, in his son Sean&#39;s memory, Lennon would always play music at home and record and make demos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1994, 14 years after Lennon’s death, during a chat with the Beatles, Lennon’s widow Yoko Ono said that she still had some of Lennon’s audio tapes. She gave them to the rest of the Beatles. &quot;If the three of us were to do something, it would be fun, but obviously not as fun as when John was here,&quot; George said. &quot;We really have to cherish hearing John&#39;s voice. I&#39;m sure he would really enjoy being with us.&quot; A chance to be together again.&quot; Now, that chance has come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We can use Lennon&#39;s music and try to make a record. Since his death, this is the closest we have been to him.&quot; Ringo said. Facing Lennon&#39;s demo tape, Paul also thought, &quot;Shouldn&#39;t we do this?&quot; But whenever he thought so, he would always interrupt himself, assuming that if he had the opportunity to ask Lennon - &quot;Hey , Lennon, do you want us to finish your song?&quot; - What would Lennon&#39;s answer be, and he believed that Lennon would say, &quot;Of course!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the song The production was not as smooth as expected. At that time, there was no technology that could separate the vocals from the accompaniment. In a way, Lennon&#39;s voice was actually hidden. Whenever they tried to make Lennon&#39;s voice clearer, the piano accompaniment grew louder, and the effect actually became worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They felt frustrated, &quot;We were kind of losing time and momentum,&quot; Paul said, as if they should abandon the song. &quot;Things cannot progress, and the fact that Lennon is no longer becomes more and more clear before our eyes.&quot; Ringo said. Just like that, &quot;Now&amp;nbsp;And Then&quot; was shelved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the year 2022. Previously, &quot;Lord of the Rings&quot; director Peter Jackson&#39;s team developed an artificial intelligence-based technology that can separate specific vocals from accompaniment sounds and repair them. This technology was proven successful in the 2021 documentary &quot;Get Back&quot; produced by Peter Jackson for the Beatles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the help of technology, Lennon&#39;s voice came out of the player again, &quot;as clear as crystal.&quot; &quot;We&#39;ve been waiting almost a quarter of a century for this moment to be able to make Now And Then again,&quot; Paul said. He called Ringo and told him he wanted to continue working on the song, and Ringo readily agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Lennon&#39;s piano accompaniment, Paul also added his own bass part, and Ringo also added his own drum beats. They retained George&#39;s guitar playing from 1995, &quot;which is a tribute to George.&quot; Paul said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A string section was also added with help from Giles Martin, son of the late Beatles producer George Martin. When recording this part, in order to keep it secret, they did not tell the string orchestra that it was a new Beatles song, but pretended it was Paul&#39;s own new single. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“All those memories came flooding back and, oh my God, how lucky I was to have these people in my life… Still making The Beatles in 2023 ’s music, wow!” Paul exclaimed, “‘Now And Then’ should be our last song.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Think of me from time to time, old friend”&lt;/strong>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;In February 1964, the Beatles performed in the United States for the first time. As they took off, more than 4,000 fans from Heathrow Airport waved goodbye; when they landed, another group of about 3,000 people greeted them when they landed. On the 9th of that year, the Beatles performed live on the Ed Sullivan Show, attracting about 73 million viewers, which accounted for about 34% of the U.S. population. The popularity of British rock and roll swept the United States with unprecedented intensity. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those were almost the most prosperous years of the Beatles. However, separation and death came to them prematurely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September of the same year as the Beatles&#39; last public performance together, Lennon informed his bandmates during a meeting with Ringo, Paul and their manager Alan Klein They, he was going to quit the Beatles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, due to business, creative, emotional and many other reasons, friction and differences had become increasingly serious, and it seemed that it was only a matter of time before they disbanded. During that meeting, George was absent, and Crane convinced the other band members to keep quiet about the breakup because some important business matters were still ongoing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 10 of the following year, Paul publicly announced his withdrawal from the Beatles, which was also regarded as a symbolic event of the dissolution of the Beatles. At that time, exactly ten years after their establishment, an American media person even claimed that it was &quot;a milestone in the decline of the British Empire.&quot; Asked whether his departure was temporary or permanent, Paul responded, &quot;I really don&#39;t know.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Years later, in a media interview, Paul denied that he had caused the band to break up. Due to Klein&#39;s request, they were kept secret about the band&#39;s breakup and had to pretend for several months that everything was normal. He simply &quot;had enough of hiding&quot; and, eventually, &quot;let the cat out of the bag.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following time, even though the Beatles have developed separately, fans still have lingering thoughts in their hearts, hoping that one day they will reunite. However, Lennon&#39;s death directly shattered this hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 8, 1980, after Lennon finished his work for the day, he returned to his residence with his wife Yoko Ono. The two got out of the car and walked to the building entrance of Dakota Apartments. At this moment, 25-year-old Mark David Chapman appeared and shot Lennon five times. Lennon&#39;s heart stopped forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;For everyone who hoped the Beatles would continue to exist, the murder was something else. It was an assassination, a ritual killing of something unspeakable, maybe It&#39;s hope, maybe idealism, or time. It&#39;s not just loss, but sudden dislocation and fragmentation.&quot; Critic Jay Cox wrote in a Time magazine cover article that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February of the following year, musician Carl Perkins wrote a song &quot;My Old Friend&quot; for Paul. The morning after it was finished, Carl took his guitar, sat down on Paul&#39;s old double reverb amp, and sang him this song: &quot;If we never meet again in this life...my old friend, won&#39;t you do it from time to time?&quot; Think of me...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Paul and his wife Linda sat on the floor and listened. After singing, Carl discovered that Paul was crying. Afterwards, he got up and left the room. Linda explained to him, &quot;Ever since what happened to Lennon, he hasn&#39;t been able to really break down... but how do you know?&quot; She said that Lennon&#39;s last words to Paul were in the hallway of the Dakota Building before his death. Exactly - at that time he patted Paul on the shoulder and said: &quot;Think of me now and then, old friend.&quot;&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Play a good band The key is chemistry. It was very special for us four people with very different personalities to become the Beatles. When we lost John, we knew that this was really over.&quot; Paul said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2001, they once again experienced the pain of the death of a close friend. This time it was another Beatle, George Harrison, who unfortunately passed away from cancer. &quot;Losing George is like losing the wind on a voyage,&quot; Paul said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November of the following year, a memorial concert organized by George&#39;s widow Olivia and his son Dani Harrison was held at the Royal Albert Hall in London. Friends such as Paul and Ringo attended. turn up. Before the show ended, Paul walked to the microphone and said: &quot;When Dani stands on the stage, it&#39;s like we are old, but George is still young.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe they are equally young. music. On November 10, 2023, with the song &quot;Now And Then&quot;, the Beatles once again topped the British music charts. This was their 18th number one single. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only does it extend the Beatles&#39; record for having the most number one singles in the history of the UK Official Charts, it also makes them the longest lag between their first and last number one hits in history. band - this song has been a full sixty years since their first number one single &quot;From Me to You&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Chen Quanxin also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[家政女工之死]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260737]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[94岁老人状告保姆：虐待自己还骗走200万养老钱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/17/chQqTYnDsbIs4FalpoE4JglV3iAmtPKYIOokEQyy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/chQqTYnDsbIs4FalpoE4JglV3iAmtPKYIOokEQ yy. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258602&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nanny Abuse Case&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I can&#39;t even figure out who Defendant 2 is,&quot; faced the judge&#39;s inquiry. Shen Yinan sat in the seat marked &quot;Defendant&#39;s Agent&quot; with a confused look on his face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Defendant 2 is your father,&quot; the lawyer reminded him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned slightly absurd scene occurred at a pre-trial meeting in a gift contract dispute case. On November 7, 2023, the Shanghai Huangpu District People&#39;s Court conducted an evidence exchange in this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Yinan’s mother Lu Delin is the plaintiff, the family’s nanny Jiang Aizhen is the defendant 1, and Shen Yinan’s father Shen Zongli is the defendant 2. According to the civil complaint, Shen Zongli once &quot;gifted&quot; 2 million yuan to the nanny Jiang Aizhen, and now Lu Delin is demanding the return. At the same time, Lu Delin sued the nanny Jiang Aizhen for being abused and demanded that the other party pay 200,000 yuan in mental damages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason Shen Yinan was &quot;confused&quot; was that this was not a single case. Civil contract disputes and criminal cases were both in progress. Relevant legal documents show that Lu Delin&#39;s abuse case has been filed as a criminal case at the Huangpu Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau, and the criminal case is currently being processed. Shen Yinan has lived abroad for many years and has insufficient understanding of the Chinese environment. His annual visits to relatives in Shanghai have been interrupted for three years since the end of 2019 due to the COVID-19 epidemic. It was also during this period that nanny Jiang Aizhen lived alone to take care of Lu Delin and Shen Zongli, and the dispute between the two parties eventually went to court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 29, 2023, Lu Delin, a 94-year-old man in Shanghai, posted his first video online under his real name, claiming that he was abused by his nanny and that his pension was transferred away by the nanny. Since then, the account has posted multiple videos, in which Lu Delin appeared on the scene to talk about his experience: &quot;I just breathed my last breath of life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not an exception. On the day the evidence was exchanged, a similar piece of news in Shanghai hit the hot search again. A nanny said that the elderly person she was taking care of wanted to transfer the property to her. &quot;I didn&#39;t take the initiative, it was my uncle who wanted to transfer it to me,&quot; the nanny explained at the processing window in the video. When the staff discovered something was wrong, they suspended the transfer process and called the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai Municipal Health Commission recently disclosed that as of the end of 2022, there were 5.5366 million registered elderly people aged 60 and above in Shanghai, accounting for 36.8% of the total registered population. In modern cities with severe aging, how to care for the elderly decently and the issue of home care for the elderly is attracting the attention of the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Aizhen did not arrive at the court on the afternoon of the 7th. The judge said that the court would announce the service and expected to summon Jiang Aizhen again in two months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwQJHfWcOurmAIXRYQe4AVq1jE8rzq5hcBrEZe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwQJHfWcOurmAIXRYQe4AVq1jE8rzq5hcBrEZe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258606&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Delin&#39;s bedroom, daughter-in-law Shen Ailun has asked the cleaning staff to clean it again&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>;The later life of a 94-year-old couple&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When I opened the closed door in front of me, the first thing I saw was a sour smell. The house should look well-ventilated, with a square shape, looking into the other side of the living room, with a wide balcony and large windows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Building 2401, Lane 118, Xietu Road, Liyuan New Village, Huangpu District, Shanghai. The other side of the mess is the great value of the house itself. This community has a total of 4 buildings, all of which are high-rise. It is located in the center of Shanghai and is close to many subway and bus lines, making life convenient. Relevant information shows that this community was built in the early 1990s, and the current price on the second-hand housing market exceeds 100,000 yuan per square meter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The house in front of me belongs to an old couple, Lu Delin and his wife Shen Zongli. They are both 94 years old and have retired for many years. Lu Delin suffered from myelitis and his lower body was paralyzed in bed; Shen Zongli is now blind in one eye, with only 0.25 vision left in one eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The couple’s only son, Shen Yinan, has settled in the United States for decades, and most of his relatives live abroad. Both of them have been to the United States to help their sons take care of their grandchildren, but each visa lasted only half a year at most. After several trips back and forth, the two of them got older and gradually had to stay in this house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, this house is vacant. On June 29, 2023, Lu Delin released his first video online under his real name, claiming that he was abused by the nanny Jiang Aizhen and that his pension was transferred away by the nanny. At present, Lu Delin and Shen Zongli have been picked up by their son Shen Yinan and daughter-in-law Shen Ailun and placed in Hangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alan Shen opened the door and showed the decorations in the room one by one. She carefully photographed, numbered, and kept these traces of her life. During the investigation stage of the case, many pieces of evidence came from this. On the table in the corner of the living room are piles of bags of fungus, day lilies, mushrooms and other supplements and wild products. There are a dazzling array of more than ten kinds. Shen Ailun, who was standing on one side, said that she had hired cleaning staff to clean the house inside and out. The sour odor that could be smelled now was only a few remnants, and those supplements &quot;were leftovers, and even more were thrown away.&quot; There are many, many have expired, and the nanny won’t make them for the elderly.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This family was originally &quot;stable and decent&quot;. Lu Delin and Shen Zongli&#39;s monthly pensions were more than 10,000 yuan, plus fixed financial interest, they had an additional monthly income of about 8,000 yuan. In addition to the house I live in, I also had another property under my name. After the demolition two years ago, I received a large amount of compensation, and my financial life is safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Son Shen Yinan regularly returns to China to visit relatives every year, &quot;a total of 586 days in 7 years, an average of 84 days per year.&quot; From 2013 to 2019, Shen Ailun sorted out the entry and exit records in these passports one by one. But this connection was broken by the sudden COVID-19 epidemic. After leaving China on November 29, 2019, Shen Yinan failed to come back for more than three years, and did not see her parents again until February 23, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5iKMmm2RPAmjZfcTckXYIjbSBIgKUcdgj6DF7z.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; height= &quot;601&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5iKMmm2RPAmjZfcTckXYIjbSBIgKUcdgj6DF7z.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258605&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shen&#39;s son&#39;s return time record sheet&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, two elderly people and the nanny Jiang Aizhen have lived in this house. A neighbor in the same unit told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that in the past few years, his family had contact with Lu Delin&#39;s family, and occasionally made some food to give away, but later stopped going to her house. &quot;The smell of (Lu Delin&#39;s) house was too strong and I couldn&#39;t get in. Feet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The kitchen is on the right hand side of the door, with moldy and hairy cutting boards and jars scattered on the countertop; on the left hand side of the door is the bathroom, a small bathroom of several square meters with white tiles, which has been renovated. Including showers, toilets, etc., the renovation cost tens of thousands of yuan. The bill came from the nanny Jiang Aizhen, and the price of the shower was noted as 4,000 yuan, but &quot;actually it was only 400 yuan.&quot; Shen Allen found out this detail from the property management office - the property management was involved in the installation of the shower. Master Xia, who has worked in property management in this community for many years, confirmed the discrepancy in this amount to a reporter from Southern People Weekly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7bOr8sa2Y9dLtafy9EpuDER4qvTRMTs0j4eM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7bOr8sa2Y9dLtafy9EpuDER4qvTRMTs0j4eM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258601&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bathroom renovated by the nanny. The showerhead in the picture is marked as costing 4,000 yuan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we arrived in the bedroom, the rancid smell became even more obvious. Lu Delin was paralyzed from the lower body and had been urinating and defecating on a chair-shaped toilet in his bedroom. The sheets and quilts had been replaced, and the mattress overflowing with white powder was put away in a box on the side. Shen Allen opened it and showed it to reporters. It was the one that Lu Delin had been using for the past few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father-in-law Shen Zongli’s shirt was also kept. There were large yellow and black stains on the collar. These were “all evidence.” In this unfamiliar space, Shen Ailun carefully collected traces of the past and determined to litigate with the nanny Jiang Aizhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The long-buried conflict&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Lu Delin family first came into contact with the nanny Jiang Aizhen in 2013, through the introduction of their upstairs neighbor Wang Wei. At that time, Jiang Work part-time in the area. By 2017, Jiang Aizhen became a long-term, fixed hourly employee of the Lu Delin family. Wang Wei said it was because &quot;Little Jiang did a good job&quot;, and Shen Ailun said it was because Jiang Aizhen was frustrated in finding a job and complained to Lu Delin and his wife that she got the job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting along for a long time, during the three years when the new coronavirus epidemic was raging, Lu Delin and his wife were cared for at home by Jiang Aizhen, with no one else to look after them. It wasn&#39;t until Lu Delin released a video, claiming that he was abused by the nanny and defrauded of his pension, that the conflict broke out in the public eye. For a long time before this, the conflict between the family and the nanny had already been laid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxBpiVrT0LPnXi3s2cUkRkL3vnFCUtPGAt8tHrAc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxBpiVrT0LPnXi3s2cUkRkL3vnFCUtPGAt8tHrAc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258603&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bedding used by Teacher Lu Delin in the past few years has a strong musty smell&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, Jiang Aizhen worked part-time for two hours at home every day, and the couple paid 6,000 yuan a month. In March 2022, Jiang Aizhen moved into this house and changed from a part-time worker to a live-in nanny, and her salary increased to 12,000 yuan per month. Shen Ailun told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that while Jiang Aizhen was receiving this salary, she was also working part-time in four other places at the same time. At this point, she felt that the nanny did not have the spirit of contract. &quot;Having paid all the salary of the live-in nanny, how can she still go to work other jobs outside?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; visited to find out more Currently, in Huangpu District, Shanghai, where Lu Delin is located, the hourly salary for hourly workers is about 45 yuan, which rises to about 50 yuan during the evening peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of the Sangcheng Neighborhood Committee to which the community belongs told Southern People Weekly that whether the price is for an hourly or full-time live-in nanny depends on how the employer and the nanny negotiate. Judging from the neighborhood committee&#39;s registration, as long as she spends the night at her employer&#39;s house, she is considered a live-in nanny. Jiang Aizhen has indeed been registered as a live-in nanny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wei, an introducer who also employs part-time workers for a long time, does not think that 12,000 yuan is a &quot;buyout&quot; price. For two elderly people who cannot take care of themselves, more money will definitely be needed. It is normal for the nanny to work other jobs. of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter of &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; consulted three local housekeeping agencies based on the current situation of Lu Delin and his wife. They all said that the price of 12,000 yuan is the price of a full-time live-in nanny, which is a &quot;buyout price&quot; and the aunt should not Go do other work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the housekeeping agencies was established in 2014 and is headquartered in Guangzhou. It has branches in Shanghai and Shenzhen. It provides customers with full-time live-in nannies through an employee system. Each aunt has undergone background checks. Their daily life is monitored by the company using a housekeeper model. This company will conduct regular follow-up visits through its stewards, and it is one of the similar institutions that attaches great importance to supervision. Even so, the quality of Auntie still relies on proactive feedback from customers. When family members are not around all year round, the elderly are forced to rely on a single nanny. &quot;This kind of feedback is relatively difficult and can be said to be blank.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3Ypu1xbkvmkyW1xrSR2bfacSHHVL1imYUJcSbwAD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/17/3Ypu1xbkvmkyW1xrSR2bfacSHHVL1imYUJcSbwAD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258600&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Daily use in the kitchen of Lu Delin and his wife The cutting board&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Besides money, there is incalculable &quot;love&quot;. During the COVID-19 epidemic, the two elderly people were cared for by Jiang Aizhen alone. They were pushed up and down in line to get nucleic acid tests, which was seen by the neighborhood committee. Whether the care was good or not, and whether there was abuse or not, are &quot;matters behind closed doors.&quot; The neighborhood committee and some neighbors used this as an excuse to express their ignorance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Shen Yinan and his wife returned to China, Jiang Aizhen repeatedly claimed that she had &quot;saved the old man&#39;s life&quot; and produced a &quot;certificate&quot; and a &quot;power of attorney&quot; handwritten and signed by Shen Zongli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A power of attorney signed on September 1, 2022 shows: &quot;Jiang Aizhen will live in our current residence a hundred years later. Jiang Aizhen will provide for us in our old age. Our ashes will be placed at home first. , and finally thrown into the Huangpu River.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In another &quot;certificate&quot; on the same day, Shen Zongli stated that he gave Jiang Aizhen &quot;one million yuan&quot;; in a &quot;certificate&quot; on March 3, 2023, , the amount given to Jiang Aizhen rose to &quot;two million yuan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not just a paper promise, on August 22, 2022 and February 7, 2023, Shen Zongli’s personal account transferred 1 million yuan to Jiang Aizhen’s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three pieces of paper, corresponding to 2 million yuan and the right to live in the house, were given to the nanny Jiang Aizhen. Whether the old man was conscious and voluntary, and whether the gift was legal and valid, the question was ultimately handed over to the court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Looking for evidence&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who was present at the time?&quot; The judge asked many times to confirm this key question, pointing to the latest gift contract-2023 On March 3, 2019, Shen Zongli handwritten a &quot;certificate&quot; of 2 million yuan to his nanny Jiang Aizhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Aizhen did not appear in court. Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun told the judge what happened: Jiang Aizhen took out a certificate signed by Lu Delin, Shen Zongli, and Shen Yinan, and asked Lu Delin and Shen Yinan to sign in the corresponding places, but they refused. At that time, Shen Ailun was present and stopped him. At that time, thinking that the matter was settled, Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun left home to go out on business. When they returned to Shanghai, they learned that the &quot;proof&quot; had actually been written long ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The certificate that was suppressed was signed on March 9, 2023. In fact, as early as a week ago, on March 3, 2023, Jiang Aizhen obtained the &quot;certificate&quot; signed by Shen Zongli. Shen Ailun discovered that Shen Zongli&#39;s Alipay had been registered, and found someone to use technical means to recover the data on the old man&#39;s mobile phone. He found a video recorded by Jiang Aizhen, which was proof that Shen Zongli had handwritten a gift of 2 million to the nanny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/TckI7M60dT3Wk8L8OodV8ejKNT3ls4Z8Y9Vh9cx6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/TckI7M60dT3Wk8L8OodV8ejKNT3ls4Z8Y9Vh9cx6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The power of attorney dated September 1, 2022 shows: &quot;Jiang Aizhen will live in our current residence a hundred years later. Jiang Aizhen will provide for us in our old age. Our ashes will be placed at home first. , and finally thrown into the Huangpu River.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A recording provided by Lu Delin&#39;s attorney Zhou Zhaocheng showed that a duty lawyer of the neighborhood committee said that Jiang Aizhen had repeatedly pushed Shen Zongli in a wheelchair to the neighborhood committee&#39;s duty lawyer&#39;s office for consultation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 3, 2023, Jiang Aizhen received the certificate signed by Shen Zongli’s handwriting. In order to ensure that the donation of &quot;2 million yuan&quot; was legal and valid, a week later, she took out a certificate again and added &quot;Lu Delin and Shen Yinan&quot; in addition to Shen Zongli. This certificate was the only one that Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun had ever seen in person. Proof of “donation”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the previous three certificates of donating 1 million yuan, donating 2 million yuan, and letting the nanny live in the house, Shen Yinan saw the nanny Fang issued them online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9LE4c03YquSx1reueA0dU9dZlxfnKOraquARP6Fm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9LE4c03YquSx1reueA0dU9dZlxfnKOraquARP6Fm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258599&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 3, 2023, Shen Zongli handwritten a &quot;proof&quot; of 2 million yuan to the nanny Jiang Aizhen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Zongli is the person in control of the family&#39;s &quot;account&quot;. The certificates were all handwritten by him. Shen Ailun said that the nanny treated Shen Zongli and Lu Delin differently. &quot;She knew which one should be coaxed, and used this brainwashing method to defraud the old man of his money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, the family trusted the nanny. The first time I realized something was wrong was when Shen Ailun mailed food to his parents-in-law. When he was talking on the phone, he discovered that his parents-in-law had not received it and did not know about it. Shen Ailun had previously sent a message to the old man&#39;s mobile phone about this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The nanny will delete the chat history,&quot; this answer was found by Allen Shen after installing the camera. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, about three years after being separated due to the new crown epidemic, Shen Allen stepped into the door of 2401 again. Her mother-in-law Lu Delin asked her to look at her feet and said they felt bumpy. Shen Ailun found that her toenails were &quot;cut&quot; and she realized something was wrong. Shen Ailun went to check the accounts and found that 2 million yuan in his parents-in-law&#39;s account had been transferred to Jiang Aizhen&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the wheelchair to the wall, Shen Allen secretly installed 7 miniature cameras to &quot;monitor&quot; the nanny. The couple pretended to return to the United States and wanted to see if the nanny was taking good care of the elderly while he was away. . Her husband told her that this was to collect evidence, and she must hold back her temper. No matter what she saw, the primary purpose was to preserve evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the next day, Shen Ailun still quarreled with Jiang Aizhen. She recalled that Jiang Aizhen had a habit of speaking, which was a bit like a teacher lecturing a child. He kept saying &quot;What&#39;s wrong with you, what&#39;s wrong with you&quot;, &quot;It made my head buzz.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Conflicts quickly broke out. One day at noon, her mother-in-law Lu Delin said she wanted to eat crabs and asked Shen Ailun to cook them. Shen Ailun asked her aunt (referring to Jiang Aizhen) to make them. Jiang Aizhen said she didn&#39;t eat crabs and couldn&#39;t cook them. &quot;I wanted to scold her at that time, but I held it back,&quot; Shen Allen continued to recall. &quot;The nanny asked my mother-in-law how to do it. My mother-in-law asked her to ask me. She was very normal when she asked me, and then I said, what did you just do? Didn&#39;t you ask my mother? Just do it as my mother said.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Patience seemed to disappear suddenly. Jiang Aizhen suddenly became unhappy, and the volume suddenly became louder, &quot;Your mother asked me to Ask you, you asked me to ask your mother, I really don’t understand you.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as these words came out, Shen Ailun couldn’t hold back his anger, “I really grew up from the eighteenth generation of my ancestors. She started scolding her, and I said don’t talk to me like that. One day I make you cry, so get out of here.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Jiang Aizhen didn’t know about the installation of cameras in her home, but Shen Ailun had already She saw the nanny&#39;s usual behavior through the video, which she found difficult to accept. &quot;She took all her anger out on my mother-in-law, and her voice broke with curses.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After watching some of the footage captured by the camera, , the night he slept at his in-laws&#39; house, Shen Ailun was afraid that Jiang Aizhen would do something extreme with a knife from the kitchen, so he took away all the large and small knives in the kitchen, put them in the room, locked the door, and took one of them away. The knife was placed under the pillow in case of emergency. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Two statements about &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Jiang Aizhen&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The backside of abuse, money fraud, and extreme behavior , is another way of saying &quot;introducer&quot; Wang Wei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wei also heard about the 2 million yuan donation, and she also saw the &quot;abuse&quot; scenes circulated on the Internet. But she always thinks that the nanny is doing a good job:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“One of the videos I saw online is that the action is relatively rough. In fact, this is how to pull an old man out of bed. There used to be an old man in my house, and Xiao Jiang also pulled him up like this. Jiang is also almost 60 years old. He is only a part-time worker and has no professional training in nursing, so he can only do this. We are used to it, and it is the same behavior in our family. The aunt is fierce, and her mouth is a bit rude. This is her temperament and character.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is also bleeding when the toenails are cut. The onychomycosis is bound to bleed when the onychomycosis is cut. The moldy bedding must have nothing to do with Xiao Jiang. This is Teacher Lu. The personal habits of the old couple. Their family’s habit is that everything that comes into their home is no garbage, everything is treasure, nothing is thrown away, and the used toilet paper must be dried and used...&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;The people who hired Xiao Jiang in this building were all introduced by Wang Wei. She said that the only ones who had problems were Lu Delin&#39;s family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Aizhen is a part-time worker introduced by the security guard earlier, and has been working at Wang Wei&#39;s house since 2012. &quot;Before my daughter-in-law returned to Shanghai this time, Teacher Lu&#39;s family had a good relationship with the nanny. They said that the nanny was their goddaughter. Fortunately, they had a nanny, otherwise they would have died. When the daughter-in-law came back, everything was reversed. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wei told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that the 2 million yuan was given to Jiang Aizhen in two installments, both for a reason: the first time was due to the epidemic lockdown. I did nucleic acid tests almost every day, and the nanny was the one who pushed her up and down every day. Another time, Mr. Shen’s house was demolished. He said that he, as an old man, could not negotiate, and it was all his fault. I entrusted this nanny to do it, and it seemed that I got some money in the end. Mr. Shen said, &quot;If his aunt hadn&#39;t helped him, he wouldn&#39;t have gotten so much.&quot; In the end, he had to ask Xiao Jiang to support him until his death. We were in the midst of an epidemic lockdown at the time, and we didn’t know when our son would come back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But these two things are different situations in Shen Ailun&#39;s eyes. In terms of physical care, Shen Ailun said that in May 2020, an old man was hospitalized with pneumonia and Jiang Aizhen took care of him, but paid the nanny an extra salary of 300 yuan a day. This was a contract, not &quot;favour or help&quot;; in terms of house demolition, The nanny did not do a good job, and the demolition money was much less than what she deserved...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Lu Delin and Shen Zongli, who are cared for by Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun, both asked Jiang Aizhen to pay back the money in the video. Before being picked up, when the old man and the nanny were living together, &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; obtained an audio recording, which was a conversation between the nanny Jiang Aizhen and Shen Zongli about money on March 22, 2023:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nanny: &quot;All the money is transferred away.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Zongli: &quot;I want to keep the money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanny: &quot;The money you keep is not the same as if you put it here with me &quot;?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Zongli: &quot;Both.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanny: &quot;I want it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Zongli: &quot;You are bullying me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The helplessness of the &quot;nanny butler&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Is it voluntary to give money to the nanny? Shen Zongli’s answers were inconsistent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first he said it was a voluntary gift, but he changed his story later when he saw the flow, audio and video of the nanny withdrawing the money. Relevant audio and video recordings show that the nanny personally admitted that she had withdrawn an extra 70,000 yuan from the elderly person’s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Ailun told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that Shen Zongli claimed to have been told by the nanny many times that his own money was the same in the nanny&#39;s account and could be withdrawn at any time if needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the three years since the COVID-19 epidemic, Shen Ailun has only returned to China once. At that time, he was going to visit his parents-in-law, but he received a note from her mother-in-law in the quarantine hotel, which said &quot;Don&#39;t go back.&quot; Considering the fear of infection at the time, Shen Allen did not return to 2401. Afterwards, Lu Delin told Shen Ailun that the note was written by the nanny and was &quot;forced.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the past three years, &quot;nanny and housekeeper&quot; has become the theme of 2401, and even the &quot;outsiders&quot; who deal with it have noticed it. inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Master Xia from the property management company told Southern People Weekly that the two old people could not take care of themselves and had to be accompanied by a nanny when they went downstairs. The nanny was always by their side, so even if the old people wanted to say something, they could not say it. Usually the two old people are at home with no relatives to take care of them. Only Lu Delin&#39;s students come occasionally, but &quot;after all, they are not family members, so they can&#39;t say much. Their family is a decent person who wants to save face and is hard to talk to.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a chain of pedicure shops nearby that nannies Jiang Aizhen and Shen Zongli go to regularly. The clerk called Shen Zongli &quot;White Rabbit&quot; because he loved to eat White Rabbit toffee and would sometimes eat several pieces at a time. Allen Shen opened the mobile shopping APP and found multiple purchases of White Rabbit toffees, all of which were mailed to 2401. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The store clerk calls their family&#39;s situation &quot;nanny butler&quot;: the nanny comes with a white rabbit, the white rabbit gets a pedicure, and the nanny also gets a pedicure. They do the same project, and the nanny pays the money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Such nannies are rare,” the clerk recalled the nanny Jiang Aizhen’s behavior. On the one hand, she felt that she was fierce and powerful, and on the other hand, the nanny always brought the old man with her. Other families are often accompanied by their children and family members. On the day of the reporter&#39;s interview, this pedicure shop received a 103-year-old man, who was accompanied by his niece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a wonton shop a few hundred meters away from the community. Jiang Aizhen sometimes takes Lu Delin and his wife to eat there. After returning to China this time, the owner of the wonton shop once privately told Shen Ailun, &quot;Quickly fire your nanny.&quot; The reporter asked the boss to find out and confirmed this, &quot;I have never seen other nannies speak so fiercely.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;There are many elderly people like Lu Delin and his wife in this community. A staff member of the Sangcheng Neighborhood Committee told Southern People Weekly that it is common for family members to visit from time to time, but it is rare for a nanny to be taken care of by herself. Previously, the neighborhood committee tried to mediate after hearing the news, but the nanny did not come. &quot;The nanny never showed up. Our neighborhood committee cannot represent any level of government or relevant departments, and cannot force the nanny to be present. We can&#39;t do that. We don&#39;t have that Power. Also, when the nanny is absent or not present, we also recommend that they take judicial channels and report the case to the court or the police.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member who has worked in the neighborhood committee for many years told &quot; According to Southern People Weekly, I have met the nanny Jiang Aizhen on a regular basis, and during the face-to-face contact, I did not feel anything related to &quot;abuse&quot;. But many things are done behind closed doors, and no one will do anything excessive in public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This will not be an exception. Shanghai is the super-large city with the highest aging population in the country. According to data released by the 2022 Shanghai Elderly Population and Aging Care Monitoring and Statistics Information, there were 5.5366 million elderly people aged 60 and above registered in Shanghai in 2022, accounting for 36.8% of the total registered population, of which 300,600 were elderly people living alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether she was abused or deceived, she was a &quot;nanny and housekeeper&quot; for three years. It wasn&#39;t until the conflict broke out and it became a hot search topic that many neighbors saw the news on their mobile phones. Some neighbors had previously seen the news about the daughter-in-law accusing the nanny Jiang Aizhen in the owner group, but many more neighbors knew nothing about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, the characters Shen Yinan, Shen Ailun, and Wang Wei in the article are pseudonyms.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“清朗·网络戾气整治”专项行动启动，打击网络厕所、开盒挂人等行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260790]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Cyberspace Affairs Office of the Party Committee of all provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities directly under the Central Government, and the Cyberspace Affairs Office of the Party Committee of the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps: &lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In accordance with the overall arrangement of the 2023 &quot;Qinglang&quot; series of special operations, the Central Cyberspace Administration of China has decided to launch a one-month &quot;Qinglang·Internet Violence Rectification&quot; nationwide from now on. Special action. The relevant matters are now notified as follows. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;1. Clear work goals&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Focus on cyber violence We will focus on key sections where anger easily breeds, strictly crack down on prominent issues such as malicious attacks and insults, provoking group confrontations, and venting extreme emotions, and resolutely punish a number of illegal accounts, groups, and website platforms to effectively curb the spread of online violence. By carrying out special rectification, we will further consolidate the main responsibilities of the website platform, thoroughly identify problems and loopholes, improve the system and mechanism to prevent and control online violence, effectively protect the legitimate rights and interests of the majority of netizens, and maintain a good online ecology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;2. Focus on rectifying 7 types of outstanding problems&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The special actions focus on key platform types such as social networking, short videos, and live broadcasts, and resolutely crack down on the following seven aspects of problems:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;1. &quot;Internet toilets&quot; and &quot;open boxes to hang people&quot; &quot;Behavior. Create special BOT accounts, post bars, topics, groups, etc., and receive and publish sarcastic, malicious comments, curses and insults targeting specific groups or individuals through anonymous contributions, remote shouting, etc. In the name of exposure and criticism, they maliciously &quot;open the box&quot; and &quot;hang people&quot;, publicizing other people&#39;s names, ID numbers, mobile phone numbers, home addresses, workplaces, personal photos, social accounts and other personal privacy information, inciting netizens to attack and abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Use hot social events to maliciously slander and spread rumors. Spread rumors and slander relevant parties involved in emergencies, or edit and process pictures and videos that are seriously inconsistent with the facts, to induce netizens to attack and question the parties involved. Use the image of the parties involved in hot events to create and publish emoticons, and use AI software to synthesize fake pictures or videos such as vulgar pornography, bloody horror, etc., to carry out rumors, attacks, and slander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Stigmatize specific groups and incite regional confrontation. Associate individual vicious social events and negative figures with gender, occupation, region and other characteristics, stigmatize and negatively label specific groups, publish gender-antagonistic, class-antagonistic, and regionally discriminatory remarks, carry out generalized attacks, and intensify social conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. Vulgar and bad live streaming behaviors such as fierce PK. Online anchors use behaviors such as showing off their courage, fighting, drinking, and swearing to increase their followers and traffic. During other people&#39;s live broadcasts, they use functions such as barrages and mics to conduct personal attacks, and even encourage extreme behaviors such as suicide and self-harm. Make up scripts of violent conflicts such as fights and fights to attract netizens to watch and disrupt public order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5. Organized and malicious abuse and reporting of others. In the name of &quot;helping with work&quot; and &quot;relieving worries and anger&quot;, they provide paid scolding services and leave abusive messages and private message attacks on specific accounts. Organize fan groups to use the platform’s “reporting” and “anti-gangster” functions to maliciously report others in batches. Publish comments that provoke war and malicious hype in the fields of entertainment, sports, e-sports, etc., inducing fans to quarrel with each other and control reviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6. Make up Internet slang and maliciously create rumors. Through pinyin, homophony, pronouns, etc., maliciously fabricate vulgar memes and bad buzzwords to pollute the Internet atmosphere. Use obscene language and foul language to deliberately provoke conflicts and create conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7. Inciting extreme emotions online. Make up sensational post titles and publish &quot;venting posts&quot; that are made out of nothing and have no bottom line. Maliciously exaggerating the conflicts between teachers and students, exaggerating parents&#39; &quot;oppression&quot; and &quot;squeezing&quot; of their children, provoking conflicting relationships, and forming a negative direction for minors. Deliberately exaggerate negativity, anxiety and resentment, and spread hateful and antagonistic remarks. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;3. Severely punish illegal accounts, groups and platforms in accordance with the law&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Special During the operation, we must persist in striking hard, close a group of account groups that seriously violate regulations and have a bad influence, resolutely ban a group of functional sections that gather violence and have outstanding problems, and strictly investigate and punish a group of people who fail to perform their responsibilities and have serious problems. The website platform that resists the temptation to commit crimes forms a powerful deterrent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Strictly investigate and punish illegal accounts, groups, and post bars. In-depth investigation of high-risk accounts and groups, resolutely ban accounts and groups with themes such as &quot;online toilets&quot;, &quot;opening boxes to hang people&quot;, &quot;inciting fights&quot;, etc., and seriously investigate and deal with anchor accounts that organize ruthless PKs and live broadcast fights , severely punish &quot;self-media&quot; accounts that publish &quot;clickbait&quot; content that deliberately incites online violence, close a group of circles, super chats, and post bars named with insulting words and where online violence gathers, and remove them from the shelves and provide paid compensation. Scolding merchants and shops waiting for services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Strictly investigate and deal with illegal function settings. Strengthen the management of key functions such as live broadcast barrage, continuous wheat, and PK, and resolutely clean up and deal with violent content online. Centrally cancel a batch of functional applications that organize malicious reports in batches. It is prohibited to push &quot;online toilet&quot; accounts to users through functions such as &quot;Related Recommendations&quot;, &quot;TA Follows&quot;, and &quot;Potentially Interested People&quot;. Strengthen the review and management of emoticon packages, P-picture puzzles, video editing, AI synthesis and other functions, and clean up and remove emoticon packages, pictures and videos containing prank attacks, provoking confrontation and other content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Strictly investigate and punish illegal platform links. Urge &lt;span>; website platforms to strengthen the management of lists, topics, recommendations, comments, private messages, etc. It is strictly forbidden to push content that incites and promotes online violence in lists, recommendations, etc., by setting up &quot;private message folding&quot; and &quot;message boxes&quot; etc. to reduce harassment from strangers via private messages. For websites, apps, and mini-programs with outstanding problems, punitive measures such as rectification within a time limit, fines, suspension of relevant functions, and shutdown will be taken in accordance with the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;4. Detailed work requirements&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/ span>;1. Do a good job in deployment and promotion. Based on local reality, we will formulate detailed implementation plans, allocate strong working forces, pay close attention to the deployment and implementation of tasks, organize to evaluate the effectiveness of website platform governance as appropriate, and supervise the implementation of rectifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Consolidate platform responsibility. Guide local website platforms to comprehensively investigate problems and loopholes, focus on key links, sections and functions, carry out in-depth self-examination and self-correction, improve content management mechanisms, and ensure that special actions achieve effective results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Strengthen publicity and exposure. Announce &lt;span>; the launch and phased progress of special actions, and key platforms publish typical cases every week. Strengthen education and guidance, encourage netizens to actively participate in reporting and complaining, and jointly resist online violence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Secretary Bureau of the Central Cyberspace Affairs Commission&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot; >;&lt;span>;November 10, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马云继续减持，阿里巴巴刺向低价]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260806]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 15:30:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Alibaba Xixi Park. Image source: Alibaba official website&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258618&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Alibaba Xixi Park . Image source: Alibaba official website&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 16, 2023, is the day when Alibaba’s new quarterly results for fiscal year 2024 are announced. On this day, many important news about this giant company were simultaneously released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jack Ma continues to reduce his stake in the founder of Alibaba; the previous &quot;1+6+N&quot; spin-off plan partially pressed the pause button, and Alibaba Cloud will no longer be completely split; the listing of Hema is also suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What changes is Alibaba facing? Where will the strategic baton be waved from now on? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Jack Ma reduced his holdings and cashed out US$870 million&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 16, Alibaba (BABA.NYSE) submitted two 144 forms to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), indicating that Jack Ma JC Properties Limited and JSP Investment Limited, subsidiaries of the family trust, plan to sell 5 million shares of the founder of Alibaba each on November 21. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on Alibaba’s closing price of US$87.07 per share on November 15, Eastern Time, the Jack Ma family can cash out US$870.7 million through this reduction. Alibaba’s market capitalization that day was approximately US$221.75 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Form 144, also known as &quot;Notice of Proposed Sale of Securities.&quot; SEC regulations stipulate that if directors, executives or major shareholders of a U.S. listed company transfer more than 5,000 shares of listed company stock or a market value of more than $50,000 in any three months, they must fill out Form 144 and report to the SEC. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Alibaba’s U.S. stock prospectus, before the IPO, Jack Ma held a total of 8.8% of Alibaba’s shares in four ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I hold 0.08% directly, 1.49% each through APN Ltd registered in the Cayman Islands and SymAsia Foundation, a Singapore non-profit organization, and through JC Properties registered in the British Virgin Islands Limited and JSP Investment Limited hold 2.78% and 2.95% of the shares respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shares sold by Jack Ma in the US stock IPO also came from JC Properties Limited and JSP Investment Limited. After the IPO, his shareholding in Alibaba dropped to 7.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Alibaba was listed on the New York Stock Exchange in 2014, Jack Ma has reduced his holdings many times. The financial report shows that Jack Ma’s large-scale reduction of holdings began in 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Jack Ma’s shareholding dropped from 7.8% to 7%, to 6.4% in 2018, to 6.2% in 2019, and to 4.8% in 2020, which is below the 5% disclosure red line. Since then, Alibaba has not disclosed Jack Ma’s shareholdings in its financial reports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba has responded that Jack Ma and Tsai Chongxin will donate their Alibaba options, which total 2% of the total equity of Alibaba Group, to support environmental protection, medical health, educational development and public welfare. ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Teacher’s Day 2019, Jack Ma resigned as chairman of Alibaba’s board of directors. A year later, Jack Ma completed his term as director and is no longer a member of Alibaba&#39;s board of directors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2023 financial report shows that Jack Ma is still a member of Alibaba’s partner committee, and the other five are Cai Chongxin, Zhang Yong, Peng Lei, Shao Xiaofeng and Wu Yongming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba implements a partnership system, in which partners nominate the majority of directors on the board of directors, rather than allocating director seats based on the number of shares. Alibaba currently has 28 partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Refocus on 1688, Xianyu, DingTalk, and Quark&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Also on November 16, Alibaba’s Q2 results for fiscal year 2024 were announced. Alibaba&#39;s fiscal year is not synchronized with the natural year, ranging from April 1 of each year to March 31 of the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This quarter, Alibaba’s revenue was 224.79 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 9%. Net profit was 26.696 billion yuan, compared with a net loss of 22.467 billion yuan in the same period in 2022, and non-GAAP net profit was 40.188 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 19%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Alibaba Group&#39;s performance this quarter was solid, with multiple businesses showing new momentum and vitality, and proactive self-reform achieving remarkable results.&quot; Wu Yongming, CEO of Alibaba Group, said in the performance announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local Life Group’s revenue increased by 16% year-on-year to 15.564 billion yuan, driven by the strong growth of Ele.me and AutoNavi, with orders increasing by nearly 20% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao’s revenue increased by 25% year-on-year to 22.823 billion yuan, mainly driven by cross-border logistics fulfillment solutions. Cainiao launched global 5-day logistics services to 8 countries and regions this quarter, including first-leg collection, trunk transportation, customs clearance, sorting and last-mile delivery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Alibaba Entertainment finally turned a profit in the last quarter, its chances of winning have further expanded. The revenue of Dawen Entertainment Group in this quarter was 5.779 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 11%, mainly due to the offline entertainment business of Damai.com and Alibaba Pictures, and the subscription growth of Youku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, Alibaba Pictures announced the acquisition of Damai.com. Benefiting from the recovery and strong demand of the offline entertainment market during the summer vacation of 2023, Damai.com recorded triple-digit year-on-year growth in GMV this quarter. In August, Damai.com teamed up with Youku to sell tickets for the offline performances and online live broadcasts of TFBOYS’s 10th anniversary concert. This exclusive online live broadcast broke Youku’s online paid performance record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two films jointly produced by Alibaba Pictures, &quot;All or Nothing&quot; and &quot;The Lost Girl&quot; ranked among the top two at the summer box office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of November 16, Wu Yongming participated in the quarterly financial analyst conference call for the first time as CEO of Alibaba Group. At the meeting, he introduced Alibaba’s first batch of strategic innovative businesses-1688, Xianyu, Nail, Quark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yongming said that Alibaba’s selection criteria for strategic innovative businesses are: having a large enough market space; having unique market positioning; complying with user demand trends and the group’s “AI-driven” strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strategic innovative business will be operated as an independent subsidiary in terms of organization. In terms of business, it will break the previous positioning restrictions within the group and use a more independent strategy to face the broad market. Alibaba Group will make continuous investment in a 3-5 year cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quark is an intelligent search app owned by Alibaba, and DingTalk is an enterprise-level intelligent mobile office platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of online transactions that Alibaba is good at, 1688 is a purchasing and wholesale network, which is often put together with Pinduoduo to compare which one is cheaper, while Xianyu is a second-hand idle transfer platform, which improves the popularity of the two within the group. The importance of Alibaba’s business shows that Alibaba’s baton is tilted towards the low-price market. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The spin-off of Alibaba Cloud and the listing of Hema will be suspended&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Alibaba’s Q2 financial report also announced the spin-off progress of each business segment. Surprisingly, the spin-off of Alibaba Cloud has been put on hold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 18, Zhang Yong, then chairman and CEO of Alibaba Group and chairman and CEO of Alibaba Cloud Intelligence Group, announced that Alibaba Cloud Intelligence Group would be completely separated from Alibaba Group within the next 12 months. Dismantled and completed listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba explained in this financial report that the United States has recently expanded restrictions on the export of advanced computing chips, which has brought uncertainty to the prospects of Cloud Intelligence Group. Its complete spin-off may not increase shareholder value as originally envisaged, so it has decided not to promote its complete spin-off. Instead, it will face an uncertain environment and focus on establishing a sustainable growth model for Cloud Intelligence Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yongming said that Alibaba Group will maintain long-term and resolute investment in the strategic direction of Alibaba Cloud. At the same time, Cloud Intelligence Group will continue to maintain an independent company operation method and adopt a CEO responsibility system authorized by the board of directors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2023, Bloomberg News stated that Hema was cooperating with CICC, Morgan Stanley and others to prepare for listing and prepare to be listed in Hong Kong next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this financial report shows that Hema’s initial public offering plan is on hold. Ali did not explain why. But this may have something to do with Hema’s lackluster performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This quarter, Alibaba’s revenue from all other segments was 4.8052 billion yuan, which remained stable compared with the same period in 2022. All other segments include Sun Art Retail, Hema, Alibaba Health, Lingxi Interactive Entertainment, Intime, Intelligent Information (mainly including UC Youshi and Quark businesses), Fliggy, DingTalk, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other segments, the revenue of Hema, Fliggy, Alibaba Health and Smart Information has increased, but the overall performance is only the same as last year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In sharp contrast to Hema, Cainiao Group has applied for an initial public offering in Hong Kong and has submitted an A1 document (listing application form) to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yongming said at the conference call that Cainiao’s core strategies for the next three years are to accelerate the construction of a global smart logistics network, seize the historical opportunities of the rapid development of cross-border e-commerce, and achieve rapid growth in international business. The second is to adhere to the path of differentiation in the country, export scientific and technological capabilities, and maintain the healthy development of business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：严厉打击倒买倒卖、伪造出生医学证明等违法犯罪行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260797]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:40:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The National Health Commission attaches great importance to the management of birth medical certificates and is supervising relevant places to seriously verify and deal with the trafficking of birth medical certificates. Regarding certification and other related issues, supervision teams have been dispatched to Xiangyang in Hubei, Foshan in Guangdong, and Nanning in Guangxi to urge and guide local governments to conduct thorough investigations, respond to social concerns, and hold relevant responsibilities accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Medical Birth Certificate&quot; is a statutory medical certification document issued in accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;Maternal and Infant Health Care Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and is an important basis for the public security organs to carry out newborn household registration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Health Commission will severely crack down on any behavior that harms the rights and interests of children, harms the interests of the masses, and disrupts the normal medical order, especially the forgery of medical birth certificates. If it is discovered, it will be investigated and punished, and we will actively cooperate with them. The public security organs crack down on criminal activities such as buying and selling birth medical certificates, and severely deal with the medical personnel involved in accordance with the law and regulations. You are welcome to report relevant clues to the local health administration department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the National Health Commission will guide medical institutions to further improve their internal management mechanisms and processes, and conduct special inspections on the standardized management of birth medical certificates across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网红民工吴桂春重返东莞：“要千方百计看两本书”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[研究发现鲨鱼可以跟人类一样品尝出苦味]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A new study recently published in the US magazine &quot;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&quot; stated that sharks and other cartilaginous fish have the same Genes that detect bitter tastes like humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258594&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The picture shows a photo of a shark provided by the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Photo courtesy of the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity/Photo by Andrew Fox)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many animals and plants secrete toxic compounds as a defense, a chemical that enables humans to perceive their taste The bitter taste receptor type 2 (T2R) gene helps humans recognize these compounds and avoid poisoning. Many bony vertebrates also have this bitter taste receptor gene, but researchers have never found it in cartilaginous vertebrates before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this study, researchers from the University of Cologne in Germany and other institutions used the latest gene sequencing technology to sequence the genes of 17 species of cartilaginous fish (including sharks and rays) and found that 12 species of cartilaginous fish All carry a taste receptor gene similar to T2R, which they named T2R1. The researchers then implanted the T2R1 genes from two of the shark species into human kidney cells in the laboratory, and then exposed them to 94 bitter substances that humans can perceive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results showed that 7 bitter substances activated the bitter taste receptors of two species of sharks, and the other 4 substances only activated the bitter taste receptors of one shark, which means that these sharks can also taste human food. Perceived bitter substances such as colchicine or bile acids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The discovery suggests the ability to perceive bitter tastes may be older than previously thought, possibly before cartilaginous fishes and bony vertebrates diverged from a common ancestor nearly 500 million years ago, the researchers said. has evolved. Teleost vertebrates continue to evolve a variety of bitter taste receptor genes. Although the researchers detected only one T2R1 gene in these cartilaginous fish genomes, this means it may be the original form of the bitter taste receptor gene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[台湾观众可能没有我们这么了解侯孝贤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeK nCcAnsCEY3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;240307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Single episode introduction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hello everyone, welcome to A Little Culture. I am the anchor of this issue, Yu Yaqin. Recently, the famous director Hou Hsiao-hsien has to bid farewell to the film industry due to health reasons. For this reason, today I invited Teacher Wang Yinjie from the China Academy of Art and my colleague Teacher Li Heng to talk about this great fan of Chinese films. A very important film master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excerpts of golden verses&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He lives in southern Taiwan, which is very different from Taipei in our impression. It has more rural character. This rural character is also the way Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some actors have said that he doesn’t even have a script. He is not a person who particularly likes to coordinate actors. A director who is very standard in the film industry, very sophisticated and precise. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He provides a very valuable preservation of personal experience and personal memory for the narration of film history. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1700&quot; height=&quot;1132&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #993300;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Guests in this issue]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Yaqin, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Heng, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yinjie, Associate Professor, School of Film, China Academy of Art&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #993300;&quot;>;[Listening Tips]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:58 Director Hou Hsiao-hsien’s life and works&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 04:17 Countryside is Hou Hsiao-hsien’s way of looking at the world&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 05:22&amp;nbsp;《 &quot;Son&#39;s Big Doll&quot; established many of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s aesthetic styles&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 09:23&amp;nbsp;After 2000, Hou Hsiao-hsien moved towards more international cooperation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 11:08&amp;nbsp;Jia Zhangke is I came into contact with Hou Hsiao-hsien from &quot;City of Sadness&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 14:33 Hou Hsiao-hsien is not a standardized director in the film industry&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 17:52 Hou Hsiao-hsien has always been photographing individuals with a faint light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 19:57 Taiwanese audiences may not know Hou Hsiao-hsien as well as we do&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 23:14&amp;nbsp;Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films have many long shots and do not pursue a lot of drama&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;► 26:19 The emotions of the characters in Hou’s films are like hearing thunder in silence&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 32:47 Hou Hsiao-hsien holds a very important position in the hearts of a generation of movie fans&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 37: 15 A kind of misalignment: The life needs of young people in Taiwan do not come from directors such as Hou Hsiao-hsien&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 41:11 We need to trust the interpretation of the world by creators of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s generation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 43:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at everyone around him in a level-headed manner&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 45:06 The use of dialect is a characteristic of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 47:05 Recommended by Wang Yinjie Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Sad City&quot; and &quot;Flowers of Shanghai&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 53:49 Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Love in the Wind&quot; and &quot;The Assassin Nie Yinniang&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;► 55:53 Three movies recommended by Li Heng: &quot;Once Upon a Time in Childhood&quot;, &quot;Goodbye South Country, South Country&quot; and &quot;Dream Life&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 58:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s masterpiece is so dazzling that it... The light of urban youth-themed works overshadowed&lt;br>;► 01:01:52 Director Hou’s films strive for a certain authenticity of the atmosphere of that era&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:06:30 When there are many things that cannot be said Whenever possible, literature is used as a metaphor and movies are used to present it&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:08:25 Hou Hsiao-hsien provides a way of retaining personal experience and memory in narrating film history&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:11 :14 Use southern aesthetics to summarize Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:16:09 Hou Hsiao-hsien influenced young directors from Taiwan, China’s sixth-generation directors, Hirokazu Kore-eda, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Audio Clip/Shao Ruier&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #999999;&quot;>;Operation Promotion/Shao Ruier, Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>