<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[西方军火商为何纷纷将亚洲总部迁至日本？丨智库视点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258557]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/13/X9yJZc2fwfFQxD6fjp3XeeU0ncr0aG0plnBPa7b4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1140&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/X9yJZc2fwfFQxD6fjp3XeeU 0ncr0aG0plnBPa7b4. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254030&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 11, 2023, according to People&#39;s Daily Online, many large Western weapons suppliers recently announced that they would move their Asian headquarters to Japan. Japan has also high-profilely promoted its equipment in the United States and its allies. The role of logistics support. Foreign media said that the measures taken by Western military industrial groups are almost synchronized with the introduction of Japan&#39;s defense budget for the next five years, and they intend to prepare in advance within the framework of a quasi-alliance and cut the budget &quot;cake&quot; to the maximum extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, British Aerospace Systems has established close ties with Japan and plans to move its Asia-Pacific headquarters from Malaysia to Japan within the year to prepare to supply Patriot PAC-3 missile defense systems to Japan. France&#39;s Thales will cooperate with Japan&#39;s Mitsubishi Heavy Industries to develop and produce equipment such as mine detectors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the combined influence of commercial and political factors, Japan suddenly became a &quot;hot potato&quot; sought after by arms dealers in the United States, Britain and France. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent times, the United States has frequently held offensive and defensive exercises with Japan, South Korea, and Australia, which has made the situation on the Korean Peninsula, Taiwan Strait, and South China Sea tense in Northeast Asia. Western arms dealers have a keen sense of smell. On the one hand, they are concerned about changes in the geopolitical situation, and on the other hand, they also fancy the business opportunities brought by Japan&#39;s substantial increase in defense spending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some analysts believe that as tensions in Northeast Asia escalate and Japan increases its defense spending, the changes made by these arms giants in order to cooperate with Japan&#39;s major adjustments to its defense strategy indicate that Japan hopes to further achieve cooperation with the United States and Europe. &quot;Military binding&quot; supports its ambition to expand its military power. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Opportunity to take advantage of&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Western arms dealers have moved their Asia-Pacific headquarters to Japan, selling arms nearby, and launching &quot;face-to-face&quot; in-depth cooperation with Japan , a win-win situation can be achieved. From a deeper analysis, this is the reason why the United States uses Japan and Japan hopes to &quot;borrow ships to go to sea.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the Biden administration has established many &quot;small circles&quot; in the hope of using, controlling and arming allies. Through the research and development of various advanced weapons and equipment, frequent military exercises with deterrence and actual combat significance, fighting &quot;proxy wars&quot;, testing the effectiveness of weapons and equipment and strategies and tactics, making huge fortunes by promoting arms, creating conflicts and conflicts, undermining regional stability, and maintaining it. In the global hegemonic position, it achieves the goal of &quot;killing many birds with one stone&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with Japan, South Korea, Australia, and the Philippines do not have advantages in military and technology. The United States&#39; selection and use of Japan is also &quot;a no-brainer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the Korean War and the Vietnam War, Western arms dealers had a history of moving their Asian defense contractor headquarters to Japan, allowing Japan to reap the benefits of its rapid economic rise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the outbreak of the Vietnam War, Japan&#39;s heavy industry restarted. As Japan is the rear area for US military war supplies, a large number of orders for military supplies continue to fall on Japan&#39;s military production lines. Mitsubishi Heavy Industries is a long-established military industrial enterprise of Japanese manufacturers. It has a complete production line of F-4 fighter jets. The F-4 Phantom fighter jets it produces have played a huge role as the main fighter aircraft of the U.S. Navy and Air Force, helping the U.S. military win 277 wars. The victory helped the US military save some face in the Vietnam battlefield. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the United States still wants to use Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the end of the Cold War, European arms dealers basically did not develop much. Therefore, European countries are also optimistic about Japan&#39;s funds and technology. At the same time, Japan also hopes to develop weapons and equipment instead of just relying on the United States. Before this, it was difficult for the United States to allow Japan to extend its olive branch to other countries in the research and development of weapons and equipment, especially heavy weapons and equipment. Now, the United States is opening up and hopes to arm Japan and allow Japan to provide assistance to the United States in the Western Pacific. assume more defensive obligations. Therefore, after the United States gave the green light, Japan and European countries moved forward in cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Japan’s security strategy has shifted from self-defense to auxiliary offense. At the end of 2022, Japan adjusted its security strategy. From the so-called self-defense in the past to the current auxiliary offense, it is expanding its military preparations in all aspects. Whether it is technology, funding, or procurement, Japan&#39;s own military production capacity alone is obviously not enough. . Therefore, Japan&#39;s turning its attention to European countries also reflects changes in its security strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“There is money to be made”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On August 27, 2023, “Nikkei Asia” reported that “the world’s largest defense contractors Businesses are transferring their business operations in Asia to Japan, because in the face of the deteriorating security situation in East Asia, Japan is preparing to significantly increase defense expenses.&quot; Japan&#39;s &quot;business&quot; with Western arms dealers is conducive to dividing the cake and achieving strong alliances. , each takes what he needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From fiscal year 2023 to 2027, Japan’s total defense budget will reach 43 trillion yen, 1.6 times that of the previous five years. The latest defense budget finalized by the Japanese Ministry of Defense for 2024 has reached 7.7 trillion yen, equivalent to more than 380 billion yuan, once again setting a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, 900 billion yen will be used to purchase various ammunition and weapons and equipment, including new ship-to-air missiles and long-range cruise missiles. For example: the mass production costs of the &quot;performance-enhanced version&quot; of the Ground Self-Defense Force&#39;s Type 12 land-based anti-ship missile with a range extending to about 1,000 kilometers, and the production costs of &quot;high-speed gliding missiles&quot; used to defend islands such as the Southwest Islands. In addition, there are 64 billion yen for a new generation fighter aircraft project jointly carried out by Britain, Japan and Italy, and 75 billion yen for a new anti-missile interceptor jointly developed by the United States and Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Japan held the largest international defense exhibition, attracting more than 250 arms companies from more than 60 countries and regions. European and American companies participating in the exhibition have shown great interest in the Japanese market. The Japanese government has planned to allocate more than 200 billion yen to purchase approximately 400 Tomahawk cruise missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan plans to deploy two Aegis system carrier ships by 2028, establish a new permanent &quot;unified headquarters&quot; in Tokyo Ichigaya, and uniformly command the three self-defense forces of land, sea and air; purchase long-range missiles and improve the Aegis system Carrier ships; develop new fields such as drones, space and the Internet, and ammunition support to improve sustained combat capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Kishida government&#39;s sharp increase in defense expenses has allowed European and American arms dealers to smell business opportunities. Behind the increase in Japan&#39;s military expenditures, it reflects that Japan and the United States have cooperated more frequently at the strategic and tactical levels in recent years. This is reflected in the fact that the US-Japan alliance is undergoing subtle and profound changes. The alliance system has gradually changed from the past &quot;American master and Japanese slave&quot;. Shifting to &quot;US-Japan coordination&quot; means that the United States needs Japan to step up to the forefront in a series of regional disputes, including regional hotspot issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relocation of Western arms dealers to Japan may further fuel Japan&#39;s maritime ambitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan has proposed that it should shift from the past &quot;marine defense governance&quot; to &quot;marine defense governance&quot;. Japan&#39;s ambition to become a maritime power is fully reflected in each phase of the basic marine plan. In addition, Japan plans to launch a series of maritime security assistance and increase strategic attention to Indo-Pacific countries, which will also bring certain complexity to the regional situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan’s ambition has always been demonstrated. Today, Japan plans to build the so-called largest warship after World War II - a modern version of the &quot;Yamato&quot; ship, which is 1.7 times the size of the U.S. Burke destroyer and exceeds the average tonnage of U.S. combat ships in terms of displacement and comprehensive combat power. This also shows that Japan can achieve great progress and development in its ocean strategy and offensive strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of weapons and equipment configuration, the United States’ Standard 6 (SM-6) air defense missiles will be used on this ship, and Japan’s air defense and anti-missile capabilities will be further improved. If the &quot;Yamato&quot; ship is equipped with a ground-attack version of the Type 12 anti-ship missile, its range can reach 1,000 kilometers. Japan&#39;s future maritime platforms will have powerful ground attack capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan’s military spending is rising and it wants to expand its military preparations. Western arms dealers see business opportunities and flock to them. Fundamentally speaking, this will allow the United States to better utilize and control Japan with the help of arms dealers and maintain the United States in the &quot;Indo-Pacific&quot; regional” and even global hegemony. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Japan&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Arms Upgrading&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Japan has introduced the core business of the Western military industry and is also trying to intentionally introduce Western technology into its own arms production chain. middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 28, the Japan Defense Equipment Agency issued the &quot;Defense Technology Guidelines 2023&quot;, reaffirming the strategy of &quot;building a nation through scientific and technological innovation&quot;, focusing on strengthening defense capabilities and developing weapons and equipment that are ahead of other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan, within 5 to 10 years, Japan will produce weapons directly related to future combat methods, and after 10 years, it will realize the equipment of important technologies. Japan has listed 12 key technologies such as unmanned technology, new energy, new materials, instant communications and data processing as pillar technologies for the future defense industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Japanese military-industrial complex giant said that the entry of Western arms companies will increase the number of orders from small and medium-sized parts suppliers. There are currently 1,100 companies engaged in the production of fighter jet parts, 1,300 companies engaged in the production of tank parts, and 830 companies engaged in the production of warship parts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan has reached an agreement with the United Kingdom and Italy to jointly develop sixth-generation fighter aircraft, and recently jointly developed high-performance missiles with the United States for intercepting hypersonic weapons. Companies established in the UK, France, Italy and other countries plan to increase the number of employees and will mainly recruit local Japanese personnel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The American L3 Harris Technology Company is an aerospace company in the United States. It has begun negotiations with the Japanese Ministry of Defense on cooperation in drones and other fields, which provides a favorable opportunity for Japan to improve its military production capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the support of European and American arms dealers, Japan follows or coordinates with the United States and the West. During this sensitive period, Japan&#39;s defense budget is also increasing year by year. If this continues, Japan will fall into an endless cycle of arms race, which will bring serious danger to the regional situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another situation is that in order to make money, Western arms dealers may use the power of capital to bribe Japanese media, add fuel to the flames, and deliberately create conflicts. Western arms dealers have moved their Asian headquarters to Japan to cooperate with Japan in military research and development and sales. The Japanese government claims that the purchase of weapons and ammunition is a &quot;defensive measure.&quot; If the United States, the West and Japan intervene in hot geopolitical issues through arms exports, it will provoke conflicts and confrontations among relevant countries and make the situation in the Asia-Pacific region even more tense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, six European and American arms dealers have moved to Japan and signed an agreement to &quot;carry out large-scale arms modifications in Japan&quot;. They are suspected of shifting arms to prepare for war, making it easier for Japan to obtain offensive weapons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan plans to rely on its military cooperation with the United States to gradually realize its so-called military ambitions in the context of great power competition and the Indo-Pacific strategy. Once the devil of militarism is released from its cage, it will have , the impact on the world will further increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the United States openly and covertly supports Japan to increase its defense budget. Japan&#39;s past &quot;exclusive defense&quot; has turned to &quot;active defense&quot; and it emphasizes the ability to attack enemy bases. The United States has adopted an attitude of encouragement and even support. Under this general premise, it is possible that the regional arms race will become more and more unfavorable, which is also caused by the United States and Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一观众从三楼看展坠亡，广东美术馆通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258581]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 19:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Situation Briefing&lt;/strong>;&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 8, Ms. Yang, a visitor, visited the Guangdong Museum of Art and accidentally fell from Exhibition Hall 12 on the third floor of our museum to Exhibition Hall 6 on the second floor at around 11:50. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident, our library immediately activated the emergency plan and quickly dialed 120 emergency hotline and 110 police hotline. At around 12 o&#39;clock, emergency personnel arrived at the scene for rescue. At around 12:25, Ms. Yang unfortunately passed away after rescue efforts failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By accessing the on-site surveillance video, listening to the statements of eyewitnesses and surveying the scene of the incident, it was found that before the incident, the spectator was holding a SLR camera, crossed the warning protection rope set up in Hall 12, and fell from the guardrail to 2 In the No. 6 exhibition hall of the building, there were shoe prints left on the guardrail platform. It was initially determined that the audience had an accident while looking for a shooting angle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our museum is deeply saddened and sorry for the unfortunate death of Ms. Yang, and expresses deep condolences to her family. Next, our library will continue to fully cooperate with the public security organs and the family members of the deceased in the investigation and aftermath. At the same time, we will further strengthen safety management and actively perform our duties as public cultural venues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;span>;Guangdong Museum of Art&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>; October 13, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[银行经营策略转向：贷款倾向制造业，“商投行”一体化加速]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258550]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When the real estate and related industries are sluggish or even risky, commercial banks facing interest rate pressure, How to adjust your own business strategy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By comparing the mid-term and annual report data of 20 listed banks vertically and horizontally in the past three years, and combined with the relevant information disclosed in their 2023 interim results conference and exchange meetings, a researcher at the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center The study found that in recent years, 20 commercial banks have been intensively adjusting their business strategies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of credit investment, 20 commercial banks are gradually shifting from leasing and real estate to the real economy, focusing on manufacturing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Investment business has become the focus of the investment business of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks in recent years, and has achieved certain results. The integrated development strategy of &quot;commercial and investment banking&quot; is progressing steadily, and the benefits of investment-loan linkage are gradually reflected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strategic &quot;digital transformation&quot; of commercial banks has begun to shift from &quot;quantitative growth&quot; to &quot;qualitative improvement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Loans tend to be in the manufacturing and technology industries&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center sorted out the 2023 interim results conferences, 2023 interim results conferences of 20 commercial banks The interim report and 2022 annual report found that 20 commercial banks all mentioned in the 2022 annual report the strategy of benefiting the real economy and providing financial support for manufacturing and national key areas. This strategy was emphasized again in the 2023 interim reports of each bank: each bank has proposed the goal of continuing to improve the quality and efficiency of serving the real economy in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the analysis of the distribution of corporate loan industries disclosed by 20 commercial banks in the 2022 interim report and the 2023 interim report, the above strategies mentioned by each bank in the 2022 annual report have achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The year-on-year growth rates of corporate loan balances in the national key strategic fields of manufacturing and technology services were 25.02% and 64.35% respectively. Judging from the absolute value of corporate loan balances, in the first half of 2023, the loan balance of manufacturing companies in 20 commercial banks reached 15.86 trillion yuan, becoming the industry with the highest corporate loan balance, surpassing companies in the leasing and business services industry with 15.35 trillion yuan. Loan balance. The industry with the highest corporate loan balance in the first half of 2022 is the leasing and business services industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that within one year, the credit structure of commercial banks has changed from the original &quot;three pillars&quot; of leasing, real estate and manufacturing to a model dominated by manufacturing. This also echoes China’s current economic form in which the old triangular cycle of “real estate, infrastructure, and finance” is moving to the new triangular cycle of “technology, industry, and finance.” At the same time, this also reflects the current new phenomenon of bank funds flowing into the real economy and supporting the development of manufacturing, scientific research and technical service industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/N9oJ5kvONawBpMQ3lLRpiKdDJJ8PVPk9WsUhQisL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height= &quot;1352&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/N9oJ5kvONawBpMQ3lLRpiKdDJJ8PVPk9WsUhQisL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main force that tilts credit towards the manufacturing industry is There are five major state-owned banks: industry, agriculture, China, construction, and diplomatic relations. In the first half of 2023, the total loan balance of manufacturing companies from the five major state-owned banks was 10.84 trillion yuan, accounting for 68.36% of the total loan balance of manufacturing companies from 20 banks. The three joint-stock banks Industrial Bank, China Merchants Bank and Shanghai Pudong Development Bank followed the five major state-owned banks with loan balances of manufacturing companies of 669.412 billion yuan, 549.976 billion yuan and 542.672 billion yuan respectively, higher than the Postal Savings Bank&#39;s manufacturing company loans of 495.732 billion yuan. Corporate loan balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center also found that loans to companies in the scientific research and technical service industries have gradually become areas of concern for joint-stock banks and city commercial banks, which may be related to the misaligned competition strategy of state-owned banks. Among them, state-owned banks and some joint-stock banks did not disclose this balance. Among the city commercial banks, Bank of Shanghai did not disclose this balance in its 2022 interim report. However, from the 2022 annual report to the 2023 interim report, the bank disclosed it. the balance of this loan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In absolute terms, in the first half of 2023, Industrial Bank and Shanghai Pudong Development Bank had the highest balances, at 36.536 billion yuan and 32.944 billion yuan respectively. In terms of year-on-year growth rates, Bank of Nanjing and Bank of Beijing have the highest year-on-year growth rates, 92.67% and 83.11% respectively. It can be seen that joint-stock banks are the main lenders in this industry, while city commercial banks are gradually paying more and more attention to this field. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Investment business&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;becomes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;an important growth point&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As the loan business turns, 20 The bank is developing its investment banking business, financial market business and “commercial investment banking” integration strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center sorted out the 2023 interim reports of 20 banks, their interim results conferences and investor exchange meetings and found that most banks mentioned strengthening investment banking business and financial markets. sector and build an integrated development strategy of “commercial and investment banking”. From the analysis of the bank&#39;s revenue structure and asset structure in recent years, this strategy has achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For financial investment business, the three indicators of investment income, net income from changes in fair value and net exchange income are particularly important, and the three indicators are highly correlated. In order to explore the actual benefits of various banks&#39; strengthening financial investment business strategies, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center conducted statistics on the sum of the above three indicators as a proportion of revenue for 20 banks in the past three years. Statistics show that, regardless of whether it is a state-owned bank, a joint-stock bank or a city commercial bank, the ratio is on the rise, and the upward trend is the most obvious for city commercial banks. With traditional credit business unable to take advantage, city commercial banks are using investment business as a breakthrough point to expand their balance sheets. Take the Bank of Nanjing, which was shortlisted for China&#39;s systemically important banks for the first time on September 22, 2023, as an example. In the first half of 2023, the bank&#39;s three income indicators accounted for 32.15% of its revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/Ofc6345KnFX3DOnrAT9TLvvgUBlY7MNjsr8GXJAv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;796&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/Ofc6345KnFX3DOnrAT9TLvvgUBlY7MNjsr8GXJAv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/HV5COF9Saq3kPHkt94b31busBbhVHgCZjn2Wv1V6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height=&quot;1852&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/13/HV5COF9Saq3kPHkt94b31busBbhVHgCZjn2Wv1V6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the above three income indicators are highly correlated with trading financial assets. In recent years, the proportion of trading financial assets to total assets of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks has also shown a growth trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/RKL1YucI0TOTVGgvItL317nTxA6jNIjeJJ9bYVcj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;866&quot; height= &quot;796&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/RKL1YucI0TOTVGgvItL317nTxA6jNIjeJJ9bYVcj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Feng Qingchao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the 2023 Interim Report of Bank of Nanjing, 2022 According to data from the interim report, 2022 annual report, 2021 annual report and 2020 annual report, at the end of June 2023, the end of December 2022 and the end of December 2021, the year-on-year growth rates of its trading financial assets were 40.32%, 39.28% and 77.41%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to conduct an in-depth analysis of the composition of each bank’s investment business, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center sorted out the trading transactions disclosed in the 2023 interim reports of the five banks with the highest three income ratios among the 20 banks. Financial asset data. According to statistics, the largest trading financial assets of these banks are funds, followed by bonds or asset management trust plans. The funds invested by commercial banks are generally bond funds and currency funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By studying the types of bond funds invested by banks, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that some banks’ bond investment strategies are to purchase fixed-term bond funds issued by the bank’s fund management subsidiaries. This strategy may have the effect of reducing bond investment costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take Industrial Bank as an example. According to the 2023 interim report disclosed by the fund products issued by Industrial Fund, the bank holds the Industrial Jiarong one-year regular open bond-type initiative issued by its subsidiary Industrial Fund Management Co., Ltd. The shares of securities investment funds and Industrial Jiafu one-year regular open bond-type sponsored securities investment funds are 99.87% and 99.88% respectively. According to Article 2 of the &quot;Notice of the Ministry of Finance and the State Administration of Taxation on Certain Preferential Policies for Enterprise Income Tax&quot;, the income obtained by securities investment funds from the securities market includes income from price differences from buying and selling stocks and bonds, dividends and bonus income from equity, and income from bonds. Interest income and other income are not subject to corporate income tax for the time being. That is to say, compared with direct investment in financial bonds, banks can be exempted from paying 25% income tax if they invest indirectly in financial bonds through fixed-term debt funds, thus reducing investment costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the debt investment subjects of direct investment bonds, 10 of the 12 commercial banks (only 12 of the 20 commercial banks disclosed this data in their 2023 interim reports) maintained year-on-year growth increase. Among them, the two banks with year-on-year decreases were Bank of Nanjing and Ping An Bank. Although the amount of debt investment of these two banks decreased by 11.49% and 1.96% year-on-year, their trading financial assets increased by 40.32% and 17.81% year-on-year, and the proportion of funds and bonds among their trading financial assets was relatively high. The increase in the total amount of bonds in the debt base or trading financial assets is sufficient to cover the year-on-year decrease in the bond investment account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In general, whether it is direct investment in bonds or indirect investment in bond funds, the financial investment business targets of various banks are mainly bonds. Judging from the overall scale and income level, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks are indeed still in the established strategy of strengthening investment business, and this strategy has also achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investment banking business of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks has also improved in the past two years. Take Industrial Bank and Bank of Nanjing as examples. According to the 2022 bond underwriting rankings of the wind database, Industrial Bank ranks 6th with a total underwriting amount of 947.746 billion yuan. The top five are Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Agricultural Bank of China and Bank of Communications. State-owned banks. Bank of Nanjing ranked 14th with 284.505 billion yuan. As of September 27, 2023, the 2023 bond underwriting rankings of the wind database show that Industrial Bank ranked fifth with a total underwriting amount of 798.374 billion yuan, surpassing Bank of Communications. Bank of Nanjing moved up one place to 13th place with a total underwriting amount of 273.62 billion yuan. Therefore, judging from the changes in the amount and ranking of the above two banks, the bond underwriting strength of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks has indeed improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Analysis of the bank&#39;s bond underwriting business found that the bank&#39;s investment banking business strategy and credit business strategy are similar, and the overall flow of funds shows the flow of funds to national key areas such as science and technology innovation and green, achieving the effect of investment and loan linkage. Take Industrial Bank as an example. According to the bank&#39;s 2023 interim report, the scale of its underwriting of debt financing instruments for green non-financial enterprises reached 13.72 billion yuan, ranking first among joint-stock banks, and it has launched its first science and technology REITs business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of income, investment business is a more important growth point for various banks. Each bank may achieve the goal of stable balance sheet expansion through the strategy of continuing to increase the proportion of this business. However, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that the above three income indicators are all related to trading financial assets, and the increase in trading financial assets will directly lead to an increase in risk-weighted assets, thereby reducing the core tier one capital adequacy ratio. Therefore, there is limited room to increase income through investment business. And&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/257314?source=147&amp;amp;source_1=238&quot;>;&lt;u>;&quot;The net profits of 20 banks account for more than 1/3 of A-shares,&quot; Wang&#39;s &quot;Fighting against the Increasing Differentiation of Interest Margin Pressure&quot; also mentioned that &quot;among the joint-stock banks, CITIC, Hua Xia and Zheshang Bank, their core tier one capital adequacy ratios are approaching regulatory red lines.&quot; Therefore, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center suggested that while vigorously developing investment-loan linkage strategies, banks should also pay attention to the tier-1 capital adequacy ratio and avoid blindly expanding their balance sheets, which could lead to regulatory red lines. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Abandon quantitative growth&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Digital transformation&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Transform into quality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;While the linkage effect of investment and lending has emerged, the attitudes of various banks towards financial technology have changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sorting out the 2023 interim reports, interim results conferences and financial technology job recruitment information of 20 banks, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that in terms of digital transformation strategies, compared with previous years, funding And with the increase in human investment, all industries will pay more attention to quality presentation in 2023. According to China Financial News Network, judging from the recruitment situation in the autumn of 2023, the financial technology positions of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Bank of China and Agricultural Bank of China have experienced a &quot;reduction in recruitment&quot; for the first time. According to data from the 2022 annual reports of the four major state-owned banks, the four banks of &quot;Industry, Agriculture, China, and Construction&quot; each have more than 10,000 technology employees, and the number of employees in financial technology positions has approached &quot;saturation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some banks’ capital investment in the financial technology field is also not as strong as in previous years. Among the 20 banks, only China Merchants Bank and Everbright Bank disclosed information technology investment data in the 2023 interim report, which were 5.206 billion yuan and 2.043 billion yuan respectively, a year-on-year decrease of 2.87% and 4.44%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in terms of quality improvement, various banks have provided many specific cases on the effectiveness of digital transformation. For example, ICBC completed the feasibility assessment of the application of quantum technology in scenarios such as bond investment portfolios and option pricing based on quantum simulators; China Merchants Bank used models to automatically review loans, and &quot;Zhaoqidai&quot; realized the entire process of corporate loans online, and customers The fastest time from application to loan disbursement is 0.5 working days; Ningbo Bank takes advantage of WeChat banking in reaching customers and product promotion, enriching voice, video and other service methods to provide customers with a more efficient and simpler financial service experience business process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can also be found through vertical quantitative comparison that compared with 2022, various banks have achieved more actual results in the field of financial technology and digital transformation. For example, as of the end of June 2023, ICBC has deepened the construction of an enterprise-level corporate digital operation and management platform, and the platform has reached more than 1.6 million customers; China Merchants Bank&#39;s &quot;AI Tips&quot; has served 11.7288 million users, a year-on-year increase of 140.84%; Bank of Beijing The &quot;Intelligent Strategy&quot; retail digital operation system has launched more than 1,200 strategies, reaching more than 170 million customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Through quantitative horizontal comparison, it can be seen that ICBC’s digital transformation and technological capabilities are the best among the 20 banks. In terms of financial technology, as of the end of June 2023, ICBC had 1,878 new public patents, and the cumulative number of patent authorizations was 2,941, ranking first among its peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The effects of technologies in various industries empowering the field of risk control are also more significant than before. Take the digitally empowered inclusive finance risk control system disclosed in ICBC’s 2023 interim report as an example. The report describes in detail the entire process of digital access, intelligent risk control, and online and offline cross-validation. Its non-performing rate has increased year-on-year. The decline also demonstrates the benefits of digital transformation. Among them, &lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/257314?source=147&amp;amp;source_1=238&quot;>;&lt;u>;&quot;The net profits of 20 banks account for more than 1/3 of A-shares,&quot; &quot;Profit King&quot; Fights Increasing Differentiation Pressure on Interest Margins&quot; &lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>; has stated that &quot;in the first half of 2023, the non-performing loan ratios of 20 banks have almost all declined, and only Ping An Bank&#39;s non-performing loan ratio has increased. 1 BP.&quot; Bank of Beijing, whose non-performing ratio has dropped by 30 BP year-on-year, even emphasized the construction of a unified risk control platform in the digital transformation section of its official report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the above analysis that technology-enabled risk control, mobile banking and technology-enhanced investment strategies have achieved certain results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the road to digital transformation is still long. Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center recently found through actual measurements of different bank counter services and surveys of practitioners in different industries that most bank counter services still take a long time to process. Although robots and intelligent counters are placed at the entrance of every bank, in terms of customer experience, the robots are more like decorations, and the services that the intelligent counters can handle are also quite limited. The business process at the manual counter is quite complicated, and the waiting time for bank staff to operate is also long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that compared to the past, the current application of information technology in online business has been more extensive and is supported by actual data. If banks can increase the application of technology in the field of over-the-counter services, such as moving more over-the-counter services online, it may be able to reduce labor costs to a great extent and improve efficiency at the same time. In fact, some banks are already trying to take this step. Postal Savings Bank disclosed in its 2023 interim report that it is exploring digital operations and innovatively launching a &quot;cloud cabinet&quot; intensive operation model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子相亲后被诬强奸，五年方还清白：强加于己的巨大冤屈如何洗刷？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258513]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a retrial verdict has brought an old news back into public opinion. According to &quot;Dafeng News&quot;, Di, a native of Luannan, Hebei, who had been sentenced to three years in prison for rape, finally waited for a fair verdict from the court on October 10, 2023: The Tangshan Intermediate People&#39;s Court ruled that &quot;the facts are unclear and the evidence is insufficient.&quot; &quot;The original verdict was revoked and Xiao Di was found not guilty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The timeline of this case is not complicated. On February 22, 2018, a dating agency in Luannan County introduced a woman to Di. After the two met, &quot;both were quite satisfied.&quot; That night, Di invited the woman and Wang, the owner of the dating agency, to dinner. After dinner, Di drove the woman in question and invited her out to play. They had a &quot;very good chat&quot; and had sex in the car. Afterwards, Di drove the woman back to the dating agency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The owner of the dating agency called Di that night and said, &quot;The woman no longer wanted to have sex after having sex&quot; and &quot;asked Di to compensate the woman with tens of thousands of yuan.&quot; In desperation, Di had no choice but to return to the dating agency and work with the boss to find the woman involved to coordinate, but they did not reach an agreement on the &quot;compensation&quot;. On the second day after the incident, Wang took two people to Di&#39;s home and formally made a &quot;compensation request&quot; of 20,000 yuan. Di thought Wang was extorting money and was unwilling to accept it. Wang called the police that day. In the next few days, Di gave Wang several thousand yuan and received the assurance from the other party that &quot;it will be fine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 1, a week after the incident, Di was detained on suspicion of rape and arrested 12 days later. On June 1, 2018, the Luannan County Procuratorate prosecuted Di for rape. On December 29 of the same year, Di was sentenced to three years in prison for rape, and his second-instance appeal was also rejected. During his sentence, Di insisted on not pleading guilty and asked to appeal. He waited until February 28, 2021, to be released after serving his sentence. After being released from prison, Di requested a retrial. After more than two years of judicial proceedings, he finally won a not guilty verdict recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This case has been delayed for five years. After many twists and turns, there are still many unanswered questions about the case. A retrial should not be the end of this case. Although the parties involved have been avenged, there are still many aspects of this case that deserve further questioning and analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the owner of the dating agency and the woman involved are suspected of extortion and should be held legally accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you examine the case carefully, it is not difficult to see the absurdity of the &quot;rape&quot; charge. I would like to ask, if &quot;rape&quot; really exists, can &quot;paying 20,000 yuan&quot; be exchanged for not calling the police? How is this different from prostitution? The woman involved “no longer wanted to have sex after having sex.” Could it be that the so-called “consent” could be revoked at any time afterwards? If this is the case, the evidentiary standards for rape cases handled by public prosecutors and prosecutors are too low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the client is not found guilty of rape, the behavior of the dating agency owner is an out-and-out extortion, and there are both completed and attempted circumstances. According to Article 1 of the &quot;Interpretation on Several Issues Concerning the Application of Laws in Handling Criminal Cases of Extortion&quot; promulgated by the two high authorities on April 23, 2013, extortion of public and private property worth more than 2,000 yuan to 5,000 yuan should be deemed as Article 274 of the Criminal Law The specified &quot;amount is relatively large&quot;. According to the standards of Hebei Province&#39;s two highs, the starting point for &quot;larger amounts&quot; is 3,000 yuan.本案中，婚介所老板敲诈既遂的金额有“数千元”，未遂的是两万元，完全符合“数额较大”的标准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，本案中的婚介所老板与当事女子还涉嫌诬告陷害罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比起近年来“网络小作文”的舆论攻势，本案中的诬告方手法可谓简单粗暴，直接向公安机关报了案。从结果来看，诬告陷害造成当事人邸某身陷囹圄三年之久，而且耗费大量时间精力才讨回了公道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本案当事人的遭遇无疑要比那些“网络小作文受害者”更惨。既然诬告已造成了让他蒙冤入狱的严重后果，那么邸某就更有理由得到相应的司法救济。刑法第243条规定，捏造事实诬告陷害他人，意图使他人受刑事追究，情节严重的，构成诬告陷害罪。情节严重的，处三年以下有期徒刑、拘役或者管制；造成严重后果的，处三年以上十年以下有期徒刑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当事人的无罪判决只是他寻求司法救济的起点，而不应该是到此为止的终点。邸某有权向法院提起刑事自诉，要求公权力追究婚介所老板与王某的刑事责任，并承担附带的民事赔偿义务，救济自己五年以来蒙受的沉重损失，洗雪被强加于己的巨大冤屈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其三，婚介所与当事女子或存在“仙人跳”、组织诈骗的重大嫌疑，这同样是警方理应深入调查的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本案中，婚介所与当事女子呈现出一副“互为配合，打法纯熟”的态势。当事女子言行前后不一，婚介所老板为“中间商”与当事人谈“补偿”。结合婚介所老板“前恭后倨”的态度，本案更是蒙上诈骗案的层层疑云，不能排除婚介所老板与当事女子串通作案的嫌疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果串通作案的嫌疑成立的话，那么本案就堪称一桩“婚介诈骗”，手法上比以往“只求赚钱”的婚托更为阴狠恶劣，较之“谋分财产”的婚骗则更粗暴直接，可以算作披着婚介外衣的“仙人跳诈骗”，涉嫌构成诈骗罪。刑法第266条规定，诈骗公私财物，数额较大的，处三年以下有期徒刑、拘役或者管制，并处或者单处罚金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而从公共利益出发，本案中的婚介所老板与当事女子也理应接受法律的严惩。如果本案的结果仅仅是一个邸某无罪而两人不受惩罚的话，那就无异于是对类似敲诈勒索与诬告陷害行为的制度激励，造成“反正敲诈与诬告不成也不会承担责任”的局面，这显然不利于遏制类似违法犯罪行为，置更多的潜在受害者于险境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，本案当事人邸某当然有理由寻求国家赔偿、补偿蒙冤入狱的各项损失，同时对婚介所老板与当事女子发起刑事自诉，追究他们的各项刑事责任，要求他们履行附带的民事赔偿义务，为自己讨回公道。有关部门也有必要介入，深入调查婚介所老板与当事女子实施团伙诈骗的嫌疑，震慑类似的幸进之徒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[猫狗鸟蛇……每年五十多万只动物命丧公路]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258541]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/rdNvCtUMWcYoDaCM7cWfhM9jc5aX1oAK7AVNT30h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;870&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/rdNvCtUMWcYoDaCM7cWfhM9jc5aX1oAK7AVNT30h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;被路杀的猫。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（课题组供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;浑身乌黑嘴巴黄色的乌鸫（dōng）是城市里常见的鸟儿，它们善于模仿其他鸟叫声，喜欢在树林中活动。道路两旁的行道树和灌木丛，为乌鸫提供了理想的栖息地，却也暗藏致命风险。南京大学生命科学学院教授李忠秋在驾车时，就曾数次遭遇突然窜出的乌鸫，差一点成为“凶手”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;动物与车辆相撞致死事故被称为“路杀”。如今，无论在人迹罕至的保护区还是车流如织的城市，车轮取代了猎枪，成为动物面临的主要威胁之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;命丧公路的动物数量超乎想象。由李忠秋担任通讯作者的研究论文近日在学术期刊PeerJ发表：南京每年可能有57万余只鸟类和兽类遭遇路杀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前国内鲜少有针对路杀的系统性研究，李忠秋团队的研究评估了南京这一个大型城市的路杀本底数据。“路杀是非常严峻的威胁，但无论学界和公众，认知都不足。”李忠秋说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;猫、狗、乌鸫、麻雀风险最高&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;我国公路总里程已达528万公里，可绕地球一百多圈。四通八达的交通路网，为人类生活提供了便利，却成为不少野生动物的天堑，每次穿越马路，都仿佛经历生死之旅。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学术研究显示，美国每年有3.4亿只鸟死于路杀，英国每年约有33.5万只刺猬命丧公路，巴西每年约有900万只大中型哺乳动物死于交通事故。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李忠秋告诉南方周末记者，路杀作为交叉学科“道路生态学”其中一项研究内容，在美国、欧洲等国家有较多学术研究，但目前国内系统开展路杀的研究还不多，且已有的研究多在保护区进行，缺乏对城市环境的分析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自2020年开始，李忠秋团队对南京市9条道路开展了为期一年的监测。这9条道路包含3条国道、3条省道和3条县道，路边生境涵盖了居民区、农田、山地、水域、开阔地、森林等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/jHJGDj2QDMJyU4a0y9f3ok1ynq3BEws2c2vzFxAb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;563&quot; height=&quot;694&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/jHJGDj2QDMJyU4a0y9f3ok1ynq3BEws2c2vzFxAb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;研究团队在南京市观察路杀的道路。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（论文截图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每隔两周，研究人员以不高于40km/h的车速走完全部路线，记录路上发现的动物尸体。行驶总里程达5831公里，相当于北京到乌鲁木齐的来回距离。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在26次监测活动中，研究人员总共发现293只遭遇路杀的动物。其中哺乳动物有136只，最常见的是猫和狗，还有黄鼬、刺猬等野生哺乳动物，一种爬行动物——虎斑颈槽蛇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鸟类有143只，最常见的是乌鸫和麻雀，这与它们种群数量大、分布广有关。其他鸟类还包括珠颈斑鸠、灰喜鹊、白头鹎等，大多属于常见物种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5月-7月是发生路杀的高峰期，这三个月的路杀数量约占全年的1/3。李忠秋解释，该时段是许多动物的繁殖季，动物幼崽缺乏生存经验，成年动物为抚养孩子而增加觅食频率，路杀概率增大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;路杀发生的地点与动物的栖息地密切相关。例如，农田、林地和湿地面积占比高的路段，路杀的风险较高；道路与河流之间距离越小，则路杀的风险越高；路杀更容易发生在远离城市主干道的地区；相较于弯曲的道路，笔直道路上发生路杀的风险更高，因为车速更快。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过模型，研究人员推算出南京每年遭遇路杀的动物数量——兽类11万余只，鸟类45万余只。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;模型基于现场监测的动物尸体留存时间、被发现的概率、南京市不同道路构成等构建。由于路杀动物的尸体不会在路面留存太久，研究者在多个路段放置冷冻鸡头和冷冻整鸡，分别代表小型和大型动物尸体，监测模拟尸体在道路的留存时间，计算出路杀被监测到的概率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/ctOxUfPfW7fH3pxoUlBEeQxIpnJsRrjlm6UaHUNb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;303&quot; height=&quot;203&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/ctOxUfPfW7fH3pxoUlBEeQxIpnJsRrjlm6UaHUNb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;被路杀的鸟。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（课题组供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;常见物种也有重要价值&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;如何帮助动物减少遭遇交通事故的风险？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多保护区在交通路线上建立动物迁徙的生态廊道。例如，青藏铁路设立了33处“易羊迁徙”的野生动物通道，藏羚羊等野生动物因此受益；湖北神农架国家公园建设了上跨式、下涵式和缓坡式三种类型共25处动物通道，便于川金丝猴穿行；云南省思小高速公路为亚洲象设置桥梁隧道，野生亚洲象对25个野生动物通道的利用率达到72%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;车水马龙的城市公路也可以建立生态廊道。例如，2020年，深圳市大鹏新区排牙山——七娘山生态廊道建成，连接两山，横跨公路，是广东省首条建成且投入使用的仅供动物通行的天桥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;深圳市规划和自然资源局大鹏管理局工作人员告诉南方周末记者，2018年，大鹏新区曾开展过野生动物道路致死调查，7月、8月两个月间，共记录了383起路杀事件，致死物种超过40种，以两栖类、爬行类动物如黑眶蟾蜍、香港瘰螈、变色树蜥等为主，也记录到少量鸟类、哺乳类动物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该工作人员表示，生态廊道不仅将破碎的生境重新连接，也有效减少了路杀的发生。在生态廊桥上布置的四十余台红外相机记录到，有六十余种动物在生态廊道范围内繁殖、觅食、活动，已记录到豹猫、野猪、豪猪、猕猴等野生哺乳动物，形成了良好的动物栖息地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李忠秋认为，城市是否建设生态廊道，需重点考虑成本和当地物种。此外还有一些有效的方法，比如在路杀热点地区树立指示牌，提醒司机此处常有动物出没，放慢车速，多观察路面情况，或设置减速带，建立动物围栏等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李忠秋坦言，目前人们对路杀的认识和研究仍较初级，“难以评估路杀对当地生态系统究竟有多大的影响程度”，但至少从数据来看，路杀问题值得引起更多的重视。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前李忠秋团队针对路杀的研究仅在南京一地开展，他希望，未来能将区域范围扩展至全国尺度，进行更深入的研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;城市中遭遇路杀的动物，虽然都是常见物种，但是它们在生态系统中仍然有独特的地位。李忠秋举例，比如常见鸟类白头鹎，在日常生活中有点恼人——香樟树下停放的车辆常常被白头鹎的鸟粪“炸弹”袭击。但白头鹎在生态系统中是一个重要的功能性鸟类，它的排泄物可以帮助植物种子传播到几公里之外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们总以人类为中心，谈论一个物种对自己有没有用。”李忠秋称，“每一个物种生活在地球上，都有它的功能和价值，越是常见的物种，越有存在的价值，不能因为常见就忽视生活在我们身边的它们。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孙卓、符建涛被拐案宣判：两名被告分别被判刑5年、2年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258520]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 13, 2023, the Shenzhen Nanshan District People’s Court prosecuted the defendant Wu Moulong for abducting children and The first-instance public verdict was made in the case of Wu Mouguang&#39;s cover-up. Wu Moulong was sentenced to five years in prison for child abduction, and Wu Mouguang was sentenced to two years in prison for the crime of cover-up. At the same time, the court ordered Wu Molong to compensate Sun Moufei and Peng Mouying for their losses of 420,000 yuan, and to compensate Fu and Peng Moumou for their losses of 420,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court found that the defendant Wu Moulong abducted the victims Sun and Fu in Nanshan District, Shenzhen on October 9 and December 28, 2007, and took them with him. He went to the defendant Wu Mouguang&#39;s residence to hide. Subsequently, Wu Moulong handed over the victims to their fellow villagers or relatives to be raised. On September 27, 2021, when the public security agency questioned Wu Mouguang, Wu Mouguang deliberately made false proofs about important plots in this case in order to cover Wu Moulong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court held that the defendant Wu Moulong abducted minors under the age of fourteen and separated them from their families or guardians, and his behavior constituted the crime of child abduction. The defendant Wu Mouguang knew about Wu Moulong&#39;s criminal behavior and gave false evidence to cover him up. His behavior constituted the crime of cover-up. The court made the above judgment based on the criminal facts, nature, circumstances and guilty plea performance of the two defendants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 20 people including some NPC deputies, CPPCC members, journalists and people from all walks of life attended the sentencing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[巴以冲突引发撕裂，澳大利亚陷入争论]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258509]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 14:56:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国产剧终于不再斗小三了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258463]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;This year, with female relations as the Among the themed film and television dramas, the operation of &quot;Good Things Come in Twos&quot; is definitely considered bold. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The first wife Lin Shuang, played by Zhang Xiaofei, actually formed the &quot;Avengers Alliance&quot; with the mistress Jiang Xi, played by Zhang Jiani, and not only joined forces to tear apart the scumbag Wei Ming played by Li Zefeng , also joined hands to start a new company and find their own value in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/fcc38fa60c059ef51b6b981089d1c881.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;531&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/fcc38fa60c059ef51b6b981089d1c881.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253859 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Going back three years, such a plot is still unimaginable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, Lin Youyou played by Zhang Yue in &quot;Only Thirty&quot; was criticized by the audience for his mistress behavior in the play, and even extended to the actor himself. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But three years later in &quot;Good Things Come in Twos&quot;, the situation has changed a lot: in addition to being annoying and hateful, the audience noticed more from Jiang Xi What is most remarkable is her suffering and tenacity, as well as the tacit understanding of sympathy with her first wife. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, looking back at domestic dramas, it is not difficult to find that the role of the mistress is always changing, and the discussion of marriage relationships with the help of this image also reflects the changes in social values. Transmutation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;White moonlight under the male gaze&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The first mistress image in a domestic drama to arouse social discussion was undoubtedly Achun, played by Wang Ji in &quot;Beijingers in New York&quot; (1993)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/fb99639737795fd72a1f8af40d7e7f3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;722&quot; height=&quot;521&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/fb99639737795fd72a1f8af40d7e7f3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253857 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She is mature, elegant and full of charm. &lt;/span>;But that’s not all. What really makes her capture everyone, including Wang Qiming played by Jiang Wen, is her smart and calm mind. No matter how deep the emotional bond is, she must always ensure her financial independence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The first time she appeared in the play, she had a dispute with the man she had had a relationship with because the man misappropriated money from her hotel - Achun put money and feelings together It was very clear that even if he got into such a deep entanglement with Wang Qiming later, when he wanted to borrow money, he would insist on making him issue an IOU and stipulate the interest rate and repayment date. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Achun is the kind of woman who understands the laws of survival in society and understands the importance of economic independence for women. Only in this way can she always maintain her The right to speak. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is this sobriety that makes Achun resonate with many people even though he is an unpleasant mistress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3a0ac1e9fad8552815a65a075d6c0276.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3a0ac1e9fad8552815a65a075d6c0276.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253858 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Come and Go&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(1998)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The same is true for Lin Zhu played by Xu Qing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this drama, Lin Zhu is a mistress who is filled with feminine charm. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;She is cultured and tasteful, knows how to enjoy life, and is full of feminine charm in her speech and behavior. She not only has her own career, but is also crazy and persistent in pursuing love. At critical moments He is also calm-minded. After learning that the male protagonist has no hope of divorce, he resolutely chooses to leave. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/57b3b73b5ebe13f27b504335e2f09ac8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/57b3b73b5ebe13f27b504335e2f09ac8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253861 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There were many similar images in this period. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, &quot;Holding Hands&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(1999)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The female college student Wang Chun played by Yu Feihong, &quot;Let Love Make the Call&quot;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;(2001)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Lou Jiayi played by Xu Jinglei, and Sun Li played An Xin in &quot;Jade Guanyin&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(2003)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/02de446beedf103223a1d1d7bf46170b.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/02de446beedf103223a1d1d7bf46170b.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;253862 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From Achun to Lin Zhu, to Wang Chun, Lou Jiayi and An Xin, the biggest thing in common among the mistresses in domestic dramas during this period&lt;/span>; is that they make people hate them Can&#39;t get up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why this is so is not only because the creators hide their moral perspective, but also because they subconsciously prefer the aesthetic characteristics of the male gaze. They are attractive in appearance and independent and healthy mentally. , and there is no need to rely too much on it economically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To put it bluntly, the image of mistresses in this period basically followed men&#39;s fantasy of the perfect lover, and the metaphors of cinnabar moles and white moonlight were everywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this reason, most of the first wives in these works appear as boring and angry characters. For example, Lu Liping&#39;s character in &quot;Coming and Going&quot;, she bosses around her partner and &lt;span>; is sarcastic and sarcastic at every turn. , he also spoke in a strange and eccentric manner, making it unbearable for the audience to watch. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/46ffd9a262f03a18e104da948890d2c0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;850&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/46ffd9a262f03a18e104da948890d2c0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253860 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In comparison, third parties are always younger, brighter and funnier, and have a larger buffer zone in terms of human nature, feelings and marriage. The result is that both It provides an outlet for men trapped in depressed marriages to vent their emotions, and prevents mistresses from being put in danger of being criticized by public opinion. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;The tool man who cannot be happy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Created by Deliberate avoidance and trick settings cannot really circumvent negative social emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2007, the four-cornered love story &quot;Thank You for Loving Me&quot; with the theme of infidelity was broadcast. The screenwriter of this drama is Wang Huiling, Ang Lee’s queen screenwriter, and many talented actors have joined the cast. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The heroine is Xiaosan Yuwei, who also continues the setting of the previous drama routine: talent, taste, ability and charm. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, after the show was broadcast, the social response was far lower than expected, and the reviews from the media and the audience were not satisfactory. &lt;/span>;Why did the character setting that had been so popular for about ten years suffer in &quot;Thank You for Loving Me Once&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The answer is actually very simple: the audience&#39;s tastes and values ​​have changed, and they can no longer agree with the &quot;good mistress&quot; setting. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2009, the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening the Content Management of Internet Audiovisual Programs&quot;. Article 12 clearly criticized extramarital affairs, polyamory and other content. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/edd436023e7219ccaf293c03812a353b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;576&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/edd436023e7219ccaf293c03812a353b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253864 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This rule later evolved into the &quot;hidden rule&quot; widely circulated on the Internet&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, that is: the protagonist should not be too carefree, and the mistress cannot be happy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The first to adapt to this change was &quot;The Temptation of Going Home&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (2010)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, which tells the story of the tragic experiences of a wealthy young woman. The story of cheating, planning revenge, and finally gaining true love became the most popular TV series at the time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It was also from that year that mistresses were no longer beautified as before, and the plot of &lt;strong>;fighting mistresses and taking revenge&lt;/strong>; began to become a domestic marriage and love story. In the mainstream of the drama, the images of mistresses are also collectively moving towards negative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1bc08b40a665571054de679662829669.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1bc08b40a665571054de679662829669.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253863 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, in &quot;The Defense of Marriage&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (2010)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, Meng Guangmei plays a &quot;professional mistress&quot; who tries to get ahead by pretending to be weak. Zhang Jin, in &quot;Marriage Like a Jade&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;(2016)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, Jiang Xin plays the arrogant mistress Hua Sha&lt;/span>; who tries to use her body to gain power, and &quot;Mother Xiang&quot; In &quot;Forward&quot; (2015), Jiang Zuping plays Hu Li, who is hooking up with her best friend&#39;s husband...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these stories, mistresses rely on their bodies and minds to stalk and seduce men. Break away from your original partner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correspondingly, the first wife also changed her previous negative image of being harsh and harsh. Although she was filled with grief and anger towards the man, she still showed strong tolerance and maternal brilliance, and finally relied on wisdom and justice to win over the man. Pull him back into marriage, or make a man feel deeply guilty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This model is still mainstream in marriage dramas in recent years, such as &quot;The First Half of My Life&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (2017)&lt;/span Ling Ling, played by Wu Yue in >;&lt;span>;, and Lin Youyou in &quot;Only Thirty&quot; are both representative characters. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/64f11317ebf05ff2621a2f047ae8fae2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/64f11317ebf05ff2621a2f047ae8fae2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253867 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this context, the mistresses&lt;/span>; were extremely bad, and their final outcome was a miserable failure. The image of the mistress in this situation can be said to have no charm at all, and is completely a tool needed to promote the plot. For example, Lin Youyou in &quot;Only Thirty&quot; has been stereotyped and instrumentalized to the extreme, and even the means of &quot;seduce men&quot; are clumsy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/efe4a2adc34017c9bf11a451719eb53b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;682&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/efe4a2adc34017c9bf11a451719eb53b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253866&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There is also Ling Ling in &quot;The First Half of My Life&quot;. Her way of intervening in other people&#39;s marriages is to use softness to overcome strength and retreat to advance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the marriage dramas of this period, people no longer care about the complexity of marriage issues, but instead focus on whether the original wife&#39;s grievances have been redressed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;03&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;It’s all the men’s fault&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Good Things Come in Twos&quot;, the situation Change again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;First of all, as the original partner, Lin Shuang is not as mean to her husband as in the early marriage dramas, nor is she as harsh as in the marriage dramas from 2010 to the present. In the play, he fights the mistress to the death. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The biggest change is Jiang Xi, who is a mistress. Not only does her image become more three-dimensional, but the creator also outlines the details in detail. It tells the whole process of her inner transformation from why she was willing to become a mistress to finally joining forces with Lin Shuang. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3347b5f486184bd8aeff720976551ba1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3347b5f486184bd8aeff720976551ba1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253865 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The story of &quot;Good Things Come in Twos&quot; begins with a unique confrontation between the first wife and her mistress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Lin Shuang met Jiang Xi, her husband’s cheating partner, at a coffee shop. When she saw two women at the next table making a quarrel for the same reason, Lin Shuang Instead, she became more sober. In her words, &quot;The mistress has nothing to do with cheating, but the most disgusting thing is the man.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So then, she got straight to the point. Di proposed: &quot;We two, join forces.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/e0038eb974117cf445d11b21443762d5. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ e0038eb974117cf445d11b21443762d5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this plot logic, the ones who are at fault are mainly men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reason why this change has occurred is because as women’s consciousness continues to develop, women have realized that in the face of failed marriages and emotional relationships, hysterical pulling is not the answer. The wisest response is to make effective choices, stop losses in time and restart your life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Obviously, this setting is somewhat idealized, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Or to put it more crudely: it is the same as the previous two stages of love and marriage dramas. , seems to go deep into the emotional relationship, but in fact it does not give women a restoration that is more in line with the current status quo. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Relatively speaking, the British drama &quot;Doctor Foster&quot; with the same theme &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (2015) &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; did a good job Better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3aa4b9ede131829b5343fe60d12aa7cf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3aa4b9ede131829b5343fe60d12aa7cf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253869 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although it is also a story about marriage and infidelity, the content discussed in &quot;Doctor Foster&quot; does not stop at the topic of how the first wife treats her scumbag husband and his mistress. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The whole point of it is to show various views and values ​​on marriage through this&lt;/span>; story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the heroine Gemma represents the kind of person who regards honesty as the highest code of conduct, so after discovering that her husband Simon had cheated, she gave him several opportunities to explain himself, but her husband The final performance broke her heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simon&#39;s setting is a bit different from the common image of a scumbag. Although he also cheated on her, he still loved Gemma, both physically and mentally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/949cc880e3657b2e19c5b1a2ebff2f56.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/949cc880e3657b2e19c5b1a2ebff2f56.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253870&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This kind of setting is more complex and full-bodied than domestic marriage dramas. In &quot;Good Things Come in Twos&quot;, the scumbag husband Wei Ming teams up with his first wife Lin Shuang and his mistress Jiang Xi - the former is an unthinking stereotype, and the latter is a crude setting that takes it for granted to cater to feminism. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Doctor Foster&quot;, Gemma did not rely on anyone. She was calm and composed in the great pain, and she calmly tried to find ways to regain what she had lost. Everything ended in the fact that the mistress was pregnant with her husband&#39;s child in front of her husband, mistress and mistress&#39;s family. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Besides this main line, there are other extramarital affairs patterns in &quot;Doctor Foster&quot;. For example, Simon&#39;s mother never forgave her cheating husband until her death; and Gemma&#39;s neighbor, she felt that as long as her husband didn&#39;t cheat, she could tolerate it, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/72b80b3b55cb2c844358f30f6b7e0e25.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;627&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/72b80b3b55cb2c844358f30f6b7e0e25.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253871 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Different processing methods are presented in the series, which are both natural and restrained, so that it does not stop at one-dimensional crusade against a certain character, but in different situations. The views on love and marriage and value choices make people think deeply about the meaning of marriage to themselves, as well as the complex psychological state of women in it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In comparison, it can be found that although domestic love and marriage dramas have evolved in three stages, they have not been able to adapt to the characters&#39; mentality and show them on a more realistic standard. The complexities of marriage. &lt;/span>;Most of them still fall into the trap of male gaze or female consciousness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 14:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[周杰伦演唱会被集体“退票”，实名制下黄牛新套路]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258487]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Jay Chou&#39;s 2023 &quot;Carnival&quot; World Tour Concert Shanghai will be held from October 12th to 15th. It is reported that tickets for the concert are hard to come by, scalpers are selling them at sky-high prices, and the number of grandstand tickets has exceeded 20,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/cc71a11c585f9c1d0e37db574e8c813d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1525&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/cc71a11c585f9c1d0e37db574e8c813d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253956&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But according to reports Recently, scalpers collectively canceled the show, which attracted a lot of attention and once topped the list of hot searches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/cc6f99143585350aff31ed026356ba14.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;354&quot; height= &quot;57&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/cc6f99143585350aff31ed026356ba14.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253953&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Too miserable It’s all Jay Chou’s fault.”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Some sellers told the media that the reason for the cancellation was that the organizer’s original plan to enter the information was not honored. Scalpers on WeChat Moments all refunded the money, saying, &quot;It&#39;s too bad and it&#39;s all Jay Chou&#39;s fault.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/247888fa70aeef972f841c1cee4268d2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;287&quot; height= &quot;236&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/247888fa70aeef972f841c1cee4268d2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253957&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/fe78c4703011ca53a626e297cffc7488.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;280&quot; height=&quot;249&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/fe78c4703011ca53a626e297cffc7488.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253958&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;Internet screenshot&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that this performance requires real-name admission. Tickets are refundable, but cannot be transferred or resold. Refunds will be stopped 48 hours before the start of the performance. In order to create a healthy and sound performance market, the &quot;strong real-name&quot; system came into being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called strong real-name is the three-in-one of person, ID and face: audiences need to bind their identity information when purchasing tickets online, and need to verify their ID cards and face recognition when entering a performance. This has greatly restricted the scalpers’ operating space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the news of &quot;scalpers collectively canceling orders&quot; came out, fans clapped their hands and said, &quot;This wave of scalpers is really bad.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/621426afba793904ef38ba703fdf4b72.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;843&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/621426afba793904ef38ba703fdf4b72.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253955&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/f8316aeee2caddff260ac835ea99a1ff.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/f8316aeee2caddff260ac835ea99a1ff.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253959&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the performance released by the three platforms of Damai, Piaoxingxing and Maoyan According to ticket data, a total of more than 110,000 tickets were released for Jay Chou&#39;s Shanghai concert. Among them, Damai released about 70,000 tickets, Maoyan released about 41,000 tickets, and Ticket Planet only released 2,400 tickets. However, on the Damai platform alone, 6.441 million people marked &quot;Want to Watch&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/adce02c773585ed6e651a66016cda50a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1141&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/adce02c773585ed6e651a66016cda50a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253962&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, Tianjin The site did not adopt a &quot;strong real-name system&quot; and the original price of in-field tickets was 2,000 yuan, which was raised to 100,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;An outrageous scene occurred at the &quot;Mayday&quot; concert&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 11, Mayday&#39;s Noah&#39;s Ark replica limited edition concert in Guangzhou officially started. During the song requesting session, an audience member selected by Mayday revealed in public that &quot;I didn&#39;t grab the (ticket), I bought it from a scalper&quot;, which made the Mayday people on the stage suddenly look embarrassed. The related topic became a hot topic on Weibo that night. Search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person involved subsequently responded on social platforms, denying the online rumors that he was &quot;taken away by the police&quot;, saying that he was asked about his ticket purchase by public security officers and returned to the hotel after watching the entire concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/4781e72f3e2b3d0150c9f9502e7fd4a3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1048&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/4781e72f3e2b3d0150c9f9502e7fd4a3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253960&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This performance The episode at the meeting brought rampant ticket scalping and other issues to the public in an unabashed way. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;False and strong real name? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As one of the hottest tours this year, the &quot;hard-to-get&quot; Mayday Guangzhou concert also adopts a strong real-name system for viewing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/47827ca05e4dd9fec696fef5ee38cf25.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1527&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/47827ca05e4dd9fec696fef5ee38cf25.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253963&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But according to the South Metropolis Daily reported that on social platforms, some viewers who watched the performance on the 11th said that the admission verification did not strictly adhere to the strong real-name principle and achieve the three-in-one of person, certificate and ticket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many viewers who entered the venue with information other than their own reported that when the second face verification was inconsistent, they only needed to go through the manual channel and sign a notification to pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/daf71ab3ac46b00c449be7907e484e49.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/daf71ab3ac46b00c449be7907e484e49.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253961&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Paper notice&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No guarantee letter is required, no original copy from a friend is required, just bring a paper ticket.&quot; Some netizens shared their entry process It said that when the ticket information is inconsistent, you can enter the mini program by scanning the &quot;Forgot ID card&quot; QR code, bind the ticket by scanning the QR code of the paper ticket, and then generate a new blue QR code at the gate. Scan the QR code to enter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some netizens said that their tickets showed that no information was entered, and they could just scan the tickets and enter without even writing a notice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the feedback from the audience, the real-name system that the organizers have emphasized many times has not been truly implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Fake tickets can also pass through the gate&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is even more outrageous than the fake and strong real names is that in this show, there was also a situation where fake tickets could be used to enter the venue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Chen, who bought the counterfeit tickets from a scalper, told Nandu reporters that after asking about the situation from five or six scalpers outside the Olympic Sports Center, he bought the ticket at a price of 1,200 yuan per ticket with a face value of 855 yuan. tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When verifying paper tickets, staff need to check whether the anti-counterfeiting code on the paper ticket is authentic, but the ticket held by Mr. Chen was not found to be fake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering according to the seat on the ticket, Mr. Chen and his friends found that someone was already seated in the seat where they bought consecutive tickets. &quot;After discovering that the seat was occupied, we both took out our tickets and looked at them, and found that the seat numbers were the same.&quot; Mr. Chen began to suspect that he might have bought a fake ticket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter compared the ticket map provided by Mr. Chen and found that there were indeed some minor differences between the fake tickets and the real tickets: the serial number and the anti-counterfeiting code were different, the font size was different, and there was no QR code under the fake tickets. The word &quot;stand&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/7825f407f105d10f8ee7dac4a6b10759.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/7825f407f105d10f8ee7dac4a6b10759.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253964&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ticket comparison provided by Mr. Chen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the other party showed the ticket purchase record from the ticketing platform, the staff asked Mr. Chen and his friends to leave first. Fortunately, he didn&#39;t have time to transfer money to the scalper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Chen said that the security staff later relented and allowed them to enter. After watching the entire concert standing in the aisle, he found someone standing in the aisle watching the performance like them. He speculated that other people might have bought fake tickets without knowing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the entire process, the counterfeit notes held by Mr. Chen not only passed the first manual inspection, but also passed the second gate inspection. Even when he finally confronted the real tickets, they were all purchased through the other party&#39;s presentation. Ticket records are used to determine the authenticity of tickets. It is also questionable whether the on-site staff can actually verify the validity of the tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fans have reported that ticketing management may be tightened&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Frequent ticketing disputes have aroused strong dissatisfaction among the public. Many fans said that they have reported to relevant departments and have been arrested. accepted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The organizer is also suspected of reacting to this. There are scalpers on the Internet saying that due to reports of real-name authentication issues, tickets for the 12th, 14th and 15th are currently unable to be entered into the system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ca8b1bb9ea46e004060fb60ed8a4d725.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;473&quot; height= &quot;284&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ca8b1bb9ea46e004060fb60ed8a4d725.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253965&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;It is reported online that scalpers said tickets could not be entered&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on the 12th, the organizer Huaxing Performing Arts once again released instructions for viewing the performance on its official WeChat public account, emphasizing that &quot;this show Real-name admission to the performance is required, and the ID card for ticket purchase must be consistent with the ID card for admission. Audiences must swipe the turnstile on site to verify their ID card and face before entering the venue with their real name.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But whether there is really any improvement depends on the live situation in the next few performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are many tricks for scalpers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that under the strong real-name system, the business of many &quot;scalpers&quot; is no longer buying and selling, but &quot;robbing on behalf of others.&quot; They will bind the customer&#39;s ID card information in advance, and if the ticket is not obtained, 100% of the money &quot;snatched&quot; will be returned to the customer. It is this mentality of giving it a try without losing money that makes many Jay Chou&#39;s die-hard fans choose to &quot;grab it on behalf of others&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some media consulted a &quot;scalper&quot; as a consumer, and the other party said that the &quot;snatching&quot; price of Jay Chou&#39;s stands at the Shanghai Stadium is 1,500 yuan, while the ticket price for the stands is 580 yuan-1,280 Prices vary from RMB 2,080 to RMB 2,500 for tickets priced at 2,080 yuan in the infield, and RMB 2,000 for tickets priced at other prices in the infield. It is understood that some are &quot;robbed&quot; manually, while more advanced ones use special software. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is difficult to distinguish the authenticity of the so-called &quot;proxy shooting&quot; service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The investigation found that if it is a real &quot;scalper&quot;, then after the customer selects the seat class, he must pay the &quot;scalper&quot; in advance the ticket fee and hundreds or even thousands of yuan in agency fees, and the ticket will be issued by a familiar person. &quot;Scalpers&quot; who follow the rules and use proxy auction software use customers&#39; personal information to grab tickets. If you fail to grab a ticket, the real &quot;scalper&quot; will refund the ticket fee and the auction fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But if you encounter fake &quot;scalpers&quot;, customers are likely to suffer heavy losses. Fake &quot;scalpers&quot; do not help purchase tickets, but use various methods such as &quot;upgrading seats&quot; and &quot;increasing the probability&quot; to induce customers to continuously increase service fees, and eventually disappear without a trace, defrauding customers of huge ticket fees and service fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, &quot;internal invitation letters/internal tickets&quot; and &quot;bringing in by staff&quot; are also full of doubts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social platforms, some netizens posted photos of &quot;internal invitations/internal tickets&quot;, but other netizens quickly pointed out: This was a fake invitation modeled after another performance—— Although the ticket looks very similar, the counterfeiter was careless and got the performance venue wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, it is also difficult to fulfill &quot;the staff will lead you into the performance site&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the information transmitted online, some &quot;staff members&quot; claim to be from the &quot;ticketing company&quot;, while others claim to be from the &quot;security company&quot;. Not to mention that their identities cannot be verified. Even if they can be led in, It is also an illegal act, and both the person taking the person and the person being taken should bear legal responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ea8fa937c2dbc8a1ddcd08ab3f06f07d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;554&quot; height= &quot;181&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ea8fa937c2dbc8a1ddcd08ab3f06f07d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253966&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public is advised to When purchasing performance tickets, stick to official channels or formal platforms, and do not trust second-hand online transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[曾梵志：过往皆风景，此刻在闪烁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258491]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/12/K1PChqShECUyd7DBIMACbOQFyPiSF6km59ypqIjV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;634&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/K1PChqShECUyd7DBIMACbOQFyPiSF6km59ypqI jV. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253939&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zeng Fanzhi&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Jiang Xiaoming/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Use 40 colors to create 400 colors&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, and use&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;3 kinds of purple&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;Create&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;A silent black&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This is “an art exhibition that was publicized in advance”: since Shanghai Pudong Art Museum announced that it will hold a large-scale solo exhibition of artist Zeng Fanzhi Since then, people have been waiting for the debut of the &quot;star&quot; whose oil paintings have fetched astonishingly high prices and his new works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 27, 2023, the exhibition &quot;Zeng Fanzhi: Past and Present (Paintings 1988-2023)&quot; opened. Fabrice Hergot, Director of the Musée d&#39;Art Moderne de Paris ( Fabrice Hergott serves as the chief curator, selecting more than 60 representative works created by Zeng Fanzhi in the past 35 years, and presenting &quot;Looking Back at the Early Years&quot;, &quot;Different Paths&quot;, and &quot;Like Meditation&quot; in the high and spacious space of Pudong Art Museum. Four units, including &quot;Extra Large Scale&quot; and &quot;Extra Large Scale&quot;, encourage viewers to experience the secret of painting as a traditional art medium that continues to thrive today through more active and personal viewing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that Zeng Fanzhi’s latest “Flickering Paintings” series makes its world debut in the exhibition. He has long since taken off his &quot;mask&quot;, turned decisively away from the various &quot;landscapes&quot; of the &quot;past&quot;, and devoted himself to a brand new experiment. Pointing to the largest work in the exhibition, &quot;Flickering Painting - Light III,&quot; Hergot said that this work reminded him of the grand atmosphere at the beginning of &quot;Genesis&quot; in the Bible. In this huge work of 480cm x 400cm, Zeng Fanzhi combined two oil canvases. The upper part depicts the magnificent scene of the sunrise with the clouds opening, and the lower part depicts the shimmering water surface reflected in the rays of sunlight. From a distance, it is a vast expanse of water. Elegant and bright pink and purple, a variety of rich and varied colors and textures can be observed up close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/i2hjFeg022j8QSil2Jvw2WEi0TCFCbMeoSBoS4NF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;959&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/i2hjFeg022j8QSil2Jvw2WEi0TCFCbMeoSBoS4NF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253938&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Still Life, 2020, oil on canvas, 60 x 60 cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Fan Members of Zhi Studio had reminded the media that the artist would not comment on the new work in this interview. However, after the press conference and when he returned to the exhibition site, a timid girl finally summoned up the courage to ask a question that everyone was curious about. ——&quot;I personally feel that these new works resemble the style of Pointillism.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Zeng Fanzhi&#39;s own response to the new &quot;Flickering Paintings&quot; was not &quot;evasive&quot; at all. Like a teacher from an art academy who faces students, he sincerely &quot;teaches&quot; the girl: &quot;The Pointillist artist you are talking about was an artist 100 years ago. At that time, he used three primary colors. When he wanted to express one primary color, he used different blues. Together with the yellow dot, let you feel the green, but it is relatively simple. Our color changes are too advanced now!&quot; As he said, he walked in front of a piece of &quot;Flickering Painting - Dragon Heads Up I&quot;, showing a mysterious and proud look. The smile continued, &quot;Compared with the artists of that era, I used 40 colors to create 400 colors in this work. Pointillism is relatively simple. In the early days of modern art, everyone was looking for their own set of colors. In terms of language expression, there are probably not hundreds of colors to be found in the works at that time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same exhibition hall of the &quot;Like Meditation&quot; unit, directly opposite the &quot;Dragon Heading Up&quot; with densely colored dots, It is a very contrasting, almost completely black &quot;Flickering Painting - Untitled&quot;. Zeng Fanzhi told me with a smile, &quot;This is really my first work in this new series, but others thought I was bragging. &quot;Compared with the complex brushstrokes, the color of this painting seems to be very pure. At first glance, it is a silent black. &quot;I particularly like this painting, but it does not use black from beginning to end.&quot; The creative process , Zeng Fanzhi combines three different shades of purple, a secret that can only be discovered when viewed up close under the right light. In order to confirm that it was deep purple, he led me to the &quot;Flickering Painting - Water VII&quot; next door, pointed to the edge of the intersection of &quot;black&quot; and white and said seriously, &quot;Look here, you can see that it is deep purple.&quot; .&quot; Because of the clear and straight dividing lines, the white waterfall on the picture appears as a solid shape in the dark background. Zeng Fanzhi said with a smile, &quot;Some of them even said, hey! What you painted is not a &#39;1&#39;?! I really don&#39;t know what to say.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a long period of partial practice, Zeng Fanzhi developed wonderful visual effects in the new series &quot;Flickering Paintings&quot;, &quot; Although color, composition and texture play their respective roles in every aspect of painting, in the medium of painting, they can never be separated from each other and become isolated existences.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, what he never forgets the most is The first moment when I successfully &quot;blacked out&quot; the picture with 3 shades of purple. Before leaving the exhibition hall, he stood next to the dark &quot;Untitled&quot; and suddenly discovered that under the influence of light, the picture took on a gray-green effect at a certain angle. Zeng Fanzhi took out his mobile phone to take a picture of its &quot;side face&quot; with great interest, and couldn&#39;t help but murmured excitedly, &quot;This &#39;like meditation&#39; should be called &#39;Niu B Space&#39;!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/FZ8FQPPOrcklj3F2o1XKD7kTHZYWnhrBQdBa26sw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;624&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/FZ8FQPPOrcklj3F2o1XKD7kTHZYWnhrBQdBa26sw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Abstract Landscape - Night, 2005, oil on canvas, 215 x 330 cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; Barefoot people wearing masks, shoeshine people at dusk&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The day before the exhibition opened, when crowds gathered to wait for the internal tour, Zeng Fanzhi was sitting cross-legged in a corner of the cafe, with his feet Wearing low-key sneakers, his indifferent expression is indeed in contrast to the high-spirited portrait in Liu Heung-cheng&#39;s photography exhibition upstairs. In 2012, Zeng Fanzhi tried on a pair of handmade leather shoes in a luxury store in London. The shoes were polished and polished. , he stood on tiptoe with his left foot, opened his suit with both hands, and was so happy that he almost flew up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the &quot;mask&quot; and the painting inside the painting, &quot;shoes&quot; are probably the most important annotations and metaphors for Zeng Fanzhi and his works. Portraits and still lifes run through his creations, and the 2009 sketch oil painting &quot;Boots&quot; is particularly special. This work was inspired by Van Gogh&#39;s 1886 work &quot;A Pair of Shoes&quot; and can be regarded as both a still life and a painting. Considered a portrait. When Zeng Fanzhi created &quot;Boots&quot;, it coincided with the explosive growth of Chinese contemporary art. The boots in the painting also represent the increasingly glamorous and glitzy life he faced. Zeng Fanzhi chose to take them off and examine them. While creating &quot;Boots&quot;, he also completed a self-portrait, in which he is holding a paintbrush, wearing a simple robe and bare feet. For a long time, the two works were hung side by side on the same wall within sight of his studio. Through this secret method, Zeng Fanzhi showed his confusion and determination for the future in his daily creations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the creation of the &quot;Mask&quot; series, the image of &quot;barefoot&quot; had already begun to emerge. Zeng Fanzhi moved to Beijing in 1993, and a year later the theme of the &quot;Mask Series&quot; emerged: he observed the crowds in big cities from the perspective of a bystander, expressing the contradiction between his individual consciousness and social identity. After the birth of this series, he began to attract attention from the international art world, and this thematic creation lasted for nearly 10 years. The &quot;Mask Series&quot; as a whole shows the trend of characters&#39; clothing becoming more and more exquisite and their facial expressions becoming increasingly blurred. However, &quot;Mask Series 1995 No. 14&quot; is a special case. The hands of the characters in the painting are exaggerated and enlarged, but the bare feet are still used. It is presented in normal proportions, so it appears top-heavy, with a certain humorous and self-deprecating temperament. The carefully dressed image forms a contradictory relationship with the naked feet, which also shows part of Zeng Fanzhi&#39;s life experience at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/HRVNziT5bJU84oTUlQD1TteDUaGfsF8bdxIRs3zY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;832&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/HRVNziT5bJU84oTUlQD1TteDUaGfsF8bdxIRs3zY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253941&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mask Series 1995 No. 7, 1995, oil on canvas, 150 x 130 cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Looking back at the early days&quot;, Zeng Fanzhi specifically mentioned two &quot;Twilight&quot; films: &quot;Twilight&quot; in 1989 and &quot;Twilight II&quot; in 1993. In the late 1980s, he studied in the Oil Painting Department of Hubei Academy of Fine Arts. At that time, he had received a series of technical training from the academy, but he was a disobedient student. &quot;&quot;Twilight&quot; in 1989 was a very important early work of mine. Because of the academic education back then, students had to go to the countryside or Tibet or the Loess Plateau every year to experience life and paint those local style paintings. But at that time, I worked with the school&#39;s I have a different idea. I said that my life is around me and I must paint places I am familiar with. I don’t go to those places in northern Shaanxi and spend two weeks painting people herding sheep. This painting is the one I pass by after school every day. Scene: A group of people are preparing to shine someone&#39;s shoes on the street. When someone comes, they sit on this chair to shine their shoes. Usually they sit here bored. To me, this scene is very interesting and touches me, so I made a sketch for them at the time, then went back and quickly completed the painting based on my feeling.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four years later, Zeng Fanzhi created &quot;Twilight II&quot; in Beijing. The old title is used in the structure, and it also depicts the streets of Wuhan in the evening. &quot;Dusk&quot; is a real-life sketch, while &quot;Twilight 2&quot; is a new composition that combines the scenes in his memory with the characters around him. The smoke on the ground on the left , glass ballast, etc. were all extracted from the fireworks and the corners of the streets of Wuhan at that time. In this way, memory fragments from his growing experience continued to flash in Zeng Fanzhi’s future creations. Even in his subsequent abstract works, sometimes he There will also be characters from legends or old movies hidden deep within the intricate lines, and they will be imagined and portrayed in a rather subjective way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/XfSsH3lKZSdGcidFVCoqHIanDhmYP9eSWZ1JPdhV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;863&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/XfSsH3lKZSdGcidFVCoqHIanDhmYP9eSWZ1JPdhV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253942&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Dusk II, 1993, oil on canvas, 180 x 200 cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>;Laughing red, melancholy green, a portrait of Freud&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2004, Zeng Fanzhi officially bid farewell to &quot;Portrait&quot; with a painting of a toy wooden horse. Mask Series&quot;. This masterpiece is often regarded as his self-portrait. The mask on the figure&#39;s face has been removed, but his expression is dull and unfathomable: he is no longer classified as an &quot;urban group&quot; of that era, but is regarded as a unique individual. Characterized by individuals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The projections of the characters and the wooden horse in different directions in &quot;Portrait&quot; create a weird and innocent atmosphere; his red coat forms a strong contrast with the green dotted on the corners of his clothes and the wooden horse&#39;s skateboard. Looking back at the &quot;past&quot;, large areas of red and a few strokes of emotional green have appeared repeatedly in Zeng Fanzhi&#39;s creations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/foJlx89PCRI51ElRK5MML0pMkeFJXZRSskKDRmfC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;959&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/foJlx89PCRI51ElRK5MML0pMkeFJXZRSskKDRmfC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253943&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Abstract Landscape - Huang, 2021, oil on canvas, 400 x 400 cm (double) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The first abstract work to be shown in this exhibition, &quot;Cow Dance II&quot; (1988), is covered with large areas of thick red paint. In order to create this work, Zeng Fanzhi spent a lot of time Lots of oil paint. According to his recollection, many classmates laughed at him for being wasteful at that time, but he remained unmoved and insisted that only enough materials can ensure a real touch, and touch can drive inspiration. He firmly believed that only through constant hands-on practice, To find the direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The background of &quot;Laughing Benin&quot; (1989) is a large area of ​​intense red, and the characters in &quot;The Melancholy Man&quot; (1990) wear sad green pants... These are all examples of Zeng Fanzhi&#39;s exploration of color expression. ’s first creations. &quot;&quot;Melancholy Man&quot; is a work I painted with my classmate Zhou Ning as the model. I was very satisfied at the time and I was very moved. From this painting, I realized how to use colors and lines to express emotions. The painting speed was very fast and I was very excited, including the look in his eyes, which allowed me to be integrated with the work when expressing it. Before, we drew a model randomly and had nothing to do with the model, but this work can integrate my own feelings into the painting. This It is a particularly important beginning in my portraiture.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/b2vV00PfuKiBh59Es1uK6V7WViF7oHn2z0nwbJcb.jpg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/b2vV00PfuKiBh59Es1uK6V7WViF7oHn2z0nwbJcb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253944&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Part of the flickering painting series__2023 Zeng Fanzhi &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Ning was also the model for &quot;Laughing Beckning&quot;. The title of that work uniquely combined the names of Zhou Ning and Max Beckmann, a German expressionist painter who had a profound influence on Zeng Fanzhi at the time. . Zhou Ning was the most frequently invited painting model by Zeng Fanzhi at that time. It was not easy to maintain one posture for a long time. In order to appease the models, Zeng Fanzhi would prepare small gifts from time to time. He still remembers that in order to complete &quot;The Melancholy Man&quot;, he reluctantly gave a box of lunch meat to Zhou Ning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/5aqsrnpy1QRbYD4ORt97Mb5EbHwyzTDC39NbMVPD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;722&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/5aqsrnpy1QRbYD4ORt97Mb5EbHwyzTDC39NbMVPD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253945&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Portrait, 2004, oil on canvas, 200 x 150 cm&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When creating &quot;The Melancholy Man&quot;, Zeng Fanzhi used a spatula extensively to present concrete shapes with abstract brushstrokes to capture the inner feelings of the characters. Emotions and compositions are both narrative and situational, yet extremely restrained. These techniques continued into his future portrait creations. After the mid-middle period, many of Zeng Fanzhi&#39;s portraits were completed with a scraper, and all the backgrounds of the characters were hidden by leaving blank spaces. In works such as &quot;Hugo&quot; (2018), an upward scratch is left on the top of the character&#39;s head to hide the brush strokes of the oil painting, while showing a certain dynamic and making the character&#39;s expression more &quot;freehand&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When I create portraits, I definitely paint people I like and people I know well. Hugo was an old photo I accidentally found. I felt very excited when I saw it. He was sitting there. There, the eyes caught my attention, so interesting! Many people think that I look at my hands first when painting, but in fact, from the moment his eyes made contact with me, I felt that this would definitely make a good portrait.&quot; Zeng Fan Zhi revealed to me, &quot;When painting eyes and faces, I have to do it in one stroke. The first 60% of this is accidental. When the color rolls inside, you have to predict what changes will happen inside with one stroke. It depends on some luck. , there is also an element of control, you must be very fast when scraping up, and it will be scraped up with just one stroke of the knife.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/12/w1quOl9L586bY8x4o3c0NC4NxzBpSFgFHIOoGt0k.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;785&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/ w1quOl9L586bY8x4o3c0NC4NxzBpSFgFHIOoGt0k.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253946&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Melancholic Man, 1990, oil on canvas, 110 x 90 cm&lt; span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Opposite the &quot;angry&quot; &quot;Hugo&quot;, the artist Lucian Freud&#39;s eyes were slightly blurred in Zeng Fanzhi&#39;s 2017 creation. The image of being closed and lying on a bed attracted everyone&#39;s attention. &quot;Speaking of Freud, I first saw his works in the library when I was in college. My first impression was also about the eyes. There were very complex emotions in the eyes he painted. It is difficult to express a person&#39;s emotions in painting. His eyes were very interesting and inspired me a lot. Later, when I painted, I also paid great attention to people’s eyes.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Freud has always been Zeng Fanzhi’s idol, and he especially admired him. The artist has strong creative power after middle age and a strong character that is not disturbed by the outside world. When I mentioned, &quot;Compared with the seated portrait in 2011, how different my mood was when I created this work on his deathbed in 2017&quot;, Zeng Fanzhi said frankly that the many portraits he created of Freud were actually They all reflect his inner projection of ideals at different stages. &quot;When I look at Freud&#39;s works, I pay great attention to the time of his creation. Then I always want to compare it with my own age. How old was he when he painted this painting? How old is he when I study it now? When I see exhibitions, I like to compare it with my own age. Let others compare, because I am also an artist. I think Freud is great. His seventies were actually the peak of his creation. His previous works were also very good, but his paintings were very tight and his eyes were very large. But the luster is a little different from that in his later years. He was a bit neurotic in his early years, but his creations in his later years, including the size and volume of his works, are all very good. I have seen many large-scale exhibitions of Freud, and he is someone I particularly admire. An artist who is 70 or 80 years old can still draw from life so well! You know, life drawing is challenging for artists.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/12/z43zVFskPkY4JcscNieL7HEofT7HnKoHquYeQKgn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;805&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/12/z43zVFskPkY4JcscNieL7HEofT7HnKoHquYeQKgn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253947&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Flicker Painting - Light III, 2019-2023 , oil on canvas, 480 x 400 cm (diptych) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zeng Fanzhi was told of the opportunity to meet Freud I was very excited about this, but unfortunately, the news of Floyd&#39;s death came not long after. This work created in 2017 was inspired by a photo of Freud in his later years, but Zeng Fanzhi highly refined and recreated it: the whole painting is filled with a sense of ethereal loneliness, and Freud’s white robe and His whole body is filled with a strange halo, and the bed he lies on only retains a few hasty outlines, showing an unfinished state... This is the last painting Zeng Fanzhi paid tribute to Freud. Zhang portrait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[困在“水下珠峰”：知名探险家韩颋和他未实现的新世界纪录]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258465]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-13 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;October 12 was originally the day when Han Ting set the 300-meter cave diving record. In April this year, Han Ting dived to a depth of 277 meters in Jiudun Skylight, once again breaking the Asian record for deepest cave diving, only 9 meters away from the world record of 286 meters. “The days are long,” Han Ting once described his experience of “just missing” the world record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiudun Skylight is what explorers call &quot;China&#39;s Underwater Everest&quot;. Du Lei, Han Ting&#39;s friend and director of the China Exploration Association, described to Nandu and N video reporters that Jiudun Skylight is like Han Ting&#39;s &quot;home&quot;. In recent years, he has continued to conduct underwater cave exploration and diving teaching here, and has participated in underwater rescues many times. Only this time, Han Ting lost contact with the outside world here and was found more than a hundred meters underwater many days later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After learning the news, Du Lei sent a sentence to the Nandu reporter: &quot;Which explorer can enjoy such an ending while fleeting in pursuit of his dream.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;Diving Flash&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At about 17:00 on October 7, Lin Zhu (pseudonym), who was playing in Jiudun Skylight, photographed Han Ting in the water. He was wearing a black diving suit, holding a breathing regulator on his chest, and was talking to his friends on the shore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon after, Han Ting lost contact. The dark waters swallowed up Han Ting&#39;s trace, and the people on the shore were anxious. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Villager Wang Na (pseudonym) was very surprised that Han Ting lost contact - on the 7th, she saw Han Ting at the skylight in Jiudun. &quot;He comes here often, dressed professionally, and looks just like usual.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Ren, who is also in the diving industry, learned the news that his old friend had lost contact. He told Nandu reporters that Han Ting originally planned to hit the 300-meter cave diving record on the 12th and conduct a live broadcast on the Internet. He has been making preparations in the past few days. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talking about the difficulties in search and rescue, Mr. Ren analyzed to Nandu reporters that the Jiudun skylight environment is relatively closed and the space is small. In addition, the underwater environment is dark and full of rocks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/d35f2518e35fc5f993bacfa3808db293.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/d35f2518e35fc5f993bacfa3808db293.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253875&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Overlooking the Jiudun skylight. Picture source: China Exploration Association&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Du&#39;an Emergency Management Bureau, on the morning of October 8, some people called the police saying that Han Ting, a well-known person in the diving industry, was in Daxing in the county on the evening of the 7th. I went diving in Zhenjiudun Skylight and still didn’t land until 11am on the 8th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident, the emergency, public security, health and health departments of the autonomous region, Hechi City, autonomous county and Daxing Town rushed to the scene in a timely manner to carry out emergency response. On the 9th, the professional rescue team of Hangzhou Blue Flag Diving International Club rushed to the incident site to carry out search and rescue work. On the 10th, the Du&#39;an County emergency department contacted a domestic professional underwater intelligent robot service company to go to Du&#39;an to participate in the search and rescue. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, the Blue Flag International Diving Club founded by Han Ting issued a statement saying that since the evening of the 7th, diver Han Ting had been missing for more than three days. Because the cave where the accident occurred was too deep, he The rescue cannot be fully launched, and there is currently no significant progress in the search and rescue work. Thank you for your concern. You can follow the official announcement for details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later the same day, Nandu reporters learned from multiple insiders that Han Ting was found more than 100 meters underwater in Jiudun Skylight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For extreme sports enthusiasts, death is not an untouchable topic. Du Lei recalled to Nandu reporters that Han Ting had discussed with him before that if his life ended, he hoped to stay in his favorite place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After learning that Han Ting was found underwater, Du Lei sent a message to the Nandu reporter: &quot;Which explorer can enjoy such an ending if he flashes away on the way to pursue his dream.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Underwater Everest&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In Du Lei’s view, Jiudun Skylight is like Han Ting’s “home”. In recent years, he has often dived and taught here. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiudun Skylight is located around Jiudun Village, Jiudun Village, at the foot of a mountain peak on the edge of Jiudun Poli Valley. The clear bottomed jelly water here maintains a water temperature of 19°C all year round and sparkles under the sunlight. Since the Chengjiang River is covered with white seaweed flowers every spring and summer, tourists who come here to play say that &quot;this is a flowering river.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Wei, who has visited this place before, told Nandu reporters that most of the tourists visiting the area are parents, children and young people. “It is indeed beautiful. Seaweed flowers grow underwater, with long rhizomes and many flowers. , very spectacular”, but “the surrounding environment is relatively primitive and I didn’t see any staff.” &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that admission to the scenic spot is free. Visitors can experience swimming, paddleboarding, diving and other projects here. Paddleboards need to be rented. Ms. Wei said that there were more people playing paddleboards, but she also saw a few tourists wearing professional clothing preparing to dive on the shore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6f887e4d453b8e3203b9514163e4c4d2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/6f887e4d453b8e3203b9514163e4c4d2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253874&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Tourists play at Jiudun Skylight. Photo provided by interviewee&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ordinary tourists like to come here to swim and see flowers, while diving enthusiasts regard this place as a &quot;game paradise&quot;. The Jiudun overflow skylight group consists of four inclined well-type skylights. Its deepest point has not yet been discovered and is known as the &quot;China&#39;s Underwater Everest&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, the Australian wet mule expedition team came here and spent more than 7 hours diving to a depth of 212 meters. However, they still did not find the bottom of Jiudun Skylight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Lei told Nandu reporters that the reason why Han Ting chose to break the Asian record and hit the world record in Jiudun Skylight is because it is deeper, more vertical, easier to dive and has better water quality than other caves. . &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He once went into the water here with Han Ting. He said that the water at a depth of 7 to 9 meters in Jiudun Skylight is close to the twilight level, or even completely dark. When it dives to 14 to 15 meters, it is basically a completely dark environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Lei introduced to Nandu reporters, “In the visible light environment, a variety of water plants of different heights and distinct layers are accompanied by groups of swimming fish, and divers seem to be swimming in a landscape fish tank. ”, and when diving deeper, “it’s like being in glass, the water has very good permeability and there are no impurities.” In addition, the rocks around the cave are very steep and vertically downward, &quot;making you feel that you can&#39;t see the bottom at a glance, and also attracting you to see what is below.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Li, a diving enthusiast, goes to Du&#39;an to dive once or twice every year. He has been to Jiudun, Tunbang, Peach Blossom Jellyfish and Sunroof. He told Nandu reporters that because he is not a local and does not fully understand the terrain, he is also worried about safety issues, so he dives with many people every time. “Everyone dives within the standards of their own diving level and looks after each other, which will reduce the number of dives.” Security risks&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Li also mentioned that there are warning signs underwater in Jiudun Skylight to remind diving enthusiasts not to enter the hole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the warning signs are frequent safety incidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2014, Mr. Wang from the Shenzhen Underwater Exploration Club and his party of three went to the site to inspect and conduct diving expeditions. One of the divers failed to surface after entering the water. Diving experts found the missing person in a cave that dived to a depth of 51 meters. After inspection, it was confirmed that the missing person had lost his vital signs at the time. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, two Chinese divers dived in Jiudun Skylight, and one of them died. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, the bodies of divers Gong Ziwei and Dong Jie were discovered underwater in the skylight of Duan Jiudun World on October 6 and 2 respectively. It is worth mentioning that Han Ting also participated in the search and rescue work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The man at the top of the tower&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the diving world, Han Ting has a resounding nickname-&quot;Old Cat&quot;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recreational diver Xiao Fei told Nandu reporters: &quot;Lao Mao belongs to the top of the pyramid in the diving world.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Hangzhou Diving Sports Association, Han Ting was born in In 1976, he obtained the PADI (International Professional Diving Training System) diver certificate in Thailand in 2014. He has been diving for 19 years and is the first recreational scuba, free diving and technical diving instructor in China. At the same time, he is also one of the founders of the Blue Flag Diving International Club. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, Han Ting began to learn cave diving exploration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A cave may have never been entered by anyone for millions of years, and you don&#39;t know what will happen in the next second.&quot; In the CCTV documentary &quot;Extreme China Season 2&quot; in Du&#39;an, Guangxi, he He explained why he loves cave diving, &quot;The experiences or feelings in the cave will sometimes bring out your dark side. This is the process of understanding and dialogue with yourself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Ting put the cave in Diving to the extreme, many records have been set: the air cave deep diving world record of 128 meters, the underwater cave Mnemo mapping depth world record of 202 meters, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April this year, he successfully dived to a depth of 277 meters in Jiudun Skylight, once again breaking the Asian record for deepest cave diving, only 9 meters away from the world record of 286 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters learned from the China Adventure Association that Han Ting first got into diving just for fun. After developing his hobby into a profession, he felt that he had an extra responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Han Ting opened the Duan Blue Flag Diving Club to cultivate more diving talents. In recent years, he has also carried out systematic exploration of underwater caves in Guangxi and is responsible for the preparation of Asia&#39;s first world-class cave diving training base in Du&#39;an. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c3a20c313405d48ef5ef2dad4122d361.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;446&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/c3a20c313405d48ef5ef2dad4122d361.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253873&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Han Ting. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, he participated in the establishment of China&#39;s scientific research diving system and assisted in the implementation of scientific research on China&#39;s extreme underwater environment; he has been responsible for or participated in many special underwater filming and difficult filming for TV or movies. Develop and implement solutions; commit to promoting public safety diving training and conducting firefighting and rescue training in diving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Han Ting participated in the exploration and salvage of the skeletons of Red Army Long March martyrs in Jiuhaijing, Guangxi, bringing to light the Red Army soldiers who had been sleeping underwater for 83 years. In 2020, he participated in the salvage work of the peach blossom jellyfish skylight accident in Du&#39;an, Guangxi, diving to 143 meters to complete the search and salvage of the remains of the victims. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The documentary &quot;Extreme China Season 2&quot; mentioned that cave diving is considered one of the most dangerous sports in the world, and even the most experienced divers will hang on by a thread. The China Exploration Association also mentioned in an article that cave diving accidents often occur in &quot;wild diving&quot; activities that are irregular and lack supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Ting was deeply touched by this: &quot;It shouldn&#39;t be like this. I hope I can do something down-to-earth to make everyone realize the right way to go and what the right attitude should be. At least it can influence a few more people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;There is a long way to go&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the view of his friend Du Lei, Han Ting, as the Asian cave diving record holder, has In the process of constantly breaking through ourselves, we have never broken through the safety bottom line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If it were me, with good feeling and good equipment, could I resist the urge to continue diving like him?” Talking about the fact that in April this year, Han Ting was only 9 meters away. Du Lei couldn&#39;t help but sigh with emotion about breaking the world record for cave diving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared to the calm Han Ting, Du Lei felt that he had a little &quot;recklessness&quot; in him. Han Ting once reminded him repeatedly: &quot;During the exploration process, never set a &#39;hump&#39; for yourself that must be reached, as this will cause particularly large safety risks.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3cc9adcdb873b540b2178328da56819c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;980&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/3cc9adcdb873b540b2178328da56819c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253872&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Jiudun Skylight Dive Route Map. Image source: China Exploration Association&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is a long way to go&quot;, Han Ting once described his experience of &quot;missing the world record&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He once said publicly, &quot;The depth of this plan is 270 to 290 meters. When I arrived at the planned area, I hesitated for 1 second. It only took 1 more minute to break the world record. However, I am now very I am happy that I resisted the temptation and stopped diving, tied knots, put arrow marks, and ascended as planned. There is a long way to go.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Ting&#39;s high degree of control over safety is also reflected in the choice of diving equipment. . Du Lei once asked Han Ting for advice on how to choose a CCR, and Han Ting recommended to him a device with two working systems. &quot;It&#39;s equivalent to two engines in one machine. If one of them breaks down, the other one can be used.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Lei told Nandu reporters that in daily activities in the water, Han Ting often carries two sets of engines. CCR. &quot;It&#39;s equivalent to him holding four safety backups, which is a big inspiration to me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April this year, Han Ting used a double-sided CCR three-way hybrid when he broke the Asian record. gas technology. According to the China Diving and Salvage Industry Association, CCR is a breathing circulation loop system that allows gas to continuously circulate in one direction in the loop. Diving with CCR can significantly reduce gas waste and greatly extend the underwater residence time, giving divers sufficient time to complete underwater exploration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, CCR also has disadvantages such as complex use and low operational fault tolerance. Du Lei analyzed that Han Ting&#39;s accident was most likely due to equipment problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Du Lei explained to Nandu reporters that in the process of continuous diving, divers need to adjust the proportion of inhaled gas according to pressure changes. But with a CCR, if the oxygen ratio decreases, the diver may not immediately notice it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Individuals may feel suffocated because the concentration of carbon dioxide in the blood is too high. However, CCR&#39;s carbon dioxide adsorbent will absorb all the carbon dioxide in the respiratory gas and will not cause people to feel suffocated.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once the oxygen supply equipment fails and the individual cannot feel the lack of oxygen, they may lose consciousness in an instant. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is currently unknown what happened when Han Ting lost contact underwater. But the departure of the &quot;man at the top&quot; does not mean that &quot;the building will collapse.&quot; On the road of adventure, brave men are still going forward. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I hope that people who are keen on exploration can learn from Han Ting’s research spirit and conduct exploration in a scientific way instead of blindly advancing. Only in this way can the entire industry become healthier.” Du Ray said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>