<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[多所高校督导学生坐前排：不提高“教风”先要求“学风”，属本末倒置丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261057]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, many colleges and universities have carried out &quot;study style&quot; construction and urged students to &quot;sit in the front row&quot; in class, which has caused concern. The school stipulates that if the front row is not full, the last row will be in violation, which is staggering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henan Xinxiang Medical College has launched a school-wide special inspection of academic style since November 20. The inspections included &quot;four no&#39;s&quot;: not bringing teaching materials, not taking notes, not asking questions, and not sitting in the front row. Phenomenon. Henan Institute of Technology requires the establishment of an &quot;inspection-nurture&quot; system, focusing on checking the &quot;attendance rate, head-up rate, and front-row student occupancy rate&quot; of students&#39; classrooms. The School of Transportation Engineering of Changsha University of Science and Technology requires students to take the initiative to &quot;sit in the front row, raise their heads, bring teaching materials, and ask questions&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first impression this gives people is , treating college students as children. In addition to requiring college students to bring textbooks, sit in the front row, and take notes, many colleges and universities require students not to stay in the dormitory for self-study at night, and there are also bed and hygiene checks. In fact, except for professional courses, classmates may not take the same courses, and different courses use different classrooms. They do not have fixed classrooms and locations like middle school and high school students. Why should we discipline college students like children and fail to respect the right of adults to self-determination? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was in college more than 20 years ago, I still remember that there were two ways for people to occupy positions. For courses with well-educated teachers, wonderful lectures, and popular courses, the front rows will be occupied first, and those who come later will have to sit in the back; for courses with mediocre or unsatisfactory teachers, dry lectures, and less popular courses, Those who came first would occupy the back row, while those who came later had to sit in the front row, endure the direct attention of the teacher, and had to pretend to listen carefully and respond positively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The former method is a medal for a good teacher. The latter method is often because although the class is not interesting or the teaching is poor, but you don’t want to fail, or because the teacher has to take attendance and take attendance, but he can’t retain the students. students will resist in a negative way. Therefore, some teachers often say in the first class: Come and go as you please, without calling names, but you will be responsible for not doing your homework or failing the exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, for teachers, their primary mission is to transfer valuable professional knowledge and skills to students by relying on their profound knowledge and superb teaching skills. This is to attract students rather than force them to accept it. own teaching content. Good spiritual food is full of fragrant air. If you don&#39;t say anything about peaches and plums, you will make your own mistakes. A melon that is twisted is not sweet, and a horse that doesn&#39;t drink water is meaningless. These principles are well known to everyone, and this is also the basic way to be a teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, teachers and schools can only ask themselves to have a good &quot;teaching style&quot; and convince students; instead of first requiring students to have a certain ideal &quot;study style&quot;, There are no requirements for teachers’ teaching ability. This is simply putting the cart before the horse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The lectures are clearly scripted and lackluster. They also require students to sit in the front row as if they are taking a popular course. They force students to raise their heads and act like they are listening attentively, interact in a pretentious manner, and deprive students of passive coping skills. The rights of the curriculum, this is simply to torture students mentally. Moreover, forcing bad courses and bad teachers to enjoy the same treatment as good courses and good teachers is like trying to sell rotten and sour apples at the same price as good and sweet apples. It is completely challenging the laws of the market and human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From an economic point of view, higher education or packaged professional subject knowledge products are no different from other goods and services. Teachers and schools are the providers, and students are the demanders. The rights and interests of both parties They are equal in terms of personality, and there is no reason why one party can discipline the other party infinitely. Reasonable classroom discipline is required. For example, no student can disrupt the peace and process of the classroom, because this damages the dignity of the teacher and the rights of other students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But conversely, it cannot be established as a rule or obligation to require college students to listen carefully, because college students are adults. From the perspective of interests, if he feels that the content is important, he will listen carefully and even study further after class. However, if he feels that he has mastered it, either this part of the content is not important, or he underestimates the importance of the content and wanders around. Outside of that, as long as it doesn&#39;t disrupt the peace and flow of the class, it shouldn&#39;t be considered a problem that needs to be solved. From the perspective of rights, there are reasonable boundaries between teachers and students. Students&#39; passive coping is the basic freedom. Students&#39; activeness and seriousness are earned (earned), not deserved. Let students grab the front row and occupy a good seat to get the best. The mental and spiritual enjoyment is the goal of teachers and can even be said to be their duty. At this point, the treatment of college students should be different from that of primary and secondary school students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for supervising whether college students bring textbooks and take notes, this ignores the characteristics of university knowledge transfer. As long as you go to a higher-end university and have teachers who are interested in teaching, the teaching materials for a course are often only outlines and summary, which will definitely involve the reading and discussion of a large number of related books and papers. Unless certain courses follow the textbook, it will be difficult to read. There is no reason why all students must bring textbooks; of course, if the textbook itself is a classic and worthy of in-depth study word for word, then students should generally bring textbooks, but if a student occasionally forgets to bring them, it is not a problem. It can be a perfect solution when used together in the classroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the teacher is reading from the text, there is no need for students to take notes; if the teacher’s lecture is particularly exciting, then the students will pay full attention and devote themselves to listening, absorbing, and absorbing what the teacher has to say. It becomes your own thing. There is no need to take notes in class, so as not to affect the absorption effect of the present. It can be summarized and organized afterwards, and it can further deepen the understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A good teaching and learning style is to respect students&#39; sovereignty as adults, allow students to exert their personal autonomy, enhance their ability to self-govern, and cultivate their sense of personal responsibility. The biggest difference between studying in universities and primary and secondary schools is that college students need to invest more in thinking and sharpen their personal understanding and analysis. Learning a major is to logically build a complete knowledge system in their brains and become a major. Part of subjectivity, the memory part is relatively secondary. Force and indoctrination are meaningless. Only things that students truly think through will become their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to improve the teaching style and study style of a certain university, a &quot;Typical Case of the School of Medical Imaging Testing and Rehabilitation&quot; was established, and three rules were established: &quot;Sit in the front row&quot;, requiring students to give priority to sitting in the front row; &quot;Double reporting&quot; , if the front row is not full, the school committee will record the list of students in the last row and report it to the teacher and counselor. Pay close attention to the implementation so that everyone does not dare to violate the rules: first time: anonymously report his behavior and ask other students to learn from it; second time: ask him to publicly review his name during the evening roll call, and the class will set up a special team to follow up and inspect; third time: Times: Inform parents that if they commit the crime again, they will need to come to the school to communicate, or they will be &quot;accompanied&quot;. Frankly speaking, this is a way to manage primary school students, and it is a very bad way to manage primary school students. It is not only inappropriate to use it on college students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寿光“明星”果蔬交易所被查，揭开“电子盘”风云二十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261073]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Shouguang is the largest vegetable distribution center in the country. Visual China/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/e4977a7f35.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/e4977a7f35.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259181&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shouguang It is the largest vegetable distribution center in the country. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After being summoned by the police, Qian Moyouxin went to Zhouyi. He asked a reporter from Southern Weekend for his birthday information and asked &quot;Master Zhou Yi&quot; for a divination. After learning that he and the reporter were destined to meet, he chose an auspicious day to meet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we met in his office, he was arranging flowers in an open glass vase about half a meter high. The flowers were pruned orchids. An empty vase indicates &quot;deficit&quot;, and all empty vases must be filled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest loss in his life occurred in the &quot;Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Electronic Disk&quot;. In just four years from 2012, he lost millions of dollars. As a result, the family fell apart and the curve of life fell to the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electronic trading is an imported product. It originally referred to the electronic bidding platform of the Chicago Mercantile Exchange for matching transactions. In China, electronic trading generally refers to electronic platforms for spot trading of commodities outside of official futures exchanges. It was originally established to promote the circulation of commodities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray was born in 2009 and moved to Tianjin the following year. It is operated by Shandong Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group (Tianjin) Commodity Trading Market Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Tianjin Trading Market). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shouguang is the administrative city of Weifang City and the largest vegetable distribution center in the country. Relying on the famous name of &quot;China&#39;s Hometown of Vegetables&quot;, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray once became a prestigious electronic tray, with agents all over the country and many traders. Until May 2020, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Pan suddenly announced that it would stop the account opening and deposit functions, and the company entity was canceled in November. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aftermath is even more turbulent. In April 2023, the Public Security Bureau of Ju County, Rizhao City, Shandong Province launched an investigation into the Tianjin Trading Market for &quot;suspected illegal business operations&quot; and took criminal measures against the operation management team and some regional agents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the county-level agent of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Distribution District, Qian Moyou was also implicated. In September, he learned from the local police that he was on the fugitive list and needed to go to the Ju County Public Security Bureau to explain the situation and turn over his illegal gains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another agent told Southern Weekend reporters that he had handed over two million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The subsequent development of electronic disks deviated from the original idea. A large number of trading platforms suspected of disguised futures and illegal operations were shut down and cancelled. &quot;It&#39;s a tough battle, a look back, and a clean-up. No industry can continue to clean up and rectify for more than ten years like the spot trading market.&quot; Wang Zaiwei, secretary-general of the Commodity Trading Place Innovation Service Alliance, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also introduced that there were more than 1,000 trading venues in the country at their peak, but today there are only about 200 left, and more than 200 of them are state-owned holdings and approved by provincial governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will the electronic disk, which has grown wildly, come to an end? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Business extended by agents&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“They were banned long ago, so there were not so many people entering the market later.” Qian Moyou recalled that the person who introduced him to open an account had vowed It is said that other trays will die upon inspection, but only the Shouguang fruit and vegetable tray is safe and sound, which shows that it is legitimate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was 2012. After more than 20 years of entrepreneurship, Qian Moyou had saved some funds, but the company was facing a development bottleneck. It happened that a friend introduced him to Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Pan to invest. Out of a businessman&#39;s caution and unfamiliarity with the agricultural products industry, he was hesitant at first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing that he was still undecided, his friend found a teacher who was familiar with the operation of Shouguang fruit and vegetable trays. The teacher actually plays the role of &quot;calling orders&quot; and guides Qian Moyou to buy and sell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, Qian Moyou registered as an agent on the Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate website (you can open several accounts), along with several relatives and friends, including public officials and people in the financial industry. &quot;They saw that I had a large amount of funds and suggested that I register as an agent to save some handling fees.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, the Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray should attract traders engaged in agriculture. However, according to Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate&#39;s &quot;Spot Spot Transaction Management Measures&quot; obtained by Southern Weekend reporters, you only need to provide your ID card and bank card number to open an account, and you do not need to provide supporting materials if you have a background in the agricultural products industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The software interface used for trading is the same as that of general futures and stock trading software. You can see the price trend K-line chart and centralized bidding transaction information. You can buy or sell agricultural product contracts by paying a 20% margin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Trading adopts the &quot;T+0&quot; system, and contracts of the same direction and type can be traded frequently on the same day. Varieties include pumpkin, winter melon, carrot, dried pepper, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the guidance of the teacher in the early stage, Qian Moyou made a small profit, so he invested more and more funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Moyou typed out the transaction records of several bank cards used for operations at that time, transferred a large number of accounts to himself, and transferred the funds to the Tianjin trading market. But Qian Moyou didn&#39;t want to pull anyone&#39;s head. The few names on the list that he couldn&#39;t remember were the handling fees he returned to the customers at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike Qian Moyou, most agents not only make profits from market transactions, but also service fees are their main source of income. Only when a steady stream of customers open accounts in their own names and guide customers to frequent transactions can agents bring generous returns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electronic disk development relies on agents. For district and county-level agents like Qian Moyou, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray generally refunds 75% of the transaction fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a 2011 judgment, agent Cui signed an agreement with Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray, and the other party entrusted it to develop customers and give customers a 75% rebate on transaction fees. If Cui&#39;s downline Wang continues to develop customers, he will receive a 70% rebate, and if Wang continues to develop his downline Li, he will receive a 68% rebate, once a week. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter contacted the original Zhengzhou agent of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Pan in the name of opening an account. He now provides online account opening for another agricultural product spot trading market, Shengtong Jiulong. If you recommend customers to him, you can open an account according to the daily schedule. The commission will be returned and 75% of the customer&#39;s transaction fee will be obtained. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;After killing the long side, kill the short side&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After following the teacher for a period of time, Qian Moyou initially grasped the trading logic. Take potatoes as an example. Compare the market and spot prices. If the spot price is high, buy long; if the spot price is low, sell short. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He divided his own funds into more than 20 accounts, and worked with the company&#39;s employees to earn a few points from trading every day, which was enough for a day&#39;s salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the methods taught by teachers sometimes work and sometimes fail. Among Qian Moyou&#39;s friends, some have studied K-line technical knowledge, but they are of no use in the Shouguang fruit and vegetable tray. In the four years since he entered the market, Qian Moyou has &quot;cut his flesh&quot; three or four times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most severe &quot;overturn&quot; was the pumpkin contract in 2014. Qian Moyou made a short order based on the spot market and was able to earn a few points at the beginning. After big funds came in, the market stopped moving. After that, when he opened the website for several days, the limit dropped, and suddenly the limit started to rise in the opposite direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to keep his position, Qian Moyou had to continue to add margin calls, and even borrowed money from friends and invested all of it in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the delivery month, Qian Moyou will top up the margin according to the specified date. Having already made a heavy bet, he firmly believed that the market would return to the spot price and the loss would not be too large. However, the end result was that the market price deviated seriously from the spot price, which also made him want to find goods offline for delivery and close the position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, Qian Moyou contacted the pumpkin dealer in Yancheng. After some inquiries, the idea of ​​delivery was shattered. After seeing the product quality, appearance, color and other standards stipulated in the delivery agreement, a Yancheng melon seller regretted that the regulations were too detailed. Even if he collected the melons from all the melon farmers in the city and let him choose at will, he would not be able to get the goods stipulated in the agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Moyou finally came to his senses and decisively exited the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;For someone like you, losing millions is nothing.&quot; Dong Hangge spoke in thick Hebei and Lu mandarin. Hearing what happened to Qian Moyou, as a friend he couldn&#39;t help but Ridicule. Dong Hangge, as the municipal agent of Shouguang fruit and vegetable trays, is now also under investigation by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Hangge’s experience in investing in electronic trading is much richer than that of Qian Moyou. He has participated in the famous Dragon Cauldron Trading and has learned the ropes of electronic trading - you have to buy against the main funds to make money. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This is a virtual disk, do you understand?&quot; Dong Hangge couldn&#39;t help but say, you are real money, and the person who is &quot;in charge&quot; is a string of fictitious numbers. Assuming that all the main funds are doing long, the market will pull in the opposite direction, forcing the long parties to cut their losses. Only by guessing the right direction can you make money along the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, working as an agent earns handling fees, but it is not enough to earn handling fees alone. He also has to help his big customers make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to inquire about the flow of funds on the market, Dong Hangge once hired a young college graduate to lurk into the municipal agent with the largest amount of client funds to inquire about the direction. He then directed his clients to go in the opposite direction. Do. On a potato contract, one of his big clients earned a full eight million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Hangge suggested that big customers should close the deal as soon as they get a good deal. Unfortunately, the customers were not satisfied. As Dong Hangge expected, the dish was full of flavour, and the customer vomited out more than half of what he had eaten. &quot;If someone (the banker) kills the short side, he will definitely turn around and kill you on the long side.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Taking the &quot;Shouguang Garlic Plate&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before going to the Public Security Bureau, Qian Moyou spent more than ten dollars I searched for information every day to study why I was &quot;operating illegally.&quot; Only then did we discover that the spot trading market was once a product of local economic revitalization and innovation and reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chang Qing, founder of China Futures Market and former researcher at the Development Research Center of the State Council, told Southern Weekend reporters that agricultural product production is scattered and farmers need price signals that can reflect market supply and demand to rationally allocate resources. &quot;The Shouguang Vegetable Wholesale Market can solve the problem of vegetable circulation, but it cannot solve the problem of low prices of vegetables hurting farmers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 1990, China has successively established five major futures exchanges. However, most agricultural products failed to enter the futures market. Chang Qing explained that most agricultural products are not suitable for entering the futures market with a large amount of capital due to their small delivery volume and easy contract manipulation (forced position). However, these varieties can be traded and innovated by local platforms or wholesale markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, Shouguang began to explore medium and forward trading of vegetables, which is equivalent to locking in the price of agricultural products for farmers in advance. It is a trading model between futures and spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2005, with the approval of the Shandong Provincial Government, four units including the China Vegetable Circulation Association jointly funded the establishment of Shandong Shouguang Vegetable Electronic Trading Market Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Shouguang Electronic Market), which can realize &quot;unplanted vegetables&quot;. &quot;Sell first&quot; and &quot;sell before receiving&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Jun, the manager of Shouguang Electronic Disk at the time, introduced that Shouguang Electronic Disk will announce the purchase price for the next 10 months, and the growers or brokers will sell the orders before planting, and deliver the quality products at maturity. goods to avoid the risks brought by falling prices to farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zaiwei began operating a commodity exchange in Shandong in 2007. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the trading volume of garlic varieties was good in the early days, and most of the participants were cold storage owners, garlic dealers and brokers. These people themselves are spot customers. Through electronic transactions, they only need advance payment to complete the transaction, saving warehousing and transportation costs. &quot;The purpose of (local trading venues) is to support the actual needs of spot customers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the electronic trading did not operate as originally envisioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shouguang electronic plate really started to become famous because of garlic, and thus got a more famous name &quot;Shouguang garlic plate&quot;. Garlic is also called &quot;white tiger&quot;. Tigers can eat people, and garlic can also eat people. If investors are not careful, they will lose all their money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high volatility of garlic prices has made it the most suitable variety for speculation among vegetables. Although Shouguang is the hometown of vegetables, it does not produce garlic. In 2005, Shouguang electronic disk entered the &quot;Garlic Township&quot; - Jinxiang County, Jining City, Shandong Province. By 2010, Jinxiang County had gathered five or six electronic trading markets. Among them, the two larger ones, besides Shouguang Electronic Trading, were Longding Electronic Trading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;At that time, electronic disk was regarded as an emerging industry such as e-commerce, and many local governments actively introduced it as a key project.&quot; Zhao Defa, former vice chairman of the Shandong Provincial Writers Association, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Defa wrote in his documentary work &quot;White Tiger&quot; that &quot;Garlic God&quot; Dong Zigang helped Shouguang build a garlic electronic disk. A president of the Garlic Chamber of Commerce commented that since Dong Zigang joined the industry, traditional trade has been changed and capital operations have been introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Zigang is from Junan, Shandong, and settled in Weifang. He made his fortune in Shouguang Garlic Distribution, and successively operated Jinxiang Nandianzi and Hengli Distribution, and served as the president of Hengfeng Electronic Distribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electronic disks also created a myth - Fu Haitang, a farmer with a background in pig raising. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2009, Fu Haitang invested tens of thousands of yuan earned in soybean meal futures into Shouguang electronic trading. Coinciding with the rare &quot;garlic you are ruthless&quot; market, Shouguang electronic trading has introduced a &quot;centralized transfer&quot; system, that is, if there are three consecutive daily limit or three lower limit, positions will be closed by agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Haitang wrote in his self-report that the main short seller at the time greeted the exchange. When the market price of garlic increased 30 times, he only earned 700,000 and was transferred centrally, so he switched to Longding Pan. , earned 6 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was also this wave of market conditions that caused the short sellers of the Long Ding Pan to misjudge the situation, which even dragged down the Long Ding Pan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, Rizhao City Deputy Mayor Wantong announced the results of the investigation into the Longding electronic trading incident to traders: After the garlic market changed dramatically, Longding failed to liquidate short sellers in accordance with regulations and instead lent Hou Dawei, the main short seller, used 30 million virtual funds to short-sell. After losing money, he misappropriated customer margins to continue short-selling and bet against traders, resulting in a serious deviation between the market price and the spot price. He lost hundreds of millions of margins and traders were unable to withdraw money normally. And after some contracts enter the delivery period, there are still huge amounts of open positions that cannot be delivered smoothly, causing disputes over delivery breaches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This matter quickly triggered a regulatory storm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission led 7 ministries and commissions to form a State Council commodity trading market investigation team that entered Shandong, and its first stop was Weifang. &quot;China Business News&quot; reported that Jiang Yang, then chairman of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, inspected a commodity trading venue in Weifang and denounced the incident angrily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this round of regulatory rectification, many electronic disks collapsed due to problems such as virtual fund transactions, poor delivery, and founders running away with their money. Executives were arrested and jailed. However, the huge funds gathered in electronic disks It still attracts batches of &quot;gamblers&quot;. If you pour down a platform, you will burn a platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zaiwei once wrote that from 2007 to 2010, a large number of trading venues emerged in Shandong, forming a situation where &quot;the whole country looks to Shandong for bulk, and Shandong looks to Weifang for bulk&quot;. &quot;There was no approval, no review, no supervision, no rules. At that time, it was completely open to work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if you get the approval, you still rely on the platform to show your magic. There are various approval departments, &quot;There are National Development and Reform Commission, Commerce Bureau, as well as the Finance Office.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, the Economic Development Zone Branch of the Yancheng City Public Security Bureau of Jiangsu Province characterized Hengfeng Electronic Trading as a disguised futures market, and Dong Zigang was jailed for ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Shouguang electronic disk survived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2009, Shouguang Electronic Disk was acquired by the private enterprise Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holding Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings), which was owned by Shandong Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group) ) is funded and established. On June 17 of the same year, Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group established Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the official website, Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group has been selected as one of the top 500 national key leading enterprises in agricultural industrialization and is a nationally renowned operator of the entire vegetable industry chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Move to Tianjin&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Either leave or close.&quot; Wang Zaiwei said that Jiang Yang&#39;s inspection put great pressure on the Weifang government, and several local exchanges were forced to make a choice. It was at this stage that Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray moved to Tianjin, and Tianjin also became a new gathering place for various exchanges across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings revealed in an interview with the self-media &quot;High Power Lens&quot; that Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray was invited by the Tianjin Municipal Government to move to Tianjin in December 2010 as a key agricultural financial innovation project. Settled in Binhai New Area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Each region’s understanding and cognition of commodity trading are very different.” Wang Zaiwei said that whether trading venues can continue to operate at this stage depends on the attitude of local regulatory authorities. In other words, the attitude of local regulatory authorities is crucial. play a decisive role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the clean-up and rectification becomes more stringent, provincial people&#39;s governments formulate regulatory rules for exchanges. Some local governments assign regulatory responsibilities to the Commerce Bureau and some to the Financial Bureau. &quot;There are still huge differences in regulatory policies across the country.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Economic Herald, from 2010 to April 2013, the professional managers of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray were Ji Hairong and Meng Qingchao (who did not hold shares). President Ji Hairong is the soul of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate. He has worked for many commodity exchanges. People in the industry are more familiar with his QQ nickname &quot;Tycoon&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2012, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray also revealed the problem of poor settlement that cannot be escaped from electronic trading. In April 2013, Ji Hairong and Meng Qingchao both lost contact. Later, it was confirmed by the media that Ji Hairong and others had been taken compulsory measures by the Shouguang City Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray is still operating normally after the accident of the two responsible persons. In their resignation announcement, they also stated that their business operations during their tenure were in compliance with relevant national laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the years of operation of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray, its historical shareholders include Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group, Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings, etc., and the major shareholder is Yang Ming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Ming is quite mysterious and low-key, and the locals know little about him. At present, his appearance can only be seen from the company&#39;s official website: sparse hair, a shiny forehead, and a beer belly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A municipal agent has participated in several Shouguang fruit and vegetable plate meetings and met Yang Ming and a group of senior executives. The guests attending the meeting were all government officials and experts in the futures field, and they preached about the standardization of the platform. After the meeting, experts will also attend a banquet with the leaders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The offices of Shouguang Vegetable Industry Group and Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings controlled by Yang Ming are both located in Shouguang Vegetable Building. Southern Weekend reporter Zhou Xiaoling/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/6bc7c988e8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/22/6bc7c988e8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259182&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shouguang Vegetables of Yang Ming Holdings Industrial Group and Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings, their offices are located in Shouguang Vegetable Building. Southern Weekend reporter Zhou Xiaoling/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Futures or spot? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Electronic disks like Shouguang fruit and vegetable disk were established as spot trading markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wang Deyi, director of Beijing Xunzhen Law Firm, told Southern Weekend reporters that in the Shouguang fruit and vegetable market, a large number of customers engage in electronic transactions without physical delivery and buy and sell standardized contracts in a centralized transaction manner. There are many cases in the Supreme People&#39;s Court. This is the core feature of &quot;illegal futures&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of spot commodities, Wang Deyi’s legal team has obtained the first winning verdicts in many places, and has represented many contract disputes between Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray investors and trading platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You Zhihui, who lives in Jiangsu, is one of the few investors interviewed who has had delivery experience. Since most investors have never actually participated in the delivery, they do not know the location of the delivery warehouse for Shouguang fruit and vegetable trays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2016, You Zhihui has been operating in Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray for a year and a half, but lost 1.2 million yuan. What really made him lose trust in the market was a delivery the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the eve of delivery, You Zhihui received a delivery note for dried chili peppers sent to him by the agent. The payment date was March 1, 2017, and he was required to complete the delivery procedures on March 2. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bill of lading shows that the quality grade is standard product, the unit of measurement is 78 tons, and the delivery warehouse is Yinshan Cold Storage in Maying Township, Wucheng County, Texas. Qichacha showed that the cold storage did store dried chili peppers. The delivery contact is Shan Yongning, who is the legal representative of Tianjin Trading Market. Southern Weekend reporters called the contact number on the delivery note, but the number could no longer be reached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that You Zhihui traveled more than 700 kilometers to Dezhou, Shandong Province, so there was little point in taking the transportation fee to transport it back to Jiangsu. To this end, You Zhihui contacted several local pepper purchasers to deliver the goods together. The purchasers would calculate the price after inspecting the goods and take them away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the problem lies in the acceptance process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The warehouse handover party asked You Zhihui to send a truck to pick up the goods on the delivery day, but refused to provide the product warehousing information. As a result, You Zhihui was unable to verify whether the goods were the goods agreed in the contract, and also refused You Zhihui to bring the purchaser into the warehouse for inspection. goods. The warehouse transfer party even wanted to buy You Zhihui&#39;s dried chili peppers at a very low price. You Zhihui&#39;s application for re-inspection to the trading market did not help, and the settlement failed in the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the electronic disks that Wang Deyi has come into contact with cannot clearly introduce the flow of customer funds, cannot truly present the total trading volume and physical delivery volume data of the trading venue, and are also unable to inform the number of customers with physical delivery and investment speculation. number of clients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, frequently changing prices do not actually encourage delivery, and investors all hope to earn the difference through spreads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buying and selling standardized contracts is also one of the characteristics of futures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Securities Regulatory Commission has a detailed definition of standardized contracts: apart from terms such as price, delivery location and delivery time, other terms are relatively fixed. After the contract is concluded, traders are allowed to exit the market through reverse operations and hedging and liquidation without actually performing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other terms refer to the quantity of traded commodities, trading margin, quotation unit, delivery quality standards, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have compared the text of the (Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Plate) with the strong wheat futures contract of the Zhengzhou Commodity Exchange, and there is no essential difference between the two.” Wang Deyi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the trading model and transaction details of Shouguang Fruit and Vegetable Tray all point to &quot;futures&quot;, the lawsuit is still difficult to fight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a large number of effective judgments on the Tianjin trading market, the courts in Tianjin did not determine it as illegal futures. The basis is that since the State Council issued Document No. 38 in 2011 and Document No. 37 in 2012, it has not been closed, banned or suspended due to illegal futures activities or futures transactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Tianjin Second Intermediate People&#39;s Court once accepted the case of dispute between Dong Yumei and the Tianjin Exchange Market sales contract. In the second-instance judgment, the Tianjin Exchange submitted evidence showing that after 2012, the Tianjin Leading Group for Cleaning Up and Rectifying Various Trading Places organized an annual review of the supervision of trading places, and the Tianjin Exchange was listed in the &quot;List of Trading Places that Passed the Annual Supervision Review&quot; 》No. 14. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter called Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings, hoping to interview the relevant person in charge. The person who answered the call claimed to be a staff member of the general office and said that he could not convey the interview request. Later, Southern Weekend reporters went to Shouguang Vegetable Building, the company&#39;s office on Haoyuan Road, but were intercepted by the guard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Tianjin trading market, Shouguang Vegetable Industry Holdings also has similar bulk commodity trading platforms in Sichuan, Shandong and other places. Among them, the exchange in Beichuan Qiang Autonomous County will be deregistered in 2021, and the two in Qingdao will operate until 2023. When Southern Weekend reporters visited recently, they found that their teams had withdrawn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Southern Weekend reporters visited two trading platforms in Qingdao and learned from security and front desk staff that Qingdao trading market staff were taken away by the police in May, and Qingdao Huihai was taken away by the police in September. Evacuate the office of Qingdao Kangda Wealth Center. Southern Weekend reporter Zhou Xiaoling/Photo&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/c91925dd3e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/c91925dd3e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259183&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters visited two trading platforms in Qingdao and learned from security guards and front desk staff that Qingdao trading market staff were arrested by the police in May 2023. Taken away, Qingdao Huihai evacuated the office of Qingdao Kangda Wealth Center in September. Southern Weekend reporter Zhou Xiaoling/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Those who farm do not speculate, and those who speculate do not farm”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The agricultural product spot trading market carries the reform expectations of futures experts and the expectations of local governments. Industrial vision, but how much role has this more than ten years of industrial innovation played? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters went to Shouguang Dili Logistics Park, the largest agricultural product logistics park, and asked more than a dozen agricultural product wholesalers if they knew about Shouguang fruit and vegetable trays. Most of them waved their hands after listening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I think no one in this market knows what you are talking about.&quot; Zhen Ling is from Heilongjiang, born in 1980. She has been engaged in pumpkin wholesale in the logistics park for more than 20 years. She grins like the comedian Jia Jia Ling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She sat in the huge trading floor watching TV shows and replying to customer messages from time to time. Her customer base is relatively fixed. Around 12 noon, there were not many people asking for prices at her stall. She told Southern Weekend reporters that the biggest role of the logistics park is to complete product grading and transshipment. Vegetables from all over the country will be transshipped here and then sent to all parts of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhen Ling, who considers herself a pumpkin expert, can keep an eye on the pumpkin market for more than 20 days. Farmers are betting on the weather. There may be a flood or a frost, and everything in the fields will be destroyed. No one dares to predict what will happen in half a year, and they can&#39;t predict it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the price fluctuations of agricultural products will also form fluctuation patterns. The market has been very poor in the past two years, and it is almost time to rise in the third year. There is no need to predict this, everyone can understand it. As a first-level wholesaler, Zhen Ling is never afraid of price fluctuations. &quot;We can only make money when prices rise and fall.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhen Ling will also deal directly with pumpkin farmers. For pumpkin farmers, regardless of whether the market is good or bad, they will still grow this species. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each county in Shouguang has special agricultural products. Farmers will bring fruits and vegetables from their own greenhouses to the county wholesale market for sale, and wholesalers will also go to different counties to purchase according to needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gaoming&#39;s family lives in Sun Jiaji Town in the southwest of Shouguang. This is also the birthplace of the winter warm vegetable greenhouse. Shouguang &quot;Caiwang&quot; Wang Leyi lives in Sanyuan Zhucun in Sun Jiaji Town. Sun Jiaji Town is based on planting cucumber and bitter gourd, and the greenhouses of every family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Out of the understanding of agricultural products, Gaoming&#39;s &quot;sacotics&quot; has been more than ten years. He has many times in Jinxiang to stock garlic and garlic, and sell it again when the price is good, which is equivalent to the &quot;two roads Trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It has heard of Shouguang Vegetables and fruit plates. Many people in the village have done transactions on the garlic disk, but this shift of the electronic disk is not necessarily farmer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Make money fast, lose money fast, the market is different from reality, and farmers will not watch this.&quot; Now the &quot;savings&quot; market is not good, and Gao Ming also started a large shed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After being found by the public security, Qian Moyou established a contact with the people who had done Shouguang Fruit and Vegetables in the past. Most of them were people like him without agricultural background. &quot; Stir -frying is not planted. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (at the request of the respondent, Qian Moyou, Dong Hang Ge, You Zhihui, Zhen Ling, Gaoming is a pseudonym) &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花大价钱建雕塑，地方的“面子”与里子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261078]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-22 18:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; Zhongjiang County, Sichuan, a &quot;bad tail&quot; scenic area stores nearly 2,000 sculptures. middle. The truth emerges: the scenic area illegally occupies agricultural land, the construction party&#39;s capital chain breaks, and the developer has regulated the representative of the representative of the suspension. The sculpture is the &quot;face&quot; of the local, but it should be the lilices of shaping the humanistic connotation. Jingzhou, Hubei, spent 170 million to build a giant Guan Gong statue, Guizhou Jianhe County, Guizhou, with a total of 86 million buildings with a total high 88 -meter Miao goddess, and 7.152 million built -in construction of the cowherd weaver statue of the &quot;ugly and expensive&quot; cowboy weaver statue ... Behind the &quot;grand&quot; of sculpture, behind the &quot;grand&quot;, it is bound to be amplified by public opinion.</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年两院院士增选结果揭晓，共133人当选]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261082]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 17:35:07&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 22, the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the Chinese Academy of Engineering announced the list of elected academicians for the 2023 academician election. Among them, China The Academy of Sciences has 59 new academicians and the Chinese Academy of Sciences has 74 new academicians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern+ reporters combed through the list and found that a total of 8 &quot;big names&quot; in Guangdong were newly elected as academicians of the two academies. The specific list is as follows: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun Sun Yat-sen University Cancer Prevention and Treatment Center&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Ning Tsinghua University, Shenzhen Academy of Medical Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Hongping Guangzhou Institute of Geochemistry, Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zheng Hairong Shenzhen Institute of Advanced Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chinese Academy of Engineering&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Enhou South China University of Technology&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Qingquan Shenzhen University&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xing Feng Guangzhou University&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Chao Guangdong Drug Experimental Technology Center (National Drug Laboratory Guangdong Branch)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The full list is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/a93bd531fc839694def7c5514999c0d6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;3199&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/a93bd531fc839694def7c5514999c0d6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259312&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ce99d370bd12e6ef5a6ed31a3a0d1733.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;3277&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/ce99d370bd12e6ef5a6ed31a3a0d1733.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259311&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国最后的狩猎部落，在大兴安岭饲养驯鹿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261075]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 16:20:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第二届全国人力资源服务业发展大会今日在深圳开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261077]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 16:41:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 21, the press conference before the Second National Human Resources Service Industry Development Conference was held. The reporter learned that the conference will be held at the Shenzhen International Convention and Exhibition Center from November 22 to 23. The theme of this conference is &quot;Stimulating the Momentum of Human Resources and Gathering Power to Build a Strong Country&quot;, including opening and closing activities, &quot;conferences&quot; and &quot;exhibitions&quot;. There are four sections: &quot;Competition&quot; and &quot;Recruitment&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Human resources are the first resource of the economy and society. The National Human Resources Service Development Conference is an important platform for exchanges and presentations, supply and demand negotiations, innovation and entrepreneurship in the field of human resources services. The human resources service industry in Guangdong and the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area cherish this exhibition opportunity. The reporter learned from the press conference that there are currently 5,845 human resources service agencies in the province, of which private enterprises account for more than 90%, with revenue of 294.5 billion yuan, and an average annual growth rate of 13.7% since the &quot;13th Five-Year Plan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The activities in the four sections are colorful&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The activities of this conference are colorful, including &quot;meeting&quot;, &quot;exhibition&quot;, &quot;competition&quot; and &quot;recruitment&quot;. This section. Zhang Wenmiao, Director of the Mobility Management Department of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, introduced that the “meeting” refers to a seminar on the high-quality development of the human resources service industry. It has three sub-forums, namely the High-quality Development Forum of the Human Resources Service Industry and the Human Resources Service of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area. High-quality industry development forum and a forum to promote the rapid development of key industries. At that time, experts, scholars and business representatives from academia and industry will give speeches, conduct discussions and exchanges, and discuss development plans in the field of human resources services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Exhibition&quot; means that the supply and demand negotiation and display activities of human resources services will be invited to invite 144 human resources service leaders and Guangdong -Hong Kong -Macao key employers to participate in exhibitions. A large number of high -quality projects will negotiate and sign contracts. A series of innovations will be Technology and products will be focused on roadshows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Competition&quot; refers to the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition and the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Human Resources Service Skills Competition. Among them, the Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition is divided into two categories: start-up and growth. A total of 1,022 projects across the country have signed up to participate. 145 projects were selected from various regions through preliminary rounds, and semi-finals and finals were held during the conference to determine the final ranking. The participating projects cover promoting employment of key groups such as college graduates, serving the real economy, and protecting workers&#39; rights and interests. The finals of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Human Resources Service Skills Competition will be held during the conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Jin” is the recruitment activity for young talents in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area. It organizes 1,395 key employers and leading human resources service companies in the Greater Bay Area to hold special recruitment sessions for domestic college graduates and overseas students. There are special areas for chain master enterprises, Greater Bay Area city enterprises, high-tech enterprises, state-owned enterprises, listed enterprises, &quot;specialized, special and new&quot; enterprises, master&#39;s and doctorate talents, etc., providing more than 50,000 high-quality jobs online and offline. At the same time, services such as live broadcasts, employment guidance, school -enterprise negotiations, and government -enterprise performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Guangdong submitted signing projects to the conference&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Achieved an intention of cooperation of 9.7 billion yuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“In recent years, the human resources service industry in Guangdong Province has experienced rapid development. development, service products are becoming increasingly abundant, and output value and scale have maintained a high growth trend.&quot; Du Minqi, director of the Guangdong Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security, said that as the organizer of this conference, Guangdong attaches great importance to hosting and participating in the conference. &quot;The four sectors of &quot;competition&quot; and &quot;employment&quot; are actively working hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Human Resources Service Industry High-quality Development Forum to be held on the afternoon of the 22nd, with the theme of &quot;Bay&quot; image renewal and surging momentum, will be held through video connections, keynote speeches, Through round-table dialogues and other forms, we will conduct in-depth discussions on the construction of a high-level talent highland in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area and the path to high-quality development of the human resources service industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of negotiation and display of supply and demand for human resources services, more than 50 exhibitors from Guangdong Province submitted more than 80 contract projects and reached an intended cooperation amount of 9.7 billion yuan. At the same time, the Greater Bay Area Achievement Exhibition with the theme of “Talent Gathering in the Bay Area, Industry Prospering the Future” will be held to showcase the development of the Greater Bay Area and the human resources service industry through information, technology, interactive experience and other rich exhibition formats. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of the Human Resources Service Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition, human resources service innovation and entrepreneurship projects, technologies and products have been collected from all industries across the province. Currently, 6 participating projects in Guangdong have advanced to the national semi-finals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of youth talent recruitment activities in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, more than 1,100 key enterprises and institutions and leading human resources service companies in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area have been organized, and the &quot;Industry-Education Evaluation&quot; skills ecological chain has been introduced. Resources such as recruitment for main institutions and high-level talent recruitment for masters and PhDs will further improve the quality of supply-demand matching and recruitment activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that this conference focuses on integrating into the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area and has many Hong Kong and Macao elements. One of the key activities of the conference - the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area Human Resources Service Skills Competition invites Hong Kong, Macau and nine mainland cities in the Greater Bay Area to participate. The competition is divided into four parts: personal style display, blind box answering, scene answering, and difficulty challenge. , 22 players will participate in the finals on the 23rd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Zhongliang, director of the Shenzhen Municipal Human Resources and Social Security Bureau, said that the conference will also set up an exhibition on the development achievements of the human resources service industry in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, with key content including the display of talent policies for Hong Kong and Macao. At the same time, an independent booth of the Hong Kong Talent Office was set up, the Hong Kong Labor and Welfare Bureau was invited to conduct a talent policy promotion roadshow, and 20 well-known organizations from Hong Kong and Macau were invited to participate in the job fair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[时隔三年，广州国际灯光节再次“光耀羊城”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261069]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 16:10:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a couple hugged by the Pearl River Enjoy the Guangzhou International Light Festival performance on Canton Tower.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/bfdbe84f95.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/bfdbe84f95.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259170&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 21, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, a couple hugged by the Pearl River and enjoyed the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival performance presented on Canton Tower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 12th Guangzhou International Light Festival will be officially held from November 21 to 30, 2023. It will be the first time to reopen offline after 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This year&#39;s lighting festival is themed &quot;Dazzle the Bay Area, Shine Yangcheng, and Create a Smart Future&quot; and is divided into &quot;new central axis venues&quot; (Huacheng Square, Haixinsha Asian Games Park, Canton Tower) and &quot;One River and Two Sides Venue&quot; (24 architectural media facades along Yanjiang Road, Haixin Bridge, Liede Bridge), a total of 25 sets of light and shadow art works are illuminated at the same time, combined with AR (augmented reality) ) visual technology to comprehensively display Guangzhou’s gorgeous city night views and cultural charm. The multi-dimensional integration and innovation of light and shadow technology and Guangzhou culture will become an excellent &quot;check-in place&quot; in Guangzhou in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival opened. A tourist took a selfie with the Canton Tower on his mobile phone.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/53631619bb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/22/53631619bb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259171&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 21, 2023 Guangzhou, Guangdong, at the opening of the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival, a tourist took a selfie with the Canton Tower on his mobile phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, when the Canton Tower met the Light Festival, its shape looked particularly enchanting.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/22/25e4f463e7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/22/25e4f463e7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259172&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, when When Canton Tower meets the Light Festival, its shape looks particularly enchanting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the light-up event on the night of November 21st, the historical heritage of Guangzhou&#39;s thousand-year city, cultural and commercial history was condensed with the help of modern light and shadow technology. The legendary images visible to the naked eye, the five-color five-color sheep coming with ears of ears, the auspicious awakening lion standing with its head held high, the soaring cloud dragon and red bird... In just 3 minutes, the waterfall-like light and shadow images broke through the &quot;dimensional wall&quot; one after another, and they were born. The Canton Tower jumped up, setting off a visual feast dedicated to Lingnan legends on both sides of the Pearl River, and also lit up the &quot;flowers of light and shadow&quot; dedicated to the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival on the central axis of the flower city in Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the lighting works display of Haixin Bridge and Liede Bridge belong to the &quot;One River and Two Sides Venue&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7f08bc249e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/22/7f08bc249e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 21, 2023 On the same day, in Guangzhou, Guangdong, the lighting works display on Haixin Bridge and Liede Bridge were part of the &quot;One River and Two Sides Venue&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a light and shadow art work was displayed at the &quot;New Central Axis Venue&quot; of the Light Festival. A total of 25 groups of light and shadow art works were lit at the same time.&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/802507970e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/802507970e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259174&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, a light and shadow art work at the &quot;New Central Axis Venue&quot; of the Lighting Festival. A total of 25 sets of light and shadow art works are illuminated at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is reported that this year’s lighting festival adopts a closed reservation system for entry, and entry must be verified with the original valid ID (certificate used for reservation). If you want to know the reservation channels, lighting time, AR show and other performance details, you can pay attention to the information released by official accounts such as &quot;Guangzhou International Lighting Festival&quot; and &quot;Guangzhou Haixinsha&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival is divided into &quot;New Central Axis Venue&quot; and &quot;One River and Two Sides Venue&quot;, which will become the unique venue in Guangzhou in the future. The best &quot;check-in place&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7aabd19bb0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/7aabd19bb0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259175&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 21, 2023, Guangzhou, Guangdong, the Guangzhou International Lighting Festival is divided into a &quot;new central axis venue&quot; and a &quot;one river and two sides venue&quot;, which will become the best venue in Guangzhou in the future. The &quot;check-in place&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蹭老式消费兴起：有助于青年与长者互相学习]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261033]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, there have been some intersections in consumer demand between young people and middle-aged and elderly groups, which has attracted attention. For example, young people Signing up for the &quot;Sunset Red&quot; tour group, some office workers who don&#39;t want to order takeout flocked to the canteen for the elderly, and some young people squeezed into various interest classes at the university for the elderly and discovered &quot;really delicious&quot;... These new trends on social platforms, It is ridiculed by the outside world as &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot;. Why has moving closer to the consumption patterns of middle-aged and elderly people become the “life they aspire to” for many young people? How to treat it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, I think the direct motivation for &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; is low price attraction. Whether it is a &quot;Sunset Red&quot; tour group, a canteen for the elderly, or a university for the elderly, what they all have in common is the relatively low price. The presupposition is that the elderly retire from their jobs and have no financial resources except pensions. With little other income, the selling price of goods or services targeted at this group is naturally lower than the normal market price. More importantly, as part of the social security system for the elderly, the government pays for some services or items (in this case, there is some controversy about young people taking advantage of the elderly), and some businesses have also started to pay for them in order to promote sales. Give it to the elderly. The fact that young people are &quot;mingling among them&quot; undoubtedly reflects their pursuit of low-priced goods or services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, traveling can be regarded as a relaxing experience. The recipes in the elderly canteen will most likely not be any different. The courses taught by the elderly university cover flower arrangement, painting, calligraphy and other talents and skills. Skills, the quality of these goods or services will not be too bad. In other words, it is not an exaggeration to say that the above-mentioned goods or services have the basic characteristics of &quot;high quality and low price&quot; and good cost performance. Young people have discovered this opportunity and made full use of it to enrich and enrich themselves. I think it is a wise move. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this truly reflects the objective fact that young people are under great pressure to survive. The overall economy is in a downward trend, the population is aging, the subsequent impact of the epidemic has not been completely eliminated, and the number of college graduates is increasing. The competition for employment is extremely fierce and it is difficult to find a job. At the same time, they are also faced with work pressure, promotion pressure, renting and buying a house, pressure to get married and start a family, pressure to have children, etc. To be honest, the overall survival and development situation of contemporary young people Not optimistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Considering specific activities such as traveling and attending classes at senior universities, we believe that young people’s participation in them is a response to the high-intensity, high-pressure, and fast-paced production that young people generally find themselves in in the context of urbanization and modernization. A kind of resistance, rebellion and temporary escape (escapism) from the way of life. Faced with various production and lifestyles with &quot;involution&quot; as their basic characteristics, which have no way to escape, young people can actively debug, adjust and make some changes, and achieve relief and decompression through travel, study, etc. Purpose, I think it is a pretty good thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; should not be understood in a narrow sense as the field of consumption, but should be interpreted from the perspective of the specific consumption process and the concrete experience in the consumption process, that is, the social nature of consumption cannot or is not easily ignored. feature. The core essence of &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; is that young people and the elderly get along and interact with each other for a certain period of time. Travel can be as short as one or two days, as long as three to five days or a week, to eat in the elderly canteen and to attend classes at the elderly university. This allows young people and older people to spend more time together, and such interactions will produce significant learning effects. And this kind of learning is two-way rather than one-way, because through such interactions and exchanges, young people can gain life experience provided by their elders, and the elders can be infected by the vitality or passion of young people. Especially for the elderly, if young people are willing to listen to their stories or sharing, they usually feel happy and satisfied, and their sense of self-worth will be significantly enhanced. In this sense, the precise expression of &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; should be &quot;mutual consumption&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A direct effect of this &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; is to repair or improve the relationship between young people and their older relatives in their families or clans. In reality, there are some young people, especially young men, who have little communication with their parents. They often keep a distance from their parents in the name of generation gap. This is the so-called &quot;disconnection&quot; phenomenon, but they have no relationship with their parents outside. Communication among the elderly is tolerant, and some young people often take the initiative or actively communicate with the elderly. Obviously, occasional or regular participation in &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot; will undoubtedly have a positive effect on increasing the close relationship between young people and their families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for &quot;old-fashioned consumption&quot;, some people may think that this will squeeze out the resources of the elderly. A bunch of chattering young people suddenly join the tour group, and the elderly will feel that the young people have somewhat affected their &quot; &quot;The right to tranquility&quot;; when a bunch of young people suddenly come to join in the fun in the seniors&#39; canteen, the old people will feel it is too noisy; when a bunch of young people suddenly break into the classroom to teach, the old people will feel crowded and uncomfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more fundamental doubt is that the above-mentioned various special services or benefits only for the elderly are paid for by the government and are part of the security system for the elderly. Now, young people are flocking to them, and there is obvious The rights or rights of the elderly are suspected of being raided. But the author believes that we should not understand the word &quot;resource&quot; statically. If the elderly or even most elderly people benefit from and acquire it because of the participation or joining of young people, this is undoubtedly another hidden precious resource. It should be noted that resources are not only economic-oriented, but also include social-oriented resources in a broad sense, which mainly refers to the level of social communication and social interaction; resources are not limited to initial static resources, and resources in a broad sense also exist after the initial resource investment. Learned resources, we might as well imagine the latter as the multiplier effect in the field of economics or investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What I mean is that a cross-age or mixed-age (fixed structure) population structure usually produces a good comprehensive effect because each other benefits from or benefits from mutual exchanges and learning. We can also understand it as the application or application of economies of scale and economies of scope theories in daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I couldn’t help but think of two things. One is in Japan. During the layout process, some kindergartens or primary schools will choose to be adjacent to nursing homes. At eight o&#39;clock in the morning, the elderly can hear the sound of reading aloud from next door as scheduled; at four o&#39;clock in the afternoon, the elderly will see the school after school at the entrance of the nursing home. The children bowed to themselves and politely said, &quot;Grandpa is good&quot;, &quot;I wish Grandma you happy and happy today&quot;; on weekends or holidays, a bunch of children and their teachers came to the nursing home to perform shows for the elderly, dinner together, together, together Play games, and as feedback, the elderly can occasionally or often go to the school next door to talk about the past and present lives of their city or community. I believe that this is the proper meaning of &quot;being productive in old age&quot; and &quot;being happy in old age&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other is that in recent years, some domestic cities have proposed to build urban development goals for specific groups. For example, Shanghai proposed to build an age-friendly city, Beijing proposed to build a youth-friendly city, and Shenzhen proposed to build a child-friendly city. Changsha proposes to build a female-friendly city. I just wonder, if this kind of special care for a certain group of people is singled out and used as an important part of urban development goals or urban development strategies, isn&#39;t it suspected of &quot;social deprivation&quot; for other groups? ? What do you mean by just being friendly to the elderly? Unfriendly to young people? Not child friendly? Is its essential point that when this kind of preferential policy for specific groups of people is used as an urban development goal or strategy, there will inevitably be a package of follow-up measures in terms of funds, projects, policies, planning, etc. To put it more bluntly, It means that a lot of real money is invested in specific groups of people, which is obviously not fair and reasonable for other groups. In the long run, this move is intended to harm or harm the city&#39;s diversity, inclusiveness and equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, I also disagree with the suggestions or suggestions of some people and even some experts to build special women&#39;s (subway) carriages or children&#39;s (high-speed rail) carriages. Why can’t we build a high-end society that is gender-friendly, gender-equal, and gender-integrated through extensive publicity and innovative practices? Why can&#39;t we be tolerant of children who are active or crying, or even adopt more positive and proactive methods, such as actively chatting with children, playing games, playing poker, etc., so that children can feel the affection of uncles, aunts, brothers and sisters in the carriage? What about warmth? Obviously, whether it is a women&#39;s (subway) carriage or a children&#39;s (high-speed rail) carriage, they are all short-sighted moves aimed at evading and avoiding the problem, and they are all deliberately or deliberately aimed at &quot;distinctiveness&quot; and &quot;community isolation&quot; ” (social segregation), all of which are against or deviating from the basic principles of mixed-age or cross-age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[南周x读库2024联合征订，买1得10，错过等1年！]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261065]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 15:08:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of this year, we [Nanzhou x Reading Library] joint subscription was launched. After the event, many readers were still asking customer service if there was any event? When will the next event be online? &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4f39e9ed29f243a7b2c88dbc5567123f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot;width =&quot; 517 &quot;height =&quot; 441 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/4F39ED243A7B2C5567123F.JPEG &quot;Data-KE Y = &quot;259141&quot; Data-MCE -width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;So, here we come——&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;If you are an old reader of Nanzhou and Duku and know both companies, you can click directly to place an order👇&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop44174528.m.youzan.com/wscgoods/detail/2ovea0fevflh4ib?dc_ps=3454431088766738433.200001&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /22/350efda899a9d005f6b91ff5e85b1c88.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/350efda899a9d005f6b91ff5e85b1c88 .png&quot; data-key=&quot;259137&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Southern Zhoux Reading Library 2024 Joint Subscription, one yuan per day, you can get:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;1. Southern Weekend one-year membership&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2. &quot;Reading Library&quot; MOOK2024 (all 7 physical magazines)&lt; /span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;3. One-year membership of Duku APP&lt;/span>; span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Limited time bonus: Joint subscription special Gift a book&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In an era of overwhelming content, the information flow of short and fast news is like a crucian carp crossing the river, but There are fewer and fewer high-quality articles that can restore the original appearance of the incident, and serious and in-depth content is increasingly needed by everyone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Strong Recommended to you, don’t miss this joint subscription&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style =&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>; &lt;strong>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot; data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;Southern Zhou Dynasty × Reading Library 2024 Joint Subscription&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot; data-brushtype=&quot;text&quot;>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;ul>; &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: Optima-Regular, PingFangTC-light;&quot;>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot; font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Southern Weekend Annual Membership Card&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;can be enjoyed&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal; &quot;>;10 value-for-money rights for news and knowledge&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal; &quot;>;&lt;span>;Get &lt;strong>;more than 10 million words/year&lt;/strong>; original articles and more than 30 years of classic accumulation&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;, no need to worry about where to go Select real and useful key information. You can also see&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Top writers and scholars columns&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;,&lt;/span>;&lt;strong >;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Dozens of audio and video courses carefully crafted by Nanzhou&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, get Benefit from the lifelong humanistic heritage and no need to worry about your own growth and learning. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: Optima-Regular, PingFangTC-light;&quot;>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;《Read Library》Mook&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font- weight: normal;&quot;>;7 volumes per year,&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;one book published every two months&lt;/strong>;. The booklet is small and beautiful, but the content is all-inclusive. Talk about&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;interesting things in the universe, life, human body, art, technology, economy and other fields&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: Optima-Regular, PingFangTC-light;&quot;>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000 ;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Electronic members of Duku app&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; can read all the contents of each issue of &quot;Duku&quot; in 2024 as soon as possible , you can read &quot;Duku&quot; selected articles from previous years, the author&#39;s exclusive audio and video, behind-the-scenes footage, etc. for free. You can also build a personal treasure house of knowledge that you can use endlessly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;li style=&quot;font-family: Optima-Regular, PingFangTC-light;&quot;>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, we also give each joint subscription readers will receive a special book as a gift (random, no designation accepted). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/li>; &lt;/ul>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Southern Weekend x Reading Library 】2024 joint subscription&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Buy 1 and get 10! &lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot; >;&lt;span>;One-year membership of Southern Weekend App&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;(original price 288 yuan)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;One-year membership of Reading Library App&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;(original price 283 yuan)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong style=&quot; font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&quot;Reading Library&quot; Mook2024&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Full Year&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;7 volumes&lt;/span>;&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&amp;nbsp;original price 294 yuan）&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>; &lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Add a special book for joint subscription&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt; /strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;span>;Total value&lt;/span>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;&lt;span>;792 yuan &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;, limited time special offer&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ff0000;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;365 yuan&lt; /strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;👇Click the image below to grab it👇&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop44174528.m.youzan.com/wscgoods/detail/2ovea0fevflh4ib?dc_ps=3454431088766738433.200001&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/22/10c922b2ac8e2f1bb38b66791723dd50.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/10c922b2ac8e2f1bb38b66791723dd50.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259140&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不想买到“毒地”房？土壤信息公开还不够]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261043]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/22/e8ed7338d9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 22/e8ed7338d9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259104&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Buyers need to check the land use history. Generally speaking, the original It is safer if it is farmland, residential, public facilities, or green space parks, and there are basically no migration pathways for pollutants from other surrounding areas. If it is a converted contaminated site, you need to pay attention to the results of soil assessment. (Picture and text unrelated) Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, the &quot;poisonous land&quot; dispute between Jiangsu Suzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd. and Shanghai Lujiazui Financial and Trade Zone Development Co., Ltd. Generate attention. Spending two generations&#39; &quot;six wallets&quot; to buy their first home is a price many ordinary home buyers have to pay. How to avoid buying a &quot;poisonous land&quot;? This has also become a topic of widespread concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;my country&#39;s soil pollution laws and regulations were promulgated relatively late. In 2019, the Soil Pollution Prevention and Control Law began to be implemented. Combined with other documents, three situations require soil pollution status investigation: The first is the change of land use to residential, public management and public services (referred to as &quot;one residential, two public&quot;); the second is the construction land plots with soil pollution risks; the third is the change of land use for production and operation of key soil pollution supervision units, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the requirements of laws and regulations such as the Soil Pollution Prevention and Control Law, soil environment investigation reports must be disclosed to the public in accordance with regulations, but the legal provisions on information disclosure are not specific enough. Soil pollution is hidden, and home buyers need to check the land use history. Generally speaking, it is safer if the land was originally farmland, residential, public facilities, or green space park types, and there are basically no other migration pathways for pollutants in the surrounding land. If it is a converted contaminated site, you need to pay attention to the results of soil assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Soil information disclosure is uneven&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Because there are no clear regulations, there are various channels for soil information disclosure, making it difficult to search with one click. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Lei, a staff member of the environmental protection organization &quot;Guangzhou Green Network Environmental Protection Service Center&quot; (hereinafter referred to as Green Network) told the Southern Weekly reporter that our country&#39;s laws do not provide for soil In what channels should the environmental investigation report be made public, what content should be made public, etc. In actual situations, some reports are made public on the websites of real estate developers, and some are published on industry forums of companies commissioned to investigate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2016, Green Network has regularly collected from hundreds of websites and compiled tens of thousands of reports related to soil pollution investigation and remediation for free public review. However, public awareness of this aggregated information is not high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The professional nature of information disclosure content also increases the difficulty for users to access it. The public generally searches for the subdivision or developer name, but reports often use parcel numbers provided by the Department of Natural Resources. Moreover, most of the public reports are simplified and lack location diagrams, making it difficult for the public to correspond their property and plot numbers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters searched the Green Network database using &quot;Beijing&quot; as the keyword and found that the vast majority of the 15 preliminary investigation reports displayed on the homepage were only Some are about 2 pages long, including a brief description of basic soil conditions, investigation plans and investigation conclusions; some are as long as 130 pages, or the full text and on-site photos are disclosed in detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Lei said that the simplified report lacks data such as sampling point maps and pollutant concentration distribution, making it impossible for outsiders to conduct detailed analysis. It is easy to judge whether the sampling process was standardized based on the photos, but the report did not present sampling photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;There is still a big gap in the information disclosure intensity and quality of soil environmental investigation reports compared with air, water, environmental assessment and other reports.&quot; Guo Lei suggested, Specific information disclosure specifications should be formulated and a unified release platform for information disclosure should be established. Especially for residential buildings and schools redeveloped from land used by heavily polluting industries, developers need to disclose detailed information, and home buyers and parents of students must make careful choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How &quot;poisonous land&quot; can be turned into &quot;treasure land&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If soil restoration is in place, there are many cases where &quot;poisonous land&quot; has been transformed into &quot;treasure land&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2008, the Beijing Chemical Plant No. 2, located in the southeastern suburbs of Chaoyang District, Beijing, ceased production, and the land was transferred to the State Administration for Residential Land Development. Dr. Yang Jin, chairman of Simple Testing Technology (Shanghai) Co., Ltd., has participated in the soil environment investigation and testing work of this project. Yang Jin introduced that the soil investigation and restoration of this project lasted for many years and cost more than 1 billion yuan. On the land Guanghua New City Community was built and residents will move in at the end of 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Transforming a &quot;poisonous land&quot; into a &quot;treasure land&quot; requires a long process of assessment and restoration. The investigation of soil pollution alone will go through three stages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first stage is pollution identification, which is mainly based on data collection, on-site surveys and personnel interviews; if possible pollution sources are found in or around the plot, then Entering the second stage of contamination confirmation, it is divided into preliminary and detailed sampling analysis, and the preparation of a soil pollution status investigation report; the third stage is mainly supplementary sampling and testing to obtain the parameters required to meet risk assessment and soil and groundwater remediation. The investigation work in the first stage can be carried out separately or simultaneously during the second stage investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Jin introduced that the sampling density for the preliminary investigation of soil pollution conditions is small, generally a 40m×40m grid layout, which is equivalent to the area of ​​four basketball courts. For a sample, it usually takes 2-3 months from the formulation of the plan to the release of the analysis results. If contaminants are detected in the preliminary investigation, detailed investigation is required. The sampling density is increased to a 20m×20m grid, which is equivalent to the area of ​​a basketball court to collect one sample. Local key areas may be denser. This step is time-consuming. About 3-6 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the soil pollution status investigation and risk assessment are completed, soil remediation must be carried out. Depending on the land area and remediation goals, the remediation work may take as short as one or two years. , the length may exceed ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cb4dd94913.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/cb4dd94913.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259105&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;In July 2022, Hefei, Anhui, at the contaminated soil treatment and restoration site in the former industrial production area of ​​Yaohai District, The staff analyzed the soil at room temperature. Visual China/Picture&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are currently more than 100 soil remediation technologies, and there are more than ten commonly used technologies, which can be roughly divided into physical There are three methods: chemical and biological. The technical principle is to transfer, absorb, degrade and transform pollutants in the soil, reducing their concentration to acceptable levels, or converting toxic and harmful pollutants into harmless substances. According to the remediation mode, it can be divided into in-situ and ex-situ remediation. The difference lies in whether the contaminated soil is moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The effectiveness of soil remediation also needs to be evaluated. my country implements a soil pollution risk management and restoration list system for construction land. Contaminated plots on the list must pass the review organized by the provincial ecological environment department and meet the established management and control or restoration goals. Only after the risks are controllable can they be removed from the list and developed and utilized. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It is difficult for the public to judge the quality of reports&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Even if a soil environmental survey has been conducted and the information has been disclosed relatively well, the quality of the reports varies. Qi, the professional threshold is high, and it is difficult for the public to understand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;These reports are prepared by professional companies and have passed expert review. Let alone the general public, let us look for problems in the reports. In fact, there is no It’s easy to find.” Guo Lei admitted that it is difficult for ordinary residents to judge whether the quality of the report is up to standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pollutants in the soil are different from the atmosphere and water and are not evenly distributed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Jie, secretary-general of Zhongguancun Zhongxin Soil Remediation Industry Technology Innovation Alliance, told Southern Weekend reporters that soil is multi-phase and heterogeneous, and pollutants are underground , invisible to the naked eye. During the soil investigation process, contaminants may not be discovered in time due to factors such as technology and cost constraints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Soil remediation has certain uncertainties, and there is no guarantee that it will be &quot;repaired&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Jin said that in reality, there is a phenomenon that after soil remediation is completed and then tested, the pollutants still exceed the standard, and even the organic pollutants in some areas &quot;increase as the soil is repaired.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are two main types of pollutants in soil - heavy metals and organic matter. Heavy metals have weak mobility and are relatively simple to repair. Generally, there are chemical curing methods, leaching methods, separation methods, etc. Since organic matter has strong mobility, thermal desorption, chemical oxidation or biological remediation methods are generally used. Organic pollutants may migrate with groundwater and other media. The soil extraction process may cause disturbance to underground pollutants, which may cause them to migrate to a wider range. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Gao Jie suggested that awareness of soil pollution prevention and control should be strengthened during the development process. For example, when digging and turning the soil, pay attention to observe whether the color and smell are abnormal, and be equipped with XRF, Rapid screening instruments such as PID can quickly determine whether soil is contaminated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Supervisory authorities should check things in advance. According to GreenNet statistics, since 2019, land use rights holders of more than 300 plots across the country have been punished by the ecological environment department for failing to conduct soil pollution surveys or risk assessments before redevelopment of the plots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Even if the reported problems are discovered, the house may have been built by then, and the difficulty of solving the problem has become more complicated.&quot; Guo Lei said that at present, The ecological environment department is improving the supervision system and requires survey companies to file sampling plans in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2022, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment issued the &quot;Guidelines for Preliminary Investigation, Supervision and Inspection of Soil Pollution Conditions in Construction Land (Trial)&quot;, stipulating that municipal ecological environment authorities Carry out supervision and inspection on the sampling and analysis work plan, on-site sampling, and laboratory testing and analysis. For investigation reports that have passed the review, the provincial ecological and environmental authorities can organize random inspections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to supervision by local environmental protection departments, Green Network will also report similar clues discovered. &quot;It is possible that some plots that should have been subject to soil environmental surveys but were not, were not discovered by either us or the environmental protection department,&quot; Guo Lei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Lei explained that there are two important reasons why soil pollution surveys were not conducted before development: First, soil pollution surveys are not subject to the same regulations as planning permits and construction permits. It is widely known that many developers do not know that soil pollution surveys are required, and legal education and publicity need to be further strengthened. Second, many local ecological environment departments do not fully grasp land change information and need to share information with natural resource departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Is it worthwhile to develop highly polluting land plots?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Jin observed that when the real estate industry was booming in the past few years, land plots in highly polluting industries Also very popular. &quot;Even if soil environmental investigation and restoration take several years and cost hundreds of millions or even billions, it is still difficult to dampen the enthusiasm of developers because of the huge returns.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;Nowadays, local governments and developers are also reflecting on whether it is worth paying such a large cost to repair a difficult and uncertain soil in order to develop residential buildings and bear subsequent risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Regulations on the Prevention and Control of Soil Pollution in Jiangsu Province&quot; that will be implemented on September 1, 2022 stipulates that non-ferrous metal mining and processing, non-ferrous metal smelting, and petroleum shall be strictly controlled. Land with serious soil pollution in mining, petroleum processing, chemical industry, coking, electroplating, tanning, pesticides, lead batteries, steel, hazardous waste utilization and disposal and other industries should not be planned as residential areas, schools, kindergartens, hospitals, Land used for nursing homes and sanatoriums can be used to expand ecological space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, even if you are unfortunate enough to live in a house built on a soil-contaminated land, residents do not need to panic too much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guo Lei said that if you live on a high floor, you are far away from the surface. Even if there are volatile and semi-volatile organic compounds in the soil, when you reach the high floor, The concentration is also very low. For houses built on &quot;poisonous land&quot;, the basements, gardens and green belts will be most affected. The gas after the pollutants volatilize will slowly penetrate into the underground space and accumulate there. It is not recommended to stay in the basement for a long time, and gardens and green belts are prone to direct contact with contaminated soil. In windy and dusty weather, residents should wear masks. If they are well protected, health risks can be greatly reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[四川“废弃神话公园”，藏着“七仙女”与“历代帝王”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260960]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-22 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, the ancient exhibition with &quot;Chinese history and culture&quot; as the core theme The famous scenic spot has many statues of emperors and generals designed in the China Progress Garden.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/eccbc4710d.JPG&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/eccbc4710d.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258918&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot with &quot;Chinese History and Culture&quot; as the core theme was designed in the Huaxia Process Garden There are many statues of emperors and generals. &lt;p>; A man-made &quot;cultural heritage&quot; with a sense of absurdity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, in Zhongjiang County, Deyang City, Sichuan, the gate of the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot was closed.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/20/a490834d30.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /20/a490834d30.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258919&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, Zhongjiang County, Deyang City, Sichuan, The gates of the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot are closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The main body of this large-scale scenic spot is built in Fengdian Town, Zhongjiang County, with a planned land area of ​​more than 10,000 acres. In 2014, the developer of the scenic spot brought the project to this small county town, claiming that it would help local people get rich. Unexpectedly, there was insufficient funds in the first year of construction. Despite being in arrears with tens of millions of project funds, the scenic spot still barely opened for business at the end of 2019. At the opening, colorful balloons floated in the air, and hundreds of people watched the red-faced Guan Gong perform his machete on the red carpet. The scene was lively. However, the scenic area&#39;s business has been bleak since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, weeds grew on both sides of the road in the ancient Mingtianxia Scenic Area.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/20/f7a677405f.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/f7a677405f .JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258920&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, the roads in the ancient Mingtianxia Scenic Area were overgrown with weeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, a &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; standing in front of a chariot looked dilapidated due to long-term disrepair.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/20/cfb05ce8ae.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/20/cfb05ce8ae.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258921&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, Yizun Station The &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; in front of the chariot appear dilapidated due to disrepair over time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;On November 9, 2023, the expression of&quot; Terracotta Warriors &quot;is solemn, as if people instantly cross from Deyang to Xi&#39;an.&quot; SRC = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/20/5ed1bad471.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/20/5ed1bad471.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258922&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, &quot;Terracotta Warriors and Horses&quot; His expression was solemn, as if people were transported from Deyang to Xi&#39;an in an instant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, hundreds of life-size &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; were arranged neatly in the scenic spot.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/20/aa9be155e6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/aa9be155e6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258923&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, hundreds of life-size statues The &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; are neatly arranged in the scenic spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to encountering the epidemic, there are traces of the failure of &quot;Ancient Famous World&quot;. Scenic spots usually attract tourists with beautiful mountains and rivers or cultural history, but the gimmick of &quot;Ancient Famous World&quot; is the &quot;immersive experience of Chinese culture&quot; brought by nearly 2,000 artificial sculptures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The themes of these sculptures are all-encompassing, interpreting mythical stories such as Chang&#39;e flying to the moon, the Eight Immortals crossing the sea, the Cowherd and the Weaver Girl, and the Seven Fairies, but the production is relatively rough. In order to let tourists experience the feeling of &quot;pointing the country&quot;, the scenic spot has also built thousands of replicas of terracotta warriors and horses. Accompanying the &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot; are nearly 500 &quot;statues of emperors from past dynasties&quot;. However, the imperial appearance, which is far from the common perception, and the text introduction full of errors, made the visitors laugh and cry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, the pond where the statue of the Eight Immortals Crossing the Sea in the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot is already a pool of stagnant water.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/8a924b14c2.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/20/8a924b14c2.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258924&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 2023 On the 9th, the pond where the statue of the Eight Immortals Crossing the Sea in the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Spot was turned into a pool of stagnant water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, a statue of an emperor surrounded by wild grass almost as tall as a person.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/20/b03c44e1a4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20 /b03c44e1a4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258925&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, a statue was surrounded by weeds almost as tall as a person. statue of the emperor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The total length of the tourist tour line is 19 kilometers, and the sculpture is scattered at more than 20 attractions. Some tourists once complained on the review software, which is equivalent to forcing people to spend money to take a sightseeing bus. In early November 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter sat on a villager&#39;s motorcycle and visited less than 10 scenic spots, which took more than 3 hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the scenic spot was temporarily closed in June 2022, the &quot;terracotta warriors and horses&quot;, &quot;seven fairies&quot; and &quot;emperors and generals&quot; were left in the barren mountains and ridges without anyone. Take care of it and live next to wind, rain, weeds, insects and ants. When Southern Weekend reporters visited the scenic spot, they only met two or three villagers in the scenic spot. The local villagers did not embark on the road to wealth. Instead, they were owed many years of land rent. Now the villagers are re-cultivation in many places in the scenic area and have planted rapeseed, a local cash crop. They said that this year, rapeseed can be sold for 3 yuan per pound. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, an aerial photo was taken of the ancient famous Tianxia Scenic Area. The scenic area originally planned a total land area of ​​more than 23,000 acres, with a total planned investment of 3.1 billion yuan.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/93c278a044.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/20/93c278a044.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258926&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 2023 On the 9th, aerial photography was taken of the ancient famous scenic spot in the world. The scenic area originally planned a total land area of ​​more than 23,000 acres, with a total planned investment of 3.1 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The ticket office, offices, commercial street shops, etc. in the scenic area were all in a mess. Doors, windows, tables and cabinets were smashed, and the floor was littered with scattered documents and broken glass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to arrears in land rent and project payments, &quot;Gumingtianxia&quot; has more than 80 million yuan in outstanding financing. Under the promotion of the scenic area promoters, perhaps investors believe that the scenic area has a bright future. Southern Weekend reporters learned from multiple judgments and on-site construction personnel that the investors attracted by the scenic spot tend to be older. Some retired men were defrauded of 210,000 yuan to buy &quot;health products&quot; and then invested tens of thousands more yuan in scenic spots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, some local residents occasionally came to the park to hang out.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/20/cdcad5f48d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/cdcad5f48d .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258927&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2023, some local residents occasionally came to the park to hang out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The scenes of abandoned scenic spots were spread through the Internet, attracting some explorers. It&#39;s just that all entrances to the scenic area are locked, and you have to overcome some difficulties to enter - climb over the wall at the main entrance, or get in through a patch of weeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Local villagers sometimes gather outside the main entrance of the scenic spot to chat. They are used to strange visitors with curiosity, and they will always kindly persuade: &quot;The above Nothing to see.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On November 9, 2023, a local resident rode a motorcycle past the &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; procession.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/20/760c445d9f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/20/760c445d9f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258928&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;November 9, 2023, one Local residents rode motorcycles past the &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; procession. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 13:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>