<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[偷遍上海所有无印良品店铺，小偷夫妻自称“品牌代理”，半年赚26万]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256731]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[幼师针扎孩子、对孩子使用麻黄碱：当让持扭曲价值观的人远离孩子丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256856]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Parents with children are very worried after reading this. On September 12, a parent of a young child in Shanghai posted a message: On March 24 this year, parents found injuries on their child who was studying at the Dahua Tadpole Music Park in Baoshan District, Shanghai, and suspected that the kindergarten teacher had abused the child. On March 27, the parents called the police, and the police issued an injury examination form for the child to go to the hospital for examination. &quot;The police issued an injury examination form to check the child&#39;s injuries that day because there were many bruises on his body. In the next few days, the police issued an injury examination form again.&quot; , doctors at the Children’s Hospital found multiple pinpoint-like holes.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hospital injury examination sheet uploaded by the parent showed that there were many pinpoint-like holes on the toddler&#39;s body. &quot;The parents immediately asked for a hair test. The results showed that all five children contained ephedrine, two of them.&quot; Child contains lidocaine&quot;. &quot;It has been more than half a year since the case was reported. Parents have suffered a lot. They have suffered from insomnia and nightmares. We just want to know the truth! What have the children experienced? What have they endured? What will happen to their physical condition in the future?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On September 13, a reporter from Dawan News called Dahua Tadpole Music Park. The kindergarten replied: &quot;You can go to the police station and they can give you the most correct answer, or the answer you want most.&quot; &quot;All our processes They all follow the arrangements of the Education Bureau and the police station.&quot; Subsequently, the reporter called the local police, but there was no reply; when calling the Baoshan District Education Bureau, a staff member said: &quot;We as a whole attach great importance to this matter and have been following up and handling it. We have also seen the content posted by parents on the Internet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Half a year has passed for such an abominable and suspected criminal incident, and there is neither any explanation nor any explanation as to whether the perpetrators have been dealt with. Below, it’s no wonder that parents are reluctant to give up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the nature of this matter is vile, and the relevant circumstances are outrageous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the injury examination notice from the Shanghai Public Security Bureau uploaded by the parents, the parents stated that the boy was only four years old. The day before he was admitted to the hospital, the parents found a suspicious pinpoint-like hole. After asking the child, they learned that &quot;maybe There is abuse or use in clinical trials.&quot; On that day, fever symptoms appeared, with the highest temperature being 39 degrees; the test results were: &quot;Stomach and energy have become worse than before, there is tenderness in the penis and scrotum, and repeated swelling and pain.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s all because you have a little more. It looks like a needle-like hole, and some of it has healed. &quot;There are also many needle-like holes in the penis and scrotum.&quot; The test conclusion is: &quot;The scrotum is red, swollen, and tender.&quot; &quot;There are many suspicious needle-like holes all over the body. The purpose is unknown. The police need to be called.&quot; Collaborative treatment.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The parent said: &quot;All five children contained ephedrine (in their hair), and two of them contained lidocaine.&quot; If what is said is true, it would be even more terrifying. Because ephedrine has central nervous system stimulant effects, it is a drug-making raw material strictly controlled by the government. Lidocaine is a local anesthetic. Think about it, everyone. Even when you go to a pharmacy to buy pseudoephedrine, a drug that relieves cold symptoms, you have to buy it in limited quantities and register your ID number. Where did the perpetrators get these drugs? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are more questions: Are these &quot;needle-like holes&quot; just a needle stick in the child, or are they the marks left by using a syringe to inject ephedrine and lidocaine? For such a long period of time, many children have been systematically injected with acupuncture, ephedrine and lidocaine. Is it a crime committed by one person, or is it a coordinated crime by multiple people? Where is the perpetrator now? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time a kindergarten teacher stabbed a child with a needle. Similar incidents have been exposed many times and occur all over the country. Therefore, we must consider the possibility of imitating crimes and abetting crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2019, the Tianjin Binhai New District Court held the first public hearing on the case of two middle five teachers of the Golden Cradle Dongcheng Kindergarten suspected of abusing their care recipients. The prosecutor alleged: From July to October 2018, the defendants Zhao and Dou, as kindergarten teachers in the fifth class of Tianjin Golden Cradle Dongcheng Kindergarten, resorted to needle sticks, pushing, and The children in care were abused by pulling and other violent behaviors, and the number of victims was as many as 24. Two kindergarten teachers were sentenced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, a mother’s 3-year-old daughter was in the middle class at Chuntian Huahua Kindergarten in Dachang Kulun Village, Saihan District, Hohhot City. One day she overheard her daughter saying that Teacher Guo from the kindergarten pricked someone with a needle. Later, I discovered that there were scabs that looked like needle holes on my daughter’s body, head, ring finger, armpits, thighs, ankles, etc. Two other parents also found scabs on their children that looked like needle holes. The kindergarten was later closed down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with these cases, the case in Baoshan District, Shanghai was even more egregious in nature, going beyond the scope of general abuse, with obvious intentions and consequences of personal injury. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, the perpetrator’s motive is worth exploring. There is always a motive for abusing or physically harming a child: feeling that the child is disobedient and disobeying management is one kind; having conflicts with parents and being angry at the child is another kind; being driven by distorted values ​​​​and crazy hatred is also another kind. kind. The last one is probably the scariest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kindergarten should be a place where children live, play and play together. It should be a place of relaxation, freedom and safety, like a sweet dream. Kindergarten teachers should love children and care for each child as their own. Having normal values, loving children, and being patient are the minimum requirements for a kindergarten teacher. If a seemingly normal face hides disgust and hatred for children, then the kindergarten will not only not be a warm and loving paradise, but will become a chilling nightmare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, especially in first-tier cities, kindergartens generally charge a lot of money. From the perspective of professional ethics, how can we take money from parents and turn away, close the door, abuse, and harm children like angels? Such evil behavior not only breaks through the bottom line of professional ethics, but also represents the degradation and loss of human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, it is necessary to conduct a thorough investigation and examination of the perpetrator&#39;s life world and spiritual world to see who the perpetrator usually associates with, what content he follows on social platforms, celebrities and himself. Media, which groups and circles to join, and see if this person and the online and offline circles he interacts with have any extreme remarks, actions or even organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, it is necessary to install monitoring equipment in kindergartens across the country. In principle, all activities of children and all interactions between teachers and children should be recorded on video to deter those treacherous people who hold distorted values. ; At the same time, kindergarten teachers and early childhood staff who are entering and working should review their social media, speech and values, and keep those who hold distorted values ​​away from children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[若尔盖：黄河在这“美丽回眸”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256735]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京跳水大爷：只愿安静跳水，不想当网红]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256880]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/16/oSNiAIUiesQ3CdeH1EU5tDMMXBURE0EqlI2luCci.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/oSNiAIUiesQ3CdeH1EU5tDMMXBURE0EqlI2luCci. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team coach Meng Derui participated in the training&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;1, 2, 3, jump!&quot; Coach Meng Derui gave the order, and more than a dozen adults and aunts in swimsuits jumped into the water from left to right, splashing everywhere. splash. &quot;Someone jumped, let&#39;s do it again.&quot; Coach Meng was in second place, and he heard that the rhythm of entering the water behind him was wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Diving Team&quot;) rehearsing the collective Solitaire &quot;Domino&quot; jump in the South Moat on September 13. Every day at two o&#39;clock in the afternoon, this group of 60 and 70-year-old people come here from all directions to participate in &quot;training&quot;. They perform tuck-knee pose, swallow pose, back swallow pose, front and back somersaults...all of them are as strong as swallows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/bh6tdihLgJ4TKcokF7joxNK1UjEYP0VgaIARgKCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/bh6tdihLgJ4TKcokF7joxNK1UjEYP0VgaIARgKCC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251009&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Between training sessions, the team members rested by the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Training is over , Zhang Yuan rode an electric bike home &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting out of the water, water droplets lay on her wheat-colored skin, which was particularly bright under the sun. . Although the team has been established for less than three years, most of the team members have 20 to 30 years of winter swimming or diving experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the personal training session, Coach Meng completed a set of backward somersault half-circle pike jumps. &quot;201B, performance level, so exciting,&quot; teammates and passing spectators clapped and praised. Applause and laughter continued on the shore - some applauded, and some who failed the jump were heckled and joked, &quot;Isn&#39;t this shot painful enough?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You see, everyone is laughing so hard Damn it, everyone is here just to have fun.&quot; Mengdry said while looking at his teammates. This 67-year-old Beijinger grew up in the alleys of Di&#39;anmen. He remembered two very happy things when he was a child. One was flying a kite on the tiles of a bungalow, and the other was swimming in Shicha Sea. In the 1960s, Meng Derui, who was in primary school, studied diving at the Shichahai Sports School. His coach later went abroad to teach and also brought out world diving champions. Because of his professional background and his friendly nature, the team members affectionately called him &quot;Meng Jiao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For every new pose, Meng Jiao explained the movements to us from head to toe and gave us personal demonstrations. No matter how cold the weather was, he could do a standard demonstration when he climbed on the platform. In his Under the leadership of the diving team, we adults have moved from a group of diving bastards to a quasi-professional level,&quot; said 62-year-old team member Zhang Yu&#39;an. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/hNnyjNZ6cmIAkejHTQVnUPMiSBtppnwc8nWRMZAn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/hNnyjNZ6cmIAkejHTQVnUPMiSBtppnwc8nWRMZAn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251002&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The team members rehearse the collective Solitaire &quot;Domino&quot; jump&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Don’t want to take risks Risking your life to become an Internet celebrity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 3, 2023, Meng Jiao led the diving team to Tianjin to socialize with local diving friends. At that time, the diving master of Tianjin Lion Forest Bridge was popular all over the world. net. Some netizens posted a video of the team members arriving in Tianjin online with the title &quot;Beijing Diving Master Comes to Tianjin to Play Gym&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, it’s not a competition at all, but an exchange and learning between diving friends. We have known each other for many years and are very familiar with each other. We go there to dive there every year because there are more suitable venues for high school students in Tianjin. The environment for bridge diving - the water is deep, the bridge is high, and the water bottom is clean.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an introduced, &quot;Like the Beijing South Moat where we train daily, the water depth is about 3 meters, and the bridge deck is 5 meters away from the water. For safety reasons, law enforcement officers do not allow us to To jump from the bridge, you can only jump from the guardrail on the shore, the height is only 2 meters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first stop in Tianjin is the Chifeng Bridge, which is more than 9 meters high. Wang Tieshun, the &quot;Ironman of Winter Swimming&quot; in the team, was the first to take the stage. In his first jump, the &quot;Reverse Swallow&quot;, his buttocks touched the water first, and he was slapped hard, which was not ideal. He analyzed that it was due to the increase in height that there was a problem with the angle of entering the water. He immediately adjusted his posture when entering the water, and performed a wonderful dance afterwards, which won bursts of applause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Brother Wang is 69 years old. Generally, when a person of this age stands at a height of 9 meters and looks down, his legs will tremble. Not only does he dare to jump, but he is also a &quot;anti-Yan&quot; who is cool and neat, so generous. People are impressed.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an said as he opened his arms in a &quot;swallow pose&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second stop was the &quot;8A-level scenic spot&quot; Lion Forest Bridge. The deck of the Lion Grove Bridge is about 6 meters above the water surface, which is an ideal height for high bridge diving. The team members just skipped here three months ago and it was a great experience. But at this time, there were already a sea of ​​people on and off the bridge, and the scene was very chaotic. Those who could jump and those who couldn&#39;t jump plunged into the water. Meng Derui saw a man walking into the water with his child in his arms, and he still has lingering fears. For safety reasons, he decided to lead his team members to evacuate immediately without jumping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/dMWAFSXngM0yU1bzVOLoG9MmUPiayHBiK0aSZBd5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/dMWAFSXngM0yU1bzVOLoG9MmUPiayHBiK0aSZBd5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251007&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Between training sessions, the team members rested by the river&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/KjcsCzMDg3BfwG13tlQPy8yejaaTwNvK3b2PsvTl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/KjcsCzMDg3BfwG13tlQPy8yejaaTwNvK3b2PsvTl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After training , the brothers went to a nearby restaurant to have a drink&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Someone at the scene recognized that we were from Beijing and chased us all the way. We were following the filming, but we still withdrew. Everyone comes to dive for physical and mental pleasure and to improve their skills. They don’t want to risk their lives to become an Internet celebrity and be in the limelight.&quot; Zhang Yuan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Changluo, director of the emergency department of Changsha Central Hospital, said in an interview with the media that high-bridge diving is very dangerous, and it is easy to get injured if you blindly try it without professional guidance. In addition to damage to the retina, head and cervical spine, if the diving posture is incorrect and the abdomen falls into the water first, the impact may damage the internal organs, or even cause fatal consequences such as spleen rupture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another risk comes from the complex and unpredictable underwater conditions of natural waters. Every time the diving team arrives at a new water area, they will send members to go into the water first to survey - how deep is the water and whether there are large rocks or sharp foreign objects. Wang Tieshun once found a shared bicycle and several broken beer bottles underwater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Safety is the most important thing for the diving team. In addition to their own safety, there is also the safety of others. Some young people passing by also want to dive with the old men on a whim. &quot;When encountering this situation, we will first dissuade them - if you haven&#39;t practiced before, don&#39;t jump blindly. If you jump, we will also remind you: the water depth here is not enough. If your head enters the water, you must raise your head in time, otherwise it will be easy to poke vertically to the bottom of the water.&quot; Meng Meng and his team members have encountered many such young people. Some of them couldn&#39;t wait to take off their clothes and shoes, and shouted to plunge into the water. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AszaMg9utuc90L8NV6qbeO7qdiwcX63odawBLdio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the training, Zhang Yuan rode his electric bike home&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the years, the team members We have rescued many people who accidentally drowned. &quot;Especially in the summer of 2023, which was extremely hot, more people came to swim than in previous years. Many delivery boys came here to take a shower. They parked their cars on the shore, took off their riding clothes, and plunged in. After a while, He was dangling in the water, and when we found out, we quickly swam over and pulled him ashore,&quot; Wang Tieshun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/H4WW5WV1eLaFoXBHmyfeNUZIaWQZ76n9Dtjaq6aI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/H4WW5WV1eLaFoXBHmyfeNUZIaWQZ76n9Dtjaq6aI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251001&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the 1990s, Meng Derui participated in the New Year diving event at Xinjiekou Gap&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The fun and hidden dangers of natural waters&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For adults and adults, on the premise of ensuring safety, the fun of swimming in natural waters is something that cannot be achieved in indoor swimming pools. Comparable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the view is wide and there are few people. You can enjoy the natural scenery while swimming. Secondly, there is the water quality. Many adults said that they cannot stand the smell of disinfected water in indoor swimming pools, which &quot;makes their brains hurt.&quot; Natural waters like the South Moat are treated gray water, which is safe and odorless. Of course, there are also economic reasons. A swim in an indoor swimming pool costs at least dozens of yuan, and you only need to prepare a pair of swimming trunks in natural waters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, as Beijing’s water ecological environment has gradually improved, the water affairs department has continued to increase the openness and sharing of river and lake spaces to meet citizens’ water-related needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About two years ago, a group of swimming enthusiasts that Zhang Yuan belongs to forwarded eight officially opened natural water swimming spots in Beijing, including Beijing Bay Sunken Square, Dongzhimen Triangle, and Yongyin Canal 8. A lake and the south moat where the diving team is currently located, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The warning sign here used to be &#39;No Swimming&#39;, but now it is &#39;Civilized Water Activities, Ensure Life Safety&#39;. Recently, the relevant departments have also equipped lockers on the shore. These are welcome new features. Weather.&quot; Mendry said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Regulations on the Protection and Management of Rivers and Lakes in Beijing&quot;, in non-water source protection areas and waters where there are no &quot;No swimming, skating and other water activities&quot; signs, event personnel or organizers should take safety protection measures. activities under the premise. However, due to safety concerns, relevant managers will dissuade you from doing so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aFL7XoG9cTQG7jiw1Edj0Za0VkTsmQItjeRiB9FN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;655&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/aFL7XoG9cTQG7jiw1Edj0Za0VkTsmQItjeRiB9FN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251005&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Every afternoon, the Beijing middle-aged and elderly diving team will train on the bank of the South Moat&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ql42WDKHFJS2FgkxK8WwWdWX82ooZHVXdh6swzDp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ql42WDKHFJS2FgkxK8WwWdWX82ooZHVXdh6swzDp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251006&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align : center;&quot;>;The two movable jumping platforms currently used by the team members are made by Wang Tieshun, which is safe, easy to move without damaging the guardrails&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&quot;Some managers are afraid of being held responsible for accidents, so they set up obstacles and prevent swimming in legal natural waters. We have our own ideas about this. Many of us have been swimming our whole lives, and we often travel in groups. How could something happen so easily? Among our team members, there are quite a few people who have rescued people who slipped and fell into the water, accidentally drowned, and committed suicide. Without daily outdoor exercise, how could we have the ability and physique to save people?&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an hopes to pay attention to nature. The management of water activities in water areas should not be “one size fits all”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As evening approached, Mr. Li, who lived nearby, took his children to the river to swim. The family had just moved to Dongcheng District for the purpose of studying for their children. One day I was riding by here and saw people swimming and diving in the river. The children also wanted to try it. Now they can&#39;t wait to come here to play in the water every day after school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For children, this kind of natural water area is definitely much better than the experience in an indoor swimming pool. You can have more fun here. Diving is not allowed in the indoor swimming pool, and you cannot change swimming lanes at will, because it will It affects other people.&quot; Mr. Li was a little concerned about the water quality at first, but the children swam for more than half a month and felt fine. &quot;The water quality here may have a higher microbial content, and the residual chlorine and urea in the swimming pool may be higher. . Chlorine is very harmful to the respiratory tract, especially children. If you keep swimming in it, there may be some potential harm. There is no such problem in natural waters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As he spoke, a large area The water plants floated slowly, and the curious children wanted to catch them, but Mr. Li immediately stopped him, &quot;Don&#39;t touch the water plants, they will tangle you up and make you unable to move your hands and feet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ZqSEGG8qNgvHrIWvY1o4zN8WQ1VQ2owc3DQpMNZF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/ZqSEGG8qNgvHrIWvY1o4zN8WQ1VQ2owc3DQpMNZF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251003&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;Beijing’s middle-aged and elderly diving team took a group photo with the Bayi Lake diving team who came to exchange and learn. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Diving is a spirit Relief&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Looking back on Meng Derui, the three years he spent learning diving in the sports school were unbearable. Other children were happily playing pinball and shooting cigarette cases after school, but he could only go to training hard. &quot;Although I was in the amateur team at the time, the training was very strict. A group of 10 jumps for each movement was counted, and five or six groups had to be danced in half a day. Basic skills such as leg presses and shoulder presses were interspersed in between. The coach was also very strict, and the movements were not up to standard. Just hit the bottom of the shoe.&quot; Meng Derui has a family with many children, and he is the sixth child. His family sent him to a sports school just to have a free place to take care of him and to exercise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Derui loves water by nature. He feels a sense of excitement when standing on the diving platform, and it is indescribable satisfaction when he jumps into the water. Later, when he went to the mountains and countryside, he took advantage of his lunch break to go to a nearby reservoir to continue practicing. After returning to Beijing for work, after dinner, I rode my bicycle to a bridge at Xinjiekou Gap to dive. On weekends or holidays, go dancing on the high platform of the outdoor swimming pool in Gongti or Taoranting Park. It costs 10 cents for two hours. At this time, there is no urging from the coach, but an inner need - when diving, you must concentrate on thinking about the movements and not have distracting thoughts, so that you can forget a lot of &quot;messy things&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring, Mengdry helped take care of his grandson. Sometimes when he did not come to training in the afternoon, his teammates knew that he must have gone to pick up his grandson. &quot;At home, it&#39;s all about fulfilling obligations, being tired and worrying. Coming here to dive with everyone is the most relaxing and joyful thing of the day,&quot; Mengdry called it a &quot;spiritual relief.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the training, the team members shared their fruits, and the brothers occasionally met up to have a drink. If a team member has a birthday or someone’s grandchild is one month old, they have to find a place to celebrate together. Not long ago, Meng Jiao&#39;s wife broke her foot. Zhang Yu&#39;an immediately sent his unused wheelchair to his home and accompanied him to the hospital. Several teammates went to visit his home. &quot;The relationship between our teammates is closer than that of real brothers.&quot; Mengdry sighed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/z2NcSoDaw1hiTgi3EsZx3v8RhVr4sY7tNJzjNbAP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/z2NcSoDaw1hiTgi3EsZx3v8RhVr4sY7tNJzjNbAP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251004&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meng Derui participated in the training&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yuan had many hobbies when he was young and studied art and decoration in his spare time , photography and design. In terms of sports, he is involved in skating, skiing, swimming, diving, cycling, running, and mountain climbing. He knows that he is not good at everything but enjoys the process and joy of learning and mastering each sport. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring, Zhang Yuan got acquainted with Meng Jiao and these like-minded teammates, and concentrated his energy on diving, almost without landing for three years. He felt physically stronger and more energetic than before. &quot;We seniors in our 60s have a very simple idea: move more, exercise more, get sick less, and put less burden on the country and our children.&quot; Zhang Yu&#39;an has many dancing friends around him, and many years of chronic diseases such as high blood pressure, hyperlipidemia, and arthritis have passed. Keep exercising and get effective control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AVhTcMPwnKlEGr8nImBensbQkNmV3Oanyl2i1hmJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/AVhTcMPwnKlEGr8nImBensbQkNmV3Oanyl2i1hmJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After training, Wang Tieshun rinsed his body with his own water. Almost every team member has such a homemade bucket&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One early morning two weeks ago, an 80-year-old man came for a morning tour of the moat alone. Died of sudden illness. After hearing this, the team members expressed their regrets. Zhang Yuan had his own thoughts: &quot;It is very sad that such an accident happened. But I think this old man died very happily and could immerse himself in his lifelong hobby at the last moment of his life. In this way Leaving silently is much better than struggling in the hospital bed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[和心智障碍者成为同事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256538]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Nervous and scared, I pushed open the door of the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether they will suddenly yell or rush to attack others, I don’t know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I walked forward cautiously, and no colleagues with mental disabilities showed up. Don’t ever encounter it, I thought silently in my heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pap tap tap~&quot; came the sound of footsteps going down the stairs, and around the corner I met the first colleague with a mental disability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The girl, with her high ponytails, smiling, with bright eyes, raised her hands and shook them at me, &quot;Sister...Hello, sister!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This It was an opening that I had anticipated a lot in advance but didn’t expect. I didn&#39;t know how to respond to her enthusiasm, so I forced a smile on my tight face, said &quot;Hello&quot;, and turned around to go upstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who knew that this girl was just here to lead the &quot;warm greeting army&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was catching up with my colleagues with mental disabilities in the factory who had changed into work clothes and went downstairs to do morning exercises. As they filed out, each one of them greeted me: some stopped and stood to say good morning to me. ; Some ran past me quickly, leaving echoes of hello drifting through my ears; others slowly walked downstairs, shyly saying good morning to me... The nervousness turned into surprise, and I suddenly Time just smiles and nods and says &quot;hello&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When they finished walking, the stairwell became quiet again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether they will suddenly yell or rush to attack others remains to be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I felt their outpouring of enthusiasm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I walked up the stairs, there were pictures of them hanging on one side of the wall: profiles of employees working hard; employees participating in events; female employees dressed beautifully for Women’s Day... They seemed to be telling me: look! I&#39;m not dangerous, I can work, I can be beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After completing the entry procedures, the ordinary employees of the factory began to introduce me to the basic information of the entire factory and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I walked into the production workshop. Every colleague with mental disabilities was working seriously at his or her position. There was only the sound of the machine and the trainer&#39;s voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are engaged in some simple assembly and sorting work, which is boring, but they enjoy it very much. On my first day here, I heard that one of my colleagues with mental disabilities was called the &quot;Clamp King&quot; because of his excellent work on clamps. This resounding name was well known in the factory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The factory is very user-friendly and will arrange work according to their characteristics and provide them with some auxiliary tools to help them complete their work more efficiently. For example, when sorting two types of parts, one large and one small, because the difference is very small, the factory will use a 3D printer to make a slot into which one type of part can be placed, so that colleagues with mental disabilities can tell which type of part it is by placing it. As I got familiar with the factory, I secretly admired it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During lunch, the employees lined up in an orderly manner when they heard the lunch bell and walked to the dining area carrying their plates. After I sat down, an employee sat next to me and started some conversation: Hello, sister, what is your name? My name is so-and-so, sister, are you here to work? Sister, you look so beautiful today. Sister, where are you from? … They spoke a little slowly and maybe a little unclear, but they were very polite. What surprised me most was that the girl with the twin tails said to me after finishing the meal: “Sister, I’ll eat and leave first, please take your time.” &quot;Then he picked up his dinner plate, wiped the table clean with paper, pushed the chair under the table, and left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They would sing their favorite songs in the lounge during lunch break, mostly catchy old songs. Some people sang seriously, some interrupted and made trouble, some sat quietly by the window and watched the scenery... The work bell rang, and they returned to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They will not shout suddenly or rush to attack others. Observation is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I was chatting with others that I was interning in a factory where people with mental disabilities were the main people. Others looked at me strangely: Can these people also work? Is it a welfare institution organized by the government? Before actually entering this workshop, I also had this &quot;strange vision&quot;. However, after truly understanding it, I realized that there is light and love here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Be civilized and polite, they are the best practitioners of this slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a graduate student majoring in journalism and communication)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot; >;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国三大车企工人首次同时举行罢工 前十天累计损失或超50亿美元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256852]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021183175256&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;The cumulative losses in the ten days before workers from the three major U.S. auto companies went on strike simultaneously for the first time may exceed US$5 billion.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2. myqcloud.com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp12 51434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/BOPk3l3OIt8A.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width= &quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/8a2e34ca5576678021183175256/BOPk3l3OIt8A.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the contract between the auto workers and the auto manufacturer expired on the 14th, and the two parties failed to reach an agreement, a large number of American auto workers began to strike in the early morning of the 15th local time. Analysts pointed out that the auto workers&#39; strike may plunge the operation of the auto industry into chaos, thereby affecting the US economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/f4c7415eb6194b0cc15e615530308082.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/f4c7415eb6194b0cc15e615530308082.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250950&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At midnight local time on the 14th, which is noon on the 15th Beijing time, the labor contracts of approximately 150,000 American auto workers with the three automakers General Motors, Ford and Stellantis expired, and both parties have not yet agreed. A new contract can be reached. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/e8e10b6679088463f2d72cd995a2fcd8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/e8e10b6679088463f2d72cd995a2fcd8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250948&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, 12,700 workers of the United Auto Workers union went on strike at the three plants of the three major automakers in Michigan, Missouri and Ohio. This is also the first time in more than 80 years since the founding of the United Auto Workers that auto workers have staged a strike against the three automakers mentioned above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;United Auto Workers President Sean Fein said that a larger &quot;general strike&quot; has not yet been held, but said that if labor and management cannot reach a new contract, &quot;any option is possible&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/433b080d4bb33de030b2175f207c4685.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/433b080d4bb33de030b2175f207c4685.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250949&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Auto industry analyst Garrett Nelson:&lt;/strong>;The most optimistic estimate we have seen so far is that in terms of strike costs, the cumulative losses in the first ten days may exceed $5 billion. The automobile industry is the largest manufacturing sector in the United States. If this situation continues into October and November, economic growth will definitely be affected in the third quarter and even more severely in the fourth quarter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花高价找“高富帅”？婚恋网站的“结婚保”与“VIP”套路多]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256741]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Relying on the rapidly developing Internet, dating and dating websites can theoretically provide broader and more convenient dating and matching services. However, in recent years, various routines and suspected cases of &quot;pig killing plate&quot; have occurred frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Beijing Business Daily&quot; reported in April this year that Ms. Zhang spent 20,000 yuan on Baihe.com to purchase a &quot;marriage insurance&quot; matchmaking service. The &quot;matchmaker&quot; who matched the service said that she would introduce high-quality men to her, and then successively Recommended 5 men.陈女士提到，5位男士并未表达出足够的交流意向，没有自我介绍，也无法证实“红娘”所提到的个人信息。在世纪佳缘北京安贞门店购买婚介服务的玉瑶（化名）也爆料，自己签订了合同，交费近10万元，门店工作人员曾向玉瑶承诺，将介绍“优质男性”且“保证成功”。而玉瑶对接几位男用户后，均未建立男女朋友关系。两位女性因对婚恋网站服务不满要求退款，但对方均要扣除高额费用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在线社交是一种宽松的、渐进式的交友模式，但婚恋网站提供的服务目的性很强，注册会员乃至购买收费服务的男女，有着明晰的婚恋诉求，期待能通过婚恋网站找到与自身要求匹配的对象，在外形、收入、职位等方面，都有相应的预期和衡量标准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;婚恋网站面向此类男女，会提供两种服务，一种是免费注册服务，用户注册后，对同在网站注册的异性用户“海选”，寻找条件相符、可交流的异性交流。然而，这种方式效率低，耗费大量时间精力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了节省筛选成本，提高成功率和安全性，部分消费者选择了婚恋网站提供的付费服务。对此，婚恋网站提供“线下红娘”服务，具体又分为电话客服和情感顾问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，澎湃新闻记者以应聘的形式卧底进入世纪佳缘网线下一家门店。短期培训上岗后，该门店即为记者开通了后台权限，通过后台可以查看世纪佳缘网注册会员的个人信息，包括用户的浏览记录和聊天记录。拿到用户“大数据”后，电话客服通过电话、短信等方式邀请用户到店里面谈。记者查询系统后台的呼叫数量统计发现，该门店的多数销售平均每天拨出电话100通左右。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当有客户到店后，负责面聊的情感咨询顾问则要运用话术引导，比如，“相对于动辄几百万上千万一套商品房，花万把块找到爱人很值”，再展示其掌握的优质备选人资料，诱导用户签约付费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;澎湃报道：2017年，曾使用过“红娘一对一”服务的消费者刘刚说，线上会员收费较低，会员之间发信息、看信息都收费，用户每年也就花费几百元会员费。高端服务价格则从一万到几十万不等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为何如此多人踩坑？婚恋市场的供需关系也起到了推动作用。世纪佳缘没有公布过付费会员男女占比，但号称“硕博相亲平台”的理想岛VIP发布《2023理想岛VIP用户报告》称，理想岛VIP用户中男性占40.2%，女性占59.8%。其中，上海、成都、广州、北京、深圳五地用户女性占比都超过六成。据悉，成为理想岛VIP后，搜索到心动异性，如需发起交换微信申请，则需付费购买会员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;婚恋网站用户呈现“男少女多”现象，或是因为男性在恋爱期间往往要承担双方约会支出大头，特别是底层男性结婚时还要支付彩礼，对于购买付费婚恋服务决策较为谨慎。一些女性基于自身年龄、对方收入、职业等方面考虑更多，通过付费服务找到优质男性的需求更为迫切。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这也就不难理解，为何在婚恋网站设计的各种服务陷阱中，女性用户更易被骗。 2021年，浙江广电《小强在线》栏目报道称，杭州市民陆女士2019年11月注册成为世纪佳缘的会员，想找一个合适的伴侣。为此，她不惜借贷13万多用以缴纳会费，因为合同规定，只要她在合同期内，跟红娘推荐的对象登记结婚，可以全额返还会费。但签约后，红娘推荐的人选往往不符合陆女士标准，最终陆女士要求全额返款。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了推荐对象与之前承诺“货不对板”，还曾有用户遭遇疑似“婚托”事件。新京报2017年报道，曾在珍爱网和世纪佳缘工作过两年的晓晴说，婚托是普遍存在的。有的销售红娘觉得这个会员没戏，或者其要求的条件很难找，那么红娘就会把自己的人介绍给对方，并明确说不能建立关系，只是凑人数，走走过场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从上述事件可以看出，婚恋网站的“按期结婚退全款”承诺、“结婚保”服务，都是以所谓兜底承诺为由，让女性用户进入其连环套路——用话术洗脑诱导其付费，在见面环节以“婚托”冒充优质男性。尽管早在2017年，共青团中央、民政部、国家卫生计生委就制定并下发了《关于进一步做好青年婚恋工作的指导意见》，要求推动婚恋交友平台严格执行实名认证和实名注册，严厉打击婚托、婚骗等违法婚介行为，但仅靠婚恋网站自律，缺乏常态化治理的力度和广度，用户维权难，此类套路就会继续蔓延。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一边补贴购车，一边对中国电动车反补贴调查，欧盟为何双标？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256872]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-17 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/vRua021qrFj0ZpFrqYpZ4Wv0gH0XflmZuPMb1fs2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1062&quot; height=&quot;708&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/vRua021qrFj0ZpFrqYpZ4Wv0gH0XflmZuPMb1fs2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250981&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月，慕尼黑车展。今年为中国车企有史以来参照数量最多的一年，不只是比亚迪、小鹏汽车、零跑汽车、上汽MG、阿维塔和赛力斯等车企参展，还包括宁德时代、亿纬锂能、欣旺达和中创新航等零部件、软硬件供应商。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出海迅猛的中国电动汽车遭遇了“绊脚石”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中国汽车工业协会数据，2023年前8个月，中国新能源汽车出口同比猛增110%。但2023年9月13日，欧盟委员会主席冯德莱恩宣布，将对来自中国的电动汽车发起反补贴调查。调查的核心内容是中国政府是否提供补贴，以评估欧盟是否需要征收惩罚性关税。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《电动汽车观察家》创始人邱锴俊认为，各国都在出台政策支持本国电动汽车产业发展，中国只是更早实行补贴而已，不存在正当性的问题。而且中国针对新能源汽车的“国补”政策已经于2022年终止，但有的欧盟成员国至今仍在对本国新能源汽车实行补贴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月14日，中国商务部新闻发言人回应，中国电动汽车产业快速发展，竞争力不断提升，这是坚持不懈开展科技创新、构建完整产业链供应链的结果。中方敦促欧盟从维护全球产业链供应链稳定以及中欧全面战略伙伴关系的大局出发，与中方开展对话磋商。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;中国电动汽车“国补”政策已经退出&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“全球市场现在充斥着更便宜的中国电动汽车。而巨额国家补贴人为地压低了它们的价格。”冯德莱恩称，这是欧盟考虑对来自中国的电动车启动反补贴调查的核心理由。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧盟委员会表示，中国在欧洲售出的电动汽车的市场份额已经上升到8%，并有可能在2025年达到15%。这一快速增长的占比是因为，中国电动车相较欧洲车型普遍存在20%左右的价格优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国政府确实给予了电动车补贴，但也很早设定了补贴的退出机制。2022年初，财政部等四部门联合发文，明确2022年新能源汽车购置补贴政策于2022年12月31日终止，之后上牌的车辆不再给予补贴，延续13年的电动汽车“国补”政策正式退出历史舞台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;反观欧洲，近年来也出台了诸多对电动汽车产业的补贴政策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，德国对纯电动汽车根据售价给予不同的补贴，4万欧元以下车型最高补贴4500欧元。2023年，法国普通消费者的购车补贴为5000欧元，低收入家庭的电动汽车补贴增至7000欧元。2023年2月1日，欧盟委员会提议增加国家补助，使欧盟国家能够在电动汽车和其他绿色产品的生产领域中与其他国家竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“发展电动汽车这样的新兴产业，各国的产业政策都非常积极，只是存在着程度的差异。”邱锴俊表示，“早年所谓的完全自由市场，完全不干预产业发展的经济理论，在欧美其实也已经不流行了，当地也对新兴产业有很强的干预和扶持。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;对中国车企影响仍需观察&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;根据欧盟法规，反补贴调查最多需要13个月，意味着还需等待约一年后的“靴子落地”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在9月13日晚间，中概股新能源汽车就已集体下跌。小鹏汽车跌3.11%，理想汽车跌0.54%，蔚来跌4.64%。港股汽车股尾盘走低，比亚迪股份、小鹏汽车分别下跌3.53%、2.47%，吉利汽车跌1.52%，长城汽车、蔚来、理想汽车小幅下跌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在反补贴调查启动前，欧洲政策相对友好，对从中国进口的汽车征收关税为10%，而美国则为27.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邱锴俊表示，目前中国车企成本优势非常明显。若调查后被加征反补贴关税，增加幅度不大，中国车企依然具备竞争力；但如果被征收惩罚性关税，例如100%、150%的级别，打击将非常大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有远见的中国车企已准备在欧洲建设工厂，反补贴调查将可能加快他们的建厂进度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港中文大学（深圳）国际事务研究院研究员吴丹建议，中国车企应在行业协会的协助下加强协调磋商，形成共进退的立场和策略，完善涉外经贸法律工具箱，准确掌握欧盟立法信息和进展，与商务部密切合作，在中欧经贸高层对话中和欧方开展谈判。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;中国有最好的电动汽车产业链&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;不少外国车企在中国设有工厂，所谓来自中国的电动汽车，也包含他们在内。反补贴调查也将波及在中国制造的非中国品牌车型，如特斯拉、宝马等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“外资品牌愿意在中国设厂，是用脚投票。不是因为中国有补贴，而是因为中国有最好的电动汽车产业链，拥有很好的汽车产业工人，正如马斯克盛赞特斯拉上海超级工厂的工人聪明且勤奋。”邱锴俊称。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月13日，欧盟中国商会发表声明，中国电动汽车及上下游产业链企业不断创新，并在激烈的中国本土市场中累积出了整体产业优势，这种优势不是凭借所谓巨额补贴而形成的。中信证券的研报也指出，当前中国电动车并不以低价为卖点，竞争力来自技术积累、质量控制、用户体验。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;产业优势体现在了价格优势上。邱锴俊向南方周末记者举例，大众汽车旗下的ID.3车型，既在中国生产，也在德国生产，在德国售价为4万欧元，而在中国售价约1.5万欧元，巨大价差引起了德国一阵舆论风潮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据研究机构JATO Dynamics的一项统计，自2015年以来，欧洲电动汽车的平均价格从4.9万欧元上涨至5.6万欧元，美国从5.3万欧元上涨至6.4万欧元，而中国从6.7万欧元下降至3.2万欧元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/sgbOXPSp4wVLuSzSIK5Atygt7XfxqiISz85gHrFJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1086&quot; height=&quot;723&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/sgbOXPSp4wVLuSzSIK5Atygt7XfxqiISz85gHrFJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年5月23日，匈牙利德布雷岑，由中国宁德时代科技有限公司(CATL)投资的电动汽车电池厂正在建设中。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;出海之路漫长且艰难&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;此次欧盟对来自中国的电动汽车发起反补贴调查，不禁让人回想起欧盟于2012年对中国出口的光伏组件进行的“双反”（反倾销、反补贴）调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邱锴俊介绍，中国光伏产业兴起时，俗称“三头在外”，即原材料、技术、市场都在国外，中国作为主要加工地，由此发展起来。在“双反”调查中，中国光伏产业遭受了巨大打击，但也正是在这个阶段，中国光伏产业充分挖掘了内生力量，原材料、技术、市场都实现了本地化，当“双反”调查撤销后，重新占据了很大市场份额。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而电动汽车行业的发展路径与光伏行业有所不同。中国电动汽车起源于本地市场，发展到一定程度后再走出国门。中国新能源汽车目前市场渗透率为35%左右，国内还有很大市场需求，。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次欧盟的反补贴调查也敲响了警钟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴丹认为，欧盟对来自中国的电动汽车发起反补贴调查是典型的贸易保护主义，是欧盟双重标准的体现，无论在法律上还是道义上都完全站不住脚。目前，关于此反补贴调查，欧盟内部也存在巨大分歧，德法内部政治势力都是既有支持也有反对，但在现今政治环境下，德法内部的支持势力有能力推动欧盟启动调查，甚至影响调查结论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但除了面临贸易保护主义的阻碍，吴丹认为，中国汽车国标与国际标准不统一、我国新能源汽车出口认证制度尚未与国际接轨、海外消费能力下滑等因素，都制约了我国新能源汽车的国际化发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴丹曾撰文表示，在当前阶段，我国车企海外投资设厂规模远不及发达国家的传统跨国汽车制造商，中国车企想要从传统贸易模式向海外事业发展模式转变，提升配套供应链自主性和品牌影响力，还要经过漫长且艰难的过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[恒大财富杜某等涉嫌犯罪人员被采取刑事强制措施]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256870]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mmbiz.qpic.cn/sz_mmbiz_jpg/Dm1HIR5mtBCpZsNIdQqubPCVicQZnZDBHsmns7gVm9iav5GtKbUibVljN4L3I5fNFCpHzwLxUYWrW5bEH9Kia5nIBw/640?wx_fmt=jpeg&amp;amp;wxfrom=5&amp;amp;wx_lazy=1&amp;amp;wx_co=1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 0.5;&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;https://mmbiz.qpic.cn/sz_mmbiz_jpg/Dm1HIR5mtBCpZsNIdQqubPCVicQZnZDBHsmns7gVm9iav5GtKbUibVljN4L3I5fNFCpHzwLxUYWrW5bEH9Kia5nIBw/640?wx_fmt=jpeg&amp;amp;wxfrom=5&amp;amp;wx_lazy=1&amp;amp;wx_co=1&quot; data-key=&quot;media-1694873788117-0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[走近霍尔果斯“守关人”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256824]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FqInwUqfJtlhA5sf3cCHzxzSO15M5p9oKUr1J14C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;539&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FqInwUqfJtlhA5sf3cCHzxzSO15M5p9oKUr1J14C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250554&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;民警对夜间出境的中欧班列进行监护&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张佳/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;晚上10点，太阳刚刚落山，铁轨和石子依旧炙热，火车发动机散发出的高温蒸得人难受。民警岳爽行走在热浪中，叮嘱各点位民警注意做好列车监护。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里是位于中哈边境的霍尔果斯铁路口岸，也是中欧（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;亚&lt;/span>;）班列西线大通道之一。铁路货场的四条车道停满等待出入境的班列，后续等待入场的列车在远方拉响汽笛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/EZXRelpVvmcOYVYSip9HBnFRDsa5IZRPBoZ79QCu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/EZXRelpVvmcOYVYSip9HBnFRDsa5IZRPBoZ79QCu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250558&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;霍尔果斯铁路口岸及周边货场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张佳/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贯穿货场东西两端，有一条1050米长的监护路。作为霍尔果斯出入境边防检查站（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以下简称“霍尔果斯边检站”&lt;/span>;）执勤三队副队长，岳爽在这条路上走过了11年，见证了铁路口岸的开通和发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;霍尔果斯有着一百多年的通关历史，是我国面向中亚、西亚乃至欧洲的距离最近、最便捷的窗口。 2012年7月，刚从军校毕业的岳爽被分配到霍尔果斯边检站，那时这座边城人口稀少，晚上10点以后大部分商铺就打烊了，街上“连吃拌面的地方都没有。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qjKUBwucyDgNE2lVo40qHUiVplDQZLmcvakaf6S3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/qjKUBwucyDgNE2lVo40qHUiVplDQZLmcvakaf6S3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250557&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;上勤前，岳爽检查民警的警容风纪&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张佳/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年12月22日，霍尔果斯铁路口岸开通试运营，岳爽作为首批民警进驻执勤现场，茫茫戈壁上只有四条铁轨、一条监护廊桥和一座临时搭建的彩钢房。按照中哈双方协定，当时铁路口岸实行7天×12小时勤务模式，但每天出入境货运列车只有七八列。岳爽用“枯燥”来形容当时的勤务，“没多大业务量，但熬人得很。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;变化发生在2014年，当年2月铁路口岸正式开放。岳爽还记得，那年夏天往来班列较以往增长了一倍还多，并呈持续增长趋势。这一变化的背景是，中国在2013年提出共建“一带一路”倡议，而霍尔果斯正处在“新丝绸之路经济带”的“核心区”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WO9Y5ktr951A1xtFgbFggEZnfeaSqjKbqpjUGkbj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WO9Y5ktr951A1xtFgbFggEZnfeaSqjKbqpjUGkbj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250553&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;检查货车车头，防止藏匿非法物品&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张佳/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;霍尔果斯在蒙古语中意为“驼队经过的地方”，自古就是丝绸之路上的重要隘口。如今，这里又是连霍（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;连云港—霍尔果斯&lt;/span>;）高速公路和312国道的起讫点，“双西公路”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;中国西部—欧洲西部&lt;/span>;）的东部入口，在促进东西方社会互通互联方面有着无可比拟的地位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/lAS1xailDfF88mOdOZIY1ETlBiJn5n8Vc4chJmHB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/lAS1xailDfF88mOdOZIY1ETlBiJn5n8Vc4chJmHB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250559&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;民警爬上廊桥，对班列进行监护&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张佳/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年3月，霍尔果斯铁路口岸开通中欧（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;亚&lt;/span>;）班列，凭借自身独特的区位优势成为国际物流陆路运输的“黄金通道”——从最初年运营量不足400列，到如今通行中欧（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;亚&lt;/span>;）班列数量累计超过3万列，班列开行线路累计达78条，辐射境外18个国家、45个城市和地区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FmGY4SHJsZgoAPseKRsjQbHW5lTUyUHAZQdV0Dn5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/FmGY4SHJsZgoAPseKRsjQbHW5lTUyUHAZQdV0Dn5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250560&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;民警预先检查出境旅客证件&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张佳/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在岳爽记忆中，最初查验主要靠人力，民警要一节一节爬进车厢、检查车底，防止不法分子或违禁物品藏匿其中非法出入境，查验一趟班列需要半个小时以上。后来他们形成一套成熟的查验流程，强化科技手段，对出入境班列进行全方位监护，如今查验一趟班列只需10分钟左右。为了更好地适应不断增长的通关需求，边检站将铁路口岸调整为365天×24小时勤务模式，任何时候都能对出入境班列做到即到即检即放。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/1eF7ZbQvGlj1T8fCvN2CBPnzdGYnDZDn2hnXiIRB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/1eF7ZbQvGlj1T8fCvN2CBPnzdGYnDZDn2hnXiIRB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250561&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;核对出境货车司机的身份&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张佳/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“春秋还好，最难熬的是夏天和冬天。”岳爽说，执勤现场夏季最高温度达50摄氏度以上，铁轨上都能煎鸡蛋，常有人晕倒在执勤现场；冬天最低气温则降到零下三十多摄氏度，民警查验时，手一不小心就被黏在车厢铁皮上，用力一撕，车厢上就会留下血淋淋的皮肉。 2018年12月，口岸遭遇暴风雪天气，积雪厚达七十多公分，为了不影响班列正常开行，民警彻夜清扫积雪，归来时每个人身上都结了厚厚的冰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在铁路口岸西北方向，直线距离约两千米之外，矗立着2018年9月启用的第六代国门。每天都有数百辆货车从公路口岸出境，将中国制造源源不断地运往中亚和欧洲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Sdb8D0QuKty04rr4pXZlh6X3aDOCxCsI4vXRGoE5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Sdb8D0QuKty04rr4pXZlh6X3aDOCxCsI4vXRGoE5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;公路客运执勤现场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张佳/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;霍尔果斯边检站执勤二队队长曾琦见证了从第五代到第六代国门的变迁，在他看来，新国门的设计理念更先进。旅客只需要指纹、刷脸，仅用15秒就可通关；货车采用一站式查验和一次性通关，提高通关效率。 2023年1月1日至7月21日，该口岸出入境车辆突破10万辆次，超过以往历年公路口岸全年的通关量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“还有许多潜在变化是平时看不到的。”曾琦说。以往出口商品主要是果蔬、百货和各类日用品，现在则增加了建材、机械设备、精密仪器等，其中国产新能源车尤其受到“一带一路”沿线国家的欢迎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WKPqmSzsnAkezItMKQ5VwS3AhY40YNpCDOQrwJIm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WKPqmSzsnAkezItMKQ5VwS3AhY40YNpCDOQrwJIm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;第六代国门前，等待出境的各类车辆&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张佳/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让曾琦感触最深的是2023年5月的一天，临近下班，等待通关的车辆还排着长队。他们紧急与哈方边检部门会晤协商，征得对方同意延长通关时间。消息传来，在界桥前等待通关的司机们不约而同鼓起了掌。他们一直工作到第二天凌晨5时许，终于将待检车辆全部验放完毕。 “看着那么多中国制造从我们这里走出去，就算再累，也值了。”2023年8月15日，霍尔果斯公路口岸开始试行24小时货运通关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年是共建“一带一路”倡议提出十周年。伴随着口岸通关量的不断增长，越来越多的旅客到霍尔果斯观光旅游，各国的“淘金者”也在不断涌入，这座边城发生着日新月异的变化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岳爽有一次出境与哈方边检部门会晤，返回时已经入夜。他站在境外漆黑的旷野中遥望霍尔果斯，那里灯火通明、车水马龙，是座名副其实的“不夜城”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胡适与吴鼎昌父子刘廷芳兄弟：从吴元黎旧藏《四十自述》说起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256625]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/LL1yxLVpALUNrKyeCE83Pod4zXgpgeFhBJuc4Sss.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;882&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/LL1yxLVpALUNrKyeCE83Pod4zXgpgeFhBJuc4Sss.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250684&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;胡适签赠给吴元黎的《四十自述》。右图为青年吴元黎。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;远在加拿大的刘荣黔先生前不久微信上给我留言：“进入八十六岁了，趁还没有失智，把家里前辈留下的遗物整理一下，其中有一些旧书，选了三本想送给你。”他知道我爱书，开玩笑道：“宝剑赠英雄。”正好有一位华人朋友回国探亲，刘先生就托她随身带上，到家后再快递我。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没过几天，我就收到了南通寄来的三本书：一本是中华书局一九三五年版康有为《大同书》，封面封底均已脱落，扉页钤“吴环生”白文印。一本是正中书局一九四三年版蒋介石《中国的命运》，扉页有毛笔题字：“赵金镛兄惠存，弟梁夔敬赠。”赵金镛、梁夔都是民国时期的外交官员。还有一本远东图书公司一九五九年版胡适《四十自述》，竟然是胡适签名本。上款是刘荣黔先生的舅舅吴元黎，落款时间在一九六〇年五月三十一日。书内夹着《传记文学》第六卷第三期刊登的毛子水《胡适之先生逝世三年》复印件。这真出乎我的意料。心心念念胡适签名本已久，想不到是刘荣黔先生帮我圆了梦。这三本书都是吴元黎旧藏。刘荣黔先生告诉我，舅舅（编者注：吴元黎）在美国去世后，他到加州帮表妹处理舅舅遗物时，向表妹要的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;查胡颂平编的《胡适之先生年谱长编初稿》（增补版），一九六〇年六月一日条云：“吴元黎和刘廷蔚来见。元黎是吴鼎昌（达诠）的儿子，谈谈吴达诠的自传《花溪闲笔》。”可见胡适是提前一天准备好了书，赠送《四十自述》亦是用心之举，富有深意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;胡适与吴元黎并无深交，可能仅见过一两面。一九四九年六月十九日，他们曾在美国相遇。胡适在日记里没有过多的记录，只写了：“5:30 &amp;nbsp;Mr.Wu（Son of 达诠）。”此时，国民政府已撤出南京，胡适到了美国。六月二十一日，胡适电告退守广州的国民政府，向新任行政院长阎锡山辞去外长职务。但胡适对吴元黎的事迹应有所耳闻。一九五九年七月一日上午，他出席“中研院”第四次院士会议，并担任会议主席。会上，蒋硕杰报告中国旅美经济学者的研究现状，提到多位经济学方面的人才，其中就有吴元黎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/KQukqc6kLu6aOF9pBLBRSMm3uroyeMm8Jxnk6R1u.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;628&quot; height=&quot;1028&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/KQukqc6kLu6aOF9pBLBRSMm3uroyeMm8Jxnk6R1u.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250679&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吴鼎昌（后排右）、陈适云（中坐）夫妇与女儿吴元俊（后排左）、女婿刘廷蔚（后排中）、儿子吴元黎（前排右）合照。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴元黎一九二〇年生于上海，早年就读于上海南洋中学、圣约翰大学，后赴英深造。一九四二年，获得伦敦大学经济学第一等荣誉学位。一九四六年，获经济学博士学位，是哈耶克的弟子。回国后，他曾在中央银行任职。一九四九年，移居美国，任旧金山大学经济系教授。陈毓贤把在北美研究汉学的华人专家分为五大拨，其中第二拨是在“中华人民共和国成立前后，一批在教会大学就读或授课的学人迁移至北美，遇上二战后北美高等学府扩充迅速，他们中英文皆通，便在各大学落脚，成了各校中国研究的中坚分子”。吴元黎就是这第二拨中的佼佼者。一九六〇年起，吴元黎任斯坦福大学胡佛研究所研究员和顾问等职。他利用胡佛图书馆的丰富馆藏，撰写了《海外华人与东南亚的经济发展》《华人在东南亚经济发展中的作用》以及《台湾：走向工业化社会》等著作。正因为吴元黎对中国问题有精湛的研究，一九六九年到一九七〇年间担任了美国国防部副助理部长（Deputy Assistant Secretar）。一九八五年，吴元黎荣获德国洪堡基金会研究奖。二〇〇八年十一月，吴元黎不慎摔倒造成颅内出血，十八日在加州斯坦福大学医院去世，享年八十八岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/3BQKBU2VVI5x5r8qEWYPN7BSq3FboPaO0bFfSg1A.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1104&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/3BQKBU2VVI5x5r8qEWYPN7BSq3FboPaO0bFfSg1A.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250683&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吴刘两家人合影。前排左起徐元约（徐淑希长子）、刘母李玺、吴母陈适云、吴元黎，后排左起刘廷蔚、刘廷芳、刘文庄（刘廷芳二妹、徐淑希夫人）、吴鼎昌、吴元俊。刘荣黔提供。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我问刘荣黔先生，对这位舅舅（编者注：吴元黎）有什么特别的印象？他说，小时候他在贵阳外公外婆（编者注：指吴鼎昌夫妇，吴时任贵州省主席）身边生活，有一天邮递员送来一个银灰色盒子，里面有一块咖啡蛋糕，很多干果，外婆告诉他这是舅舅从伦敦寄来的，那种甜味至今没有忘记。抗战胜利还都南京，舅舅带了碧眼金发的舅母回来，这是他第一次见到舅舅，也是他第一次直接和“外国人”说话，觉得怪怪的。后来，舅舅去了美国，而他全家到台湾居住。一九六二年，外婆去世，舅舅曾回台奔丧。一九六五年，他在巴黎留学，舅舅舅母来看他，见他白天学设计，晚上在饭店打工，生活艰苦，舅舅建议他到美国改学经济，毕业后比较容易找工作，也可助他一臂之力。他回答舅舅：“我只会画画。”一九六五年，刘荣黔移居加拿大，几年后把父母接到加拿大住，舅舅每年都会来探亲。刘先生父母去世后，他常到加州探望舅舅，陪舅舅聊天，商讨纪念吴陈适云（编者注：吴鼎昌之妻）基金会的事。舅舅去世时，他正在北京，来不及奔丧，后来便去加州帮不认识中文的表妹整理满屋的中文书籍和资料。刘先生说，舅舅一生低调，动作说话和缓，善于倾听和发问，对后辈非常关心照顾。 “可能舅舅年轻时候在英国读书，受到英国人的冷幽默影响，在谈话中往往会冷不防让人发笑。记得那年在巴黎，我们坐在露天咖啡馆，他说巴黎很有趣，一半巴黎人坐在咖啡馆看另一半巴黎人。如果以一句话来形容我对舅舅的印象：他是一位带有幽默感的君子。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;胡适与吴元黎的父亲吴鼎昌却是老相识了，并对他有很高的评价。一九三一年二月二十六日，曹纕蘅邀柯劭忞、郑孝胥、江瀚、杨钟羲等人一起吃饭，也请了吴鼎昌、胡适，这是他们第一次见面。当天胡适日记有记：“吴君是一个能干的人，我久想见他，屡次相左。今日始初次见他。”吴鼎昌比胡适年长七八岁，是实业家、银行家，担任过中国银行总裁、盐业银行总经理以及北京政府财政部次长等职。后来，他收购了《大公报》，自任社长，请胡政之任总经理、张季鸾任总编辑，使《大公报》获得新生，成为全国颇有影响的报纸之一。因此，给胡适留下了“能干”的印象。当年十一月，南京国民政府设立财政委员会，胡适、吴鼎昌同为委员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gvp2av25spnjzLea2PNQn5ygS6DkCvKHe2kwJAk4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;479&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gvp2av25spnjzLea2PNQn5ygS6DkCvKHe2kwJAk4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250682&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘廷蔚吴元俊婚礼照片。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（刘荣黔供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一九三三年六月十一日，胡适赴美访问前夕，经过天津，吴鼎昌专门去拜访。他们“谈了两点多钟”，吴鼎昌“主张&#39;还政国民&#39;最力，也主张把许多建设事业暂时中止”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一九三四年一月三十一日，胡适与吴鼎昌在南京汪精卫的官舍相遇，在座还有张季鸾、任鸿隽、陈衡哲、唐有壬、曾仲鸣等，他们大谈外交内政问题。意犹未尽。散后，回到寓所，胡适与吴鼎昌谈到深夜。当时，中日关系日趋紧张，对于外交内政政策，有很多不同的声音。胡适与吴鼎昌的意见显然不同，但这并不影响胡适对吴鼎昌的好印象。当年七月，胡适撰写《从私立学校到燕京大学》，谈到私人捐款兴学，又举了吴鼎昌的例子：“钱多的可以改造一个大学。……钱少的也可以专补助某一校某一部分，如吴鼎昌先生的捐助南开大学经济学系助学金额。这样方才可以积少成多，使已有成绩的学校变为更有成绩。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;胡适与吴元黎、刘廷蔚谈到的《花溪闲笔》，是吴鼎昌在贵州省政府主席任上写的，一九四〇年十月由贵州日报社印行，有《赴任时》《到任后》《省》《县》《中央行政与地方》《杂感》《附言》七章。过了三年，胡政之劝吴鼎昌续写《花溪闲笔》，故有《续编》九章，即《省政》《县镇》《新县制》《县与乡镇》《新生活》《治安与帮会》《经济与统制》《财政与会计》《杂感》，于一九四三年十月由贵州企业股份有限公司印刷所刊行。吴鼎昌办过报纸，据说诗文都很不错。曹聚仁说过：“余读其《花溪闲笔》正续编，喜其平实近情。他的女公子，集其所作诗篇，分送至好；我看了，觉得名下无虚士，有可传之作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;离开贵州后，吴鼎昌担任过国民政府文官长兼国民党中央设计局秘书长、总统府秘书长等职，曾向蒋介石建议邀请毛泽东到重庆谈判。一九四九年一月，已退休的吴鼎昌在儿子的催促下，来到香港生活。一九五〇年八月二十二日，吴鼎昌以癌症不治在港病逝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WrMFUIDTySoVmp3a1GM2tmUVYsCQiSp4eHl8e3wK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;610&quot; height=&quot;927&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/WrMFUIDTySoVmp3a1GM2tmUVYsCQiSp4eHl8e3wK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250681&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘廷芳（左）刘廷蔚（右）兄弟。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（刘荣黔供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与吴元黎同去拜访胡适的刘廷蔚，胡适日记里没有作介绍。刘廷蔚是吴鼎昌的女婿，刘荣黔先生的父亲，一九〇三年生，浙江温州人。燕京大学毕业后留学美国康奈尔大学，获昆虫学博士学位。学成回国，历任沪江大学生物系教授、南京中央农业实验所技正、中央农业实验所贵州工作站技正、农复会农业组技正等职。一九四九年，农复会迁到台湾后，刘廷蔚任第一组即后来的植物生产组组长，直到一九六五年退休。刘廷蔚还是一位诗人，诗作颇受陶行知、徐志摩、沈从文赞赏，出版过诗集《山花》《我的杯》。其妻吴元俊乃吴鼎昌长女，一九一二年生，曾就读于燕京大学，与周一良同学，颇有才华，在校时协助容庚编《金文续编》。曹聚仁说的为吴鼎昌印诗集的女儿就是吴元俊。刘廷蔚吴元俊于一九三三年七月结婚，相濡以沫一辈子。晚年，他们随儿女在加拿大、美国生活。一九九四年一月，刘廷蔚在加拿大去世。二〇〇一年十二月，吴元俊在美国去世。两人都活到九十多岁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;胡适与刘廷蔚没有什么直接的交集，但对他的大哥刘廷芳却是很熟悉的。刘廷芳少年之时就深得苏慧廉、蔡博敏、司徒雷登等人的赏识，司徒雷登更是推荐他到上海圣约翰大学深造，后又安排他赴美留学。刘廷芳在美先后获哥伦比亚大学学士、硕士学位，耶鲁大学神学院神学士学位，哥伦比亚大学教育心理学博士学位。回国后，与司徒雷登一道在燕京大学工作，是司徒雷登开创燕大事业的重要助手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/kzPxt48fnGol2uq1muiA1nHoLJfOKkF0tqevZMwr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;525&quot; height=&quot;815&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/kzPxt48fnGol2uq1muiA1nHoLJfOKkF0tqevZMwr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250680&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;晚年吴元黎。上世纪四十年代，吴元黎主张赋予穷人权利，由他们自由发展。另一位著名经济学家方显廷则主张依靠精英的规划发展经济，由精英替穷人作主，两人的争论以方显廷得势而告终。吴元黎退走美国，名字渐渐被人遗忘。直到2007年，美国的经济思想史学者保罗·特雷斯科特才重新发现了吴元黎，认为吴方论战是发展经济学史上最早的论战。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;胡适日记里最早关于刘廷芳的记载在一九二一年四月二十八日：“到刘廷芳家吃饭。刘君治宗教学，家藏宗教史的书甚多。”同年五月十八日：“上午，司徒尔先生与刘廷芳牧师与霍进德先生来谈。”同年六月三十日，北京大学、男女两高师、尚志学会、新学会等在中央公园今雨轩为杜威一家饯行，胡适与刘廷芳、吴卓生夫妇都在。胡适代表北大致词，自己译成汉语又讲了一次。吴卓生代表女高师致词，则由刘廷芳翻译成汉语。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一九二一年时，燕京大学想改良国文部，司徒雷登、刘廷芳邀请胡适去主持工作，但胡适没有同意，而是推荐周作人去。他认为周作人在北大用非所长，很可惜，所以让他“出去独当一面”。不巧周氏病了，此事就搁置了一年。次年，燕京方面又提起此事，故一九二二年三月四日，胡适邀司徒雷登、刘廷芳、周作人来，为他们做介绍，让他们自己当面谈。胡适日记记道：“他们谈的很满意。”周作人在燕大教了十来年书，直到被北大聘为研究教授，不能兼外校课程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一九三七年一月十一日，胡适“到燕大刘廷芳吃饭”。此后胡适日记再无刘廷芳出现。刘廷芳后来当选为立法委员，但因身体状况一直欠佳，一九四二年赴美就医，一九四七年逝世于新墨西哥州一家长老会医院，享年五十六岁。不知胡适与刘廷蔚见面时，有否想起他的哥哥刘廷芳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘荣黔先生现生活于加拿大魁北克省蒙特利尔市，一直邀请我去游玩。 “别忘了我这年纪已经在倒数计时了，请尽早成行。”而我却想，他应趁现在还能走动，早点回家看看。刘荣黔久居海外，从未到过老家温州。二〇一五年五月，他在杭州举办“无意之境”摄影艺术展，我去观摩学习，匆匆一面。幸好还有微信，分别后我们可以随时网上交流。那是刘荣黔先生离老家最近的一次。几个月前，南京大学沈卫威教授来温州大学讲座之便，让我陪他去寻访刘廷芳旧踪。那一带正进行历史街区改造，刘廷芳回国后为他母亲建的小洋房已不得入。沈教授透过一幢办公楼里的卫生间窗户才看到刘氏故居一角。所以，请刘荣黔先生“尽早成行”吧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>