<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[格力电器：董明珠“绯闻”是造谣，已向公安机关报案]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260839]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 17, Gree Electric responded to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News: &quot;Regarding the recent efforts of many self-media To obtain traffic, maliciously edit relevant videos, and use vulgar and filthy words to insult and slander company executives, Gree Electric has reported the case to the public security organs, which have accepted and filed the case.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanduwan Financial News reporter learned that recently There are rumors on social platforms that Dong Mingzhu, chairman and president of Gree Electric Appliances, is in love with Wang Ziru, the &quot;channel reform project leader&quot; of Gree Electric Appliances. In a recent TV program, Dong Mingzhu responded, &quot;I don&#39;t even watch it. I don&#39;t think it matters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the same program, Wang Ziru said: &quot;I didn&#39;t watch it.&quot; &quot;I passed the salary slip issued to me by Gree&quot; and &quot;asked for an office close to the Dong Zong to facilitate reporting&quot;, etc., which have attracted much attention and controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Cheetah Mobile CEO Fu Sheng expressed his views on Wang Ziru in WeChat Moments. Fu Sheng said, &quot;I can only say that Wang Ziru is not only a freeloader, but also a gangster.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public information, Wang Ziru is the founder of ZEALER (ZEALER Network Technology). Tianyancha shows that ZEALAR was established in June 2012. It is a technology information website focusing on electronic product evaluation and Q&amp;A, and then expanded its mobile phone repair business, mobile device hardware laboratory, etc. Wang Ziru is not only the executive director and general manager of ZEALER, but also a digital review blogger with 1.97 million fans. He once became popular because of his public debate with Smartisan CEO Luo Yonghao over the review controversy of the Smartisan T1 mobile phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/514e9a75ea33ae08723cd84c26eaf5b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258706&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The picture comes from Wang Ziru&#39;s personal Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from public information, Wang Ziru and Dong Mingzhu met in 2016. In an entrepreneurial program &quot;I Am the Founder&quot; broadcast that year, Dong Mingzhu served as the mentor of Wang Ziru&#39;s team. Afterwards, Wang Ziru posted a photo of herself and Dong Mingzhu on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/2067962a043e7e520701b62cdbf74731.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258707&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9119cff505d87f419fc3688441c0a05d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258708&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The picture comes from Wang Ziru&#39;s personal Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, Dong Mingzhu held a nationwide tour of live broadcast to bring goods. Wang Ziru appeared as the host many times, and together with Dong Mingzhu, they won 703 million yuan in sales. That year, Dong Mingzhu&#39;s 13 live broadcasts totaled 47.6 billion yuan, accounting for nearly 30% of Gree Electric&#39;s total revenue in 2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2021, Gree Electric confirmed the news of Wang Ziru joining Gree Electric. At that time, industry insiders said that Wang Ziru’s department was affiliated with Gree’s President Office and Cultural Training and Communication Center. During the same period, Wang Ziru resigned from his position at ZEALER, the media he founded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are rumors that Wang Ziru’s rank in Gree is equivalent to that of vice president, with an annual salary of more than 3 million yuan. However, judging from Gree Electric’s financial reports in the past two years, Wang Ziru has never appeared in the executive compensation table middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After joining Gree Electric, Wang Ziru rarely appeared on public platforms. Gree Electric did not disclose his specific work content. However, it is known from some public reports that he is currently in charge of the Gree channel reform project. In late May this year, Wang Ziru, who had been with Gree for two years but had not yet appeared, appeared publicly in Nanchang for the first time as the &quot;channel reform project leader&quot; and spoke at the 2023 Gree Electric (Jiangxi) new marketing model presentation conference. In October and November, Gree Electric Shandong and Hebei Sales Companies also issued documents, and Wang Ziru gave a speech at a new marketing model conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that at the beginning of this year, news appeared on social platforms that Gree Electric Chairman and President Dong Mingzhu was in love with his company’s post-85s male executive. The news originated from the big V Gong A screenshot posted by Wen Xiang on the Internet. In February this year, Dong Mingzhu took the initiative to mention and denounced in an interview with reporters from Nanduwan Financial News and other media: &quot;Vulgar, obscene, and boring! It is not an exaggeration to use these words to describe it.&quot; She clearly denied the love scandal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March this year, big V Gong Wenxiang apologized to Dong Mingzhu, chairman and president of Gree Electric Appliances, for his previous remarks in the Southern Metropolis Daily. Gong Wenxiang said in his apology statement that he made distorted remarks about Ms. Dong Mingzhu’s private life on Toutiao on February 26, which were widely disseminated and objectively damaged Ms. Dong’s reputation. &quot;I deeply regret and am deeply sorry to Ms. Dong. The special newspaper expresses my public apology and sincere remorse to Ms. Dong, and hopes to obtain Ms. Dong&#39;s forgiveness. I will use this as a lesson in the future to be a self-media person with three upright views.&quot; .&quot; Gong Wenxiang said in the statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 17, Gree Electric responded to a reporter from Nanduwan Financial News: It is worth mentioning that the Internet is not a place outside the law. The company will take legal measures to resolutely safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of the company and employees. We maintain a zero-tolerance attitude towards any malicious slander and rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the TV program mentioned above, Wang Ziru said that no company is drowned in saliva. As a business operator and manager, you should spend more time focusing on what you should do. things to do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[跨越45年，披头士乐队的最后一首歌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260778]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/ugwAYHhpApNoKEoTS7occJos7QvHMSE4qPCs2MW0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ugwAYHhpApNoKEoTS7occJos7QvHMSE4qPCs2MW0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258571&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Beatles were founded in 1960, a milestone in the history of pop music band. In 1980, lead singer John Lennon was shot and killed. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 30, 1969, on the rooftop of Apple Records headquarters at 3 Savile Row, England , the Beatles held a 42-minute impromptu concert. It was almost at the last moment that the idea was settled - they discussed it and then fell silent until John Lennon said, &quot;...let&#39;s do it!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Noon Around 12:30, the four people arrived on the rooftop. As word spread, people began to gather in the surrounding streets and on the rooftops of nearby buildings. That day, Lennon wore a fur coat, and Ringo put on his wife&#39;s red coat. In the biting cold wind of January, the members sang a total of five songs in a loop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concert finally came to an end with the melody of &quot;Get&amp;nbsp;Back&quot;. Lennon said humorously to the audience: &quot;On behalf of the band and ourselves, I want to say thank you. I hope we have passed the audition.&quot; However, the public at the time may not have expected that this would be the last of the Beatles. A public performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 2, 2023, after a span of 45 years, a new Beatles collaboration called &quot;Now And Then&quot; finally came to the public. After the familiar &quot;one, two, three&quot; timer, the accompaniment sounded, and Lennon&#39;s voice slowly flowed out:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;em>;&quot;&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;I know it&#39;s true / It&#39;s all because of you / And if I make it through / It&#39;s all because of you&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;……&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lennon in the MV The faces of George and George were still young, wearing bright costumes from that time, playing in the same space as Paul and Ringo. Different from their youthful and fresh appearance, the wrinkles on Paul and Ringo&#39;s faces are clearly visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It was incredibly touching to hear that they were still working together after all these years,” Lennon’s son Sean said. “It was my dad and Paul and George. , the last song we made together with Ringo.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;We&#39;ve been waiting almost a quarter of a century&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now And Then&quot; The story begins in 1978. Lennon recorded this vocal demo with accompaniment while playing the piano in his apartment in New York. By that time, he had focused on his family and had all but put his music career on hold, not touring or fulfilling any major label obligations. However, in his son Sean&#39;s memory, Lennon would always play music at home and record and make demos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1994, 14 years after Lennon’s death, during a chat with the Beatles, Lennon’s widow Yoko Ono said that she still had some of Lennon’s audio tapes. She gave them to the rest of the Beatles. &quot;If the three of us were to do something, it would be fun, but obviously not as fun as when John was here,&quot; George said. &quot;We really have to cherish hearing John&#39;s voice. I&#39;m sure he would really enjoy being with us.&quot; A chance to be together again.&quot; Now, that chance has come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We can use Lennon&#39;s music and try to make a record. Since his death, this is the closest we have been to him.&quot; Ringo said. Facing Lennon&#39;s demo tape, Paul also thought, &quot;Shouldn&#39;t we do this?&quot; But whenever he thought so, he would always interrupt himself, assuming that if he had the opportunity to ask Lennon - &quot;Hey , Lennon, do you want us to finish your song?&quot; - What would Lennon&#39;s answer be, and he believed that Lennon would say, &quot;Of course!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the song The production was not as smooth as expected. At that time, there was no technology that could separate the vocals from the accompaniment. In a way, Lennon&#39;s voice was actually hidden. Whenever they tried to make Lennon&#39;s voice clearer, the piano accompaniment grew louder, and the effect actually became worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They felt frustrated, &quot;We were kind of losing time and momentum,&quot; Paul said, as if they should abandon the song. &quot;Things cannot progress, and the fact that Lennon is no longer becomes more and more clear before our eyes.&quot; Ringo said. Just like that, &quot;Now&amp;nbsp;And Then&quot; was shelved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the year 2022. Previously, &quot;Lord of the Rings&quot; director Peter Jackson&#39;s team developed an artificial intelligence-based technology that can separate specific vocals from accompaniment sounds and repair them. This technology was proven successful in the 2021 documentary &quot;Get Back&quot; produced by Peter Jackson for the Beatles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the help of technology, Lennon&#39;s voice came out of the player again, &quot;as clear as crystal.&quot; &quot;We&#39;ve been waiting almost a quarter of a century for this moment to be able to make Now And Then again,&quot; Paul said. He called Ringo and told him he wanted to continue working on the song, and Ringo readily agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Lennon&#39;s piano accompaniment, Paul also added his own bass part, and Ringo also added his own drum beats. They retained George&#39;s guitar playing from 1995, &quot;which is a tribute to George.&quot; Paul said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A string section was also added with help from Giles Martin, son of the late Beatles producer George Martin. When recording this part, in order to keep it secret, they did not tell the string orchestra that it was a new Beatles song, but pretended it was Paul&#39;s own new single. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“All those memories came flooding back and, oh my God, how lucky I was to have these people in my life… Still making The Beatles in 2023 ’s music, wow!” Paul exclaimed, “‘Now And Then’ should be our last song.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Think of me from time to time, old friend”&lt;/strong>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;In February 1964, the Beatles performed in the United States for the first time. As they took off, more than 4,000 fans from Heathrow Airport waved goodbye; when they landed, another group of about 3,000 people greeted them when they landed. On the 9th of that year, the Beatles performed live on the Ed Sullivan Show, attracting about 73 million viewers, which accounted for about 34% of the U.S. population. The popularity of British rock and roll swept the United States with unprecedented intensity. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those were almost the most prosperous years of the Beatles. However, separation and death came to them prematurely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September of the same year as the Beatles&#39; last public performance together, Lennon informed his bandmates during a meeting with Ringo, Paul and their manager Alan Klein They, he was going to quit the Beatles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, due to business, creative, emotional and many other reasons, friction and differences had become increasingly serious, and it seemed that it was only a matter of time before they disbanded. During that meeting, George was absent, and Crane convinced the other band members to keep quiet about the breakup because some important business matters were still ongoing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 10 of the following year, Paul publicly announced his withdrawal from the Beatles, which was also regarded as a symbolic event of the dissolution of the Beatles. At that time, exactly ten years after their establishment, an American media person even claimed that it was &quot;a milestone in the decline of the British Empire.&quot; Asked whether his departure was temporary or permanent, Paul responded, &quot;I really don&#39;t know.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Years later, in a media interview, Paul denied that he had caused the band to break up. Due to Klein&#39;s request, they were kept secret about the band&#39;s breakup and had to pretend for several months that everything was normal. He simply &quot;had enough of hiding&quot; and, eventually, &quot;let the cat out of the bag.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following time, even though the Beatles have developed separately, fans still have lingering thoughts in their hearts, hoping that one day they will reunite. However, Lennon&#39;s death directly shattered this hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 8, 1980, after Lennon finished his work for the day, he returned to his residence with his wife Yoko Ono. The two got out of the car and walked to the building entrance of Dakota Apartments. At this moment, 25-year-old Mark David Chapman appeared and shot Lennon five times. Lennon&#39;s heart stopped forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;For everyone who hoped the Beatles would continue to exist, the murder was something else. It was an assassination, a ritual killing of something unspeakable, maybe It&#39;s hope, maybe idealism, or time. It&#39;s not just loss, but sudden dislocation and fragmentation.&quot; Critic Jay Cox wrote in a Time magazine cover article that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February of the following year, musician Carl Perkins wrote a song &quot;My Old Friend&quot; for Paul. The morning after it was finished, Carl took his guitar, sat down on Paul&#39;s old double reverb amp, and sang him this song: &quot;If we never meet again in this life...my old friend, won&#39;t you do it from time to time?&quot; Think of me...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Paul and his wife Linda sat on the floor and listened. After singing, Carl discovered that Paul was crying. Afterwards, he got up and left the room. Linda explained to him, &quot;Ever since what happened to Lennon, he hasn&#39;t been able to really break down... but how do you know?&quot; She said that Lennon&#39;s last words to Paul were in the hallway of the Dakota Building before his death. Exactly - at that time he patted Paul on the shoulder and said: &quot;Think of me now and then, old friend.&quot;&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Play a good band The key is chemistry. It was very special for us four people with very different personalities to become the Beatles. When we lost John, we knew that this was really over.&quot; Paul said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2001, they once again experienced the pain of the death of a close friend. This time it was another Beatle, George Harrison, who unfortunately passed away from cancer. &quot;Losing George is like losing the wind on a voyage,&quot; Paul said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November of the following year, a memorial concert organized by George&#39;s widow Olivia and his son Dani Harrison was held at the Royal Albert Hall in London. Friends such as Paul and Ringo attended. turn up. Before the show ended, Paul walked to the microphone and said: &quot;When Dani stands on the stage, it&#39;s like we are old, but George is still young.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe they are equally young. music. On November 10, 2023, with the song &quot;Now And Then&quot;, the Beatles once again topped the British music charts. This was their 18th number one single. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only does it extend the Beatles&#39; record for having the most number one singles in the history of the UK Official Charts, it also makes them the longest lag between their first and last number one hits in history. band - this song has been a full sixty years since their first number one single &quot;From Me to You&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Chen Quanxin also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[家政女工之死]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260737]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[94岁老人状告保姆：虐待自己还骗走200万养老钱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260804]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/17/chQqTYnDsbIs4FalpoE4JglV3iAmtPKYIOokEQyy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/chQqTYnDsbIs4FalpoE4JglV3iAmtPKYIOokEQ yy. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258602&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nanny Abuse Case&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I can&#39;t even figure out who Defendant 2 is,&quot; faced the judge&#39;s inquiry. Shen Yinan sat in the seat marked &quot;Defendant&#39;s Agent&quot; with a confused look on his face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Defendant 2 is your father,&quot; the lawyer reminded him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned slightly absurd scene occurred at a pre-trial meeting in a gift contract dispute case. On November 7, 2023, the Shanghai Huangpu District People&#39;s Court conducted an evidence exchange in this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shen Yinan’s mother Lu Delin is the plaintiff, the family’s nanny Jiang Aizhen is the defendant 1, and Shen Yinan’s father Shen Zongli is the defendant 2. According to the civil complaint, Shen Zongli once &quot;gifted&quot; 2 million yuan to the nanny Jiang Aizhen, and now Lu Delin is demanding the return. At the same time, Lu Delin sued the nanny Jiang Aizhen for being abused and demanded that the other party pay 200,000 yuan in mental damages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason Shen Yinan was &quot;confused&quot; was that this was not a single case. Civil contract disputes and criminal cases were both in progress. Relevant legal documents show that Lu Delin&#39;s abuse case has been filed as a criminal case at the Huangpu Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau, and the criminal case is currently being processed. Shen Yinan has lived abroad for many years and has insufficient understanding of the Chinese environment. His annual visits to relatives in Shanghai have been interrupted for three years since the end of 2019 due to the COVID-19 epidemic. It was also during this period that nanny Jiang Aizhen lived alone to take care of Lu Delin and Shen Zongli, and the dispute between the two parties eventually went to court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 29, 2023, Lu Delin, a 94-year-old man in Shanghai, posted his first video online under his real name, claiming that he was abused by his nanny and that his pension was transferred away by the nanny. Since then, the account has posted multiple videos, in which Lu Delin appeared on the scene to talk about his experience: &quot;I just breathed my last breath of life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not an exception. On the day the evidence was exchanged, a similar piece of news in Shanghai hit the hot search again. A nanny said that the elderly person she was taking care of wanted to transfer the property to her. &quot;I didn&#39;t take the initiative, it was my uncle who wanted to transfer it to me,&quot; the nanny explained at the processing window in the video. When the staff discovered something was wrong, they suspended the transfer process and called the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai Municipal Health Commission recently disclosed that as of the end of 2022, there were 5.5366 million registered elderly people aged 60 and above in Shanghai, accounting for 36.8% of the total registered population. In modern cities with severe aging, how to care for the elderly decently and the issue of home care for the elderly is attracting the attention of the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Aizhen did not arrive at the court on the afternoon of the 7th. The judge said that the court would announce the service and expected to summon Jiang Aizhen again in two months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwQJHfWcOurmAIXRYQe4AVq1jE8rzq5hcBrEZe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/c0jwQJHfWcOurmAIXRYQe4AVq1jE8rzq5hcBrEZe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258606&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Delin&#39;s bedroom, daughter-in-law Shen Ailun has asked the cleaning staff to clean it again&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>;The later life of a 94-year-old couple&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When I opened the closed door in front of me, the first thing I saw was a sour smell. The house should look well-ventilated, with a square shape, looking into the other side of the living room, with a wide balcony and large windows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Building 2401, Lane 118, Xietu Road, Liyuan New Village, Huangpu District, Shanghai. The other side of the mess is the great value of the house itself. This community has a total of 4 buildings, all of which are high-rise. It is located in the center of Shanghai and is close to many subway and bus lines, making life convenient. Relevant information shows that this community was built in the early 1990s, and the current price on the second-hand housing market exceeds 100,000 yuan per square meter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The house in front of me belongs to an old couple, Lu Delin and his wife Shen Zongli. They are both 94 years old and have retired for many years. Lu Delin suffered from myelitis and his lower body was paralyzed in bed; Shen Zongli is now blind in one eye, with only 0.25 vision left in one eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The couple’s only son, Shen Yinan, has settled in the United States for decades, and most of his relatives live abroad. Both of them have been to the United States to help their sons take care of their grandchildren, but each visa lasted only half a year at most. After several trips back and forth, the two of them got older and gradually had to stay in this house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, this house is vacant. On June 29, 2023, Lu Delin released his first video online under his real name, claiming that he was abused by the nanny Jiang Aizhen and that his pension was transferred away by the nanny. At present, Lu Delin and Shen Zongli have been picked up by their son Shen Yinan and daughter-in-law Shen Ailun and placed in Hangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alan Shen opened the door and showed the decorations in the room one by one. She carefully photographed, numbered, and kept these traces of her life. During the investigation stage of the case, many pieces of evidence came from this. On the table in the corner of the living room are piles of bags of fungus, day lilies, mushrooms and other supplements and wild products. There are a dazzling array of more than ten kinds. Shen Ailun, who was standing on one side, said that she had hired cleaning staff to clean the house inside and out. The sour odor that could be smelled now was only a few remnants, and those supplements &quot;were leftovers, and even more were thrown away.&quot; There are many, many have expired, and the nanny won’t make them for the elderly.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This family was originally &quot;stable and decent&quot;. Lu Delin and Shen Zongli&#39;s monthly pensions were more than 10,000 yuan, plus fixed financial interest, they had an additional monthly income of about 8,000 yuan. In addition to the house I live in, I also had another property under my name. After the demolition two years ago, I received a large amount of compensation, and my financial life is safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Son Shen Yinan regularly returns to China to visit relatives every year, &quot;a total of 586 days in 7 years, an average of 84 days per year.&quot; From 2013 to 2019, Shen Ailun sorted out the entry and exit records in these passports one by one. But this connection was broken by the sudden COVID-19 epidemic. After leaving China on November 29, 2019, Shen Yinan failed to come back for more than three years, and did not see her parents again until February 23, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5iKMmm2RPAmjZfcTckXYIjbSBIgKUcdgj6DF7z.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;399&quot; height= &quot;601&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/tj5iKMmm2RPAmjZfcTckXYIjbSBIgKUcdgj6DF7z.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258605&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shen&#39;s son&#39;s return time record sheet&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, two elderly people and the nanny Jiang Aizhen have lived in this house. A neighbor in the same unit told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that in the past few years, his family had contact with Lu Delin&#39;s family, and occasionally made some food to give away, but later stopped going to her house. &quot;The smell of (Lu Delin&#39;s) house was too strong and I couldn&#39;t get in. Feet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The kitchen is on the right hand side of the door, with moldy and hairy cutting boards and jars scattered on the countertop; on the left hand side of the door is the bathroom, a small bathroom of several square meters with white tiles, which has been renovated. Including showers, toilets, etc., the renovation cost tens of thousands of yuan. The bill came from the nanny Jiang Aizhen, and the price of the shower was noted as 4,000 yuan, but &quot;actually it was only 400 yuan.&quot; Shen Allen found out this detail from the property management office - the property management was involved in the installation of the shower. Master Xia, who has worked in property management in this community for many years, confirmed the discrepancy in this amount to a reporter from Southern People Weekly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7bOr8sa2Y9dLtafy9EpuDER4qvTRMTs0j4eM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/zghc7bOr8sa2Y9dLtafy9EpuDER4qvTRMTs0j4eM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258601&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bathroom renovated by the nanny. The showerhead in the picture is marked as costing 4,000 yuan&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/picture)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we arrived in the bedroom, the rancid smell became even more obvious. Lu Delin was paralyzed from the lower body and had been urinating and defecating on a chair-shaped toilet in his bedroom. The sheets and quilts had been replaced, and the mattress overflowing with white powder was put away in a box on the side. Shen Allen opened it and showed it to reporters. It was the one that Lu Delin had been using for the past few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father-in-law Shen Zongli’s shirt was also kept. There were large yellow and black stains on the collar. These were “all evidence.” In this unfamiliar space, Shen Ailun carefully collected traces of the past and determined to litigate with the nanny Jiang Aizhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The long-buried conflict&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Lu Delin family first came into contact with the nanny Jiang Aizhen in 2013, through the introduction of their upstairs neighbor Wang Wei. At that time, Jiang Work part-time in the area. By 2017, Jiang Aizhen became a long-term, fixed hourly employee of the Lu Delin family. Wang Wei said it was because &quot;Little Jiang did a good job&quot;, and Shen Ailun said it was because Jiang Aizhen was frustrated in finding a job and complained to Lu Delin and his wife that she got the job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting along for a long time, during the three years when the new coronavirus epidemic was raging, Lu Delin and his wife were cared for at home by Jiang Aizhen, with no one else to look after them. It wasn&#39;t until Lu Delin released a video, claiming that he was abused by the nanny and defrauded of his pension, that the conflict broke out in the public eye. For a long time before this, the conflict between the family and the nanny had already been laid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxBpiVrT0LPnXi3s2cUkRkL3vnFCUtPGAt8tHrAc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/bxBpiVrT0LPnXi3s2cUkRkL3vnFCUtPGAt8tHrAc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258603&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bedding used by Teacher Lu Delin in the past few years has a strong musty smell&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Initially, Jiang Aizhen worked part-time for two hours at home every day, and the couple paid 6,000 yuan a month. In March 2022, Jiang Aizhen moved into this house and changed from a part-time worker to a live-in nanny, and her salary increased to 12,000 yuan per month. Shen Ailun told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that while Jiang Aizhen was receiving this salary, she was also working part-time in four other places at the same time. At this point, she felt that the nanny did not have the spirit of contract. &quot;Having paid all the salary of the live-in nanny, how can she still go to work other jobs outside?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; visited to find out more Currently, in Huangpu District, Shanghai, where Lu Delin is located, the hourly salary for hourly workers is about 45 yuan, which rises to about 50 yuan during the evening peak hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of the Sangcheng Neighborhood Committee to which the community belongs told Southern People Weekly that whether the price is for an hourly or full-time live-in nanny depends on how the employer and the nanny negotiate. Judging from the neighborhood committee&#39;s registration, as long as she spends the night at her employer&#39;s house, she is considered a live-in nanny. Jiang Aizhen has indeed been registered as a live-in nanny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Wei, an introducer who also employs part-time workers for a long time, does not think that 12,000 yuan is a &quot;buyout&quot; price. For two elderly people who cannot take care of themselves, more money will definitely be needed. It is normal for the nanny to work other jobs. of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter of &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; consulted three local housekeeping agencies based on the current situation of Lu Delin and his wife. They all said that the price of 12,000 yuan is the price of a full-time live-in nanny, which is a &quot;buyout price&quot; and the aunt should not Go do other work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the housekeeping agencies was established in 2014 and is headquartered in Guangzhou. It has branches in Shanghai and Shenzhen. It provides customers with full-time live-in nannies through an employee system. Each aunt has undergone background checks. Their daily life is monitored by the company using a housekeeper model. This company will conduct regular follow-up visits through its stewards, and it is one of the similar institutions that attaches great importance to supervision. Even so, the quality of Auntie still relies on proactive feedback from customers. When family members are not around all year round, the elderly are forced to rely on a single nanny. &quot;This kind of feedback is relatively difficult and can be said to be blank.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3Ypu1xbkvmkyW1xrSR2bfacSHHVL1imYUJcSbwAD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/17/3Ypu1xbkvmkyW1xrSR2bfacSHHVL1imYUJcSbwAD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258600&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Daily use in the kitchen of Lu Delin and his wife The cutting board&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Han Ruxue/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Besides money, there is incalculable &quot;love&quot;. During the COVID-19 epidemic, the two elderly people were cared for by Jiang Aizhen alone. They were pushed up and down in line to get nucleic acid tests, which was seen by the neighborhood committee. Whether the care was good or not, and whether there was abuse or not, are &quot;matters behind closed doors.&quot; The neighborhood committee and some neighbors used this as an excuse to express their ignorance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Shen Yinan and his wife returned to China, Jiang Aizhen repeatedly claimed that she had &quot;saved the old man&#39;s life&quot; and produced a &quot;certificate&quot; and a &quot;power of attorney&quot; handwritten and signed by Shen Zongli. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A power of attorney signed on September 1, 2022 shows: &quot;Jiang Aizhen will live in our current residence a hundred years later. Jiang Aizhen will provide for us in our old age. Our ashes will be placed at home first. , and finally thrown into the Huangpu River.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In another &quot;certificate&quot; on the same day, Shen Zongli stated that he gave Jiang Aizhen &quot;one million yuan&quot;; in a &quot;certificate&quot; on March 3, 2023, , the amount given to Jiang Aizhen rose to &quot;two million yuan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not just a paper promise, on August 22, 2022 and February 7, 2023, Shen Zongli’s personal account transferred 1 million yuan to Jiang Aizhen’s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three pieces of paper, corresponding to 2 million yuan and the right to live in the house, were given to the nanny Jiang Aizhen. Whether the old man was conscious and voluntary, and whether the gift was legal and valid, the question was ultimately handed over to the court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Looking for evidence&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who was present at the time?&quot; The judge asked many times to confirm this key question, pointing to the latest gift contract-2023 On March 3, 2019, Shen Zongli handwritten a &quot;certificate&quot; of 2 million yuan to his nanny Jiang Aizhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Aizhen did not appear in court. Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun told the judge what happened: Jiang Aizhen took out a certificate signed by Lu Delin, Shen Zongli, and Shen Yinan, and asked Lu Delin and Shen Yinan to sign in the corresponding places, but they refused. At that time, Shen Ailun was present and stopped him. At that time, thinking that the matter was settled, Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun left home to go out on business. When they returned to Shanghai, they learned that the &quot;proof&quot; had actually been written long ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The certificate that was suppressed was signed on March 9, 2023. In fact, as early as a week ago, on March 3, 2023, Jiang Aizhen obtained the &quot;certificate&quot; signed by Shen Zongli. Shen Ailun discovered that Shen Zongli&#39;s Alipay had been registered, and found someone to use technical means to recover the data on the old man&#39;s mobile phone. He found a video recorded by Jiang Aizhen, which was proof that Shen Zongli had handwritten a gift of 2 million to the nanny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/TckI7M60dT3Wk8L8OodV8ejKNT3ls4Z8Y9Vh9cx6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1706&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/TckI7M60dT3Wk8L8OodV8ejKNT3ls4Z8Y9Vh9cx6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258604&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The power of attorney dated September 1, 2022 shows: &quot;Jiang Aizhen will live in our current residence a hundred years later. Jiang Aizhen will provide for us in our old age. Our ashes will be placed at home first. , and finally thrown into the Huangpu River.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A recording provided by Lu Delin&#39;s attorney Zhou Zhaocheng showed that a duty lawyer of the neighborhood committee said that Jiang Aizhen had repeatedly pushed Shen Zongli in a wheelchair to the neighborhood committee&#39;s duty lawyer&#39;s office for consultation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 3, 2023, Jiang Aizhen received the certificate signed by Shen Zongli’s handwriting. In order to ensure that the donation of &quot;2 million yuan&quot; was legal and valid, a week later, she took out a certificate again and added &quot;Lu Delin and Shen Yinan&quot; in addition to Shen Zongli. This certificate was the only one that Shen Yinan and Shen Ailun had ever seen in person. Proof of “donation”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the previous three certificates of donating 1 million yuan, donating 2 million yuan, and letting the nanny live in the house, Shen Yinan saw the nanny Fang issued them online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/9LE4c03YquSx1reueA0dU9dZlxfnKOraquARP6Fm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1706&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/9le4c03yqusx1reuea0du9dzlxfnkoraquarp6fm.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;258599&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; p style = &quot;colorRor : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; March 3, 2023, Shen Zongli handwritten&quot; proof &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Zongli, a&quot; certificate &quot;of 2 million yuan, was the person who mastered the family&quot; account &quot;. The proof was handwritten. Shen Ailun said that the way of treating Shen Zongli and Lu Delin is different. &quot;I know which one should coax, and used such a brainwashing method to deceive the old man&#39;s money.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Initially, the family trusted the nanny. For the first time, I found out that there was something wrong. It was time for Shen Ailun to mail the food to her in -laws. When I talked about the phone, I found that the in -laws did not receive it and did not know it. Earlier, Shen Ailun sent a message to the elderly mobile phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The nanny will delete the chat history,&quot; this answer was found after Shen Ailun installed the camera. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February 2023, after about 3 years due to the new crown epidemic, Shen Ailun stepped into the door of 2401 again. The mother -in -law Lu Delin asked her to see her feet, saying that she felt potholes, and Shen Ailun found that the toenail was &quot;cut&quot;, and she realized that something was wrong. Shen Ailun went to check the account and found that 2 million yuan on his in -law&#39;s account was transferred to Jiang Aizhen&#39;s name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From a wheelchair to the wall, Shen Ailun secretly installed 7 micro -cameras to &quot;monitor&quot; nanny. The couple falsified to return to the United States. . Her husband told her that this was to obtain evidence, and she had to hold back her temper. No matter what she saw, the primary purpose was to retain evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But the next day, Shen Allen still quarreled with Jiang Aizhen. She recalled that Jiang Aizhen had a habit, a bit like a teacher&#39;s feeling of training children, &quot;What are you going to, what&#39;s going on&quot;, &quot;I can hear my head buzzing.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p >; The contradiction quickly erupted to the table. One day at noon, her mother -in -law Lu Delin said that she wanted to eat crabs and asked Shen Allen to do it. Shen Ailun said that she asked her aunt (referring to Jiang Aizhen). Jiang Aizhen said that she would not eat crabs and would not do it. &quot;I wanted to scold her at that time, but I held back,&quot; Shen Ailun continued to recall. &quot;The nanny asked my mother -in -law how to do it. My mother -in -law asked her to ask me. She was normal when she asked me. Didn&#39;t you ask my mother? You can do it according to my mother&#39;s method. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Patience seems to have disappeared suddenly. Jiang Aizhen suddenly became unwilling, and the volume suddenly became larger. Ask you, you asked me to ask your mother, I really don&#39;t understand you anymore. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; As soon as this sentence came out, Shen Ali couldn&#39;t hold back the fire. I started scolding her. I said you don&#39;t want to talk to me like this. One day I asked you to cry, and you rolled it out. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; At that time, Jiang Aizhen did not know how to install a camera at home, but Shen Ailun had already Seeing the normal behavior of the nanny through the video, it made her difficult to accept. &quot;She sprinkled all her breath on my mother -in -law, and her throat scolded the sound.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; After watching the camera On the night of sleeping in her in -laws, Shen Ailun was afraid that Jiang Aizhen did extreme things from the kitchen, and took away the large and small knives in the kitchen, put it in the room, locked the door, and put one of them. The knife is placed under the pillow to prepare the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; About &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; Jiang Aizhen &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; It is another saying of Wang Wei, an introduced person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Wei also heard the gift of 2 million yuan, and she also saw the &quot;abuse&quot; picture circulating online video. But she always believes that the nanny is okay: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The video seen online is that the action is rude. In fact, the old man gets up like this. I used to have an old man before, and Xiao Jiang pulled like this. Jiang is also almost 60 years old. It is only a clockwork. He has not received professional training in nursing. It can only be that. We are used to this action in our house. She has a temperament and character. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>;&quot; There are toenails to cut bleeding, cut asylon nails, and gray -cut nails must be bleeding. The moldy bedding must have nothing to do with Xiao Jiang. This is Teacher Lu. Their old couple&#39;s personal habits. Their habits of their family say that they have entered their family, there is no garbage, all treasures, and nothing are thrown. /P>; &lt;p>; The Xiao Jiang who hired Xiao Jiang in this building was introduced by Wang Wei. She said that only the Lu Delin family said that the problem was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jiang Aizhen is the clockman introduced by the security guard earlier, and it will be done at Wang Wei&#39;s house since 2012. &quot;Before the daughter -in -law returned to Shanghai this time, Mr. Lu&#39;s family had a good relationship with the nanny. They said that this nanny was his own daughter. Fortunately, there was a nanny, otherwise his life was gone. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Wang Wei told&quot; Southern Character Weekly &quot;that the money of 2 million yuan was given to Jiang Aizhen twice, all for a reason: the first time was because of the epidemic control. Time does nucleic acid almost every day. The nanny push up every day and rely on her alone. Another time is that a house of Mr. Shen was relocated. He said that he could not negotiate with him. I commissioned this nanny to do it, and finally seemed to get some money. Mr. Shen said, &quot;If it wasn&#39;t for his aunt to help him, he would not get so much.&quot; In the end, he had to ask Xiao Jiang to give himself the end of his elderly. At that time, during the epidemic closure, I did not know when the son came back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But these two things are another situation in Shen Allen&#39;s eyes. In terms of physical care, Shen Ailun said that in May 2020, there was an old man who was hospitalized with pneumonia, and Jiang Aizhen was taken care of, but paid an additional salary at the price of 300 yuan a day. This is a contract, not &quot;love or help&quot;; It is that the nanny is not done well, and the demolition funds have taken a lot less ... &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, Lu Delin and Shen Zongli, which are taken care of by Shen Yinan and Shen Allen, asked Jiang Aizhen to pay for the money in the video. Before being taken away, when the elderly and nanny coexisted, &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; obtained a recording. It was a conversation between the problem of money because of the problem of money on March 22, 2023: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Babysitter: &quot;All the money is transferred.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Shen Zongli: &quot;My money is to keep.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; nanny: &quot;You keep it here &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Shen Zongli:&quot; Two. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; nanny:&quot; I want it. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Shen Zongli:&quot; You bully me. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; The helplessness of &quot;nanny housekeeper&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Is it voluntary to give nanny money? Shen Zongli&#39;s answer is different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At first he said that he was voluntarily gifts. He didn&#39;t change his mouth until he saw the babysitter&#39;s flowing water, recording, and video. Related recording and videos showed that the nanny personally admitted that it took 70,000 yuan for the elderly&#39;s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shen Ailun told &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; that Shen Zongli claimed that he had been told many times that his money was the same in the nanny account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For 3 years in the new crown, Shen Ailun only returned to China once. At that time, she was ready to visit her in -laws, but she received a note written by her mother -in -law when she received her mother -in -law, which reads &quot;Don&#39;t return&quot;. Considering that he was afraid of infection at that time, Shen Allen did not return to 2401. Afterwards, Lu Delin told Shen Ailun that the note was written by the nanny, &quot;forced.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In 3 years, the &quot;nanny housekeeper&quot; became the theme of 2401, and even the &quot;outsiders&quot; who dealt with it were seen. inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Master Xia of the property told &quot;Southern Character Weekly&quot; that the two elderly people could not take care of themselves, and they had to accompany the nanny. The nanny had been around. The old man couldn&#39;t say anything even if he wanted to say anything. Usually, the two elderly people are at home, and they have no relatives. Only Lu Delin&#39;s students occasionally come, but &quot;after all, they are not family members. Many words cannot be said. Their family is decent people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A nearby chain -to -foot shop is regularly gone by nagbles Jiang Aizhen and Shen Zongli. The clerk called Shen Zongli as a &quot;big white rabbit&quot;, because he loves to eat big white rabbit toffee, and sometimes he eats several pieces at a time. Shen Ailun turned on the mobile phone shopping app. There were many large white rabbit toffee purchases, which were mailing to 2401. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The clerk called the &quot;nanny housekeeper&quot;: the nanny brought the big white rabbit, the big white rabbit&#39;s foot repair and nanny also repaired, and did the same project. When they paid, the babysitter paid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;This kind of nanny is rare,&quot; the clerk recalled the actions of the nanny Jiang Aizhen. Other families are often accompanied by their children&#39;s family. On the day of the reporter&#39;s interview, the 103 -year -old man was received by the niece, accompanied by a niece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Starting from the community, a few hundred meters apart in a shop, Jiang Aizhen sometimes takes the Lu Delin couple to eat. After returning to China this time, the owner of the shop told Shen Ailun privately, &quot;Hurry up your nanny.&quot; The reporter learned from the boss and confirmed this, &quot;I have never seen other nanny speeches so fierce.&quot; &lt;/P >; &lt;p>; Elderly people like Lu Delin and his wife have many in this community. The staff of the Sangcheng neighborhood committee told the Southern Character Weekly that it is a common phenomenon to visit from time to time from time to time. It is rare to take care of the nanny alone. Earlier, the neighborhood committee tried to mediate after hearing the news, but the nanny did not come. &quot;The nanny has never appeared. The neighborhood committee cannot represent which government or relevant departments on behalf of the government or relevant departments. Power. Also, when the nanny is absent or is not present, we also recommend that they take the judicial way and report to the court or public security. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The staff who have worked in the neighborhood committee for many years told&quot; &quot; &quot;Southern Person Weekly&quot;, usually encountered a nanny Jiang Aizhen, and did not feel the &quot;abuse&quot; related matters in the contact. But many things are closed, and no one will do what excessive things will do in the court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This will not be an example. Shanghai is the most aging cities in the country. According to data published by the monitoring statistics of the elderly population and aging cause in Shanghai in 2022, the 60 -year -old population of Shanghai household registration in 2022 had 5.536 million, accounting for 36.8%of the total household registration population. Among them, the elderly live alone were 3.06 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Whether or not being abused or deceived, for 3 years, the &quot;nanny housekeeper&quot;, until the contradiction broke out and rushed to the hot search, many neighbors saw the news on the mobile phone. Some neighbors had previously seen the news of their daughter -in -law complaining about the nagged Jiang Aizhen, and more neighbors knew nothing about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (The requirements of the interview, the characters Shen Yinan, Shen Ailun, Wang Wei are a pseudonym.) &lt;/p>; &lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:oraange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https: // feedx .net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt; /div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“清朗·网络戾气整治”专项行动启动，打击网络厕所、开盒挂人等行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260790]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Cyberspace Affairs Office of the Party Committee of all provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities directly under the Central Government, and the Cyberspace Affairs Office of the Party Committee of the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps: &lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In accordance with the overall arrangement of the 2023 &quot;Qinglang&quot; series of special operations, the Central Cyberspace Administration of China has decided to launch a one-month &quot;Qinglang·Internet Violence Rectification&quot; nationwide from now on. Special action. The relevant matters are now notified as follows. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;1. Clear work goals&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Focus on cyber violence We will focus on key sections where anger easily breeds, strictly crack down on prominent issues such as malicious attacks and insults, provoking group confrontations, and venting extreme emotions, and resolutely punish a number of illegal accounts, groups, and website platforms to effectively curb the spread of online violence. By carrying out special rectification, we will further consolidate the main responsibilities of the website platform, thoroughly identify problems and loopholes, improve the system and mechanism to prevent and control online violence, effectively protect the legitimate rights and interests of the majority of netizens, and maintain a good online ecology. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;2. Focus on rectifying 7 types of outstanding problems&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The special actions focus on key platform types such as social networking, short videos, and live broadcasts, and resolutely crack down on the following seven aspects of problems:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;1. &quot;Internet toilets&quot; and &quot;open boxes to hang people&quot; &quot;Behavior. Create special BOT accounts, post bars, topics, groups, etc., and receive and publish sarcastic, malicious comments, curses and insults targeting specific groups or individuals through anonymous contributions, remote shouting, etc. In the name of exposure and criticism, they maliciously &quot;open the box&quot; and &quot;hang people&quot;, publicizing other people&#39;s names, ID numbers, mobile phone numbers, home addresses, workplaces, personal photos, social accounts and other personal privacy information, inciting netizens to attack and abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Use hot social events to maliciously slander and spread rumors. Spread rumors and slander relevant parties involved in emergencies, or edit and process pictures and videos that are seriously inconsistent with the facts, to induce netizens to attack and question the parties involved. Use the image of the parties involved in hot events to create and publish emoticons, and use AI software to synthesize fake pictures or videos such as vulgar pornography, bloody horror, etc., to carry out rumors, attacks, and slander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Stigmatize specific groups and incite regional confrontation. Associate individual vicious social events and negative figures with gender, occupation, region and other characteristics, stigmatize and negatively label specific groups, publish gender-antagonistic, class-antagonistic, and regionally discriminatory remarks, carry out generalized attacks, and intensify social conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. Vulgar and bad live streaming behaviors such as fierce PK. Online anchors use behaviors such as showing off their courage, fighting, drinking, and swearing to increase their followers and traffic. During other people&#39;s live broadcasts, they use functions such as barrages and mics to conduct personal attacks, and even encourage extreme behaviors such as suicide and self-harm. Make up scripts of violent conflicts such as fights and fights to attract netizens to watch and disrupt public order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5. Organized and malicious abuse and reporting of others. In the name of &quot;helping with work&quot; and &quot;relieving worries and anger&quot;, they provide paid scolding services and leave abusive messages and private message attacks on specific accounts. Organize fan groups to use the platform’s “reporting” and “anti-gangster” functions to maliciously report others in batches. Publish comments that provoke war and malicious hype in the fields of entertainment, sports, e-sports, etc., inducing fans to quarrel with each other and control reviews. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6. Make up Internet slang and maliciously create rumors. Through pinyin, homophony, pronouns, etc., maliciously fabricate vulgar memes and bad buzzwords to pollute the Internet atmosphere. Use obscene language and foul language to deliberately provoke conflicts and create conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7. Inciting extreme emotions online. Make up sensational post titles and publish &quot;venting posts&quot; that are made out of nothing and have no bottom line. Maliciously exaggerating the conflicts between teachers and students, exaggerating parents&#39; &quot;oppression&quot; and &quot;squeezing&quot; of their children, provoking conflicting relationships, and forming a negative direction for minors. Deliberately exaggerate negativity, anxiety and resentment, and spread hateful and antagonistic remarks. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;3. Severely punish illegal accounts, groups and platforms in accordance with the law&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Special During the operation, we must persist in striking hard, close a group of account groups that seriously violate regulations and have a bad influence, resolutely ban a group of functional sections that gather violence and have outstanding problems, and strictly investigate and punish a group of people who fail to perform their responsibilities and have serious problems. The website platform that resists the temptation to commit crimes forms a powerful deterrent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Strictly investigate and punish illegal accounts, groups, and post bars. In-depth investigation of high-risk accounts and groups, resolutely ban accounts and groups with themes such as &quot;online toilets&quot;, &quot;opening boxes to hang people&quot;, &quot;inciting fights&quot;, etc., and seriously investigate and deal with anchor accounts that organize ruthless PKs and live broadcast fights , severely punish &quot;self-media&quot; accounts that publish &quot;clickbait&quot; content that deliberately incites online violence, close a group of circles, super chats, and post bars named with insulting words and where online violence gathers, and remove them from the shelves and provide paid compensation. Scolding merchants and shops waiting for services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Strictly investigate and deal with illegal function settings. Strengthen the management of key functions such as live broadcast barrage, continuous wheat, and PK, and resolutely clean up and deal with violent content online. Centrally cancel a batch of functional applications that organize malicious reports in batches. It is prohibited to push &quot;online toilet&quot; accounts to users through functions such as &quot;Related Recommendations&quot;, &quot;TA Follows&quot;, and &quot;Potentially Interested People&quot;. Strengthen the review and management of emoticon packages, P-picture puzzles, video editing, AI synthesis and other functions, and clean up and remove emoticon packages, pictures and videos containing prank attacks, provoking confrontation and other content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Strictly investigate and punish illegal platform links. Urge &lt;span>; website platforms to strengthen the management of lists, topics, recommendations, comments, private messages, etc. It is strictly forbidden to push content that incites and promotes online violence in lists, recommendations, etc., by setting up &quot;private message folding&quot; and &quot;message boxes&quot; etc. to reduce harassment from strangers via private messages. For websites, apps, and mini-programs with outstanding problems, punitive measures such as rectification within a time limit, fines, suspension of relevant functions, and shutdown will be taken in accordance with the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;4. Detailed work requirements&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/ span>;1. Do a good job in deployment and promotion. Based on local reality, we will formulate detailed implementation plans, allocate strong working forces, pay close attention to the deployment and implementation of tasks, organize to evaluate the effectiveness of website platform governance as appropriate, and supervise the implementation of rectifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Consolidate platform responsibility. Guide local website platforms to comprehensively investigate problems and loopholes, focus on key links, sections and functions, carry out in-depth self-examination and self-correction, improve content management mechanisms, and ensure that special actions achieve effective results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Strengthen publicity and exposure. Announce &lt;span>; the launch and phased progress of special actions, and key platforms publish typical cases every week. Strengthen education and guidance, encourage netizens to actively participate in reporting and complaining, and jointly resist online violence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Secretary Bureau of the Central Cyberspace Affairs Commission&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot; >;&lt;span>;November 10, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马云继续减持，阿里巴巴刺向低价]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260806]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 15:30:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Alibaba Xixi Park. Image source: Alibaba official website&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/17/e08a25e8cc.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258618&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Alibaba Xixi Park . Image source: Alibaba official website&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 16, 2023, is the day when Alibaba’s new quarterly results for fiscal year 2024 are announced. On this day, many important news about this giant company were simultaneously released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jack Ma continues to reduce his stake in the founder of Alibaba; the previous &quot;1+6+N&quot; spin-off plan partially pressed the pause button, and Alibaba Cloud will no longer be completely split; the listing of Hema is also suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What changes is Alibaba facing? Where will the strategic baton be waved from now on? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Jack Ma reduced his holdings and cashed out US$870 million&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 16, Alibaba (BABA.NYSE) submitted two 144 forms to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), indicating that Jack Ma JC Properties Limited and JSP Investment Limited, subsidiaries of the family trust, plan to sell 5 million shares of the founder of Alibaba each on November 21. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on Alibaba’s closing price of US$87.07 per share on November 15, Eastern Time, the Jack Ma family can cash out US$870.7 million through this reduction. Alibaba’s market capitalization that day was approximately US$221.75 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Form 144, also known as &quot;Notice of Proposed Sale of Securities.&quot; SEC regulations stipulate that if directors, executives or major shareholders of a U.S. listed company transfer more than 5,000 shares of listed company stock or a market value of more than $50,000 in any three months, they must fill out Form 144 and report to the SEC. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Alibaba’s U.S. stock prospectus, before the IPO, Jack Ma held a total of 8.8% of Alibaba’s shares in four ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I hold 0.08% directly, 1.49% each through APN Ltd registered in the Cayman Islands and SymAsia Foundation, a Singapore non-profit organization, and through JC Properties registered in the British Virgin Islands Limited and JSP Investment Limited hold 2.78% and 2.95% of the shares respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shares sold by Jack Ma in the US stock IPO also came from JC Properties Limited and JSP Investment Limited. After the IPO, his shareholding in Alibaba dropped to 7.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Alibaba was listed on the New York Stock Exchange in 2014, Jack Ma has reduced his holdings many times. The financial report shows that Jack Ma’s large-scale reduction of holdings began in 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Jack Ma’s shareholding dropped from 7.8% to 7%, to 6.4% in 2018, to 6.2% in 2019, and to 4.8% in 2020, which is below the 5% disclosure red line. Since then, Alibaba has not disclosed Jack Ma’s shareholdings in its financial reports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba has responded that Jack Ma and Tsai Chongxin will donate their Alibaba options, which total 2% of the total equity of Alibaba Group, to support environmental protection, medical health, educational development and public welfare. ecology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Teacher’s Day 2019, Jack Ma resigned as chairman of Alibaba’s board of directors. A year later, Jack Ma completed his term as director and is no longer a member of Alibaba&#39;s board of directors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2023 financial report shows that Jack Ma is still a member of Alibaba’s partner committee, and the other five are Cai Chongxin, Zhang Yong, Peng Lei, Shao Xiaofeng and Wu Yongming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba implements a partnership system, in which partners nominate the majority of directors on the board of directors, rather than allocating director seats based on the number of shares. Alibaba currently has 28 partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Refocus on 1688, Xianyu, DingTalk, and Quark&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Also on November 16, Alibaba’s Q2 results for fiscal year 2024 were announced. Alibaba&#39;s fiscal year is not synchronized with the natural year, ranging from April 1 of each year to March 31 of the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This quarter, Alibaba’s revenue was 224.79 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 9%. Net profit was 26.696 billion yuan, compared with a net loss of 22.467 billion yuan in the same period in 2022, and non-GAAP net profit was 40.188 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 19%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Alibaba Group&#39;s performance this quarter was solid, with multiple businesses showing new momentum and vitality, and proactive self-reform achieving remarkable results.&quot; Wu Yongming, CEO of Alibaba Group, said in the performance announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local Life Group’s revenue increased by 16% year-on-year to 15.564 billion yuan, driven by the strong growth of Ele.me and AutoNavi, with orders increasing by nearly 20% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cainiao’s revenue increased by 25% year-on-year to 22.823 billion yuan, mainly driven by cross-border logistics fulfillment solutions. Cainiao launched global 5-day logistics services to 8 countries and regions this quarter, including first-leg collection, trunk transportation, customs clearance, sorting and last-mile delivery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Alibaba Entertainment finally turned a profit in the last quarter, its chances of winning have further expanded. The revenue of Dawen Entertainment Group in this quarter was 5.779 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 11%, mainly due to the offline entertainment business of Damai.com and Alibaba Pictures, and the subscription growth of Youku. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, Alibaba Pictures announced the acquisition of Damai.com. Benefiting from the recovery and strong demand of the offline entertainment market during the summer vacation of 2023, Damai.com recorded triple-digit year-on-year growth in GMV this quarter. In August, Damai.com teamed up with Youku to sell tickets for the offline performances and online live broadcasts of TFBOYS’s 10th anniversary concert. This exclusive online live broadcast broke Youku’s online paid performance record. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two films jointly produced by Alibaba Pictures, &quot;All or Nothing&quot; and &quot;The Lost Girl&quot; ranked among the top two at the summer box office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of November 16, Wu Yongming participated in the quarterly financial analyst conference call for the first time as CEO of Alibaba Group. At the meeting, he introduced Alibaba’s first batch of strategic innovative businesses-1688, Xianyu, Nail, Quark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yongming said that Alibaba’s selection criteria for strategic innovative businesses are: having a large enough market space; having unique market positioning; complying with user demand trends and the group’s “AI-driven” strategy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The strategic innovative business will be operated as an independent subsidiary in terms of organization. In terms of business, it will break the previous positioning restrictions within the group and use a more independent strategy to face the broad market. Alibaba Group will make continuous investment in a 3-5 year cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quark is an intelligent search app owned by Alibaba, and DingTalk is an enterprise-level intelligent mobile office platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the field of online transactions that Alibaba is good at, 1688 is a purchasing and wholesale network, which is often put together with Pinduoduo to compare which one is cheaper, while Xianyu is a second-hand idle transfer platform, which improves the popularity of the two within the group. The importance of Alibaba’s business shows that Alibaba’s baton is tilted towards the low-price market. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The spin-off of Alibaba Cloud and the listing of Hema will be suspended&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Alibaba’s Q2 financial report also announced the spin-off progress of each business segment. Surprisingly, the spin-off of Alibaba Cloud has been put on hold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 18, Zhang Yong, then chairman and CEO of Alibaba Group and chairman and CEO of Alibaba Cloud Intelligence Group, announced that Alibaba Cloud Intelligence Group would be completely separated from Alibaba Group within the next 12 months. Dismantled and completed listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alibaba explained in this financial report that the United States has recently expanded restrictions on the export of advanced computing chips, which has brought uncertainty to the prospects of Cloud Intelligence Group. Its complete spin-off may not increase shareholder value as originally envisaged, so it has decided not to promote its complete spin-off. Instead, it will face an uncertain environment and focus on establishing a sustainable growth model for Cloud Intelligence Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yongming said that Alibaba Group will maintain long-term and resolute investment in the strategic direction of Alibaba Cloud. At the same time, Cloud Intelligence Group will continue to maintain an independent company operation method and adopt a CEO responsibility system authorized by the board of directors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2023, Bloomberg News stated that Hema was cooperating with CICC, Morgan Stanley and others to prepare for listing and prepare to be listed in Hong Kong next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this financial report shows that Hema’s initial public offering plan is on hold. Ali did not explain why. But this may have something to do with Hema’s lackluster performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This quarter, Alibaba’s revenue from all other segments was 4.8052 billion yuan, which remained stable compared with the same period in 2022. All other segments include Sun Art Retail, Hema, Alibaba Health, Lingxi Interactive Entertainment, Intime, Intelligent Information (mainly including UC Youshi and Quark businesses), Fliggy, DingTalk, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other segments, the revenue of Hema, Fliggy, Alibaba Health and Smart Information has increased, but the overall performance is only the same as last year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In sharp contrast to Hema, Cainiao Group has applied for an initial public offering in Hong Kong and has submitted an A1 document (listing application form) to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Yongming said at the conference call that Cainiao’s core strategies for the next three years are to accelerate the construction of a global smart logistics network, seize the historical opportunities of the rapid development of cross-border e-commerce, and achieve rapid growth in international business. The second is to adhere to the path of differentiation in the country, export scientific and technological capabilities, and maintain the healthy development of business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：严厉打击倒买倒卖、伪造出生医学证明等违法犯罪行为]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260797]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:40:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The National Health Commission attaches great importance to the management of birth medical certificates and is supervising relevant places to seriously verify and deal with the trafficking of birth medical certificates. Regarding certification and other related issues, supervision teams have been dispatched to Xiangyang in Hubei, Foshan in Guangdong, and Nanning in Guangxi to urge and guide local governments to conduct thorough investigations, respond to social concerns, and hold relevant responsibilities accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Medical Birth Certificate&quot; is a statutory medical certification document issued in accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;Maternal and Infant Health Care Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and is an important basis for the public security organs to carry out newborn household registration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Health Commission will severely crack down on any behavior that harms the rights and interests of children, harms the interests of the masses, and disrupts the normal medical order, especially the forgery of medical birth certificates. If it is discovered, it will be investigated and punished, and we will actively cooperate with them. The public security organs crack down on criminal activities such as buying and selling birth medical certificates, and severely deal with the medical personnel involved in accordance with the law and regulations. You are welcome to report relevant clues to the local health administration department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the National Health Commission will guide medical institutions to further improve their internal management mechanisms and processes, and conduct special inspections on the standardized management of birth medical certificates across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网红民工吴桂春重返东莞：“要千方百计看两本书”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[研究发现鲨鱼可以跟人类一样品尝出苦味]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A new study recently published in the US magazine &quot;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&quot; stated that sharks and other cartilaginous fish have the same Genes that detect bitter tastes like humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258594&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The picture shows a photo of a shark provided by the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Photo courtesy of the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity/Photo by Andrew Fox)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many animals and plants secrete toxic compounds as a defense, a chemical that enables humans to perceive their taste The bitter taste receptor type 2 (T2R) gene helps humans recognize these compounds and avoid poisoning. Many bony vertebrates also have this bitter taste receptor gene, but researchers have never found it in cartilaginous vertebrates before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this study, researchers from the University of Cologne in Germany and other institutions used the latest gene sequencing technology to sequence the genes of 17 species of cartilaginous fish (including sharks and rays) and found that 12 species of cartilaginous fish All carry a taste receptor gene similar to T2R, which they named T2R1. The researchers then implanted the T2R1 genes from two of the shark species into human kidney cells in the laboratory, and then exposed them to 94 bitter substances that humans can perceive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results showed that 7 bitter substances activated the bitter taste receptors of two species of sharks, and the other 4 substances only activated the bitter taste receptors of one shark, which means that these sharks can also taste human food. Perceived bitter substances such as colchicine or bile acids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The discovery suggests the ability to perceive bitter tastes may be older than previously thought, possibly before cartilaginous fishes and bony vertebrates diverged from a common ancestor nearly 500 million years ago, the researchers said. has evolved. Teleost vertebrates continue to evolve a variety of bitter taste receptor genes. Although the researchers detected only one T2R1 gene in these cartilaginous fish genomes, this means it may be the original form of the bitter taste receptor gene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[台湾观众可能没有我们这么了解侯孝贤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeK nCcAnsCEY3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;240307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Single episode introduction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hello everyone, welcome to A Little Culture. I am the anchor of this issue, Yu Yaqin. Recently, the famous director Hou Hsiao-hsien has to bid farewell to the film industry due to health reasons. For this reason, today I invited Teacher Wang Yinjie from the China Academy of Art and my colleague Teacher Li Heng to talk about this great fan of Chinese films. A very important film master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excerpts of golden verses&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He lives in southern Taiwan, which is very different from Taipei in our impression. It has more rural character. This rural character is also the way Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some actors have said that he doesn’t even have a script. He is not a person who particularly likes to coordinate actors. A director who is very standard in the film industry, very sophisticated and precise. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He provides a very valuable preservation of personal experience and personal memory for the narration of film history. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1700&quot; height=&quot;1132&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #993300;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Guests in this issue]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Yaqin, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Heng, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yinjie, Associate Professor, School of Film, China Academy of Art&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #993300;&quot;>;[Listening Tips]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:58 Director Hou Hsiao-hsien’s life and works&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 04:17 Countryside is Hou Hsiao-hsien’s way of looking at the world&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 05:22&amp;nbsp;《 &quot;Son&#39;s Big Doll&quot; established many of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s aesthetic styles&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 09:23&amp;nbsp;After 2000, Hou Hsiao-hsien moved towards more international cooperation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 11:08&amp;nbsp;Jia Zhangke is I came into contact with Hou Hsiao-hsien from &quot;City of Sadness&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 14:33 Hou Hsiao-hsien is not a standardized director in the film industry&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 17:52 Hou Hsiao-hsien has always been photographing individuals with a faint light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 19:57 Taiwanese audiences may not know Hou Hsiao-hsien as well as we do&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 23:14&amp;nbsp;Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films have many long shots and do not pursue a lot of drama&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;► 26:19 The emotions of the characters in Hou’s films are like hearing thunder in silence&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 32:47 Hou Hsiao-hsien holds a very important position in the hearts of a generation of movie fans&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 37: 15 A kind of misalignment: The life needs of young people in Taiwan do not come from directors such as Hou Hsiao-hsien&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 41:11 We need to trust the interpretation of the world by creators of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s generation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 43:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at everyone around him in a level-headed manner&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 45:06 The use of dialect is a characteristic of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 47:05 Recommended by Wang Yinjie Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Sad City&quot; and &quot;Flowers of Shanghai&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 53:49 Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Love in the Wind&quot; and &quot;The Assassin Nie Yinniang&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;► 55:53 Three movies recommended by Li Heng: &quot;Once Upon a Time in Childhood&quot;, &quot;Goodbye South Country, South Country&quot; and &quot;Dream Life&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 58:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s masterpiece is so dazzling that it... The light of urban youth-themed works overshadowed&lt;br>;► 01:01:52 Director Hou’s films strive for a certain authenticity of the atmosphere of that era&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:06:30 When there are many things that cannot be said Whenever possible, literature is used as a metaphor and movies are used to present it&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:08:25 Hou Hsiao-hsien provides a way of retaining personal experience and memory in narrating film history&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:11 :14 Use southern aesthetics to summarize Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:16:09 Hou Hsiao-hsien influenced young directors from Taiwan, China’s sixth-generation directors, Hirokazu Kore-eda, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Audio Clip/Shao Ruier&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #999999;&quot;>;Operation Promotion/Shao Ruier, Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这部罪案片，悬疑为壳，人性为核]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260769]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The dramatization of crime films often has two levels . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first level is to explore the truth of the murder. Under the sensory stimulation of extreme violence, the protagonist takes the audience&#39;s perspective to reveal the truth bit by bit. The plot has twists and turns and even reversals, providing plot excitement. The other layer is to explore the theme of human nature. The protagonist often has some kind of commonality with the victim and murderer of the case. The story of the detective story is also the protagonist&#39;s growth of exploring himself and &quot;finding himself&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the case was finally solved, the protagonist found the truth of the case and the answer to the confusion in life. They point to an ending in the interweaving, and the audience sees two stories and gets a double plot impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those character arcs in drama theory are actually not complicated. Excellent stories not only reveal the truth about the character&#39;s personality, but more importantly, tell the arc or change of the character&#39;s inner nature during the course of the story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Knowing this, it is easy to understand the director&#39;s intention. In crime films, these two layers are often intertwined, but with different emphasis. For example, &quot;The Mistake on the River&quot; currently in theaters focuses on the latter layer. The director was afraid of being misunderstood, so he directly wrote &quot;No Answer&quot; on the poster. It just reminds the audience that the main purpose of this movie is to explore the human nature related to the case. The investigation itself is not important. There is no need to worry about who the murderer is. There is no answer at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, the new film &quot;Pursuit&quot; directed by Zeng Yingting and starring Junning Chang and Ethan Ruan is not so literary and extreme. Although this movie has some fresh topics, it does not challenge the audience&#39;s entertainment interests too much and is a very regular crime film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/65d82de147164b79f0bb63f091c3cc89.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1531&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/65d82de147164b79f0bb63f091c3cc89.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258558&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Female worker accident He died tragically and was involved in a series of female murders. Finger-cutting, heart-breaking, imprisonment...bizarre cases, cruel murderers, and sensory-stimulating gimmicks are all cut into the trailer. Seasoned genre film viewers are very familiar with this method of publicity, and of course they know that a gimmick is just a gimmick, and its scale will only be safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that &quot;The Hunt&quot; is a movie dominated by female characters, and you can even consider it a female movie (although it is very genre). In the crime genre, very few women lead the investigation. We might as well try to recall the positioning of female characters in crime films. They are often victims or perpetrators (which appears as a reversal card at this time). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this crime movie, the protagonist is the detective Wu Jie played by Junning Chang. She is the leader and the soul of the drama. If you put aside your female identity, Zhang Junning&#39;s role is not special. This is a decadent Matthew Scudder-like character who looks like a professional, capable, and tough detective on the outside, but is broken on the inside. We have seen countless similar male characters. The decadent man finds himself and his original intention through handling cases, which is very cliché. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Pursuit&quot;, we cannot ignore the gender issue, it is the theme of this movie. The audience is first put into a female perspective. Wu Jie, who has experienced pain in the film, is facing the difficulty of how to survive. She tried to commit suicide in the car. This is the starting point of the character&#39;s story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Jie encountered the case of an unknown female corpse. Objectively, the instinct of the criminal police prevented the idea of ​​​​suicide. When she starts to handle the case, the story becomes logical and has two layers: one is that Wu Jie is solving the case of the unknown female corpse and wants to find the murderer; the other is that Wu Jie is also facing her spiritual death and trying to find a way to survive. The answer to go down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/55ac85fe659166239979062a3d35d39b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/55ac85fe659166239979062a3d35d39b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from &quot;Pursuit&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the movie, detective Wu Jie has a dialogue: &quot;We always say that the corpse will choose someone to handle the case, and she chose me.&quot; Of course the dead would not choose. The fact is that Wu Jie chose this case. She wanted to seek justice for the dead, and her motivation was not only her professional status, but also her responsibility as a woman and her need to heal herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, female identity shows special significance. On the surface of the story, a female detective is investigating murder cases against women. Inside, there is a woman who empathizes with women who have been hurt—both physically and emotionally—and ultimately healed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of empathy is not uncommon, but it is difficult to become the main line. There is a scene in &quot;Silence of the Lambs&quot; where a group of male detectives are drinking coffee and talking during an indoor scene involving a woman&#39;s autopsy. Jodie Foster, who was inside, felt uncomfortable and helpless when she saw the naked female corpse. Finally, she mustered up the courage to clear the men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, the story itself of &quot;Pursuit&quot; did not give me much new ideas and was very routine. However, the empathy between the female detective Wu Jie and the female victims always reminds me of the scene in &quot;Silence of the Lambs&quot;. The female perspective runs throughout, and this amplified empathy transcends the limitations of the screen, which is beyond the expectations of ordinary crime films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/039ed79c018630d1e3a528e179f0fb4d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;552&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/039ed79c018630d1e3a528e179f0fb4d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; As a category. They are all movies with female protagonists, and women are the protagonists in an absolute sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is easy for the audience to take a certain unconscious stance, not because of the performance of the two actors, but because of the female protagonist&#39;s genre film, which not only brings freshness, but also brings strangeness. Feeling unwell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9c3085713ee0bf1bd85bcd6b68ee6ac7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;858&quot; height= &quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9c3085713ee0bf1bd85bcd6b68ee6ac7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258557&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Type films and There is no need for extraordinary acting skills, it is very craftsmanship, it should be performed, it cannot be missing or wrong. In my eyes, the &quot;craftsmanship&quot; of performances in genre films is a compliment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is Zhang Junning or Zhang Xiaofei, they provide a fresh sense of crime themes. Although the story still has loopholes and problems of one kind or another, more and more complete and different types of female protagonists appear in On the screen, this is a good phenomenon that deserves applause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>