<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[海底捞“科目三”爆火，有创意还是“辣眼睛”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261690]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Chatting is not as good as dancing. Making oneself feel comfortable is everyone&#39;s talent...&quot; In Haidilao, watch Dancing seems to be more important than chatting and eating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Haidilao has made a splash again with the launch of the &quot;&lt;strong>;Subject 3&lt;/strong>;&quot; dance service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;Subject Three&quot; is not the &quot;Subject Three&quot; of the driver&#39;s license assessment, but a dance that mainly consists of waving hands, twisting hips and half-crotch feet. The music above, the magical dance steps, and the exciting scenes have made the business of many Haidilao stores become booming. Some customers enjoy it: &quot;The fatigue of the day is healed here&quot; &quot;Haidilao can cure social fear&quot; &quot; The boys are so handsome.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But &lt;strong>;&quot;Dance&quot; must be reversed&lt;/strong>;, and Haidilao&#39;s &quot;Subject Three&quot; has also caused a lot of controversy. Some customers complained that &quot;the dancing is tacky and noisy&quot; and &quot;it feels uncomfortable to bring children here to eat.&quot; Accompanying the controversy are the feelings of Haidilao employees themselves: “There is no reward commission”, “It’s hard to refuse customers’ requests”, “It’s really embarrassing inside”, “It’s meaningless”, and even a young man from a store in Changxing County, Zhejiang&lt; strong>;I was admitted to the hospital with a bone bruise due to skipping &quot;Subject Three&quot;&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eating with atmosphere, singing and dancing to entertain is not Haidilao’s exclusive program. For example, Chongqing Hot Pot Factory is called “Sheniu Hot Pot Restaurant” by customers. Behind the &quot;local flavor social shake&quot;, &quot;fancy decoration&quot; and &quot;grandstanding&quot; is the fierce competition in the catering industry. While trying to acquire customers at a low cost, they also want to speed up breaking out of the circle. However, no matter what, service comes first, and the core of a restaurant should be Still taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Under the sea &quot;Subject Three&quot; became a hit, what do you think? Come to the comment area to share your opinions, and I will send you a hot comment immediately. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[数据安全榜：谁在尽心倾力守护您的金融隐私？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261700]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 20:07:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In today’s digital age, financial privacy security is greatly testing everyone’s A financial institution also affects everyone&#39;s most sensitive nerves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;But accidental events often produce extraordinary panic and associations. In November 2023, some financial institutions experienced successive risk incidents at home and abroad, and even encountered hackers, and their core data was leaked or hijacked. The incident triggered deep thinking in the financial and technological circles: How can we do our best to protect users’ financial privacy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In fact, regulators attach great importance to the security of national financial data and personal financial information, and have successively introduced a series of regulatory specifications aimed at establishing a system that covers all financial data. Life cycle safety management system mechanism. Among them, the protection of personal financial information has become an important part of the security management of financial data life cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to objectively evaluate the data security strength of the banking and life insurance industries, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducted a survey on 20 systemically important commercial banks and 9 mainstream life insurance companies. Conduct systematic evaluation. Consistent with the construction logic of the indicator evaluation system of the wealth management list, green finance list, and digital finance list, the quantitative and qualitative indicators of the data security list account for 70% of the weight, and external expert review and media factors each account for 15% of the weight. In view of the differences in relevant information disclosure rules and actual disclosure situations between banks and insurance companies, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has constructed quantitative and qualitative indicator systems for data security in the banking and life insurance industries based on the key disclosure points of each bank and insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the strict data security standards of each bank and insurance institution under evaluation, and the rare data security accidents so far, this list focuses on the above-mentioned bancassurance institutions’ The strategic importance of data security, the transparency of information disclosure and the effectiveness of data security work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Bank ranking indicator system: the most important performance in four dimensions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Banking industry data security ranking The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the evaluation indicator system are divided into four dimensions: organizational construction, institutional processes, technical tools and effectiveness, and include five secondary indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking Indicator System (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/01/63c5f14834.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1151&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/63c5f14834.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking Index System ( Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the banking industry data security ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Organizational construction&lt;/strong>; refers to the organizational structure of commercial banks in terms of data security. The research team of Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center considered the number of relevant responsible departments disclosed by commercial banks. The weight of this indicator accounts for 10%, reflecting the importance commercial banks attach to data security and information protection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;System process&lt;/strong>; refers to the degree of standardization of the process of building a data security system for commercial banks. Standardized institutional processes are an important cornerstone and guarantee for commercial banks to build data security systems. Under this dimension, we mainly examine the number of relevant systems and normative documents on data security of commercial banks, divided into two secondary indicators: the number of its own relevant systems and the number of normative documents related to supplier management, with a total weight of 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Among them, supplier management refers to when a commercial bank collects, transmits, stores, filters, analyzes, exchanges, and shares all data belonging to the bank. , a management mechanism for effective risk identification, assessment and effective control of relevant external partners. At present, most commercial banks do not pay enough attention to data security when conducting annual reviews of various suppliers. For suppliers who have access to sensitive bank data, once the supplier has security vulnerabilities or misbehaves, it is likely that the information security and data security of commercial banks will be threatened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to encourage commercial banks to pay more attention to the management of suppliers in terms of data security, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has disclosed the relevant supplier management systems disclosed by commercial banks. The number of documents is included in the indicator system, accounting for 10% of the weight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Technical tools&lt;/strong>; are a core part of the network security system. This indicator directly reflects the commercial bank&#39;s ability to protect data and privacy and the effectiveness and reliability of data security protection. In view of the fact that the research and evaluation of relevant technical tools in the data industry has been very systematic, we use the number of certification systems disclosed by each commercial bank to determine the bank&#39;s technical strength in data security. The weight of this indicator is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Performance indicators&lt;/strong>; account for 30% of the weight, which is the largest single indicator dimension and the only qualitative indicator to fully reflect the Results-oriented data security ranking evaluation logic. This indicator has a significant impact on the data security evaluation results of commercial banks. For commercial banks that have information security incidents, customer personal information leaks, major IT system failures and other incidents in 2023, we will warn the relevant commercial banks by reducing their scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;It needs to be emphasized that in order to encourage commercial banks to increase the transparency of information disclosure in the field of data security and reduce information asymmetry, we have not disclosed relevant information for some banks. In the case of indicator data, the relevant indicator will be given the lowest score. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bank&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Data Security&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;List&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Big banks dominate the top three&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The bank data security list shows that Agricultural Bank of China ranks first, followed by Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Bank of China. . The comprehensive scores of the three major banks all exceed 70 points, showing significant advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Agricultural Bank of China has obtained 51 various certifications related to data security, far more than any other bank. The bank was the first among major state-owned banks to issue the &quot;Data Security Management Measures (Trial)&quot; and established a comprehensive data security management system based on this. At the same time, the bank adheres to the &quot;minimum necessary&quot; principle, conducts mining and applications within the scope and authority of reasonable use of data, and encrypts sensitive customer information to maximize data security and privacy and avoid leakage and abuse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking of Banks (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/01/07ccf19c0d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2273&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/01/07ccf19c0d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Bank Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/ Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Among joint-stock banks, Ping An Bank and China Merchants Bank ranked fourth and fifth respectively on the list, performing relatively well. Ping An Bank insists on using safe and available tools and technologies for data integration, including using security umbrella technology to automatically desensitize data and automatically protect sensitive groups, and ensure the independence and security of analysis scenarios through data safe houses. The bank&#39;s credit cards use a self-developed privacy computing platform to accurately identify external and debit card customers, effectively reducing customer acquisition costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life insurance ranking indicator system:&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Three dimensions&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;7&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;Sub-indicators&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance is a typical data-intensive industry, with a large amount of personal information, market information and transaction information. Regulators attach great importance to data security in the life insurance industry. Since 2023, regulatory agencies have issued regulatory documents such as the &quot;Measures for the Administration of Consumer Rights Protection in Banking and Insurance Institutions&quot; and the &quot;Notice on Strengthening Network and Data Security Management in Third-Party Cooperation&quot;, requiring life insurance institutions to establish a consumer personal information protection mechanism. And carry out self-examination and rectification of data risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;How is the performance of life insurance institutions? Based on public information such as financial reports, ESG or CSR reports, official announcements, and public reports disclosed by the nine life insurance companies, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducted a quantitative analysis of the nine life insurance companies from the three dimensions of data security, internal governance, and external review. and qualitative evaluation, and set up 7 sub-indicators, each with a weight of 10%, and the total weight of quantitative and qualitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On this basis, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center integrated expert review scores and media factors (each accounting for 15% weight) to build a life insurance data security ranking indicator system . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator system of life insurance ranking of data security ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/12/01/e5b3f8b417.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1379&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/e5b3f8b417.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security Ranking Life Insurance Ranking Index System ( Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the life insurance data security ranking indicator system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the data security dimension, the emphasis on data security work of life insurance institutions is measured by the number of times &quot;data security&quot; or &quot;data privacy&quot; is mentioned in ESG reports, and the effectiveness of data security work of life insurance institutions is measured by whether major information security incidents occurred in the past year. . The judgment of this indicator is based on the description of major information security events in the annual report or ESG report. The total weight of the above two indicators accounts for 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the internal governance dimension, life insurance institutions are qualitatively evaluated based on three indicators: whether to set up an independent data security department, whether to formulate a data security protection system, and whether to conduct an annual information security review. Implementation of internal data security work. The total weight of the above three indicators accounts for 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The external review dimension qualitatively evaluates the acceptance of life insurance institutions in the professional field of data security based on two indicators: whether the App has violated user privacy issues and whether it has obtained ISO/IEC27001 certification. Level of recognition. The total weight of the above two indicators accounts for 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Insurance ranking: China Life wins the championship, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;AIA Taikang ranks among the top three&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The life insurance data security list shows that China Life leads AIA Life to take the first place with an advantage of 1.59 points, and AIA Life ranks second. The comprehensive scores of both life insurance companies exceeded 80 points, 8 points ahead of the third place Taikang Life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Data Security Ranking - Life Insurance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/01/c7c504fb5f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1186&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /12/01/c7c504fb5f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data Security List Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/ Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Looking at the scores of quantitative and qualitative indicators, China Life, China Pacific Insurance, AIA Life and Taikang Life all scored over 60. This shows that they perform better overall in multiple dimensions such as data security, internal governance and external review. In the end, China Life won the championship due to its high scores in both external judges&#39; scores and media factor scores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life proposed a comprehensive &quot;Technology China Life&quot; strategy as early as 2012, and has continued to increase investment in data security for 11 years. As one of the first batch of pilot financial institutions, China Life took the lead in the industry to migrate and put into production the Xinchuang database of key business systems, achieve 100% distributed architecture transformation of key business systems, and successfully build a new self-controlled distributed cloud architecture digital base. The company also proposed and built the first data center in the domestic life insurance industry and a high-standard underground computer room that obtained T4 certification. In addition, the company has also successfully developed a safe, green and elastic China Life Hybrid Cloud using internal private cloud and external public cloud resources, which integrates computing, storage and containers to significantly improve data security and computing capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also found that although the life insurance institutions at the bottom have not yet experienced major information security incidents, they have shortcomings in internal governance and external review obvious. For example, 4 institutions under evaluation did not set up independent data security departments, 2 institutions did not conduct annual information security audits, and the apps of 3 institutions were accused of infringing on user privacy, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that life insurance institutions at the bottom of the list urgently need to pay more attention to the construction and improvement of data security systems, and at the same time adopt more stringent and transparent policies. In the face of public concerns, the public&#39;s information disclosure standards should be strengthened through practical and effective measures to enhance public trust in the data security of life insurance institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 20:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李白的多重面孔：一轮夜空悬，千片秋江月]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261635]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In history, there are few Chinese poets like Li Bai. It attracted much attention during the era in which he lived. Topics, legends, and stories about him were widely circulated when he was alive, and they did not decrease with his death, but became more abundant and mysterious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A scholar did not take the imperial examination, but was recruited to the Jinluan Palace; a commoner did not have the merits of building a large scale, but was favored by the emperor; a person who intended to clarify the troubled times, He was killed by Changliu Yelang; a man who once scattered more than 300,000 yuan a year ended up with nothing in his later years; a poet fought with people in Chang&#39;an City; a Hanlin scholar who was waiting for an imperial edict, drank freely with his craftsmen; A man with lofty ideals who is &quot;willing to serve as the Prime Minister&quot; is keen on refining elixirs and collecting herbs; a madman who looks down on the powerful is excited when facing the common people&#39;s wild rice...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Faced with this prototype that combines many contradictions, people are puzzled and determined to &quot;understand&quot; him. People not only want to understand him, but also &quot;use&quot; him, either to support themselves, to self-explain, to self-comfort, to self-liberate, or to use the past to satirize the present, or to make use of topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What does Taibai look like? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;No photos or videos can answer the question of Li Bai&#39;s true face. For guessing about Li Bai&#39;s appearance, we can only rely on sporadic descriptions in historical materials and the poet&#39;s autobiography to seek clues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The senior poet He Zhizhang exclaimed that Li Bai was &quot;relegated to a fairy&quot; when he first met him. Taoist master Sima Chengzhen commented on Li Bai that &quot;the Jun family has immortal Taoist bones, which can travel with the gods to the eight extremes&quot;. There are many documents written about Li Bai&#39;s contemporaries like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai claimed in &quot;Books with Han Jingzhou&quot;: &quot;Although the body is less than seven feet, his ambition is ten thousand.&quot; The ancients said that tall people are like Zhuge Liang and others are all &quot;eight feet long&quot;, and the seven-foot-long man is only of average height. Even though Li Bai was majestic and magnificent, he was not tall and mighty. He should be a small man. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai&#39;s fanboy Wei Hao described Li Bai in the preface to &quot;The Collection of Li Hanlin&quot; as having &quot;bright eyes, trembling like a hungry tiger, sometimes belted, The romance is brewing.&quot; His friend Cui Zongzhi&#39;s poem &quot;Gift to Li Twelve Bai&quot; also described Li Bai&#39;s &quot;eyes that illuminate people&quot;. It can be seen that Li Bai&#39;s eyes are indeed bright and special. Li Bai calls himself a &quot;savage&quot;, and the &quot;hungry tiger&quot; is seeing his state of breaking through the restraints, which is in sharp contrast with the &quot;or time belt&quot; below. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the Tang Dynasty, there have been many portraits of Li Bai left. Although Li Bai&#39;s true appearance has disappeared with history, some characteristics of Li Bai&#39;s image can be directly appreciated from the painting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the poems of Song Dynasty poets Rao Jie and Chen Shidao, we can know that the Tang Dynasty painter Zhou Fang once painted the image of Li Bai. In Zhou Fang&#39;s writings, Li Bai is a scholar wearing a black gauze hat and a white silk robe, which is highly consistent with the dress of most scholars in ancient times. Wusha was originally a skullcap commonly worn by the people, but it was not until the Ming Dynasty that it became an official hat. The white silk robe, made of white ramie, became the mainstream of fashion in the mid-Tang Dynasty, and people even became obsessed with this kind of clothing. Li Bai&#39;s own description is different from the image in the painting: &quot;Wrapped in grass and covered with black gauze scarf, upside down with purple fur.&quot; ​​He said that he often wore &quot;purple fur&quot;, which was different from the &quot;white fur&quot; described by Zhou Fang &quot;. However, among the many paintings depicting Li Bai&#39;s image in later generations, most painters chose the &quot;black gauze and white gauze&quot; clothing feature. It can be said that Zhou Fang&#39;s &quot;portrait&quot; of Li Bai became a &quot;sample&quot; for later painters to create Li Bai&#39;s image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The stele gallery of the Li Bai Memorial Hall in Jiangyou, Sichuan contains the &quot;Kuangshan Taibai Statue Stele&quot; and &quot;Li Bai Statue Stele&quot; painted by the famous Northern Song Dynasty painter Li Gonglin. The former depicts Li Bai when he was studying in the mountains, clothed in cloth, carrying a bamboo stick, and high-spirited. Many subsequent images of young Li Bai originated from this. In the latter&#39;s prime, Li Bai had a round face, plump ears, and an enlightened, joyful and peaceful expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Taibai Chanting Picture&quot; is the most representative image painting of Li Bai in existence, and was written by the Southern Song Dynasty painter Liang Kai. Liang Kai had a willful and informal personality of &quot;hanging over the wall with his gold belt and leaving his job&quot;. Coupled with his fondness for wine, it can be said that he and Li Bai cherished each other. In the painting, Li Bai is wearing loose clothes similar to Taoist robes, and his hair style depicted in burnt ink is slightly tilted back, as if he is reciting a poem in front of the moon. With a few strokes, he captures the subtle moment when Li Bai is reciting a poem, from his head to his head. The feet are almost in one go. The modern painter Zhang Daqian painted many paintings of Li Bai in his life, most of which were based on the shapes in Liang Kai&#39;s &quot;Li Bai Xingyin&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/28f6db5ac1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;2874&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/28f6db5ac1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260278&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai&#39;s Songs&quot; by the Southern Song Dynasty painter Liang Kai is now in the Tokyo National Museum. Information map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qing Dynasty painter Su Liupeng used &quot;Taibai Drunken Picture&quot; to express the feelings of the literary people. In the painting, Li Bai is supported by two chamberlains. The servant&#39;s clothes are gray, his eyes are submissive, and his posture is like hiding and peeping. Li Bai wears a bachelor&#39;s scarf on his head, a white bachelor&#39;s coat, cinnabar-colored boots and a belt, with bright colors and a sense of nobility. His beard is flowing, his eyes are open, and he is half drunk and half awake. This portrait is reminiscent of Li Bai, who &quot;got drunk in the palace and made Gao Lishi take off his boots&quot;, revealing his arrogant freedom and boldness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/1b2cae5820.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;2376&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/1b2cae5820.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260279&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Taibai Drunken Picture&quot; by Qing Dynasty painter Su Liupeng, now in the Shanghai Museum. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is said that in the Ming and Qing Dynasty warehouses of the Forbidden City in Beijing, the Nanxun Hall has a particularly impressive collection of calligraphy and paintings, including more than ten small portraits of Li Bai and Du Fu. It is unknown when these small portraits were painted, and the people in the paintings are far from the stereotypes. Du Fu is not the common thin image, but a dark and fat man. Although Li Bai has a fair complexion, he does not have much beard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Taibai Hall in the Li Bai Memorial Hall is home to a bronze statue created by Li Xiangqun, a professor at the Academy of Fine Arts of Tsinghua University. The poet&#39;s slender body stands upright in the hall, with his head raised to the sky, his raised chin and beard fluttering, his lips slightly parted as if he wants to speak. The most special thing is that his eyes are blurred. After the statue was exhibited, it was recognized by the cultural and art circles, and was accepted by young people. However, some people over the age of sixty expressed great confusion about the lack of eyes and the freehand treatment, and some even protested. It can be seen that the folks in Taibai&#39;s hometown have an irreplaceable affection for Li Bai. The image of Li Bai created by tradition has been deeply rooted in the hearts of the people, and it seems that he should be what people imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1283&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/28/8580deb4ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259842&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bronze statue of Li Bai in Taibai Hall, author Li Xiangqun. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhu Yuan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;relegated immortal&quot; with &quot;a proud waist&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I am a madman in Chu, Feng Ge laughs Confucius.&quot; &quot;A life of arrogance and misery is not harmonious, and kindness and help are a good matchmaker.&quot; &quot;Arrogance&quot; is not only a self-constructed trait of Li Bai in his poems, generations of creators tell Li Bai&#39;s stories, and they are also happy to express it. this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai claimed that &quot;An Neng can crush my eyebrows and bend my waist to serve the powerful, making me unhappy?&quot; He just said that his character was incompetent. Dai Wei&#39;s &quot;Shu Pu&quot; of the Song Dynasty said: &quot;People in the Tang Dynasty said that Li Bai could not bend his body because he had a proud waist.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If there are changes in character, there are also bending and stretching changes. , but the physical &quot;arrogance&quot; cannot be changed, which pushed Li Bai&#39;s arrogance to absolute status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;People believe that Li Bai is anti-secular at heart and an anomaly of the times. From inducing the foot of Gao Lishi to take off his boots, to having the prime minister grind his ink, and the concubine holding an inkstone, from riding a donkey into the county government office to fishing for ao at sea, all kinds of extreme deeds are unparalleled in ancient and modern times, both at home and abroad, among which &quot;the strong man taking off his boots&quot; is the most representative. sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The notebook novels of the Tang and Five Dynasties, &quot;Supplement to the History of the Tang Dynasty&quot;, &quot;Youyang Miscellanies&quot; and &quot;Songchuang Miscellaneous Records&quot; all record this story. The difference is that only &quot;Songchuang Miscellaneous Records&quot; records that Li Bai was slandered and retaliated by Gao Lishi because of this incident. In &quot;Supplement to the History of the Tang Dynasty&quot; and &quot;Youyang Zazu&quot;, Li Bai&#39;s behavior of asking Gao Lishi to take off his boots was severely denied by Xuanzong. In the former, Li Bai was directly kicked out by the emperor after he asked to take off his boots. The emperor asked Gao Lishi to take off his boots, which was criticized by the emperor as &quot;he is a poor man&quot;. The former statement has been almost forgotten except for the adoption in &quot;Old Book of Tang&quot;. In subsequent stories, Gao Lishi taking off his boots has become an established fact. Perhaps, the repressed people want to take this opportunity to make a fool of themselves and feel happy by spitting out the blockages in their chests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the notebook novels related to Li Bai in the Song Dynasty, there are also some fictional stories that are almost exaggerated but vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Bai in Zhao Lingchou&#39;s &quot;Hou Zhenlu&quot; is like a famous scholar in the Wei and Jin Dynasties:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Li Bai visited the prime minister in the Kaiyuan period and sealed a board with the title: &quot;Li Bai, a fisherman on the sea.&quot; The prime minister asked: &quot;Sir, when you go to the sea to catch a giant turtle, what do you use as a hook and line?&quot; Bai Said: &quot;The wind and waves let go of one&#39;s emotions, and the universe controls one&#39;s ambitions. Use the rainbow as a thread and the bright moon as a hook.&quot; He also said, &quot;What can be used as bait?&quot; Bai said, &quot;Take the unloyal husband in the world as bait.&quot; Prime Minister Chang Ran . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Shu&#39;s &quot;Qing Suo Gao Yi&quot; writes that Li Bai rode a donkey into the county government office while drunk:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: regular script, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zai said: &quot;Who are you, how dare you be rude?&quot; Taibai said: &quot;Begging for a confession.&quot; When Zai ordered the confession, Taibai did not write his name, but said: &quot;I once got a dragon scarf to wipe my saliva. The emperor holds a spoon, a strongman cleans his boots, and a noble concubine holds an inkstone. I am allowed to walk on horseback in front of the emperor&#39;s gate, but I am not allowed to ride a donkey in Huayin County?&quot; Seeing this, the prime minister was shocked. He stood up and thanked him and said, &quot;I didn&#39;t know that Hanlin was here, so he failed to greet me. &quot;Wanting to stay, Taibai ignored him and rode off on the donkey again. &lt;p>; The warriors and the ministers took off their boots and knotted their socks.&quot; Holding the inkstone and grinding the ink were all performed by Yang Guozhong, which fulfilled the theory that Concubine Yang, as the &quot;king&quot;, could not hold the inkstone and grind the ink for the ministers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obviously, people&#39;s imagination of Li Bai does not stop at the image of a &quot;madman&quot;. What is more thorough than describing Li Bai&#39;s &quot;smiling man&quot; is &quot;relegating an immortal&quot; to Li Bai. &quot;With his identity firmly established, he came from heaven and returned to heaven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;About Li Bai&#39;s life and death, from the legend of &quot;Chang Geng entering a dream&quot; to &quot;catching the moon and riding a whale&quot;, it has a profound impact on later generations of creators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Story of the Wind&quot;, which blurs the boundaries between feature films and documentaries, is the last work of Dutch director Ivens. It tells the story of his pursuit of wind and Chinese culture. course. Evans walked out of Méliès&#39;s moon mouth and walked on the moon&#39;s surface. In addition to chatting with Chang&#39;e, he also saw Li Bai on the earth through a small hole. Li Bai was lying drunkenly on a small boat, chanting, &quot;If you don&#39;t see me, the bright mirror in the high hall will have sad white hair, and the morning will be like blue silk and it will turn into snow at dusk.&quot; Suddenly a huge moon shadow appeared on the water, and Li Bai wanted to wrap his hands around it, turn over and fall into the water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ede594b86c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;643&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/ede594b86c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260280&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Bai goes boating with wine on a moonlit night in Evans&#39; film &quot;The Story of the Wind&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Historical materials mostly record that Li Bai died of illness. Bai Juyi wrote a poem &quot;Li Bai&#39;s Tomb&quot;. Although it does not explicitly refer to catching the moon and drowning, &quot;Li Bai&#39;s tomb by the quarrying river&quot; &quot;This sentence is quite fascinating. By the late Tang and Song dynasties, poems and articles on Li Bai&#39;s death had been extensively discussed, such as Hong Mai&#39;s &quot;Essays of Rong Zhai&quot;: &quot;It is said in the world that Li Taibai was quarrying stones in Dangtu. He was drunk and boating in the river. He looked down and took some stones in the shadow of the moon, and drowned. Therefore, there is a catching platform on the ground.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The stars and the moon depend on each other. Li Yangbing&#39;s &quot;Preface to the Thatched Cottage Collection&quot; said that Li Bai was born because his mother dreamed that Chang Geng was pregnant, so he was named Bai, the word is too white. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the writing of Zhang Dachun, a contemporary Taiwanese writer, the origin of this name for Li Bai is his devout identity. &quot;Li Bai in his childhood has already Knowing that he is a star who has fallen into the mortal world, looking at his parents from this point of view is just a tool that God had to borrow to cultivate him in this mortal life; looking at his brothers from this point of view is only a matter of ten years. A companion who accompanies children in spring and autumn.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;As a star, it emits fairy sounds. The guest&#39;s heart is not abiding, and the lingering sound is silent.&quot; Zhang Dachun With this sentence, Li Bai is identified as a person who is like a passer-by in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Fake Taoism and true Confucianism? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Part of Li Bai&#39;s story immortalizes Li Bai, while another part of Li Bai&#39;s story increasingly highlights his mortal qualities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The inspirational legend of &quot;an iron pestle ground into a needle&quot; was recorded in &quot;Fangyu Shenglan&quot; by Zhu Mu of the Song Dynasty. This story shows that Li Bai&#39;s talent is not innate. It is not something that comes from a dream, but is accumulated through hard study. The genius in the eyes of the Tang people was so down-to-earth in the eyes of the Song people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tu Long of the Ming Dynasty wrote Li Bai&#39;s family life in the legendary &quot;Cai Hao Ji&quot;, describing his wife Xu Xiang&#39;e and son Bo Qin, showing Li Bai as a husband With his father, he released the aloof poet into the secular life. This was unheard of in operas of the Yuan Dynasty, and the theme did not appear again in operas of the Qing Dynasty. However, contemporary literary and artistic works often depict Li Bai&#39;s relationship with his hometown and relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is interesting is that the emphasis on Li Bai&#39;s entry into the world and the image of him as a man of lofty ideals who made great achievements are almost overwhelming in today&#39;s literary and artistic works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai stood at the entrance of the altar. When he stepped onto the altar, he broke with yesterday. Yesterday was the life of the human world. In the life of the human world, he Pursuing: &#39;I am willing to serve as an assistant to make the country peaceful and the people peaceful, and the country peaceful.&#39; He wants to be Guan Zhong, Lu Zhonglian, Zhuge Liang, Xie An, Jiang Ziya... &#39;Abandoning the world&#39; means abandoning all these.&quot; Jiangyou writer Wang Huiqinghua said She completed the novel &quot;Li Bai&quot; with more than 700,000 words in 2018. She attributed the reason why Li Bai entered Taoism to avoid being hunted by Li Linfu&#39;s minions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Master Taixuan, who presided over the ceremony, quoted a famous line from &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; to warn Li Bai: &quot;If you want to avoid punishment, it is better to abandon the world.&quot; But Li Bai knew that he most What is difficult to do is to give up the world. Li Bai in the novel once said to the grass-roots sage Zhang Xu when he was young: &quot;Confucius said, &#39;Heaven moves vigorously, and a gentleman should constantly strive for self-improvement.&#39; I don&#39;t believe there is no such thing.&quot; It is completely Confucian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The chapter &quot;Li Bai: The Gambler&quot; in Bei Mingyu&#39;s novel &quot;A Guest from Chang&#39;an&quot; is written more straightforwardly, &quot;Li Bai said a lot of things that flattered others in his life. The scenes and words are all based on the Taoist&#39;s realistic outlook on life of &#39;for my own use&#39; - in order to realize his ideal of becoming a high official, there is nothing he cannot do. But as he gets older, he becomes more and more attached to the silly pursuits of Confucianism.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Li Bai was young, he thought of himself as the roc in Zhuangzi&#39;s works. He once again mentioned it in his last work &quot;Song on the Road&quot;: The great roc flies to inspire the eight descendants, and the sky destroys the power. Not good. The remaining wind is stirring for eternity, and the fusang is hanging on the stone gauze. Later generations will pass this on, who will cry when Zhongni dies? Bei Mingyu lamented: &quot;Since he was young, he has firmly believed that this big bird that shakes eight generations and stirs the world is himself. He has a high and far direction, but he is in the middle. According to Zhuangzi&#39;s carefree , It’s good to fly, it’s good to fold, so just fold. However, Li Bai thought of Confucius in such a tragedy. ... Li Bai spent his life seeking immortality, and when he was about to die, he found that he was still with him in the end. Confucius stands together.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Li Bai&quot; premiered in 1991 and has been performed for more than 30 years. It can be called a classic of Beijing People&#39;s Art Theater. The play is based on Li Bai&#39;s more than sixty years of life, and chooses the five or six years in his later years to form the background of the whole play. It also expresses the secular side of Li Bai&#39;s hesitation between &quot;official&quot; and &quot;hidden&quot;. Screenwriter Guo Qihong pointed out in Li Bai&#39;s character introduction: &quot;&#39;Piaoran Taibai&#39; seems to be the consensus of people all the time, but I think it is not always the case.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/23d10fdd14.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/30/23d10fdd14.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beijing People&#39;s Art In the drama &quot;Li Bai&quot;, Pu Cunxin plays Li Bai. Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The play opens with the scene of Li Bai coming to the throne for King Yong. Li Bai carried &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; and &quot;Li Sao&quot; with him. Taoist friend Wu Yun teased him, thinking Using Zhuangzi&#39;s free and easy mind to complete Qu Yuan&#39;s tragic career is the opposite. Li Bai responded with a smile: &quot;The north is from the head, and the north is the south!&quot; After the experience of Ye Lang, Li Baiben had to enter the way with his wife, but he met Guo Ziyi to visit the day before. , Li Bai, 60, suddenly changed his mind and joined His Majesty Guo Ziyi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Li Bai related works launched in 2023, represented by the animated film &quot;Changan 30,000 Miles&quot; and the musical &quot;Will into the Wine&quot;, all chose not to be in the poem Xian Taibai&#39;s high and easy stay, but pushed a lonely and frustrated Li Bai to the eyes of the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/730e64747a.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 607 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/730e64747a.png &quot;data- key =&quot; 260282 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; In the musical &quot;Will into Wine&quot;, Zheng Yunlong plays Li Bai. Photo of the player &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After Li Baijin in &quot;Will into the wine&quot;, he did not see the emperor. Instead, he saw Gao Lishi and Yang Guifei. The ground told Li Bai, Mo Dangzhen, he and her are just play things in this palace. The show left Chang&#39;an with Li Bai&#39;s losses and returned to his hometown to make a knot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In-depth attention to Li Bai&#39;s inner world and the pursuit of life, and was born in the miscellaneous drama &quot;Shijiji&quot; of the Qing people. Earlier, the songs of each dynasty paid more attention to the description of Li Baipin. In this regard, Jiang Shizhen was very dissatisfied. He was eager to be Li Bai&#39;s name. This dissatisfaction is also a kind of dissatisfaction with his identity. The two have experienced it very much. Going down, they are all old as literati. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Jiang Shizhen once expressed in the article that when he read his own works, he would say that this is an excellent poet. How short it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So, what does Li Bai think of himself? I am afraid this biggest mystery will not have a clear answer. Only the historical horselights continued to rotate, and gradually illuminated him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; • &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>; (&quot;>; ( Part of the content of this article refers to: &quot;Born My Materials: Biography of Li Bai&quot;, &quot;The basis and trajectory of the evolution of Li Bai&#39;s image&quot;, &quot;Evolution of Li Bai&#39;s image in painting works&quot;, &quot;Research on the Story of Li Bai in the Tang and Song Note Novels&quot;, &quot;Yuan Ming and Qing Li Bai&#39;s theme opera opera Research &quot;) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 19:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国考连续6年“扩招”，大专生可报考岗位减少106个丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261673]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-12-01 19:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;November 26, 2023, test site in Wuhan Wenhua College, Hubei Kao District, Hubei, Many candidates are reviewed at lunch breaks. (People&#39;s Visual Pictures) &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/b870989b.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;596&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/b870989b.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;260330&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999;&quot;>; On November 26, 2023, at the test site of the Wuhan Mandarin College of the Hubei Examination Area in Hubei Examination Area, many candidates reviewed the lunch break. (People&#39;s Visual Pictures) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 26, 2023, the central authorities and its direct institutions in the 2024 examination were officially held in public subjects in public civil servants, and the test was officially launched in 237 cities and 87682 test rooms across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the State Civil Service Bureau, a total of 3.33 million people passed the recruitment unit&#39;s qualification review. The number of applicants exceeded 3 million for the first time. Among them, 2.613 million candidates performed registration before the exam. 2.252 million people actually took the exam with a reference rate of about 86.2%. The &quot;National Examination&quot; plan recruited 39,600 people, and the ratio of the number of people participating in the test to the number of recruitment plans was about 57: 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is not difficult to find historical data, and the scale of the &quot;National Examination&quot; recruitment is rising as a whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In August 1993, the State Council promulgated the &quot;Interim Regulations on the National Civil Service&quot; to establish and implement the civil service system at the state administrative agencies at all levels. In June 1994, the former Ministry of Personnel issued the &quot;Interim Provisions on the Recruitment of State Civil Service&quot;, which marked the formal establishment of the national civil servant examination system and organized the first central state administrative organs civil servant recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the first time, the &quot;National Examination&quot; provided 490 places of more than 30 national organs, and the 4,400 people officially applied for the exam, equivalent to 9 people competing for 1 position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since then, the number of &quot;national examinations&quot; has continued to increase. From 2019 to 2024, the number of recruits was 14,500, 24,100, 25,700, 31,100, 37,100, and 39,600, respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cheng Lianchang, the former executive deputy minister of the Ministry of Personnel and the leading group leader of the national civil servant system, has personally experienced the process of establishing and implementing the civil service examination system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He has recalled that the previous hiring system was in the form of recommendation, delivery, introduction, and transfer. In his opinion, this lack of openness, justice, and science, often causing the situation where the people they want by the state government cannot find it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 29 years after the first &quot;National Examination&quot; was held, civil servants recruited the requirements for their degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Liu Youzhen, chief researcher at Huatu Education, noticed that there were 56 posts in the 2024 National Examination College students, which was 106 from the previous year. The number of positions and recruiters who require the master&#39;s degree to increase significantly, and the postgraduate graduate degree and above are required to have 246 posts, an increase of 814 from the previous year; there are 24 posts requesting a doctoral degree, an increase of 14 over the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Grassroots positions are still recruiting big testors. The &quot;National Examination&quot; has nearly 27,000 plans to supplement directly to the county (district) level and below, and properly adjusts the qualifications, majors, working years and experience of grass -roots positions in difficult and remote areas according to the actual situation. Further enrich the grass -roots civil servants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another thing worth noting is that &lt;span>; 2024 The State Administration of Finance and Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration for the first time &lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In March 2023, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Reform Plan for Party and State Institutions&quot;. It was decided to set up the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration on the basis of the Bank of China Insurance Supervision and Administration. On May 18, the State Administration of Finance and Administration was unveiled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The State Administration of Finance and Administration has a total of 1,166 positions this time. It is planned to recruit 1,660 people, and the number of recruits is ranked fifth in the system in each system. As of one hour before the end of the registration, the total number of applicants exceeded 80,000, with the largest competition ratio of 591: 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Earlier, the Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission recruited and other positions in the national examination at the same time, but it was actually a public institution managed by the Civil Service Law. The post was essentially a career establishment. However, after the reform, the State Administration of Finance and Administration has become a direct institution of the State Council, and the post is already administrative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Liu Youzhen, this year Huatu Education has opened 22 custom -made classes at top universities such as Peking University, Tsinghua University, and Renmin University of China to provide special training for students dedicated There are more than 2,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is worth noting that while the number of &quot;national entrance examinations&quot; reached a record high, the number of postgraduate applicants in 2024 decreased by 360,000 after 8 years in a row. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Liu Youzhen&#39;s view, in the severe employment situation, seeking stability is still the primary factor for most candidates to choose to take the test. &quot;To test the public, simply avoid the increasingly difficult postgraduate entrance examination, and directly join the test of the army. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Personnel movement &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Hu Jinglin as the Party Secretary of the State Administration of Taxation &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body_GB2312, simkai, simkai, simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The State Administration of Taxation, on November 28, 2023, the relevant responsible comrades of the Central Organization Department attended the meeting of the State Administration of Taxation and announced that Hu Jinglin was appointed Secretary of the Party Committee of the State Administration of Taxation eliminates the position of party secretary of the State Administration of Taxation of Wang Jun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hu Jinglin, born in June 1964, is a doctor of economics. He served as the first director of the National Medical Security Bureau in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Tang Fangyu no longer serves as the chairman of the Chongqing CPPCC &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body_GB2312, SIMKAITI; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, the official website of the Chongqing CPPCC&#39;s official website showed that Tang Fangyu served as the chairman of the Chongqing CPPCC from January 2023 to October 2023, and he has no longer served. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tang Fangyu, male, Han nationality, born in August 1963, graduate student, member of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Public information shows that Tang Fangyu has successively served as Deputy Director of the Party Construction Bureau of the Central Policy Research Office, director of the Political Research Bureau of the Central Policy Research Office, Director of the Research Office of the Central Office, Deputy Director of the Central Office, and the Central Office of the Central Office The director of the office and other positions, as chairman of the Chongqing CPPCC and secretary of the party group in January this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Zhang Chunlin as Deputy Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt; /Strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the &quot;Shanxi News Broadcasting&quot; of Shanxi Satellite TV, recently, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China approves: Zhang Chunlin serves as a member of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee, a member of the Standing Committee, and deputy secretary. Earlier, Zhang Chunlin served as Deputy Secretary of the Party Committee of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Public information shows that Zhang Chunlin, male, Han nationality, born in February 1965, Sichuan Deyang, joined the work in August 1986, joined the Communist Party of China in January 1986, the population of the School of Economics and Management of Xinjiang University, the population of the School of Economics and Management of Xinjiang University, He graduated from resource and environmental economics, has a postgraduate degree, and is a doctor of economics. He is a member of the 20th Central Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Welcome to the new vice governor &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the afternoon of November 30, the second plenary session (closing party) of the sixth meeting of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress of Shaanxi Province was held. It was decided to appoint Chen Chunjiang as deputy governor of Shaanxi Province. Chen Chunjiang had previously served as assistant to the Minister of Commerce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 30, the Standing Committee of the Hebei Provincial People&#39;s Congress decided to appoint Zhao Dachun as the deputy governor of the People&#39;s Government of Hebei Province. Zhao Dachun had previously served as the deputy general manager of China Mobile Communications Group Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the WeChat public account &quot;Hubei People&#39;s Congress&quot;, on the morning of December 1st, the sixth meeting of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress of Hubei Province was approved by the Sixth Session of the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress of Hubei Province. Governor. Previously, Weishengbin was a member of the party group of the Hubei Provincial Government and Secretary -General of the Provincial Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Deputy Minister of Science and Technology Zhang Guangjun returned to college &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti; &quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 29, 2023, Huazhong University of Science and Technology held a meeting of teachers and cadres and announced that Zhang Guangjun was the secretary of the Party Committee of Huazhong University of Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Guangjun, born in March 1965, academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering. He used to be the vice president of Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, and the president of Southeast University. In November 2021, Zhang Guangjun became the deputy minister of the Ministry of Science and Technology and a member of the party group until this adjustment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; 15-year-old admitted to the University of Science and Technology of the University of Science and Technology, Anhui 80s Hall Officer Performs a new job &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti, stkaiti, stkaiti, stkaiti ; &quot;>; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, the official website of the Anhui Forestry Bureau has been updated. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhou Mi was born in September 1982. Anhui has nothing to do, doctorate in Confucianism, and post -doctoral economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In September 1997, at the age of 15, he was admitted to the Junior Class of the University of Science and Technology of China and studied in the university. After graduating in 2006, he served as the director of the Comprehensive Division of the Anhui Provincial Government Development Research Center (Research Office). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In February 2011, the 29 -year -old Zhou Mi served as deputy secretary of the Anhui Provincial Party Committee of the Communist Youth League. According to the Beijing News, he became the youngest office cadres in the country at that time. At the end of 2019, he went to Xinjiang to participate in the work of aid in Xinjiang. In January of the following year, he served as Deputy Secretary of the Hetian Committee of Xinjiang, the member of the Xuancheng Municipal Committee, and the headquarters of the headquarters in front of the Anhui Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Anti-corruption Chronicle &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; former deputy mayor of Chongqing Xiong Xue was arrested &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI , Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The former deputy mayor of Chongqing Xiong Xue was suspected of accepting a bribe. A few days ago, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate made a decision to arrest Xiong Xue on suspicion of bribery. The case is being handled further. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 13, 2023, the website of the State Commission of Discipline Inspection of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported that Xiong Xue lost his ideals and beliefs, deviated from his original mission, and was indifferent to political consciousness. Division, distorted political performance, formalism, false reports of fraud, confrontation of organizational review, and great superstition activities. Xiong Xue was also accused of incorrect family style, regardless of taught spouses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 【&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In the first round of the financial regulatory system for more than a month, the former director of the Shenzhen Insurance Regulatory Bureau fell off &lt;/span>; &lt; Strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 27th, according to the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection Commission, According to the news, Zhang Huiyi, the secretary of the Party Committee and Director of the Shenzhen Insurance Regulatory Commission&#39;s Shenzhen Supervision Bureau, is suspected of serious disciplinary violations and is currently being reviewed and investigated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is worth noting that from October 10th to October 12th, the Party Committee of the General Administration of Finance Supervision held a 2023 inspection mobilization and training meeting. The meeting pointed out that the inspection was the first inspection of the system after the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China and the establishment of the General Administration of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Sixth-level professional and technical personnel who lost virtue after drinking are dismissed, and many people are punished &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: Kai style, regular body_GB2312, simkai , Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Hunan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection reported on November 29 that on the evening of August 18, 2023, the Hunan Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition held in Xiangxi Prefecture After the semi -finals of the Biomedical Medicine, the results of the results of the Hunan Provincial Department of Science and Technology and the Deputy Director of the Regional Division, the job of the job &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tang Songbo, deputy director of the Management Committee of the Xiangxi High -tech Zone and Weng Lizhi, deputy director of the Xiangxi State Bureau of Science and Technology, invited Li Yangbao (trial period) and professional and technical staff Liu Jian (level 6), director of the Provincial Torch Entrepreneurship Center guided by the Sai Organization, and others at a restaurant in a restaurant in Jishou City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After dinner, Weng Lizhi contacted the high -speed railway Jishu East Station to send 6 people such as Li Yangbao, Tang Songbo, Liu Jian and other 6 people into the VIP room. During the waiting period, Liu Jian lost his state of ethics and harassed two female waiters many times, causing a bad impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In November 2023, Liu Jian was severely warned within the party (two years of affected periods), government affairs removal, Tang Songbo and Li Yangbao were severely warned and dismissed within the party. The party was severely warned, and the rest were dealt with by warning or admonition of the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Ministerial information &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; National Bureau of Statistics: There is no end to the extreme harmfulness of statistical fraud. , Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 30, 2023,&quot; Statistics WeChat &quot;WeChat public account announced the National Bureau of Statistics 2023 Special 2023 The first inspector of the Statistics Inspector to the special statistical inspector to Shaanxi. The inspection found that some cadres and government leaders in Shaanxi Province have not yet deeply understood the extreme harmfulness of statistical fraud and the extreme importance and urgency of statistical counterfeiting. The assessment pressure boost statistical fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; National Health and Health Commission: acute respiratory diseases continue to rise, strive to increase the clinic &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/Span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 26, a spokesman for the National Health and Health Commission Mi Feng introduced at a press conference that recently China&#39;s acute respiratory diseases have continued to rise, with various types Related to the hyperplasia of the respiratory pathogens. All localities should strive to increase the relevant clinic and treatment areas, appropriately extend the service time, and strengthen the protection of drug supply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; People&#39;s Bank of China: Continue to increase the tilt of monetary policy on private small and micro enterprises &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The People&#39;s Bank of China issued a report on November 27. The People&#39;s Bank of China will continue The annual service goals of private enterprises, the weight of the relevant business of private enterprises in performance assessment, etc., increase financial support for private enterprises, and promote the reduction of comprehensive financing costs of enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Rule of rule of law &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; The Supreme Law released a typical case of anti-domestic violence, and mental violence is also family violence &lt;/span>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style , Kaiti_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; November 25 is the&quot; International Elimination of Women&#39;s Violence &quot;. Typical cases of domestic violence, further clarifying that mental violence is also family violence. In trial practice, in addition to the spiritual violations such as frequent abuse and intimidation, it is also spiritual infringement to threaten self -injury such as drinking pesticides and jumping buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaita_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>;&quot;>; 2022, a total of 2430 hackers crimes &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ Span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 30, the Ministry of Public Security held a press conference. Li Tong, deputy director of the Cyber ​​Security Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security, introduced at the press conference that since 2022, the national public security organs have detected a total of 2,430 hackers crime cases, 7092 suspects were arrested, and illegally seized train tickets, hospital registration, hospital registration, and hospitalization. Social resources such as scenic spots and concert tickets invading hackers who violate families and personal privacy lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; In the previous October, more than 34,000 electrical crimes were prosecuted in October. , Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 30, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate issued the case of the case handling of the procuratorial organs. From January to October 2023, the national procuratorial organs sued a total of more than 34,000 crimes of telecommunications network fraud, an increase of nearly 52%year -on -year. The characteristics of the criminals, low income, and low academic qualifications are still obvious, but the higher cultural levels have risen crimes. In the first three quarters of 2023, among the three types of criminals of telecommunications network fraud, help letter, and hidden in the country&#39;s procuratorial organs, more than 4,400 people, more than 5,900, and more than 7,600 people (including undergraduate, masters, and doctors) were more than 4,400. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Science and Education News &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kai style , Kaiti_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti; &quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti; &quot;>; Lei Jun personally donated 13 to Wuhan University 13 Cash 100 million cash, set a record for colleges and universities nationwide &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti; &quot;>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: Kai style Kai Table_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On November 29, 2023, the 130th anniversary of Wuhan University celebrates. Lei Jun, an alumni of the 1987 -level computer department and the founder of Xiaomi Group, personally donated 1.3 billion yuan to Wuhan University to refresh the largest donation of a single donation since the establishment of Wuhan University. This is also the largest personal cash donation received by universities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 【&lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Beijing Municipal Education Commission: Students do not do hard requirements during illness &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span STYLE = &quot;FONT-FAMILY: Kaita, Kai Trees_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; &lt;/SPAN>; &lt;/STRONG>; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On November 25, the WeChat public account of the Beijing Municipal Education Commission &quot;Capital Education&quot; According to the news, Beijing has entered the high incidence of respiratory infectious diseases, and the number of children infected in infection has increased. The school does not have a hard requirement for the homework of students during the illness. It is not recommended to catch up and make up the homework during the illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; The first batch of four universities in the Xiong&#39;an Campus of the Xiong&#39;an Campus started construction &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti; &quot;>;]]] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 28, the first batch of relief at the Xiong&#39;an Campus of the Xiong&#39;an Campus of the Beijing Ministry of Commission was held in Xiong&#39;an New District, marking Beijing Jiaotong University and Beijing University of Science and Technology The Xiong&#39;an campus including Beijing Forestry University and China University of Geosciences (Beijing) all started construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Local political conditions &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt; span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Yunnan: reduce conference expenditure from the source, reduce the number of councils and participants &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family : Kai style, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, the website of Yunnan Provincial Department of Finance said that the meeting will implement classified management and classification approval from the meeting. The number of meetings, the number of sessions, and the number of participants in strict control of meetings, and various meetings of various meetings should not exceed 1 day. The first, second, third, and fourth meetings are 600 yuan, 500 yuan, 400 yuan, and 300 yuan per person per day as the upper limit. At the same time, it is promoted to adopt the form of online conferences under the premise of meeting the requirements of confidentiality and network information security, and preferentially selects existing application systems such as TV telephones and electronic government internal networks internal telephones, electronic government affairs networks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Zhejiang Lishui issued a house purchase consumer coupon, with a maximum of 40,000 &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti; &quot;>; ] &lt;/Span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 28, 2023, Lishui City, Zhejiang Province announced that it issued a house purchase consumer coupon with a validity period of 60 days and a total amount of 18 million yuan. Promote reasonable housing consumption. &quot; This is the first prefecture -level city in Zhejiang in recent years to issue deductible housing consumer coupons. According to the rules of use, 42 real estate purchases in the 42 real estate registered in the event, more than 3 million house purchases in urban real estate or more than 1.5 million real estate purchases in the development zone can be reached 40,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: Kaiti style , Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Fujian: Taiwan compatriots 65 years old and above can take free urban public transportation, etc. &lt;/span>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti ; &quot;>; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 27, the Fujian Provincial Party Committee, the Provincial Development and Reform Commission and other departments held a press conference to announce the implementation of Fujian Province to implement the&quot; CPC Central Committee and the State Council The Opinions on Supporting Fujian Exploration of the Cross -Strait Construction Cross -Strait Integration Development Demonstration Zone of the Straits of the Strait &quot;&quot; The first batch of 15 policies and measures, including 65 years of age and above, can take free urban public transportation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Voice &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; [&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; STYLE = &quot;FONT-FAMILY: Kai, Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; Mao Weiming: &quot;Even the first month of his hometown, not as good as a lamp in your hometown&quot; &lt;/span>; &lt;strong style = &quot;font-family: Kai style, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>;] &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 27, 2023, Deputy Secretary of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee and Governor Mao Weiming visited and investigated some Xiang merchants in Beijing . &quot;Even if there is a first moon in his hometown, it is not as good as a lamp in his hometown.&quot; Mao Weiming said that his hometown is always the strong &quot;backing&quot; and warm &quot;harbor&quot; of the majority of Hunan merchants. We will adhere to the concept of &quot;making the majority of Hunan merchants more incentives in Hunan&quot;, guide the supporting enterprises that support the complementary advantages of resources and meet the needs of Hunan development to the hometown, and achieve mutual benefit and win -win situation in two -way running to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; The website of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee, China Youth Daily, Beijing News, CCTV News, &quot;Wuhan University&quot; WeChat public account, &quot;Capital Education&quot; WeChat public account, etc.) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 19:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[涉56项违规行为，中信银行被罚没超2.24亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 18:40:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The State Administration of Financial Supervision’s administrative penalty information disclosure table shows that CITIC Bank was fined 224 million yuan. Involved in 56 violations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bAQDUFr9Qa7UfuPHCnK1xuzCp6Kr5381T8IIU8Vi.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1102&quot; height=&quot;3895&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bAQDUFr9Qa7UfuPHCnK1xuzCp6Kr5381T8IIU8Vi.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260389&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[基辛格，时代纵横者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261684]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 12/01/JrAlKuYydBfzmqHvKNPyVrV7ck8oK6BbyenF3EB9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JrAlKuYydBfzmqHvKNPyVrV7ck8oK 6BbyenF3EB9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260342&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kissinger&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2023 local time, the former US National Security Assistant and Secretary of State was a famous diplomat, politician and politician who profoundly influenced the development of US foreign policy and geopolitics in the 20th century. Family and scholar Henry Kissinger died at the age of 100. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/nzs2VAJeIaxcrRWol73AbMPNHNlwqUzj3C28Gigo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;688&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/nzs2VAJeIaxcrRWol73AbMPNHNlwqUzj3C28Gigo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kissinger and his brother Walter&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1923, Heinz Alfred Kissinger was born in a German-Jewish family in Fürth, Bavaria, Germany. His father was a teacher and his mother was a housewife. A year later, a younger brother was added to the family, Walter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a child, Kissinger was keen on playing football and once joined the youth training of Fürth Football Club. But with Hitler coming to power in 1933, the Nazi regime&#39;s oppression of the Jewish community intensified. Because he broke into the stadium to watch games in violation of Jewish segregation regulations, Kissinger was often scolded and beaten by guards, and he was also kicked out of the team. Later, Kissinger&#39;s father was also dismissed from his teaching position without reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before everything got worse, Kissinger&#39;s family immigrated to the United States in 1938, and he later changed his name to Henry Kissinger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/urcUvA76c5dNtpo6hqBOMmoB02EtHgR8Z7JDixSR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;627&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/urcUvA76c5dNtpo6hqBOMmoB02EtHgR8Z7JDixSR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260334&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 10, 1971, U.S. President Richard Nixon (left) and National Security Advisor Kissinger talked in his office at the White House&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1969, Nixon appointed Kissinger as National Security Assistant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before entering politics, Kissinger was already a well-known international political scholar, and had served in many institutions or think tanks with a background in the US government. He served as the candidate for Nelson Rockefeller’s presidential campaign three times. foreign policy adviser, during which he sharply criticized Nixon as &quot;the most dangerous presidential candidate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after Nixon became president, the two dramatically became a tacit understanding partner. Faced with the turbulent global situation in the 1960s, Nixon gave Kissinger great room for action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 1971, Kissinger secretly flew to Beijing during his visit to Pakistan, and facilitated Nixon&#39;s visit to China in 1972 that shocked the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39lKQDl4vF2RSxAuLFZ7SuaXJkVKh07cK6toF9xt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39lKQDl4vF2RSxAuLFZ7SuaXJkVKh07cK6toF9xt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260337&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 25, 1972, in Beijing, US President Richard Nixon and his wife attended the dinner and took a group photo. Kissinger was on the right in the front row&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/8OmIyZ9ID8DQMC1bf1umluLDmCPENPAoX5WbMgGE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;643&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/8OmIyZ9ID8DQMC1bf1umluLDmCPENPAoX5WbMgGE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260333 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 3, 1974, in the Moscow Kremlin, during the seven-day summit, U.S. Presidents Nixon (middle), Secretary of State Kissinger (left) and Soviet leader Brezhnev (right) toast &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1972 On February 21, 2011, US President Richard Nixon arrived in Beijing and began his visit to China. On February 28, the Sino-US Joint Communique was released, announcing the normalization of relations between China and the United States. Later studies generally believed that the normalization of Sino-US relations greatly affected the Soviet Union’s diplomatic strategic considerations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Kissinger&#39;s promotion, shortly after Nixon&#39;s visit to China, he visited Moscow in May of that year and met with Soviet leader Brezhnev, which contributed to the &quot;Soviet-US Joint Communique&quot; and &quot;Soviet-American Joint Communique&quot;. The release of 9 documents including the Principles of Mutual Relations between the United States and the United States. In the following years, leaders of the United States and the Soviet Union had frequent exchanges and reached positive consensus on the use of offensive strategic weapons and nuclear weapons testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The improvement of relations between China, the United States and the United States and the Soviet Union directly drove the overall global situation to a positive direction. Kissinger’s diplomatic thoughts on balancing the balance of power among major powers to achieve national interests and international peace were fully reflected in this process. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d6FcaaBTeWxWoEz7WkduMF52Df2s0DWpdbN8Mtu6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;647&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d6FcaaBTeWxWoEz7WkduMF52Df2s0DWpdbN8Mtu6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;January 23, 1973, Paris, France, Special Advisor to the Delegation of the Democratic Republic of Vietnam Le Duc Tho (front row, second from right) and U.S. National Security Advisor Kissinger (back row, second from left) Signing the &quot;Paris Peace Accords&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger traveled to Vietnam twice from 1965 to 1966 . During his visit, he realized that the United States &quot;neither knew how to win wars nor how to end them.&quot; In the end, the war that dragged the United States into the quagmire ended in his hands. After Nixon came to power, Kissinger conducted a series of difficult negotiations with the leaders of North and South Vietnam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The normalization of Sino-US relations has greatly promoted the easing of the situation in Indochina. In October 1972, Kissinger and Viet Cong leader Le Duc Tho achieved a decisive breakthrough in secret negotiations in Paris. Kissinger announced that &quot;peace is close at hand.&quot; Nixon&#39;s popularity surged during the presidential election. Finally, he Re-elected by overwhelming margins in 49 states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 1973, all parties signed the Paris Peace Accords. A ceasefire between North and South Vietnam, the United States withdraws all troops from Vietnam, and the North Vietnamese release all American prisoners of war. Kissinger and Le Duc Tho were also awarded the Nobel Peace Prize. Le Duc Tho refused to accept the award, and Kissinger announced that he would donate the prize money to the children of American servicemen killed or missing in the Vietnam War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/aEHVSSeCESW1K1fSjsluI22dS6GuKWQLx61XkSTe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;651&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/aEHVSSeCESW1K1fSjsluI22dS6GuKWQLx61XkSTe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260335&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 1, 1975, Kissinger looked at the scenery at the hotel in Jerusalem&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/9cpZ0bwTEFEdWXjCAMueQJmkECax1YU41eU989c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;627&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/9cpZ0bwTEFEdWXjCAMueQJmkECax1YU41eU989c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260338&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 6, 1975, on a round-trip flight between Egypt and Israel, Kissinger was reading a newspaper when his wife Nancy patted him on the head&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the &quot;Yom Kippur War&quot; (the Fourth Middle East War) broke out in 1973, Kissinger once again ran for mediation First line. Out of American political interests and his own blood, he tried to delay the ceasefire to give the Israeli army more time to expand its results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, Kissinger once tried to delay the United States&#39; arms and material compensation to Israel, and was committed to promoting UN Security Council Resolution 242 to achieve peace. After the Middle East oil-producing countries, led by Saudi Arabia, imposed an oil embargo on the United States, Kissinger ended up trying to mediate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1973 to 1975, Kissinger traveled between the leaders of Egypt, Saudi Arabia, Syria and Israel, carrying out &quot;shuttle diplomacy&quot; and successfully obtained the support of Egyptian President Sadat and others. trust, and promised to sell arms in exchange for Saudi Arabia lifting its oil embargo, leading to two agreements on the Sinai Peninsula issue - Israel would withdraw from parts of the Sinai and gave up its demand to end the state of war, and Egypt agreed to The opening of the Suez Canal with non-military supplies is considered one of the few diplomatic achievements of the United States during the Ford administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/o1q3WNAyhmZGGEL5Nzv7fAT5ymgO7YXcoQxWZUQS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/o1q3WNAyhmZGGEL5Nzv7fAT5ymgO7YXcoQxWZUQS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260340&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December 11, 1995, from left: Kissinger, Princess Diana, Colin Powell and news anchor Barbara Walters attended the 41st World Cerebral Palsy Federation Association Awards Night. Princess Diana received the UCP Humanitarian Award at the gala &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger was arrested during the Watergate scandal under Nixon After being forced to resign, he continued to serve as National Security Assistant and Secretary of State in President Ford&#39;s administration. But not long after the Sinai Agreement was reached, Kissinger was replaced as National Security Assistant by Brent Scowcroft in a cabinet reshuffle known as the &quot;Halloween Massacre&quot; in November 1975. . After Ford lost the 1976 presidential election, Kissinger resigned as Secretary of State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, Kissinger has traveled in the three circles of politics, business and academia: he established the China Venture Capital Company and served as chairman and CEO; served as &lt;span>;Philip MacMoran&lt;/span>; ( Freeport-McMoRan); served as chairman of the National Commission on Terrorism in the United States... In addition, he has also included principals, political consultants or board members of various institutions, some of which are even controversial positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, he also released at least 7 books, including his own memoirs, political commentary, and even an observation about artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JYae0XIfuOZUxCQWPlzJTjPnpET6kHVJA6tmXXjh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height= &quot;1367&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JYae0XIfuOZUxCQWPlzJTjPnpET6kHVJA6tmXXjh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 12, 2000, Texas Governor and Republican presidential candidate George W. Bush (left) and former U.S. Secretary of State Kissinger waved to reporters on the porch of the Governor&#39;s Mansion in Austin Regards&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/Ed1vgBH06Ddfp1DQZKMlRM4Wymy6WtqU6ULx3DCA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01 /Ed1vgBH06Ddfp1DQZKMlRM4Wymy6WtqU6ULx3DCA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260341&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 10, 2017, US President Trump (right) Meeting with former US Secretary of State Kissinger at the White House &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a man with outstanding contributions and rich experience in American history As a veteran politician with extensive connections in the political and business circles, Kissinger has basically become the “mountain” that every U.S. president since Nixon has consulted or paid a visit to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 17, 2016, Kissinger met with President-elect Donald Trump. They discussed global affairs, and they met again the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later in an interview on August 17, 2017, Kissinger said helplessly when talking about the president who the whole world could not figure out and who often took eccentric opinions: &quot;I hope (Special) Trump) had an Augustinian moment. For St. Augustine...he behaved completely differently in his early years than he later did, but one day he was suddenly inspired and became the saint he became. Of course people don&#39;t expect the president to be like that, but You can always think about it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2PTa6qPaaUQlpQGsxzBkOEEHQB6WjdDcyh2u7FBN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2PTa6qPaaUQlpQGsxzBkOEEHQB6WjdDcyh2u7FBN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260339&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1985, Kissinger visited Qingping Street Market in Guangzhou&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(An Ge/Photo)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ndCunHHZsub4iKGwPsjAt2o4msQiBIyW89wi1unV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;612&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ndCunHHZsub4iKGwPsjAt2o4msQiBIyW89wi1unV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260343&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 12, 2005, in Xuchang, Henan, former US Secretary of State Kissinger came to the home of Liang Shuhua, a villager from Group 7, Xuzhuang Village, Dengzhuang Township, to experience the family life of local farmers. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Visual China/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/12/01/A6Kexysn0JdEdAamq5QldrHwtAwsF6BrCqUPBBQy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ A6Kexysn0JdEdAamq5QldrHwtAwsF6BrCqUPBBQy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, former US Secretary of State Kissinger held a meeting in New York Speaking at the annual awards dinner of the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until he entered the political arena, Kissinger He has never shown much interest in China, but after gaining an in-depth understanding of China through his work, he began to have a new understanding of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After deciding to promote the development of Sino-US relations, Kissinger carefully studied Chinese culture, history, politics and other national conditions, and paid close attention to China&#39;s political and economic development. From 1971 to 2023, Kissinger visited China more than 100 times, a record unique among Western politicians. He once said, &quot;China is the country with which I have the longest and most in-depth exchanges. China has become a very important part of my life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Kissinger&#39;s death, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said, Dr. Kissinger is an old friend and good friend of the Chinese people, and a pioneer and builder of Sino-US relations. &quot;He has long been concerned about and supported the development of Sino-US relations, and has visited China more than a hundred times, making historic contributions to promoting the normalization of Sino-US relations. The Chinese people will remember Dr. Kissinger&#39;s sincere feelings and important contributions to Sino-US relations. Contribution. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“电玩捕鱼”涉赌案：矛盾的时间点，反转的证词]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261669]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A game called &quot;Monopoly Video Game Fishing&quot; was banned by Guangxi Cangwu Public Security Bureau Identified as gambling. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bc41c3b44b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bc41c3b44b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260322&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;A game called &quot;Monopoly Video Game Fishing&quot; was recognized as gambling by Guangxi Cangwu Public Security Bureau. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Monopoly Video Game Fishing” is a game developed and operated by a game company in Beijing. In more than two years, players have recharged a total of approximately 157 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the eyes of the public security organs in Cangwu County, Guangxi, this &quot;fishing&quot; is not a game, but gambling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 18, 2022, the actual controllers of the gaming company, Zong Chao, Zhong Liuqing, and seven employees were arrested by the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau on suspicion of opening a casino. On October 23, 2023, the first instance verdict of the Cangwu County Court was that Zong Chao was sentenced to 6 years and 10 months in prison, Zhong Liuqing was sentenced to 5 and a half years in prison, and the remaining 7 people were sentenced to prison terms ranging from 2 years to 2 years and 11 months. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The judgment stated that the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau, based on the clues discovered during the work, confirmed after preliminary inspection that some players of the game involved were from Cangwu County, and the reporter and three witnesses were also from Cangwu County. They The testimony confirmed that the game involved was suspected of gambling, and Cangwu County was the place where the crime was committed and had jurisdiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people who attended the trial that, coincidentally, two of the witnesses were held in the same cell as the defendant. During the first-instance trial, the defendant&#39;s statement of situation showed that both witnesses stated that they completed the transcript under the arrangement of the public security agency staff, and that they had not been exposed to this game before making the transcript. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when the two witnesses were later questioned by the detention center, they overturned their statements in the description of the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zong Chao and Zhong Liuqing refused to accept the verdict and have submitted an appeal to the Wuzhou Intermediate Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Gray areas and luck&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The persons involved, Zong Chao, Zhong Liuqing, and the start-up employees of the game company were all former colleagues of a major Internet company. In 2018, they resigned from their original units and established Beijing Sihai Interactive Entertainment Technology Co., Ltd. to jointly operate fishing games. In the second half of 2019, the game will be launched online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gameplay of the fishing game is that after users recharge RMB to obtain game gold coins, they then use the gold coins to fire fish. After successfully fishing, they win gold coins at a multiplier rate. At the same time, in the &quot;Fortunate Beans&quot; mode, users can obtain &quot;Fortunate Beans&quot; when fishing, and &quot;Fortunate Beans&quot; can be exchanged for phone bills, physical goods, JD shopping cards, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance verdict quoted a defendant’s confession. He had an online group with Zong Chao, Zhong Liuqing and others as well as lawyers to discuss whether this game would hit a legal red line. The opinion given by the lawyer is that the gameplay of this game is in a gray area. There is no law that says you can do this, and there is no law that says you can&#39;t do it this way, so you just took a chance at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of the defendants and their lawyers, the reason why this game cannot be considered gambling is that although the gold coins won by fishing are proportional to the &quot;explosion rate&quot; and &quot;multiplier&quot;, the gold coins It cannot be used to exchange RMB. The lucky beans that can be converted into RMB have their own generation mechanism, which has nothing to do with &quot;explosion rate&quot;, &quot;bet size&quot; and &quot;magnification&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The case will be heard in public on &lt;/span>; March 28, June 25, and June 29, 2023. Zong Chao&#39;s defense lawyer defended his innocence. The lawyer pointed out in court that the essence of gambling is to achieve &quot;big gains with small things.&quot; In order to ensure that the game operation does not fall into the scope of the crime of opening a casino, the game operator has a limit on the proportion of the recharge amount for the lucky beans that come with the game, and the operator has set up a blacklist to intercept players who try to &quot;compromise with small things&quot;. Outside the game. Therefore, this game cannot achieve &quot;using small to gain big&quot;, so it is not gambling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment of the court found that when players use cannons that consume more gold coins and have higher multiples when fishing, the energy bar will grow faster, and different levels of lucky beans can be produced correspondingly. There is &quot;a small way to make a big difference&quot;. It has a cash withdrawal function and is recognized as a gambling game. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&amp;nbsp;&quot;A moment of negligence&quot;? Conflicts occurred at multiple points in time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 15:50 on January 2, 2022, local Pan Jianfeng went to the Shiqiao Town Police Station in Cangwu County to report that he had downloaded the &quot;Monopoly Video Game Fishing&quot; App at home. After registering with a real name, I found that this game can be recharged online, and then you can win &quot;Fu Beans&quot; by playing the game, and the &quot;Fu Beans&quot; can be exchanged for RMB and withdrawn. He told the police that he had recharged 36 yuan and withdrawn 2 yuan, so he thought it was a gambling game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance judgment, on December 20, 2021, 13 days before Pan Jianfeng reported the case, the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau had noticed this App and conducted a preliminary inspection. After verification, it was found that there were Cangwu members. 41 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Cangwu County Public Security Bureau opened a case for investigation on the day Pan Jianfeng reported the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case will be heard in public from March 28, June 25 to June 29, 2023. During the trial, defense attorneys for several defendants raised questions about the close time between Pan Jianfeng’s game registration, cash withdrawal, and crime reporting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Game background data shows that Pan Jianfeng registered for the game at 15:15:56 on the day of the report. The screenshot of the withdrawal interface he provided showed that he withdrew the money at 15:49:17. In other words, he had just registered for the game 25 minutes before being questioned, and the time of withdrawal was only 43 seconds after being questioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for Pan Jianfeng, the defendant’s defense lawyer believed that there were contradictions in the time when witnesses Wang Kai, Qin Jun, and Chen Tao withdrew cash from the game and were interviewed by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Kai, Qin Jun, and Chen Tao started at 10:25 on January 7, 2022, 12:10 on January 7, 2022, and 10:30 on January 10, 2022. Shiqiao Police Station for questioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Kai said when questioned that he had recharged 54 yuan in the game and withdrawn 2 yuan; Qin Jun said he had recharged 36 yuan and withdrawn 2 yuan; Chen Tao also said he had recharged 36 yuan and withdrawn 2 yuan. 2 yuan. All three stated in the inquiry that they could provide screenshots of the withdrawal page. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, the lawyer pointed out that in the screenshots provided by the three people, the withdrawal times of Wang Kai and Qin Jun were both at 21:31 on January 8, while Chen Tao made the withdrawal at 13:27 on January 10. . In other words, their withdrawal time was later than the time when they were asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the above time issue raised by the lawyer, the prosecutor issued a statement from the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This document explains that Pan Jianfeng first played games at home and reported the case to Shiqiao Police Station around 15:00 on January 2. He cashed out after an on-site operation demonstration. The police station accepted the case at 15:50. The defendant&#39;s defense lawyer also pointed out the issue with the timeline: Pan Jianfeng arrived at the police station around 3 p.m., so the game should have been registered at the police station. During the trial, the prosecution and defense debated this issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation statement also pointed out that when the case investigators produced the interrogation transcripts of Wang Kai and Qin Jun, they used the version of the transcripts dated January 7 and forgot to modify the interrogation time. The actual time was January 9; production When Chen Tao took notes, he was also &quot;slip and careless&quot; and wrote down the time of the inquiry incorrectly. The correct time was from 14:30 to 15:40 on January 10. According to this explanation, Chen Tao completed the withdrawal one hour before accepting the inquiry. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reversal of witness statement&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, witnesses Qin Jun and Chen Tao were later detained at the Cangwu County Detention Center on suspicion of provocation and were detained together with the defendants Zong Chao and Zhong Liuqing respectively. In a prison cell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both witnesses said that they completed the transcript under the arrangement of the public security agency staff, and even signed the transcript without reading the content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, Zong Chao submitted a handwritten statement by Qin Jun, describing the process of reporting the case: At the end of 2021, his friend Wang Kai from the same town called him and asked him to take someone to the Shiqiao Police Station. Play a fishing game together. He took Pan Jianfeng to the police station. Wang Kai shared the game download link with them on WeChat, and then they registered, recharged and cashed out, then sent screenshots of the relevant game to the police, and signed and left after all was completed. He said that he had not been exposed to this game beforehand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Tao is detained in the same cell as Zhong Liuqing and other three defendants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, all three defendants submitted their own handwritten explanations. One defendant said that four days before the first trial, he received a subpoena in the prison cell. Chen Tao noticed the name of the game company on it and said, &quot;I think I reported it.&quot; The defendant asked Chen Tao why he reported it. Chen Tao&#39;s answer was, &quot;I haven&#39;t played it. I was just called to the police station to sign the transcript.&quot; He also said that he had not read the transcript. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the two men’s statements were reversed in the interviews recorded by the detention center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the record on May 15, 2023, Chen Tao said that after the court session at the end of March, Zhong Liuqing came to him and asked him to write a written certificate or testify in court to prove that he went to the public security organ to report online gambling. The situation is false and does not actively reflect the facts. He didn&#39;t agree because what he said before was true. After that, Zhong Liuqing wrote a written material and asked him to sign it, proposing that as long as he agreed to testify in court and overturned his previous record at the public security organ, he could be given 50,000 yuan, 100,000 yuan or even 500,000 yuan, but he did not agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qin Jun said in the conversation three days later that his statement of situation was &quot;written in a confused way&quot; and &quot;They spoke so artistically and literately, but I don&#39;t know why they were dismissed.&quot; Brainwashed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment of the Cangwu County Court held that the testimonies of Pan Jianfeng, Qin Jun, Wang Kai, and Chen Tao were objective and true and relevant to the case, and they were recognized. The above-mentioned description of the situation and other materials provided by the defendant are inconsistent with the facts ascertained in the case and will not be accepted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Pan Jianfeng, Chen Tao, Qin Jun, and Wang Kai are all pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https:// /feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;bR >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西检察机关依法对李东涉嫌受贿案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261675]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 15:04:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Reporters learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate today (1st) that former party members of the National Energy Investment Group Co., Ltd. The case of deputy general manager Li Dong suspected of accepting bribes was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the case was reviewed and prosecuted by the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Yichun City, Jiangxi Province. Recently, the Yichun City People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Yichun City Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ informed the defendant Li Dong of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant Li Dong, and listened to the opinions of the defender. The prosecution charged: The defendant Li Dong used his position as deputy secretary and manager of the party committee of Shenhua Zhungeer Coal Company, deputy secretary and chairman of the party committee of Shenhua Group Zhungeer Energy Co., Ltd., deputy chief engineer of Shenhua Group Co., Ltd., Shenhua Group Members of the party group and deputy general manager of a limited liability company, members of the party group and deputy general manager of China Energy Investment Group Co., Ltd., seeking benefits for others and illegally accepting property from others, if the amount is particularly huge, should be investigated for bribery according to law. criminal responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[数字金融榜：哪些银保机构更“智慧”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261671]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 14:35:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;No technology, no finance. my country&#39;s digital finance, which has always been at the forefront of its global counterparts, has ushered in a historic opportunity: not only has it stood at the forefront of the historical transformation of the AI ​​​​big model, but it has also ushered in the policy trend - the Central Financial Work Conference clearly requires five major articles such as digital finance to be done well. article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital finance has thus become the strategic frontier for competition among major financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Study by Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that the large models of domestic financial institutions have entered a &quot;battle of hundreds of models&quot; and have explored smart finance in different vertical fields. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details, please see the Southern Weekend App &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/261381&quot;>;Financial Industry&#39;100 The model war is in full swing, how to break through in compliance?&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which banks have invested the most in technology? Which financial institution has more technology staff? Which financial institutions have already applied AI technology to financial practices? Which insurance company has smarter claims settlement? In order to objectively present the technological strength of various financial institutions, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has set up indicator evaluation systems for 20 banks and 9 life insurance companies, and based on this, selected the bank financial digital list and the life insurance digital financial list. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bank ranking indicator system: six dimensions and eleven sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to objectively present the competitiveness of 20 banks in financial technology, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center constructed a digital The quantitative and qualitative index evaluation system of the financial list mainly includes four dimensions: technology investment, digital banking, digital risk control and digital payment, and eleven secondary indicators, and gives different weights to each indicator based on the difference in importance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center assigned media factor weights to 20 banks based on a special survey, and invited an external expert jury to conduct an independent real-name assessment of the comprehensive competitiveness of the 20 banks in the field of digital finance. Review. Both scoring weights are 15% each. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the financial institutions under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this basis, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center constructed the 2023 banking industry &quot;digital financial list&quot; indicator system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator system of digital financial ranking bank ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /01/e7a07f5b05.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/e7a07f5b05.png &quot; data-key=&quot;260323&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Indicator system of bank ranking of digital finance ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now for banks The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the ranking index system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology investment refers to the degree of investment of financial and human resources by banks in digital finance, including R&amp;D and innovation investment, technical equipment investment and talent team building, etc. Invest. Technology investment reflects the bank’s emphasis on digital transformation and its investment strength. The total weight of the five secondary indicators is 38%, which is the dimension with the highest weight among the six dimensions. It also highlights the intensity and effectiveness of commercial banks’ “real money” investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital banking means that banks use information technology and digital technology to realize the digitization, automation and onlineization of business processes and provide more convenient and efficient financial services. Quantitative indicators of the development status of digital banks include the number of monthly active users of mobile banking, user reviews of mobile apps, etc. Relevant awards awarded by authoritative third-party organizations for bank digitalization can also be used as qualitative indicators of the bank&#39;s digital strength. The total weight of the above three sub-indicators is 16%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital risk control means that banks use big data, artificial intelligence, cloud computing, machine learning and other technical means to monitor and predict risks in real time and take corresponding risk management measures. Digital risk control can improve the accuracy and efficiency of risk management and reduce the risk of non-performing assets. Therefore, we select the non-performing loan ratio indicators and their changes reported by each bank as of the mid-term report of 2023 to reflect the actual effectiveness of digital risk control of each bank; at the same time, from the perspective of information disclosure, we disclose the “digital” or “digital” or The frequency of &quot;intelligent risk control&quot; is calculated to encourage commercial banks that disclose more proactively and adequately in digital risk control. The total weight of the above two sub-indicators is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital payment means that banks realize the digitization and online payment methods through the application of mobile payment, electronic payment and virtual currency and other technical means. Digital payment can provide more convenient and secure payment methods and promote consumers&#39; consumption activities and financial transactions. We conduct a qualitative evaluation on whether each commercial bank has been included in the central bank&#39;s designated operating agency for digital payment. If included, the commercial bank will receive a 6% weight bonus. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bank list: China Merchants Bank strives to take the top spot among state-owned banks and joint-stock banks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The 2023 banking industry digital finance list shows: the comprehensive ratings of China Merchants Bank, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Ping An Bank in the field of digital finance. Ranked in the top three. But the more prominent phenomenon is that some joint-stock banks have overcome their disadvantages in scale and strength and are making great efforts in the field of digital finance and are showing initial results. Reflected in the list, China Merchants Bank and Ping An Bank both entered the top three, forming a situation in which they compete with large state-owned banks such as Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Bank of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Digital Finance List Bank List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01 /39e97963a6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2275&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39e97963a6.png&quot; data -key=&quot;260324&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Digital Finance List Bank List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, the four major state-owned banks It has always been a &quot;leader&quot; in technology investment. In 2022, ICBC, Agricultural Bank of China, China Construction Bank and Bank of China will all exceed the 20 billion mark in technology investment. Among them, ICBC invested the most, reaching 26.224 billion yuan. The number of scientific and technological talents in major banks is also significantly ahead of most joint-stock banks. Among them, ICBC has 35,000 scientific and technological personnel by the end of 2022, ranking first among all banks. Supported by a very large customer base, the average number of monthly active users on mobile terminals of the four major banks exceeds 90 million, which is almost five times the average of joint-stock banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are already followers or even surpassers in joint-stock banks. For example, China Merchants Bank and Ping An Bank, both headquartered in Shenzhen, are relatively disadvantaged in terms of scale and strength, but their investment in technology is not inferior at all, and they are even more &quot;heroic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared in terms of absolute numbers, CMB has 10,800 technology talents, almost catching up with some major state-owned banks; from the perspective of proportion indicators, CMB’s technology investment will account for 4.51% of operating income in 2022, which is 1.65 higher than ICBC in the same period. percentage points; at the same time, the bank’s latest NPL ratio remains at 0.95%, which is significantly better than the average NPL ratio of the four major banks of 1.34%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, China Merchants Bank has been the most active commercial bank in technology investment since the &quot;Ma Weihua Era&quot;. On the one hand, from taking the lead in transforming retail banks to proposing a light banking strategy, from a mobile-first strategy to fully implementing digital transformation, they all relied on huge investments in technology that lasted for many years; on the other hand, the introduction of new financial technologies has strongly supported its business expansion and customer Improved experience. In particular, the bank&#39;s retail business advantages have been continuously consolidated and expanded, thereby promoting its industry-leading growth rate in terms of asset size, revenue, profit and other indicators for a long time. As a result, China Merchants Bank has become a benchmark bank on the digital finance list in the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike China Merchants Bank, Ping An Bank has accumulated nearly 6,000 financial technology patents in the past five years, relying on the strong technological research and development capabilities of Ping An Group, ranking first in the banking industry. Ping An Bank has 9,000 scientific and technical personnel, second only to the four major banks and China Merchants Bank. However, scientific and technical personnel account for 10% of the bank&#39;s employees, far exceeding the average of the four major banks of 4.76%. Although it failed to enter the central bank&#39;s list of &quot;Designated Digital Payment Operators&quot;, Ping An Bank ultimately won third place with a clear advantage due to its comprehensive performance in technology investment, digital risk control, digital banking and other dimensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;BoCom’s high investment has not yielded high results&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Only from the evaluation results of qualitative and quantitative indicators, China Merchants Bank, Bank of Communications and ICBC all scored more than 50 points. Among them, Bank of Communications&#39; qualitative and quantitative scores surpassed ICBC and ranked second. Its technology investment accounted for 5.26% of revenue, ranking first among the 20 banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, compared with the top three banks in the comprehensive ranking, Bank of Communications has experienced a long-term sluggish growth rate in terms of scale, revenue and profit, and its non-performing rate has not significantly improved due to its conservative business strategy. This shows that its high proportion of technology investment has not significantly improved the bank&#39;s productivity and has not significantly improved the bank&#39;s business and financial performance. Meanwhile, outside judges gave the bank average marks. The bank&#39;s final score ranked only sixth. This may have something to do with its mediocre business performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to its short establishment, the scores in both technology investment and digital banking are the lowest among the six major state-owned banks. Therefore, the Postal Savings Bank ranked only 13th in the list. However, the bank is accelerating the &quot;digital ecological bank transformation&quot; and strives to explore transformation methods that are consistent with its own endowments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that in terms of digital risk control, the bank’s digital infrastructure and digital risk control system came into effect as soon as they were completed, and its score was second only to Bank of Communications among major banks. The bank&#39;s low non-performing loan ratio of 0.81% ranks second among 20 banks, only higher than Bank of Ningbo, and performs better. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Among the urban commercial banks with the fastest growth in technology investment among joint-stock banks, Bank of Shanghai is far ahead&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The overall digital financial competitiveness of joint-stock banks continues to improve, but the trend of differentiation is obvious&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of total investment in financial technology, joint-stock banks are not as good as state-owned banks, but they maintain a high growth rate in technology investment. In 2022, the investment amount of the six joint-stock banks that disclosed relevant data on financial technology investment increased by an average of 11.2% year-on-year, which was twice the average growth rate of major state-owned banks in the same period. Among them, Industrial Bank’s technology investment in 2022 will increase by nearly 30% year-on-year, ranking first in the industry in terms of growth rate. At the same time, the average proportion of technology investment in revenue of the nine joint-stock banks exceeds 4%, which is higher than the average level of 3.5% for state-owned banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;City commercial banks, which are in the third tier of commercial banks, have always been in a state of catching up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Limited by their own scale, the overall scale of technology investment of city commercial banks is not large, but the technology investment of a few city commercial banks is growing rapidly. Among them, Bank of Shanghai is the leader in digital reform of city commercial banks. Its technology investment in 2022 will be 2.132 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 15.06%, accounting for 4.18% of operating income. The Bank of Shanghai is not only far ahead among city commercial banks, but also not inferior among the 20 banks. It surpasses 6 joint-stock banks and 1 major state-owned bank, ranking among the top ten, ranking ninth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In general, although they are the best among more than 100 city commercial banks, the five city commercial banks are still limited by scale, strength and operating geographical area, and their competitiveness in the digital financial field cannot be compared with that of national banks. . If limited funds can be concentrated into a certain segment of financial technology, the five city commercial banks can still achieve good results in regional market competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Life insurance ranking indicator system: four-dimensional evaluation of eight secondary indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to objectively present the digital competitiveness of the nine life insurance institutions, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center focused on digital capabilities and digital strategies Two dimensions are used to construct a quantitative and qualitative index evaluation system for the life insurance industry’s digital financial rankings. The weight of this item in the overall score is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to the bank ranking indicator system, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center assigned media factor weights to 9 life insurance institutions based on a special survey and invited an external expert jury to review the 9 life insurance institutions. The weight of the two scores is 15% each. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this basis, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center constructed an indicator system for the digital finance list of the insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the life insurance index system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital capabilities. This dimension refers to life insurance companies relying on digital technology to innovate and upgrade their business models in the entire chain, including product research and development, marketing, channel expansion, operations management, underwriting and claims payment, while also controlling costs more accurately and effectively in order to obtain more Profit margins. In view of the actual information disclosure of nine life insurance companies in terms of digital capabilities, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center mainly examined comparable data such as the average claims timeliness of life insurance companies directly related to customers, the number of monthly active users of the App, and the version rating of the App. The total weight of the three indicators accounts for 45%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital strategy. This dimension means that in the process of promoting digital transformation, life insurance institutions make all-round adjustments and iterations in organizational structure, organizational culture, business models, business processes and technology applications, in order to form a top-level design that adapts to the development needs of life insurance business in the digital era as soon as possible. Since the degree of disclosure of digital strategies by life insurance companies is uneven, from a comparable perspective, the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center chose to conduct quantitative statistics on the frequency of &quot;digitalization&quot; in regular reports to reflect life insurance institutions&#39; commitment to digital transformation from the perspective of information disclosure. Attention. At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center qualitatively analyzed the digitalization of 9 life insurance companies through four indicators: whether to disclose technology and patent data, whether to apply AI intelligent technology, whether there is any violation of user privacy, and whether to obtain third-party honors in digital technology. strength. The total weight of the above five indicators is 25%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator system of life insurance ranking of digital finance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /01/82e671b259.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1487&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/82e671b259.png &quot; data-key=&quot;260325&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Indicator system of life insurance ranking of digital financial ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Insurance ranking : Ping An won the first place, followed by China Life and China Pacific Insurance Co., Ltd.&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The list of digital finance in the life insurance industry shows that Ping An Life has the highest score, with China Life and China Pacific Insurance ranking second and third respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Digital Finance List - Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01 /2e32db32bb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1185&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2e32db32bb.png&quot; data -key=&quot;260326&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Digital Financial Ranking - Life Insurance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the competition of digital capabilities, China Life Insurance, AIA Life and Ping An Life are equally powerful, with scores between them. Ping An Life App ranks first in terms of average number of monthly active users, with 98% of users making claims online. China Life is even more outstanding in terms of average claims settlement timeliness. The ultra-high claims settlement timeliness of 0.39 days per order is an example of how digital technology has successfully reshaped the entire claims settlement process. As the only foreign-funded life insurance institution shortlisted for the evaluation, AIA Life’s App received the highest score, which shows that users highly recognize the life insurance App’s functionality, security, and operational convenience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the digital strategic dimension, Ping An Life mentioned “digitalization” as many as 40 times in its annual report, which is almost as many times as the combined number of mentions of CPIC Life and Sunshine Life, which followed closely behind. Its emphasis on digital transformation is evident. China Life does not score high in this dimension. One of the reasons is that it is conservative in the application of AI intelligence and its response speed lags behind its peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center found that digitalization has gradually become a key word for the strategic transformation of my country’s insurance industry. Almost all insurance institutions have established digital operations departments or information technology departments, and most of them mention their own &quot;digital transformation&quot; development strategies and digital transformation-related initiatives in their annual reports. Specific to life insurance institutions, the nine life insurance institutions evaluated this time have continued to increase investment in technology, among which China Pacific Life Insurance and PICC Life Insurance have established technology subsidiaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, the life insurance industry still has a long way to go in digital financial transformation. Whether it is the &quot;Tao&quot; at the digital strategic level or the &quot;Technology&quot; of digital capability building, there is still huge room for development in the digitalization of life insurance companies. At the same time, in the face of the certainty of huge investments and the uncertainty of transformation results, life insurance companies face many risks and challenges in their digital transformation. The good news is that in some subdivisions and in certain business indicators of individual life insurance companies, the &quot;honey scent&quot; brewed by technological innovation can already be smelled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that from the perspective of industry trends, the technological dividends brought by digital transformation will continue to lead the transformation of the life insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一座湖南县城“利剑出鞘”：近八百公职人员进退公租房]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261658]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[吴秀波终究不是司马懿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261649]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the China Executive Information Disclosure Network, recently, the well-known actor Wu Xiubo and his name Horgos have not Both Culture Media Co., Ltd. have added information on the persons subject to execution, with the execution subject matter being approximately 466 million yuan, and the execution court is the Jiangsu Provincial High Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response, Wu Xiubo posted responses on Weibo one after another. He exposed the chat records and evidence that one of the original investors of the film crew, General Manager of Jiangsu Huali Culture Media Co., Ltd. Jin, and Zhang, the producer of &quot;Army Master Sima Yi&quot; and deputy general manager of Jiangsu Huali, misappropriated the crew&#39;s funds, accusing him of misappropriating the crew&#39;s funds. The two &quot;fake investment but real misappropriation&quot; deliberately signed the supplementary agreement with a fake seal, and then set up a trap to deceive him, causing him to lose all his money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2015, Wu Xiubo established Fuji Culture, holding 99% of the shares and with a registered capital of 50 million yuan. Wu Xiubo, who is also the director and the leading actor, began to produce &quot;The Great Military Advisor Sima Yi&quot;. Jiangsu Huali is one of the major investors, accounting for 50% of the investment share. Zhang took the initiative to serve as the chief producer and served as the legal representative and general manager of Fuji Culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Phoenix.com’s financial analysis, during the cooperation period, Jin asked to divest because the investment amount was too large. Under Zhang’s operation, Jiangsu Huali signed an agreement with Fuji Culture to transfer 45% of the investment income rights. Transferred to Fuji Culture &quot;without premium&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2017, &quot;Army Master Sima Yi&quot; became an instant hit as soon as it was aired. The number of views once exceeded 7 billion, and its revenue was nearly 1 billion yuan. According to a post on the official Weibo &quot;TV Series Tiger Roar and Dragon Yin&quot;, after the show was confirmed to be profitable, Kim arranged for Horgoswari, which he actually controlled, to sign a &quot;global exclusive distribution agreement&quot; and &quot;information network dissemination agreement&quot; with Fuji Culture. Agency Distribution Agreement&quot;, stipulating that Horgoswari has the right to share half of the proceeds. The relevant agreement was signed by Jin asking Zhang to &quot;help&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2017, Jiangsu Huali demanded payment for the proceeds from the show, but learned that the proceeds from the broadcast of &quot;Sima Yi&quot; by Jiangsu Radio and Television Group did not go to Jiangsu Huali, but to another company. One investor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since October 2017, Jiangsu Huali and Horgos Huali have successively taken another investor and Fuji Culture to court. After investigation by the Yili City Public Security Bureau and court evidence collection, it was found that the official seal included in the previous agreement signed between Jiangsu Huali and Fuji Culture was privately forged by Zhang, the legal representative of Fuji Culture. Zhang was criminally detained for engraving an official seal privately and has not yet been released from prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case of Horgoswari suing Fuji Culture was brought to the Jiangsu High Court, and Fuji Culture lost the case. In November 2023, Wu Xiubo waited until the Supreme Court upheld the original judgment of the Jiangsu High Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, whether Wu Xiubo’s accusation is true or not remains to be officially investigated. But at the beginning, he agreed that Zhang would concurrently serve as the legal representative and general manager of Fuji Culture, which also allowed him to take the lead in daily operations. The investor sends someone to serve as the legal representative or general manager of the invested enterprise. Which side this person will take when it comes to conflicts of interest between the investor and the invested enterprise is a major issue related to the development of the enterprise. Wu Xiubo did not have sufficient professional knowledge and experience, and he also did not establish a complete supervision mechanism, such as hiring special personnel to effectively supervise Zhang&#39;s daily operations and investment decisions, which further amplified the risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This can&#39;t help but remind people of &quot;Sima Yi, the Great Military Advisor&quot;, which brought Wu Xiubo to the peak of his acting career, but suffered &quot;an unreasonable disaster&quot; as a result. In the vast sea of ​​history, Sima Yi is undoubtedly a very controversial figure. He led his army twice to successfully resist Zhuge Liang&#39;s Northern Expedition and expedition to pacify Liaodong, which laid the foundation for the subsequent unification of the Three Kingdoms. However, because of his monopoly of power, his son Sima Zhao was granted the title of King of Jin, ousting the royal family of Cao Wei, and his grandson Sima Yan became emperor, thus ending Cao Wei. Wu Xiubo successfully performed Sima Yi, making this role more full and vivid. Whether it is looking like an eagle or a wolf, or facing the respect and love of a troubled wife, Wu Xiubo has shown a high level of acting skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Sima Yi became a powerful minister was inseparable from his wisdom and determination. It&#39;s a pity that Wu Xiubo brought Sima Yi to life, but that was just an artistic creation. In the more complex business world, Wu Xiubo did not have the decisiveness and insight to make a successful transition from an actor to a businessman. As a result, he reported being deceived by the joint efforts of Jin and Zhang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another major setback in Wu Xiubo’s life was his dispute with actress Chen Yulin. In September 2018, actress Chen Yulin posted on WeChat Moments that she had been in love with married actor Wu Xiubo for seven years, and also claimed that Wu Xiubo cheated on actress Zhang Zhixi at the same time. In January 2019, Chen Yulin&#39;s parents issued an open letter stating that after Chen Yulin exposed his relationship with Wu Xiubo, Wu Xiubo, his agent, and lawyer asked Chen Yulin to come forward to clarify and be willing to compensate financially. After the two parties reached an agreement, Chen Yulin went abroad to recuperate in peace. On November 4, 2018, Wu Xiubo took the initiative to let Chen Yulin return to China. The next day, Chen Yulin was arrested at the airport by Wu Xiubo on the pretext of &quot;exposing privacy and extorting money.&quot; Subsequently, Wu Xiubo issued a statement from his lawyer, stating that the content of Chen Yulin&#39;s parents&#39; open letter was untrue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Sina Entertainment’s report on February 18, 2021, the verdict in the case of Wu Xiubo being blackmailed by Chen Yulin was exposed. The verdict showed that Chen Yulin was sentenced to three years in prison and suspended for three years. Judging from the court&#39;s judgment, the fact that Chen Yulin blackmailed Wu Xiubo was established. Wu Xiubo was extorted over and over again, so he called the police because he couldn&#39;t bear it. After calling the police, he did not act harshly, otherwise it would not be a matter of probation. But Wu Xiubo&#39;s acting career also failed to recover. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly in the emotional entanglement with multiple women, Sima Yi, played by Wu Xiubo, knows how to hide his clumsiness and reveal his cleverness, and is soft-hearted towards the concubine Bai Lingjun given by Cao Pi and his wife Zhang Chunhua in the play. Respect the virtuous wife. But in reality, Wu was manipulated by Chen Yulin, ruining his reputation and losing money. It can be seen that the actor&#39;s performance is not equivalent to his behavior as a person. This may also be the illusion of many successful people, including celebrities. Acting as a person does not mean becoming that person; success in the acting career does not mean being able to be as good as a fish in water in other fields, but it exposes emotional intelligence, financial Shortcomings in business and other aspects eventually led to catastrophe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>