<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[网购二手“人脉”真的靠谱吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260873]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[不在职业资格目录中的“律师经纪人”，3860元拿证]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260871]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lawyers and brokers&quot; have appeared in many lawsuits related to contract disputes. (People Visual courtesy)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Lawyers and brokers&quot; appear in many lawsuits related to contract disputes. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 14, 2023, a recommendation letter issued by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association was circulated in the legal community. The letter showed that the association recommended a &quot;lawyer broker&quot; to the Haicheng City People&#39;s Court as a litigation agent in a loan dispute case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the letters of recommendation were made public, many lawyers posted on social media to express concerns that lawyer brokers might corrupt the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lawyer broker&quot; is not the first time that &quot;lawyer broker&quot; has appeared. With this keyword, 27 civil and enforcement cases can be retrieved on the Judgment Document Network. Among them, 24 cases in which lawyers and brokers acted as litigation agents were heard by courts at all levels in Liaoning Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is certain that lawyer brokerage should be a job type &quot;created&quot; by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association. The association recommends others as litigation attorneys in the name of social groups. However, relevant legal persons pointed out that the operations of the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association violated relevant legal regulations, and there are no occupations related to &quot;lawyer brokerage&quot; in the national professional qualification catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After this matter was fermented in the legal community, the local lawyers association issued a reminder: Lawyers discovered the problem of &quot;lawyer agents&quot; and &quot;legal agents&quot; when performing their duties. You should raise objections to the case-handling agency where you are located, and do not participate in the operations of relevant companies or institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;For each case represented, 500 yuan is required to be paid to the association&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;In past cases, &quot;lawyer brokers&quot; mainly appeared in insurance disputes, contract disputes, and private lending disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a motor vehicle traffic accident liability dispute ruled by the Yuhong District People&#39;s Court of Shenyang City in March 2023, Xiao drove a passenger car and rode an electric bicycle and ran a red light. Yang Mou collided, causing Yang to be injured. Yang then sued Xiao and the two insurance companies that Xiao insured, demanding various compensations totaling about 250,000 yuan. Both of Yang&#39;s litigation attorneys are &quot;lawyers and agents.&quot; In the end, the Shenyang Yuhong District Court ordered the insurance company to pay compensation of about 120,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a contract dispute with the case number (2022) Liao 14 Min Zhong No. 1093, Yang and Liu signed a tableware factory transfer agreement, stipulating that Yang A certain person paid the transfer fee of RMB 170,000 in installments, but after the first payment period expired, Yang did not pay as agreed. Liu then sued Yang to demand performance of the contract and payment of liquidated damages, totaling approximately 200,000 yuan. Yang lost the case and appealed to the Huludao Intermediate People&#39;s Court, entrusting a &quot;lawyer agent&quot; to serve as his litigation agent. The Huludao Intermediate People&#39;s Court did not support Yang&#39;s appeal, and the second instance upheld the original verdict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The similarity between these cases is that the &quot;lawyers and brokers&quot; who represent the cases come from the same social organization: the Lawyers and Brokers Special Committee of the Liaoning Brokers Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The National Social Organization Credit Information Disclosure Platform shows that the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association was registered and established in 2007. Its supervisory unit is the Liaoning Provincial Supply and Marketing Cooperative Federation, and its business scope In order to guide the work of the brokerage industry in the province, organize broker business training and provide legal, policy, information consulting services, etc. to brokers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Special Committee for Lawyers and Brokers is a subsidiary organization of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association. The association stated in the &quot;Instructions for the Liaoning Provincial Broker Qualification Certificate&quot; that, Possessing the Liaoning Provincial Broker Qualification Certificate can solve the problem of agency litigation qualification: you only need to pay 3,860 yuan once, and you can obtain the certificate after training and examination. &quot;You can pass the test without a legal basis.&quot; After that, you can act as an agent in civil litigation in Liaoning Province. cases, and engage in related activities such as appearing in court to respond to lawsuits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, those who have obtained the broker qualification certificate need to pay 500 yuan to the association to issue a recommendation letter for each case they represent. In addition, the broker&#39;s qualification certificate needs to be inspected every year, and the fee is 50 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Obviously different from citizen agents&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lawyer broker The events have once again put citizen agency in the spotlight. However, attorney-broker representation cases initiated by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association are significantly different from normal citizen representation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the amendment of the Civil Procedure Law in 2012, the law allowed three categories of citizens to represent civil litigation cases: close relatives of the parties, relevant social groups or employees of the unit where they work. persons; other citizens entrusted by the parties concerned and approved by the People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Zhiwei, deputy director of the Supreme People&#39;s Court Applied Law Research Base of Southwest University of Political Science and Law, said that the quality of citizen agency services is poor, fees are irregular, and it is easy to breed judicial rent-seeking, Regarding issues such as bribing judges, when the Civil Procedure Law was revised in 2012, &quot;other citizens permitted by the court&quot; were deleted, and the scope of citizens as entrusted litigation agents was limited to two categories: close relatives or staff of the parties; communities where the parties are located, Citizens recommended by units and relevant social groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Further requirements for community recommendation can be found in the interpretation of the Supreme People&#39;s Court on the application of the Civil Procedure Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It stipulates that if relevant social groups recommend citizens to serve as litigation agents, the groups should be non-profit legal persons registered and established in accordance with the law. The principal shall be a member of a social group, or the domicile of one of the parties shall be in the area of ​​activity of the social group. In addition, the recommended person should also be the person in charge of the society or a staff member who has a labor relationship with the society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with relevant regulations, Wu Zhiwei believes that strictly speaking, the behavior of the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association violates the provisions of Article 87 of the Judicial Interpretation, &quot;These people do not Qualified to act as an agent in legal matters.&quot; The agency affairs must fall within the business scope specified in the articles of association of the social group. The business scope of the broker association is generally related to brokers. However, judging from the currently public judgment documents, the client in the case is not Brokers, &quot;If brokers have relevant civil disputes, they act as litigation agents, which is in compliance with the regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another question is whether social groups can provide paid services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As early as 1993, the Ministry of Justice issued the &quot;Reply on Individual Citizens Not to Engage in Paid Legal Services Without Approval&quot; which explicitly required that citizen agents No remuneration can be collected. According to relevant regulations, travel expenses in citizen representation can be reimbursed by the parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But lawyers and brokers obviously charge fees. On November 14, 2023, the verdict of a contract dispute in Liaoning Province was circulated in the lawyer community: a lawyer and agent was sued by the client for failing to perform his obligation to appear in court in a previous divorce lawsuit, and requested the return of 5,000 yuan in legal services. fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Tips for Social Organizations to Carry out Legal Service Activities&quot; issued by the Social Organization Administration Bureau of the Liaoning Provincial Department of Civil Affairs on March 22, 2023 has mentioned that individual Social organizations illegally recommend citizens to act as agents in lawsuits and seek unfair economic benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This reminder sheet mentions that in accordance with relevant regulations, law-related social organizations strictly implement a management system with dual responsibilities between the registration management agency and the business supervisory unit. Social organizations shall carry out activities in accordance with the purposes and business scope stipulated in their articles of association and shall not engage in for-profit business activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Not in the National Vocational Qualification Catalog&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although Liaoning Province The Brokers Association has issued lawyer broker qualification certificates to many people, but the profession of &quot;lawyer broker&quot; is not included in the &quot;National Vocational Qualification Catalog&quot; announced by the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security in 2021. The professional qualifications stipulated in this catalog all specify the implementing departments or units, and require that no other institution or unit can set up professional qualifications for implementation on its own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend called Chen Wencheng, president of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association, on related issues. He first stated that he could only undertake work in Liaoning Province. However, he later stated that he currently does not directly engage in civil litigation, nor does he engage in lawyer-broker-related business. As of press time, the association’s official website is no longer displayed properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 16, Southern Weekend reporters called the Liaoning Provincial Department of Justice several times. The operator said they did not know anything about &quot;lawyers and brokers&quot; and that they could consult the local authorities for specific information. Lawyers Association. Southern Weekend reporters called the Liaoning Provincial Lawyers Association several times but received no reply as of press time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to upstream news reports, relevant staff of the Liaoning Provincial Department of Civil Affairs responded that they would investigate the situation related to the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, the Beijing Tongzhou District Lawyers Association issued a reminder that if lawyers discover problems with &quot;lawyer agents&quot; and &quot;legal agents&quot; when performing their duties, , you should raise objections to the case-handling agency where you are located, and do not participate in the operations of &quot;legal brokers&quot;, &quot;lawyer brokers&quot; and other related companies and institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Liaoning Province, Fushun Civil Affairs Bureau, Tieling Civil Affairs Bureau and other agencies have issued similar reminders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国人的家当]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2003, I have been shooting the &quot;Inheritance&quot; series 20 years, a total of 148 works. I moved a family&#39;s belongings stored in different spaces into the same space and posed for photos with their owners, most of which were taken outdoors with the home as the backdrop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;90% of my past works were shot in China. It was a period of rapid economic development and modernization and globalization in China. I used this special Recorded by posing, the real internal space is briefly exposed in the external space, combined with the changes in the current environment, urban expansion, technological development, and changes in people&#39;s lifestyles, to create a dynamic social picture with static documentary . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, I started photographing American families. Home is the smallest unit that makes up society, and many such units make up the entire society. I continue to use the &quot;Household Possessions&quot; series to reflect the internal structure and diversity of contemporary American society. I have observed that the basic material living standards of American families, regardless of urban or rural areas, are not much different, so I pay more attention to showing their spiritual attributes. I spend a long time preparing for each photo, learning the characters’ stories in advance, visiting their rooms, thinking about the purpose of the shoot, and carefully selecting items for display. The choice of family covers both native Americans and immigrants who miss their hometown, as well as concepts about love, career, identity and gender, and the passage of time. The objects in each picture have been carefully arranged, using materials to reflect spiritual life. I moved these spiritual items in space and placed them in the same picture to visually enhance the common scenes. , highlighting the current living conditions, beliefs and emotional memories of this family or individual, and using a photo to outline a combination of reality and the spiritual world. Readers can directly think through the photos and their stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thank you so much to the families who were willing to face my camera, show off their possessions, and share their stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Whitney Jensen August 2022&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 16/cbb711c0c3.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/cbb711c0c3.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Whitney Jensen August 2022&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Whitney Jensen, 36 years old. She was a very cheerful and enthusiastic woman who was born and raised in Galesburg, Illinois, USA. She traveled to Iowa, fell in love and got married while traveling, and worked in the hospitality industry for many years. When the marriage ended and the coronavirus pandemic hit, she moved to Peoria, found work as a photographer, and was profiled in magazines while taking pictures in the park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She currently works as a salesperson in a BMW store. She also enjoys interior design and creates small art installations of her own. In addition to her job at the BMW store, she has other part-time jobs, including helping out at a non-profit organization and performing poetry readings every Thursday night at the Contemporary Arts Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many of Whitney&#39;s belongings come from family members, such as her grandma&#39;s antique box and her cousin&#39;s old sofa who was shot. She is full of affection for these items and is closely related to her. A friend who she grew up with gave her an owl necklace with her first month&#39;s salary, and she has been collecting all kinds of owls ever since. Her name Whitney itself means wise owl, which was the name given to her by her aunt. She was born during the era when singer Whitney Houston was most popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;George, the Shoeshine Man February 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/bef1b74cca.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/bef1b74cca.JPG &quot; data-key=&quot;258479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;George, the Shoeshine Man February 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;George Manias, 92, celebrated his 76th working anniversary with friends, family and customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He has worked for U.S. Presidents Gerald Ford, Ronald Reagan, George W. Bush, Bill Clinton, Barack Obama and Joe Biden, every Illinois governor since 1952, every Peoria mayor since 1957 and many celebrities, diplomats and businessmen have polished their shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1931, George was born in Peoria, Illinois, USA. His parents were Greek immigrants. When he was four, he returned to his parents&#39; native island of Crete, which the Nazis had occupied. George was captured and forced to carry water for the Germans barefoot and starve. After World War II, George and his family returned to Peoria in 1946 penniless. At the age of 15, George began working as a shoeshine boy to earn money to help his family. Through hard work, George used the money he saved to buy a store named &quot;George&#39;s Shoe Shine and Hat Shop.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;George won many honors and medals, and his decades of hard work were praised by visitors from around the world. George treated everyone equally, and treated shoes regardless of whether they were high or low. He rubbed shoe polish on the leather with his bare hands. As for other secrets, he thought it was too early to reveal them now. Every January 1st, George would write the year on a brick for good luck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now he works four hours a day, five days a week, and his 86-year-old brother Manny accompanies him every day. He considers the chairs in this room to be his most important possession; it is a place where he meets people and unites the community. In addition to his shoe polishing tools, there are photos of him with six U.S. presidents and dignitaries. George never married. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Colleen Johnson June 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 5d4803a8f6.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/5d4803a8f6.JPG&quot; data- key=&quot;258480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Colleen Johnson June 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;Colleen, 58 years old, her husband passed away due to illness a few years ago and currently lives alone. She works as the director of development for a software, website design and networking company in downtown Peoria. She was often active in events commemorating historical events, particularly the abolitionist movement and the Civil War, and she spoke on behalf of racial equality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Colleen loves old furniture and heirloom items, some of which are Asian antiques from her grandmother&#39;s collection. She loved bringing nature into the house and collected art and decorations mostly related to plants and animals. Her decorations are often paired, with lotus, leaves, and bird elements recurring, and the green plants and flowers she raises are also often paired. She likes to keep and recall beautiful things. Among these souvenirs are the dolls handmade by her grandmother, the quilts made by her mother, and the shirts of her late husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Colleen is a mother and grandmother in life. Her son and daughter-in-law live in another city 90 minutes away. Their daughter is 3 years old. There is also a son on the way. Colleen has an adorable Yorkshire terrier named Toto who enjoys the joy of a new life. Colleen enjoys walking and exercising by the river and participating in sailboat racing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She has just started a new relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Prasanna Jeer 2023-4&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 536232ce15.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/536232ce15.JPG&quot; data- key=&quot;258481&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Prasanna Jeer April 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Prasana Gill and his wife Lavanya are from Chennai, South India. After completing his education and working in India for several years, he came to India 13 years ago with many dreams and hopes. U.S. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Prasana is an IT employee who works for Caterpillar. He dances every day after work. Dance carries his passion and dreams. He founded two dance schools in his spare time, teaching traditional Indian dance and Bollywood dance. In the past seven years, he has had more than 100 students. Prasanna and his students have become the centerpiece of major festivals in Peoria. As a mainstay, they also perform voluntarily for charity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some of Prasanna’s dance items were brought from India, and some were handmade by them. Their daughters, Oviya and Iniya, learned to dance at an early age, and dance was an integral part of this Indian family&#39;s life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Prasana said that he has realized his dream in the United States and is grateful to the people who gave him the opportunity. He is willing to use his own strength to repay the community and use dance to People connect, share joy, share love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Alexander Martin May 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f7e76b5835 .JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f7e76b5835.JPG&quot; data-key =&quot;258482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Alexander Martin May 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;Alexander Martin is an artist, performer, educator, and community advocate. Born and raised in the Appalachian Mountains of West Virginia, she moved to Illinois about 9 years ago to pursue a graduate degree and has lived here ever since. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She strives to exist authentically, powerfully and joyfully in this space, and her works give her such a platform. It also allows her to share personal narratives and stories of her community and celebrate their existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This home is the first house she has ever owned and is a very important space to her. She wanted the house to be a refuge, a safe space to exist, a space of joy, a sacred place of relaxation and happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fashion and clothing play an important role in her life. From performance outfits to everyday wear, she dresses and embellishes with meaning, and it&#39;s important to her to have a variety of items to create her looks. It’s her way of expressing and living authentically every day. She truly believes that being an artist is not just about the work you create, but also about how you live your life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Meng Li &amp;amp; Chunhui Pan April 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/d4a15b82ec.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/d4a15b82ec .JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meng Li &amp;amp; Chunhui Pan April 2023 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pan Chunhui studied abroad after graduating from Peking University, and stayed in the United States to work after graduating with a doctorate. He is a very representative student who was one of the top Chinese students to study abroad. He has been working for Caterpillar, a Fortune 500 company, and has lived in the United States for 31 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The hostess Li Meng also had a similar experience. After getting married, she gave up her nine-to-five job, but spent a lot of time as a volunteer, and was especially keen on publicity. Chinese culture. She is a board member of Global Fest and the person in charge of the Chinese booth, and she also appeared in the Chinese Spring Festival Gala performances. Much of the furniture, home furnishings and decorations were brought over from China and stayed with them for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The calligraphy work &quot;Home&quot; they held in their hands was made with their parents when they got married. Each of them wrote one or two strokes with a brush to form This &quot;home&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Burt Raabe &amp; Lisa Raabe April 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/16/61ddc6fa3c.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/61ddc6fa3c.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bert and Lisa Rabe (Burt Raabe &amp;amp; Lisa Raabe) April 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Burt and Lisa Raabe have been married for 20 years and have lived in this house 10 years. Lisa grew up in northwestern Pennsylvania and graduated from the Art Institute of Chicago. She holds a master&#39;s degree in art therapy from Illinois State University and has been involved in counseling for 15 years, as well as being a yoga teacher. She is now a full-time artist and holds an MFA from Bradley University. Her work has been exhibited throughout the Midwest and she has received several awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bert&#39;s great-grandfather came to the United States from Germany to farm in 1867. He grew up in Walnut City, Illinois, and graduated from Bradley University in 1968. , served in the Peace Corps in India as a welder, consultant and mentor. He now writes poetry and has published two books of poetry, several of which have also been published in magazines. Bert and Lisa enjoyed traveling and made many trips to India. In the United States, they love Chicago, Washington, D.C., and Myrtle Beach. They prefer taking trains to flying or driving. Many of the items in the photos are materials Lisa used for her artwork; there are also items from both homes and second-hand stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mae &amp;amp; Jonathan Wright June 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/4913f98a0a.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4913f98a0a .JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258485&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mae &amp;amp; Jonathan Wright June 2023 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;May is the executive director of the Central Illinois Arts Partnership and the public history coordinator and affiliated faculty member at Bradley University. She received her master&#39;s and doctoral degrees in theology from the University of Edinburgh in Scotland, where she studied changes in ancient Greek religious manuscripts over time. She returned to Peoria, Illinois, in 2013, and subsequently fell in love with and married Jonathan. Jonathan is a writer, editor, communications expert, vinyl DJ, and veteran of the Peoria music scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Jonathan owns more than 10,000 vinyl records; May collects art from local artists; and they both have extensive book collections. Jonathan reads mostly nonfiction. In the early years of their relationship, May was more oriented towards academic/ancient Greek books, and religious studies, but in recent years she has begun immersing herself in novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They have three cats named Luna, Hermione and Frega, but the larger family is the community. They spend a lot of time doing volunteer work. May is a member of the Central Illinois Women&#39;s Foundation and the City of Peoria&#39;s Public Art Advisory Committee, as well as a member of the Central Illinois Animal Welfare Grants Committee. Jonathan serves on the steering committees of the Peoria Symphony, the Central Illinois Jazz Society, the Turner Center for Entrepreneurship Advisory Council at Bradley University, and the Peoria City/County Racial Justice and Equity Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Their house tells the story of their time as a couple. It was an old house built in 1913 and needed a lot of maintenance when they purchased it. Jonathan and May gradually transformed it into a beautiful space that they never wanted to leave. The tree in the front yard was planted by them as a couple and has grown with their marriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Erica Pamson May 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/e6cf25f6a1.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/e6cf25f6a1.JPG &quot; data-key=&quot;258486&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Erica Pamson May 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Erica, 29, just completed her BA in Art Therapy at Millikin University in Decatur, IL, and will be attending Lesley University in Cambridge, MA Graduate programs in healing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She is also a circus juggler, visual artist, and performance artist. On stage she is known by the name Hexli. She performs throughout the United States and her work combines different types of performance arts, including butoh, juggling, fire dance, ritual bodywork, and live painting. The &quot;Hexli&quot; tapestry is her personal vaudeville flag, a hand-sewn gift from her friend and well-known actor The Enigma, who also gave her the stage name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She has lived in this apartment for two years. Her home contains many performance costumes and props, as well as completed and in-progress paintings. This home was her first place that was truly her own, and she felt extremely grateful for the opportunity to grow and create in this space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Neng Wang &amp;amp; Lucy Feng April 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/6ba90c1112.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6ba90c1112. JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258487&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Neng Wang &amp;amp; Lucy Feng April 2023&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Neng and Feng Luxi are a pair of first-generation immigrants born in the 1980s from mainland China. I have been in the United States for more than ten years, and I have gone through many obstacles all the way, first studying and then working, and moving several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The two met through church activities in different cities, fell in love and got married, and now live in the small town of Peoria, Illinois. People also accumulate some belongings of their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Kirk Perry &amp;amp; Barbie Perry May 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/16/a7a5fc9eb1.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/a7a5fc9eb1.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kirk Perry and Barbie Perry Perry &amp;amp; Barbie Perry) May 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Barbie was born into a white Midwestern family. Her parents both experienced the Great Depression. Her father was a German prisoner of war for 18 months during World War II, and the war had a devastating impact on him and the entire family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Barbie experienced domestic violence, mental illness, drug and alcohol problems, and was hospitalized multiple times for suicidal ideation. The lack of structure in her life and inability to seek help led to a difficult life throughout her childhood and into her twenties. She gave birth to her daughter Stephanie and was a single mother for 13 years. My daughter has had 15 surgeries since she was 1 year old. The birth of her daughter became a turning point in Barbie&#39;s life, and she began to save herself through various therapies. She was able to finish school and find work, working in a variety of jobs including ice cream server, retail salesperson, waitress and more. This difficult life ended when Barbie met Kirk Perry in 1997 and married him a year later. Since then, with love and a patient ear, Barbie has lived a beautiful, fulfilling, and loving life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Kirk Perry is a retired criminal intelligence analyst who worked for the Illinois State Police. He holds an associate&#39;s degree in criminal justice, a bachelor&#39;s degree in administrative justice and a juris doctorate. In his career of more than thirty years, he not only solved many criminal cases and sent many bad guys to prison. He fell in love with books at the age of six and never stopped reading. He has a collection of over 10,000 comic books. Barbie has been making art since 2015, all about feminism, while Kirk has written three novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the couple, the Barbie collection is a testament to their love. During their marriage, Barbie and Kirk have had seven dogs, with Biscuit being their current favorite. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Brandie Centi-Fislar August 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/16/9294743f69.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/9294743f69.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258489&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brandie Sendy-Fislar Centi-Fislar) August 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Brandy Centi-Fislar, 31, from Clearfield, Pennsylvania, High School Class of 2010 After graduation, she enrolled at Lincoln College in Lincoln, Illinois, on swimming and soccer scholarships. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2012, she earned an associate degree in art and transferred to Illinois State University in Normal, IL to begin her art studies. She began with an art education and later switched professions to glassblowing. At the same time, she began dating her now-husband. Over the next 10 years, she and her husband completed their bachelor&#39;s degrees together and worked multiple jobs in an effort to stay financially stable. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After a lot of good times and some bad times, they now have a dream house filled with their fur babies (three dog and two cats) to enjoy life with less stress. She still blows glass full-time and enjoys being creative every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“从深度和广度推动中新合作” | 亚太群英荟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260859]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, on November 1, 2023, Assistant Minister of Foreign Affairs Nong Rong and the Ministry of Trade and Industry of Singapore Permanent Secretary Lin Mingliang held the China-Singapore Bilateral Cooperation Mechanism Senior Officials&#39; Meeting via video link. In March this year, Singaporean Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong visited China, and China-Singapore relations were upgraded to a comprehensive, high-quality, forward-looking partnership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking the opportunity to take China-Singapore cooperation to a new level, Southern Weekend researchers interviewed Professor Liu Hong, Associate Vice President of Nanyang Technological University in Singapore. As an alumnus of Xiamen University and Fudan University, Liu Hong has studied and worked in many countries in Asia, North America, and Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Hong said that in the past ten years or so, he has noticed from his teaching, research and management work that the relationship between China and Singapore is showing several characteristics: all-round, advancing with the times and high quality. . From the early days of China learning from Singapore, it has changed into a two-way trend of mutual learning and mutual reference. As China-Singapore relations enter a new stage of development, Nanyang Technological University is also constantly improving the level of cooperation projects to further promote the friendship and cooperation between Singapore and China in terms of depth and breadth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Liu Hong&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/cac4375609.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1544&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/cac4375609.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Photo by Liu Hong&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Lou Xiaoxi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;When you go to China, seeing it once is better than hearing it a hundred times&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have studied and worked in universities in many countries around the world, and you feel that Chinese students are similar to students from other countries. What are its characteristics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The general characteristic of students in mainland China is that they are very diligent and studious. With more than 10 million college students graduating every year, competition is fierce. Among the college students from various countries that I have come into contact with, Chinese students can be said to be leading in terms of diligence and studiousness. On the one hand, this is because the Chinese nation has a tradition of loving learning, but on the other hand, it is also because social competition is becoming increasingly fierce, so everyone must stand out. Employment for college students is a big challenge. Chinese students are very concerned about the development of the world situation and have a strong desire to study abroad. I personally studied in the Netherlands and the United States, and then worked in Singapore and the United Kingdom. I stayed at Kyoto University and Osaka University in Japan for almost two years, and I have many personal experiences. I think Chinese students are very diligent and studious. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think are the differences between the Eastern and Western higher education systems? Same? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have studied in the Netherlands for more than a year and in the United States for more than five years. Western countries have a tradition of pursuing knowledge. It does not take test scores as the main goal, but a more divergent and diverse goal. Students choose some subjects based on their own interests, so they can look at some issues from multiple perspectives. However, I think Western education has a major flaw - a lack of understanding of developing countries, including China. Recently, some scholars have analyzed that in international political economics textbooks and related papers in the 2010s, China only accounted for less than 11%, which is a very small proportion; but China is now the second largest economy in the world. , its total GDP is close to about 20% of the world&#39;s, which shows that there is a lack of knowledge about China in university textbooks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to let the West better understand China through education ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;During my tenure in the UK, I organized several times for hundreds of college students from different universities across the UK to go to China for two to three weeks. After Zhou’s study tour and immersion, I named this project “Experience a Dynamic China”. Many British people&#39;s understanding of China is very lacking and outdated, and most of it is what they read in books. We organize them to travel to different cities such as Beijing, Shanghai, Nanjing, Guangzhou, and Jinan, and to different places (including rural areas), allowing them to experience a constantly changing and developing China. I think that in international education and exchanges, we can have more Chinese stories and more Chinese voices. One of the sources is to let foreigners experience it for themselves. The feedback I received from the participants of these immersion activities was that after many people returned home, they said that their impressions of China had almost undergone earth-shaking changes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Scientific research results landed in the Greater Bay Area&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;How does Nanyang Technological University promote cooperation in education between China and Singapore in the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Greater Bay Area is now a region with the greatest development potential in China. Singapore and China have cooperated to establish the Sino-Singapore Guangzhou Knowledge City. Our university has jointly established the Sino-Singapore International Joint Research Institute with the Knowledge City and South China University of Technology, and the progress is very good. In addition to integrating industry, academia and research, the Knowledge City also arranged for some government officials to come to us for training. I am currently leading a research project on business environment improvement and enhancement commissioned by Guangzhou Development Zone and China-Singapore Knowledge City. We hope that when talking about China&#39;s development, we do not just talk about it on paper, but rather have an understanding of China&#39;s latest development, and then connect China&#39;s development with the development of the world. In this process, what useful experiences can Singapore provide? How can we make progress together? In fact, the purpose of our project is to promote friendly relations between Singapore and China, and ASEAN and China. This big goal is the direction that my colleagues and I work together. This is also the main goal of the new president of Nanyang Technological University, Professor Ho Tak Wa, who recently proposed to create a &quot;Nanyang Technological University Singapore-China Knowledge Hub&quot;. Both the Singaporean government and Nanyang Technological University are paying great attention to and attaching great importance to the development of the Greater Bay Area. For example, the Sino-Singapore Guangzhou Knowledge City I just mentioned has become a national-level project between China and Singapore, relying on and benefiting from it. Against the background of the rapid development of the Greater Bay Area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As the Associate Vice-President of Nanyang Technological University, I have a lot of thoughts on the future What are the plans for cooperation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Whether it is in Guangzhou, Hong Kong, or Shenzhen, we have a lot of cooperation now and in the future. These cooperations not only focus on In cultivating talents, we also pay special attention to the integration of industry, academia and research. The relationship between New Zealand and China is more about learning from each other and advancing with the times. Our main purpose is to transform the latest scientific research results from around the world, especially Singapore, into the fertile soil of the Greater Bay Area, make them take root, sprout and promote them. This is why we set up an international joint research institute in Guangzhou, and why our cooperation with Shenzhen focuses on innovation. Singapore and Shenzhen focus on cooperating to build a series of new developments such as smart cities and digital economy. Shenzhen leads not only China but also the world in innovation. We have been cooperating a lot with universities in the Greater Bay Area. Student exchanges and scientific research cooperation with universities in Hong Kong will also be further deepened. In the future, our Nanyang Graduate School of Public Administration may further increase talent training in places such as Guangzhou and Shenzhen. Shenzhen is paying more and more attention to ASEAN. Of course, ASEAN can also use the platform of Shenzhen or Guangdong to further develop. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the field of public governance, Singapore and China have What experiences can be learned from each other? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Our research pays special attention to public governance in Asia. Now, some theories, experiences and models of global public governance are mainly based on Western experience. We hope to explore the experiences of these countries through in-depth analysis of the development of Singapore, China, and other ASEAN countries, and analyze how they contribute to global public governance theory and practice. We have many research projects, including focusing on the “One Belt and One Road” as a new model of cross-border governance, focusing on mutual learning and reference between Asian and African countries, and also including the “Belt and Road” context in which Chinese enterprises “ Going global&quot; and different models of cooperation with other countries are several research focuses of myself and our school. We hope to continue to maintain close contact with the Chinese government, state-owned enterprises or universities in the future. As China-Singapore relations enter a new stage of development, we are constantly improving the level of projects and further promoting the friendly cooperation between Singapore and China in terms of depth and breadth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Essence of Civilized Dialogue&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;What do you think of the “One Belt, One Road” initiative? What are the key directions for future development? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This year marks the 10th anniversary of the “Belt and Road” initiative, which is a very important development milestone. In the past few months, I have been invited to give no fewer than 10 speeches on the Belt and Road Initiative. It can be seen that different countries in the world are very concerned about the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative, although their starting points are different. The &quot;five links&quot; in the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative include people-to-people connectivity and policy communication, which are two aspects that our college and I are very concerned about. I regard the people-to-people bonds and policy communication in the &quot;five links&quot; as a piece of software; infrastructure construction, trade, and investment are hardware. Only when hardware and software are organically combined can they play their best roles. For future development, on the one hand, we must think about how to further improve the quality and influence of the “One Belt, One Road” project based on the achievements made in the past 10 years, including focusing on a series of topics such as digital economy, green development, and public health. It will become the focus of the future development of “One Belt, One Road”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now the young generation is &quot;going out&quot; in Chinese culture What role can it play? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Hong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Chinese culture &quot;going out&quot; to engage in civilized dialogue requires us to further develop it. In this process, young people from China, as well as Chinese state-owned enterprises, Chinese scientific researchers, university teachers, etc., all played important roles. I think that in terms of future development, it is very important to grasp the essence of Chinese cultural development, including some characteristics of Chinese cultural traditions: being upright but not old-fashioned, respecting the past but not retrospecting. First of all, you must understand your own culture, have your own cultural roots, and then start a dialogue with other cultures. Secondly, we still need to treat other cultures with an attitude of equality, tolerance, openness and respect. In terms of culture, every country&#39;s culture has its own characteristics and advantages, which are the product of different countries&#39; own environments. We should adopt an attitude of understanding and respect and cannot say that China does this, why don&#39;t you this way? Only by understanding and communicating can we truly &quot;go global&quot; with our culture. Third, we must still pay attention to innovation. Whether it is Chinese culture or the culture of other countries, it must reflect the development characteristics of the new era, including the fourth industrial revolution we are now in, an era of parallel globalization and anti-globalization. , global geopolitics has also undergone many changes. Under such circumstances, we should look at creative transformations of Chinese culture and world culture to achieve more effective dialogue. The &quot;Global Development Initiative&quot; and &quot;Global Civilization Initiative&quot; proposed by the Chinese government have provided Chinese wisdom for the development of the world. Chinese wisdom has very profound connotations, but in terms of communication and exchange methods, we still have more room for efforts to let countries around the world understand the essence of Chinese culture. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一中学发生拥挤踩踏事件：改善硬件设施与提高管理水平当双管齐下丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260863]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A campus accident involving casualties touched people&#39;s hearts. On November 14, 2023, the People&#39;s Government of Wuzhi County, Henan Province reported a casualty incident in a local middle school: At about 10 a.m. on November 13, some boys in the first and second grades of Xinghua Middle School in Wuzhi County went to the toilet between midterm exams. At that time, he fell and was injured due to crowding going up and down the stairs. The students involved were immediately sent to the hospital for examination and treatment. Currently, one student died after all-out efforts to rescue him failed, one seriously injured student is being treated with all-out efforts, and four students with minor injuries are hospitalized for observation and treatment and will be discharged in the near future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Beijing News&quot; report, the details of the incident revealed by insiders are: &quot;The toilets in Xinghua Middle School are on two floors. The men&#39;s toilets have to be climbed up by stairs. The stair railings are all intact. I don&#39;t know. Why did a stampede happen?&quot; According to pictures of the school posted online, there were no toilets in the teaching building of the school where the incident occurred. Students had to go down to the teaching building first and then take the stairs upstairs to use the toilet. The tragedy also happened while going up and down the stairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the accident, many schools across the country required teachers on duty to be arranged on each floor during class breaks. Some media have called for more &quot;break time&quot; or &quot;examination time&quot; to allow students more time to go to the toilet. Some netizens believe that schools should improve hardware facilities and install toilets on every floor of the teaching building. In addition to these obvious problems, this accident is still worthy of analysis in terms of responsibility distribution and preventive measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the nature of the accident. Media reports all reported the accident as a &quot;stampede&quot;, but the wording in the report was &quot;crowding and falling.&quot; So, what was the nature of the accident? This deserves further investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If what &quot;informed people&quot; said about &quot;the stair railings are intact&quot; and what netizens revealed about &quot;the toilets are in another building&quot; are true, then the accident may have occurred during the ten minutes between exams. The students first went down to the teaching building, and then to the &quot;toilet building&quot; next door. The high-density flow of people caused congestion and falls while going up and down the stairs, which ultimately led to the tragedy of one death and five injuries. The students who died unfortunately should have died from one of the following possibilities: first, suffocation caused by high-density crowds; second, falling from a high place due to gravity; third, being trampled after falling due to crowding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second issue is the cause of the accident and the attribution of responsibility. After the accident, insufficient number of toilets and insufficient time between exams were two major objective causes identified by netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A midterm exam usually takes about two hours, at least three times the length of a normal class, which will greatly increase the frequency of bathroom breaks. Candidates need to go to the toilet to relax between exams, which will undoubtedly further increase the frequency of going to the toilet. If you add in the factors of greater psychological pressure on candidates and more hurry and panic when going to and from the toilet, the superposition of multiple variables is enough to amplify the safety risk: the common two-hour exam time and the common nervousness increase the group resonance. The probability of occurrence also increases the probability of accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The school’s hardware facilities could not be changed on the day of the incident, and the exam time and exam time had also been determined. Then, I am afraid that the only thing the invigilator could do that day was to prevent the students from going out to use the toilet, so as to 100% eliminate any possibility of this accident. What should be asked is, who made these rules? Who is responsible for such poor hardware facilities? This is the person who should be held responsible, not the invigilator who was just enforcing the rules on the day of the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Again, how to prevent similar accidents from happening again? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not the first time that similar accidents have occurred in China. In the stampede at the No. 3 Experimental Primary School in Puyang, Henan in March 2017, students &quot;rushed down like a flood&quot; after finishing morning reading; and in the stampede at a middle school in Xuchang, Henan in November 2000, students were studying in the evening Something happened after class. Similar accidents have occurred many times across the country. The causes of these accidents are similar: the recess time is short, or the class duration is too long. As soon as the bell rings, students rush to the toilet or go out, causing stampedes due to congestion. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, only by controlling variables and prescribing the right medicine can we find a solution to prevent such accidents. It is certainly necessary for schools to install toilets in strict accordance with the &quot;Design Code for Primary and Secondary Schools&quot;. Installing diversion barriers at densely populated entrances and exits of schools is also a way. During large-scale activities such as exams, sports games, and school celebrations, it is also indispensable for the school to arrange dedicated personnel to ensure the order of the flow of people and implement staggered peak management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to upgrading hardware facilities, schools should also focus on improving software, that is, management levels. Specific to this incident, we should also ask whether the school arranged for off-peak exams that day, and whether there was a dedicated person responsible for maintaining order in the flow of people? To be more specific, did the school allow candidates to use the toilet when the exam was in progress on the day of the incident? This will also ease the stress of going to the bathroom between exams. Also, does the school provide safety education on preventing crowding and stampeding, and does it conduct corresponding safety drills? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how good the hardware facilities are, they have an approved capacity, and their redundancy has a limit. You cannot expect that everything will be fine by building more toilets, expanding the volume of the teaching building, and installing diversion barriers. Otherwise, those facilities There will be no stampede accidents in large-scale tourist attractions that are well-established. Long-term scientific management is the best guarantee to prevent problems before they occur, and its importance is by no means inferior to improving hardware facilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, schools cannot lock students in classrooms because of such incidents, and cannot make the temporary arrangement of &quot;arranging on-duty teachers on each floor between classes&quot; permanent, as this may increase the number of students. It has reduced the non-teaching burden of teachers and led to the misunderstanding that &quot;schools should have unlimited safety responsibilities for students&quot;. To improve school management, schools can also think about delegating more power and giving students more freedom out of classrooms, teaching buildings and playgrounds, so that students can practice their ability to deal with risks and learn to protect themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么有的人睡觉打着呼噜就“嘎”了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260615]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Recently, Olympic gymnastics champion Yang Wei revealed that he has respiratory problems , attracted everyone&#39;s attention. He revealed in his social updates that he could not breathe in while sleeping. This situation once lasted for 6 minutes. According to the advice given by the doctor, &quot;The once strong athlete now wears &lt; /span>;&lt;span>;On the ventilator&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In fact, Yang Wei’s symptoms are not an isolated case. Celebrities from different industries and ages have also appeared on the hot topic due to the same situation. Search. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;When US President Biden gave a speech in June this year, the media discovered that there were traces of ventilator straps on his face; In a program, Fok Qigang disclosed the fact that he suffers from insomnia disorder and moderate sleep apnea; Chen Qiaoen once underwent surgery because his throat collapsed during sleep and he could not breathe air; artist Hu Haiquan took the initiative to wear a respirator because of snoring during the program machine to sleep. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;We all know that snoring after falling asleep generally only affects the sleep of the person next to you, but unexpectedly, in some cases, Snoring may be accompanied by apnea, causing people to &quot;repeatedly suffocate&quot; in their dreams, which may even endanger their lives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/Mrxb5DiqLERFb732b6q8D5iS8yyU84GFLNAOqBZV.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/Mrxb5DiqLERFb732b6q8D5iS8yyU84GFLNAOqBZV.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258641&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Can snoring cause apnea? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Yang Wei’s condition is medically called “apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Syndrome&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;&quot;, including three types: obstructive, central, and mixed. Among them, &quot;obstructive sleep apnea hypopnea syndrome (OSAHS)&quot; is the most common, commonly known as &quot;snoring&quot;, and is mainly characterized by sleep Snoring, accompanied by breathlessness and hypoxia, may lead to sudden death in severe cases. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Of course, not all snoring will be diagnosed as apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Symptom&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, there is currently no confirmed necessary relationship between the two. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;According to the &quot;Multiple Obstructive Sleep Apnea in Adults&quot; released by the Sleep Respiratory Disorders Group of the Respiratory Disease Branch of the Chinese Medical Association in 2018 &quot;Discipline Diagnosis and Treatment Guidelines&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Guidelines&quot;), the diagnostic criteria for apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; mainly include two: the number of apnea and hypopnea events, and How often both occur. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The apnea mentioned here is almost literal. It means that the airflow disappears or is significantly weakened during breathing, while hypopnea means , refers to the reduction of respiratory volume and blood oxygen saturation below the basic level. During a 7-hour sleep period, if apnea and hypopnea recur more than 30 times, or the apnea-hypopnea index (AHI) is greater than 5 times per hour, you can be diagnosed with apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Sign&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Obstructive apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Symptom&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; (OSA) and central The difference between apnea syndrome (CSA) and apnea syndrome (CSA) is that the former is apnea caused by upper airway obstruction, and the respiratory drive function of the central nervous system is normal, which can be simply understood as oral The nose stops but the brain is fine. The latter is caused by an abnormality of the central nervous system. When the brain stops, the mouth and nose also stop. Mixed apnea syndrome (MSA) is a combination of both. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Surprisingly, apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;symptoms&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;surface It only interferes with sleep at night. In fact, this kind of sleep rhythm disorder caused by irregular breathing will cause more lasting adverse effects on daily life, such as daytime sleepiness, memory loss, and even possible psychological, Intellectual and behavioral abnormalities. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Medical experts who released the &quot;Guidelines&quot; believe that the rapid increase in weight of OSAHS patients in a short period of time may be related to hypertension, Coronary heart disease, arrhythmia, stroke, type 2 diabetes and other complications may occur. Family members of patients with the above symptoms can pay more attention. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/ilQWhKpfm6lliE77D97DPZ0enP7fLxHRjSSusvvU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/ilQWhKpfm6lliE77D97DPZ0enP7fLxHRjSSusvvU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258642&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Why is this disease easily missed&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In 2019, the academic journal &quot;Lancet-Respiratory Medicine&quot; published a paper titled &quot;Obstructive The survey report &quot;Sleep Apnea and the Global Economic Burden&quot;, based on the diagnostic criteria published by the American Academy of Sleep Medicine (AASM), compiled the prevalence data of obstructive sleep apnea from 16 countries and 17 studies. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;This report believes that the prevalence of obstructive sleep apnea has increased from 2%-4% 10 years ago to 24% Above, more than 85% of sleep apnea patients are missed. Researchers further speculated based on data that approximately 936 million adults aged 30 to 69 worldwide suffer from varying degrees of obstructive sleep apnea, with China having the largest number of affected people, followed by the United States, Brazil and India. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;When it comes to why sleep apnea is particularly easy to miss diagnosis, the author of the report believes that this may stem from everyone&#39;s concern about sleep health. Two prejudices. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;First of all, everyone is more accustomed to blaming age and stress for fatigue in daily life. &quot;As people get older, they cannot sleep well.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s normal.&quot; &quot;The KPIs at work are too heavy and I can&#39;t sleep just thinking about them.&quot; They rarely think about sleep diseases. In fact, repeated apnea during sleep can also lead to a decline in body function, leading to migraines, chronic fatigue and other diseases. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Secondly, in some traditional concepts, snoring often becomes a sign of &quot;sleeping soundly&quot;. Even if the family members notice the abnormality, They rarely interrupt and pay attention to them. To take a step back, some people&#39;s snoring is inherently irregular, and the occurrence of apnea is somewhat random, making it difficult for relatives and family members to effectively identify it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The &quot;Guidelines&quot; specifically mention that body obesity (referring to body weight exceeding 20% ​​or more of the standard body weight) may increase the risk of developing diseases. The risk of sleep apnea; the prevalence increases positively with age, more women suffer from the disease after menopause, and men have a higher prevalence than women during their reproductive years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In addition, sedentary people, long-term drinkers and smokers, and people with a family history of OSAHS are also at higher risk. disease risk. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;In the final analysis, this disease is common, but it is not easy to find. Fortunately, we can now use the power of some technology . Many domestic medical studies have confirmed that portable oximeters and mobile phone snoring analysis apps are helpful in early diagnosis and screening of OSAHS patients. Perhaps in the near future, monitoring of apnea syndrome&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Signs&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;can be as convenient and fast as monitoring body temperature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;More importantly, if you suspect that you or your family members have similar symptoms, you should go to the hospital as soon as possible and use professional equipment for diagnosis. Treatment is provided by surgery, braces, ventilators, etc. One-third of a person&#39;s life is spent in sleep. Healthy sleep is true health. I wish you all a good sleep and good health every day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[离经叛道的“禁片之王”，终于迎来大结局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260850]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;This month, the biggest event in the animation industry&lt;/span>;, the non-animated version of &quot;Attack on The ending of &quot;Giant&quot; is none other than this. The long-awaited final work finally brings an end to this epic series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/ea5a811e3e55d28ca36b543387fd4f66.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;537&quot; height=&quot;416&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/ea5a811e3e55d28ca36b543387fd4f66.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258721&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Attack on Titan&quot; is the representative work of Japanese comic artist Isayama Hajime. It has a total of 139 chapters and was serialized in comic magazines for twelve years from 2009 to 2021. In 2013, the TV animation version of &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; came out. After ten years of production, a total of four seasons were released (except for the theatrical version and special episodes). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Douban entry, the complete viewing order of the entire drama is: &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; (2013) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; Season 2 (2017) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; Season 3 (2018) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; Season 3 Part.2 (2019) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; Final Season Part.1 (2020) Part.2 (2022) → &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; The final season&amp;nbsp;the final part&amp;nbsp;the first part&amp;nbsp;the second part (2023). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/260482835e33291d29483186b6089ea3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;337&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/260482835e33291d29483186b6089ea3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258720 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The unique world view structure, bizarre background setting, incredible imagination, bloody battle scenes, and sensitive issues made this work popular as soon as it came out. attracted the attention of all walks of life. But while attracting countless viewers, it was also banned by many countries in the world due to its large scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite this, it still achieved a good rating on Douban, with Jiji scoring 9 points+, and even the least optimistic final chapter has a rating of 9.3. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/4c766315fbedf871e47850543e220dc2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;483&quot; height=&quot;439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/4c766315fbedf871e47850543e220dc2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258723&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Since the comic version has been completed in 2021, the audience already knows the ending of this work. It is worth noting that when the comic was completed, it caused huge controversy due to the plot that violated human ethics and was criticized by fans as a &quot;bad ending&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fundamental reason is that Allen, the protagonist of &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;, is suspected of &quot;matricide&quot;. With his precognitive ability, he most likely manipulated the Immaculate Titan to eat his mother, leaving a huge psychological trauma on his young self. He then joined the Survey Corps, determined to get rid of the Titan. This setting is mainly to make the whole story logical and &lt;span>; form a closed loop of cause and effect. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But whether it is based on the emotions of the characters or the emotions of the audience, this setting is difficult to accept, and there is a sense of powerlessness in trying to justify it. To paraphrase netizens, this move is tantamount to “Harry Potter manipulating Voldemort to go back in time and kill his parents”, “Batman buying a thief to go back in time and kill his parents”, “Iron Man instructing the Winter Soldier to go back and kill him” One’s own parents”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the animated version, this &quot;matricide&quot; plot was brushed aside and explained in an extremely vague manner. Because of this, it wasn&#39;t as controversial as the comic version, but it just added a bit of tragedy to Allen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/fb44a83ea8c8765afcbe894da7e5f7fa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height=&quot;389&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/fb44a83ea8c8765afcbe894da7e5f7fa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258722 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reason why &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; is hailed as&lt;/span>; a masterpiece is that it reflects reality and depicts an imaginary world with great conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story begins with an invasion of giants on Parady Island. Human beings were unable to resist the giants, so they built three high walls (Xina, Rose, and Maria) to resist the giants, in exchange for a hundred years of peace. But the terrifying giant still came. &quot;On that day, mankind finally recalled the fear of being dominated by giants, and the humiliation of being trapped in a birdcage&lt;span>;.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Eren and his friends Mikasa and Armin suffered heavy blows during the Titan invasion, and were eventually admitted to the Survey Corps to fight against the Titans together. At first, the growth path of Allen and others followed the routine of traditional hot-blooded comics. But as the plot continues to advance, the audience soon discovers its anomaly - it does not stick to the binary opposition of good and evil, but digs deeper into the complexity of human nature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reversal in the plot drives the audience and the protagonist to constantly think together and break, rebuild, and break their own thinking. Allen&#39;s life was hanging by a thread during the battle, but he unexpectedly forced out his giant power. There are also many giants hidden in the Survey Corps. The three comrades who have been with Allen through life and death not only have the power of giants, but they are also &quot;spies.&quot; I originally thought that giants were inhuman monsters, but I didn&#39;t expect that giants are also human beings. Giants have also suffered from wars and are victims of racial antagonism. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f9462227c0cb4cb5237e2357034e66a9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;693&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f9462227c0cb4cb5237e2357034e66a9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258724 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;All humans who can become giants&lt;/span>; are Eldians. They are regarded by ordinary people as &quot;descendants of demons.&quot; Two thousand years ago, the Eldians, who received the power of giants from their ancestor Ymir, became kings of the world. A hundred years ago, the Eldians were defeated by the Marais. The royal family led some people across the ocean to Parady Island and lived an isolated life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And those Eldians who stayed in other countries were reduced to slaves and lived like a concentration camp. For thousands of years, ordinary people have been deeply hostile to the Eldians and have always wanted to get rid of them. This kind of hostility led Allen to &quot;blackening&quot;, and he decided to use the sound of the earth to launch the &quot;Destruction Plan&quot; - hundreds of thousands of 60-meter-tall super-large &lt;span>; Innocent Titans ran rampant on the earth, indiscriminately Trampling all life, massacred 80% of the human population outside Parady Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The final chapter tells about the &quot;final battle&quot; after the earthquake started. At the end, Mikasa found Eren&#39;s true body under the cover of other members, then cut off Eren&#39;s head and gave him a passionate kiss. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/d6f86c8569a729a1ad946452176faf14.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/d6f86c8569a729a1ad946452176faf14.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258719 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the surface, &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;&lt;/span>; tells the story of &quot;a boy who slays dragons and eventually turns into a dragon.&quot; However, upon closer inspection, it is not that Simplicity is about sacrifice, but also about salvation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ellen&#39;s death has long been doomed. As early as the investiture ceremony, he had already predicted the future. He repeatedly tried to change his destiny, but all ended in failure. In order to break the reincarnation, let the giant&#39;s power disappear completely, and let the Eldians be treated as equals and even respected, he can only embark on an extremely lonely road. He started the roar of the earth, started the massacre, and then made his companions heroes, intending to use his own sacrifice to exchange for the peace of the Eldians. &lt;span>; As he himself said, &quot;This is to save Parady Island.&quot; The only way to win over everyone”. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What Allen did was another way of ending sorrow with war. He weighed the difference between salvation and sacrifice, and finally chose to sacrifice the whole world to save those around him. This decision transformed him from a hero into a demon. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/adcd3b5f37cd9df03705d86e6529a58d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/adcd3b5f37cd9df03705d86e6529a58d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258725 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to exploring the complexity of human nature, &lt;/span>; &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; also involves many profound propositions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, freedom. Allen has always pursued freedom. Since he was a child, he has been curious about the sea outside the wall and the other side of the sea, thinking that it is an ideal world of freedom. But in the end, he discovered that &quot;there are enemies on the other side of the sea.&quot; So-called freedom, especially absolute freedom, does not exist at all. As a result, Allen finally became a free slave until death freed him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example is the discussion on the meaning of survival. In the final chapter, Armin and Zeke have a philosophical conversation. Jike is a typical pessimist. He believes that the fate of human beings is to undergo an endless and painful reincarnation. The purpose of life is to reproduce, which is meaningless. Armin believes that the meaning of life lies in the moment and the feeling of living in the present: picking up shells at the beach, running with friends, reading at home on a rainy day, watching squirrels eating tree fruits... these may seem random. The sporadic fragments constitute a colorful chapter in human life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;These propositions give &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; a depth that ordinary hot-blooded comics do not have. Therefore, in a sense, in the past ten years, the audience has watched Allen and others grow and part ways, and at the same time, as their personal minds have matured, they have gained more perception and understanding of this work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The divisions and wars in the human world caused by issues such as wealth and poverty, race, ideology, etc., are always recurring and endless. Just like the current Israeli-Palestinian conflict, they always seem to verify the metaphors contained in Isayama Hajime&#39;s &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; again and again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the end of the story, Mikasa buried Eren under the tree where he liked to take a nap. In the future, even if the power of giants is lost, human wars will never stop. At this time, a man discovered the tree where Allen was buried. He walked in, and just like the ancestor Ymir thousands of years ago, he was about to gain the power of a giant...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This seems to tell us that as long as the fate of mankind changes over and over again, , then the tragedy will not be completely ended. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/daf3712a921d7eb60a4ae64d6f372410.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/daf3712a921d7eb60a4ae64d6f372410.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258726 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this case, is this world of constant conflicts still worth our efforts, struggle and life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This goes back to the conversation between Zeke and Armin. They are like the two sides of Sou Isayama. On the one hand, they reveal the nature of the world and point out its cruelty to us; on the other hand, they give us warmth, hope and strength, allowing us to base ourselves on the present, cherish precious moments, and live our lives well. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Perhaps, in the final analysis, everything is just a matter of choice. Will you choose to be Zeke or Armin? Or do you have other options? No matter how you want to survive in the world, it all depends on you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当WeWork不再work]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260848]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/18/JGRhwuRuCpQduncfyATYDZirEwUctBOQITGqN4gD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/JGRhwuRuCpQduncfyATYDZirEwUctBOQITGqN4gD . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258717&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;August 19, 2023, Beijing, WeWork joint shared office space&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 12th, Huang Wei, who was on his way to work, suddenly received a mass notice from the front desk - the office area will be closed from now on. Stop water supply. Soon after arriving at the company, he was told that the WeWork co-working space in Shanghai World Trade Center could no longer continue to operate, and tenants needed to move to other WeWork properties as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Wei’s start-up team has just settled in September 2023. The rent was lower than he expected, with the monthly quote for a single workstation being 1,200 yuan. When he first returned to China at the end of 2019, he learned about the market situation. The price of a WeWork near the Suzhou River for the same configuration of workstations was around 2,000 yuan. The salesman told him that if the high vacancy rate hadn&#39;t affected his business, he wouldn&#39;t have been able to sign for this location at this price. At that time, in this WeWork, the office areas with less than 5 people were quite saturated, while the offices with more than 10 people were completely vacant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;first come, first served&quot; reminder at the front desk did not allow him to hesitate. Huang Wei quickly selected an office space located one kilometer away by WeWork. When he saw the news that &quot;WeWork filed for bankruptcy protection&quot;, he had already moved into the WeWork office area in Shanghai Plaza for half a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, local time, in order to get rid of huge debts, WeWork filed for bankruptcy protection in New Jersey, USA. However, the bankruptcy filing is limited to WeWork&#39;s offices in the United States and Canada. The next day, WeWork China issued a statement stating that WeWork China had separated from WeWork at the end of 2020 and had independent operating and management capabilities as an independent brand. &quot;The major strategic restructuring decisions made by WeWork in the United States and Canada have no connection with WeWork China.&quot; .&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;WeWork, founded in New York, USA, is known as the &quot;originator of shared office.&quot; WeWork will lease commercial buildings for a long time at preferential prices, then divide them into shared office spaces after redesigning and renovating them. WeWork will provide flexible leasing contracts for freelancers, start-ups and large enterprises, etc., and earn rent differences and additional service fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, when it was first founded, the negative impact of the U.S. financial crisis was still continuing. Commercial buildings were widely idle due to the wave of business closures, a large number of companies laid off employees, and the unemployed became freelancers. WeWork, which emerged at that time, not only provided stylish decoration and flexible leasing options, but also provided free coffee drinks and organized a variety of community activities... WeWork co-founder Adam Neumann advocated &quot;space as a service&quot; and declared To create a &quot;physical social network&quot;, a &quot;world that allows people to live rather than just make a living.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/uDRbK6SD0u9ElpCRqVlC0VN5YV3jgatYqoXhjH1r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/uDRbK6SD0u9ElpCRqVlC0VN5YV3jgatYqoXhjH1r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258715&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 6, 2019, in Tokyo, Japan, SoftBank Group Chairman and President Masayoshi Son attended a press conference. SoftBank said the value of its investment in WeWork fell by nearly $4.6 billion &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;U.S. benchmark after financial crisis Interest rates have been at a low level for a long time, and capital is eager to enter the private equity market to seek higher returns. In an era when the concept of the sharing economy was highly popular, WeWork became the darling of capital and became a unicorn only four years after its establishment. In 2019, with the support of major shareholder SoftBank, WeWork&#39;s valuation soared to an astonishing US$47 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, SoftBank Group CEO Masayoshi Son called WeWork &quot;the next Alibaba.&quot; Alibaba is the most successful investment case of this &quot;unicorn hunter&quot;. In 2000, SoftBank invested US$20 million in Alibaba, which was only one year old. 14 years later, Alibaba went public, and the value of SoftBank’s shares increased approximately 2,900 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SoftBank was once the investment benchmark in the sharing economy track. Masayoshi Son advocates injecting massive amounts of capital into start-up companies to help them quickly crush competitors in scale and become a dominant brand in the market, hoping to achieve long-term profitability after gaining absolute advantages in users and the market. Uber and Didi are SoftBank’s investment cases in the sharing economy track during the same period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, half a year after WeWork reached the peak of its valuation, it fell into a long and steep decline stage. In August 2019, as the initial public offering (IPO) application was exposed, WeWork&#39;s consecutive losses triggered market concerns about the company&#39;s profitability. Neumann&#39;s financial and leadership issues have also been exposed one after another. In the same month, Uber, which had just been listed for half a year, suffered its largest loss since announcing its financial report after falling below the issue price. For a time, there was a lot of discussion about the bursting of the unicorn bubble. WeWork&#39;s plans to go public are on hold indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, Neumann resigned as CEO and new management was brought in to help restructure the company&#39;s leasing business. It wasn&#39;t until October 2021 that WeWork finally went public with a valuation of US$9 billion. However, going public is not a panacea. Instead, it has become a magnifying glass that continues to expose problems. Although WeWork has always regarded itself as a technology company, it has never been able to achieve non-linear growth relying on its own profits, and its business model has not departed from the category of asset-heavy commercial real estate leasing. WeWork&#39;s customers are mainly small and entrepreneurial institutions with weak risk resistance and high liquidity. As competition in the industry becomes increasingly fierce, WeWork has to face the problem of price reductions and rising costs in order to retain these customers who are extremely cost-sensitive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The COVID-19 epidemic broke out around the world in 2020, and working from home became a common trend. The economic recession caused a large number of customers to close their businesses, and the office vacancy rate increased sharply. As a &quot;second landlord&quot;, WeWork still needs to pay rent to the landlord. WeWork, which emerged from the previous crisis, became a victim of the new crisis. Maturity mismatch may bring huge profits during economic booms, but it is a heavy burden during economic downturns, and the Federal Reserve&#39;s several rounds of interest rate hikes since the epidemic have exacerbated WeWork&#39;s debt burden. The long-standing systemic risks have ushered in a concentrated outbreak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/gjloiN0n5FG6LPE2jsj5YWdTUDrfDfeu0wMnJf7h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/gjloiN0n5FG6LPE2jsj5YWdTUDrfDfeu0wMnJf7h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258716&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On April 12, 2018, WeWork co-founder Neumann visited Shanghai&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, WeWork pointed out in its second-quarter financial report that taking into account losses and expected cash needs, coupled with increased membership losses and current liquidity levels, the company&#39;s continued operations depend on management. Whether the company can improve its liquidity and profitability over the next 12 months. As of June 30, the company still had $2.9 billion in long-term debt and $13.3 billion in long-term lease debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;WeWork CEO David Tolley believes that &quot;unsustainable leases must be repriced&quot; due to a lack of &quot;the necessary financial flexibility to adapt to the rapidly changing commercial real estate market.&quot; Filing for bankruptcy protection is WeWork&#39;s attempt to survive in adversity. WeWork is seeking court approval to terminate 69 leases that are &quot;substantially unable to operate&quot; and negotiate with more than 400 landlords to modify existing leases. Analysts generally believe that WeWork’s exit will lead to a further increase in the already high office vacancy rate, which will have a negative impact on the cash flow and value of office buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like a cycle. While the market is enthusiastically discussing the butterfly effect caused by the WeWork crisis, competitors are more willing to regard WeWork&#39;s &quot;big defeat&quot; as an &quot;episode&quot; in industry changes, or even as an opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The great irony of WeWork’s bankruptcy is that it happened at a time of record performance for the industry.” Jamie Hodari, CEO of Industrious, a New York-based shared office operator, told the Financial Times &quot;I made a metaphor during the interview, &quot;When a Marriott hotel is not doing well, it will become a Hyatt hotel.&quot; Mark Dixon, CEO of IWG Group, who is also a shared office operator, said in an interview with the BBC, IWG has now acquired and relaunched 40 office spaces that were once part of WeWork. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the lessons learned from WeWork, the shift from the asset-heavy model of &quot;direct leasing&quot; to the light-asset model of &quot;profit sharing&quot; has been a common effort in the industry in recent years, and now it is even more urgent. However, whether owners are willing to accept this adjustment still depends on their comprehensive assessment of the economic environment and operational value. A recent report released by IWG shows that 200 of the 204 new office spaces it signed in the third quarter of 2023 are asset-light operations, but overall, 60% are still operated by traditional leasing methods. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Chinese market, WeWork China also hopes to become the traffic entrance in the stock era. &quot;The business model that only relies on rent difference is very difficult, but this is also our core competitiveness and advantage,&quot; Quan Bin, vice president of WeWork Greater China, said in a recent interview with &quot;Guandian New Media&quot; that companies must survive To achieve better and longer results, we must work faster and more resolutely in reducing costs and increasing efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/aXaJ158QLVgKsFL7LpYGSCNn5DIyBk8rsjRTmAeT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/aXaJ158QLVgKsFL7LpYGSCNn5DIyBk8rsjRTmAeT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258718&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shanghai, WeWork joint shared office space&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Huang Weilai He said that while the decrease in rent costs is a good thing, it also reflects the downturn in the real estate industry. Huang Wei&#39;s entrepreneurial project involves architectural design, and the quality of his business is closely related to the ups and downs of the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2019, Huang Wei returned to China from the Netherlands and worked successively in a European and American architectural design company and a local design studio. &quot;Party A is not doing well, and it is even more difficult for those who provide design services downstream. The number of projects that can be received has shrunk severely, and the industry is seriously involved. If you want to survive, you must either sink or shrink. Even if you can get orders, The price/performance ratio is also very low. Many of my classmates and friends have changed careers.&quot; In early 2022, Huang Wei and two other partners co-founded Miaoqi Design Studio. Faced with uncertainty and the threshold of 30 years old, Huang Wei still persistently wants to try again in the industry he loves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After starting a business for more than a year, he has been sharing his entrepreneurial experience on social media. This small office relocation incident was also edited into a short video by him. At the end of the video, he talked about his views on this &quot;uncertain era.&quot; Unexpectedly, this became one of his most watched videos recently. Private messages poured in like snowflakes. Many comments expressed their empathy for such sudden changes. Of course, there are more &quot;advertisers&quot; selling his office space to him. According to CBRE&#39;s forecast, the new supply of Shanghai&#39;s office market in the second half of 2023 is expected to exceed 950,000 square meters, the highest level in the past decade. Demand is weak, supply is increasing, and the office market is still in a slow recovery period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Wei quickly crossed the message board. The sudden closure of offices pales in comparison to the pressure to continue operations. His lease is signed until September 2024. 2023 is about to pass, and the intensity of competition in the industry is far more intense than last year. At the bidding meeting, master-level firms competed for it, and it has become very common to choose one of two to three hundred proposals. How about next year? He still &quot;has hope.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 14:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[梁静茹演唱会“柱子票”案开庭：主办方是否应提前告知成焦点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260853]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In May this year, many viewers reported that they bought &quot;pillar tickets&quot; at Leung Jingru&#39;s Shanghai concert, and the view was It was obscured by the pillars surrounding the stage, causing heated discussions. On November 17, Ms. Li, who bought the &quot;pillar ticket&quot;, told Nandu reporters that a total of nine audience members filed lawsuits against the concert organizer, Shanghai Rubik&#39;s Cube Pan-Cultural Performing Arts Co., Ltd. On November 15, the first instance of the Meilong People&#39;s Court of the Minhang District People&#39;s Court of Shanghai opened in public to hear the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/67dacecd2e0c7f3166cf55332857d456.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;481&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/67dacecd2e0c7f3166cf55332857d456.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258728&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;On-site picture of the &quot;pillar ticket&quot; provided by Ms. Li. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;9 viewers sued the concert organizer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On May 20th and 21st this year, the 2023 Leung Jingru World Tour Concert was held in Shanghai held, many audience members reported that after arriving, they found that their view was blocked by the pillars around the stage, and &quot;looking at the singers became like looking at the pillars.&quot; Some netizens posted on social platforms saying, &quot;I spent 1,599 to win the pillar position at Liang Jingru&#39;s concert&quot; and &quot;I spent 1,599 to buy something bad&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 17, Ms. Li, a concert attendee, told Nandu reporters that nine audience members, including herself, filed lawsuits against the concert organizer, Shanghai Rubik&#39;s Pan-Cultural Performing Arts Co., Ltd., demanding reasonable refunds. payment and compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 15, the first instance of the Meilong People’s Court of the Minhang District People’s Court of Shanghai opened in public to hear the case. Ms. Li said, &quot;The result of the court trial has not yet been announced. We are waiting for the organizer&#39;s mediation plan. If we still cannot accept the plan they propose, we will wait for the court&#39;s decision.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Li introduced that this Among the 9 spectators who filed the lawsuit this time, 6 were spectators of the May 20th matinee and 3 were spectators of the May 21st matinee. The ticket prices included 1,299 yuan, 999 yuan, etc. &quot;We submitted materials to the court in early August to apply for filing a case, and received news of the court filing the case at the end of August. We all met through social media, and because the early negotiations with the organizer failed, we had no choice but to choose to sue. We wanted to We need to find out whether the organizer has violated our legitimate rights and interests.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Li said that she purchased two tickets for the second-floor stand worth 1,299 yuan on May 20, and the attendance rate that day was quite high. The photo shows that in the middle of Ms. Li&#39;s field of vision is a hollow pillar, and the singer can be vaguely seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Nandu reporter searched for the seat distribution map and found that the two diagonal lines formed by the four corners were basically blocked by pillars, but this was not marked on the page. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the organizer, Shanghai Rubik&#39;s Cube Pan-Cultural Performing Arts Co., Ltd., has responded that it is only responsible for the implementation of Liang Jingru&#39;s Shanghai concert, and the stage will not be built by the company. During the ticket sales stage, the company did not know that the stage design would have four pillars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Li told Nandu reporters that the organizer had said that within the coverage area approved by it, a 200 yuan shopping card would be given as a token of appreciation. &quot;No matter what the price of the ticket, only 200 yuan will be compensated.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The focus of the dispute is whether the organizer should inform in advance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 15, during the court hearing of the case, the two sides focused on &quot;whether the organizer should notify Court investigations and debates were conducted on controversial issues such as informing in advance the existence of &#39;pillar tickets&#39; and whether these locations would affect the concert experience.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Li introduced to Nandu reporters that the nine plaintiffs&#39; requests mainly include three aspects - requesting an order to order the defendant to return the plaintiff&#39;s concert ticket money; ordering the defendant to pay punitive damages to the plaintiff; ordering the defendant to pay punitive damages to the plaintiff; Bear the litigation costs of this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plaintiff’s attorney said that the focus of this case is whether the defendant informed all the plaintiffs in advance whether their views would be blocked. The plaintiff’s purpose for attending the concert was to “see” it, and having his view blocked was a very serious breach of contract. The plaintiff&#39;s right to know was violated, resulting in the loss of the right to choose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The defendant’s attorney said that the reason why the performance used load-bearing columns was because the venue’s ceiling was not load-bearing enough. Without the load-bearing columns on the ground, the performance would not have been able to be held normally and would not have passed the safety approval. So the ground load-bearing columns were used. Columns are also common practice in the industry. &quot;It is common sense that certain positions in the auditorium will inevitably block the view. The defendant has never deliberately mentioned in the publicity that there are no pillars or obstructions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plaintiff believes that the design and layout of the scene It should have been completed earlier. Before the concert begins, the organizer should also fulfill its corresponding responsibilities, inform consumers whose vision will be blocked, and ask them whether they want a refund or other solutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The defendant’s attorney stated that the defendant set up the stage mainly for safety reasons and did not intentionally deceive the audience. Moreover, this performance is the first stop of a series of tours, and they cannot be harshly criticized for considering so many things in advance. details. The response methods for other subsequent performances were improved after being affected by this performance. The first stop cannot be required based on the handling plan for subsequent performances; nor can it be considered that the defendant did not inform the defendant in advance just because the line of sight was blocked at some individual performances. There is an intention to deceive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about 3 pm on the 15th, the trial of this case ended, but the verdict was not announced in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The China Consumers Association has criticized the phenomenon of &quot;pillar tickets&quot; by name&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Concert organizers have dealt with &quot;pillar tickets&quot; differently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nandu previously reported that on August 14 this year, Shanxi Xingtai Lighting Culture and Entertainment Co., Ltd., the organizer of Jay Chou&#39;s 2023 Carnival World Tour Concert in Hohhot, issued an announcement saying that it would meet the needs of fans and allow more Fans can experience the joyful atmosphere of the concert live and reduce congestion outside the concert. After coordinating and fighting with all parties, the organizer will sell the seats with poor visibility in the area blocked by the sound console at a special discount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the organizer stated in the announcement that the viewing angle of the seats in this area is affected by the sound console and is blocked to varying degrees. It is impossible to fully see the entire stage. A large screen is set up behind the sound console for the convenience of the audience. Watch, special discounted tickets are non-refundable and non-exchangeable after purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 2, the China Consumers Association criticized the phenomenon of various &quot;pillar tickets&quot; and &quot;wall tickets&quot;, pointing out that consumers encountered &quot;blind selection&quot; of seats when purchasing performance tickets online, and some performance venues did not support consumption. The visitor chose his seat when purchasing the ticket, but when he arrived at the venue, he learned that what he had purchased was a &quot;pillar ticket&quot; or a &quot;wall ticket&quot; with blind spots, which caused a ticketing problem of &quot;only sounds but no people&quot; throughout the concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Consumers Association said that relevant performance ticketing platforms and organizers should consider how to better protect the rights and interests of consumers and improve the consumer experience from the perspective of promoting the release of consumption potential. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 13:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说 | 陈云生：宪法监督的研究任务依然任重道远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chen Yunsheng, the first Ph.D. in constitutional law in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Born in 1942 in Pinggu County, Beijing (now Pinggu District);&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1966, graduated from the Law Department of Beijing Institute of Political Science and Law (now China University of Political Science and Law); worked in Guangxi after graduation Served in judicial, education, and administrative work; in 1978, he was admitted to the Law Department of the Graduate School of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences for further study. After graduating with a master&#39;s degree, Worked at the Institute of Law of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences; in 1983, he studied for a doctorate in constitutional law under the tutelage of the jurist Zhang Youyu; , STKaiti;&quot;>;Received a doctorate in law in 1987;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Served as a professor of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences Deputy director, professor and doctoral supervisor of the Constitutional Administrative Law Research Office of the Institute of Law, part-time professor and doctoral supervisor at 7 universities including Shanghai Jiao Tong University Law School and Beijing Normal University Law School, and honorary expert advisory member of the Expert Advisory Committee of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. Enjoy special allowances from the State Council. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In October 2023, Chen Yunsheng was in his study in the suburbs of Beijing. (Southern Weekend reporter Chen Yifan/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/018fc437d2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;811&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/16/018fc437d2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258522&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Chen Yunsheng In a study in the suburbs of Beijing. (Southern Weekend reporter Chen Yifan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;81-year-old Chen Yunsheng seldom rests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;His days start at four or five in the morning, walking briskly, cooking, reading and writing in Pinggu District on the outskirts of Beijing, leading a regular old age life. He planted beans, sweet potatoes, pumpkins and corn on a piece of wasteland he &quot;claimed&quot;, and irrigated and cultivated it from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The interest in farming stems from his background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This rural boy, born in Pinggu in 1942, is the first high school student, the first college student, and the first doctor of law in the village. In 1966, after graduating from Beijing University of Political Science and Law (now China University of Political Science and Law), he was assigned to rural areas in Guangxi, where he ate and lived with farmers, waking up to the steaming heat of beef and feces every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the country resumed the postgraduate examination, he relied on a &quot;survived&quot; constitutional law tutorial and was admitted to the law school of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences with the first score in the reexamination. graduate School. Later, he studied for a doctorate and became the only student of the famous legal scholar Zhang Youyu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During this period, he read all the professional books in the law school and went from a &quot;minion&quot; in constitutional law to &quot;the first person in the country to supervise the constitution.&quot; In 1980, he participated in the formulation of the &quot;82nd Constitution&quot; amendment. He always believed that the true meaning of the Constitution did not lie in the constitutional document itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On his academic journey, he did not like to participate in administrative affairs and turned away many opportunities. He laughs at himself as &quot;a lonely ghost in academia&quot;, who only seeks to achieve the ultimate in knowledge and will never be swayed by trends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He advised students to endure loneliness. He always followed the third item of Descartes&#39; code of conduct: he always only sought to overcome himself, not to overcome fate, but only to change his own desires, not to change the order of the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;God helps me&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After retirement, what is your daily life like now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I usually get up at four in the morning, have something to eat, and then go to the river. exercise. I used to run or walk. After I got seriously ill in May or June this year and was exhausted, I cycled for an hour to exercise. Then come back to research or write for an hour, then make breakfast and clean up. After breakfast, I go to work in the fields, usually for two hours, and then come back to continue my research. Two days ago, I was still harvesting vegetables grown in the fields. After lunch break, I worked at my desk again. Then I went to the fields to do some work, and then rode a bike for exercise in the evening. There are no weekends or holidays, and I don’t know what day of the week it is every day. It has been the same day for decades. For me, going out to give lectures and attend societies is also a rare way to rest. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; There are not many old people like you who are still farming in their eighties. Why do you live such a life as a farmer? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My family has been poor farmers for generations. There are five brothers in the family, and I am the second oldest. When I was a child, Confucius said, &quot;I am a young man, so I can do many despicable things.&quot; In addition to going to school, I had to help the family with work, planting fields, harvesting wild vegetables, chopping firewood, feeding pigs and cows, and I did all the work that rural children do. Pass. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When I was about to enter middle school, a junior high school was established in a neighboring village. Children from the eastern, southern and northern areas of Pinggu could go to school. As a result, after we registered, Found that there was only an open space. The first thing we do when we go to school is dig the foundation and build the house. It took more than half a year to have a classroom and a canteen, and a simple basketball court was built. The students borrowed villagers&#39; houses as dormitories and kitchens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, the school funds were not enough, and there happened to be a shoe factory that made cloth shoes, so we contracted part of the factory&#39;s projects. My shoemaking skills were relatively good, so I was made a supervisor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the high school entrance examination, the whole county accepted more than a hundred high school students. I was the first in the village to pass the high school entrance examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the college entrance examination, only three subjects: mathematics, Chinese and chemistry. In the summer, I lay on the field or on the hillside and looked at the clear sky. Meteors came one after another, and the Milky Way was clearly visible. So when I applied for my college application, my first choice was the astronomy department, but only a few people were recruited, so I failed. Beijing University of Political Science and Law was my last choice. My grades were up to standard and I was admitted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your time What is college like? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I entered school in 1962. The schooling system was first 5 years and then changed to 4 years. , mainly studied political and legal subjects. In the first two years, he studied Marxism and criticized revisionism. During this period, he also organized a trip to Emei County, Sichuan (now Emeishan City) to carry out the &quot;Four Clean-ups&quot; movement. After graduating from college, I was assigned to Guangxi, but the receiving unit in Guangxi sent a telegram: &quot;Please postpone your registration.&quot; This was postponed for two years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; When you went to Guangxi two years later, what impressed you most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I just arrived at my workplace in Guangxi. I haven’t settled in yet and haven’t unpacked my luggage yet. The leader organized employees to beat gongs and drums and send me to the countryside to receive education from poor and lower-middle peasants and undergo labor training. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I was assigned to a village on the China-Vietnam border, eating and living with farmers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I live on the lower floor of the building, with the soles of my feet facing the cowshed. The space under my bed is not wasted, and I have a litter of puppies, which are close to my ears. It&#39;s the chicken coop next door. At three or four o&#39;clock in the morning, a cow started to defecate. The smell of feces was steaming, and it immediately spread to the entire building. Then the dog under my bed also started to defecate. These are small things. I clean up dog excrement every morning. Cow dung smells bad, but it doesn’t touch my body. The most difficult thing is the rooster, which makes me unable to rest. &lt;p>; Like a decent and authentic farmer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;My biggest achievement in rural Guangxi is that I endured hunger and hardship, tempered my perseverance, and laid a solid foundation for my subsequent development in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When did you decide to participate? Postgraduate examination? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After two years in the countryside, I returned to the county and later Go to rural areas and serve as a member of the basic humanities education team. Although I went to college, I had no room for improvement and felt that my personal future was bleak. On the other hand, I have a strong sense of ruralism and cannot leave my hometown, so I still want to return to the north for development. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​day in 1977, my wife suddenly asked someone to bring me a message from the county seat, saying that the country wanted to recruit graduate students. I learned about it and it was indeed an opportunity. But I didn’t study very well in college. I stayed in the countryside for another 10 years without reading newspapers or listening to the radio. I thought at that time that the number of undergraduates we graduated in 1962 was more than 400. If we add those who graduated two or three years ago, there would be more than 1,000. Many of these people have married and established businesses, and many have become leaders and have stable incomes and families. Therefore, there are definitely not many people who applied for the exam, probably only a hundred or so. I decided to give it a try and reported it to the county leader. He was very supportive and let me go back to the county to prepare for the exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After all, put down the book for ten How many years have passed, how to prepare for the exam? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There was only two months of preparation time. The first problem was, I I can&#39;t find any books, especially no professional books to read. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another problem is English. The English I learned in college is basically wasted. I borrowed junior high school textbooks and started learning from ABCD. I was completely unsure. After studying for two or three months, I thought I had made some progress and was ready to take the exam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then how to deal with it in the end What about the exam? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The day before the exam, I was still memorizing textbooks, the 1975 Constitution and the Some newspaper articles. God helped me with the exam questions. I remember that the title of the essay at that time was &quot;Follow Chairman Hua on the New Long March&quot;, and the legal theory examination question only had five words - &quot;The French Civil War&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Leading the new Long March, the compositions are all relatively familiar political discourse. Naturally, whether it will be difficult for the candidates depends on their personal performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the preparation for the exam, I borrowed some Marxist-Leninist books. I have repeatedly read the articles about proletarian revolution and proletarian dictatorship in the book, such as &quot;Critique of the Gotha Program&quot; and &quot;The French Civil War&quot;, and have gained a lot of experience, so it is natural to answer the jurisprudence exam questions smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I was left with no knowledge of English, so I was happy as soon as I opened the test paper. It was an English report from the &quot;People&#39;s Daily&quot; about learning from Dazhai in agriculture. I don’t speak English well, but I am very familiar with the feats of Dazhai people in transforming the world and the professional terms involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, if you were asked to translate &quot;seven ditches and eight beams&quot;, I don&#39;t know the English words for &quot;gou&quot; and &quot;liang&quot;, but when I saw &quot;seven (seven)&quot; )&quot; and &quot;eight&quot;, I immediately knew that this must be Qigou Baliang, and I passed the English test at this time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;After the adoption of the 1982 Constitution, &quot;little fame&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is life as a graduate student different from what you imagined? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Goed to school on September 1, 1978, and registered at the Law Institute of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences Later, I discovered that there was no school building for graduate students. The school leaders went to Beijing Normal University to borrow space. We built a simple classroom with linoleum in the open space between other people&#39;s buildings, and borrowed the building to use as a dormitory, with 8 people in one room. This is how study and life at the postgraduate level are settled. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than a year later, the Graduate School of the Academy of Social Sciences also found it inconvenient, so they asked us to move out and live in Beijing No. 11 School again. go. Usually, we go to the School of Law of the Academy of Social Sciences for classes and come back after class. I study for 12 hours a day, exercise for 2 hours in the morning and evening, and sleep for 6 hours. After studying hard for three years, my academic performance was quite good, and the school leaders were quite satisfied with it. After graduating with a master&#39;s degree in 1980, I stayed at the law school to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is related to undergraduate graduation Later I was assigned to work in rural areas of Guangxi, and my experience was completely different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That’s true, especially when I entered the work and formulated 82 Working on the Constitution. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; What specific jobs have you been involved in? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The work of amending the Constitution was mainly led by the then Deputy Chairman of the Legislative Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress. The director, Mr. Zhang Youyu, is in charge, and a secretariat is set up to be responsible for research and drafting work. At that time, Wang Shuwen, director of the Institute of Law of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, was a member of the Secretariat, so Zhang Youyu naturally handed over some of the academic research and data preparation work of the Secretariat directly to Wang Shuwen. Every time Wang Shuwen received a task, he hurried back to the law school and summoned all the staff to divide the work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The five of us are generally not allowed to leave the unit and stick to our jobs 24 hours a day. As soon as they come, we are instructed to conduct research immediately and write research day and night. Report, at that time we could only take a brief rest in the office. It was late at night, and we bought a bowl of instant noodles to eat by ourselves. At that time, it was difficult to find information, and the academic world was in a state of desolation. There were books transferred from Tsinghua University and Peking University in the law school. No one had read them for more than 20 years. The dust was an inch thick, so I dug through the dust to look for information. From the beginning of preparations in 1980 to the completion of the constitutional amendment in 1982, we persisted in this way for more than two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The process of constitution-making is complicated. We are only doing the most preliminary work. After the report is submitted, experts from the Secretariat will collect opinions from all parties and then bring it up to the leadership level. After the draft was passed, the People&#39;s Daily published a total of three solicitations for opinions. At that time, people were very enthusiastic about participation, and they may have hoped that through the formulation and implementation of the Constitution, the social disorder and national chaos like the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; could be ended forever. During the public participation in the discussion, more than 3,000 opinions were collected, and some people even suggested which words and punctuation should be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Participated in the formulation of the 1982 Constitution Has the related work had any impact on you personally? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; After the adoption of the 82 Constitution, the Constitution suddenly became a major event that attracted national attention. First of all, there was a lot of publicity. At that time, even &quot;little minions&quot; like me published hundreds of articles on tofu cubes in newspapers. Publishing houses have also requested manuscripts from us, from leaders to experts to little people like us. I was extensively involved in publishing dozens of pamphlets promoting the new constitution. In the process, I became &quot;a little famous&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Speaking of Mr. Zhang Youyu, what special impression do you have of him? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because of the amendment of the Constitution, I had contact with Mr. Zhang Youyu, who was eight years old at the time. When he was more than ten years old, he thought the articles I wrote were more interesting, so he liked to ask me to help him write manuscripts, and then he would revise them. I actually took on the job of his writing secretary. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Around 1982, leaders of the State Council advocated the cultivation of academic successors by several senior experts in the traditional &quot;master-apprentice&quot; format. Mr. Zhang Youyu chose me at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After more than a year of studying, the country changed the inherited master-apprentice model and officially changed it to a modern doctoral education system. I took the state-mandated doctoral examination, which included jurisprudence, constitutional law, English and politics. I was the only candidate and thus became his doctoral candidate. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;As a scholar, we must maintain a &quot;normal mind&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt; strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You studied constitutional law with Mr. Zhang. How did you later pay specific attention to constitutional supervision? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because after the implementation of the 1982 Constitution, it is only a textual legal provision. However, whether the implementation process of government agencies is just and rational, and whether the implementation and supervision mechanism of the Constitution are scientific, all need to be continued to study. Naturally, I entered into the study of the theory of constitutional supervision. Judicialization of constitutional supervision has been my main focus for more than ten years. I have published three books, one of which is my revised and expanded doctoral thesis. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The fate of constitutional law is to deal with the highest power of the country. At that time, I strongly advocated changing the Legal Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress into the Constitution and Law Committee. This was proposed by me, and was repeatedly demonstrated by generations of constitutional scholars. In 2018, the &quot;Constitution and Law Committee&quot; was finally established in the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think about academics? Relations with politics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Academics cannot be separated from society, nor can they be completely isolated from politics. There are quite a few scholars who place their main academic interests and attention on directly serving real-life politics and law. This is understandable. Of course, people need to study practical problems. This is also a university knowledge, and it is a more difficult knowledge. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;The problem is that people who do this kind of knowledge should adjust their mentality. You must be mentally prepared that not all research reports and suggestions for improvement that address practical issues should or may be accepted and adopted by the relevant political decision-making bodies. We have said that theoretical conclusions and political decisions do not always coincide. Theoretically, it is necessary to study physics carefully and observe the subtle details, while in politics, it is necessary to weigh the pros and cons, pursue advantages and avoid disadvantages. The two stand on different positions and pursue different value goals, so the conclusions and decisions will naturally be different. As a scholar, it is important to maintain a &quot;normal mind.&quot; It is naturally a happy and encouraging thing to have your opinions adopted. Even if your opinions are not adopted, you should not feel disappointed or discouraged. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; As far as you&#39;re concerned, what&#39;s the fun in learning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My book has been published. If someone reads it and experiences it, do you think it’s good? Just accept it, if it’s not good then reject it. However, we do not consider its impact when doing scholarship. That is a matter of whether contemporaries and future generations agree with it. It may be thirty or fifty years before anyone is interested in reading the book I wrote in depth. I know that at that time there was a scholar who had done such research and had such advanced ideological understanding. I don’t expect anyone of this generation to understand. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;Doing academic work is not only for gaining practical benefits, but also for learning. &quot;Liangzhizhi&quot; and a means to support my family. In addition to doing academic work, I also want to increase my knowledge. I groped forward according to my own research ideas, had the courage to explore, studied all my life, and was willing to be lonely. I would never be moved by the trend or follow the trend. So I laughed at myself at a certain society and said that I was a lonely ghost in the academic world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;I just want to learn this knowledge thoroughly and achieve what I think As mature as you are, you can enjoy it. My students said that 30 years later, they are still studying the topic of &quot;constitutional supervision&quot; that I studied at the time. Because the research task of constitutional supervision has a long way to go. In my academic career, I have gone through a meaningful and tortuous path. If I can achieve the ultimate in this aspect of knowledge, it will be a blessing to be able to masturbate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;For this reason I am&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Nowadays, young people, whether they are looking for a job or taking postgraduate entrance examinations, are facing fierce competition, and they are also relatively confused. . What advice do you have for young people? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have taught at Beijing Normal University for seven or eight years, and I have a deep understanding of this situation. When a master&#39;s degree or doctorate is admitted, the first thing to do is to take exams, such as judicial qualification certificate, computer certificate, IELTS, etc. You have to take five or six certificates in three years, so how can you have time to study and read? Now that you&#39;ve almost passed the certification exam, it&#39;s time to send out your resume and look for a job. He waited until two weeks before the defense of his master&#39;s thesis before he hurriedly put together the paper, and its quality can be imagined. I always tell students that if they study well, they will not have to worry about finding a job in the future, and gold will shine. This society must always be supported by people with knowledge and vision. But secondly, the competition in society is so fierce that people will be unemployed immediately after graduation. Nowadays, many people deliver food after graduating from Ph.D., which is very realistic. If you set your starting point so low in the beginning and just find a job to support your family, how can our society progress? In the past, we talked about &quot;I think, therefore I am&quot;, but now I think it is &quot;I am, therefore I am&quot;. The reason why you are who you are is because of the things you have done. Personal self-realization and success always require a lot of effort or even a lifetime of effort. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of the current master&#39;s and doctoral training system? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yunsheng:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think our current training system is a kind of indoctrination education, and it is strict and strict. out. When I was studying for my Ph.D., the teachers only had one class every three to five weeks. They mainly relied on themselves to go out to listen to lectures and academic conferences, and tried their best to expand their knowledge. When I was studying in the United States, the school invited a professor from another school or our own school to give a keynote speech during lunch every day. Others listened while eating, or put down their knives and forks and raised their hands to ask questions, and no minute was wasted. Today’s students are also less active in participating in academic activities. Therefore, the main difference between the current and previous training models is that one is indoctrination and the other is heuristic; one is open and the other is closed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江苏205国道将收费引质疑：公共福利易涨难降，能否推进有待观察丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260825]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a toll station was built on the Huai&#39;an section of 205 National Highway in Suqian, Jiangsu, and the news that vehicle tolls will be collected soon has aroused social concern. great concern and doubt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to China Jiangsu Net, on October 20, the Jiangsu Provincial Government approved that after the Suhuai Toll Station of National Highway 205 is completed and meets the traffic conditions, it will be managed as a government loan repayment road and jointly operated by Suqian and Huaian. Charges have been set and the charging standards for various types of vehicles have been determined, ranging from 10 yuan to 50 yuan. Media reports indicate that the toll station has been built. This means that tolls may be activated on this section of the national highway at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New toll stations on national highways! Many people believe that this is contrary to the country&#39;s policy of gradually canceling ordinary highway toll stations in recent years. However, the Jiangsu Provincial Transportation Department stated that the toll collection of first-class highways for which the government repays loans complies with the policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the current &quot;Toll Road Management Regulations&quot;, roads constructed by the government using loans or paid funds raised from enterprises and individuals can collect tolls upon approval. The Suqian and Huai&#39;an sections of National Highway 205 were built with government loans. According to the Jiangsu Transportation Department, this section still has nearly 1 billion yuan in debt to be repaid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sorting out the historical context of the Suhuai Toll Station on National Highway 205, we can find that the toll collection on this section is not a recent decision. In the early 2010s, the Suqian and Huai&#39;an sections of National Highway 205 were successively renovated and expanded and upgraded to first-class highways. In 2014, the Jiangsu Provincial Government approved in a document the establishment of a toll station at the junction of National Highway 205 Huai&#39;an and Suqian, and the two cities will jointly charge fees. In 2018, the Jiangsu Provincial Development and Reform Commission approved the feasibility report for the construction of the toll station. Today, the toll station is built and the provincial government issues documents approving the toll. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the minds of many people, only expressways still charge tolls, and all other ordinary highway toll stations have been abolished. However, in fact, there are not only ordinary highway toll stations, but they have increased in the past two years. According to information released on the official website of the Jiangsu Provincial Department of Transportation, as of December 2022, there are still more than 10 national and provincial highway toll stations in Jiangsu Province. Also on National Highway 205, more than 90 kilometers north of Suhuai Toll Station, there is Xinyi Toll Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Toll Road Statistical Bulletin of the Ministry of Transport, at the end of 2021, there were 308 first-level highway main line toll stations and 115 second-level highway main line toll stations across the country. Compared with the end of the previous year, there were 308 second-level highway main line toll stations. The number of toll stations decreased by 7, but there were 8 more toll stations on first-class highways. The total mileage of tolled first-class highways was 17,600 kilometers, an increase of more than 200 kilometers over the previous year. Media reports show that since 2022, at least 7 new national highway toll stations have been added in various provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in recent years, it has become a trend to cancel tolls on ordinary highways. The central government has repeatedly proposed reducing road transportation costs and reducing road and bridge tolls. As early as 2009, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Transport and the Ministry of Finance jointly issued a document calling for the gradual and orderly elimination of tolls on secondary roads for government loan repayment. The revised draft of the &quot;Toll Road Management Regulations&quot; released in 2018 stipulates that the construction of new first- and second-level toll roads and independent bridges and tunnels will be stopped, and only expressways can collect tolls. However, this revision has not yet been completed. In 2020, the General Office of the State Council forwarded the &quot;Implementation Opinions on Further Reducing Logistics Costs&quot; from the National Development and Reform Commission and the Ministry of Transport, once again requesting to ensure that the overall burden of truck tolls is not increased. Under these policies, a large number of toll plazas have been eliminated across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, although it is not impossible to collect tolls at the Suhuai Toll Station of Jiangsu&#39;s new 205 National Highway, although at the beginning of the reconstruction and expansion of this road section, the project was based on loans for road construction and toll repayment, and the funds mainly came from banks. Loans, and there are still huge loans that have not been repaid, but this is now and then. In the early 2010s, the construction and reconstruction of first- and second-level toll roads was still allowed, but after a few years the policy has changed. Except for expressways, the central government has discouraged and even explicitly proposed to stop the construction of first- and second-level toll roads, and many places have also canceled them. A large number of toll stations on primary and secondary roads have been installed. Especially in the past year or two, due to the impact of the epidemic, the economy is struggling to recover. Under such circumstances, adding new toll stations and increasing public transportation costs will of course be questioned by the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there is no explicit regulation, &quot;national highways, provincial highways and other ordinary highways should be free of charge&quot; has become &quot;common sense&quot; in the public mind, just like highways are free on holidays. Once this kind of psychological expectation is formed, if you want to reverse it, you will certainly be questioned. It is easy to bring welfare from scratch, but it is difficult to bring it from existence to nothing. It is easy to go from paid to free, but difficult to go from free to paid. If the previously charged service is changed to free, the public will think they have benefited. But conversely, if it was free before and now it has to be charged, everyone will feel that their interests have been violated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is true not only in public policy, but also in business. Since the birth of the Internet, various services have been almost free for ordinary users. Netizens are accustomed to enjoying free services. Once charges start to be charged, they will of course feel very unhappy if they have to pay to watch videos or use large-capacity, high-speed download network disks. Broadband and data traffic have been charged from the beginning, and no one thinks these should be free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a truly free lunch does not actually exist. If you want to watch free videos, you have to endure a lot of ads; if you want to use a free network disk, you can only endure the download speed of a small water pipe. Likewise, public benefits also need to be paid for by someone. There are no tolls on national highways, and construction and maintenance costs are indispensable. They can only come from fiscal revenue such as taxes, which means taxpayers must pay for them. If the local government&#39;s fiscal revenue is sufficient, then of course it won&#39;t be a problem. But if finances are tight, I&#39;m afraid we can only reduce spending on road construction and maintenance, or consider charging fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Suhuai Toll Station of National Highway 205 is preparing to collect fees at this time, which may be related to the local financial difficulties in recent years. But it remains to be seen whether it can move forward after attracting huge attention and opposition. Although Suqian and Huai&#39;an are in northern Jiangsu and are less economically developed than southern Jiangsu, they are still much more prosperous than many places in the west. There is still 1 billion in road construction loans, which may not be too big for local finances. of holes. What&#39;s more, Jiangsu, as the country&#39;s second largest economic province, should have enough financial resources to make transfer payments to local governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if no tolls are allowed on national and provincial roads in the future, will the enthusiasm of local governments to build new roads be greatly reduced? This is also worth noting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>