<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[担心被称“普信”，不敢接触异性：一位大学老师对男生女生的观察]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260410]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On a recent Friday, at 2:30 in the afternoon, I parked my car in the parking lot of Guangzhou University and found that the playground There were two boys playing basketball, and they came to play so early. My curiosity drove me to get closer. I pitched and chatted with them. They are freshmen from the School of Foreign Languages. They are not only classmates, but also fellow Zhanjiang fellows. It happened that there were no classes or homework on Friday afternoon, so we were bored, so we met to play basketball. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Men and women are clearly differentiated&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As I walked, I asked how many people were in their class. They told me that there were 34 girls and 5 boys. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why didn&#39;t you think about asking the female classmates in the class to go out for fun?&quot; I asked casually. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They were quite surprised by my suggestion: &quot;Teacher, I don&#39;t know any of the girls in the class.&quot; &quot;Teacher, I know two girls in our class, but they asked me to date them. This is absolutely impossible.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are 34 girls, how many people have you added to WeChat?&quot; I continued to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I added 5 people, but I don’t have much contact with them.” Classmate A said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three, and they are all cadres in the class, but I only contact them when something happens.&quot; Classmate B replied to me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You are a freshman now. You should have a lot of courses, and there should be many opportunities to take classes together.&quot; I continued to ask. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yes, we have classes together almost every day. The problem is that although we are in the same classroom, boys sit with boys and girls sit with girls. In class, they mainly listen to the teacher&#39;s lectures; after class, they disperse separately. , there is little communication and interaction with each other.&quot; Student A said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Both boys and girls, everyone deliberately keeps their distance. Everyone agrees that as soon as they enter the classroom, boys and girls will sit separately.&quot; Classmate B added. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, college students should have relatively free control of their time. Their physical and mental development has matured, and their need for interaction with the opposite sex is relatively strong. It is normal for them to date and become friends with the opposite sex, but the reality is not in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although classmates in the same class can meet every day and have many contact opportunities, having contact opportunities does not necessarily mean that substantial familiarity, understanding and understanding will occur in real life. Where is &quot;Geng&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seeing the confusion on my face, classmate B told me the whole story, &quot;Teacher, have you heard of some hot words on the Internet, such as &#39;licking the dog&#39;, &#39;lowering the head&#39; and &#39;Pu Xin&#39;?&quot; ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After his explanation, I realized that among boys and girls, the one who takes the initiative to add the other party’s WeChat account or asks for the other party’s contact information will be considered by a small number of members of the opposite sex to be a “dog licker” and a “lower” person. This situation is relatively common for boys who take the initiative. In other words, when a boy takes the initiative to add a friend to a girl he is interested in or finds interesting, some girls will think this is a strange thing and ask, &quot;What do you want to do?&quot; &quot;What are your intentions?&quot; &quot;Do you want to pursue her?&quot; Me?&quot; If the boy is not the right person for the girl, the girl will think that the boy is &quot;general trustworthy&quot;, which means &quot;ordinary but confident&quot;. The problem is that some girls may not think this way, but in order to avoid girls thinking this way, boys do not want to be misunderstood and bear the stigmatized label of &quot;normal men&quot;, so they would rather or simply not be active or take the initiative to avoid embarrassment, even in the face of The girl you are most attracted to or the girl you like the most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Does the teacher know about the &#39;campus wall&#39;?&quot; Classmate A asked me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course I don’t know. He explained to me this way: &quot;It is a public platform for students to publish information. It seems that every university has it. For example, once I join someone else and I am rejected, they will remove me. If I post screenshots of others on the &#39;campus wall&#39;, then all the students in the school will know about me, and I will be polite and sweep the floor in school, unable to hold my head up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I can&#39;t control the other person&#39;s thinking, thoughts and actions. , I am even more unable to face and avoid this kind of risk, so I will not take the initiative to get close to the opposite sex.&quot; Classmate B said helplessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Invisible Wall&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This reminds me of: A year ago, I played ball with several boys from my senior graduating class. They told me that after four years, they could not recognize any of them. Students in the same class may not be able to name their classmates. In their eyes, students of the opposite sex in the same class or major are just &quot;classmates&quot; rather than &quot;friends&quot;, &quot;close friends&quot; or &quot;besties&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to my observation, a basic feeling is that the current friendship or friendship between college students in the same major or class, especially between people of the opposite sex, is very weak. They are either busy or idle, and they are busy. Even if they may have a crush on a classmate of the opposite sex, they will never take the initiative or actively express their needs or wishes to make friends or interact with each other. In other words, after entering college, an &quot;invisible heart wall&quot; suddenly appears between boys and girls. This wall imprisons boys and girls, and no one wants to take the initiative to tear down this wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, it was high school before entering college. The relationship between classmates in high school was generally very good. They got along with each other day and night, discussed and solved problems together, had fun and decompressed together. The boys handed ambiguous notes to the girls they liked, and the girls Look at the boy you like a few more times, meet at a corner of the school gate next night during self-study, and arrange to go home together. When you are excited, hold each other&#39;s hand and give him warmth, strength or encouragement. How normal is this? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;My college years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;I can’t help but think of my college career, which was from 1997 to 2001. In the first class in the first week after the military training, the head teacher spent two whole classes asking each student to come up to the podium and introduce themselves. Then everyone went to a restaurant at the school gate to have lunch together, and they quickly became familiar with each other. . Boys and girls meet together for morning reading, breakfast, and class; after dinner, everyone has evening self-study together. After self-study, they play badminton for an hour on a wide road in the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public displays of love were also extremely common at that time. When it comes to the person of the opposite sex they like, a generous and cheerful person will express their feelings directly, &quot;Can I ask you to watch a movie?&quot;; a shy and reserved person will use an intermediary to act as a matchmaker and express their intention to date through a small note or letter. If two people have dinner together, watch a movie (usually an all-night movie), and then hold hands, it basically declares that the &quot;intimate male-female relationship&quot; has been basically established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, it is normal to express this emotion or affection to someone you like or like. I remember clearly that there were 42 people in our class, 22 boys and 20 girls. When I graduated as a senior, there were as many as 5 couples. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Concerned about the values ​​​​and true psychology of contemporary college students&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Boys today are generally not interested in love, don’t they want to know and understand girls? Or on the contrary, are girls today generally not interested in falling in love and not wanting to get to know and understand boys? I feel neither. Faced with the overall environment of high employment pressure, some people have been nervous since their freshman year and are busy with postgraduate entrance examinations, public entrance examinations, College English Level 4 and 6, driver&#39;s licenses, teacher qualification certificates, etc. However, in addition to &quot;many things to do&quot;, they When people still feel lonely or lonely in their hearts, they also long to meet or have a beautiful love. The problem is that no one wants to be considered a &quot;dog-licking tribe&quot;, &quot;Xiatou tribe&quot; or &quot;Puxin tribe&quot;, and no one wants to take the initiative Go out and get to know the opposite sex. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Contemporary college students are relatively unfamiliar with their classmates, so who are they relatively familiar with? It is understood that compared to students taking public courses or professional courses, it is easier for them to get acquainted with people who have the same or similar interests or hobbies. For example, the relationship between classmates within hip-hop clubs, literary clubs, basketball clubs, opera clubs, etc. should be close to classmates who have taken the same professional course. The reason is that various clubs are more in line with the interests or hobbies of students. This is what they like or like to do in their hearts. Everyone communicates and learns skills together, and closely cooperates and collaborates together, which can often brew the seeds of emotion. And in In professional courses, the course itself may be relatively difficult, and most students are not very interested in discussing or communicating together, so the establishment of close relationships naturally takes a long time. From a spatial perspective, professional classrooms are formal, formal and serious spaces, while various clubs are informal, informal and leisure spaces. The latter make people relatively relaxed, relaxed and natural. This is the informal space. effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let college students feel more relaxed and light, make them feel physically and mentally happy, let them dare and have the courage to do the &quot;duty things&quot; that suit their age group, let the friendship between classmates return to innocence and depth, and let the conversation Talking about love has become a matter of course, which is what the new atmosphere of contemporary college students should mean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to achieve the above goals, I believe that relevant parties should pay more attention to the values ​​​​and true psychology and mentality of contemporary college students. Each university has set up public required courses on the psychology of college students to encourage and advocate the construction of an open An inclusive and harmonious relationship between men and women breaks down all kinds of conceptual barriers and obstacles that create gender opposition and hostility. In terms of course learning, teachers may wish to encourage students to conduct group discussions, and suggest that men and women be paired into groups to create a good atmosphere for heterosexual discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, relevant parties should find breakthroughs in extracurricular time, fill students&#39; extracurricular time with as many public activities as possible, and create opportunities for male and female students to contact, understand and understand each other, such as organizing students to carry out Campus tours, city tours, outings, autumn outings, weekend hikes or dinner parties, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a professor at the Department of Sociology, Guangzhou University)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010; &quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[辛柏青：适度的，饱满的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260363]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/3o5PaHrmlWyAEtsipZOYUbuJyvzjyK2zBnv225d7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/3o5PaHrmlWyAEtsipZOYUbuJyvzjyK 2zBnv225d7. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2020, director Zhang Lu returned to Beijing from South Korea and was quarantined in a hotel in Guangzhou for two weeks in accordance with the COVID-19 prevention and control policy at the time. He wrote a script and sent it to Xin Baiqing, saying that the protagonist Gu Wentong was written for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Wentong is from Beijing. He is divorced. His daughter is fostered at his sister’s house. He lives in the old house left by his mother. He has an affair with a young girl and then separates. His best friend as a boy is in a foreign country. suicide. This person who once wrote poetry now makes a living by writing articles about food. He wanders the streets and alleys of Beijing, lonely, and has a sense of drifting that cannot be stabilized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actor Xin Baiqing previously collaborated with Zhang Lu in &quot;The Long Confession&quot; (2021) - the brothers Lichun and Lidong went to Japan from Beijing to find Yanagawa, a girl with whom they had a bond when they were young. Having something on your mind. Xin Baiqing plays Li Chun, who already has a family. He goes to a foreign country and hides his loneliness and discomfort in a nonchalant way. He said, &quot;Director Zhang Lu prefers to write about people who have a sense of wandering and loneliness.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xin Baiqing let Zhang Lu see this feeling at a certain moment when Xin Baiqing was resting or lost in thought on the set. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Wentong lives next to the White Tower, and Xin Baiqing also grew up in Beijing. Zhang Lu once said that Xin Baiqing has the &quot;not anxiousness&quot; of an old Beijinger. People who are not in a hurry seem to be taking things too slowly, have heavier traces of time on their bodies, and have a closer relationship with the past than those who keep running forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Wentong in &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; looks like a man trapped in time. He wears lazy cloth shoes, only a ginger corduroy jacket and a floppy backpack. Most of the time Walking, occasionally taking the bus, and eating braised food that &quot;only people over fifty years old miss&quot; are separated from everything that is happening at the moment, and I am used to saying sorry to everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why do I look at such a person more often?&quot; Zhang Lu said in an interview with &quot;Watching Movies&quot;, &quot;Because for this kind of person, the past time is still there, and the present time is still there. Subtle changes have occurred, and two things from time are squeezing on him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Gu Wentong, the past time and the present state are both related to the missing father: the five-year-old In 2006, my father was accused of molesting a woman on the bus and my mother kicked him out of the house. When he reached middle age, he suddenly received news that his father&#39;s &quot;hooligan crime&quot; was an unjust case. For so many years, his father had been watching him from a distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scene of reconciliation between father and son was brief. The two danced a ballroom dance in a simple room accompanied by DVD footage from the last century. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two grown men dancing together is not a Chinese way of expressing emotions, let alone Xin Baiqing&#39;s. He asked Zhang Lu, how to dance? Zhang Lu said that he can dance when the time comes. He asked Tian Zhuangzhuang, who played the father, that he could understand all the scenes in the script and could imagine the final appearance, but the dancing scene was weird. Tian Zhuangzhuang also said that there will be a solution on that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When that day came, Xin Baiqing said one line first: Dad, stand up. The two of them jumped stiffly a few times. Xin Baiqing said to Tian Zhuangzhuang, Dad, the blood vessels in your hands are like earthworms - this is what his daughter said to Gu Wentong before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Zhuangzhuang glanced at his hand, and then put his hand on Xin Baiqing&#39;s shoulder. Dancing comes naturally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That’s right, Xin Baiqing sighed. &quot;With this one action, my father&#39;s emotions for so many years fell into his hands and onto my shoulders. This action is small, but it contains too much content.&quot; He thought, &quot;When you go straight to the result and the goal, When you are doing this, you will wonder why it is so difficult? But forget about the result and purpose, and when you enjoy the process and express it, the results will appear naturally.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/35L5QZOT7RYnaU2SmvxFrPGenorKPmviuYXjG1ST.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/08/35L5QZOT7RYnaU2SmvxFrPGenorKPmviuYXjG1ST.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Movie &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; Stills &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;People&#39;s Insurance Drama&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot; will be released. The film was shortlisted for the main competition of the 73rd Berlin Film Festival at the beginning of the year. In April, director Zhang Lu attended the &quot;Light of the White Tower&quot; post-screening event at the Beijing Film Festival and commented, &quot;Xin Baiqing&#39;s performance is self-evident. It&#39;s easy to win awards for hard-working performances. Xin Baiqing deserves the award.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In terms of fame, Xin Baiqing may not be a first-line star actor. In some years, he did not have many film and television works. But in the movie &quot;Legend of the Demon Cat&quot; (2017), in just a few scenes, the audience was completely attracted by his performance as Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He only has one scene in the script: Gao Lishi carries Li Bai to the Banquet of Bliss. Li Bai was drunk and composed a poem, &quot;The clouds want the clothes and the flowers want the face.&quot; Drunkness is the keynote. Xin Baiqing thought, does he really want to act drunk? &quot;My understanding of Li Bai is that it was a period when Li Bai was particularly sober, because all his illusions about his official career had been shattered. Everyone was praising him for being a high official. He knew very well that it was over.&quot; To have Drunk state, but you must be sober and cannot act drunk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the set, director Chen Kaige said that there would be no need to walk in the scene later, and he would just shoot it directly. Great, Xin Baiqing later said, &quot;I am willing to collide with the most vivid things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first shot was passed in one go. When he got to the monitor, Chen Kaige first said something off-topic, &quot;We have to cooperate in the future&quot;; then he showed Xin Baiqing the monitor: Xin Baiqing sat up, stretched out, and rubbed against the golden tortoise, and then asked Concubine Yang Youyou ,who are you? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Kaige said, this is Li Bai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;TV drama viewers may have known Xin Baiqing through &quot;Happiness is Like a Flower&quot; (2005) in the early years or &quot;Da Qin Fu&quot; (2020) in recent years. The role that really makes him remembered is Zhou Bingyi in the period drama &quot;Human World&quot; (2022) - the eldest brother in an ordinary family in Northeast China: sent to the countryside as an educated youth, admitted to Peking University, and later became an official with outstanding contributions during the reform and opening up period. The shadow of many people in special times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Screenwriter Wang Haiyu received an invitation to adapt and read Liang Xiaosheng’s original novel. He felt that the description of Zhou Bingyi was relatively thin, such as the process of demolishing the &quot;Guangzi Film&quot; in the shantytown where he grew up after he took over the government. Passed a few pens. In Wang Hailu’s story, his younger brother Zhou Bingkun represents the family (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;the grassroots people&lt;/span>;), and his older brother Zhou Bingyi represents the country (&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Government officials&lt;/span>;) are the backbone. So she put a lot of effort into writing the scene after Zhou Bingyi became a leading cadre. &quot;If I have to say it, the first half of this play is Zhou Bingkun&#39;s home court, and the second half is Zhou Bingyi&#39;s home court,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About halfway through the broadcast of &quot;Human World&quot;, Wang Hailu and Xin Baiqing met at an event. Zhou Bingyi&#39;s highlight hasn&#39;t been aired yet. Wang Haiyuan doesn&#39;t know what Xin Baiqing can do. The two parties only exchanged a few polite words. She seemed to have heard Xin Baiqing say, &quot;This script is very literary.&quot; She thought this was just a polite comment. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After watching the complete drama, Wang Hailu regretted not chatting more with Xin Baiqing, &quot;This is such a good actor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A brief example: watching the demolition of shantytowns in the drama Before that scene, I was a little nervous. I gave Zhou Bingyi a few thousand words of lines for that scene. When the plot came to that point, I could only write it like this. I thought the director might have a way to reduce the difficulty of performing this scene during filming. ——I didn’t dare to expect the actor to fulfill his wish. At that time, I had the impression that Xin Baiqing was a niche actor in literary films. ——Unexpectedly, the ten-minute scene was filmed in one shot. Xin Baiqing used his His understanding of the characters, his talent in temperament, and his line skills have successfully endowed him with the real nobility that a ruler should have.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than a year has passed since the premiere of &quot;Human World&quot;, and Zhou Bingyi was demolished in a shanty town. Clips of handling disputes on the spot and explaining policies to neighborhood friends whom he has known since childhood are still circulated on self-media and have become classic examples of both performance and speech. Wang Haiyuan started her career as a novelist, and was later transferred to the General Political Repertory Theater to do drama. She said, &quot;At that time, I often heard senior teachers say that the theater protects the people, and the people protect the opera. The success of Zhou Bingyi&#39;s character must be the people protect the opera.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BRGvtnAAlX0OGVZ0J1Igr0XPE8tD9S34KazHwDXT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/BRGvtnAAlX0OGVZ0J1Igr0XPE8tD9S34KazHwDXT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A person&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;After &quot;The Human World&quot;, Xin Baiqing received a large number of official roles. But he doesn&#39;t want to be typecast. Only fresh roles can arouse his curiosity. He filmed the first feature film &quot;Three Decades&quot; by documentary director Xu Tong, playing the villain Yan Yonggang, and starring with Duan Yihong who played the policeman Jia Guozhi. In the prosperous era, Yan Yonggang injured policeman Jia Guozhi during a pursuit. Jia was not killed, and Yan was not arrested. A blood feud was formed, but a sympathy for each other was born. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his original novel &quot;Jinbao Island&quot;, Xu Tong wrote about Yan Yonggang, a son of an official, like this: his actions are dark, his person is fair, and he has a sinister aura. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Tong and Xin Baiqing went to the writer Acheng&#39;s house to discuss the adaptation of &quot;Zhenbao Island&quot;. That was the first time he met Xin Baiqing. As soon as he parked the car, he saw Xin Baiqing arriving in an SUV behind him. Alone, no team, no assistant. &quot;I felt very comfortable at that time. He was very natural and alone. He didn&#39;t have the habits of the entertainment industry or the behavior of actors.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After meeting at Acheng&#39;s house, Ah Cheng Cheng told Xu Tong, pay attention, Bai Qing is holding her breast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Tong later observed carefully that Xin Baiqing had no breasts at all. He was about 1.8 meters tall and stood straight. Xu Tong asked Xin Baiqing, has he always been in this shape? Xin Baiqing said yes. It has been like this for decades, and he is neither fat nor thin at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Tong understood that Acheng was not referring to the body shape, but to the impression that Xin Baiqing was holding her breasts. &quot;Because of his thin temperament and subtlety.&quot; Similarly, Xu Tong found that Xin Baiqing had a special look in his eyes, &quot;He looks at things, not directly with his eyes shining, but as if there is a gap between them. Layers of things, the light is recycled and contained inside.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aware of these two points, and looking at the characters created by Xin Baiqing, Xu Tong felt, &quot;His expressions are moderate and at the same time full and full. It means that the thing behind his back is full.&quot; Chen Kaige had a similar evaluation of Xin Baiqing. He said that Xin Baiqing &quot;eats very deeply and vomits very little.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spring of 2022, &quot;Three Decades&quot; will start filming in Shaanxi. Xin Baiqing promised Xu Tong to join the group in advance and turned down other arrangements. &quot;After he said the Spring Festival, I walked over.&quot; Xu Tong recalled, &quot;Looking back on our work during that period, I feel that he is not an actor. He did not regard our cooperation as a project. He just Create a character. Familiarize yourself with the environment, enter the space, and then get into the character.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was a script reading before the start of filming, and everyone didn&#39;t talk much. Xu Tong said that Xin Baiqing and Duan Yihong had already turned the characters over and over. If you understand everything thoroughly and talk too much, it will affect the spontaneity of the scene. He described the performances of the two actors as &quot;very exciting and very surprising&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although they were happy to work together, Xu Tong and Xin Baiqing did not interact much after that drama. Part of the reason is Xu Tong&#39;s intention. &quot;I need to keep a distance from the actors in order to create a sense of strangeness. Having too many personal relationships will affect my imagination of the characters in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He feels that Xin Baiqing is more I understand this, so I rarely appear outside of the role. &quot;If the audience is too familiar with your face, when you create a character again, the credibility of that character will be reduced, or the impact will be lost.&quot; It will decrease.&quot; A good actor needs to maintain a considerable degree of solitude. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WiaFJATdWFFloHdXydwOnr5AsDfw9IIQK1u6CqPj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/WiaFJATdWFFloHdXydwOnr5AsDfw9IIQK1u6CqPj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;三板AX ”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The partners of Xin Baiqing we found are very willing to talk about his performances, but it is not easy to talk about performances with him himself. Like Zhang Lu said, he was holding on to his mouth; or like Xu Tong That said, he was recycling it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rather than describing his mental journey in detail, he would rather summarize it this way:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My working method is to try my best to turn literary descriptions into visual images. The first step is my Where does the image come from? What does he look like, what is his hairstyle, what clothes he wears, whether he wears glasses, the way he walks, the way he talks, and whether he has any habitual movements. In fact, these are all learned when he was in school. The most basic. Then, some of the background of the script is not written in the script, but I want to give him some rich emotional relationships, or some experiences, so that I can imagine a deeper dimension for this character. After the performance, This character will not be so one-sided and single, and the audience will feel that he may have more aspects and three-dimensionality.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The basic skill of this actor is to observe life, there are no other skills, nothing new The content is all three-dimensional, but you have to do these three things in a down-to-earth manner, that is, the actor is armed to the teeth.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is by relying on these three things that he leaves his comfort time and time again. District and meet the challenges of new roles. &quot;When I take a role, I only consider whether I am interested in it, not whether I can control it. When I see a new role and I can&#39;t control it, I stop acting, and there will never be any progress.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first glance Look, Li Chun in &quot;The Long Confession&quot; looks nothing like Xin Baiqing. Producer Xu Jiahan recalled that the first actor selected by the crew was Zhang Luyi, who will play the younger brother Lidong, a somewhat stubborn middle-aged literary artist suffering from cancer. They asked Zhang Luyi, find yourself a brother, who is suitable? Brother Lichun is a bit like the opposite of Lidong, secular and open-minded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Luyi replied: Xin Baiqing. He felt that Xin Baiqing was a bit &quot;sultry&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So there was the first collaboration between Xin Baiqing and director Zhang Lu. In a scene, in a Japanese B&amp;B, Li Chun and his young lover Yanagawa sat opposite each other and talked, and Xin Baiqing burst into tears, &quot;It was telling and repenting. I felt that kind of expression was particularly clear.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Lu yelled, come on, one more line, and asked Xin Baiqing to say his lines to the wall. &quot;I thought at the time, wasn&#39;t the one just now bad? Of course I didn&#39;t discuss it with the director. Since there is already a stronger expression, I will repeat what the director said.&quot; In the next line, Xin Baiqing turned his back to the camera and muttered to himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the finished film, Zhang Lu used the latter one. Xin Baiqing thought, yes, Lichun may have feelings for Yanagawa, or maybe he just came here to find himself. &quot;And my kind of performance limits all possibilities to one, but makes the road narrower.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Xin Baiqing quickly understood Zhang Lu&#39;s style. He said that watching Zhang Lu&#39;s movies is like reading poetry, and there is no standard answer. When I interviewed Zhang Lu at the end of 2020, he indeed said that movies should be like poetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the role of Li Chun, Xin Baiqing won the China Film Golden Rooster Award for Best Supporting Actor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the time of &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot;, the two had a very good understanding and didn&#39;t have too much discussion. Zhang Lu would ask him if he felt comfortable acting? Quite comfortable. That’s it, take the next one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The so-called comfort (means), I think everything is right. There is no &#39;strange&#39; in this scene, there is no such uncomfortable and difficult movements, behaviors, and tone. It is waves. It is a calm, still and deep expression of expression, rather than which note pops up and becomes stronger; which note becomes deeper. Maybe it is used in this movie, and the comfortable feeling is like this.&quot; Xin Baiqing said . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Being burdened with the dissatisfaction of the times and the family, in the ambiguous relationship between the sexes and the dramatic father-son relationship, the role of Gu Wentong has a lot to play. But Xin Baiqing knew that what Zhang Lu wanted was a performance that was not externalized, or even a non-acting one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He often said that people in life are multi-faceted. You may be talking about something happily one second, but you may fall into a very self-conscious mood the next second. I don’t know why. People often get distracted and say nonsense. These are real life conditions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This puts higher demands on performers. Not acting requires a particularly strong inner concentration, otherwise you will feel that I am wrong if I don’t act? But precisely when I don’t doubt myself and am particularly determined, another unspeakable state may arise. The audience It will be captured. If you don’t act, you may need to be more fulfilled in your heart. This enrichment does not mean that your purpose is more fulfilling, but that your past life, experience, your temperament, and the connotation of your thoughts will be felt at that moment. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 29, 2023, the closing ceremony and awards ceremony of the Beijing Film Festival was held. As Zhang Lu said, Xin Baiqing really won the award. He won the &quot;Tiantan Award&quot; for Best Actor for &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot;. This is his first movie award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sD0TPDJ9dOvlC0xXjG9FRfXGk083Fk6e61ffRF8m.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sD0TPDJ9dOvlC0xXjG9FRfXGk083Fk6e61ffRF8m.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the drama &quot;Hurry Up&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Game sense &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to film and television roles, Xin Baiqing has always been an actor at the National Theater. The first major theater play was director Tian Qinxin&#39;s &quot;Hurry Up&quot; (2001). He played the protagonist Tian Han. The play included self-narration that broke the fourth wall, emotions with his cousin, his wife, and his beauty, as well as several scenes in the play. For example, the Syrian boy in &quot;Salome&quot; translated by Tian Han and Guan Hanqing in the script written by Tian Han were both played by Xin Baiqing. Later, in &quot;Red Rose and White Rose&quot; (2007), he played &quot;Liu Xiahui&quot; known to all Shanghai. In &quot;Four Generations Under One Roof&quot; (2010), he played the role of Guan Xiaohe, who lives in an alley and seeks fame and wealth from the Japanese, and won the Drama Golden Lion Award for Performance. In &quot;Green Snake&quot; (2013), he played Fahai, who was both human and divine. In 2023, he will also play Su Shi in Tian Qinxin&#39;s new play &quot;Spring Dawn on Su Di&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xin Baiqing remembers the words of director Tian Qinxin, whom he has collaborated with many times: The biggest difference between drama and film and television, or the biggest charm of drama is that it can be dressed up. Movies and TV dramas won’t look for Xin Baiqing, but Tian Qinxin will. &quot;It feels very playful to dress up this character, and it makes me suddenly enlightened. It has become a fun thing. It doesn&#39;t mean that I have to go through all the trouble to create someone. The drama is as big as the sky.&quot; , such a big yoke is put on you, no.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In more than 20 years on the stage, Xin Baiqing’s roles are not many, and he can count them on two hands. Looking back now, every role has He could still recall the stories. Compared with film and television, drama is far away from fame and fortune. Xin Baiqing himself sometimes wonders why he has never left drama? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fame and fortune may be just a moment. It&#39;s great that my play has become popular. It is recognized by so many people. I enjoy it very much, but it will pass soon. But acting in a play requires being in the rehearsal room every day. Rehearsing all the time, this kind of simple happiness is so rare. The older I get, the things, social environment, and relationships I face become more and more complicated. (Performing a play) This thing is not complicated. I can go back to simplicity If you find the place where you were when you were little, you will be particularly happy.&quot; Xin Baiqing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He has a very clean temperament. This kind of cleanliness is rare.&quot; Tian Qinxin said that in the rehearsal venue, she would sometimes be suddenly moved by Xin Baiqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, the new version of &quot;Kurst&quot; was staged. Xin Baiqing went to watch it as an audience member and felt that the younger generation of actors performed better than himself. &quot;When I was young, I was a bit heartless. I just had fun and played silly every day. I didn&#39;t care about my brain and didn&#39;t take things personally. Because it would be very painful if I pretended too much, you know?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&quot;But there is no way, life is just stuffed into my arms, and I have stuffed a lot of it into my arms over the years.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What has life stuffed into him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Fire, rice, oil and salt are all put in it. You really can&#39;t tell the details. This is living and living.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the version of &quot;Hurry&quot; played by Xin Baiqing, there is a section where Tian Han Watching a theater in Tokyo, I read a confession, to the effect that I have found my passion, just like a planet has found its orbit: &quot;I was confused when I was a child, and I probably can&#39;t understand it. I only love the color I want, I will let it pull out a track and lead me to revolve freely.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I said this line and asked Xin Baiqing if it resonated with him when he was young, but he denied it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When I was a child, I really didn’t know what it meant. I just pronounced the word out to compose a new word to express a state of sadness. What is life, what is pulling, what is my color. , I don’t know what I want. Now that I’ve reached this age, I know everything, and I don’t need to say such words anymore. I have all the insights, but it’s been a cold autumn.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Through his works, it is difficult to trace the trajectory of his climb in performance. Nor did he give a so-called “eureka moment.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I understand your question, but there is no specific node. Because life itself has no nodes. My life is stable, but are you willing to experience the stable life with your heart? I have experienced it with my heart, age, age, and stability. What time brings to people will be subtle and accumulated little by little.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He only said that if he plays Tian Han again now, it should be different. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Blunt&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2008, when director Jiang Wei was filming &quot;Latent&quot;, his first consideration was to cast Xin Baiqing and Zhu Yuanyuan to play the roles of Yu Zecheng and Cuiping. He felt that Xin Baiqing had some Literary popularity. Unfortunately, Zhu Yuanyuan was pregnant. Jiang Wei said that Xin Baiqing could go alone, but Xin Baiqing did not go to accompany the childbirth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After &quot;Latent&quot; was aired, it became a phenomenon-level TV series, winning awards all over the country. Xin Baiqing has regrets, but not regrets. This isn&#39;t the only time I&#39;ve run into a favorite character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The role Xin Baiqing wanted to play most was Faust. In Goethe&#39;s play &quot;Faust&quot;, the learned scholar makes a deal with the devil Mephistopheles, selling his soul in exchange for endless knowledge and wisdom, and willing to go to hell after death. Later, when someone actually approached him to play &quot;Faust&quot;, he refused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why didn&#39;t I act when this opportunity came to me? I struggled for a long time, and then I realized that what I wanted to act was not Goethe&#39;s Faust.&quot; He couldn&#39;t say anything. Explaining what Faust he wanted to play, he knew what he didn’t want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I feel quite blunt, and in life I feel that I am not very bright or very smart anyway.” Xin Baiqing said of himself. But he has his own little world. When he is particularly tired, or driving in a car, he watches other people play Four Kingdoms Army Chess on the Internet. Sometimes when he sees that the game is too bad, he also says that he can’t stand it anymore, so he closes it and clicks to play it again later. &quot;Just like that, I am very happy in my heart, but when I communicate with others, I become a very boring person.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xin Baiqing likes diving. Putting his life on the bottom of the water, distracting thoughts were forced to be reduced to a minimum. The oxygen content, diving depth, and direction were all no problem. When he could finally relax and take a look at the bottom of the sea, he felt that it might be similar to the feeling of being in space, and he felt better. It becomes wider. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone who is an actor is sensitive, but sensitivity can sometimes hurt oneself. As an &quot;introvert, not good at expressing people&quot;, Xin Baiqing uses this method to let himself go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jiahan is the producer of &quot;The Long Confession&quot; and &quot;The Light of the White Tower&quot;. She said, &quot;In real life, Teacher Bai Qing is very polite and harmonious with the crew. &quot;&quot;The Long Confession&quot; was filmed in Japan. Xin Baiqing did not understand Japanese, but &quot;will try his best to adapt and is unwilling to cause trouble to others.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;But you always feel that he has a little secret, and he just happened to find an outlet in the script.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, the 1993 undergraduate students of the Performance Department of the Central Academy of Drama were about to graduate and were rehearsing. During the break, a dozen classmates went to have lunch with the teacher. Walking in Dongmianhua Hutong in front of the school, the teacher asked, who among you can continue to act in dramas after graduation? The originally cheerful atmosphere suddenly became quiet. At that time, acting in a drama meant being poor, and no one said anything. Xin Baiqing added, &quot;I would be happy to act in dramas for the rest of my life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, Xin Baiqing will be 50 years old, and some of his teachers at that time have passed away. Whenever he rehearses a play, attends a class reunion, or visits his teacher&#39;s grave, he will recall that scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[微短剧的“危险”狂飙]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260414]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 14:33:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Micro short dramas are booming from all levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of market size, according to data from a third-party research report quoted by Chinese Online, the market size of short dramas in 2022 will be more than 10 billion yuan, and the scale of micro short dramas in 2023 is expected to exceed 30 billion yuan. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of market supply, according to data from the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television, the number of micro-short dramas registered for the whole year in 2021 is 398, while the number of registered micro-short dramas in 2022 is close to 2,800, a year-on-year increase of 600%; March 2023 -In August, the number of national key online micro-short dramas that have been approved for planning and registration was basically over 260, and in July and August they were 361 and 401 respectively, indicating a significant increase in supply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a company perspective, Chinese Online, Huace Film and Television, Mango Super Media, Huayi Brothers, Ningmeng Film and Television, Palm Reading Technology, and Changxin Media have all increased investment in this area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the other side, due to the &quot;kitsch&quot; of the subject matter, the market supervision of micro-short dramas still remains uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 10, Chinese Online closed at 25.40 yuan per share, a decrease of 9.19%. Previously, from November 2 to 9, the company&#39;s stock price doubled in just 6 trading days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1dd74182eae8ccd0b188c70e077d37fa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/1dd74182eae8ccd0b188c70e077d37fa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257894&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The micro-short drama &quot;Twenty-Nine&quot; starring Yang Rong has been viewed more than 800 million times on Douyin short video platform. Image source: Poster from the show&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Comfortable and Intensive&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The biggest feature of micro-short dramas is their high recycling efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese Online, a popular micro-short drama concept stock, stated in the investor exchange minutes that short dramas are characterized by short content and a large number of episodes, usually 80-100 episodes, each episode is less than two minutes, and the plot is It has strong drama, the creative content is more in line with the needs of the masses, the story is quick to reverse, and the plot is exciting and dense. Rely more on platform advertising to reach C-end customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this basis, micro-short dramas have a short commercial verification cycle and high recycling efficiency. They mainly rely on advertising. As long as the streaming side can achieve the first-day recycling target, they can continue to optimize the distribution strategy. Then achieve high ROI recovery. From script polishing to filming, production, and delivery verification, a work can complete verification and closed-loop in a short time, with a high asset transfer rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the production cycle of micro-short dramas is short, the production cost is low, and the shooting cycle is generally within a week. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If it doesn’t work, just change the subject. The cost is too low. Just shoot for another.” A micro-short drama entrepreneur told a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This allows Chinese online, which has a weak film and television foundation, to quickly enter the core track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The company has the advantage of massive IP. At present, short drama scripts are mainly derived from adaptations of online novels. The company has 5.5 million IPs and can continuously provide high-quality short drama IP adapted scripts, with outstanding long-term running capabilities.&quot; Chinese online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old content giant Huace Film and Television is also rapidly entering this market. The company disclosed that it began researching the short drama track in the second half of last year and started building teams in June this year. There are currently 6 teams, and it is also introducing screenwriters, producers, and cooperating with casting companies. &quot;The future positioning is to enter the top five of micro-short dramas.&quot; Huace said. What it considers to be its advantage is obviously its production capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Objectively, film and television giants still have advantages in laying out this track. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Ningmeng Film and Television, at the beginning of 2023, its micro-short drama &quot;Twenty-Nine&quot; had a total playback volume of more than 800 million times on the Douyin short video platform, and the average playback volume of each episode exceeded 40 million times, related topics have been played a total of 1.45 billion times on the entire site, which is the highest level among Douyin short video micro-series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But at present, the biggest feature of micro-short dramas is their &quot;refreshing feeling&quot;, and there seems to be little demand for high-quality productions. Everyone from micro-short drama entrepreneurs to middle-level executives of leading film and television companies admitted to 21st Century Business Herald reporters that the current advantages of leading film and television companies in this market are relatively limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, after the second season of &quot;Twenty-Nine&quot; was released, it ranked TOP 1 on the most popular micro-short drama list and occupied the TOP 1 spot on Douyin&#39;s micro-short drama list for 5 consecutive weeks. However, the popularity has dropped significantly compared to the first season. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Platform Changes&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Behind the popular short drama is a lonely long video. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many project leaders of film and television companies lamented to reporters from the 21st Century Business Herald that as platforms “reduce costs and increase efficiency,” it is becoming increasingly difficult to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The financial report shows that iQiyi’s content costs in 2022 will be 16.5 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 20%. In addition, the company is also promoting self-produced dramas. At present, the proportion of iQiyi’s self-made content assets continues to rise, from 32% in 2018 to 63% in 2022. iQiyi also revealed that among the new key dramas released every year, the proportion of original content will increase from 20% in 2018 to more than 50% in 2022. All of the above have squeezed the profit margins of film and television projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incentive for this change is the fragile profit model of long videos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second quarter of this year, iQiyi’s revenue was 7.802 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 17.2%; net profit attributable to the parent company was 365 million yuan, compared with a net loss of 214 million yuan in the same period last year. But from a quarter-on-quarter perspective, iQiyi’s revenue is in a declining range. Driven by &quot;Hurricane&quot;, in the first quarter, its revenue reached 8.349 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 15%; the net profit attributable to the parent company was 618.1 million yuan, while the net profit in the same period last year was 169.1 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why the performance of long video is so volatile is that user demand is becoming fragmented and the monetization efficiency is relatively low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Analysys Qianfan data, in September 2023, iQiyi’s monthly active users dropped to 568.67 million, and Tencent Video’s monthly active users dropped to 450.17 million. During the same period, Douyin’s monthly active users dropped to 797.67 million, and Kuaishou’s monthly active users dropped to 522.36 million. The difference between long and short videos is obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, from the perspective of advertising, advertisers are rushing to short videos due to higher monetization efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiangpiaopiao disclosed that in the first half of the year, its frozen lemon tea sales increased by 547.09% year-on-year, and its online channels increased by 235% year-on-year. Douyin channels accounted for about 30%, and the cumulative repurchase rate remained high. Jinzai Food also stated that in terms of online channels, the company’s new media channels such as Douyin performed well, with a year-on-year increase of approximately 600%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the marketing department of a leading beverage company told a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald that compared with long video platforms such as iQiyi, short videos have a more direct marketing effect and are much more efficient in monetization. “There are basically no big expectations for the monetization of long videos,” he said. Another founder of outdoor sports products also expressed similar views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the double attack of traffic and revenue, the long video ecology is moving towards the stock market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, content companies have to rush to micro-short dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Uncertainty&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, the micro-short drama market is also facing various problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A large number of film and television companies and even platforms are currently unwilling to be too high-profile in this business. The core lies in the policy instability of micro-short dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The standardized supervision of short dramas can be traced back to August 2020. The State Administration of Radio, Film and Television has added a rapid registration and filing module for online micro-short dramas to the key online film and television drama information filing system, marking the official inclusion of micro-short dramas into the supervision system. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2022, the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television issued a document clarifying that the review of domestic online dramas, including short plays, will be included in the management of administrative licensing matters, and it is necessary to obtain a distribution license from the relevant radio and television administrative departments before they can be broadcast and released; In November, we issued an article to carry out special rectification of mini-program micro-drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While guiding the standardized development, the State Administration of Radio, Film and Television also provides necessary support to short plays. In December 2022, the &quot;Opinions on Promoting the Prosperous Development of Short Play Creation&quot; proposed to cultivate and expand the main body of short play creation. Provide tilted support to short plays in terms of resources, talents, marketing, broadcasting, and publicity. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It must be noted that at present, cool dramas are still the mainstream in the market. According to Juduo Engine, the core of current short dramas is &quot;cool&quot;, and 90% of the themes are based on &quot;cool&quot;. There are various ways to be cool, including God of War, time travel, counterattack, rebirth and other themes. As a result, there is a tendency of &quot;kitsch&quot;. According to a reporter from the 21st Century Business Herald, regulators are paying close attention to a large amount of &quot;edge&quot; content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The market direction is full of uncertainty.” Many upstream and downstream participants in the industry stated this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, from the perspective of market size, micro-short dramas are still limited compared to long videos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, iQiyi alone’s revenue will reach 29 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 5%. This data far exceeds the overall market size of micro-short dramas in the same year and is close to the expected size of micro-short dramas in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are three main types of terminal profits from short dramas. They provide membership payment, advertising monetization and e-commerce delivery respectively. Membership payment includes regular membership fees and the purchase of a single drama. The monthly membership price for mainstream long-form video platforms is 22-25 yuan, and the membership fee for short-drama exclusive platforms is higher, around 30 yuan; the single-drama payment standard is 1-25 yuan. 3 yuan/episode, and a single episode of popular dramas can cost up to 10 yuan. Advertising revenue is also an important part of short drama revenue, including pre-roll advertising, ad placement, and IP authorized marketing. Among them, pre-roll advertising is exclusive to long video platforms, and soft advertising placement is a common method for short video platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, this profit model still tends to be short-term and fast, and is still far from a truly mature business model. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[此情可待成追忆：本师吴金华先生逝世十年祭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260212]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/xJaaVqlw63PvYAuRlUUy4wQFy4drzzlOu07pkyhn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/xJaaVqlw63PvYAuRlUUy4wQFy4drzz lOu07pkyhn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Wu Jinhua, Distinguished Professor of Fudan University and Researcher of the Institute of Ancient Books (1943-2013) 2007 Photos taken during his visit to the United States in December. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, nine years had passed since I graduated from Nanjing Normal University with an undergraduate degree in ancient literature. One spring afternoon, I went up to the fourth floor with my four-year-old daughter in my arms. When I took out the key and opened the door, I woke up from my own heavy breathing. Because I was unwilling to let my life go down, I decided to go back to college to start another kind of growth. At that moment, I thought of you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, after graduating from college, I stopped thinking about you for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I saw you in college, you had a bald head like a European monk, energetic eyes behind big glasses, and thick lips that were always smiling. Except in summer, he seems to always wear a blue or black tunic suit with one or two pens in the top pocket. A classmate from the previous class said that they saw you wiping the blackboard with the sleeves of your Mao suit while you were engaged in class. We didn’t take your class very often, so we never saw you do this in class, but I did see you darken your face after class. The corners, cuffs, pockets, etc. of the tunic suit looked like they were stained with chalk dust. I was admitted to Nanjing Normal University in 1984. The various inexplicable and severe restrictions I had suffered before led to strong rebellion in the tolerant university. During those four years, I couldn’t see anything, including you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As graduation approaches, my view of you has changed a lot. I went to your home to receive guidance on my graduation thesis. That was the only individual communication in the past four years. The house was very crowded and there was no desk, so you invited me to sit down at a small round dining table filled with books and started talking about my thesis. During this period, I have been attracted by a copy of &quot;The Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; spread out in the middle of the table. The blank space on the opened page is filled with long and short school slogans written in different pens. When you talk about it later, you forget why, as if you are looking for an example to illustrate, you start to flip through the book. Then I saw clearly that every page of the book was filled with colorful words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AvnX5ym43zUn0CFTMDMl2eAOkOZRhgh5Toicl6Pv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1045&quot; height= &quot;780&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AvnX5ym43zUn0CFTMDMl2eAOkOZRhgh5Toicl6Pv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; annotated by Mr. Wu Jinhua. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am very ashamed. What you talked to me about academics that day was quickly forgotten. Only the appearance of this book still comes to mind from time to time. After graduating from Nanjing Normal University, I returned to my hometown of Changshu. After only a year or two, my arrogance naturally turned into decadence. In the next few years, I rarely read. When the weather is bad, I wander aimlessly by Shang Lake at the foot of Yushan Mountain, letting the rain and snow fall from my head. Try to persuade yourself and try to play cards day and night with all kinds of people from all walks of life. Smoking more and more aggressively, especially when alone. I often drank, got drunk late at night, and sat alone in the darkness on the side of the road, crying silently. It wasn&#39;t until this spring afternoon that everything came to an abrupt end. I decided to start over and do something seriously for a long time. What came to mind again at that time was the &quot;Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; filled with words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I wrote to you. I didn’t even know that you left Suiyuan two years ago (Editor’s note: the former site of Yuan Mei Suiyuan, the old campus of Nanjing Normal University). Your reply from Shanghai said that it was a pleasure to know that you wanted to come to study. Professionally, as long as we don&#39;t completely abandon what we have learned and review it, not many people can compete. What you have to do is to concentrate on preparing foreign languages. In the winter of that year, in the last two months before the postgraduate entrance examination, it seemed to be raining all the time. I locked myself in a room, lowered the curtains, put away the clock, and read, recited, and dictated, day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I came to your home after being admitted to Fudan University, you came out of the study. Because you still retained the memories from ten years ago, you looked much older and had less hair, but your eyes Still energetic. I said, I came too late, I should have come ten years ago. You immediately said with a smile on your face, it&#39;s not too late, I just started at your age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first year, you asked me to translate the papers of Japanese scholars in conjunction with foreign language learning. Before submitting the completed translation, you asked me to write a translator&#39;s note. For those few hundred words of notes, you revised it four or five times. Through repeated frustrations, I began to slowly understand what &quot;negative rhetoric&quot; is. When you finally changed the schedule, you smiled and said gently that it seemed that you had been away from school for too long and you were no longer in the mood. But it doesn’t matter, just start slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the first school year, you asked me to go to the library to borrow different versions of &quot;Jiankang Records&quot; and use my summer vacation time to do the revision. After school started, I reported the findings of the review to you, and you seemed very happy. I remember when my wife came over to pour us water, you turned around and said to your wife seriously, &quot;Ji Zhongping is very attentive. I have read this book so many times, but I didn&#39;t see many of the problems he found.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/TwzgBI2zDO3U2Oc4bzNaQFJrUsHg4ccOFXYQFWid.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;843&quot; height= &quot;723&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/TwzgBI2zDO3U2Oc4bzNaQFJrUsHg4ccOFXYQFWid.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257544&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qing Yi Xun Tang published &quot;Jiankang Record&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I came to Fudan again to study for a Ph.D., it was the first time I talked about choosing a doctoral thesis topic. You introduced what you discovered. A category of words created using classic sentences. I blurted out that the use of such words should be to make the rhetoric more elegant. After hearing this, you patted your thigh with an exaggerated movement that was completely beyond my expectation and said, Great, this understanding is great, this is your invention. Well, let&#39;s call this type of words Yayan words, and you can do this topic. The next day, I went to class in the liberal arts building and saw my senior who had just finished class and said to me, the teacher said in class that you have an important invention. A few days later, I met a friend from East China Normal University and told me that Teacher Wu went to their school for a meeting and said at the meeting that I had an amazing invention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In those years when I was studying at Fudan, after having long conversations with you, on the way back to school late at night, I would always stand up and pedal my bike hard, eager to sit down at my desk the next second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was a teenager, I read books such as &quot;The Detectives of Sherlock Holmes&quot; and &quot;Three Heroes and Five Righteousnesses&quot;. I imagined that when I grew up, I could become a detective who pursues the truth and an impartial judge. However, I realized that this was unrealistic when I became an adult. . You taught me how to do collation and exegesis, and how to make reliable inferences through thorough investigation and meticulous analysis. I will pursue the truth relentlessly and base myself on the facts without any compromise. Everything depends on me. Discovering a typo is like exposing a villain; restoring an original word is like clearing up an unjust case. Sitting at my desk late at night, I felt like Sherlock Holmes sitting in a carriage on his way to investigate a case, or like Bao Zheng sitting in the lobby of the Kaifeng government office. I don’t have any great talents to gain wealth in the world, nor do I have any ambition to achieve greatness in the world. When I come to this world, I have to live in a certain way. If I can live my life with this feeling besides being harmless to humans and animals. I have been content for the rest of my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I remember one time, when I said goodbye to you and said I was leaving because a friend had an appointment to play football, you asked me, does football really fascinate you so much? At the time I just said yes. I didn&#39;t tell you that day why I never tire of football, because it was the only relatively fair game I could participate in. On our court, there are only simple and clear rules, relying only on one&#39;s own skills and efforts, everything is under the sun, and all power and influence are meaningless. I don&#39;t know any skills other than poetry, I just like to participate in this kind of game with my own ability and enthusiasm. Only this kind of game can allow me to truly feel the joy of life, even though no one cheers, there is no income, and there is even the risk of breaking my muscles and bones at any time. I am very superficial, and my understanding of knowledge is no different from playing football. Although I still play football twice a week to this day, I know very well that in my lifetime, my strength and speed will gradually fade away. One day, I will no longer be able to run as much as I want on the court. However, even then, , I can still continue to experience the same fun on my desk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first met you, I brought you some tea. You told me seriously that this would never happen again. We don’t need this when we get along. If you can write an article and show it to me, that would be better than giving me anything. From then on, all I can think of in return is to write something to you. In the days I spent with you, I don’t remember saying any words of gratitude in front of you in a serious manner. You passed away suddenly in June 2013. I rushed back to Shanghai from Kyoto. I came down from your house alone late that night and sat in the small garden next to the building. I regretted that I had not had time to say many things to you in person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know if we can meet again in another world in the future. If not, then we will never have the chance to say those words in person, so I have no choice but to write the above words. Although It&#39;s just a very small part of it. If you have a soul, you will surely understand what I mean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/308zXIMnik3dYv81fwpnBsMOKS9TN8ELyu6dHtcC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1242&quot; height= &quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/308zXIMnik3dYv81fwpnBsMOKS9TN8ELyu6dHtcC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Jinhua and Mr. Jao Tsung-I (left), taken in 1993. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to gratitude, there is also an apology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although my lifestyle has changed completely since I came to Fudan to study, some of the beliefs I formed since I was a student at Nanjing Normal University have not changed. Those beliefs may just be a joke in the eyes of others today, but I am willing to stick to them for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was studying for a master&#39;s degree at Fudan University, the Institute of Ancient Books Collation held a meeting for students to evaluate scholarships. The meeting had a section that was equivalent to self-declaration. The students who spoke in front talked about what they had done and what they had published, and they talked very enthusiastically. Although I have done some research and published papers in journals, I cannot speak like they did. Seeing that it was almost my turn, I stood up quickly, picked up the blank form that was given to me, handed it to the teacher who was hosting the meeting, and said that I was ashamed and felt that I could not compare with them, so I quit first. The next day, you called my dormitory and told me seriously that as long as you applied, you would have won at least the second prize. This is very important, don’t do this next time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, I still don’t think this is important. My idea is very simple, because I didn’t win this award, I got through with it. What kind of honor can there be for an award that requires application only? After the doctoral thesis was written, you told me twice that after the defense, we would go to the Academy of Social Sciences to apply for the Lu Shuxiang Award, or go to Peking University to apply for the Wang Li Award. The first time I pretended not to hear, but the second time I told you clearly that I would not apply. When I was studying for a PhD at Fudan University, I won the highest award in liberal arts, but I never thought about applying. You applied privately on my behalf. You suddenly called me after 11 o&#39;clock the next night and told me that you had applied for me, and now you only need me to go to the award meeting the next day to make an introduction. I hesitated for a while and reluctantly agreed. Of course I know this is all your hard work, and I really can&#39;t bear to disobey you late at night. The next day I only used half of the allotted time and ended my uncomfortable self-cutting hastily. When I left the venue, I felt relaxed all over. I didn&#39;t care whether I won an award or not. I just felt that I had gone through this process, which was more or less an explanation to you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I like football very much, I rarely take the initiative to ask people to play football. Because I don&#39;t like others to accompany me reluctantly because of my invitation. I don’t like the state of being in my heart but not in my heart, and I certainly don’t want my friends to be like this. The games we play are just a bunch of ragtag games, but everyone is united physically and mentally. It is a game without any dirty things other than football. Although my technical level is limited, I thought I was enjoying the real joy of gaming. Any association with anything other than football would probably make me feel uncomfortable. It makes me feel a little sad to think that one day we all in this world will inevitably end in clouds and rain. However, I am not depressed at all when I think that all the hard work I have done will eventually be wiped out. Every run, every pass, every shot, while doing your best, the fun is in it. The moment I came off the field, I had finished enjoying football. In the days to come, if you tell me how I was in that game, I actually feel nothing. I rarely remember what kind of goals I have scored, even if they were just played yesterday. What I never forget every day is just where to start the next game. I have little knowledge and cannot give any lofty meaning to my profession. I just hope that the research I engage in can be as pure as football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VRZYDxiw00rhnLfbpNMeNxJZTtpKlMrnQUwItYFq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;531&quot; height= &quot;742&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VRZYDxiw00rhnLfbpNMeNxJZTtpKlMrnQUwItYFq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Jinhua graduated from the Chinese Department of Nanjing Normal University in 1966. In 1968, he was assigned to teach in a middle school in Ganyu County, Xuzhou area. In 1978, he returned to his alma mater and studied the history of Chinese under the tutelage of Mr. Xu Fu. After graduating in 1981, he stayed at the school to teach. In 1986, he won the second prize of the Young Linguist Award of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. In 1991, he was promoted to professor. In 1995, he was transferred to Fudan University. Institute of Collation of Ancient Books, author of &quot;Exegesis of the Chronicles of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, &quot;Research and Interpretation of Shishuoxinyu&quot;, &quot;A Series of Research on Ancient Documents&quot;, &quot;A Series of Research on the Chronicles of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I quit my original job when I came to study for a Ph.D. During the holiday in early October of the first semester, you asked me to go to your house for dinner. During this period, you asked me if I have any requirements for my workplace after graduation. I said it didn&#39;t matter to me, as long as I had a bite to eat. You said, then see if you are willing to stay. I said of course that&#39;s good, so I can always be by your side. Then you said that you believed that I would have no problems with my business, but you hoped that I could do some things outside of business to ensure that I could stay. I told you on the spot that I didn&#39;t want to. I just wanted to make a living based on my own ability. You mentioned it twice after that, and I explicitly rejected it both times. The last time, I even said that if I had to do that to stay, then I would go somewhere else. If I have to do academic work that way, then I would rather live on the streets pulling a cart and carrying bags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I know that&#39;s arrogant and rude to say. In fact, I have never seen and can&#39;t imagine anyone talking to you like that. Of course I fully understand that you have my life in mind, but if I do what you say, I will have trouble sleeping at night. These beliefs have been rooted in my heart since I was a teacher in Nanjing. They are the promises I made to myself. Even when I was dissolute, I never violated them at all. Perhaps, for others, there shouldn&#39;t be any doubts about doing something like that, because everyone does it, but I am me, and in my opinion, no matter how many people do it, it is impossible to change this kind of thing. nature, I cannot deceive myself, so I am willing to accept the life I choose. I think if the research we did is credible, it must be the only judgment made based on real materials and strict logic. The beliefs I adhere to are the same kind of non-dual judgment. It is impossible for me to change because of the intervention of anyone other than facts and logic, not even you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You are very strict with students. My wife once told me privately that even several older doctoral students were scolded by you until they cried in front of them. I don’t know why you are so tolerant to me. You have never spoken harshly, so that I have the confidence to speak freely in front of you again and again, especially for those beliefs that are ridiculous in the eyes of others, but you always smile gently and make some remarks. Advice, and ultimately make it clear that you respect my choice. I admit that if you were still alive, I still would not apologize to you for things like the above. Because although I am stubborn, during the time when I was studying with you, I regarded you as the judge of this world to a certain extent. I need to state the facts clearly to you, and then get a fair ruling from you. . It&#39;s not that I don&#39;t respect you, but I&#39;m afraid that my apology will change your original decision. In my opinion, such a change of judgment, even if it is beneficial to me, no longer has the meaning of a ruling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has been ten years since you went to another world, and I no longer need you to make any judgments. Therefore, please accept my apology now. I apologize to you for all my past arrogance. Apologize. Forgive me, more than 20 years ago, I just wanted to go back to the peach blossom land I once had. I didn’t know it at that time. Things have changed, and the place I yearned for has already kept pace with the times. But I have always been like that warrior who is searching for a sword, stubbornly guarding that place. mark. Forgive me, I don’t want to live just for food, that’s no different than a dolphin or a dog. I want a life with wine. The gentle smile you show in the face of those unbridled smiles is a great comfort to an inappropriately lonely student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People often say that once you are a teacher, you will always be a father. This is just a matter of etiquette, because how much emotion can be created in a day&#39;s interaction. Deep feelings are the accumulation of emotions generated after long-term mutual understanding. I know there are teachers who are different from you, but for more than ten years, you are the only one to me. To this day, I still feel lucky that on that spring afternoon twenty-six years ago, when I said goodbye to comfort and wanted to start another kind of growth, you adopted me, just like a father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[药品集采12小时：“割肉”也不想丢标]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260396]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2bf7fc80a8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2bf7fc80a8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257839&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;This collective purchase 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased, and the prices of the selected drugs were reduced by an average of 58%, the second largest price reduction in history. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;If the company&#39;s market share in the next four years was determined within 12 hours, how would you choose? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the morning of Monday, November 6, 2023, the temperature in Shanghai dropped sharply, but there were crowds of people outside the Fengxian District Conference Center and the discussion was lively. The ninth batch of centralized bulk procurement of state-organized drugs is underway here, and representatives of various pharmaceutical companies carrying sealed quotation information materials are waiting anxiously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;We have ten manufacturers bidding together for our drug varieties, and the competition is fierce, (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai , STKaiti;&quot;>;Long procurement cycle&lt;/span>;) is both a temptation and a challenge. I personally think it will prompt companies to further lower their quotations.&quot; A representative of a pharmaceutical company from Shangqiu, Henan told a reporter from Southern Weekend that the company is It was my first time to participate in the national centralized drug procurement, and I started preparing for this round of application since passing the consistency evaluation half a year ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Starting at eight o&#39;clock, business representatives poured into the first floor of the conference center. Within 12 hours, a total of 382 products from 262 companies participated in the bidding. The staff of the notary office will unseal, announce and read out the product specifications and quotations of each pharmaceutical company one by one, and then release the list of proposed winners; the proposed pharmaceutical companies will then Transfer to another hotel conference center to wait - enter into groups according to the order of drugs, and select and confirm the supply area in the next four-year procurement cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that there were pharmaceutical distribution, local state-owned enterprises and other related enterprises inside and outside the site eagerly waiting for the event. Although these companies themselves are not participating in this collective purchase, they are also looking forward to the results of the ninth batch of collective purchases, especially if they can collide with some cooperation opportunities with the selected pharmaceutical companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At about 19:00 on November 6, the National Medical Insurance Administration announced that 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased in this centralized purchase, and the average price of the selected drugs was reduced by 58%. It can save 18.2 billion yuan in drug costs every year - the second largest price reduction in history, second only to the previous record high of the first national procurement after the 4+7 pilot (59%). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Once the bid is lost, it will be &quot;sidelined&quot; for the next four years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The ninth batch of centralized procurement It covers medications for common and chronic diseases such as infections, tumors, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, gastrointestinal diseases, and mental illnesses, as well as key drugs such as emergency drugs and shortage drugs. At present, during the period of high incidence of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection, the much-anticipated azithromycin oral suspension is also on the list of this centralized purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;What is different from the first eight batches of centralized procurement is that once selected, the procurement cycle will be extended from two years to four years, that is, from the implementation date to December 2027 March 31st. This is more attractive to pharmaceutical companies than in previous years. On the morning of November 6, many business representatives kept discussing the topic of extending the procurement cycle while waiting for declarations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;While waiting, a representative of a Jiangxi pharmaceutical company looked embarrassed while holding a thick stack of written documents. &quot;During the eighth batch of collective purchases, we did not win the selection for an exclusive product with a high market share, and most of the volume on the market was &#39;divided up&#39; by several successful bidders. Therefore, we participated in this collective purchase, even if we &#39;cut the meat&#39; We don’t want to lose the bid, we have to keep the production line.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Hengwei, deputy general manager of the marketing center of Zhonghuan Pharmaceutical Group Co., Ltd., introduced to Southern Weekend reporters that the three projects they applied for Two products are planned to be selected. “Both are new products that have just been introduced into the Chinese market, and are also recommended drugs in the diagnosis and treatment guidelines. Although the current market sales are not large, it is expected to have a large growth in the next four years. Taking into account the patient Drug accessibility and hospitals will give priority to the centralized procurement of drugs from the winning bidders, and we have shown the greatest sincerity for this centralized procurement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Jiang Changsong, assistant to the dean of the National Medical Insurance Research Institute of Capital Medical University and director of the price procurement office, said that the procurement cycle of centralized procurement has been extended to four years for the first time, further ensuring The stability of drug use in medical institutions also means that if pharmaceutical companies &quot;lose their bids&quot;, they will have to watch their huge market share &quot;sideline&quot; in the next four years. &quot;National centralized drug procurement means large and stable quantities, and the supply cycle To ensure long-term growth, companies must exchange prices for volume and ensure supply.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to a report from the National Medical Insurance Administration, among the pharmaceutical companies participating in this centralized procurement, 266 products from 205 companies have been qualified for selection, including 200 domestic companies. 260 products from pharmaceutical companies and 6 products from 5 international pharmaceutical companies (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Including 1 original research drug and 5 imported generic drugs&lt;/span>;), the proportion of bidding companies planning to be selected is about 78%, with an average of 6.5 companies planning to be selected for each variety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Amiodarone injection to treat arrhythmia, dopamine injection to rescue shock, oxytocin injection to induce labor, etc. 5 kinds of shortage medicines and emergency rescue For pharmaceuticals, we use the &quot;volume-driven&quot; procurement method to stabilize corporate expectations and achieve a balance between multiple goals of ensuring supply and reasonably reducing prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/065d42ac9d. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/065d42ac9d.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257840&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the morning of November 6, 2023, representatives of pharmaceutical companies submitted application materials on the first floor of the Fengxian District Conference Center in Shanghai. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Fierce battle: The battle for pharmaceutical companies’ supply areas&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;November On the morning of the 6th, after the acceptance of application materials and the disclosure of application information ended, the companies to be selected could not relax their nerves because they would face another &quot;fierce battle&quot; that afternoon - the selection and confirmation of supply areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to the &quot;National Drug Centralized Procurement Document&quot; released by the National Drug Joint Procurement Office on October 13, 2023, the companies to be selected must first determine their main suppliers. Region, the first-ranked company will give priority to selecting one region among the supply regions. All companies to be selected will confirm the remaining regions in order. Each company will select one region at a time. Repeat the above process until all region selections are confirmed. The selection process for the reserve area is similar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, the purchase quantities of all drugs in different specifications in various provinces and regions are also announced, which can be used by applying companies to formulate constituency strategies accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the afternoon of November 6, two large conference rooms were prepared at the constituency site, one for business representatives to wait, and the other for confirming supply area information . The organizer calls the numbers one by one according to the drug types, and after checking the ID cards and authorization letters, the companies enter the selection areas in groups. This process starts around 14:00 that day and continues until the evening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Tian Yong, executive deputy general manager of Qilu Pharmaceutical Group Sales Corporation, told Southern Weekend reporters that there are multiple considerations for corporate constituencies. “First look at the donor district hospital report. How big the volume is? Secondly, it depends on the market capacity of the province. Thirdly, it depends on the importance that enterprises attach to different regions. For example, enterprises tend to choose Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou to enhance brand awareness. For example, our Shandong enterprises certainly want to choose the area at their doorstep, but they also Maybe he wasn’t selected and was picked by a company with a higher ranking.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Some business representatives also mentioned that some western provinces may not be popular in the electoral process due to low reporting volume and high distribution costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed at the scene that after the first round of companies entered the conference hall to select areas, it took more than an hour for people to come out one after another. Representatives of pharmaceutical companies should adjust their constituency plans in a timely manner based on the conditions of their competitors. Someone not only recorded his own district selection, but also made notes on the district selection of other companies. The filled-in notes attracted onlookers. People competed to take photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Determining the main drug supply and supply areas is largely to avoid situations where the centralized procurement of drugs cannot be supplied in sufficient quantity in time or the selected company is disqualified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Starting from this year (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Collection of medicines to ensure supply&lt;/span >;) Judging from the situation, it is much better than before.&quot; Gao Xiaoyan, deputy director of Shanghai No. 7 People&#39;s Hospital, told Southern Weekend reporters. Zhang Lan, director of the Pharmacy Department of Xuanwu Hospital of Capital Medical University (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as Xuanwu Hospital&lt;/span>;), also said that hospitals all hope to collect drugs collectively Achieving quality and quantity supply requires the guarantee of a long-term mechanism, including the supervision and evaluation of winning bidders by relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/fc7500b81f. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/fc7500b81f.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;From the afternoon to the evening of November 6, 2023, the companies to be selected will enter the venue in groups according to drug types and select supply areas. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Scientific and rational use of drugs attract attention&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;National Drugs From the beginning, centralized purchasing focused on large varieties, and now it has progressed to include all varieties that are clinically deemed necessary. In the implementation of each batch, Ruijin Hospital covers a relatively large number of varieties. So far, it has The procurement cycle of the first five batches of centralized medicines has been completed, and the sixth batch is in progress.&quot; Ruijin Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;The following Bian Xiaolan, director of the Pharmacy Department of Ruijin Hospital, said that medical institutions are now very concerned about how to use drugs more scientifically and rationally in the next step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Since 2018, the National Medical Insurance Administration has organized nine batches of national drug procurement, including a total of 374 kinds of drugs, with an average reduction of more than 50%. Zhang Lan, director of the Pharmacy Department of Xuanwu Hospital, said that centralized purchasing has been carried out on a regular basis, and clinicians have been observing the efficacy of centralized purchasing of generic drugs for some time. On the basis of respecting the patient&#39;s wishes, doctors will combine the diagnosis and treatment guidelines and the patient&#39;s condition to provide patients with Choose the right medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In response to some voices saying that generic drugs selected through centralized purchasing may not be as effective as original drugs, Xuanwu Hospital has led a number of hospitals with strong research capabilities to conduct centralized purchasing and selection in batches. Real-world research on generic drugs. A recently published study covering 29 medical institutions in 16 provinces across the country and about 140,000 real cases showed that the clinical efficacy and safety of generic drugs selected through centralized procurement are equivalent to those of the original drugs (see Southern Weekend’s October 22 report for details&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/259061&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;140,000 cases, 2-year PK, centralized purchasing of generic drugs What is the efficacy and safety?》&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Currently, (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;generic drugs and Original drugs&lt;/span>;) differences are within controllable range. Moreover, the drug configuration of different hospitals will be slightly different according to the actual situation. Our hospital tends to be equipped with both centralized drugs and original drugs, with the patient as the center and combining their needs. The medication plan will be comprehensively considered based on disease progression, past medication, etc.,&quot; Bian Xiaolan told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Ruijin Hospital selected endocrine metabolism-related drugs and cardiovascular and cerebrovascular drugs based on clinical characteristics, and participated in the second and third batches of national centralized procurement led by Xuanwu Hospital. Real-world studies of generic pharmaceuticals. Bian Xiaolan said that there are now more and more evaluation systems and tools. For example, Shanghai is developing a comprehensive drug clinical evaluation management system, and relevant research will be announced in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Zhang Lan introduced that real-world research on the fourth and fifth batches of generic drugs selected by the national centralized procurement has been launched, and the original data collection and reporting process will be more perfect in the future. Provide evidence-based support for clinical medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[危险的快递驿站：一场不该发生的意外]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh20BlLq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;589&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh2 0BlLq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The doctor asked us to prepare for the worst&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At noon on August 25, 2023, Zhang Xiang, who was on a business trip, received When I got the call that my wife was injured and rushed back to Taiyuan, Shanxi Province, it was already past two o&#39;clock in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The son was sitting on an iron chair in the waiting area, keeping his mother&#39;s mobile phone, myopia glasses, and the pair of white sandals that he had thrown off when he fell from the second floor. Lin Mei was lying on the hospital bed with her eyes open and her face pale. She was soon sent to the intensive care unit (ICU). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon that day, Lin Mei had cut the vegetables. The message pushed by the Tmall APP on her mobile phone showed that the plasticine purchased online for her son had arrived at the Cainiao Station near the community. She put down the kitchen knife, casually wore a pair of jeans and a pair of white sandals, and took her son out to pick up the express delivery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If everything goes well, she will pick up the express delivery and return home in 10 minutes and prepare lunch. They had just moved into this new house, and the developer called the couple to apply for a real estate certificate together. Unfortunately, the housing management center was off work at that time, and they agreed to do it as soon as they got back from a business trip. She and her husband are high school classmates. They have known each other for 20 years and been married for more than ten years. After working hard together, they finally have a car, a house and a 10-year-old son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The first floor of the station is a convenience store, and the second floor is the Cainiao Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by respondent)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from the later surveillance video that when picking up the parcel, Lin Mei was looking at the pickup code on her mobile phone while looking for the express delivery on the shelf. She did not notice at all that there was an open hole under her feet. , she unfortunately fell into the hole at her feet while looking sideways for the courier. The opening is usually used by the boss to load and unload goods. The height from the opening on the second floor to the ground on the first floor is 2.8 meters. The opening should usually be closed, but it was not closed in time when the incident occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Cainiao Station uses a steel frame and steel plate structure to divide the space of a shop into two floors. The first floor is a convenience store selling fruits and vegetables, and the second floor is for express delivery. You usually need to go to the second floor to find the items. Self-service scan code pickup. The express delivery station and the convenience store have the same owner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the owner of the inn, he once fell from the entrance of the cave. At that time, he accidentally dodged and fell. He only injured his leg and rested for a while. &quot;He had psychological defenses, but my wife didn&#39;t have any psychological defenses. She was completely confused when she fell and had no idea what happened.&quot; Zhang Xiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lin Mei in the hospital bed&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Outside the ICU door, Zhang Xiang wrote a few lines of note about &quot;Don&#39;t think about it&quot; and asked the nurse to send it in. He also added in the blank space of the paper &quot;You can visit at five o&#39;clock every afternoon&quot;, drew two smiling faces, and included a pen for him to send in. Lin Mei can write something. When the note was sent out later, it was wet and there was no writing on it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After his vital signs stabilized, he underwent three surgeries in succession, and various complications occurred, including pneumonia, urinary system infection, pressure ulcers, and blood clots. &quot;The four major complications accounted for all, and there were new ones every day. Challenge.&quot; Zhang Xiang lost more than ten kilograms in more than a month. &quot;It&#39;s so painful!&quot; He described that the filter to treat blood clots was implanted into the blood vessel from the thigh when it was made, and was removed from the neck when it was removed. come out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first major surgery was cervical spine surgery, and Zhang Xiang was deeply impressed. He remembered that when Lin Mei came out of the operating room, she was lying down with a relaxed expression and a smile on her face, &quot;Because I felt that the operation was finally completed, and I felt that it might be very promising and that she might be cured soon.&quot; Later, like this The smiles are getting fewer and fewer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yu, the attending physician at the Rehabilitation Medicine Department of the Second Hospital of Shanxi Medical University, told Southern People Weekly that during the fall, Lin Mei hit her head on the side wall and suffered a cervical vertebra fracture. Partial spinal cord injury, resulting in quadriplegia. The lower limbs are completely immobile and the upper limbs have very little movement. There is a loss of sensation and movement in the legs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A note written by Zhang Xiang when Lin Mei was in the ICU&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;He explained that the cervical spinal cord is a part of the brain tissue that extends from the brainstem to the spinal canal of the body. After injury, it is not controlled by the brainstem, so symptoms of paralysis will occur. Spinal cord injury results in a loss of the ability to transmit sensations to the brain, resulting in abnormalities in lower-level neurons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The doctor asked us to prepare for the worst.&quot; Zhang Xiang said, &quot;It&#39;s too painful. If cancer is a death sentence, spinal cord injury is equivalent to Ling Chi.&quot; Lin Mei was unable to turn over on her own, and even He cannot move his toes, only pathological twitching, unable to control his nerves voluntarily, has no sweating function, and cannot sense cold or heat. She would suddenly shiver but not feel cold. Sometimes I feel very cold, like being in a world of ice and snow, but actually the quilt covers me well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My upper limbs have little strength and I cannot hold the dishes, so I can only feed him. Zhang Xiang rented a house near the hospital and cooked for his wife. His family members and caregivers took turns taking care of him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yu said that there is very little hope of recovery from complete spinal cord injury, and there is almost no hope of recovery. &quot;Lin Mei is currently in a state of complete injury. It is very difficult to recover both legs, but we cannot make a conclusion on the time. Our hospital usually takes about 3 months. If the signs and symptoms are still the same after 3 months , you can draw a conclusion.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Lin Mei’s cumulative treatment expenses have exceeded 180,000 yuan, and there will be many expenses in the future. After many communications, Cainiao has only paid 20,000 yuan so far, and the owner of Cainiao Station has paid 35,000 yuan. For more than a month after the incident, the rookie inn was still operating normally, and even the hole was still in use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An accident that should not have happened completely changed the fate of a family and the life of a 37-year-old woman. Her son had just entered the fifth grade of elementary school, and she might be in a hospital bed for the rest of her life. spend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The accident exposed many hidden dangers of the express delivery station model. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Dangerous Occurrence: How does Cainiao Station operate? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The owner of a rookie inn in a county told &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; that his store was opened two years ago, and there are two relatives in the store to help. &quot;For a normal inn, two or three people are enough.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;According to his description, Cainiao does not charge a franchise fee, and the initial investment to open a Cainiao Station is not high: you need to purchase scanners, workbenches, cloud monitoring, shelves and other equipment from the Cainiao official website, and the cost is about 1 About 10,000 yuan; plus the 3,000 yuan deposit, store rent, and water and electricity bills, the cost of opening a rookie post station is basically about 30,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of store review, “You need to submit an application online after looking at the place and house. The store’s requirements are not strict. After the application is completed, they will come over to see it. Then go directly to the courier or courier company. The person in charge of the area can negotiate the price.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The income source of the post station is mainly cooperation with the express company, and the express company pays the delivery fee and mailing income to the owner of the post station. The official website of Cainiao Station shows that the delivery fee for each express delivery is 0.5-1 yuan, and the shipping income is 3-5 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rapid coverage of the post station model is also related to the intensifying price war in the express delivery industry. When express delivery companies trade price for scale, profits will inevitably be affected, resulting in lower outlet delivery fees and further compression of profit margins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to save the cost of terminal distribution in the &quot;last mile&quot;, express delivery stations came into being. Survey data from the China Logistics Association shows that terminal distribution costs account for more than 30% of the total costs in the logistics industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Jun was once a self-operated express delivery outlet operator under an e-commerce platform, responsible for the &quot;last mile&quot; end delivery. &quot;The company has indeed made a lot of money.&quot; She mentioned that the express delivery company is responsible for renting houses. Fees, electricity and water bills, and free computer equipment and camera installation. The basic salary of three people at the outlet needs to be paid. In addition, the delivery fee for each express item needs to be paid. The operator only needs to pay a deposit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She and her relatives have been operating the outlet for about 6 years, and the delivery fee has gradually decreased from 4 yuan at the earliest to 1.5 yuan and 1 yuan. In this store, two people are responsible for delivering express delivery, and one person is responsible for guarding the store, responsible for dividing items, sending express delivery, and handling returns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They will deliver the goods to each customer&#39;s door and call them one by one. At around 4 o&#39;clock in the morning, I need to get up and go to the highway intersection to pick up the express delivery, and then come back to unload the goods and scan the code to separate the parcels. Every day&#39;s parcels must be delivered on the same day. When facing consumers directly, you will encounter various situations. If you want to do this job well, you must have a strong sense of service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, the e-commerce platform shut down its self-operated express delivery company due to high logistics costs, and Chen Jun stopped operating it. &quot;Compared with the ones we did before, this express delivery station model does save a lot of costs for the express delivery company and saves the energy of the courier, but it is not as convenient for users as before.&quot; The express delivery company is fully responsible for end-of-line delivery , it became the inn owner who was responsible for his own profits and losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competition in the industry is fierce, and there are more and more brands of express delivery stations, such as Jitu Express Station, Yuantong Mama Station, Zhongtong Tuxi Life... There will even be multiple express stations in one community. Some netizens use their own Complaints from experience: &quot;Because the community is relatively large, I picked up 6 parcels from 6 different stations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Delivery fees also continue to fall. Two rookie station owners interviewed by &quot;Southern People Weekly&quot; Said that in their area, the delivery fees are only 0.3 yuan and 0.5 yuan per order respectively, which are both lower than the prices a few years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The Cainiao Station in my community has changed seven or eight owners in the past two years.” A netizen said that the transfer fee of this kind of station is generally not low. &quot;Po Lee&quot; situation - the money earned from operating the inn is not as much as the transfer fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, running a side business becomes an option that can increase your income source. According to the official website of Cainiao Station, it mentioned in the introduction &quot;How does Cainiao Station make money?&quot; In addition to the stable fee income, relying on the fixed flow of people brought by the station, it can run side businesses, sell daily necessities, fast-selling products, etc. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the problem is that, as a high-frequency life scenario, express delivery service is the critical &quot;last mile&quot;. If the shop owner cannot invest enough energy, it will be difficult to ensure service quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was the case at the rookie station where Lin Mei had an accident. In this store, the post station has become a side business, and the main business is a fruit and vegetable supermarket. &quot;Since everyone is coming, this is a natural drainage channel, so they put the fruits and vegetables on the first floor, and pick up express delivery on the second floor, and it is self-service.&quot; Zhang Xiang mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUOJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUUOJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Drilling &quot;holes&quot; privately in the steel frame structure poses safety risks. The &quot;hole&quot; was open at the time of the incident, and Lin Mei fell out of it &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The criticized franchise Model and legal risks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Data from the State Post Bureau show that from 2010 to 2022, my country’s express delivery business volume increased 47.3 times. The rapid development of e-commerce has brought huge demand growth to the express delivery industry. The express delivery station model came into being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;JD.com has built its own logistics since 2007, and has won a reputation among customers with its high-quality services. Alibaba is well aware that the cost of building its own logistics is high. In order to improve the platform&#39;s express delivery service quality, it joined forces with retail, real estate, logistics and other companies to build the Cainiao Network in 2013. Its model is relatively light and it is positioned as the &quot;data hub&quot; in the logistics system. &quot;, that is, a logistics platform that adopts a franchise model. Cainiao Company does not bear the specific operating costs of the station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Jack Ma also stated that he would &quot;definitely not do logistics.&quot; This played a role in the development of Taobao and Tmall and in wooing logistics companies, allowing him to further control the logistics sector. Cainiao has both the traffic provided by Alibaba e-commerce and a stable logistics and distribution network. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Alibaba’s 2023 fiscal year annual report, Cainiao Group has become the fastest-growing business within Alibaba Group, with revenue of 55.681 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 21%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, 2023, Cainiao Smart Logistics Network Co., Ltd. officially submitted a listing application to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, becoming the first business group to officially start the IPO process since Alibaba’s “1+6+N” organizational reform . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight years ago, Cainiao launched the first &quot;Cainiao Station&quot; to provide express delivery services in Wuhu, Anhui. The prospectus shows that Cainiao now has more than 380 logistics distribution centers and 170,000 post stations around the world. It operates the world&#39;s largest Cainiao post station network and handles more than 80 million packages per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This franchise model has also attracted controversy. Its original intention is to provide consumers with diversified last-mile services and improve distribution efficiency, but it is also very easy to shirk responsibility from each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, the courier company is only responsible for the step to the post station, and the post station directly makes money from the courier company, not from the consumers. There is no direct transaction relationship between the rookie and the consumer. . Cainiao has brand influence, but it is difficult to strictly supervise each franchise station, so it is difficult for customers to obtain a better service experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The express delivery station model itself also has certain legal risks. Article 25 of the &quot;Interim Regulations on Express Delivery&quot; issued by the State Council in 2018 stipulates that enterprises engaged in express delivery business shall deliver express delivery to the agreed address, recipient or recipient designated by the recipient, and notify the recipient or The recipient shall accept the goods in person. The recipient or agent has the right to accept the goods in person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in the post mode, it is difficult to deliver goods to your door. The owner of the Cainiao Station in the above-mentioned county said that there are indeed many requests for door-to-door delivery. &quot;Everyone can deliver it. Now if the station does not deliver, it may fall on the courier company. The express company will ask the courier to deliver it to him, and then he will complain later.&quot; There will be a fine if you use the post station.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, on social platforms, some users said, &quot;It is useless to complain. You will be blacklisted by the post station, and you will not be included in the warehouse in the future. You will have to return it from the post station every time. When you go to an express delivery outlet, your delivery will always be slower than others. Currently, there is no effective method.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Yinggang, a partner at Jingheng Law Firm, told Southern People Weekly that without Consumers agree that express delivery companies have no right to put goods purchased by consumers into express delivery stations. The e-commerce contract signed by consumers through the Internet stipulates that the purchased goods will be delivered to the designated address with free shipping or payment of postage. &quot;If the express delivery company changes the delivery location or delivery method without the consent of the consumer, it will constitute a breach of contract. They should be responsible for continuing to perform the contract or other remedies, and bear liability for breach of contract.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The consequences of the safety hazards caused by poor supervision of the station are even more serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the official website of Cainiao Post, the specific requirements for the post store are: located on the first floor (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;parallel to the road&lt;/span >;), there is no floor limit for office buildings and commercial buildings. However, the station where Lin Mei&#39;s accident occurred did not comply with this requirement and built a steel frame structure privately, and was not subject to supervision and rectification by Cainiao Company during its operating hours. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Consumers have absolutely no idea what the relationship is between the head office and the outlets. They only know that Cainiao is a big company. Going to pick up packages is completely the information pushed to us by Tmall’s backend. This is a public operation. place, but there was no safety guarantee at all, which led to the tragedy.&quot; Zhang Xiang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Yinggang said that in the Lin Mei incident, &quot;In the case of franchising, from the perspective of consumer protection, and based on franchising, the franchisor and the franchise store should bear joint and several liability to the outside world. The owner of the station If its own negligence or fault causes harm to others during the service process, the liability for compensation cannot generally be exempted. Without the consent of the consumer, the express delivery company should also bear joint tort liability.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; h4>;After the Fall&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wake up every day is the most painful moment for Zhang Xiang. Do you think this is true? If only it were a dream. But the reality is so cruel and real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But he needs to cheer up and comfort his lover when she is depressed and breaks down crying. He read Su Dongpo&#39;s poems and Shi Tiesheng&#39;s articles to Lin Mei by the bedside, telling her that a person&#39;s destiny cannot be perfect and there will always be some ups and downs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than two months, Lin Mei has been lying in the ward most of the time. Occasionally, she can see the clouds outside the window. &quot;Look, there are more and more clouds outside.&quot; She looked at the clouds, Tell Zhang Xiang. This reminded him of an ordinary day in the past. When the two of them were walking together, Lin Mei would say: &quot;Look at the clouds in the sky. In fact, let&#39;s take a walk outside together, look at the clouds in the sky, and enjoy the beautiful scenery of nature.&quot; The wind is very happy.&quot; Zhang Xiang said, &quot;Now that I think about it, I was the happiest at that time, but I didn&#39;t think so at that time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhang Xiang&#39;s eyes, Lin Mei is a very simple and knowledgeable person. The person who runs the house, she is the only one who knows where everything in the house is. Just after the accident, Zhang Xiang stayed home for one night, but &quot;I couldn&#39;t sleep at all. I felt very uncomfortable every night. I saw her marks and shadow everywhere in the house. I couldn&#39;t do anything about it.&quot; Sleep. In a rental house, a strange place is better.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since they were together, Lin Mei would make dumplings for Zhang Xiang in person every year on his birthday. Not long ago, on Zhang Xiang&#39;s birthday, Lin Mei said to him, &quot;I can&#39;t make dumplings for you today.&quot; &quot;Later, my mother made dumplings and I went home to get them. She didn&#39;t eat many, only five or six.&quot; Zhang Xiang recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the business trip, Zhang Xiang went to the supermarket to buy a crucian carp and made Lin Mei&#39;s favorite crucian carp soup. He remembered that Lin Mei was very happy to finish eating that day. She took out his leather shoes and polished them. The white edges of the black leather shoes were polished as white as snow. &quot;It&#39;s like new ones.&quot; Zhang Xiang sighed, &quot;When I came back, I saw this pair The edges of the shoes are still white, but the person is no longer the same.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yu mentioned that in the hospital, the golden recovery period is 3-6 months. If you are paralyzed for a long time, the unavoidable complication is the reduction of cardiopulmonary function. If there is no financial pressure, you can do some rehabilitation training and use movable limbs to compensate for the out-of-control limbs. Some training in life and work can improve other functions of the body. maintained at a certain level. The follow-up care and family recovery stages place higher demands on caregivers, and require a lot of hard work from family members and caregivers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I once promised to take her to some places. I originally planned to go this year. No matter how she recovers in the future, I will take her there even if she is in a wheelchair. Of course, it will be very inconvenient to sit in a wheelchair, so I just want to cure her as much as possible and fulfill my promise to her.&quot; Zhang Xiang said that he would continue to &quot;demand justice.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a young writer, Zhang Xiang had a new book published in August. After Lin Mei’s accident, the publishing house sent him a sample book by express delivery, but he found that he could only go to the Cainiao Station to pick it up. “I feel like I don’t want to do this all my life. I have to go to that place again, but I have no choice but to get my book, because I have no choice.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Lin Mei and Chen Jun are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[直男最爱的迪卡侬，靠卖一条裙子赚了几十亿？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, a style of sports culottes has become popular on social media What is surprising is that this &quot;fairy skirt&quot; is neither Lululemon, a must-have for the middle class, nor well-known brands such as Nike and Under Armor, but Decathlon, an old friend of straight men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Decathlon, which has always been known as an affordable paradise and a favorite among straight men, why did it rely on women to get out of the industry this time? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data shows that since 2022, the number of notes about Decathlon on Xiaohongshu has reached 100,000+. With the surge in traffic, it has also driven the sales of its women&#39;s products. Sales, according to the top 5 sales of its Taobao official flagship store, the lowest-ranked women&#39;s yoga pants have sales of up to 30,000+. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, Decathlon’s annual sales will reach 14 billion euros, and China has become one of the largest overseas markets, among which women’s demand is the most dazzling. In Decathlon’s official store, Women&#39;s products account for about half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is closely related to the development of China&#39;s outdoor economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China&#39;s outdoor products market will reach 315 billion yuan in 2020, and is expected to reach 599 billion yuan in 2025. Compared with European and American countries, the scale of my country&#39;s outdoor economic market is still Larger development space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A survey shows that the groups participating in outdoor sports in China are mainly young women in the front line and new front lines. They spend more, buy more, and save more to become contemporary women. The three major characteristics of tourism consumption have gradually set off a niche movement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, Decathlon has seen the development potential of &quot;female consumers + niche sports&quot;. Today, &quot;Know&quot; will take you to explore Decathlon&#39;s transformation secrets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73293&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70108&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256944&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73287&quot; group-id=&quot;0 &quot; asset-id=&quot;70102&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P2 .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256945 &quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73288&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70103&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1438&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256946&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73289&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70104&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P4. jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256947&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73290&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70105&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256948&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img -id=&quot;73291&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70106&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; img -title=&quot;P6-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256949&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73292&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70107&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P7-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256950&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省卫健委党组书记、主任朱宏接受审查调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260404]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:55:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据广东省纪委监委消息：广东省卫生健康委党组书记、主任朱宏涉嫌严重违纪违法，主动投案，目前正接受广东省纪委监委纪律审查和监察调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;朱宏简历&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朱宏，男，汉族，1966年9月出生，在职研究生学历，1982年9月参加工作，1986年3月加入中国共产党。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;历任南方医科大学南方医院党委委员、副院长，广东省医学学术交流中心主任，南方医科大学南方医院党委书记，广东省卫生健康委党组书记、主任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[探索宇宙中相互竞争的隐秘力量：欧几里得望远镜发布首批照片]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260406]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 09:14:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;北京时间2023年11月7日晚，欧洲空间局发布了欧几里得望远镜（Euclid）拍摄的首批5张全彩图片。这些图片是科学家对欧几里得望远镜获得的首批数据进行初步处理的成果，却已经展示出望远镜的强大观测能力——此前从未有望远镜在横跨如此大的天区上获得这样清晰的图像。他们相信，这台望远镜已经做好准备，创造有史以来范围最大的宇宙三维地图，帮助我们洞察“暗”宇宙中暗物质和暗能量的本质，从而揭示宇宙中隐藏的秘密。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧几里得（Euclid）是古希腊著名数学家，被称为“几何之父”，他的《几何原本》流传于世，奠定了此后两千多年几何学发展的基础。现在，科学家已经认识到，物质和能量密度与宇宙的几何紧密相关，决定着宇宙的未来。因此，欧洲空间局（ESA）决定把探索宇宙结构与演化的望远镜以欧几里得的名字命名，以纪念这位几何学先驱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;五&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;个关键问题&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;根据目前的主流宇宙学理论，宇宙中可见的普通物质只占5%，其余的95%包括25%的暗物质和70%的暗能量。因此，了解暗物质和暗能量的本质，成为当今科学中最重大的课题之一。在这个领域的研究中，欧几里得望远镜有望在下个十年甚至更长的时间里发挥重要作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在最远达到100亿光年的范围内，欧几里得将会对超过1/3的天空中的数十亿个星系进行观测，创造一幅宇宙的大尺度结构图。科学家希望通过探索“暗”宇宙的组成和演化，研究宇宙学中的5个关键问题：宇宙网（宇宙中的物质排列在一个巨大的网络中）的结构和演化历史、暗物质是什么、宇宙的膨胀是如何随着时间发生变化的、暗能量的本质是什么以及我们是否真的完全理解了引力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2007年3月，研究人员提出了两个研究方案，以响应欧洲空间局对2015年至2025年间的宇宙探测规划，分别是“暗宇宙探索者”（Dark Universe Explorer，DUNE）和“光谱全天宇宙探索者”（Spectroscopic All Sky Cosmic Explorer，SPACE）。两个方案提出了互补的技术来探测暗能量。经过一段时间的评估和论证后，这两个方案进行了合并，这就是后来的欧几里得望远镜。 2011年10月，欧洲空间局科学任务委员会选定了欧几里得望远镜；2012年6月，望远镜项目正式立项。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过十多年的论证、设计、建造和测试，欧几里得望远镜终于整装待发。 2023年7月1日，欧几里得望远镜由美国太空探索公司（SpaceX）的猎鹰9号（Falcon 9）火箭搭载，在美国佛罗里达州卡纳维拉尔角航天发射场成功发射升空。 7月底，望远镜飞抵距离地球约150万千米的日地第二拉格朗日点附近，顺利进入工作轨道。欧洲空间局的盖亚望远镜（Gaia）以及美国国家航空航天局（NASA）的詹姆斯·韦布空间望远镜（James Webb&amp;nbsp;Space&amp;nbsp;Telescope）也都工作在环绕这个点的轨道上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;欧几里得望远镜工作的艺术想象图。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（欧洲空间局/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧几里得望远镜高约4.7米，直径3.7米，由服务模块和载荷模块组成。其中，发挥探测功能的载荷模块包括一台直径1.2米的望远镜和两台科学仪器：可见光波段相机（VIS）和近红外波段相机（NISP）；服务模块主要包括发电和配电、姿态控制、数据处理、推进、热控制、遥控和遥测等装置。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧洲空间局对欧几里得望远镜寄予厚望。 “暗物质将星系拉在一起，使它们的旋转速度比可见物质本身所能解释的要快；暗能量正在推动宇宙的加速膨胀。欧几里得望远镜将首次允许宇宙学家同时研究这些相互竞争的黑暗奥秘，”欧洲空间局科学主任卡罗尔·蒙代尔（Carole Mundell）在欧洲空间局官网上表示，“欧几里得望远镜将帮助我们在理解整个宇宙上实现飞跃，这些精美的图像表明，该任务已准备好帮助回答现代物理学的最大谜团之一。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;五张&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;惊艳图片&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;欧几里得望远镜首批公布的5张图片分别是英仙座星系团（The Perseus Cluster of galaxies）、漩涡星系IC&amp;nbsp;342星系、不规则矮星系NGC&amp;nbsp;6822、球状星团NGC 6397和马头星云（The Horsehead Nebula）的图片。望远镜进行观测的视场很大，达到0.5平方度，超过满月所占的天空面积，拍摄这次发布的5张图片只用了不到一天的时间。从明亮的恒星到微弱的星系，欧几里得望远镜依靠强大的观测能力，创造出非常清晰的可见光和红外图像。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;英仙座是宇宙中已知的最大结构之一，距离地球2.4亿光年。在这张英仙座星系团的图片中，显示了这个属于星系团的1000个星系，以及背景中更远的10万多个星系。这是天文学家第一次能够在这么大的图片中以这样高的细节水平捕捉到如此多的英仙座星系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;欧几里得望远镜拍摄的英仙座星系团。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（欧洲空间局/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些微弱的星系中有许多是天文学家之前观测不到的，因为其中一些非常遥远，它们发出的光用了100亿年的时间才触达我们。天文学家已经证明，只有在宇宙中存在暗物质的情况下，像英仙座这样的星系团才能形成。他们将通过欧几里得望远镜观察许多像英仙座这样的星系团，绘制其中的星系的分布和形状，从而更多地了解暗物质是如何把这些星系结合在一起形成星系团，并塑造了我们今天看到的宇宙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在轨运行期间，欧几里得望远镜将对数十亿个星系进行成像，揭示暗物质和暗能量对它们施加的无形影响。在欧几里得观测到的第一批星系中，有一个被昵称为“隐藏星系”（Hidden Galaxy），这个与银河系外形相似的漩涡星系的正式编号为IC 342，又被称作考德威尔5号。得益于欧几里得望远镜的红外观测能力，天文学家已经发现了这个星系中恒星的关键信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;欧几里得望远镜拍摄的漩涡星系IC 342。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（欧洲空间局/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在早期宇宙中，大多数星系看起来都不是像银河系一样的典型螺旋形，它们不仅外形不规则，而且也都很小，是构成像银河系这样的更大星系的基石。在距离我们相对较近的宇宙中，我们仍然可以找到一些这样的星系。在欧几里得望远镜发布的图片中，就有一个编号为NGC 6822的不规则矮星系，距离地球160万光年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;欧几里得望远镜拍摄的不规则矮星系NGC 6822。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（欧洲空间局/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧几里得望远镜还拍摄了球状星团NGC 6397，这是距离地球第二近的球状星团，距离地球约7800光年。球状星团是数十万颗恒星通过引力结合在一起的集合。目前，除了欧几里得望远镜之外，没有其他望远镜可以在一次观测中看到整个球状星团，同时识别出星团中这么多的恒星。这些微弱的恒星可以告诉我们银河系的历史以及暗物质的位置。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;欧几里得望远镜拍摄的球状星团NGC 6397。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（欧洲空间局/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在欧几里得望远镜这次发布图片的天体中，马头星云是最近的一个，它也被称作巴纳德33，是猎户座的一部分，距离地球约1500光年。在这张马头星云的图片中，我们不仅能看到壮观的全景，也能洞察其中的细节。在欧几里得望远镜对这个恒星摇篮的新观测中，科学家们希望找到很多处于形成早期的暗淡的、此前从未见过的木星质量的行星，以及年轻的褐矮星和婴儿恒星。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;欧几里得望远镜拍摄的马头星云。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（欧洲空间局/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;六&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;年持续观测&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;虽然首批只发布了5张图片，但是这些图片已经体现出在望远镜研制背后科学家和工程师付出了巨大努力，才造就了这些杰作。欧几里得项目经理朱塞佩·拉卡（Giuseppe Racca）在欧洲空间局官网上表示：“我们对这台望远镜的高标准得到了回报。这些图片中有如此多的细节，这要归功于特殊的光学设计、望远镜和仪器的完美制造和组装以及极其精确的指向和温度控制。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧几里得项目科学家勒内·劳雷斯（René&amp;nbsp;Laureijs）这样评价：“我们以前从未见过这样的天文图片，其中包含如此多的细节。它们比我们所希望的更加美丽和清晰，向我们展示了附近宇宙中已知区域内许多以前从未见过的特征。现在我们已经准备好观察数十亿个星系，并研究它们在宇宙历史中的演化。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧几里得望远镜的首秀令天文学界备受鼓舞，很多人持有和勒内·劳雷斯相同的观点。这些图片显示出欧几里得望远镜的各种仪器具有非常优良的性能，天文学家可以使用这台望远镜来研究宇宙中物质的分布及其在最大尺度上的演化。以大量覆盖大面积天空的高质量观测结果为基础，他们将向我们展示宇宙中黑暗和隐藏的部分。而在暗物质和暗能量的领域之外，这些图片还展示了欧几里得能够帮助天文学家创造一个关于单颗恒星和星系物理学的信息宝库。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧几里得联盟负责人雅尼克·梅利尔（Yannick Mellier）表示：“在接下来的几个月里，欧几里得联盟的科学家将分析这些图片，并在《天文学与天体物理学》杂志（&lt;em>;Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics&lt;/em>;）上发表一系列科学论文，以及关于欧几里得任务的科学目标和仪器性能的论文。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在欧几里得望远镜发射升空之后的几个月里，科学家和工程师一直在测试和校准望远镜的科学设备。这个团队目前正在进行最后的微调，以便在2024年年初开始常规的观测工作。随着任务的进行，望远镜获得的数据会每年对外发布一次，并向全世界的研究人员开放。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据计划，欧几里得望远镜将开展为期6年的观测，此后将根据用于推进的低温气体的余量来评估延长任务期的可能性。在未来的6年里，我们可以期待欧几里得望远镜不断带给我们新的惊喜，用更多的精彩图片向我们展示宇宙隐藏的魅力。而对观测数据的分析则会持续更长的时间，天文学家将在这些数据中细致搜寻解开暗物质和暗能量谜团的线索。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[万亿特殊再融资债券：云南、内蒙古、辽宁超千亿，北上广未发行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260402]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73412&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70221&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG211250367208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;云南和内蒙古均发行了1076亿元，位居全国之首。视觉中国／图&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257853&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;云南和内蒙古均发行了1076亿元，位居全国之首。视觉中国／图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“已经通知所有债权人过来结算欠款。”一位西部省份的基层官员向南方周末记者介绍，此次发行的特殊再融资债券资金已到账，正在兑付手续齐全的政府债务。&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月初，各地开始大规模发行特殊再融资债券。据南方周末记者统计，截至11月5日，25个省（直辖市、自治区）共计发行了1.13万亿元，相当于甘肃2022全年的GDP。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特殊再融资债券由省级政府代发，对市县政府来说，相当于多出一笔低息的偿债资金，能够置换高息债务，拉长还款周期。与平时发行的再融资债券相比，特殊再融资债券不列明具体偿还的债券信息。根据过往发行历史，它主要用于偿还各地的隐性债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位地方财政系统官员向南方周末记者透露，此次特殊再融资债券有两个主要投向，一个是置换高息的非标债务，另一个是偿还政府部门拖欠企业的账款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此轮特殊再融资债券发行前，7月24日，中共中央政治局召开会议，强调要有效防范化解地方债务风险，制定实施一揽子化债方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月7日，中国人民银行副行长张青松在国际金融领袖投资峰会上表示，“少数省份或面临偿债压力，相关省份的大部分债务都具有实体资产支持。加上已制定一揽子以市场为导向的方案，相信随着针对性政策的实施，部分地方政府债务风险将逐步得到收敛。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;云南、内蒙古、辽宁发行超千亿元&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;根据此次特殊再融资债券发行信息，截至11月5日，发行金额排名前三的省份是：云南（1076亿元）、内蒙古（1067亿元）、辽宁（1006亿元）。发行最少的地区是山西，仅有28亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果以（政府债务/GDP）*100%的方式计算债务率，2022年，上述三地的债务率在31个省级行政区（不包含港澳台）中，分别排名第九、第十、第十二。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次，仅有北京、广东、上海、浙江、海南、西藏六个地区未发行特殊再融资债券。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，广东、浙江、上海、北京四地债务率较低，且经济发达。海南与西藏的政府债务体量不大。2022年，西藏的政府债务余额仅有568亿元，在31个省级行政区中排名倒数第一。海南债务余额3487亿元，排名倒数第四。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从发行结构来看，截至11 月5 日，发行的特殊再融资债券中，一般债规模为7594亿元，占比67.3%；专项债规模为3686亿元，占比32.7%。一般债的资金用途广泛，专项债则投向受限。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本轮特殊再融资债券发行过程中，尚未有部门对各地额度进行解释。但根据发行情况来看，资金还是更多流向财政自给率相对低的中西部省份，以及债务规模较大、债务率较高的地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“省里要求我们先处理高息的非标债务。”一位北方省份的财政系统官员告诉南方周末记者，发行特殊再融资债券后，他所在的地级市获得了超过百亿元资金，目前正在安排兑付非标产品。今年以来，当地曾发生多起非标违约事件，还本付息压力大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;债务置换外，另一个重要用途，是还清政府拖欠企业的账款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月26日，内蒙古披露的债券发行信息显示：其拟发行再融资一般债663.2亿元，募集资金用于偿还政府负有偿还责任的拖欠企业账款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而10月6日，上述发债材料进行了更新，资金用途调整为偿还存量债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前内蒙古发布的《关于2022年度自治区本级预算执行和其他财政收支的审计工作报告》显示，清理拖欠民营企业中小企业账款政策未落实，拖欠62家1.11亿元。此外，2021年年底，内蒙古暂付款余额高达470.55亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月20日，国务院总理李强主持召开国务院常务会议。会议指出，省级政府要对本地区清欠工作负总责，抓紧解决政府拖欠企业账款问题，解开企业之间相互拖欠的“连环套”，央企国企要带头偿还。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在要求各家债权人先完善手续。”上述西部省份基层官员介绍，比如以前修一条道路，企业要完善竣工验收的一整套手续，报省里审核通过才放款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，部分地区开始打折偿还拖欠企业的账款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月26日，无锡德林海环保科技股份有限公司（688069.SH）发布公告称，公司与玉溪市水利局、大理洱海保护投资建设有限责任公司，就部分项目应收账款达成债务重组方案，上述应收账款共计1.6亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据公告，德林海同意给予债务人一定折让，经本次债务重组，预计能够收回1.2亿元。工商资料显示，洱海投资公司为国有企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公告解释，此次债务重组的背景有两个，一是上述国常会上，要求解决好企业账款拖欠问题；二是云南省政府着力化解存量隐性债务，施行隐性债务清零政策，督促落实了多项化债措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发行特殊再融资债券，无疑是化债措施中的重要一项。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73413&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70222&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG1515.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2266&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257854&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;较前两轮速度更快、金额更高&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;过去几年，特殊再融资债券出现过两轮发行高峰期。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，2020年12月-2021年9月，特殊再融资债券共发行6278亿元，主要用于建制县隐性债务化解试点。紧接着，2021年10月至2022年6月，共发行5041.8亿元，主要用于全域无隐性债务试点，集中在北京、上海、广东三地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据粤开证券研究院院长罗志恒统计，2018-2022年地方政府债券到期续发比例分别为81.3%、87.3%、87.2%、86.3%和86.1%，均处于较高水平，主要是偿还2015-2017年发行的债券。等到了2023年1-8月，到期续发比例提升至90.5%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到期续发比例=（再融资债券-特殊再融资债券）/到期规模。一般来说，地方政府债券到期后，除发行再融资债券，还会安排财政资金等进行偿还。换言之，地方财力紧平衡状况加剧，更依靠发行债券的方式，续存到期债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与前两轮发行的特殊再融资债券相比，此次发行的速度更快。一个多月的时间，发行金额就超过万亿元。此次发行金额也接近前两轮之和，且尚未结束。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得注意的是，再融资债券置换隐性债务后，会增加政府债务余额。根据现行规定，对地方政府债务（一般债和专项债）实行限额管控，债务限额与债务余额的差值，就是当地特殊再融资债券的最大发行额度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以此次主要发行的一般债为例，截至11月5日，内蒙古、天津、贵州等七个地区，已经超过了当地最大发行额度，即债务上限。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央财经大学教授温来成向南方周末记者介绍，部分地方发行特殊再融资债券，可能突破当地债务限额。为此，财政部会在全国人大核定的地方债务限额基础上，进行统筹调剂，增加部分地区的债务限额。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如，2022年9月重庆市发布的《关于2022年市级预算调整方案（草案）的报告》中提到，财政部要求专项债务中，结存限额按约70％比例由各省（区、市）留用，按约30％比例由中央收回，用于各省（区、市）之间统筹调配。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，特殊再融资债券作为一种特别手段，仅能在短期内缓解地方政府债务压力，且发行金额有限，无法彻底解决各地的隐性债务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北方一家县级城投公司高管告诉南方周末记者，他所在的省份此次发行了数百亿元的特殊再融资债券，因为公司今年陆续发生非标逾期事件，偿债压力大，他曾向上级政府部门打报告申请债券资金支持，但未能成功。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，发行万亿特殊再融资债券后，地方城投平台融资需求依旧旺盛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海一家融资租赁平台的工作人员告诉南方周末记者，他负责的几个省份，均发行了特殊再融资债券，但没有影响业务开展，最近接触的多家城投平台，仍急需流动资金。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花都华侨农场访问记：海外中国人筚路蓝缕，在国内也同样熠熠发光]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260343]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;最近一个周末，我带儿子在广州二沙岛闲逛，误打误撞进了广东华侨博物馆，其中一个展厅里的华侨农场引起了我浓厚的兴趣，作为从事社会学的教师，我产生了探访华侨农场的想法。我在网上一搜，发现我所在的城市郊区就有一个华侨农场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月6日恰逢没课，一大早，我便约了一位同事一同前往目的地——坐落于广州市花都区花东镇的华侨农场。花都华侨农场辖区面积14.55平方公里，在册人口5200多人，其中涵盖印度尼西亚、越南、马来西亚、泰国、日本、新加坡、柬埔寨、印度、老挝、新西兰、马达加斯加、香港、澳门等13个国家和地区的归侨侨眷共计4800余人。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;华侨农场的前世今生&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;经过一小时车程，我们抵达了“华侨农场”公交站。简单咨询了一位小卖部的阿姨，我们便去了马路对面的侨兴苑小区，她说这里住着不少归侨。小区不小，一起有近30栋住宅，有一半的房屋构造是一楼架空，靠后山的位置散布着一些私人建房。在一栋房子的一楼空旷平台，我们邂逅了正在忙着包装手机壳的两位阿姨，她们是越南归侨。我和同事一边帮忙装手机壳，一边与她们闲聊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她俩是1978年回国的，当时分别只有10岁和8岁，被统一安置在这里，当时农场的管理实行男女分开，住在集体宿舍里面。即使是一家人，也要分散开来，不能住在一起。当时的宿舍由泥砖砌成，里面是一排排上下铺的“碌架床”，由于人很多，空间非常狭促。后面，由于接收的归侨实在太多，宿舍不够住，就只能住进附近村子里的祠堂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农业生产与生计方面，农场与周边村落类似，他们也是被划归到若干生产队，除种植水稻、蔬菜、花生、水果、柑橙、荔枝、芒果外，他们还开垦山坡，种植茶园。据悉，早在上世纪70年代末，华侨农场就已为花都最重要的茶叶生产基地，茶业一度兴盛，生产的茶叶驰名全省，远销海内外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当年开山种茶的情景依然历历在目。一位阿姨说，一个个密林丛生的小山头，大家用斧头锄头开垦成了种茶基地；没有机械，他们就徒手搬小茶苗到山上栽种，再一桶一桶挑水浇灌。渐渐地，秋风田、湾弓塘一带，形成了一片绿意盎然的茶山，面积有几百公顷。当时每天要按时劳动，一般早上7时，就要起床去采茶，因为那时露水正浓，是采摘的最佳时间。虽然条件艰苦，但大家积极性都很高，午间休息的时候，大家会围在一起，听其中一位大声朗读当天的报纸，有时也会有人带头唱歌……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同的是，凡落户农场的归侨，皆可享受与城镇居民一样的福利与待遇，有粮票、布票、肉票等物资供应。如今，他们退休多年，亦可享受退休工资待遇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，阿姨告诉我们，方圆十里八乡的农村人都以嫁自家的女儿到农场为荣，因为女儿会立马成为可以“享受待遇”的“职工”，个人命运就有可能发生重大转机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2007年，当地政府决定对华侨农场实施住房改造项目，投资1.3亿元，总建筑面积超过7万平方米，建成了侨南苑、侨港苑、侨兴苑等新住宅区，职工只需缴纳一点点钱，就可以有宽敞明亮的房子住了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那周边村民不是很羡慕你们？”我问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当时的确是这样，但现在不同了，我们很羡慕他们。”一位阿姨说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原来是华侨农场所在的花东镇政府近些年利用毗邻白云国际机场的优势，致力于打造航空物流产业集聚区、航空维修产业集聚区、电子商务产业集聚区和临空先进制造业集聚区，对华侨农场及附近村庄进行高强度的开发，华侨农场因为本身就是国有土地，属于政府内部不涉及产权置换的土地开发与利用行为，到农场职工手上的可见性福利寥寥，而附近村庄则不一样，很多村民因为被征地得到了数额不菲的补偿款，有的甚至只需增缴几万块就可以直接住上各种综合配套齐全的楼宇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿姨们包装手机壳打零工，一天可以赚个80-100块，反正在家闲着也是看手机，就做点事，人也舒服。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位阿姨的原话是，“我很小的时候，我妈就教育我要勤劳，现在退休了，但身体还算硬朗，就找一点事来做，我心里踏实。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一些人退休就知道打牌，刷手机，但我不喜欢。打牌输钱，我心疼；老看手机看坏眼睛，我不舒服，还不如做事。”另外一位阿姨这样说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;归侨的作用&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;接近中午12点，阿姨们要回家吃饭。同她们道别后，我们便去马路对面的侨南苑找吃的。在一家餐厅，我们邂逅了一家印尼归侨在聚餐。与她们简单打个招呼，说明来意，不想她们非常热情，竟邀请我们与她们同吃。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;席间闲聊得知，阿姨姓温，在家中排行老四，上面有一个哥和两个姐，下面有一个妹，她于1960年回国，那时候她6岁。如今，老母亲已98岁高龄，神志依然清晰，精神依然矍铄。温姨说，她爷爷早年远赴印度尼西亚，算是“下南洋”的首批队伍，他们先后养过猪、做过豆腐，在当地成家、安定下来。她父母也继承祖辈基业，主要靠在印度尼西亚西南部小城市或小城镇做豆腐、卖豆腐维持生计。很显然，他们没有选择去竞争更激烈的首都或大城市落脚或谋生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;勤奋、节俭、做小本生意，在艰难与逆境中前行，可不能小觑这些特质，这些特质给温姨这一代人从小打下了脑子活、懂经营的基础。回国后，温姨及其家人相继经营起了豆制品厂、制衣厂、木材加工厂及饭店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;需要说明，这些所谓的“小微企业”并非私营，而是归农场所有，生产出来的产品都需上缴农场，经由农场统一销售或其他处置。相比附近终日务农的村民，温姨一家及其他像温姨一样长期在国外打拼过的人的思维与想法明显更胜一筹，他们很大程度上推动了农场的全面转型与升级，为农场的产业多样化经营闯出一条路来，倚靠他们的先知先觉与身先士卒，农场拉开了产业化的序幕。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从更大范围讲，温姨及一帮人率先推动了花都地区的农村工业化进程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就温姨个人而言，她胆大、外向，善于社交，18岁就拿到了A类驾驶证，成为1980年代农场司机班里唯一的女司机，经常开着长挂车全国各地跑，自然见多识广，才思敏捷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;温姨还是一位地道的美食制造家，每逢过节，不论是中国的节日，还是印尼的节日，抑或是街坊邻里有人结婚、有家里添丁、有孩子升学或参军办宴时，她都会提前一周准备各种食材，有时甚至专程去香港购买，制作各类极具印尼特色的精美点心，譬如千层糕、曼煎粿、宝塔饭、巴东菜、发酵黄豆块、加多-加多等，供亲友及乡邻品尝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毫无疑问，归侨身份让各国特色美食在华侨农场得以传承与光大，乡邻们在品尝各国美食过程中进行着跨文化交流，这样的朝夕共处与频繁交流，无疑营造了一个多样丰富文化的社区氛围，对于化解社区矛盾与争端、构建社区发展共同体、提升社区自组织能力、增进社区治理效能产生积极作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;归侨身份亦对后代的发展产生垂范作用。席间还有温姨的侄子，他饭后便欲启程去香港，继而转机去印尼。原来，他父母很早就定居香港，他小学及中学是在香港念的，大学及研究生在美国完成，目前在印尼巴厘岛一家地产公司上班。不难看出，祖辈或长辈们的跨国经历，对后代的受教育水平及人生际遇产生深远影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;温姨告诉我，农场有数量不少的第三代跨国移民，多少得益于或受益于祖辈们构建起来的跨国联系网络。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;我的感想&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;下午3时许，我们请温姨带我们去她曾经“战斗”过的一些地方走走、看看，她欣然应许，我们相继去了五队、六队和九队。一路上，我们发现从前的临时农场管理办公室、茶厂、制衣厂等早已改头换面，原址上已建起了很多涉及新能源与高科技等领域的新型企业。道理至简，华侨农场属国营单位，管理方式较大程度沿袭计划经济体制，很多传统产业难以跟上新的发展形势，不少企业纷纷破产，取而代之的是新项目纷纷上马，新企业纷纷进驻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看到曾经劳作的地方，只有少数厂牌孤独地伫立在那里，温姨露出了遗憾与无奈的表情。时代在改变，华侨农场也在转型，这是无法阻止的客观规律。未来，华侨农场将继续深度融入都市化与现代化。在这一过程中，我以为有关方面可以尝试开展下面几件事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，应该鼓励大学老师、相关研究人员或学生群体开展针对归侨及其后代的口述史研究，做好各年龄层次人口的采访与调查，成为花东镇乃至花都区地方志的重要组成部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，通过政府与民间合作的方式，成立华侨农村博物馆或展览馆，让华侨文化与华侨精神发扬光大，将其打造为花都旅游中的特色与亮点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其三，积极申报建设省级或市级国际化社区，华侨农场是实实在在与真真切切的国际化社区，有关部门在升级改造与后续规划过程中不能或不宜一味地“去农场化”，华侨农场作为一种地方性特质早已成为花东镇或花都区地方性知识的重要组分，有关方面需要充分尊重地方，尊重地方原真性，让上述地方在新时期国际化社区营建过程中得以体现与绽放，这无疑很大程度助力地方营销（place marketing），进而成为招商引资的重要社会资本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者系广州大学社会学系教授）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 22:55:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>