<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[财政部党组书记调整：蓝佛安系“财政老兵”，刘昆推动央地财政关系改革]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258258]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 16:10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Announcement on the official website of the Ministry of Finance, on the afternoon of September 28, 2023, relevant responsible comrades from the Organization Department of the Central Committee attended the leadership of the Ministry of Finance At the cadre meeting, it was announced that the central government decided that Comrade Lan Fo&#39;an would be appointed as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Finance and Comrade Liu Kun would be removed from the post of Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before taking over as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Finance, Lan Fo&#39;an served as Secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee and Director of the Standing Committee of the Provincial People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/rEGJKiwYT330dBdFQmqiHE6OuiyOp6Rm2cdvSBSL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/rEGJKiwYT330dBdFQmqiHE6OuiyOp6Rm2cdvSBSL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 10, Lan Foan visited teachers in Taiyuan City. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Shanxi Provincial Government official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Lan Foan returns to the financial system&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;The newly appointed Party Secretary of the Ministry of Finance, Lan Foan, is a &quot;veteran&quot; in the financial system. He has been engaged in financial work for nearly 20 years and has worked in the audit department for 8 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the Chinese government website, Lan Foan was born in 1962 in Huizhou, Guangdong. He graduated from Hubei University of Finance and Economics (now Zhongnan University of Economics and Law). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from university, Lan Foan worked in the Budget Department of the Ministry of Finance for three years. In 1988, Lan Fo&#39;an returned to his hometown of Guangdong and worked in the budget department and office of the Guangdong Provincial Department of Finance for 11 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1999, Lan Fo&#39;an briefly left the financial system and went to work locally as the deputy mayor of Dongguan City. Two years later, Lan Fo&#39;an returned to the Guangdong Provincial Department of Finance as deputy director until 2007. During the same period, Liu Kun was the Party Secretary and Director of the Guangdong Provincial Department of Finance (2002-2010). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2007, Lan Foan was transferred to the Guangdong Provincial Audit Office and served as Party Secretary. A year later, he took over as director of the Audit Office. In 2011, Lan Foan published a paper introducing the role of auditing in the government governance process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lan Fo&#39;an said that auditing, as the &quot;immune system&quot; to ensure the healthy development of the economy and society, should play the functions of &quot;prevention, exposure and resistance&quot; in ensuring the healthy operation of the economy and society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After eight years of working in the Guangdong Provincial Audit Office, Lan Foan once again went to work locally and became the Secretary of the Shaoguan Municipal Party Committee. In January 2016, Lan Fo&#39;an was promoted to deputy governor of Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2017, Lan Foan transferred to Hainan and served as a member of the Standing Committee of the Hainan Provincial Party Committee, Secretary of the Provincial Discipline Inspection Commission, and Director of the Provincial Supervisory Committee. In 2021, Lan Fo&#39;an was transferred to Shanxi and served as deputy secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee. In the same year, he took over the post of governor of Shanxi Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Shanxi Radio and Television, when Lan Foan was transferred to work in Shanxi, Lou Yangsheng, then Secretary of the Provincial Party Committee, said at an enlarged meeting of the Provincial Party Committee Standing Committee, &quot;Comrade Lan Foan is politically determined and has clear thinking. Familiar with party affairs and economic work, diligent and dedicated, courageous to take on responsibilities, vigorous in promoting work, fair and decent, rigorous in handling affairs, and strict in self-requirements.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, Lan Fo&#39;an, who had served as governor of Shanxi Province for more than a year, was promoted to secretary of the Shanxi Provincial Party Committee. Ten months later, Lan Fo&#39;an went to Beijing and served as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Liu Kun has been the party secretary for more than five years&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the Ministry of Finance, Liu Kun, who was born in December 1956, is over 66 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2018, Xiao Jie, then Minister of Finance, transferred to the State Council and was promoted to State Councilor and Secretary-General of the State Council. Liu Kun took over as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Minister of the Ministry of Finance. Before taking over, Liu Kun served as a member of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, director of the Budget Working Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, and deputy director of the Financial and Economic Committee of the 12th National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until September 2023, Liu Kun had served as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Finance for five years and seven months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 13, 2023, the first session of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress held its fifth plenary session. The conference voted to appoint Liu Kun as Minister of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the founding of New China, Liu Kun is the first Guangdong-born Minister of Finance. According to information from the official website of the Ministry of Finance and People&#39;s Daily Online, Liu Kun studied in the Department of Economics of Xiamen University majoring in finance from 1978 to 1982. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduation, Liu Kun worked in the General Office of the Guangdong Provincial Government for a long time. In 2002, Liu Kun, who served as deputy secretary-general of the Guangdong Provincial Government, served as party secretary and director of the Guangdong Provincial Department of Finance for eight years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, Liu Kun was promoted to deputy governor of Guangdong Province. According to the official website of the Guangdong Provincial Government, during his three years as deputy governor, Liu Kun was in charge of social security, establishment, supervision, civil affairs, rural areas, supply and marketing cooperatives and other fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, Liu Kun returned to work in the financial line again and went to Beijing to serve as a member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to People&#39;s Daily Online, Liu Kun is in charge of the Treasury Department (Treasury Payment Center), Economic Construction Department, Supervision and Inspection Bureau, and the Ministry of Finance&#39;s local financial inspectorate offices and investment review centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2016, after working in the Ministry of Finance for three years, Liu Kun transferred to the National People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee and served as director of the Budget Working Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee. The National People&#39;s Congress website shows that the Budget Working Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress Standing Committee is a ministerial-level unit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until March 2018, Liu Kun succeeded Xiao Jie as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Minister of the Ministry of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/qKbY29D5QNEPrR0nypQ3VWjLpFQJBYIIPP9Qgfsm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height= &quot;731&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/qKbY29D5QNEPrR0nypQ3VWjLpFQJBYIIPP9Qgfsm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 7, Finance Minister Liu Kun held talks with World Bank President Peng Anjie. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Ministry of Finance official website/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Promote the reform of central and local fiscal relations&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; At the end of March 2018, the newly appointed Minister of Finance Liu Kun attended a forum hosted by the Development Research Center of the State Council and talked about the reform of central and local fiscal relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Kun said in his speech that on the premise of maintaining the overall stability of the financial structure of the central and local governments, scientifically determine shared taxes, central and local sharing methods and proportions, increase local taxes appropriately, and continue to optimize transfer payments. system and expand the scale of general transfer payments. Establish and improve the regular evaluation and exit mechanism for special transfer payments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the local tax system must be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In conjunction with the implementation of the reform of central and local revenue division, we will study and adjust the collection links of some consumption tax items and the attribution of revenue, and actively and steadily promote the reform of the local tax system. Adjust the tax system structure, cultivate local tax sources, strengthen local tax powers, and manage Following the relationship between taxes and fees, we will gradually establish a stable and sustainable local tax system.&quot; Liu Kun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform of the financial relationship between the central and local governments has lasted throughout Liu Kun’s five years as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Minister of the Ministry of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, the State Council issued the &quot;Reform and Promotion Plan for Adjusting the Division of Central and Local Revenue after Implementing Larger-scale Tax and Fee Reductions&quot;, aiming to further rationalize the fiscal relationship between the central and local governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plan proposes to mobilize the enthusiasm of both the central and local governments, stabilize the overall pattern of revenue division between the central and local governments formed since the reform of the tax-sharing system, and consolidate the results of revenue division reforms such as the &quot;five-to-five sharing&quot; of value-added tax. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Adjust and improve the VAT excess credit refund sharing mechanism, establish a long-term mechanism for VAT excess credit refund, determine the tax refund scale based on the fiscal revenue situation, and keep the &quot;Fifth Five-Year Plan&quot; sharing ratio between the central and local governments unchanged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, some current consumption tax items levied in the production (import) link will gradually be moved to the wholesale or retail link to expand local revenue sources and guide local governments to improve the consumption environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, Liu Kun also gave a lecture entitled &quot;my country&#39;s Central and Local Financial Relations&quot; to the Standing Committee of the 13th National People&#39;s Congress, detailing the current status and future reforms of my country&#39;s central and local fiscal relations. direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Kun said that to further rationalize the fiscal relationship between the central and local governments, we must improve the local tax and direct tax systems, improve the revenue division model with shared taxes as the main body, and improve the common fiscal authority system, strengthen the central fiscal authority and Expenditure responsibility and other directions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, Liu Kun wrote in an article published in &quot;Qiushi&quot; magazine that fiscal and taxation reforms are advancing in depth, further reforming the budget management system, and further promoting the division of financial powers and expenditure responsibilities between the central and local governments. Reform and implement common fiscal power transfer payments with Chinese characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Strictly control the scale of local debt&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the five years when Liu Kun served as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Minister of the Ministry of Finance, one of the major pressures he faced was the issue of local fiscal revenue. The contradiction between payment and financing has intensified, and debt risks are increasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2019, Liu Kun and the two vice ministers of the Ministry of Finance answered questions from domestic and foreign reporters around the theme of &quot;fiscal and taxation reform and fiscal work&quot;, during which they talked about the issue of local debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Of course I don&#39;t shy away from it. Some local governments use financing platform companies to illegally and illegally borrow debts in disguised forms beyond the legal limits. This is the so-called hidden debt of the government.&quot; Liu Kun emphasized, &quot;We Take strict measures to not allow the occurrence of new hidden debts, and require a steady settlement of existing debts.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about how to resolve existing debts, Liu Kun said that he will insist that the central government will not bail out, and whoever raises the debt will be responsible. , to achieve &quot;Whose family&#39;s children will be held&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of 2018, the Ministry of Finance began to establish a local implicit debt monitoring system to dynamically monitor the debt scale of each region. Beginning in 2019, a local government debt risk rating mechanism was established to classify local debt risks into four levels: red, orange, yellow, and green. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We must balance the relationship between promoting development and preventing risks, rationally arrange deficit, debt and expenditure policies, and do a solid job in resolving hidden debt risks of local governments.” At the beginning of 2021, Liu Kun was interviewed by Xinhua News Agency At the time, it was mentioned that the current local government debt risks in my country are generally controllable, but some areas are still adding hidden debts, and the debt repayment risks in individual areas have increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Kun said that putting a &quot;tightening ring&quot; on local government debt will create an additional &quot;safety valve&quot; for economic and social development. Next, the financial department will actively take measures such as &quot;opening the front door&quot; and &quot;blocking the back door&quot;, ensuring and regulating simultaneously, to further improve management, strengthen supervision, promote the &quot;sunshine&quot; of local government debt, and effectively cage debt risks. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, the third session of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress held its first plenary meeting in the Great Hall of the People. Liu Kun made a report on the 2022 central government&#39;s final accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He pointed out that the next step will be to focus on six tasks: intensify efforts to improve efficiency and implement proactive fiscal policies, strengthen expenditure guarantees in key areas, secure the bottom line of &quot;three guarantees&quot; at the grassroots level, and effectively prevent and resolve local government debts. risks, increase financial and accounting supervision, and do a solid job in audit rectification, &quot;the second half of the article.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July, the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting to analyze and study the current economic situation and plan economic work for the second half of the year. The meeting pointed out that it is necessary to effectively prevent and resolve local debt risks and formulate and implement a package debt reduction plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 28, when Liu Kun reported to the Standing Committee of the National People’s Congress on budget implementation this year, he emphasized that “the central finance actively supports local governments in resolving hidden debt risks and properly resolves existing hidden debts. Resolutely investigate and deal with the behavior of new hidden debts, and prevent new debts at the same time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href= &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style =&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国队无悬念领跑，创历史最佳战绩。杭州亚运会奖牌榜回顾丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258244]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 14:52:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[唐慧、唐世科寻衅滋事案公开宣判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258246]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 14:48:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the 8th, the People&#39;s Court of Dao County, Hunan Province publicly pronounced the verdict of Tang Hui and Tang Shike in accordance with the law. The defendant Tang Hui was convicted of picking quarrels and provoking trouble and was sentenced to four years in prison. The defendant Tang Shike was convicted of picking quarrels and provoking trouble and was sentenced to three years and six months in prison. The illegal income of RMB 60,000 from defendants Tang Hui and Tang Shike shall be recovered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After trial, it was found that from 2010 to 2012, the defendants Tang Hui and Tang Shike used the Yongzhou Fourth People’s Hospital to fail to detect Tang Hui’s ectopic pregnancy, which resulted in the removal of her right fallopian tube. After reporting the incident, he repeatedly insulted and threatened hospital staff to pressure the hospital for compensation (the Yongzhou Medical Association determined that it did not constitute a medical malpractice), and Yongzhou Fourth People&#39;s Hospital was forced to pay 60,000 yuan to Tang Hui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, tree obstructions caused large-scale and frequent power outages in Xiaolitang Village, Fujiaqiao Town, Lingling District, Yongzhou City, seriously affecting the normal production and life of residents. State Grid Hunan Electric Power Co., Ltd. Yongzhou City Zero When the Ling District Power Supply Branch organized obstacle clearance construction according to the notice from superiors, 14 wild young camphor trees and other forest trees on the Majiaxiang Mountain in the second group of the village were felled. Tang Hui and Tang Shike claimed for compensation from the Lingling District Power Supply Branch on the grounds that &quot;the wild camphor trees in the mountains reserved by Tang Shike were illegally logged.&quot; The amount of compensation was gradually increased from 30,000 yuan to 500,000 yuan. Later, for fear of being suspected of extortion, Tang Hui and Tang Shike filed a lawsuit with the People&#39;s Court of Lingling District, Yongzhou City, demanding compensation of 3.596 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to achieve the purpose of obtaining compensation through judicial procedures, the two maliciously reported, repeatedly chased, intercepted, and insulted the investigators, made trouble in public places, spread false information on the Internet, and seriously affected the lives of others. work and life, causing serious disorder in public places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court held that the defendants Tang Hui and Tang Shike used excuses to cause trouble, chased, intercepted, pestered, and insulted others many times, seriously affecting the work and life of others, and the circumstances were egregious; they took 60,000 yuan of property by force, The circumstances are serious; making riots in hospitals and other public places, causing serious disorder in public places, constitutes the crime of picking quarrels and provoking trouble. The Dao County People&#39;s Court made the above judgment in accordance with the law based on the facts, nature, circumstances and degree of social harm committed by defendants Tang Hui and Tang Shike. The two defendants appealed in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[西安某大学女生被63页PPT控诉出轨：如此公之于众侵犯隐私吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258240]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 13:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a female student at Xi&#39;an International Studies University was accused of cheating by her boyfriend in a 63-page PPT, which became a hot topic on social networks. Putting aside the elements of gossip, this matter is also worthy of analysis from a social and legal perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The man who posted the complaint PPT claimed to work at an accounting firm in Shanghai, and the girl who was accused was a senior student at Xi&#39;an International Studies University. They began to fall in love at the end of 2022, but within nearly a year , this girl had an affair with two ex-boyfriends. The man believed that his girlfriend&#39;s &quot;cheating&quot; had seriously hurt his feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The incident spread widely on the Internet and caused many disputes among netizens. Some people think that it is a serious mistake for a girl to cheat on her boyfriend and cuckold her boyfriend; others say that the relationship between the two is just boyfriend and girlfriend, not husband and wife. What the girl does is not illegal, but making a PPT and distributing it on the Internet is an infringement of personal rights. Privacy Violations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social networks, sexual incidents such as &quot;cheating&quot; and &quot;cheating&quot; naturally tend to attract great attention. But different situations do have different legal properties. Legally speaking, the Civil Code only stipulates that husband and wife have an obligation to be loyal to each other (this includes exclusiveness in relationships, sex, etc.), but there is no statutory obligation of loyalty between lovers. Therefore, if one party of a couple who has received a marriage certificate cheats on the couple, it is a clear violation of the law. There is no statutory obligation of loyalty between lovers, let alone the consequences of disloyalty. Love and feelings do not fall into the category of &quot;civil legal acts&quot; regulated by the civil law, and are not subject to the principle of &quot;good faith&quot; in the civil law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in addition to statutory laws, there are also customary laws that regulate public social behavior, including public order and good customs, moral evaluation, etc. For couples who have established a romantic relationship, customary law also requires mutual fidelity. If either party commits betrayal, they should be subject to moral criticism and must return gifts, etc. The betrayed party also has the right to punish the betrayed party by disclosing the facts and using moral force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the past, this kind of moral criticism was generally limited to acquaintances or relatively small circles such as communities, villages, and work units. Nowadays, with the development of social networks, such incidents may quickly spread throughout the entire network. The person being criticized will not only lose his reputation in a small circle, but may also be &quot;socially dead&quot; on the entire network. Moreover, moral criticism on the Internet may be more violent and direct than in a circle of acquaintances, and may even trigger a storm of public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, if you post the other person&#39;s information on the Internet after being &quot;cheated&quot;, is it suspected of leaking personal information and infringing on privacy? There is no precedent for similar situations. In 2021, the incident of &quot;Female internet celebrity was accused by her CEO boyfriend in a 65-page PPT&quot; also became a hot topic on the Internet. In the end, the man was found by the police to have violated the Public Security Management Punishment Law by &quot;spreading other people&#39;s privacy&quot; and was administratively detained for 6 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the latest complaint PPT, the girl involved was not only named by name and identity, but also the girl’s student ID card, photos of her and her “cheating partner”, and the girl’s relationship with them Screenshot of chat history. This information may be considered personal privacy. Many legal practitioners have warned that this kind of &quot;exposing private information&quot; accusations may violate the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, there is another detail. The man who accused his college student girlfriend of cheating later issued a statement saying that he only sent the PPT he made to his girlfriend’s roommates and colleagues, hoping that they could persuade and educate him. . He did not post the documents on the public Internet and did not want the incident to spread further. If this is the case, all parties involved can call the police and ask the police to investigate clearly who posted the document on the public Internet, causing huge publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also worth noting that there is more than one similar case of online accusations of cheating. Some boyfriends accuse their girlfriends of cheating, and some girlfriends accuse their boyfriends of cheating. The discussion and evaluation of such issues cannot be treated differently because of the gender of the perpetrators. Women&#39;s privacy is privacy, and men&#39;s privacy is privacy. When a man posts a PPT to accuse his girlfriend of cheating, it is an invasion of privacy and should be punished. When a woman publicly accuses her boyfriend of cheating, it is also an invasion of privacy and should also be punished. For similar incidents, relevant departments should treat them equally and either punish them all or not at all. They cannot selectively enforce the law because of gender differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《坚如磐石》，癫狂张艺谋]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258192]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;When talking about &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;, we The unavoidable topic is Zhang Yimou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a national-level director, he has won numerous awards and is also surrounded by controversy. Between praise and praise, the audience can reach a consensus that he is a very stylized director. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Little characters under a thick historical narrative, national character intertwined with power and desire, strong and adventurous use of colors, symbolic protagonists and group performance, and unbridled grand scenes The spectacle brought about...all the signals make it easy for the audience to tell that this is a film branded by Zhang Yimou. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/525ef413691a4e03e0afdaee4db01e50.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;668&quot; height=&quot;276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/525ef413691a4e03e0afdaee4db01e50.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253173 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This style has been throughout Zhang Yimou&#39;s career as a director. It will evolve differently in different eras, but the underlying theme is the same. This continuous output makes Zhang Yimou and his works like a solid building, both good and bad, remaining unchanged. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After a long time, the audience will get bored easily. Just like &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; released during the Spring Festival this year, even criticism has become boring. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But there are exceptions. Once Zhang Yimou shoots realistic themes, he will easily become a &quot;pioneer&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;As early as 1989&#39;s &quot;Codename Jaguar&quot;, he was exploring the shooting method of commercial action films, which was very ahead of the times; &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;1997&#39;s &quot;If You Have Something to Say&quot; &quot;Said&quot;, large-scale hand-held photography combined with unrestrained and bizarre stories, and even some stream-of-consciousness displays; and 2000&#39;s &quot;Happy Times&quot;, under the surface of comedy, is wrapped in tragedy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the intersection of stability and exploration, &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is something special. This movie, which was filmed in 2019, was belatedly released after three years of the epidemic. From subject matter to scale, it&#39;s a bit too sharp. This can also be seen in the &quot;green&quot; tone of the trailer. It seems that the old director is &quot;going crazy&quot; and wants to explore in an unfamiliar genre. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/125b2f0b75d2d3087d490aa6cab3a7a9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;404&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/125b2f0b75d2d3087d490aa6cab3a7a9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253172 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The movie has a group of acting talents, and the actors in the film don&#39;t wear makeup at all. This provides a gimmick for marketing, but returning to the movie itself, it is also the need for the theme. The large area of ​​cold blue-green tones steals the show more than the actors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It is unnatural and unusual, and contains explosive emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the real world, green represents health, environmental protection, vitality, etc. It is a very positive color. But in genre movies, large areas of cold green are &quot;taboo&quot; and are mostly used in specific scenes. Audiences who are familiar with genre movies can easily think of those eerie green lights in horror movie sequences, or those props or scenes of poison, decay, and imprisonment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f3a012e0f370e3e2a835f7b41b0c0ce8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;407&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f3a012e0f370e3e2a835f7b41b0c0ce8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253171 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the non-existent Jinjiang City in &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot;, it is filled with cold green. Zhang Yimou still seems not satisfied. In the whole movie, you can&#39;t even find a few scenes of lighting that make people feel safe. Even in the conversation scenes between front and back, the camera has to keep shaking slightly. This is such a radical and risky approach that it is difficult to explain it with light &quot;stylization&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The unusual &quot;green&quot; is the title of &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;. It represents conspiracy, violence, corruption, etc. In the imaginary city, behind the decent identity, there are many dirty deals hidden. This provides sensory stimulation for the complexity of the characters and the sudden &lt;span>; violence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I felt a sense of insecurity throughout the movie. The audience is neither flattered nor protected. Conflicts and violence come unexpectedly, and the scale is extremely large. You can even feel the uncontrollable intense emotions of the main creator. At every key point of the plot, he will never show mercy and give you a break. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/dc907405800990169839ba1fc44896d3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/dc907405800990169839ba1fc44896d3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253168 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the anti-crime theme, the worst thing to do is to make faces. The righteous side has no brains and is naturally correct; the evil side is unhappy and is determined to destroy things. For a large-scale movie, the difficulty is not to find a group of excellent actors, but to make each character stand out regardless of the size of the role and become a solid node in the story network. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Screenwriter Chen Yu&#39;s approach is to weave the characters into an intricate network of relationships starting from the two poles of good and evil. For example, Chen Chong, who plays the lover of the deputy mayor, does not have a heavy role, but such a minor role has a clear relationship with the characters of Lei Jiayin, Zhang Guoli, and Yu Hewei. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The most impressive part is when Li Zhitian, played by Yu Hewei, comes to threaten. Chen Chong was motivated by his interests, and his words were sharp and he refused to give in. But after learning about the betrayal of her husband who missed his old love, Chen Chong went from sadness to anger to decisiveness in an instant, until the confrontation was over, when the door was closed, tears flowed out, and the whole person collapsed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/942a89a62ae35ca160f9a98a68147270.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/942a89a62ae35ca160f9a98a68147270.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253170 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Such a character has a dark interest chain side and a sentimental side as a lover. The complexity of the character does not need to be elaborated, and it all depends on the actors&#39; superb performances. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this is a group drama, and it is not enough just for a character to be well written or for an actor to perform well. In a group drama, the characters intertwine and interact to form a network with a complex structure but clear lines. Each &lt;span>; character must work hard at a node to create a resonant force, giving the whole story a sense of fate. It seems that everyone is heading towards the end, and the journey is extremely exciting, and the result is already determined. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/353cabfdbb000381dc01ffa4e1263e39.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;407&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/353cabfdbb000381dc01ffa4e1263e39.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253169 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this movie with a very average cast, Yu Hewei provides a subversive performance. If the whole story is viewed as a storm, Lai Chih-Tian is certainly the eye of the storm. In the transaction with the powerful party, he is a pawn in front of the stage; in the confrontation with the righteous party, he is an old fox who calmly responds; and in front of his daughter, he is a doting father who switches in a second. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Zhang Yimou uses several famous scenes to accumulate his complexity, his origin and struggle, hegemony and ruthlessness, violence and cruelty, meticulousness and tenderness... &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The scene that impressed me most was the moment before facing death, he lowered his voice and did not want to disturb his sleeping daughter. The director did not zoom in. Amidst the violence and chaos, the hero, who always talked and laughed freely, could only plead feebly. It is precisely this feeble request, the request that is easily ignored, that is the two sides of this character: he seems to be in control, but in fact he is in a panic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is not grand, exciting, or pleasing to the audience. Instead, it is full of extreme use of color, turbulent camera language&lt;span>;, and complex and dark plots. It is another side of Zhang Yimou, not pleasant, but shocking enough. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[地方城投为何弃美元债，发日元债？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258234]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/08/w1sXZW7OyMDxPsetTQcXnApMd5ld6UzE1Wb1raow.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/w1sXZW7OyMDxPsetTQcXnApMd5ld6 UzE1Wb1raow. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253300&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ganyu District, Lianyungang City, Jiangsu Province, the city invested in the first Japanese yen bond. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local urban investment companies have found a new overseas financing channel - Japanese yen bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This bond is the first local state-owned enterprise yen bond.” In April 2023, the official website of China Chengxin Green Gold International Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as China Chengxin Green Gold) stated that Lianyungang City Ganyu City Construction and Development Group Co., Ltd. issued Japanese yen bonds with a scale of 5.8 billion yen (approximately 280 million yuan). The bond term is 3 years and the coupon rate is 1.8%. China Chengxin Green Gold provided evaluation opinions for this bond issuance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Prior to this, the main overseas bonds issued by local urban investment companies were US dollar bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Chinese-funded enterprises, Japanese yen bonds refer to bonds denominated in Japanese yen borrowed from overseas by domestic enterprises and the overseas enterprises or branches they control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, since 2023, as of October 6, 2023, 7 urban investment companies across the country have issued 7 yen bonds, with a total scale of 66.4 billion yen (approximately 32 billion), with a coupon rate between 1.4% and 2.3%. Urban investment companies that issue Japanese yen bonds are distributed in Jiangsu, Shandong, and Sichuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the Japanese yen bond issued by Jiangsu Hanrui Investment Holdings Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Hanrui Investment) in August was the largest, reaching 16.72 billion yen (approximately 800 million yuan), with a coupon of The rate is 1.7%. Hanrui Investment is 100% owned by Zhenjiang State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The actual issuance cost is much higher than the coupon rate&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The issuance materials of 7 Japanese yen bonds show that 4 companies belong to municipal urban investment platforms. Three are county-level urban investment platforms. The bonds issued are all with fixed interest rates, the issuance period is three years, and they have an SBLC (Standby Letter of Credit) issued by the bank as a credit enhancement method. However, none of the seven yen bonds showed bond ratings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, a standby letter of credit refers to a standby letter of credit issued by a bank to the beneficiary at the request of the applicant, guaranteeing that when the applicant fails to perform its responsibilities or obligations as agreed between the parties, the bank, as the guarantor, will act on behalf of the beneficiary. It fulfills payment obligations or financial compensation obligations of a certain amount and within a certain period of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The urban investment company where Chen Gong works issued a Japanese yen bond in 2023, and he participated in the issuance. Chen Gong told Southern Weekend reporters that in order to allow the bank to issue a valid letter of credit, the company made a physical mortgage to the bank, and the value of the mortgage was higher than the financing amount. In addition, the company pays two points to the bank as a filing fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The coupon rate of 1.4%-2.3% means that the buyer’s profit margin is limited. The latest five-year LPR is 4.2%. In addition, urban investment platforms in Jiangsu, Shandong and other places are generally under heavy debt pressure and have debt repayment risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, who is buying the Japanese yen bonds of urban investment companies? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Like U.S. dollar bonds, the buyers are mainly domestic financial institutions.” Chen Gong further introduced that the company’s Japanese yen bonds were purchased by a domestic bank, and the purchase matters had been negotiated with the bank before issuance. , that is, through the channel of Japanese yen bonds, &quot;because the interest rate is low, on the basis of the coupon rate, the company privately pays two points of interest to the buyer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, there is a transaction fee of about 3‰ for issuing bonds. Including certification fees, etc., the actual issuance cost of Japanese yen bonds is much higher than the coupon rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the bond issuance materials, the above-mentioned seven urban investment companies issued Japanese yen bonds mainly to supplement working capital, project financing and refinancing of offshore bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Gong explained that domestic financing is restricted, and the direct purpose of issuing Japanese yen bonds is to alleviate financial pressure. In addition, it can also complete the local investment promotion task. &quot;Although domestic institutions are buying, if they go through overseas channels, it becomes overseas funds.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Chinese-funded U.S. dollar bond issuance hits record low&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For a long time, Chinese-funded enterprises, including urban investment companies, have mainly issued U.S. dollar bonds overseas. debt. However, in the past period, the issuance of Chinese dollar bonds has been shrinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Lianhe Credit Ratings report shows that in the second quarter of 2023, due to the Federal Reserve’s interest rate hikes that pushed up issuance costs and the impact of credit risk events, the issuance of Chinese U.S. dollar bonds shrank significantly. From April to June, a total of 656 Chinese dollar bonds were issued, with an issuance scale of only US$9.221 billion, a record low in the past decade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of the industry distribution of issuers, the financial sector is the area with the largest issuance scale in a single quarter, and the issuance scale accounts for 59% of the total quarterly issuance. The issuance scale of urban investment companies was 19.78%, and the proportion of the real estate sector’s issuance scale was reduced to less than 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Xiangyu, president of Hong Kong Renhe Investment, has been engaged in high-yield bond investment for many years and is familiar with the Chinese dollar bond market. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the main reason why urban investment companies turned to Japanese yen bonds was that the cost of issuing US dollar bonds was too high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If the company issues US dollar bonds, the actual cost will be around 12%.” Chen Gong revealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other countries are also actively issuing Japanese yen bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, &quot;Nihon Keizai Shimbun&quot; reported that in the second quarter of 2023, the amount of Japanese yen bond issuance was approximately 850 billion yen (approximately 40.9 billion yuan), reaching the highest level in a single quarter in four years. highest level. The Bank of Japan said it would continue to implement large-scale easing policies, with interest rates stabilizing and bond issuance becoming easier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April previously, Berkshire Hathaway, owned by stock god Warren Buffett, issued five yen bonds, raising a total of 164.4 billion yen (approximately 7.9 billion yuan). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Chen Gong is a pseudonym)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西新余公开中奖者信息：彩票公信力应高于“个人隐私权”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258202]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, Xinyu, Jiangxi Province disclosed information about a lottery winner, which attracted widespread attention. Information about Chinese lottery winners is generally considered to involve personal privacy and will not be made public. Xinyu can be said to have pioneered the trend and is worthy of promotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official social media account of the Propaganda Department of the Xinyu Municipal Party Committee &quot;Xinyu Release&quot; released a notice from the Xinyu Branch of the Jiangxi Sports Lottery Center on October 4, stating that a resident of the city won an instant sports lottery of 300,000 yuan. Yuan prize money, some netizens questioned his identity. In order to clarify the facts, with the consent of the winner, his personal information was disclosed. He was Luo Weijun from Beicun, Zhouyu Road, Xingang District, Yushui District, this city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some netizens still expressed doubts about the disclosed information about the winners. Some asked why the ID number and photo were not disclosed. Others said that after asking the village committee, the village committee said there was no such person. However, objective analysis shows that since the official has chosen to disclose the winner&#39;s information, it would be foolish to make further fraud, because it would be easy to be discovered and fall into a larger whirlpool of public opinion; netizens can independently verify whether it is true or false. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Keeping the winners confidential is written into the lottery management regulations, and not disclosing their information is &quot;lawful&quot;. Therefore, although domestic doubts about lottery winners continue, almost no lottery management agency has disclosed winner information. In February 2023, the Shaanxi Sports Lottery Center released a video of an 18 million yuan sports lottery winner claiming his prize. The winner&#39;s sentence &quot;I am from the Sichuan and Chongqing area&quot; aroused doubts among netizens. There are also many winners in the lottery claiming videos wearing clothes with the logo of the lottery center, which also makes many netizens suspect that the winners are sports lottery insiders. In the face of these doubts, the Sports Lottery Center either did not respond, or said that the winner wore clothes provided by the Sports Lottery Center to avoid exposing his identity. Almost no lottery management center chooses to make winner information public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason for not disclosing lottery winner information is that the Lottery Management Regulations formulated by the State Council stipulate that the personal information of lottery winners should be kept confidential. The purpose of this regulation is to protect the privacy of the winners to prevent the information about their overnight wealth from being known to the public and causing some adverse consequences. The original intention of keeping the winners secret may be good, but it has affected the credibility of the lottery. Many people suspect that the information about winning big prizes is just false information released by the lottery center to induce lottery players to buy lottery tickets. The so-called &quot;fictitious person who gets something for nothing to deceive a large group of people who want to get something for nothing in order to support a small group of people who get something for nothing.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These doubts are not groundless. During the live broadcast of lottery draws, there have been farces of &quot;re-recording&quot;, and there have been &quot;anti-gravity&quot; incidents such as lottery machine balls being adsorbed on the track and not falling. This inevitably leads to suspicion that the winning numbers can be manipulated. Previous corruption in the Lottery Management Center has also been confirmed by officials. Many former directors and deputy directors of the China Welfare Lottery Center were investigated and punished for serious violations of disciplines and laws. The National Audit Office&#39;s audit of lottery funds in 18 provinces and autonomous regions showed that more than a quarter of the funds were used in violation of laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To break doubts and restore credibility, the lottery system needs to be more transparent. Disclosing lottery winner information is an effective way. Welfare lotteries and sports lotteries are public welfare undertakings, and the public has the right to know where the funds they raise go. Especially when the credibility of the lottery has been severely challenged, the social public interest of openness, fairness and justice in the lottery should take precedence over the personal privacy rights of the winners. If someone is worried that their personal privacy will be leaked after winning the lottery, they can choose not to buy a lottery ticket. Even if they win, they can also give up the prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purpose of disclosure is to maintain the credibility of the lottery. Lottery systems in most countries require the disclosure of winner information. Lotteries in most states in the United States require winners to disclose their names, photos, regions and other information. The Western Canada Lottery Company clearly stipulates that lottery winners must disclose their personal identities, otherwise they cannot claim the prize. Although the European &quot;Millions Lottery&quot; does not compel the disclosure of personal information of lottery winners, about a quarter of the winners still choose to disclose their identities. Practice has proved that disclosing personal information has not caused any problems for these winners. For lottery winners, the biggest problem they face is the change in mentality after becoming rich overnight, rather than the danger of &quot;persuading donations&quot;, &quot;forcing donations&quot;, &quot;borrowing money&quot; or even being stolen or robbed from the outside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Jiangxi Xinyu Sports Lottery Center encountered doubts this time, it did not avoid or prevaricate on the grounds of &quot;keeping the lottery winner confidential&quot;. Instead, it disclosed some of his information with the consent of the lottery winner. . This is a huge improvement and deserves a lot of praise. However, as the &quot;Lottery Management Regulations&quot; still clearly stipulate that winner information must be kept confidential, this approach can only be a &quot;special case.&quot; Theoretically, under current regulations, if the winner does not agree to disclose personal information, the lottery center cannot force it to be disclosed, and the lottery center has no incentive to proactively contact the winner to seek consent. After all, &quot;keeping the winner&#39;s confidentiality&quot; is its legal duty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is necessary to amend the lottery management regulations to make the disclosure of winner information a principle and non-disclosure as an exception. If the winner is worried that the disclosure of personal information will have a serious negative impact on him or her, he or she can apply to the judge, who will decide whether he or she can receive the prize anonymously. Or, if you claim the prize anonymously, you can only receive a small part of the prize, and the rest of the prize will be regarded as forfeit. Only by putting the lottery players&#39; right to know first can the lottery have credibility and the public welfare undertakings of the lottery gain lasting vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“约旦科比”终局之战发挥不理想，菲律宾男篮70:60胜约旦队亚运夺冠]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258222]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 09:58:04&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Jordanian player Rhonda Jefferson (right) Breakthrough with the ball in the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/38957690c3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/38957690c3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253280&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Jordanian player Rhonda Jefferson (right) dribbled the ball through during the game. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The men&#39;s basketball event of the Hangzhou Asian Games was completed on October 6, 2023. The Philippine team, with a more balanced overall strength, defeated the first-ever Asian Games 70:60. The Jordanian team reached the Asian Games final and won the championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the first half of the final, the Philippines took the lead. Philippine player Justin Brownlee attracted the opponent&#39;s defense and then assisted his teammates to score consecutively, scoring 11:5. Start. Renda Jefferson, known as &quot;Jordan Kobe&quot;, continuously attacked the opponent&#39;s basket, causing damage and narrowing the point difference. At halftime, the two teams were tied at 31, still on the same starting line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The complete picture caption is not shown - Jordan&#39;s core player Rhonda Jefferson has some similarities with the late NBA superstar Kobe Bryant from his appearance, playing style, jersey number and sneakers. . On October 6, 2023, Jefferson played 39 minutes and 53 seconds, scoring 24 points, 12 rebounds, 5 assists and 2 steals.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07 /cbd819722f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/cbd819722f.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;253281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ronda Jefferson, the core player of the Jordan team, from his appearance and playing style to his jersey number and sneakers, They are all somewhat similar to the late NBA superstar Kobe Bryant. On October 6, 2023, Jefferson played 39 minutes and 53 seconds, scoring 24 points, 12 rebounds, 5 assists and 2 steals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Because his appearance and playing style resemble the late American star Kobe Bryant, Jefferson attracted the attention of some fans. With his outstanding performance, the Jordan team made it all the way to the finals, but in the final battle against the Philippines, his performance was not ideal. As the core players of the two teams, Jefferson and Brownlee both scored more than 20 points in the finals, but Brownlee&#39;s offensive efficiency was higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Philippine team player Angelo Kwame (front right) fought during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/07/9cb12d74f2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/07/9cb12d74f2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 6, 2023, Philippine Team Player Angelo Kwame (front right) fights during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Jordanian player Rhonda Jefferson (middle) made a layup during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/07/ba465f8e4b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/07/ba465f8e4b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253283&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, Jordanian player Lun Jefferson (center) makes a layup in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of the final, the two teams were still inseparable. In the second half of the third quarter, the Philippines team began to exert its strength, making consecutive shots and penalties. With a tip-in at the buzzer at the end of the third quarter, the Philippines led by 10 Entering the final quarter. In the fourth quarter, the Philippine team played steadily, and the Jordanian team continued to try to narrow the gap with long-range shots, but the cold touch did not improve. The game lost suspense after Jefferson missed two key free throws. In the end, the Philippine men&#39;s basketball team defeated the Jordan men&#39;s basketball team 70:60 and won the gold medal in the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, the Philippines team finally defeated the Jordan team 70:60 and won the men&#39;s basketball championship of the Hangzhou Asian Games.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/6870d1a676.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/07/6870d1a676.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253284&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 6, 2023, Philippines The team finally defeated the Jordan team 70:60 and won the Hangzhou Asian Games men&#39;s basketball championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, Justin Brownlee, the core player of the Philippine team, bit the gold medal in his mouth.&quot; src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/400e64352b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/400e64352b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253285&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On October 6, 2023, Justin Brownlee, the core player of the Philippine team, bit the gold medal in his mouth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Winning the Hangzhou Asian Games is the fifth time the Philippine team has won the Asian Games men&#39;s basketball gold medal. They have also won 1 silver medal and 2 bronze medals. The Jordanian team, which won second place, has also created the best result of the Jordanian men&#39;s basketball team in the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 6, 2023, the Philippine team that won the final cut off the net as a souvenir to symbolize the honor achieved.&quot; src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/215cdd3a5e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/215cdd3a5e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253286&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>;On October 6, 2023, the Philippine team that won the final cut off the net as a souvenir to symbolize the honor achieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[百余家企业被“公开除名”，科学减碳有多难？ ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258230]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/QCLASjAcX5D3H6FtvhpuGOvsy1zfw8Tf7DDvzPyM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/QCLASjAcX5D3H6FtvhpuGOvsy1zfw8Tf7DD vzPyM. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;July 24, 2023, Suichuan County, Ji&#39;an, Jiangxi Province, Zhufeng Peak, clouds and mist Swirling wind turbines. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If achieving carbon neutrality is regarded as a marathon, many companies are willing to stand on the starting line. But after the gun goes off, only half of the players actually take a step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to work together, there are many &quot;group chats&quot; around the world - various environmental initiatives attract companies to join and promise to achieve what goals by when. However, if the company fails to report progress to the &quot;group owner&quot; in a timely manner, it may be removed from the group chat or even have its name made public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, a group leader known for its strictness, &quot;The Science Based Targets Initiative (SBTi)&quot;, marked 121 companies and financial institutions around the world in August 2023. &quot;Commitment&amp;nbsp;removed&quot; tag, the list keeps growing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SBTi was jointly launched in 2015 by the World Resources Institute (WRI), the Center for Global Information (CDP), the World Wildlife Fund (WWF) and the United Nations Global Compact (UNGC), in partnership with the Paris Agreement and global temperature control goals. Companies joining need to set goals and submit progress regularly. A total of 1,097 companies around the world will have their goals verified by SBTi in 2022. In February 2023, a report by the UNGC and Boston Consulting showed that companies that had made commitments in accordance with the Science-Based Carbon Target Initiative standards accounted for 35% of the total market value of global companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The companies removed this time include 100 foreign companies such as Amazon, Schneider, and Yahoo Japan, as well as 21 Chinese companies (including Hong Kong and Taiwan) such as Trina Solar, ZTO Express, and Qinhuai Data. This move was considered &quot;unkind&quot;. Amazon was once a core sponsor of SBTi, and the Earth Foundation established by Amazon CEO Bezos is still a core sponsor of SBTi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An SBTi spokesperson told Southern Weekend reporters that the public removal of the list of companies is to increase the transparency and responsibility of corporate climate actions. SBTi has the responsibility to increase its ambitions based on the increasingly urgent situation of climate science. However, SBTi has not completely closed the door. Removed companies are welcome to resubmit their goals. After being successfully verified, they can rejoin the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is too difficult to clock in on time&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Committed to setting a Science-based target (SBT) within 24 months, and is the first person to join SBTi step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, this goal is in line with the Paris Agreement: to control global temperature rise within 2°C and strive to limit it to 1.5°C. For specific companies, it includes short-term and long-term goals. For example, a company can set a short-term goal of &quot;using 2021 as the base year to reduce emissions by 42% by 2030.&quot; The long-term goal must comply with SBTi&#39;s net zero standards. More than 90% carbon emission reduction needs to be achieved by 2050. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After submitting the letter of commitment, the company needs to submit its goals to SBTi for verification within 24 months. It is similar to preparing to run a marathon, planning when and where to run, and how to check in. In the past, companies that failed to submit targets on time, withdrew their commitments or made operational changes would be removed from the list by SBTi in the background, but the new policy is to make them public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 21 Chinese companies removed by SBTi (including 1 Hong Kong company and 3 Taiwanese companies) cover various industries such as logistics, photovoltaics, and information and communication technology (ICT). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters contacted 17 companies registered in the mainland. Two companies admitted to Southern Weekend reporters that the current corporate carbon emission reduction work is insufficient; one company explained the progress of the company&#39;s carbon emission reduction work; Zhongtong Express, Hebei Chengxin Group, Guangzhou Yayao Electrical Appliances, Jiangsu Hongbang Chemical Technology Co., Ltd. and other companies declined Southern Weekend&#39;s interview request; 10 companies did not respond, and Southern Weekend reporters did not find any public statements from these companies regarding the removal. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Enterprises also have difficulties in being removed from the list for failing to submit the &quot;punch in&quot; plan in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SBTi standards are constantly updated, and the latest version is version 5.1. In version 5.0 in July 2022, the minimum temperature rise for short-term targets is tightened from below 2°C to 1.5°C, and the target period that companies can set is shortened from 15 years to 10 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ray Atkinson, a spokesperson for Smithfield Foods, which was removed, said in an email that SBTi introduced new metrics and different reporting for the forest, land and agriculture industry in September 2022. requirements, which prevents pork producers and food processing companies from submitting science-based targets by the deadline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Enterprise types and sizes vary, and the difficulty of setting goals also varies. After being removed, Amazon issued an announcement stating, “Developing appropriate carbon emission guidelines and practices for a large enterprise like Amazon is complex and takes time, making it difficult for us to submit meaningful and scientifically accurate carbon emissions within the required time. emissions targets”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, SBTi provides targeted goal setting guidance for 14 industries including aluminum, clothing and footwear, aviation, construction, and information and communications technology (ICT). The remaining industries need to follow unified standards set a goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that among the 121 companies that were removed, the top three industries were food and beverage processing, technical hardware and equipment, and the chemical industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ZkXhQqbUW3vIGTre0rLrbi2LpIIRglKAs0iIwxkL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1121&quot; height= &quot;1419&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/ZkXhQqbUW3vIGTre0rLrbi2LpIIRglKAs0iIwxkL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253288&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Analysis of the list of companies removed by SBTi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Huang Siqi compiled Liang Shuyi&#39;s drawing/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The emissions of these three industries mainly come from scope 3, that is, the corporate value chain All other indirect emissions generated in. For large enterprises, Scope 3 is the biggest carbon reduction challenge. (According to SBTi requirements) linearly reducing absolute emissions by 2.5% per year is very difficult.&quot; Third-party carbon emissions management agency Yan Luhui, founder and CEO of Carbon Block, speculated that this may be the reason why these companies have difficulty submitting targets for verification on time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the Chinese companies whose commitments were removed by SBTi this time, a new energy manufacturing company that did not want to be named told Southern Weekend reporters that the company’s carbon emissions from the upstream supply chain accounted for less than 1% of the total carbon emissions. The proportion is relatively large. How to collaboratively promote carbon reduction across the entire industry chain is the biggest difficulty facing the new energy manufacturing industry in reducing carbon emissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;SBTi’s emission reduction requirement for scope 1 and scope 2 is to linearly reduce absolute emissions by 4.2% per year. Yan Luhui believes that this is for manufacturing industries where scope 2 emissions account for more than 80%, such as textiles or cosmetics. For suppliers, it is also very difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jun, founder of Climate Future and author of &quot;The Carbon Neutrality Era&quot;, told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Submitting a letter of commitment to SBTi is very simple. You only need to fill in the basic company information to &#39;join&#39; SBTi, but the settings The conditions for the goal are very stringent. It is like a university that has basically no admission qualification requirements, but it is difficult to graduate.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meeting the SBTi requirements is not easy around the world. According to data updated in real time by SBTi, as of October 3, 2023, a total of 6,249 companies around the world have made commitments, but only 3,540 companies have submitted their goals on time and passed verification, accounting for only 57%. The remaining companies that have not submitted their goals are still within the 24-month commitment period. If they fail to submit their goals after the deadline, they are also at risk of being removed from the list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/cBe9ohHdPpTd9f5cBEwGT6L21ziX19pey9x6JLSI.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1896&quot; height= &quot;844&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/cBe9ohHdPpTd9f5cBEwGT6L21ziX19pey9x6JLSI.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253289&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;As of October 3, 2023, the situation of companies joining SBTi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(SBTi official website screenshot/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Change passive into active&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Join SBTi Many of the Chinese companies are not well-known to the public, and most of their businesses are to&amp;nbsp;B. Even joining SBTi may be driven by downstream brands. Many interviewees called it &quot;passive participation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ambitious companies often encourage suppliers to participate in carbon reduction actions. &quot;Dell&#39;s supplier management guidelines clearly require suppliers to fulfill their SBTi commitments, which is how many Chinese companies join SBTi.&quot; said Ma Yingying, climate and energy project director of the environmental organization Institute for Public and Environmental Affairs (IPE). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters counted information on 121 removed companies. The top three countries and regions are the United States, China (including Hong Kong and Taiwan companies) and the United Kingdom, with 23, 21 and 14 companies respectively; as of press time, In the total list of companies joining SBTi, the TOP3 countries and regions are also the United Kingdom, the United States and China (including 225 mainland companies and 242 companies from Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun, founder of the Institute of Public and Environmental Affairs (IPE), said that a group of multinational companies have made net-zero emission commitments after the Paris Agreement. If local supplier companies cannot follow up on the climate commitments made by brand customers, they will It is possible to be at a disadvantage in global competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, while publicly removing its corporate commitments, SBTi also released the &quot;2022 SBTi Monitoring Report&quot;, which focused on the performance of Chinese companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An SBTi spokesperson responded to a reporter from Southern Weekend. The report shows that in 2022, the number of Asian companies that have set scientific carbon targets and commitments is growing rapidly, with China experiencing the largest increase - the number of companies submitting effective targets has increased by 194%. , “As the source of many global supply chains, China’s growing participation in SBTi could have a huge impact on global businesses’ Scope 3 emissions.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Carbon tariffs and other policies are forcing Chinese enterprises to turn from passive to active and integrate with international standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The EU&#39;s &quot;Carbon Border Adjustment Mechanism&quot; (CBAM), known as carbon tariffs, requires countries or regions that strictly implement carbon emission reductions to pay (return) corresponding taxes when importing (exporting) high-carbon products. taxes or carbon quotas. A total of six categories of commodities, including steel, cement, aluminum, fertilizer, electricity and hydrogen, were included in the first batch and will enter the substantive implementation stage from 2026. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun said that if the carbon boundary adjustment mechanism cannot be effectively followed up, the transitional stage will have an impact on export companies. After formal implementation, the costs of export companies will increase due to carbon tariffs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the analysis of public financial reports and company official website introductions, Southern Weekend reporters found that &quot;operating international business&quot; or &quot;having plans to go overseas&quot; are also common features of removed Chinese companies. For example, Yingqu Technology carries out manufacturing activities in China, Southeast Asia and Europe; Narada Power&#39;s market covers 160 countries and regions around the world; Sichuan Yongxiang, a subsidiary of Tongwei Group, regards product exports and overseas investment as the future development direction of photovoltaic companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to following the requirements of multinational companies, there are also Chinese brand companies taking the initiative to implement scientific carbon targets. In November 2020, JD Logistics became the first domestic logistics company to complete the establishment of scientific carbon targets. In January 2023, Lenovo’s 2050 net-zero emissions target was officially approved by SBTi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Large companies are willing to implement the initiative. On the one hand, it can drive domestic brands to improve their competitiveness and compete with world brands in supply. On the other hand, it can also drive small and medium-sized enterprises to realize their emission reduction responsibilities and public consumption behavior. Respond to the emission reduction initiative and jointly build my country&#39;s dual-carbon goals.&quot; said Guan Weijia, general manager of Guangzhou Jet Carbon Technology Co., Ltd., a domestic comprehensive dual-carbon service provider. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The starting time is later, but the judging standards are the same&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For Chinese companies, the starting time is later, but the referee will not lower the judging standards. is the bigger challenge we face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Yingying also found that the carbon management level of many manufacturing enterprises in China is still in its infancy. On the one hand, they lack an in-depth understanding of proper terms such as carbon targets; on the other hand, they lack mastery of their own carbon emission data. Not enough, I blindly joined SBTi under the call, but it was difficult to achieve the goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For companies that are expanding rapidly, it is not easy to increase production while reducing carbon emissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guan Weijia told Southern Weekend reporters that most of the early Chinese companies that actively responded to SBTi were industry leaders with high brand goals and keen business acumen. Why was it removed? Compared with terms such as &quot;broken trust&quot; and &quot;greenwashing&quot;, a more appropriate understanding should be that there is a deviation and incompatibility between the company&#39;s low-carbon goals and implementation path plans. &quot;From a subjective perspective, this group of companies is by no means just shouting slogans and doing nothing. It must be admitted that Chinese companies started their low-carbon actions later than international companies, and there is currently a certain gap. Therefore, under the same goals, domestic companies need to pay more Work harder.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Jun said that on the one hand, more digital solutions are needed to help Chinese companies achieve their goals. On the other hand, SBTi also needs to cooperate with stakeholders to develop scientific and reasonable emission reduction target setting methodologies based on different development stages and emission reduction responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will SBTi refer to the principle of common but differentiated responsibilities and set different goals for different development stages? An SBTi spokesperson responded to a reporter from Southern Weekend, &quot;All companies must abide by the same standards. Our standards currently do not distinguish between developed and developing countries, but we may review this carefully in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overview Join After all, among SBTi Chinese companies, only a few have had their commitments removed. Yan Luhui believes that SBTi&#39;s public removal of corporate commitments is also a positive signal, which can urge companies to propose goals in a more prudent and responsible manner and not to make blind promises. Regardless of whether they join SBTi or not, companies must have a clear “check-in” plan if they want to achieve any of their own carbon reduction goals. The first step is self-examination. Yan Luhui believes that only by understanding one&#39;s own carbon emissions can we find feasible and practical emission reduction methods that are in line with the company&#39;s experience and development. &quot;The core is to identify the hotspots of one&#39;s own emission reduction and promote emission reduction in a targeted manner.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After figuring out the situation, companies also need to plan a feasible emission reduction path for the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, technology companies’ largest emissions come from data center electricity consumption, and data centers can be moved to western provinces such as Qinghai and Ningxia where green electricity is abundant; consumer goods companies have high raw material consumption, so they focus on finding In terms of alternative materials, some stationery brands use renewable recycled lunch boxes as raw materials for pen holders; the core of logistics companies is to reduce fuel emissions from transportation, and they can shorten the distance by changing transportation methods or optimizing routes through artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[总感觉自己被封印在床上？你不是一个人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258212]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/07/17e7725c5a6728bd21a29bd726d67530.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/07/17e7725c5a6728bd21a29bd726d67530.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the blink of an eye, the balance during the National Day holiday has been cleared. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The workers of this generation expressed their inseparability from the bed with jokes, &quot;I don&#39;t want to get up, I want to sleep until the sea is gone&quot; and &quot;The only thing I can afford now is The only thing I can&#39;t put down is the chopsticks, and the only thing I can&#39;t get out of is the bed.&quot; It seems that lying down all the time during holidays and having difficulty getting up during the workday is a post-holiday syndrome among young people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;With the acceleration of the pace of life and the increase of social pressure, more and more people are sleeping poorly and unable to sleep. Poor sleep has become a modern urban disease, and sleeping at night Lack of time and poor sleep quality means staying in bed until the next day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Staying in bed has gradually become a disease of modern people. The sound of roosters, the system&#39;s built-in ringtones, songs you like or hate, mixed ringtones... Various songs with different styles will always sound at the same time at the same time every day, but none of these can wake you up from your sleep. of you. &quot;Give me two more minutes to freeze my memory.&quot; Jay Chou&#39;s lyrics may represent the voice of many seriously bedridden patients. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Where does bedridden syndrome come from? Is it a unique product of modern society or has it evolved from ancient times? Will staying in bed affect your life? How do we say goodbye to &quot;sleeping in bed&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Crowing of cocks doesn’t work, even the ancients also stayed in bed&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It’s not just modern people who like to stay in bed Beds, our ancestors more than 2,000 years ago actually loved to sleep in. The situation and conversation between them lying in bed may seem familiar to people today. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are two sentences in &quot;The Book of Songs·Zheng Feng·The Woman Said Cockcrow&quot;, the woman said: &quot;Cockcrow&quot;, and the scholar said: &quot;Meudan. Zixing looks at the night , stars have bad days.&quot; Meaning, the heroine said: &quot;The rooster has crowed.&quot; The subtext is that it&#39;s time for you to get up. The male protagonist struggled in bed and said: &quot;It&#39;s not yet dawn. If you don&#39;t believe me, open the window and look at the sky, the stars are shining brightly.&quot; Does the male protagonist&#39;s answer sound like what modern people say, &quot;It&#39;s still early, let me sleep for five more days.&quot; Minutes&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reasons our ancestors had when getting up are the same as those of modern people. In &quot;The Book of Songs, Qifeng, Cockcrow&quot;, another bed-ridden lover&#39;s answer is believed to have touched the hearts of many modern people. He said: &quot;It is bright in the east, the light of the moonrise.&quot; Oh, it is not bright in the east, it is the light emitted by the moon. This justification for staying in bed is equally applicable to modern people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition to the common people who love to stay in bed, sometimes the emperor will stay in bed according to his temper. It is often said in the play: &quot;The courtiers are waiting for the cold weather at the fifth watch.&quot; The ministers have to go to court every morning at the fifth watch, waiting to see the emperor. But the emperor sometimes didn&#39;t want to get up early when he went to court so early to listen to politics. The most famous one is probably the sentence in Bai Juyi&#39;s &quot;Song of Everlasting Sorrow&quot; describing Tang Xuanzong and Yang Guifei, &quot;The spring night is short and the sun is rising, and the king will not go to court early from now on.&quot; Tang Xuanzong was so obsessed with beauty that he stayed in bed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Another emperor who was famous for staying in bed should be Ming Shenzong Zhu Yijun. During the middle and late periods of Zhu Yijun&#39;s reign, he rarely went to court. He did not attend the early dynasty for more than thirty years, becoming the emperor with the longest period of &quot;passive sabotage&quot; in the history of the Ming Dynasty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/49ed8865628d023fd418e64280c782f7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/49ed8865628d023fd418e64280c782f7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253245 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt; span>;There are a thousand reasons for those who stay in bed&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Shu Guozhi wrote in &quot;Lying in Bed&quot;: &quot;Lying in bed, I have already woken up, but I have no intention of Get up. The body that lay flat for eight or nine hours the night before has rested enough, and the dream of traveling thousands of miles while sleeping the night before has also stopped. However, this lazy body is still willing to lie down, and the hairspring after the dream is still there. I want to float.&quot; I believe that seriously bedridden patients will sympathize with this statement. Everyone knows that staying in bed is a bad habit. But why can&#39;t I get up once I fall into bed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The imaginative person said: &quot;On the first day, my quilt was sick, and I had to take care of it in bed. On the second day, although the quilt&#39;s disease was cured, But the bed was infected, and I had to take care of it together with the quilt. On the third day, they all recovered, but I was sick, and my quilt and bed had to take care of me...&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;At this time, the psychological school influenced by Freudian theory jumped out and said: &quot;No, no. This is the desire of the id. People have id, ego and superego. When lying in bed, the id It is believed that the body needs more adequate rest in bed, and the superego requires it to get up out of compliance with the rules. People are always contradictory when staying in bed, because the desires of the id conflict with the norms of the superego.&quot;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Scientists tell us that sleeping in bed is actually related to melatonin and light. A gland called the &quot;pineal gland&quot; at the bottom of the human brain secretes melatonin, a hormone that promotes sleep. Its secretion principle is related to sunlight: exposure to sunlight will inhibit the secretion of melatonin, making people in a state of wakefulness; when there is no exposure to sunlight, melatonin begins to be secreted, making people drowsy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Moreover, the time and body temperature when people enter deep sleep can also affect how quickly people get up. As shown in the figure, the higher the body temperature, the more awake the person is, and vice versa, so exercising more can ensure full energy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8a30c4137147207f636b4dc0fea4ef3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;245&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a8a30c4137147207f636b4dc0fea4ef3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253247 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(Zhihu/Screenshot)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, Lai The relationship between bed and work efficiency is also very subtle. Milgram pointed out in his research that staying in bed is a unique type of procrastination behavior compared to other procrastination behaviors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Traditional research believes that the procrastination behavior of staying in bed will only have a negative impact on individuals. Research by domestic scholar Wang Lingzhi shows that students&#39; procrastination behavior will make them unable to complete academic tasks within the prescribed deadline, resulting in poor academic performance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although the traditional academic view is that procrastination will bring a series of negative impacts to individuals, some researchers have recently proposed that procrastination can also benefit individuals at some level. Bring about some positive behavioral consequences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Choi&amp;amp;Chu used a questionnaire method to divide procrastinators into active procrastinators and passive procrastinators in their research. They proposed that active procrastinators can do some things during procrastination. Make more thoughtful decisions and have higher arousal levels under stress levels. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Don’t worry, staying in bed can be “cured” &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Although, staying in bed is not a cure It&#39;s a disease, but if it happens while staying in bed, the consequences may be more serious than getting sick. So, how to “treat” this bad habit? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;First of all, we must develop correct sleeping habits and develop correct waking procedures. For example, if the temperature in the bedroom is suitable, ideally the temperature in the bedroom should not be too low. Especially in winter, if the temperature difference between the inside and outside of the bed is too large, it will take a lot of courage to climb out of the warm bed. Don’t keep the room temperature too warm, as this will make it easier for people to fall asleep and feel groggy when they wake up. The ideal temperature is 16℃-21℃, and put a small basin of water in the room to prevent the air from being too dry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the same time, the room should not be too dark. Research by Professor Maas of Cornell University in the United States has found that sunlight sends a signal to the biological clock, stops the secretion of melatonin that makes people sleep, and activates the awake neurons in the brain to help us wake up. Before going to bed, you can leave a small crack in the curtains, so that the morning sunlight can shine in through the window, telling the body that a new day has begun and it is time to get up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Be prepared and prepare an extra alarm clock. For some people, one alarm clock is not enough. If the alarm clock goes off, you will continue to sleep after it, and when you wake up, you will find that it is already late for work. Then prepare two alarm clocks. The set times should not be too close to each other, preferably 30 minutes apart. The second alarm clock should be set for a time when you must wake up. One is placed at the head of the bed, and the other is placed a little further away. You have to get out of bed to turn it off. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It’s no wonder that alarm clocks that deduct money if you don’t get up are so popular among young people. This alarm clock called Kello limits the number of &quot;naps&quot; the user is allowed to do after setting the alarm in a week. If the user does not get up and turn off the alarm after the preset time, Kello will deduct money from the subsidy in the APP. , are you still staying in bed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, you must regain consciousness as soon as possible and massage your face. When you have just woken up and haven&#39;t opened your eyes, you can use massage to increase blood circulation and help you wake up slowly. First, use the palms of both hands to press around the eye sockets from outside to inside, then the forehead, cheeks, and ears. Use your fingertips to gently tap with different intensity until the entire face is touched. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The most important thing is to adjust the sleep rhythm. Getting up at a regular time and sleeping for as long as you need is the most basic and effective way to get rid of bed rest. Try to get up on time every day for a few days, and you will find that the time you go to bed is quietly advancing every day. Slowly, your body will establish a new sleep and wake-up pattern. You will feel sleepy at the fixed time, and you will feel sleepy when you get up early in the morning. Much more awake. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;So, dear friends, don’t be reluctant to leave the bed. Start a new day by refusing to stay in bed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上交所、深交所：现阶段A股市场实行T+0交易的时机不成熟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258220]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Shanghai Stock Exchange and the Shenzhen Stock Exchange’s WeChat official account, some self-media said recently that A-share trading will be extended after the holiday. Time, and trial T+0 trading on some stocks. How do the exchanges comment on this? The Shanghai Stock Exchange and the Shenzhen Stock Exchange said that we are aware of the above rumors and the relevant content is not true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 18 this year, the relevant person in charge of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, when answering reporters’ questions about activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence, proposed to study the appropriate extension of the trading hours of the A-share market. This work involves a wide range of areas and has a large impact. The exchange is conducting in-depth research and demonstration in accordance with the unified deployment of the China Securities Regulatory Commission. In addition, the relevant person in charge made it clear in answering reporters’ questions in the early stage that the time for implementing T+0 trading in the A-share market is not mature at this stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3cea3d840728c32846d0f2b3128b670e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;699&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/3cea3d840728c32846d0f2b3128b670e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253263&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a3dc335b53bd38baf6fe7c7138841cc9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;721&quot; height=&quot;619&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/a3dc335b53bd38baf6fe7c7138841cc9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253264&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>