<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com<item><title><![CDATA[苦等五年，第二批罕见病目录公布：新增86个病种]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257274]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 13:15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/Cig8PapifnL34jPiIf4CiVkuwLzvF8PVvESVrRTB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1082&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/Cig8PapifnL34jPiIf4CiVkuwLzvF8PVvESV rRTB. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251495&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 7, 2022, Xiamen Maternal and Child Health Hospital, medical staff sampled rare diseases Noxinaxen Sodium Injection, a specific drug for spinal muscular atrophy, is ready to be injected into children. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 20, 2023, the official website of the National Health Commission announced the second batch of rare disease catalogs. Add 86 rare diseases such as achondroplasia to the catalog, and the registration date is September 18. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“(This is) something that everyone has been calling for for a long time.” For Huang Rufang, founder of the Coude Rare Disease Center, as well as many rare disease patients and related medical professionals, this is a five-year battle. Much eager waiting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2018, five departments including the National Health Commission jointly formulated the &quot;First Batch Rare Disease Catalog&quot;, which for the first time disclosed 121 rare diseases to the public in the form of a catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This catalog provides an important basis for various departments to formulate policies related to rare diseases. The health department organizes efforts to clarify diagnosis and treatment guidelines for these diseases one by one, and relies on industry organizations to carry out training for medical personnel to improve the standardized diagnosis and treatment of rare diseases. ability. At the same time, a series of supporting systems have been introduced to strengthen the research and development of rare disease-related drugs, accelerate review and approval, and access to medical insurance, which have greatly improved the current situation of rare disease diagnosis and treatment in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, a total of 207 rare diseases have been included in the two batches of rare disease catalogs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/E5gEIt4kPP1SGOGXeuadq6Dpjbou9c1Y4Hh1lnJl.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;914&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/E5gEIt4kPP1SGOGXeuadq6Dpjbou9c1Y4Hh1lnJl.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251496&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture of the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Many I have never heard of the disease.&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;To be honest, I have never heard of many diseases, and I don’t know what to say.&quot; Xing Huanping of Meier SMA Care Center saw She told Southern Weekend reporters after the second batch of rare disease catalogues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 20 million rare disease patients in China, the SMA (spinal muscular atrophy) patients helped by Xing Huanping are lucky to have technological breakthroughs from pharmaceutical companies and good opportunities from government reforms. In 2018, SMA was also included in the first batch of rare disease catalogs, and two innovative drugs for symptomatic treatment were approved for marketing in China and entered the national medical insurance catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many rare disease patients and families who were not included in the first batch of catalogs are looking forward to the second batch of catalogs being released, hoping that their diseases will be included in the catalog, so that everyone can at least be seen and have access to the list. More hope.&quot; Xing Huanping said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past five years, all sectors of society have paid close attention to the expansion of this &quot;niche&quot; directory, and the National Health Commission has also disclosed the progress. In February 2022, the &quot;Reply to Recommendation No. 9415 of the Fourth Session of the Thirteenth National People&#39;s Congress&quot; published on the official website of the National Health Commission mentioned that the selection process for the second batch of rare disease catalogs has been launched in due course in accordance with regulations and is in the process of material review. stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Up to that time, the National Health Commission had successively received applications for adding disease categories submitted by relevant departments, &quot;more than 200 copies of relevant materials.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why are these rare diseases included? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There are more than 7,000 rare diseases in the world, and there are more than 1,000 rare diseases in China. Therefore, catalog selection requires considerable prudence and science. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Working Procedures for Formulating the Catalog of Rare Diseases&quot; issued by the National Health Commission in May 2018, the catalog should be formulated based on national conditions and fully combined with factors such as economic development, population situation, and social security levels. And refer to the management experience of countries or regions with similar social development levels to our country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The diseases included in the catalog should meet the following conditions at the same time: there is international and domestic evidence that the incidence or prevalence is low; it is harmful to patients and families; there are clear diagnostic methods; there are treatment or intervention methods , affordable, or there is no effective treatment or intervention but it has been included in the national scientific research project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in November 2019, the China Rare Disease Diagnosis and Treatment Service Information System established and developed by the National Health Commission was put into use, and 324 hospitals in the National Rare Disease Diagnosis and Treatment Collaboration Network began to use the system to register rare disease cases. Work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This system has collected information on about 500,000 rare disease patients. This information is of great significance for gradually understanding the number and distribution of rare disease patients in my country, diagnosis and treatment bottlenecks, disease burden and difficulties, etc. It has important guiding value for government departments to formulate a more scientific and reasonable national strategic plan for rare diseases.&quot; the National Health Commission mentioned in the aforementioned reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“There will be more challenges in the future”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ma Tao, Executive Secretary of the Beijing Sickness Challenge Charity Foundation, learned that the second batch of catalogs was announced, and the first Immediately, I forwarded the news to the WeChat group where my colleagues and the person in charge of the patient organization belong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“On the whole, some of the diseases included in the second batch of catalogs have related patient organizations. These rare disease patient organizations have also done a lot of appeals in recent years, and everyone’s efforts have finally come to fruition. .&quot; Ma Tao told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After calming down, Ma Tao, who has been paying attention to rare diseases for many years, thought that the release of the second batch of catalogs might be the beginning of another long journey. How to diagnose, treat, protect and return more diseases to society requires joint attention and investment of resources from all walks of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that in addition to rare disease organizations, some pharmaceutical companies with related rare disease drug research and development also successively forwarded news of the second batch of catalog announcements on the 20th, such as Zai Lab, Langyu group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;There will be more challenges in the future. For the Pain Challenge Foundation team, our service scope and service capabilities also need to quickly adjust and improve, and continue to work hard.&quot; Ma Tao said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/lrktG44jOOsvFv6MGB3BeOCFImNK4k0GmWYA4lAm.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height= &quot;1152&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/lrktG44jOOsvFv6MGB3BeOCFImNK4k0GmWYA4lAm.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251497&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture from the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/xTVCDAsUlGlKwYhATyMOTbndqtmWN86cFIIMJfxX.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;958&quot; height=&quot;1174&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/xTVCDAsUlGlKwYhATyMOTbndqtmWN86cFIIMJfxX.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture from the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/21/odwQpM9PwOk0QfEGV1yAfwXjkVUxWKGa5xxp2s6Q.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;966&quot; height=&quot;1172&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/odwQpM9PwOk0QfEGV1yAfwXjkVUxWKGa5xxp2s6Q.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251498&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Screenshot/picture of the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/V0dpaBgEqDAfsmKEB5WCxy6jOvBiogAMhDqrBF0W. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;948&quot; height=&quot;1170&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/V0dpaBgEqDAfsmKEB5WCxy6jOvBiogAMhDqrBF0W.png&quot; data-key= &quot;251499&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture of the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/TsYEQMGbCvSpIMNw7927zlhOaQunMAzCsHpssWuj.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;948&quot; height=&quot;1054&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/TsYEQMGbCvSpIMNw7927zlhOaQunMAzCsHpssWuj.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Screenshot/picture from the official website of the National Health Commission)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p >;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“特产互寄”走红，不出门体验当地特色，真的香吗]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257222]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州多区取消限购，买房不再受户籍和社保限制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257250]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 11:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/F9TJYfwjWZ9iJm0jvRlDsk1tav3YuMXNvpnEy8EH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/F9TJYfwjWZ9iJm0jvRlDsk1t av3YuMXNvpnEy8EH. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251493&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangpu District in Guangzhou is one of the three districts where purchase restrictions have been relaxed this time. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You can buy as many sets as you want, anyone can buy them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On September 20, 2023, Guangzhou released new real estate regulation policies. Li Yujia, chief researcher of the Guangdong Provincial Housing Policy Research Center, was invited by relevant departments to write relevant comments one day in advance. He learned that Guangzhou, except for core areas, has lifted purchase restrictions, and buying a house is no longer subject to household registration and social security restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that Guangzhou has become the first city among China’s first-tier cities to relax purchase restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Notice of the General Office of the Guangzhou Municipal People&#39;s Government on Optimizing Policies for the Stable and Healthy Development of the City&#39;s Real Estate Market&quot;, the purchase restriction areas only mention parts of Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, Nansha and Baiyun Districts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these 6 districts, households registered in Guangzhou are limited to purchasing 2 units; households not registered in the city are limited to purchasing 1 unit after paying social security for 2 years, and the time to pay social security is shortened from 5 years to 2 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, only two of the 11 districts in Guangzhou, Conghua and Zengcheng, had no purchase restrictions. After the policy adjustment, Huangpu, Panyu and Huadu were added to the non-restricted areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Real estate prices are starting to increase&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Guangzhou’s new property market policy was announced at around 6 p.m. Zheng Yang, a real estate consultant, was working at a sales office in Huangpu District. Not long ago Foreign customers who are in a hurry to buy a house come to inquire about the qualifications for buying a house. After seeing the news, Zheng Yang immediately contacted the other party and said that the house that was not available for purchase more than an hour ago can now be purchased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Yang said that the company has not had time to react and the price has not been adjusted for the time being. Due to sluggish sales, the price of this property was lowered some time ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huangpu District is about 30 kilometers away from the city center. It is one of the gathering places for home buyers in Guangzhou. Other areas where purchase restrictions have been lifted are similar to Huangpu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that Guangzhou currently maintains purchase restrictions mainly in the four central urban areas of Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan and Tianhe. These areas were developed earlier and are mainly housing stock, with low elasticity of supply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Baiyun is close to the central area and has convenient transportation. It is located in the sub-periphery. There are many new Guangzhou residents buying homes but the supply is small, and the purchase restriction policy has also been maintained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nansha, which is far away from the central city, aims to create a platform for entrepreneurship, innovation, and livability in the Greater Bay Area. It is an important area for Hong Kong and Macao residents to start businesses and live in the mainland. Therefore, despite the long real estate inventory cycle in recent years, we still insist on purchasing restrictions to reduce dependence on real estate and create conditions for the concentration of industries and talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A real estate project in Nansha is raising prices. A real estate consultant told Southern Weekend reporters that after the new policy is introduced, price adjustments will be implemented faster. By next week at the latest, the average real estate price will increase by 5%-8%. He believes that maintaining purchase restrictions represents the value of Nansha District. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Pay less value-added tax on second-hand houses&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to relaxing purchase restrictions, the new policy also proposes to include Yuexiu, Haizhu, Liwan, Tianhe, Baiyun, Huangpu, Panyu, and Nansha , Zengcheng and other districts have adjusted the value-added tax exemption period for individual sales of housing from 5 years to 2 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as this policy for second-hand houses came out, seven or eight new houses were listed in several communities that Song Ming was responsible for within a few hours, and two owners contacted him to lower the sales price. Song Ming has been a second-hand housing agent in Yuexiu District for eight years and now maintains more than a dozen properties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Ming told Southern Weekend reporters that life will not be easy in 2023. The company&#39;s gold medal brokers can only sell one house a month, and many peers cannot sell one in half a year. It is the peak sales season of &quot;Golden Nine and Silver Ten&quot;, and the market is still sluggish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia said that from July to August 2023, Guangzhou’s second-hand housing price index fell among the top 70 cities in the country. The purpose of changing the value-added tax exemption period from 5 years to 2 years is to reduce the cost of transaction links, promote the smoothness of selling and buying, not only satisfy the immediate needs but also ease the demand for house replacement, and ensure the entry of transactions of rigid needs and improvements, new houses and second-hand houses. A virtuous cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the introduction of the New Deal, Li Yujia predicts that in the remaining four months of the year, Guangzhou’s commercial housing market is expected to gradually shift from a continued excessive decline to a bottoming out and stabilizing trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, the Guangzhou New Deal is the implementation of the spirit of the Political Bureau meeting of the Central Committee on July 24, 2023. This meeting proposed that we should adapt to the new situation of major changes in real estate supply and demand, implement city-specific policies and make good use of the policy toolbox, and meet residents&#39; rigid and improved housing needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is not a cyclical change, but a trend change.” Li Yujia said that during the long-term overheating period in the past, the regulatory policies characterized by tightening and demand-side suppression are no longer applicable. Gonna quit.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Zheng Yang and Song Ming are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[商家标低了团购价格该反悔吗？得失不能只看短期，声誉关乎长期利益]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257210]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a customer surnamed Chen in Foshan, Guangdong reported that he bought 6 coins worth 788 yuan for 1 yuan on a certain platform. After buying the set meal, when I went to the store to consume it, I was told that I couldn&#39;t use it and was kicked out of the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have family members who are in business, and it is very common for businesspeople to get prices wrong. On the merchant&#39;s side, once the wrong price is marked, it means a loss of profits. 788 seconds will change to 1. The gap is too big. You can imagine the anxiety in your heart. The store involved stated that it had a live broadcast on the evening of September 9, and the promotional price of the package originally priced at 1,488 yuan was 788 yuan. However, due to a platform system problem, the price was mistakenly changed to &quot;1 yuan purchase&quot;, which triggered panic buying. When it was discovered that it had been It was too late, 500 copies were already sold out in 20 minutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The platform responded that the 1-yuan package was caused by a mistake in the merchant&#39;s own settings. Regarding the merchant&#39;s own practice of setting the store to permanently close in the background, the platform stated that its account has not been canceled and the agreement between the two parties remains. Take effect. Considering the user experience, the platform did not forcefully cancel orders, actively handled customer complaints, and provided some compensation to consumers in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting the price wrong, there are roughly two ways to deal with it. One is to &quot;cancel&quot; the wrong price and recover the loss. The merchants involved actually did this later. In order to protect their interests, they even used non-hospitality methods to drive people away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the merchant&#39;s &quot;repentance&quot; is not without legal basis, because the customer in this incident was involved in &quot;unjust enrichment.&quot; The Civil Code clearly defines unjust enrichment: the fact that there is no legal basis and causes others to suffer losses while oneself gains benefits. Although there is still room for debate as to whether consumers&#39; &quot;1 for 788&quot; behavior is an act of unjust enrichment, because some merchants do engage in such preferential activities, but there is no doubt that merchants have used legal means to put &quot;bleeding bandages&quot; on themselves s right. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, the phenomenon of &quot;snatching wool&quot; by taking advantage of merchants&#39; incorrect pricing occurs frequently, and it is not uncommon for businesses to be stopped according to law. On January 16, 2021, the staff of Chow Tai Fook&#39;s official flagship store entered an incorrect price into the system, and Wang and his wife spent 40,000 yuan to buy gold jewelry with an original price of 250,000 yuan. Chow Tai Fook asked him to cancel the order and was willing to pay the couple 500 yuan each as compensation. After being refused, Chow Tai Fook took Wang and his wife to court. The court ruled that the online shopping contract entered into between the two parties should be revoked. The reason is that Chow Tai Fook marked the price of the gold jewelry involved in the case as far lower than the purchase and actual sales price, which is obviously inconsistent with normal merchant sales behavior, and Wang and his wife failed to provide corresponding evidence to prove that the plaintiff engaged in low-price promotions. Behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But no matter what, the mistakes made by merchants are not caused by consumers. When consumers&#39; enthusiasm for &quot;squeezing out wool&quot; is extinguished by cold water, the reputation of the business may also be damaged. A bright double-edged sword is visible. The aforementioned “788 Set Meal Store” was deducted 3 business points by the platform, and caused a stir on the Internet. The heavy hidden price paid for this is clear evidence. The market economy is a credit economy. When merchants are unwilling to bear the consequences of mistakes, credit has been put into question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another way is to make mistakes and let consumers benefit. But such courageous merchants are rare. In fact, the &quot;one-yuan set meal&quot; is not unrealistic. Many merchants have launched &quot;one-yuan dishes&quot; and &quot;free tastings&quot; in the past, so it is understandable that consumers have expectations of a &quot;one-yuan set meal.&quot; If a merchant believes that instead of trying to &quot;repair&quot; the bad impression it has caused to consumers, it is better to accept the order generously and let consumers enjoy it, then the merchant is likely to obtain unprecedented benefits by becoming a party to a top-notch news event. self-exposure effect. In an era where traffic is king, this kind of focus effect caused by the explosion of public discussion spaces cannot be obtained by spending money on advertising. What&#39;s more, doing so itself is also a warning to one&#39;s own behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to reports, on October 26, 2021, there was a price error in the Yuanqi Forest official store. The original price of 79 yuan for a box (12 bottles) of sparkling water was changed to 10 yuan for 3 boxes, causing users to place crazy orders. , apparently the Vitality Forest suffered heavy losses. However, some people pointed out afterwards that the exposure, popularity, traffic and discussion gained by Yuanqi Forest in this incident brought the brand publicity value to more than 40 million yuan, which far exceeded the losses caused by &quot;mistakes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no absolute &quot;standard&quot; for how to view and calculate the gains and losses involved, but there is no doubt that the public&#39;s feelings in such incidents cannot be underestimated. Consumers come to the store with the hope of enjoying the &quot;one-yuan set meal&quot; but return disappointed. This result is unfair and unfriendly to consumers. In similar incidents, merchants or platforms often use &quot;compensation&quot; to explain the problem, indicating that they are somewhat aware of this problem, but in many cases, merchants do not do enough. This is also the root cause of many consumer complaints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Think of this, what choice should a person make when he makes a mistake. Whether to admit your mistake or not is a choice of interests, but also a moral choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In interpersonal communication, we should not take advantage of other people&#39;s mistakes. This is a normal way of being a human being. But when we make a mistake ourselves, we must consider from a moral perspective whether we should have the courage to admit the mistake and bear all the &quot;costs&quot; it brings, or whether we should try our best to cover it up, deny it, and pass the blame to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, when the economic cost of making a mistake is too great for an individual to bear, it is not incomprehensible to try to gain forgiveness from others and thus get a chance to &quot;recover.&quot; But this is an extreme situation after all. Under normal circumstances, as long as admitting our mistakes will not cause us to be &quot;broken&quot; or unable to sink, we should still face right and wrong with a realistic and unavoidable attitude. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If merchants can still &quot;withdraw&quot; the wrong price, then people cannot &quot;withdraw&quot; what has happened in social media. In this case, whether you care about temporary gains and losses, or whether you care more about long-term reputation (meaning long-term gains and losses), is a very test of character. Facts have shown that we can never completely avoid making mistakes, but being good at &quot;paying for&quot; our mistakes after making them is a knowledge that urgently needs to be &quot;popularized&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[长沙欢迎研发：一场以研发为名的“双转型”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257248]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/21/KpQ4bok8YdveVizq9XBCdcLO6aGmzuqVS6fUixGi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/KpQ4bok8YdveVizq9XBCdcLO6aGmzuqVS6fU ixGi. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There is a surging crowd outside Cha Yan Yuese&#39;s shop. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2018, Hu Biliang, who had studied and worked in the United States for more than ten years, decided to return to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2007, Hu Biliang has studied at the University of Southern California and the University of Pennsylvania, studying under the &quot;father of CAR-T cell therapy&quot; Carl June. After receiving his PhD in the field of cellular immunotherapy, Hu Biliang is also paying close attention to the development of the domestic biopharmaceutical industry. In June 2018, having already started a family in the United States, he decided to return to Changsha with bare hands and start from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years later, another summer, four kilometers away from Hu Biliang&#39;s office, a new R&amp;D institution with the functions of talent gathering, cutting-edge research and achievement transformation - Peking University Changsha Computing and Digital Economy Research The institute (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Peking University Changsha Research Institute&quot;&lt;/span>;) was opened. Bai Zengding, who has been recognized as a high-level talent in a certain first-tier city, decided to give up a subsidy of nearly one million yuan and join the institute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Changsha, an Internet celebrity city, is extremely popular on social media, especially in summer. As a popular summer travel destination, there is even a joke circulating here that &quot;Yuelu Mountain was stepped down by 2cm due to tourists.&quot; However, somewhat unexpectedly, as tourists are coming in droves, top scientific and technological talents are also coming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Changsha welcomes research and development.&quot; This unwritten city attitude has been regarded as a guideline by local politicians before, and finally made its highlight debut in the summer of 2023. On June 19, Shen Xiaoming, Secretary of the Hunan Provincial Party Committee, announced at the opening ceremony of the Yuelu Internet Summit that Changsha is planned to become a global R&amp;D center city. On July 30, the Changsha Municipal Government issued relevant policies and implementation opinions. On September 1, a group of scientific and technological R&amp;D institutions from universities, scientific research institutions, and leading enterprises unveiled their names on site or signed contracts to start construction at the first opening ceremony of Changsha&#39;s efforts to build a global R&amp;D center city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A research and development craze began to stir up this central city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the craze, there are more mysteries of urban development worth studying. After investigation, Southern Weekend found that Changsha’s plan to build a global R&amp;D center city and the micro-innovation practices of this long-established construction machinery capital reveal two transformation models currently taking place in Changsha: First, the integration of manufacturing centers into R&amp;D centers Transformation; second, the integration and transformation from production center to life center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Driven by the &quot;dual transformation&quot;, Changsha&#39;s urban functions and innovation levels are quietly undergoing spiral advancement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/6SXRBhrbyDeoO8GPXQ62tjSsf51l3OfWzy3kWnuE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/6SXRBhrbyDeoO8GPXQ62tjSsf51l3OfWzy3kWnuE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The smart mobility chassis developed by Changsha Automobile Innovation Research Institute can realize functions such as four-wheel independent steering and four-wheel independent drive, and can easily complete U-turns and lateral driving on the spot. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Changsha Evening News all-media reporter Yi Yi/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Interactive network of developers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;I personally have always I am doing research and development in the direction of biopharmaceuticals, hoping to develop a better innovative drug through my own technological innovation.&quot; Having been engaged in virus-related research and gene therapy for more than ten years, Hu Biliang has always regarded the research and development of innovative drugs as a professional pursuit and life goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people did not understand his decision to return to Changsha from the United States to continue this research career, but Hu Biliang had his own considerations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Hunan’s biopharmaceutical industry does have a weak foundation compared to the United States. But if an innovative drug can be produced here, it will not only bring better treatment options to tumor patients in our hometown, but also I can also contribute to the development of the biopharmaceutical industry in my hometown, which is also the core value and significance I pursue in my technology research and development journey.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With such fighting spirit and expectations, in the summer of 2018 , Hu Biliang returned to Changsha alone with bare hands to make preliminary preparations for starting a business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, he was no longer alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here we have support from colleagues in terms of laboratories and equipment, preferential treatment for factories in industrial parks, and assistance from government talent and entrepreneurship policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hu Biliang detailed the help he received from many sources during his entrepreneurial journey and attributed it to &quot;luck.&quot; But in fact, behind this &quot;luck&quot; is the entire city&#39;s respect for the high-tech industry, its preference for high-tech talents, and its expectations for the achievements of high-tech wisdom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such an environment, the implementation process of research and development is relatively smooth. In 2023, Hunan Siweikang Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. founded by Hu Biliang received clinical trial approval for a national Class 1 new drug. This is the first biopharmaceutical IND approval in Hunan Province, which is of great significance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hu Biliang’s plan, in the next three years, the first clinical trial of cell drugs will be completed, and the cell drugs developed by the team can be successfully launched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not only a technological milestone breakthrough, but also the starting point for the vigorous development of a regional industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both are new research and development forces, and they also chose Changsha, but Peking University Changsha Research Institute is the starting point of a different story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an important platform for the transformation of Peking University’s scientific research results, the institute’s research centers fully considered Changsha’s local industrial characteristics when they were first established to “get closer to the market frontier and industrial needs.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Digital Transformation Promotion Center where Bai Zengding is located conducts applied research around data elements and is committed to serving the national strategy of enterprise digital transformation and traditional industry upgrading; the Industrial Intelligence Research Center next door is oriented towards intelligence. The digital transformation needs of manufacturing, logistics and transportation, supply chain and other fields enable the digital transformation and upgrading of enterprises through data, algorithms and models. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Changsha is a big manufacturing city. From hardware, software to cloud services, as well as the huge amount of data in the manufacturing production and processing links, it provides us with a very rich material library, which is why we chose to come here. The reason for being a platform for the transformation of scientific and technological achievements.&quot; Bai Zengding said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to overseas R&amp;D teams and new R&amp;D institutions, there is also a third type of &quot;foreign force&quot; worthy of attention—foreign-funded R&amp;D centers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On one side are newcomers. In 2019, Schaeffler established the second R&amp;D center in Greater China in Xiangjiang New District, and closely interacted with local enterprises Xiangjiang Intelligent and Xidi Intelligent Driving. Through collaborative R&amp;D and information sharing, it accelerated the development of Changsha&#39;s intelligent connected automobile industry. Development process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One is to increase investment. For example, Soenger China plans to invest a total of 3 billion yuan and continue to increase its R&amp;D investment in Changsha. The newly built Soenger Global New Energy Products and Technology R&amp;D Center has a construction area of ​​tens of thousands of square meters and is expected to be put into use within the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the influx of new foreign R&amp;D forces, R&amp;D paradigms of local companies are also sprouting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry is the source of innovation, and enterprises are the core subject of innovation. According to Du Debin, dean of the Institute of Global Innovation and Development at East China Normal University, Changsha, the capital of central China, needs to build a global R&amp;D center city based on its own advantageous industries, conduct differentiated competition, cultivate global R&amp;D centers in subdivided industries, and then spread through innovation. The effect gradually moves closer to the target. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take construction machinery as an example. In 2007, when Hu Biliang went abroad for further study, Shi Wenbing graduated from Huazhong University of Science and Technology majoring in mechanics. Full of longing for the future, he got on the school recruitment bus of Sany Heavy Industry. Soon after, Lu Chuang, who came from Yichang, Hubei Province, decided to continue his studies in the mechanical major of Central South University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Here is the most active market and the most cutting-edge technology in the construction machinery industry.” With the same expectation, the two came to Changsha one after another. Since then, the paths of fate have secretly marked their intersection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fifteen years later, Shi Wenbing became a senior engineer of Sany Heavy Industry, leading a number of major R&amp;D projects, constantly breaking through technical bottlenecks, and going global with the company, using global innovation resources to carry out technological research. It is understood that SANY Group’s overseas business now covers more than 160 countries and regions, and it has 13 overseas manufacturing centers in the United States, Germany, India, Brazil, and Indonesia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After working at the State-owned Enterprise Research Institute for 8 years, Lu Chuang joined an upstream company that provided products and services to Sany Heavy Industry and served as the general manager of Hunan Zhongji Shenyi Testing Technology Co., Ltd., establishing a testing center from scratch. The test base fills the gaps in some testing and pilot service projects for construction machinery and core components. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same industrial chain, in different positions, the chain owner enterprises and supporting enterprises each perform their own duties and jointly contribute to the industrial iteration of construction machinery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Top overseas R&amp;D teams have settled in Changsha, laying the foundation for building chains for emerging industries; new foreign R&amp;D institutions are highly consistent with local industrial clusters; foreign-funded R&amp;D centers continue to increase their presence and interact closely with local companies; at the same time, Changsha Leading companies go global, supporting companies collaborate with each other, and the chain has close relationships and collaborative research. The panorama of Changsha’s R&amp;D entities has basically emerged. Various types of R&amp;D entities show their talents and release the energy of innovation. This is a real and frequent innovation story happening in Changsha. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Wang Fan, director of the Science and Technology and Standards Institute of CCID Research Institute, Changsha’s innovative practices coincide with his views. Wang Fan believes that in building Changsha into a global R&amp;D center city, chain owners should play a leading role, promote in-depth cooperation between large and small enterprises in the chain, continuously strengthen and optimize the chain, and form leading enterprises, supporting enterprises, colleges and universities, and scientific research institutions. An ecological development pattern of collaborative linkage, competition, cooperation and symbiosis among institutes, third-party platforms, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of their existence, the goal of becoming a global R&amp;D center city is not unrealistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the prosperous R&amp;D panorama, what is the driving force that nourishes its vigorous growth? In other words, why does Changsha need R&amp;D so much? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ICcdKzLORYoraEapZrlBHrva0dplbH8IVfOb9GKC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/ICcdKzLORYoraEapZrlBHrva0dplbH8IVfOb9GKC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shenyi researchers are conducting simulation assembly experiments. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Two-way drive of R&amp;D and manufacturing&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Want to answer the above questions , we must first understand Changsha’s industrial background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are seven major 100-billion-level manufacturing industry clusters here, including engineering machinery, automobiles and parts, new materials, electronic information, and energy storage materials. The total digital economy has exceeded 450 billion yuan, and high-tech industries have increased. The average annual growth rate is more than 10%, accounting for 29.6% of GDP. It is also home to the third largest construction machinery industry cluster in the world. The other two are Illinois in the United States and Tokyo in Japan. It is known as the &quot;Construction Machinery Capital of China&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCID Consulting&#39;s &quot;Research Report on the Top 100 Advanced Manufacturing Cities (2022)&quot;, Changsha ranks eighth in the development of advanced manufacturing, ranking first among cities in the central and western regions. This city, which is famous for its soft power of &quot;entertainment&quot;, is also closely related to the hard-core &quot;manufacturing&quot; industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But at the same time, a background of the post-epidemic era that cannot be ignored is the dramatic changes in the international economic and trade pattern, the weakening of the domestic demographic dividend and the tight industrial space. The combined effects of multiple factors have led to the transformation and upgrading of China&#39;s manufacturing industry. Imminent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the views of many researchers, this boom in scientific and technological innovation in the name of research and development, which occurred in the manufacturing city of Changsha, has a certain inevitability: to strengthen technology research and development innovation, increase the localization substitution rate, It is not only a &quot;charge&quot; for the transformation and upgrading of the manufacturing industry, but also a &quot;battle&quot; for core technology dominance, and it is also a &quot;pursuit battle&quot; for the ranking of central cities in the new round of industrial revolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;R&amp;D means &quot;research and development&quot; and refers to the key links in the manufacturing industry from laboratory technology to new product development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Changsha’s proposal to build a global R&amp;D center city is actually a signaling mechanism with a very clear goal, and has a clear intention of leading the way in industrial transformation and upgrading.” Chen Ling, director of the Industrial Development and Environmental Governance Research Center of Tsinghua University, said Now, Changsha is the first city to specifically focus on the &quot;R&amp;D link&quot; as a brand building. In a sense, it takes advantage of local manufacturing advantages to take the lead in the transformation and upgrading of the manufacturing industry driven by R&amp;D breakthroughs or innovation. Judging from the local government&#39;s strategic planning, Changsha City does not intend to leave this transformation and upgrading completely to the market&#39;s own trial and error, but to carry out large-scale planning, layout and investment through the government&#39;s organized approach. This is a comparison Outstanding features. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The source of the government’s organized and planned leadership behavior still comes from enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2018 National People’s Congress and the National People’s Congress, Liang Wengen, then chairman of Sany Group, once proposed that in the face of the digitization of construction machinery and manufacturing, the group would “either turn over or capsize.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Sany Heavy Industry Changsha Factory No. 18 was rated as a &quot;Lighthouse Factory&quot;. This is the second one in Hunan Province and represents the highest level of intelligent manufacturing and digitalization in the global manufacturing field. All equipment in the factory is connected to the Internet, and the flow of production information, usage, and assembly line information is completely connected. All parts transfers in the factory are carried out by AGV (Automated Guided Transport Vehicle) automatic distribution robots.工业机器人代替人工作业，“降本增效”这一高质量发展的代名词，有了生动的场景做支撑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;深耕机器人领域十余年的高狄，对技术研发如何改变传统制造业，有着长久的观察与思考。他所在的长泰机器人，以挖掘制造业技术升级场景、满足应用需求为己任。在高狄看来，若想在工业机器人领域，走到全球的领先位置，长沙或许可以在软件与工业互联网赛道上着重发力，打出差异化的优势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，高狄着重网罗人工智能领域的高科技人才。同样来自东北的郭东妮就是其中一个好苗子。这位看起来白净乖巧的95后女工程师，实际是机器视觉及人工智能算法研发项目组组长，曾带着平均年龄不到30岁的硕士“娘子军”，研发出具有自主知识产权的布匹瑕疵检测系统——“ZTVT胎基无纺布自学习视觉系统”，用人工智能解放了工人的双眼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长泰机器人并不是个例。超能机器人、顶立科技等一众专精特新企业，正依托长沙的科教资源与产业优势，在机器人、智能装备、新材料等诸多领域，爆发出蓬勃的创新生命力。通过细分领域的技术突破，加速产业的升级过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“技术创新实际上包含两个方面，一个是通过技术创新，催生新产品，最后可能会形成一个新的产业；另一种是通过科学技术的创新，推动产业升级换代。后者的需求永远存在，并且体量更大。”杜德斌分析道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，长沙建设全球研发中心城市，就是要通过一系列措施，集聚大量的研发中心，包括跨国公司的研发中心、本地的研发中心、新型研发中心等多种类型，催生商业模式、技术的革新，从而带动产业的升级与城市功能的转变，使长沙从产品生产中心转型为知识生产中心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;制造业的转型升级在国际上有诸多城市案例，以产品生产中心（制造中心）与知识生产中心（研发中心）的关系来看，大概分为三种：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一种是以香港为代表的模式。因生产要素成本上涨，改革开放以来，香港通过“三来一补”的模式将制造业转移至珠三角地区，却并未转向发展研发，而是转型为以金融业与现代服务业为主的国际金融中心——而同为“亚洲四小龙”的韩国、新加坡和中国台湾纷纷搭建起了自己的研发网络。不过，香港对研发始终保持着关注，曾于上世纪90年代探索过“数码港”计划等促进研发的政府行动，而今更是大力发展创新科技，打造向北与深圳科创资源融合的“北部都会区”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二种是以底特律为代表的“单一制”模式。作为美国汽车工业的心脏地带，因转型升级的脚步慢于市场变化，底特律一度人口快速流失、产业急速衰退，经过一系列复苏计划的刺激与引导，这里如今变身为汽车工业的研发中心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样以汽车工业为支柱产业的慕尼黑，却走出了与底特律完全不同的产业路径。这里有宝马历史最悠久的工厂，还有奥迪、曼恩集团等汽车公司的研发总部，是生产与研发兼而有之的“双融合”模式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在杜德斌看来，面对以实体经济为主的产业结构，中国诸多城市应参考慕尼黑汽车产业的发展经验，鼓励企业进行技术研发，同时保留生产中心与研发中心。 “融合转型、兼而有之，才是我们城市产业健康发展的目标。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;视野从海外诸城回到长沙，不难发现，以制造业为重，如今建设全球研发中心的长沙，不正是“慕尼黑模式”的后来者吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多种研发主体汇聚而来，彼此之间密切联动。其本质来源于长沙产业基础好，新技术在这里有着庞大的市场需求与应用场景，从而敦促技术的快速迭代；而新的研发成果又将赋能制造业升级，促进其从规模向研发、品牌等微笑曲线的两端转移。研发与制造之间双向驱动，共同作用于城市竞争力的提升。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至此，我们已然窥得长沙第一个“转型”的全貌：从制造中心到研发枢纽转型，从产品生产中心到知识生产中心转型，并且不是单向度的从“你”到“我”，而是两种中心的相融，是“制造”与“研发”的协同，是“产品生产”与“知识生产”的共生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更为可贵的是，在长沙，这种“融合转型”的模式，不仅发生在产品与知识的生产环节，还发生在“生产中心”与“生活中心”的平衡之中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/FM1Ft4HE3SUe23WhfemVZKpDJ0Rl7Xib6mxHmjTN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1181&quot; height=&quot;2067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/FM1Ft4HE3SUe23WhfemVZKpDJ0Rl7Xib6mxHmjTN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;人才“引与留”的秘密&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;生产中心与生活中心的兼顾与融合，是长沙独有的城市优势。这一特点的直接影响，就是吸引大量人才奔涌而来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十年间，长沙常住人口增长率32.3%，其人口增长绝对值与增幅均位居中国重点城市前列。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈玲介绍，根据清华大学产业发展与环境治理研究中心（CIDEG）联合施普林格·自然集团（Nature Research）发布的《国际科技创新中心指数2022》（Global Innovation Hubs Index, GIHI2022）报告，长沙与人才相关的指标都表现不错，诸如每百万人专业人才流入、每百万人的活跃科研人员数量、高被引科学家数量等指标，几乎都在全球50-70名的排位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人才是创新的核心要素，得人才者得未来。而诸多数据显示，长沙这座城市，在人才吸引力上有着异于其他城市的优势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里既有胡璧梁、白曾鼎等湘籍人才的回归，也是石文兵、吕闯等湖北人才的应许之地，还是高狄、郭东妮等不同年代东北老乡的共同选择……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人才的脚步，早已打破了地理区域的限制，展现出新的流动规律。多名专家分析指出，人才“引与留”的奥秘，在“人随产业走”这一既有定律之外，还在于城市生产中心与生活中心的均衡融合程度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而后者的关键之处在于，能否满足人才对于职业成长与劳动回报的物质性需求；能否满足人才对于房价、教育、医疗等公共服务的保障性需求；能否满足人才对于文化、休闲、消费等公共空间享有的精神性需求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三种需求同时满足，并不是一件容易的事。但是，长沙已然出现了一种新趋势，正由单一生产中心向生产与生活中心融合空间转型。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在王凡看来，生产中心和生活中心的融合是时代趋势，需要更加强调人的主观能动性，应对人的诉求，所反映的是全面、协调、可持续发展的理念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;95后的郭东妮，早在湖南大学读书时，就爱上了长沙的美食和友好的房价，并决定以后留在“这座快乐的城市”。如今的她，工作中是一个专业严谨的女工程师，生活中则是爱跳街舞的活力女孩，休息时与同事一起开车去湘江边露营；或一起玩剧本杀到半夜，回家路上被热闹的小吃街吸引，再大快朵颐吃个夜宵。这是烟火气给人的能量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;80后的吕闯，似乎与郭东妮过着平行生活。十五年前，吕闯选择来到长沙，是为了这里的教育资源与就业机会。在读书期间，每当迷茫困惑时，他就会一个人去爬岳麓山。稍坐片刻，山不言，人自明。如今的他，对商业广场不感兴趣，但仍会不定期带着家人故山重游，体会自己不同阶段的心态变化。这是大自然给人的滋养。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诚如前文所言，胡璧梁回到长沙后，得到了当地人才政策的大力帮扶。在与相关领导的交流中，他深切感受到了政府对于人才的珍惜与尊重，政策服务人才的细心与贴心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“长沙市人才政策实实在在地帮助我解决了一些现实难题，尤其是小孩子入学的问题。”胡璧梁说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年，长沙人才政策22条重磅出台；五年后，长沙人才政策“升级版45条”出炉，从7大方面、提出45个政策要点；两个月后，新政的26个配套实施办法在原有政策基础上再度升级。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从22到45再到26，没有最优，只有更优；没有功劳簿上的安常守成，只有更大的信心和更强的决心。而住房补贴、税收返还等切实的福利政策保障了人才的权益，让他们来得值得。这场“双向奔赴”，成就的是人与城的双份惊喜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同年龄阶段与性格特质的人，对理想生活的定义也不相同，但他们却做出了相同的选择。唯一合理的解释，大概就是这里符合每个个体大多数的需求与想象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生产中心向生活中心融合转型的趋势，构建了长沙“生活友好”的城市特质，而“生活友好”则为“研发友好”与“制造友好”持续赋能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人才政策丰富全面，生活成本较低，医疗教育等公共服务优质，文化创意底蕴深、活力足，多种特质相结合，共同构建出研发空间、生产空间、文化空间、消费空间、文旅空间等均衡相适宜的综合城市系统，促进研发创新人才的集聚，而后智力成果在这里诞生与转化，进一步促进产业转型升级，形成产业和人口螺旋进阶的良性循环，以此为基础带动城市配套设施的完善与生活品质的提高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在谈到如何看待“长沙建设全球研发中心城市”这一话题时，陈玲表示，长沙将“全球研发中心城市”提高到城市名片的高度，通过政策措施展开系统化综合化的运营与布局，势必会产生品牌效应，吸引企业和人才的关注。而这一做法与这座城市一贯以来的形象极为吻合。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的，长沙一直是个鼓励文化创意、包容新兴事物的城市。植根于每个市民心中的休闲娱乐精神与人间烟火气，让这里诞生了制霸卫视黄金档的芒果台，也诞生了茶颜悦色、文和友等一众新消费品牌。其独特的城市气质、多样的旅游资源，持续性吸引大量游客慕名而来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游客必打卡的茶颜悦色，日前宣布投资5.2亿元建设品牌研发及生产基地，重点进行产品技术研发与产品风味研发。相较于第二产业来说，第三产业的研发环节含义更广，不仅包括前端产品、技术的探索，还包括在终端环节的产品与服务创新，从细节出发提升消费体验。此外，茶颜悦色还深入挖掘城市本土文化，通过包装、logo、门店设计等诸多要素，带动传统茶文化以及地域文化的传播。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;提出“拿深圳同等高薪，住长沙宜居房子，干全球软件事业”的万兴，则是长沙创意领域加大研发的另一个例证。 2022年，万兴全球运营总部暨创意软件全球研发中心已正式落户长沙。 3.0项目追加投资已启动，拟规划建立近10万平米的“万兴创意世界产业园”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，文化娱乐与硬核制造的“双面长沙”形象，被“研发”这一纽带连为一体，形成舆论场上的叠加效应，长沙欢迎研发，不限赛道，有胆你就来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“两个转型”同时进行，“三个友好”彼此关联，在中国中部地区开展着的创新实践及其下步走向，不仅将带动新一个创新中心的崛起，也对制造业城市的转型具有示范意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欢迎研发的长沙，也必将被未来欢迎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（南方周末研究员唐家乐、李婧对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[合作25年，一朝决裂：石榴集团“宫斗”祸起境外架构]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257194]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/qYTwUTUzpFC3i0UZdd3SK9eiBsZFmeTTJ4JXWhsL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/qYTwUTUzpFC3i0UZdd3SK9eiBsZFmeTTJ4 JXWhsL. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251285&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pomegranate Group’s Beijing headquarters is located in the Fengtai Branch Center of Zhongguancun Science and Technology Park, also known as the Pomegranate Center. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now both parties are retreating, guaranteeing the delivery of housing, protecting the interests of owners and investors, and not giving the government Cause trouble, so try not to occupy public issues anymore.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, 2023, a Southern Weekend reporter interviewed Cui Wei, chairman and major shareholder of Pomegranate Real Estate Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Pomegranate Group) At that time, the company gave this reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a media communication meeting held 4 days ago, Cui Wei knelt down in public, hoping that financial institutions would not withdraw loans due to the company’s chaos. If financial institutions cause real losses, I will jump from the 22nd floor of the Pomegranate Center where we are.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, nearly three months have passed since internal strife broke out in this private real estate company, which ranks among the top 100 private real estate companies in China. During this period, incidents such as Cui Wei &quot;stealing the official seal&quot; and the dismissal of vice chairman and second shareholder Sang Chunhua frequently aroused public opinion. Sang Chunhua was also involved in a scandalous news. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Cui Wei held a media communication meeting, Sang Chunhua also held a media communication meeting on September 14 and released a reconciliation signal at the meeting. He shouted to Cui Wei: &quot;I am still willing to give in and let you get more until we reach an agreement and stop the dispute.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two sides have been at odds for some time. In 2021, Pomegranate Group failed to go public in Hong Kong. The next year, Sang Chunhua proposed a separation, believing that Cui Wei had not made the right decision in more than ten years and did not want to be held hostage again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei proposed that his equity would require a 30% premium when the company was separated, but Sang Chunhua refused to accept it. Conflicts accumulated over the years are about to break out. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Exposing each other&#39;s shortcomings&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2001, Cui Wei and Sang Chunhua cooperated to establish Beijing Agile Real Estate Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Agile) in Beijing; in 2008 , the two parties also established Huamei K2 Real Estate Investment Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Huamei K2), named after K2, the world’s second highest peak; in 2016, the company was renamed Pomegranate Group, aiming to be the “Apple in the real estate industry.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the more than 20 years since its establishment, Pomegranate Group has developed more than 90 projects in more than 30 cities across the country, focusing on mid-to-high-end residential products. At the press conference on September 11, Cui Wei once stated that the company has not had a single uncompleted building, a financial bad debt, or a bank overdue payment so far. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How difficult it is to achieve such results, so why do we have to come out like this on June 21st?&quot; Sang Chunhua once shouted to Cui Wei from a distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night, a drama of &quot;stealing for official seals&quot; was staged in the conference room on the 16th floor of the Pomegranate Group&#39;s office building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the statement of a company employee signed by &quot;Zhang Yongkai&quot;, Cui Wei believed that &quot;Vice Chairman Sang Sir (Sang Chunhua hopes to be as capable and efficient as the Hong Kong police) has violated the company&#39;s system and affected the company&#39;s operations and other illegal acts &quot;, forcing members of the seal team, including Zhang Yongkai, to stamp documents that could not see the full text. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Cui Wei put the official seal into his pocket and said, &quot;Not only does he have to stamp it, but he also needs to take the seal home. This is his own company, he is the chairman, and this is his right. No one else can control it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After struggling until 4 a.m., the members of the seal team were allowed to go home. From this day on, Pomegranate Group announced that Sang Chunhua would be terminated from his labor contract and all his duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei said that the company’s dismissal of Sang Chunhua was legal and “a serious, legal and regulatory adjustment and defense of corporate governance rights.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main reason for the dismissal of Sang Chunhua was that Sang arranged for relatives, classmates, fellow villagers, etc. to enter the company. The company was internally controlled by relevant interest groups. He was sidelined as the chairman, and the company&#39;s internal management and cost control were extremely chaotic. . Moreover, Sang had problems with his lifestyle, which caused damage to the company&#39;s goodwill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 6, Liu Xia, CEO of Yunhe Variable Group, an investment company, reported Sang Chunhua on Weibo with his real name, saying that he invited many people to participate in unhealthy activities in Beijing on the pretext of eating. I was abused on WeChat and over the phone for dozens of minutes.&quot; It was later revealed that Li Guangtian, president of Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai regions of Pomegranate Group, and Ding Qingwei, president of Jiangsu region, were also involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 8, Sang Chunhua issued a statement saying: &quot;The dissemination of my unverified and untrue remarks by online platforms and individuals has seriously violated my right to reputation. I demand that the slander be stopped immediately.&quot; stigma, and reserves the right to pursue the legal responsibilities of online platforms and individuals. I have entrusted a lawyer to initiate relevant legal procedures.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with Cui Wei&#39;s many accusations, Sang Chunhua also held multiple press conferences, Fight back against it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to disclosing the situation on June 21, Sang Chunhua claimed that the dismissal was without legal decision-making procedures of the company. He also accused Cui Wei to the media of improperly occupying company property and refusing to return it, and installing bugs in the vehicle he was riding in. device. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also attending the press conference with Sang Chunhua on September 14 was Lin Xinwu, the former general manager of the Risk Control Center and Chairman of the Board of Supervisors of Pomegranate Group. He said that Pomegranate Group launched an A-share listing plan in 2016, and 62 core members paid in 216.8 million yuan as partners to participate in the share reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the A-share listing was blocked, Pomegranate turned to Hong Kong stocks in 2021, but still failed, and the partners’ funds were not returned. It wasn&#39;t until the official seal incident broke out on June 21 that Cui Wei, the working partner, &quot;collectively forced the wife to marry&quot;, asked for part of the money back. But the five partners, including him, were not only fired, but also did not receive refunds, totaling 33.5 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sang Chunhua also disclosed that Cui Wei had firmly refused to agree to dividends for 25 years, and the two borrowed money from the company when they needed it. In recent years, Cui Wei has borrowed hundreds of millions of yuan from companies in public names, and his whereabouts are unknown. Cui Wei also used company funds to speculate in Shougang stocks, resulting in a cumulative loss of 6 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei also accused Sang Chunhua of having &quot;huge and sudden&quot; external personal debts, endangering the company&#39;s operational security. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Apprentice or shareholder? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Behind the back-and-forth attacks are actually hidden equity differences between the two parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until August 4, Sang Chunhua still couldn’t enter the office. Downstairs of the company, he held a report on national enterprise credit information disclosure and introduced himself to the camera, saying that he was the director and general manager of Pomegranate Group and held 42% of the shares. The company has only two shareholders, with Cui Wei holding the other 58%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the camera, Sang Chunhua has short buzzcut hair and wears a pair of black-rimmed glasses. He called Cui Weilian twice, but no one answered. Then he dialed 110 and claimed to the police, &quot;I am the boss of this company and he has no right to fire me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, after the shareholding of Pomegranate Group was penetrated, it was two companies registered in Hong Kong, and the national enterprise credit system could not see the shareholding status of the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Pomegranate Group went public in Hong Kong in 2021. The prospectus obtained by Southern Weekend reporters shows that the company has established an overseas equity structure, with Cui Wei holding 57.42% of the shares, Sang Chunhua holding 41.58%, and investors Chen Jianyong holds 1% of the shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yonggang has worked at Pomegranate Group for nearly ten years and is still working next to Sang Chunhua. He told Southern Weekend reporters that Chen Jianyong was a friend of Sang Chunhua. He withdrew his shares after the listing failed. Now Cui Wei and Sang Chunhua hold 58% and 42% of the company&#39;s shares respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the failure of listing, the prospectus of Pomegranate Group is currently invalid and cannot be viewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the face of the media, Cui Wei, a former geography teacher, always calls Sang Chunhua his &quot;best student&quot;, &quot;just like Cao Yunjin to Guo Degang.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that he went overseas as a state-owned enterprise in 1993 and founded CITIC Real Estate Brokerage Company in Nanjing the following year (Editor’s note: public information cannot be found) and engaged in second-hand housing real estate brokerage. In 1998, he recruited Sang Chunhua, who was 20 years and 4 months old. At that time, Sang had no real estate sales experience and his monthly salary was 300 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was the World Cup in France that year. One night, Sang Chunhua was watching the game alone in the store when he met the owner Cui Wei who came to inspect the store. The two chatted for a long time while watching the game. Choi is 10 years older than Sang. After that, the two went to Qingdao and Beijing together to gradually expand the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cui Wei said that it was not until he transformed the sales agency business into a demutualized company and donated part of his shares to Sang Chunhua free of charge that Sang became a shareholder. Subsequently, the company entered the real estate development business, and he transferred the shares of the sales agency company held by Sang into the development company, and successively granted him the positions of general manager and vice chairman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the share split is regarded by Cui Wei as a huge mistake, laying the foundation for today&#39;s disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Sang Chunhua did not accept Cui Wei&#39;s statement that he was a student and an employee. He claimed that in the past 25 years, &quot;two people started a business and started from scratch.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the press conference on September 14, Sang Chunhua introduced that he started working in 1996. When he met Cui Wei in 1998, he was already the sales director of a real estate company in Nanjing, doing first-hand housing business. , and it was he who mobilized Cui Wei, who was still doing second-hand housing at the time, to enter first-hand housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Sang Chunhua, when they went north to start a business in Qingdao, the two had already determined the equity ratio of 70:30. In 2001, the Shandong team was disbanded, and he and Cui Wei came to Beijing again and registered Agile in the same year. At that time, we negotiated shares in Henderson Center and finally reached a ratio of 58:42. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The so-called gift of shares is nonsense, and not paying for it is even more of a joke.&quot; Sang Chunhua said bluntly. Zhang Yonggang provided Agile&#39;s industrial and commercial information to Southern Weekend reporters, which showed that the company&#39;s registered capital was 10 million, with Cui Wei investing 5.8 million yuan in currency and Sang Chunhua investing 4.2 million yuan in currency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yonggang told Southern Weekend reporters that in 2008, Cui Hesang established Huamei Qiaogoli and transferred the shares of Agile. The ratio of 58:42 was still maintained, which was the predecessor of Pomegranate Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the press conference on September 14, Sang Chunhua said that on September 8, he took the initiative to interview Cui Wei and proposed to end the dispute, but the other party insisted on a 30% premium from the major shareholder. &quot;We still have to grab it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Trouble with overseas structures&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The reason why Pomegranate Group has corporate governance chaos is because it involves overseas structures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sang Chunhua pointed out that Cui Wei did not agree to dismantle the overseas structure after the company failed to go public in 2021. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qichacha shows that Pomegranate Group is 100% owned by Beijing Minjiang Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Minjiang Technology). The latter’s legal representative is Cui Wei. After the equity penetration, it is owned by two Hong Kong companies. The Hong Kong company is in turn held by a company registered in the British Virgin Islands. Under this offshore structure, neither of the two major shareholders directly holds shares in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Equity lawyer Lu Qinghua once represented equity disputes similar to those of Pomegranate Group and authored the book &quot;Corporate Control&quot;. She analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters that the domestic company Pomegranate Group is 100% owned by Minjiang Technology, and Cui Wei, the legal representative of Minjiang Technology, has the right to decide the candidates for the board of directors of Pomegranate Group. In the absence of special provisions in the company&#39;s articles of association, the legal representative also has the right to manage the official seal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since August 2023, the management of Pomegranate Group has undergone a major change. After dismissing Sang Chunhua and Lin Xinwu, the company added four directors and one supervisor within one day. According to Sang Chunhua, the new directors include Cui Wei’s wife, Zhu Yanhua, who was appointed without his consent as the second shareholder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Lu Qinghua’s view, under the overseas equity structure, Sang Chunhua does not directly hold shares of Pomegranate Group. This means that even if Sang Chunhua sues Cui Wei to dismiss him without going through legal procedures, it will be more difficult to win the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Zhigang, a professor at the School of Finance at Renmin University of China who focuses on corporate governance research, holds a different view. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the ownership structure must ultimately restore the individuals who actually invested and reflect the true wishes of the investors. The appointment and removal of company directors require the approval of a majority of shareholders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, he also agreed that if litigation is involved under an overseas structure, the actual legal effect of overseas awards may face challenges, and the litigation process may be a difficult tug-of-war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Zhigang introduced that the disputes at Pomegranate Group reflected some common issues in the governance of private enterprises. Many private enterprises focus on investment in the early stages of entrepreneurship. The founders are independent of each other and are maintained by family ties, friendships, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the company becomes bigger, some companies fail to handle the problem of profit distribution through institutional methods such as equity and compensation, or do not pay attention to the formation of a standardized corporate structure by introducing external investors. Problems caused by corporate governance often As a result, it is difficult for its business to last forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by the dispute, Pomegranate Group began to face the risk of bank loan withdrawals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industrial Bank took the lead in sending a notification letter to Pomegranate Group, requiring it to deposit the remaining 74 million yuan of principal and interest repayable for this year on a 1.8 billion yuan loan into a supervisory account before August 12, 2023. Otherwise, Industrial Bank has the right to declare all loans to expire early and hold the borrower and guarantor responsible for breach of contract. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pomegranate Group’s 2022 corporate bond annual report shows that as of the end of 2022, Pomegranate Group’s total interest-bearing liabilities were 16.678 billion yuan. Among them, bank loans within one year were 375 million yuan, and trust borrowings within one year were 1.146 billion yuan. A total of three interest-bearing bonds are in existence, with a total amount of 2.916 billion yuan, all of which will mature in 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as of the end of 2022, Pomegranate Group’s monetary funds were only 2.864 billion yuan, of which 536 million yuan was a restricted amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Zhang Yonggang is a pseudonym in the article. Southern Weekend reporter Shi Xuan also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[槟榔可抗疫？清代岭南槟榔是如何传入湖南的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257184]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-21 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/e3omQSpv9dvANv9zp23MpwIIPDQCbcg8IXxCkuDt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/e3omQSpv9dvANv9zp23MpwIIPDQCbcg8 IXxCkuDt. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251274&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 26, 2017, at a betel nut processing factory in Wanning, Hainan, farmers were sorting out Just purchased betel nuts. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The custom of chewing betel nut in Lingnan area is closely related to its medicinal value. The people in Xiangtan, Hunan are addicted to betel nut, which was originally needed to treat diseases and fight epidemics. However, once a habit is formed, it cannot be stopped. Xiangtan was the main distribution center for betel nut from Lingnan to the north in the Qing Dynasty. Several major epidemics in Xiangtan from the forty-fourth year of Qianlong to the second year of Tongzhi promoted the custom of chewing betel nuts. According to industry legends, the key figure in the introduction of betel nut was Bai Jing, the magistrate of Xiangtan County. Bai Jing’s father, Bai Weixi, once served as the magistrate of Yingde County, Guangdong. This was a special opportunity for Lingnan betel nut to be introduced to Xiangtan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Removing miasma means preventing epidemics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The ancients have known the medicinal value of betel nut for a long time. Yang Fu, a native of Nanhai in the Eastern Han Dynasty, has recorded the consumption of betel nut in his &quot;Foreign Objects&quot; It can &quot;lower qi&quot; and aid digestion. Since then, there have been endless literature records about betel nut&#39;s functions of lowering qi, reducing swelling, repelling insects, repelling miasma, and treating epidemics. The article &quot;Miasma, Plague and Addiction: The Spread and Reconstruction of Betel Nut Food Customs in Local Social Changes&quot; by Zhang Enxun and Shen Lingling of Xiangtan University comprehensively sorted out the discussions on the medicinal value of betel nut in the past dynasties, and pointed out: &quot;Betel nut was the most important food in the Tang and Song Dynasties. As the central government developed tools for removing miasma in Lingnan, during the Qing Dynasty and the Republic of China, betel nut became a medicinal material for treating plague that witnessed the development of commercial networks and local social changes in modern China.&quot; Here &quot;treating plague&quot; and &quot;removing miasma&quot;, in other words It’s about epidemic prevention and control. Whether in Fujian, Guangdong or Hunan, the original legitimate reason for chewing betel nut is to prevent and cure epidemics. This does not exclude some people from eating betel nut in search of pleasure or for ceremonial needs. The three can coexist at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ancients used medicinal plants to ward off miasma and prevent epidemics. In the late Ming and early Qing dynasties, some people spread the idea that smoking can ward off miasma. Zhu Shengheng, a scholar in Xiangtan in the Qing Dynasty, wrote an article &quot;Wilder Theory&quot;: &quot;Lu Song produces wilted leaves. If you cut them and smoke them, they are said to be able to ward off miasma.&quot; People in Xiangtan call tobacco leaves &quot;wilt leaves&quot;. The article believes that Luzon cigarettes were introduced to Fujian in the early Qing Dynasty and soon became popular all over the country. However, the reason why people smoked at first was to &quot;prevent miasma&quot;. Zhu Shengheng had a profound understanding of the dangers of smoking and pointed out that &quot;the harm of wilting is related to opium&quot;. (He Gejin edited and annotated pages 504-505 of the second volume of &quot;Selected Essays of Xiangtan Dynasties&quot;) It is worth noting that both tobacco and betel nut can be addictive. Just as the Qing court called opium a &quot;foreign medicine,&quot; cigarette merchants and betel nut merchants emphasized its medicinal value in order to eliminate people&#39;s psychological barriers to addictive foods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chewing betel nut can lead to addiction and waste money, which is contrary to the Confucian values ​​​​of the Ming and Qing Dynasties. Hunan society has long advocated frugality, and mainstream literati were very repulsive to this idea. Luo Ruhuai, a well-known scholar in Xiangtan, felt that chewing betel nut was a waste of money: &quot;The Gaitan people chewed betel nut even though they chewed it when they were children. People who have heard of it say that it costs a hundred coins in its prime, but the cost of a family throughout the year is often Twenty or thirty years old, isn’t it also diān?” (Page 262 of &quot;Luo Ruhuai Collection&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Businessmen who deal in betel nuts must have high-sounding reasons to resist the criticism of the Confucian class and tempt Consumption, medical treatment and epidemic prevention are the most legitimate reasons. Before the popularization of modern medicine, people generally believed that &quot;miasma&quot; existed in southern provinces. Lingnan, Hunan, Guizhou and other places were once considered &quot;miasma areas&quot;, and infection with &quot;miasma&quot; was often fatal. So, if smoking and chewing betel nut can ward off &quot;miasma&quot;, there is no doubt about its legitimacy. After all, life-saving is the first priority. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Xiangtan epidemic in the 44th year of Qianlong&#39;s reign, Bai Jing, the county magistrate, used betel nut to treat the &quot;bulging disease&quot; among residents. This led to the formation of the custom of chewing betel nut, which has since become popular after several major epidemics. This explanation seems to be The most reasonable. The two &quot;Xiangtan County Chronicles&quot; of the Qianlong Dynasty do not mention betel nut, but the Jiaqing &quot;Xiangtan County Chronicle&quot; clearly records that &quot;betel nut and wilted leaves are a hobby&quot;, which can prove that this custom was formed between the late Qianlong Dynasty and the early Jiaqing Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jCrzhRxq7xXdSOsG8coxqKII3uojM8yiaKJ0hOlx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;833&quot; height= &quot;1189&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/jCrzhRxq7xXdSOsG8coxqKII3uojM8yiaKJ0hOlx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251273&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cao Yu&#39;s book and video of &quot;One Chew for Two Thousand Years: From Medicine to Drug, the Popular History of Betel Nut in China&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The promotion of Xiangtan Magistrate Bai Jing&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Young scholar Cao Yu&#39;s &quot;Yi Chew&quot; The book &quot;Two Thousand Years: From Medicine to Drug, the Popular History of Betel Nut in China&quot; attempts to provide a new explanation for the origin of the custom of chewing betel nut in Xiangtan, Hunan. He synthesized the research results of various parties and revealed that Xiangtan was both a rice market and a distribution center for medicinal materials. During the Tongzhi period, there were sufficient betel nut stocks and the return of the Hunan army led to an increase in consumption capacity. The overland trade of betel nut from Lingnan to the north originally had two routes: the east route (via Jiangxi) and the west route (via Hunan). The Taiping Rebellion war blocked the east route, and Xiangtan&#39;s position as a commercial center was strengthened during the Taiping Rebellion. Betel nuts from Lingnan and across the mountains to the north are first gathered in Xiangtan and then distributed throughout the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cao Yu focused his attention on the disbandment of the Hunan Army in 1864, and made the following two conclusions in the book: &quot;The habit of chewing betel nuts in the Xiangtan area is likely to be caused by these two forces-the backlog. The custom of chewing betel nuts in Xiangtan flourished from 1864 to 1880. During this period, no large-scale plague occurred in Xiangtan, so chewing betel nuts was a common practice. The legend of eating betel nut to avoid the epidemic is not a historical fact...&quot; Cao Yu chose the blank period of the epidemic recorded in Guangxu&#39;s &quot;Xiangtan County Chronicle&quot; for demonstration, but Jiaqing&#39;s &quot;Xiangtan County Chronicle&quot; records that the consumption of betel nuts in Xiangtan was very popular in the early Jiaqing period, and this account was ignored . If we must consider the role of demobilizing the Hunan Army, I think these retired soldiers just spread the custom of betel nut eating to various counties in Hunan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/RcwjQ3vjzJX6sZUqrKPfwet1YlrZrwuoxkQGBOnP.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;601&quot; height= &quot;911&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/RcwjQ3vjzJX6sZUqrKPfwet1YlrZrwuoxkQGBOnP.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251272&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Xiangtan County Chronicle&quot; records about betel nut eating customs. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Xiangtan County Chronicle&quot; compiled by Wang Kaiyun and published in the 15th year of Guangxu&#39;s reign is the basic historical material for studying the betel nut food customs in Xiangtan. Volume 9 of the book &quot;Huo Zhi&quot; states: &quot;In Guangzhou merchants, silver vermilion, sunflower fan, and betel nut are the most popular. Dozens of people are cut off every day at home, and the shop is twice as prosperous. ... If you calculate that you can earn a hundred qian a day, you should spend 5 qian a month. Six million, spending more than two million for such a year...it&#39;s a lot of money.&quot; Silver vermilion and betel nut came to Xiangtan as medicinal materials, but the addictive nature of betel nut makes it difficult for consumers to stop once they accept it. As a local literary leader, Wang Kaiyun was very disgusted with the consumption of betel nuts. In his preface to the county annals, he criticized &quot;the cost of betel nuts is equivalent to rice beams.&quot; This means that the people in Xiangtan spent almost the same amount on betel nuts as they spent on food. Because of his job, Wang Kaiyun only talked about the scale of the betel nut business in his chronicle, and was not willing to discuss the origin of betel nut consumption in Xiangtan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author believes that the custom of betel nut consumption in Xiangtan was promoted by several major epidemics in the Qing Dynasty. The key year was the forty-fourth year of Qianlong. Volume 9 of Guangxu&#39;s &quot;Xiangtan County Chronicles&quot; &quot;Five Elements Chronicles·Epidemic&quot; records &quot;the great epidemic in the forty-fourth year of Qianlong&quot;, &quot;the great epidemic in April of the sixteenth year of Daoguang&quot;, &quot;the great epidemic in the twenty-second year of Daoguang&quot; and &quot;in July of the second year of Tongzhi&quot; epidemic&quot;. The forty-fourth year of Qianlong&#39;s reign was 1779, which was a key year for the formation of betel nut eating customs in Xiangtan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Junliang, the veteran of the betel nut industry in Xiangtan, recorded this legend: There was a great epidemic in the 44th year of Qianlong&#39;s reign. Many residents suffered from bulging disease and medicine was ineffective. The county magistrate Bai Jing, who was from Guangdong, was well versed in medical theory and understood the properties of medicine. He gave the medicinal betel nuts he brought to the patients to chew. After chewing them, they all felt their abdomens felt comfortable. After chewing them several times, the swelling disappeared and the pain was relieved. After that, the original patient chewed it, and the non-patients also chewed it, and the habit gradually formed, &quot;but at that time, betel nut was regarded as a kind of medicine.&quot; (Huang Junliang: &quot;What I Know about the Betel Nut Industry in Xiangtan&quot;, &quot;Xiangtan Literary History&quot; Series 12) Huang Junliang has been an apprentice in a betel nut shop since 1926. The deeds he knows about Bai Jing belong to the common memory of the industry and cannot be ignored. It is understandable that scholars such as Zhou Daming, Zhang Enxun, Shen Lingling and others doubted the authenticity of the legend in the industry because they discovered that Bai Jing was born in Fengtian, but they did not pay attention to Bai Jing&#39;s connection with Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bai Jing, whose courtesy name is Xi Song Dynasty and whose name is Puzhai, is a bannerman of the Han army with a white flag in the sky. When he was appointed as the magistrate of Xiangtan County, he wrote an article called &quot;The Stele of Yanxi Pavilion&quot; and said: &quot;I was kind to the family and was raised in the office. At that time, Xu Yu said that your father was a wise man and had good governance...&quot; (Jiaqing&#39;s &quot;Xiangtan County Chronicle·Art&quot;) &quot;Wen&quot;) that is, Bai Jing&#39;s father served as the magistrate of Yingde County, Guangdong. According to Daoguang&#39;s &quot;Yingde County Chronicle&quot;, the county magistrate Bai Weixi from the 15th to 19th years of Qianlong&#39;s reign was a person with a white banner. Based on this, it can be roughly determined that Bai Weixi is Bai Jing&#39;s father. Most of the family members of officials lived with them. Bai Jing should have lived in Guangdong, so she was misunderstood as a &quot;Cantonese&quot;. The author believes that it was their father and son&#39;s experience in Guangdong that led Bai Jing to use the medicinal betel nut brought from Guangdong to treat the residents when the epidemic and &quot;bulging disease&quot; were prevalent in Xiangtan. Wang Kaiyun had a prejudice against Bai Jing, perhaps because of his introduction of betel nuts. In the biography of officials and teachers in &quot;Xiangtan County Chronicle&quot;, Wang Kaiyun commented that Bai Jing&#39;s governance &quot;was a little arbitrary or biased, and there are similarities and differences among the commentators so far.&quot; Wang Kaiyun wrote &quot;The pastoral order is responsible for his forgiveness&quot;, indicating that he was very dissatisfied with Bai Jing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 16th year of Daoguang (1836), the 22nd year (1842), and the second year of Tongzhi (1863), several major epidemics occurred in Xiangtan, which made the custom of betel nut popular in Xiangtan. For the Xiangtan people to form the custom of chewing betel nuts, sufficient supply was only a sufficient condition, and the occurrence of several major epidemics was a necessary condition. The key figure in the formation of the custom was the county magistrate Bai Jing. The custom of betel nut eating in Xiangtan began to take shape in the forty-fourth year of Qianlong&#39;s reign due to Bai Jing&#39;s promotion. After several major epidemics, it became more popular. The traditional medical theory of betel nut to prevent plague and prevent miasma successfully connected the two. Modern medicine has proven that chewing betel nut has the risk of causing oral cancer. As for its anti-epidemic effect, everyone has different opinions, but the ancients believed it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[博主用无人机跟踪女性被抓，高科技产品何以沦为隐私“刺客”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257244]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 23:22:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[引资、清欠、对接客户，民营经济发展局的地方经验]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257186]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/Rvy8q7luPDejmkqUB9hN86ERPv2YIOGA9TsHDna4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1123&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/Rvy8q7luPDejmkqUB9hN86ERPv2YIOGA9TsHD na4. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251276&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 4, 2023, Cong Liang, deputy director of the National Development and Reform Commission, introduced that the Central Committee The Editorial Office officially approved the establishment of the Private Economic Development Bureau within the National Development and Reform Commission. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Once the Private Economic Development Bureau was established, it attracted the attention of the whole society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 4, 2023, Cong Liang, deputy director of the National Development and Reform Commission, introduced that the Central Organization Office officially approved the establishment of a Private Economic Development Bureau within the National Development and Reform Commission. It is a specialized agency to promote the development and growth of the private economy. Its role is to strengthen the overall coordination of policies in related fields and promote the implementation of various major measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cong Liang introduced that the main responsibility of the bureau is to formulate policies to promote private economic development and establish a communication mechanism with private enterprises. In the more than 100-word description of responsibilities, there is no word related to &quot;management&quot;, but &quot;service&quot; is the main word. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first time a private economic development bureau has been established at the national ministry level, but it is no stranger to it at the local level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters searched Qichacha and local government official websites and found that at the peak of the country, there were more than 200 related agencies such as private economic development bureaus, private economic development promotion bureaus, and private economic development service bureaus. Now, There are still more than 180 private economic development bureaus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They belong to different departments in different places. For example, the local industry and information technology departments will have small and medium-sized enterprise development agencies, and the market supervision department will also have internal agencies to promote the private economy. The human resources and social security, taxation, judicial, and financial supervision departments will also have corresponding service offices as needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The starting point was around 2000. At that time, some provinces, cities, districts and counties began to set up departments related to private economic development, and added the brands of Township Enterprise Administration or Small and Medium Enterprises Bureau, and then the names would be many times. change. After 2019, local small and medium-sized enterprise bureaus were abolished under institutional reform and adjustment, and have now become subordinate offices of local industry and information bureaus, economic and information bureaus or market supervision bureaus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the relevant institutions add a brand to the existing institutions, that is, one team and two brands. Only a few areas have set up a separate &quot;Private Economic Development Bureau&quot; as a municipal government agency. Government departments, such as Qingdao, Ya&#39;an, Jinan, Chongqing Beibei District, Chongqing Jiulongpo District, etc., are generally established after 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What kind of exploration experience and inspiration can these local experiences provide to national departments? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Private bureaus have long existed in many places&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As early as around 2000, some provincial governments already had agencies responsible for the private economy, named Township Enterprise Administration Bureau, Private Economic Administration Bureau, Small and Medium Enterprises Bureau, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After several institutional reforms, their figures have been blurred. Now, their development can only be seen through public documents such as cadre resumes, budget and final accounts of the year, unit profiles, and function introductions on the government’s official website. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the resume of a cadre from the Industry and Information Technology Bureau of Yucheng City, Dezhou City, Shandong Province stated that he worked for the Private Economic Development Bureau of Yucheng City from 1997 to 2013. After that, the company he worked for was changed to the Economic and Information Technology Bureau of Yucheng City. Bureau of Industry and Information Technology, and will become Yucheng City Industry and Information Technology Bureau after 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For another example, the Shanxi Luliang Lishi District Small and Medium Enterprises Service Center details its development history in the official website introduction. Its predecessor was the Lishi County Community and Team Enterprise Management Bureau in 1976, and was changed to the Lishi County Community and Team Enterprise Management Bureau in 1984. The Lishi County Township Enterprise Administration Bureau established the Lishi Township Enterprise Service Center after the organizational reform in 2002, and was listed as the Lishi Private Economic Development Bureau. This agency began to be responsible for the supervision, guidance, coordination and services of small and medium-sized enterprises, township enterprises and the private economy in the region. In August 2004, it was renamed &quot;Lishi District Small and Medium Enterprises Bureau&quot; again, retaining the brand of &quot;Lishi District Private Economic Development Bureau&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the book &quot;Shanxi Economy: Forty Years of Reform and Opening Up&quot;, in 2003, Shanxi Province adjusted its organizational structure and transitioned the provincial-level Township Enterprise Administration Bureau to the Private Economic Development Bureau. The following year, it added It has the sign of Shanxi Provincial Small and Medium Enterprises Bureau. Since then, 11 prefecture-level cities and 119 counties and cities in Shanxi Province have established small and medium-sized enterprise bureaus, and their functions have been expanded from the original township enterprises to county economies, private economies, and small and medium-sized enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng, director of the Office of Private Economic Development Bureau of Qingdao, Shandong Province, told Southern Weekend reporters that before and after the institutional reform in 2019, small and medium-sized enterprise bureaus across the country were withdrawn and merged, and the functions of the original small and medium-sized enterprise bureaus were merged into the local industry and information bureaus and economic bureaus. The Information Bureau and the Market Supervision Bureau will add the Small and Medium Enterprises Bureau brand to these departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the Industry and Information Technology Bureaus of Taiyuan City, Shuozhou City, Luliang City, Yangquan City, Yuncheng City and other places in Shanxi Province have added the name of Private Economic Development Promotion Bureau, and the districts and counties under their jurisdiction have also The Ministry of Industry and Information Technology has added the name of the Private Economic Development Promotion Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wenzhou has added the name of the Private Economic Health Development Promotion Bureau to the Municipal Economic and Information Technology Bureau. Guang&#39;an, Zigong and Ziyang in Sichuan Province have also registered private economic development bureaus in the Economic and Information Bureau, while Neijiang, Aba and Liangshan prefectures have registered private economic development bureaus in the Market Supervision Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over the past two decades, the emergence of private economic development bureaus in local government agencies has roughly coincided with the peak of the central government’s policies to encourage the development of the private economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, the &quot;36 Non-Public Economy Articles&quot; was the first central document to promote the development of the non-public economy since the founding of New China. In 2019, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Creating a Better Development Environment to Support the Reform and Development of Private Enterprises&quot; to support the private economy in many aspects. In 2023, the &quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Promoting the Development and Growth of the Private Economy&quot; was publicly released, proposing 31 policies and measures to encourage and promote private enterprises to become better, bigger and stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Need a comprehensive coordination department&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Li Xiaofeng worked in the Private Economic Development Division of the Enterprise Registration Bureau under the Qingdao Municipal Administration for Industry and Commerce, doing comprehensive coordination for private enterprises The work includes formulating the key points of the national private economy work and gathering relevant data on private market entities that were originally scattered in various departments. &quot;It is better to do macro-level work and understand the overall situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scope of the work of the Industrial and Commercial Bureau on the private economy is limited to this. Although other departments also have work related to the private economy, they are all in Fulfill responsibilities within their respective scope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, the Qingdao Municipal Government carried out institutional reforms. Under the condition of a limit of 38 working departments, the Private Economic Development Bureau and the Ocean Bureau were added to the reform plan. These two bureaus became components of the municipal government. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Li Xiaofeng was transferred to the Private Economic Development Bureau and served successively as the director of the Coordination and Guidance Division and the director of the office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He explained to Southern Weekend reporters that in the past, although different units had departments serving the private economy, their focus was different due to functional limitations. For example, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology pays more attention to industrial enterprises and their industries, while departments such as science and technology and commerce focus on high-tech, consumer enterprises and their industry development. A full-time department must be established to cover all aspects of private economic development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the original agency, Li Xiaofeng found that the private economic development bureau, a dedicated department, can play a better coordination role. &quot;We are now doing comprehensive coordination, platform building and other service work, not industry authorities.&quot; , closer to the role of the integrated department.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The advantage of this role is that it facilitates coordination between various departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Private economic work covers a wide range of areas and is highly policy-oriented, requiring close collaboration among various departments to form a synergy.” Zhang Shixin, deputy secretary-general of the National Development and Reform Commission and director of the Personnel Department, also made a similar statement in an interview. The National Development and Reform Commission established the Private Economic Development Bureau in order to better play the role of overall coordination, comprehensive policy implementation, and promotion of development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Li Xiaofeng believes that at the national level, the Private Economic Development Bureau is an internal agency of the National Development and Reform Commission. There is no need to dissolve and merge relevant departments that have been established separately but are not placed in the National Development and Reform Commission. &quot;Serving private enterprises inherently involves coordination and cooperation among multiple departments, and there will be no overlapping or conflicting functions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Now Qingdao&#39;s private economy does not support half the sky, but is the main force.&quot; Li Xiaofeng told the South Weekend reporter, Qingdao’s private investment can still maintain double-digit growth from 2019 to 2020. From January to July 2023, Qingdao&#39;s private investment grew by 6.1%, 6.6 percentage points higher than the national average. Private investment projects under construction drove investment by 3.6 percentage points and contributed 77.3% to the city&#39;s investment growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Office of Jinan Private Economic Development Bureau wrote a reply to Southern Weekend reporter: The bureau was established in March 2019. In the first half of 2019, the number of private market entities in Jinan was 993,300, and currently it is 1.505 million, accounting for 98.6% of the city’s market entities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Serving private enterprises that meet industrial needs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first step in providing good services is to let private enterprises and local private bureaus understand each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the Qingdao Private Enterprise Bureau understands the situation of private enterprises through streets, districts and cities, and has set up 300 enterprise policy service specialists composed of government personnel and enterprise service agencies. On the other hand, it sets up a system for private enterprises through gradient cultivation and management. Different growth tracks, discover small and medium-sized enterprises with development potential. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingdao Yunlu Co., Ltd. (688190.SH) project leader Geng Runer told Southern Weekend reporters that receiving the honorary title from the government is an affirmation of the company and provides a measurement standard for investment institutions and financial institutions to judge the value of the company. , which helps corporate financing to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yunlu Co., Ltd. is engaged in the design, development and sales of advanced magnetic metal materials. It is a mixed-ownership enterprise with shares held by central enterprises. Geng Runer is mainly responsible for project declaration and other work. She said the company has become a unicorn with support from the local government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Qingdao’s 2023 public list of innovative small and medium-sized enterprises, most of the awarded companies are high-tech and other new manufacturing industries, with occasionally one or two companies related to the food and clothing industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of a Qingdao garment factory told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;We may have contacted the private bureau, but we don&#39;t know much about it.&quot; The main dilemma faced by enterprises at present is the high labor cost. Many garment factories in the industry have moved to Southeast Asia, India and other places with lower labor costs. Her company mainly undertakes OEM foreign trade orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many people would rather earn a salary of 3,000 yuan in an urban office than work in a factory. (The salary) is over 6,000 yuan and no one comes,” she said. She is now also seeking transformation for the company, no longer following the OEM model, and trying to operate her own brand through the Internet platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng said that every local government has its own industries that it focuses on developing. Qingdao has 24 key industrial chains, which are consistent with Qingdao’s urban industrial planning and development needs. Textile and clothing is an advantageous industrial chain among the 24 industrial chains. For example, Qingdao Kute Intelligent Enterprise has found a transformation path in personalized intelligent customization of clothing. &quot;It still depends on whether the enterprise&#39;s model and core competitiveness can adapt to the development and changes of the social situation, so as to effectively respond to the market-oriented survival of the fittest.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Jinan, the main practices of the private bureau include establishing private economic monitoring and analysis services The system monitors and analyzes comprehensive indicators such as operating income, profits and taxes, and R&amp;D investment, and dynamically grasps the development of private enterprises. The bureau also requested the municipal government to issue &quot;Several Measures on Carrying out Climbing Actions to Support the Leapfrog Development of Private Enterprises&quot;, clearly implement 21 cultivation measures in 5 major actions including financing promotion, and carry out a 5-year targeted cultivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of a cryptographic company located in Jinan said that the relevant departments of the Jinan Municipal Government have helped them solve issues such as office space property rights and matching financing needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of another biopharmaceutical company located in Jinan told Southern Weekend reporters that they are a leading company in the local area. Jinan’s business environment has developed greatly in recent years, and the city has set up dedicated services for leading companies. &quot;After all, large companies are large and make great contributions.&quot; He affirmed the work of the government, but also said that it is difficult to address all aspects of enterprise personalized issues and provide adequate services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, Jinan’s four leading industries are big data and new generation information technology industry, intelligent manufacturing and high-end equipment industry, biomedicine and comprehensive health industry, and high-quality steel and advanced materials industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;When do businesses need the government? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Due to his work, Li Xiaofeng often comes into contact with private enterprises of various sizes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, in the past when enterprises dealt with the government, they hoped that the government would not disturb them. However, in critical periods such as the early stages of enterprise development and bottleneck periods, the government also needs to provide resource support. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Geng Runer once represented the company in a creative meeting organized by the Private Economic Development Bureau, and the company put forward development demands with creative solutions. The plan jointly submitted by Yunlu Co., Ltd. and downstream companies is amorphous high-efficiency energy-saving transformers. The main customers are local power supply bureaus and urban rail transit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A creative meeting will invite 3-5 companies to share their proposals. In addition to business representatives, there were also government staff, project reviewers and invited customer representatives present. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recommending products to state-owned enterprise users on government platforms is undoubtedly a shortcut to quickly open up customer sources and build trust between both parties. Two months after the creative meeting, Yunlu Co., Ltd. successfully participated in the communication and promotion meeting for the follow-up project implementation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng told Southern Weekend reporters that companies of all sizes participating in the creative meeting will be selected in the early stage. The ideas proposed by the companies will be selected. The selected ideas will be fully demonstrated by experts from the private sector bureau and relevant government departments, and they are in line with Qingdao’s industry. Projects in the development direction can enter subsequent promotion meetings, and coordinate various relevant departments to resolve the resources needed for project and industrial development, such as land, talents, funds, etc., which are generally concerned by enterprises. Since 2019, more than ten events have been held, attracting an investment amount of approximately 40 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Geng Runer said that because they are in a &quot;stuck&quot; industry such as key materials technology, there is an urgent need for talents. The Private Sector Bureau and the Human Resources and Social Security Bureau helped the company introduce a Japanese expert and solved the problem for the expert. Talent green card issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of funding, Li Xiaofeng introduced that in addition to certain rewards and subsidies for some companies after listing, the Financing Cooperation Office of the Private Sector Bureau will also organize matchmaking activities such as &quot;Government, Bank and Enterprise&quot; to guide private companies in need to connect with finance. Institutions, companies raise financial needs, and financial institutions promote products. &quot;Compared with the company going door to door to find banking institutions, he can contact eight to ten financial institutions once he participates in the matching event.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jinan Private Economic Development Bureau also mentioned in its written reply that they established The Cultivation Database of Ten Thousand Potential Enterprises, the Cultivation Database of Thousands of Key Enterprises and the Database of Hundreds of Investment Institutions have connected local private enterprises to obtain 280 rounds of fund investment. At the same time, it also promotes the connection between corporate financing needs and banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Sheng is the head of a company that provides service products to government departments. His company has conducted business in many places across the country and mainly obtained government procurement projects through bidding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, most private enterprises that provide service products to the government will inevitably encounter the problem of &quot;difficulty in collecting accounts&quot;. It often happens that the accounts are delayed, and some private enterprises will also Encountered a situation where &quot;new officials ignore old accounts&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, the National Development and Reform Commission and other departments issued 28 specific measures to promote the solution of outstanding problems faced in the development of the private economy, including increasing efforts to clean up the accounts owed to private enterprises, focusing on cleaning up Accounts owed to small, medium and micro enterprises by government agencies, institutions, and state-owned enterprises, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng introduced that the Qingdao Private Sector Bureau has been paying attention to this problem since its early establishment and began to clear arrears for small and medium-sized enterprises in 2019. As long as the enterprise raises the issue, the private sector bureau will take the lead in issuing supervision orders to government departments that are confirmed to have delinquent accounts after investigation, urging them to pay off the delinquent accounts owed to small and medium-sized enterprises in installments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中梁盛为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[室同道合？一份包含MBTI的大学宿舍分配问卷背后]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257236]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/WMQEIGA7Wvi4EPEkbHyFT4Z5APMlsNC8bZMa7Kli.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;853&quot; height=&quot;753&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/WMQEIGA7Wvi4EPEkbHyFT4Z5APMlsNC8bZMa7Kli. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251432&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Nongjian/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is still one week before the start of the semester. On the evening of August 10, 2023, 115 undergraduate freshmen in the class of 2023 at the Zhiyi Academy of Beijing Institute of Technology received a questionnaire, including MBTI, favorite &quot; &quot;Idol&quot; (idol, refers to idol artists), as well as work and rest habits. This questionnaire is prepared for freshman dormitory assignment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before dawn the next day, the dormitory list was released. The person who was commissioned to design the questionnaire was their senior sister, Lu Jiahui, a 2022 student of Zhiyi Academy. Her original intention in designing the questionnaire was to bring people in the same circle together based on the results of the questionnaire, &quot;so that they can spend their four years in college more happily.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lv Jiahui’s own dormitory experience was somewhat regretful. The roommates had different hobbies and “basically had nothing to talk about.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, this questionnaire was posted on social media, and the topic &quot;BIT Dormitory Allocation Statistics MBTI&quot; became a hot search topic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, dormitory allocation in colleges and universities was often done randomly. Nowadays, more and more colleges and universities are exploring other methods, and MBTI is just the latest one. Nanjing University and Chengdu University use questionnaires to collect information about freshmen, and then assign or recommend roommates to them through algorithms; while some schools such as Communication University of China and Zhuhai Institute of Science and Technology (formerly Jilin University Zhuhai College) give students the right to choose. Spontaneously organize and publish &quot;resumes&quot; written with their living habits, personality and hobbies to find suitable roommates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The seemingly various allocation methods are more or less designed to avoid possible conflicts in university dormitories. Wang Qing, a lecturer at the School of Humanities at Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics, has studied the relationship between university dormitories. She believes that &quot;if these factors are taken into account when arranging dormitories, conflicts will be reduced to a certain extent.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the dormitory conflicts There is another deeper social and cultural change of youth. Wang Qing also agreed: dormitory allocation can only solve part of the contradiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;BIT Dormitory Allocation Statistics&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;MBTI&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The most concerning question in this dormitory allocation questionnaire is: MBTI is one of the most popular personality tests today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;MBTI is the abbreviation of Myers-Briggs Type Indicator. The test result consists of 4 letters and refers to a person’s attention direction, cognitive style, judgment style and lifestyle. Dimensional tendencies. The framers were an American mother and daughter named Briggs and Myers respectively. In the eyes of this mother and daughter who had no professional background in psychology, they could use four rulers to classify complex human nature into 16 species. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The MBTI test has been widely used in company recruitment and team building, but its scientific validity has also been questioned. Some studies have found that more than half of people retest after a few weeks or more than a year. , will get different results, so there are flaws in its consistency, stability and reliability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Jiahui, who allocates dormitories to 115 freshmen, is a &quot;peer mentor&quot;, that is, a senior who answers questions in the freshmen group. She believes in the accuracy of the MBTI. Her MBTI type is &quot;entj&quot;, which is called a commander personality. This type of person tends to make quick decisions and has strong action ability. It only took her an hour and a half to complete the questionnaire design, and sent it out at 7:30 pm on the 10th. At 4:30 am on the 11th, the dormitory allocation results for the entire grade were sent to the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The questionnaire was quickly posted online. On August 12, Lu Jiahui discovered that the entry &quot;BIT dormitory allocation statistics MBTI&quot; had been on the hot search list for nearly ten hours, ranking highest at second place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to MBTI, the questionnaire also discussed whether snoring, talking in sleep, getting up at night, chasing stars, &quot;two-spined salamander&quot; (two-dimensional), etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The questionnaire also attracted attention within BIT. “My counselor’s phone number was blown up by counselors from other colleges.” Then, the questionnaire became popular in the school. Someone left a screenshot of the same questionnaire on Lu Jiahui’s social media: “The College of Economics and Management also has it! ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This trend has spread to more colleges and universities. On August 29, a student at the School of Intelligent Accounting and Management of Guangdong University of Finance and Economics discovered that the questionnaire collected by her college for dormitory allocation only included MBTI types, and the final allocation results were mainly based on &quot;i people&quot; (introverts) and &quot;e people&quot; ” (extrovert) distinction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ru Jingfei, a counselor at the School of Law of Southwest University of Political Science and Law, looks for inspiration in her own employment guidance and mental health classes. In addition to the MBTI, the questionnaire she designed also included &quot;questions that are likely to cause conflicts in dormitory life&quot; collected from graduates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, many colleges and universities have begun to reject the past &quot;blind box&quot; method, which is a randomly assigned dormitory allocation plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, dormitory allocation mainly considered students with the same major, class, and adjacent student numbers to be grouped together. The ordering of student numbers usually referred to the pinyin and strokes of the surname. There are also schools that arrange dormitories according to the order of registration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Chengdu University asked freshmen to fill out a questionnaire including questions such as &quot;Are you a social cow or a social fear&quot; and &quot;Do you accept durian, snail noodles and other odorous foods&quot; to match freshmen with roommates. In the same year, according to the official account of Lanzhou University, in order to &quot;allow students to choose like-minded roommates,&quot; some colleges introduced a method of allocating dormitories by selecting roommates from each other, and students posted self-introductions in the group like &quot;writing a resume.&quot; and expectations for roommates, making a two-way choice. When the 2023 freshmen of the University of Electronic Science and Technology of China choose their own rooms online, they can check the waking up and sleeping habits of the selected roommates in a certain room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/zO1vXlylqmdxb8XSjKWbv3lP67K8DLqIsXTODMm5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;988&quot; height= &quot;659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/zO1vXlylqmdxb8XSjKWbv3lP67K8DLqIsXTODMm5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 16, 2023, the seniors guided the 2023 freshmen to go through the registration procedures at Huzhou College in Zhejiang Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Yes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;iYes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;e A&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;more interesting&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Controversy also ensued: whether the roommates assigned through MBTI are reliable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Lu Jiahui’s conception, MBTI is not the most important. Her priority was an open-ended fill-in-the-blank question about &quot;other needs&quot; in the questionnaire, and then the order of consideration was: personal work and rest habits, interests and hobbies, and then MBTI. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the open-ended fill-in-the-blank question, some people followed the prompts and filled in who they wanted to live with. If both parties were willing, they would be placed together; some people filled in &quot;I don&#39;t want to be in the same dormitory with star chasers.&quot; &quot;. Through the collected questionnaire answers, Lu Jiahui could not judge who could accept these unexpected demands, but she set a self-evaluation question about &quot;tolerance&quot;, with a full score of 5 points - people with high self-evaluation scores were considered There is a greater chance of accepting the individual needs of roommates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the dormitory allocation of the School of Intelligent Accounting and Management of Guangdong University of Finance and Economics, a freshman observed that the configuration is roughly &quot;two i and two e&quot; in one dormitory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ru Jingfei did not directly judge which personalities are suitable. She reminded students to consider whether they need roommates with complementary or similar personalities. She also suggested that &quot;Having I&#39;s and E&#39;s will make dormitory life more interesting.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different allocation methods are related to different needs. Even on the indicator of student origin, different people have different considerations. Southwest Political Science and Law is located in Chongqing. Ru Jingfei does not recommend that everyone in a dormitory come from the same place, and believes that &quot;it is best to have someone from Sichuan and Chongqing in a dormitory, so that it will be much more convenient when going out to play.&quot; What Lu Jiahui is most afraid of is the difference in eating habits between the north and the south. &quot;It&#39;s very uncomfortable if you can&#39;t eat one piece.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lanzhou University advocates &quot;multicultural integration&quot;. One college stipulates that &quot;each dormitory has students from the south and the north&quot; and &quot;no less than 3 provinces of origin.&quot; &quot;Diversity&quot; also has another meaning. In 2022, in order to avoid collective late arrival at &quot;eight in the morning&quot;, the school&#39;s law school assigned a classmate who is accustomed to getting up early to each dormitory to serve as the &quot;dawn rooster&quot; of each dormitory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plans vary, but what most designers care about is whether roommates can chat with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Behind closed doors, the dormitory is just a circle.” A significant comparison is that the college dormitories of Lu Jiahui’s good friends are all “two-dimensional” and they can play well; and her own roommate , there are those who pursue Korean entertainment, and there are those who like racing, &quot;basically there is nothing to talk about.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nanjing University has set up a questionnaire since 2017, which not only counts interests and hobbies, but also uses algorithms to find potential correlations between different hobbies. Guo Yamin, a teacher at the student affairs office of the school, once introduced to the media that the interests and hobbies of the &quot;post-00s generation&quot; are wide and highly dispersed. The school&#39;s &quot;hidden semantic model&quot; algorithm can use some implicit characteristics to deduce the students&#39; possible hobbies from their existing hobbies. Match roommates based on your interests, such as putting those who like drama with those who like history, or those who like biology with those who like physics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, Nanjing University’s questionnaire is adjusted every year. Guo Yamin explained to Southern Weekend reporters, “The concerns of each generation of children are different.” In the 2023 questionnaire, freshmen were asked whether they prefer the AA system (everyone shares the expenses equally) or taking turns to treat guests when going out with their roommates, and whether they can accept invitations from their roommates to go out with friends on weekends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Yamin said, &quot;Nowadays, children have lived alone since childhood. When they suddenly enter collective life, there are always a lot of discomforts.&quot; The school&#39;s approach is to try to reduce the &quot;discomforts&quot;, Don&#39;t group people who are too different together. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A dormitory relationship intervention experiment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Qing, a lecturer at the School of Humanities at Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics, once tried to find a set of methods for running-in university dormitory relationships through his own experiments. Methodology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qing has served as the head teacher for five years since 2016, and has actively or passively intervened in many dormitory conflicts. Some students asked her for help privately: They had a bad relationship with someone in the dormitory, which caused a lot of trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before 2023, Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics will allocate dormitories randomly within classes. In 2020, Wang Qing decided to select a part of the dormitory and artificially interfere with the direction of dormitory relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, considering that there were many female students in the College of Humanities, Wang Qing decided to start with the female college dormitories. She selected 38 freshmen girls from four classes, and organized a group activity of &quot;making love together&quot; once a month after enrolling in the dormitory, a total of three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, it was discovered that the conflicts in the boys’ dormitories were more serious, but they were not good at asking for help. Wang Qing learned from research that the physical conflict rate in boys&#39; dormitories is higher, and the degree of intimacy and integration and satisfaction with interpersonal relationships in the dormitories are also lower than those in girls&#39; dormitories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The theme of the activity is related to the mechanism of dormitory relations. Wang Qing analyzed that dormitories are spaces where public and private attributes are mixed, where individuals eat and sleep, but where strangers live together. In such a space, students need to learn how to grasp the scale - what is the place where individuals can play, and where is the place where others should be respected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The theme of the first event is public order. Wang Qing simulated a scene: At 11 o&#39;clock in the evening, you are very tired and want to sleep, so you close your eyes. Your roommate is anxiously catching up on homework and typing on the computer. Wang Qing hopes that through empathy, the dormitory group can form the first agreement: strictly abide by the work and rest system and not interfere with others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this end, she developed a 27-page intervention manual, which planned the process of each activity and mentioned common dormitory crises such as &quot;small groups&quot;. She tried to guide students to think about how to solve these situations when they happened in their dormitories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the three activities, the students’ feedback achieved the results she expected. They underwent two tests to compare the development of the quality of interpersonal relationships in the dormitory before and after the event. The survey included tense situations such as cold wars and verbal conflicts, as well as collective activities and emotional exchanges within the dormitory. The students were also asked what they thought about the situation. How satisfied are you with the dormitory relationship, and whether you want to apply for a dormitory change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another 36 female college students who had not participated in the activities also accepted this test. Comparing the two, Wang Qing concluded that appropriate communication intervention can indeed eliminate interpersonal conflicts and alienation in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 2020, Wang Qing will no longer serve as the head teacher. Ru Jingfei, who has been a counselor for seven years and has tutored more than 1,200 students, has discovered that there are more and more dormitory conflicts among college students, and they tend to break out in lower grades. She was once called to the student dormitory in the middle of the night to deal with a fight. &quot;If you can, just mediate. If it doesn&#39;t work, you have to change (dormitory).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qing introduced that at present, China’s intervention against conflicts in college student dormitories generally focuses on post-event repair and remediation. From the perspective of school management, some dormitories with poor relations can be regularly selected for intervention. However, Wang Qing also knows very well that as time goes by, the effect of the original intervention will become weaker and weaker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One reason is that the concepts, psychology and behavioral logic of the new generation of students are changing. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Lying talk sessions have become a legend&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In today’s school administrators’ vision, intervention in dormitory allocation can avoid some foreseeable conflicts earlier. . A survey of 3,875 college students across the country by Shanghai Ocean University showed that the main reasons why students are dissatisfied with dormitory relationships are work and rest habits, personal hygiene, introversion/extroversion personality, and whether to play games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, intervening in dormitory allocation is not a one-time solution. Ru Jingfei believes that even if the allocation method has been optimized, it can only solve superficial conflicts such as work and rest. She and other counselors often discuss that students’ self-awareness has become stronger and they are exposed to more information, which has brought about changes in dormitory relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When chatting with Wang Qing, a counselor said that students born in the 1970s and 1980s would think that roommates may be very important partners in life. They have a great influence not only during the study period, but also after graduation. Later, it can also become a boost for emotional and career growth. But now, many children have very clear goals after entering college: enrolling in graduate school, going abroad... From the beginning of their freshman year, they will arrange their lives according to their goals, and will not participate in group activities such as dinner parties. The dormitory may just be their own resting place. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digitalization is also exacerbating this individual loneliness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Wang Qing went to college about 20 years ago, mobile phones were only used for making calls and sending text messages. A very important dormitory activity at that time was sleeping in bed after lights out. “Nowadays, many children actually don’t have beds. Talk, everyone is very busy, mobile phones can meet many needs, and the connection, intimacy and integration between people will be reduced a lot.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Psychology Center of Beijing University of Chemical Technology reported in 2019 The school conducted a survey among 400 students. More than 80% of the students believed that the relationship in the dormitory was harmonious, but nearly half admitted that there were frictions in getting along. When asked to describe the relationship in the dormitory in one sentence, 40% chose &quot;like family&quot;, while more people chose &quot;ordinary friends&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qing, who is no longer the head teacher, is still worried about the situation of the students. &quot;(dormitory conflicts) occur every year, so I think this is not an accidental problem. A large part of the group will have such problems during their studies.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Jiahui is also not sure about the effect of dormitory allocation. She plans to verify the effect of dormitory allocation in mid-September and conduct an offline or online anonymous survey on freshmen who are willing to be interviewed to ask them how they get along with their roommates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some more acute problems cannot be avoided by dormitory allocation. Wang Qing gave an example. For example, if two people in the dormitory happen to be two candidates for the scholarship, they may have potential conflicts of interest. In addition, professional views, conduct, etc. may also cause conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Qing wrote the 2020 experiment in the article &quot;Analysis of the Intervention Effect of Intervention on Interpersonal Relationships in Female College Students&#39; Dormitories&quot;. In the article, she concluded: The quality of interpersonal relationships in college students&#39; dormitories is the highest at the beginning of getting along, and will be followed later. progressively worse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What a student said to Wang Qing left a deep impression on her: &quot;My roommate is not my friend, we just live together.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 22:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[发明了火药的中国，为何明清时火器技术落后了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257188]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Gunpowder is one of the four great inventions in ancient China, but there are also some controversies surrounding gunpowder. For example, Lu Xun said &quot;Foreign countries use Gunpowder is used to make bullets to defend enemies, but China uses it to make firecrackers to worship gods.&quot; Another example is that in recent years, some people on the Internet have claimed that yellow gunpowder invented by Europeans in the 19th century is the real gunpowder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These two statements are debatable. After China discovered gunpowder, it was used to make various firearms for use on the battlefield. The world moved from the Middle Ages to modern times, and the entire process relied on black gunpowder. Yellow gunpowder greatly accelerated this process in the late modern period, but the significance of black gunpowder cannot be ignored, and without black gunpowder as the basis, Europeans would not have been able to invent yellow gunpowder. gunpowder. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The huge potential of Chinese firearms&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Gunpowder first appeared in Taoist priests&#39; alchemy furnaces and was used as medicine. Ancient medicine believed that saltpeter can cure internal heat and stomach bloating, and sulfur can &quot;convert gold, silver, copper and iron&quot;. The two together are a kind of medicine for treating diseases, so they are called gunpowder. &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; believes that &quot;gunpowder can expel insects and ward off evil spirits.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Synopsis of the True Yuan Miao Dao&quot;, written in the mid-Tang Dynasty, records the power of the earliest gunpowder. Burning saltpeter, sulfur, realgar and honey together can cause deflagration and quickly burn the house clean. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the invention of gunpowder, it was quickly used on the battlefield. Some people used &quot;flying fire&quot; in the melee between warlords in the late Tang Dynasty. The &quot;Wu Jing Zong Yao&quot; of the Northern Song Dynasty recorded the formula of gunpowder at that time. The saltpeter content used in the explosion was very low, but the content of various combustion accelerants such as oil, rosin, and asphalt was very high. This shows the role of gunpowder in war at this time. It was an incendiary bomb rather than a bomb or bullet. In addition, the gunpowder at this time was sometimes added with arsenic to burn it and poison the enemy. It can be said to be the earliest chemical weapon in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Throughout the Tang Dynasty and Northern Song Dynasty, Chinese gunpowder was often used to make incendiary weapons, such as gunpowder arrows, fire caltrops, fire poles, poison smoke balls, and artillery (cannon stones coated with gunpowder and thrown by catapults) etc., are all incendiary firearms. Among them, the gunpowder arrow developed by Feng Jisheng in the early Song Dynasty used the recoil of burning gunpowder to push the arrow. It can be said to be the prototype of today&#39;s rocket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in terms of technical content and effectiveness, these firearms did not surpass those of their contemporaries in Europe. In 678 AD, when the Eastern Roman Empire faced a siege of 200,000 troops from the Arab Empire, it used copper pipes to spray &quot;Greek fire&quot; to burn enemy ships and annihilate the huge Arab navy. The formula of &quot;Greek Fire&quot; has been lost, but it should be a petroleum-based compound that can burn on the water surface and is extremely powerful when combined with mechanical spray. &quot;Greek Fire&quot; has long since become a secret weapon guarding the sea of ​​Constantinople. Many powerful enemies were defeated by &quot;Greek Fire&quot; and were helpless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the era of confrontation between the Song and Jin Dynasties, due to frequent wars between the Song and Jin Dynasties, both sides invented new firearms to assist in combat, and Chinese firearms achieved great development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song general Chen Gui invented the musket. Although its function was closer to a flamethrower than a firearm at this time, the design of the tubular bamboo tube prepared the conditions for the firearm; Song general Wei Sheng invented the &quot;Ruyi Zhan&quot; for installing muskets. &quot;Car&quot;, pulled by animal power. In the Southern Song Dynasty, all warships were equipped with trebuchets that threw artillery (incendiary bombs). When Wanyan Liang invaded the Song Dynasty, the Song general Li Bao led the navy to surprise the Jin army&#39;s naval base Chenjia Island, using rockets, artillery, etc. to burn Firearms completely annihilated the huge Jin Army naval division. It can be said that China&#39;s water warfare weapons have reached the level of &quot;Greek fire&quot; at this time. The Southern Song Dynasty gunboats can be regarded as the earliest gunboats in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jin people invented the world&#39;s earliest artillery - iron artillery for sieges; flying muskets that burned better than bamboo pole muskets, which can be called individual flamethrowers; and iron cans for storing gunpowder. The sky-shattering thunder made was ignited and thrown out. The sound was scary, and the exploded iron can fragments spattered damage to the surroundings. It can be said to be the earliest bomb in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Song-Mongolian War, the Song Dynasty invented the earliest firearm - the bamboo musket, which fired bullets to kill the enemy as far as 150 steps. In the Yuan Dynasty, the musket was Bamboo was changed to metal, and metal fire guns were created. By the end of the Yuan Dynasty, they had become popular in the military. However, until the early Yuan Dynasty, China&#39;s firearms were still mainly incendiary firearms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the Southern Song Dynasty to the Yuan Dynasty, Chinese firearms basically cover all categories of thermal weapons still in use until modern times. However, the Islamic world quickly learned various categories of Chinese firearms, and was even better in research and development. After being introduced to Europe, European firearms developed rapidly, leaving the rest of the world far behind. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Middle East and Europe came from behind&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Song Dynasty was the golden age of trade and cultural exchanges between China and the Islamic world. Many Arabs, Persians, and Central Asians settled in China and were even employed by the Song Dynasty. army, who quickly spread their knowledge of gunpowder and firearms back to Arabia. In addition, the Mongolians widely used firearms against the Islamic world during their Western Expeditions, which also promoted their learning of firearms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1240, the botanist Ibn Beytar of Al-Andalus (now southern Spain) introduced Chinese saltpeter in his book &quot;Medical Prescriptions&quot; and called it &quot;Chinese snow salt&quot;. &quot;Fire and saltpeter&quot; introduced its deflagration properties. In 1256, Kublai Khan&#39;s brother Hulagu established the Ilkhanate in Persia. Hassan Rahman, a Syrian who served in the Ilkhanate, wrote a military book &quot;Equestrianism and War Strategies&quot;, which introduced China in detail. Firearms, gunpowder formulas and saltpeter purification technologies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;West Asia and North Africa were originally rich in sulfur, but they did not know the use of nitrate, so they failed to invent gunpowder. Once they knew how to synthesize gunpowder, firearms developed rapidly in the Islamic world. The Mamluk dynasty that ruled Egypt created a new type of firearm &quot;Madafa&quot; based on the musket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Motor Method&quot; replaced the Chinese bamboo gun barrel with a larger wooden barrel, and replaced the Chinese projectiles with stone balls. In fact, it transformed the musket into the prototype of modern artillery; there is also a The method of loading arrows in wooden tubes and using gunpowder to push iron arrows to attack may come from the tradition of crossbows in the Mediterranean region. Later, the earliest artillery in Europe also used iron arrows to attack, and it was probably influenced by this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The motor method is actually superior to the firearms of the Yuan Dynasty and the Mongol Khanates. Moreover, the Arabs in the Middle Ages liked to experiment. The chemistry derived from alchemy was very outstanding, and the purification of gunpowder was also better than that of China. It can be said that they are catching up from behind. In other words, in the future, Europeans will learn firearms from the Islamic world from a higher starting point than China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest document recording firearms in Europe is the coronation address written by the Bishop of London for King Edward III in 1326. Below the coronation address is a picture of a bottle-shaped cannon, which uses gunpowder to shoot giant arrows. In Europe, the Italian city-states who were constantly striving for hegemony were the first to master the manufacturing technology of firearms. Later, firearms were also mastered by Britain, France and Germany, and they showed great glory in the Hundred Years&#39; War between England and France. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was during the Hundred Years War that European artillery shifted its goal from killing people to siegeing cities. Europeans began to build huge cannons that could collapse city walls, and built larger and larger cannons in the competition. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1375, French cannon makers cast a huge cannon weighing 2,000 pounds (about 900 kilograms) in Caen. Two years later, Philip the Brave, King of Burgundy, blasted it with a huge cannon. He defeated the British at Alderac Castle and proved the value of the cannon. In the second half of the Hundred Years&#39; War, King Henry V of England used huge artillery to capture dozens of castles in France. Later, King Charles VII of France established the most efficient artillery in Europe, sweeping across the British army and recovering more than half of the country occupied by the British. France. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Europeans installed this kind of giant cannon on ships. In the Age of Discovery, they were invincible. Vasco da Gama led a few gunboats to travel across East Africa and India, equipped with dozens of giant cannons. The ships can often easily defeat enemies several times, ten times or even dozens of times larger. During the colonial expansion, the Europeans built bastions and deployed huge cannons in the colonies, which frightened thousands of indigenous troops and left them helpless. Europeans easily gained control of the entire world&#39;s seas through gunboats and fortresses, and dominated modern history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The artillery from Western Europe also returned to Eastern Europe. The Russians used advanced guns and artillery to blow up the Mongolian khanates and advance rapidly toward the east. The Islamic world also introduced advanced firearms from Western Europe, and three gunpowder empires emerged, including the Ottoman Empire, the Safavid Empire of Persia, and the Mughal Empire of India. Even Central Asia, which was relatively isolated in modern times, had self-made weapons because of the teachings of the Ottoman Empire. Arquebus and light artillery capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1453, the Ottoman Sultan Mehmet II captured Constantinople and eliminated the Byzantine Empire. The exaggerated Urban cannon played a major role, and the Sudanese pro-army Yeniceri was also an excellent force. Musket Army. In 1526, Babur, the relic of the Timur Empire, marched into India. In the Battle of Panipat, he used artillery to defeat the elephant soldiers of the Delhi Sultanate. He entered India and established the Mughal Empire. Later, the Mughal Empire set up a cannon factory. , a standing army with 70 guns. Due to poor road conditions, it was difficult for Persia to use giant cannons, and the use of firearms lagged behind. However, in the early 18th century, Nader Shah, who replaced the Safavid dynasty, used advanced muskets imported from Europe and camel-borne Wasp cannons to sweep through Persia and India. , Central Asia, defeated the Ottoman army many times, and became the last great conqueror in history. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The system of the Ming and Qing Dynasties brought the glory of Chinese firearms to an end&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;While firearms are advancing rapidly around the world, China, which invented firearms, has been left behind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Emperor Kangxi of the Qing Dynasty was amazed by the performance of the Dzungar firearm &quot;Zanbalak&quot;. During the reign of Emperor Yongzheng, he copied it on a large scale and equipped it for the Qing army, which later developed into a gun. This kind of &quot;Zanbarak&quot; is a camel-borne wasp cannon, but it is an outdated weapon invented by the Mamluk Dynasty three to four hundred years before Emperor Kangxi. Although it is still somewhat unique in the geographical environment of Persia and Central Asia, Function, but it is several eras behind the advanced artillery in Western Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The firearms in the Middle East and Europe overtook China in the Yuan Dynasty, mainly because the intensity of the war at that time was not high, and there was no need to improve firearms like the Europeans who fought every day. At the end of the Yuan Dynasty, the uprising army revived firearms. However, the firearms of Zhu Yuanzhang and other heroes in the late Yuan Dynasty all followed the path of weight rather than quality. Although the Ming army&#39;s firepower equipment rate reached 10% during the Hongwu period, with hundreds of thousands of firepower soldiers, the level of firearms may not reach the level of the Song Dynasty, let alone compare with Europe at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Zhu Yuanzhang fought against Chen Youliang at Poyang Lake, the &quot;big bowl mouth barrel&quot; he used was an anti-personnel shotgun, the &quot;no help&quot; was an incendiary bomb, and the so-called &quot;artillery&quot; was a trebuchet to throw incendiary bombs. Burn enemy warships. When attacking Zhang Shicheng&#39;s last stronghold in Suzhou, Zhu Yuanzhang used catapults instead of cannons to attack the city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that in the use of firearms in the troubled times of the late Yuan Dynasty, the transformation of European firearms into giant cannons was not seen. American sinologist Ouyang Tai believes that this is because China&#39;s rammed earth city walls are too thick to be destroyed by giant cannons, so there is no need to build giant cannons. However, Zhu Yuanzhang always used catapults that were much less powerful than giant cannons when he attacked the city. It can be seen that siege equipment does not necessarily rush to destroy the city wall, and there is no reason to give up the development of giant cannons. It should be because the overall technical level of Zhu Yuanzhang&#39;s army is too low and they cannot build them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After seizing the world, Zhu Yuanzhang closed the country on the one hand and suppressed the people who killed the soldiers on the other. This resulted in a gap in knowledge and technology, and many technologies may have been lost as a result. Although the Ming army has a high firearms equipment rate, the Ming Dynasty has strictly prohibited private ownership and research and development of firearms since the founding of the country. Local governments cannot make their own firearms and must uniformly deploy them through the court, thus eliminating the possibility of society improving firearms on its own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the above reasons, the firearms of the Ming Dynasty were very backward. In the middle period, when the Portuguese appeared on the southeastern coast, their pre-loaded eagle cannons that could be fired continuously were regarded as artifacts by the Ming army. They called them &quot;Flan cannons&quot; and copied them. However, this kind of cannon was not popular in Europe at that time. It is already outdated and second-rate. Later, the ordinary naval guns of the Dutch became the &quot;Red Yi cannons&quot; used by the Ming army to save lives in the war with the Jianzhou Jurchens. The first ones the Ming army fished from sunken ships were fished from the sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the Ottoman Empire muskets, whose performance was obviously inferior to that of Europe, were modified by the Ming Dynasty Zhao Shizhen into the &quot;Rumi gun&quot; (Rumi means Rome, and the Ottomans regarded themselves as Rome), which was regarded as a sharp weapon. It can be seen that the Ming Dynasty The level of firearms is low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Jurchens suffered continuously under the Ming army&#39;s Hongyi artillery, they developed artillery on their own. With the guidance of the surrendered Ming army artillery team and European missionaries, their artillery use once led East Asia. However, as the Manchus learned from the Ming Dynasty and turned to isolation, these welcome changes gradually faded away. In 1724, Emperor Yongzheng expelled missionaries, and the Manchu Qing Dynasty&#39;s introduction of Western technology slowed down significantly. In 1776, after Emperor Qianlong pacified Jinchuan and Jinchuan, he achieved perfect martial arts and believed that there would be no trouble at home. In order to prevent firearms from flowing into the people, he destroyed a large number of firearms caught in the war. Made firearms, the pace of China&#39;s firearms innovation came to an abrupt end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some overseas sinologists believe that China&#39;s unified system does not have as many wars as Europe, which is the biggest reason for the sluggish development of firearms in China. However, in fact, during the Ming and Qing Dynasties, there were no wars to quell civil unrest and bring people back home. There were quite a few, some on a very large scale, but they did not promote the development of firearms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most important reason is that the Ming and Qing Dynasties reversed the enlightened attitude of the Tang and Song Dynasties and reached their peak in preventing social autocracy. They were the masters of the Qin system and tried to monopolize the most advanced firearms technology as far as the eye could see. Not only is it closed to the country, cutting off economic and technological exchanges with the West, but it is also unwilling to allow the private sector to promote the research and development and upgrading of firearms. Naturally, the entire society has no enthusiasm and motivation for researching firearms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the emperors of the Ming and Qing Dynasties felt that the dynasty was in a military crisis, they would also vigorously introduce advanced European firearms, which shows that they have the ability to learn advanced technology. If this continues, even if the research and development is poor, they will not lag behind Europe. is too big. But once the crisis has passed, it will cut off ties with overseas countries and ignore the booming development of firearms outside the region until the Europeans knock on the country&#39;s door with powerful ships and cannons that the Manchus could not imagine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>