<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[文物保护的困境与探索]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260664]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Recently, a thousand-year-old cliff statue monument located in Nanjiang County, Sichuan Province was found to be painted with &quot;makeup&quot;, and netizens called it &quot;disfigured&quot; &quot;. There have been many incidents of man-made destruction of cultural relics this year. How can we ensure that cultural relics are preserved for a long time without being damaged? Cultural conservation workers are constantly exploring.</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:56:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话人类学家项飙：怎么去面对已知无解的问题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260661]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Xiang Biao sat among a group of young people in Guangzhou, laughing with everyone, occasionally frowning and speaking, More often than not, listening to each person’s thoughts, experiences, and traumas. Most of these traumas come from family of origin and close relationships. Sometimes everyone forgets that Xiang Biao exists. During a party, he quietly got up to wash the dishes, and almost no one noticed him. These young people are participants in the &quot;Seeing the First 500 Meters&quot; social art workshop launched by artists He Zhisen and Xiang Biao, as well as Duan Zhipeng, a doctoral student at the Oslo School of Architecture and Design. The works of the workshop have participated in the 9th Shenzhen-Hong Kong Urban/Architecture Biennale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last time Xiang Biao returned to China was in 2019 before the epidemic. Xiang Biao is the director of the Max Planck Institute for Social Anthropology in Germany and a professor of social anthropology at the University of Oxford in the UK. He became famous for his research on Zhejiang Village in Beijing. After many years abroad, he has become active in the Chinese-speaking world again in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Xiang Biao returned to China this time, he frequently chatted with various people. For example, every time he took a taxi, he didn’t want to miss the opportunity to talk to the driver. In his hometown of Wenzhou, he found that most taxi drivers were over 45 years old and usually had another job. A driver told Xiang Biao that he helped people open credit cards. Xiang Biao was curious about who else was using credit cards now that mobile payment is so convenient. The driver said that some people need small loans for short-term turnover. And looking for customers to open a card involves the gray chain of data buying and selling. In an online car-hailing car in Guangzhou, when the conversation came up about the career of the driver&#39;s son, he pointed to the platform recording equipment in the car and made a shushing gesture, and the conversation stopped. &quot;These are all new points for me. I don&#39;t know if they are useful, but they can help me discover the richness of society.&quot; Xiang Biao told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiang Biao said that he is a person who is far away from art. He almost never watches movies and rarely goes to art galleries and exhibition halls. There was only one exception when he served as a judge for a German artist’s application project. . &quot;This is a German habit, to find people with different subject backgrounds to participate in the review.&quot; He said. The &quot;Seeing the First 500 Meters&quot; workshop is his most in-depth participation in a public art and social art activity. His original idea was to encourage everyone to go to the community and meet strangers, but on the one hand, due to the uncertainty caused by the epidemic in 2022; on the other hand, many people found that if the radius of 500 meters continued to be reduced, the things they were most concerned about would be , is family and companionship. As a result, many of the workshop&#39;s works were skewed. Everyone&#39;s anxiety is superimposed on social and personal life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Zhisen once held an exhibition in a vegetable market in Guangzhou. On the podium of South China University of Technology, he said that he had held more than 100 workshops, and most of them dispersed after seeing the first 500 people. m” members are the most closely connected. I heard that Xiang Biao made a special trip to Guangzhou to chat with everyone. Some of the participants in the workshop came from Nanjing and some from abroad. On this day, Xiang Biao sat quietly in the back row of the lecture hall, like an older student. He followed workshop member Manman through the noisy lanes and handshake buildings of Shipai Village to the art space in the urban village. This space, known as the &quot;mobile club&quot;, was originally a garbage recycling station. Xiang Biao talked with everyone about Wenzhou, the south, and the differences between the north and the south of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pV6FUnCDyc5oDAwewe9FJCGkWMNjCZKxZczL7bL2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pV6FUnCDyc5oDAwewe9FJCGkWMNjCZKxZczL7bL2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258366&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In October 2023, Xiang Biao (first from left in the back row) communicated with young people at the &quot;Mobile Club&quot;, an art space in Guangzhou. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiang Biao found that he was more popular among young people in China than he imagined, but he did not feel that he was a young person not as a mentor, but as an interlocutor. Dialogue research is also his working method in facing the research direction of &quot;common anxiety&quot;. In October 2023, Southern Weekend reporters conducted an exclusive interview with Xiang Biao in Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Understanding art through anthropology, &quot;recognition&quot; is different from &quot;understanding&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why has the contemporary art world paid more and more attention to anthropology in recent years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The so-called elite art collected in galleries and museums can do a lot in terms of methods, techniques and forms of expression. But if it is public art, if you only make breakthroughs in form and method, it will be meaningless to the common people. Others will not know what your breakthrough is, and it cannot evoke that kind of resonance. The common people will not understand what you are doing. If there is no connection with his life, then he cannot participate or be further stimulated. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, public art needs to be ideological, to find a problem, and then this problem can be expressed in a very condensed artistic way, whether it is a drama, an installation, or a painting. Well, once you express it, everyone can recognize it, and at the same time, the way you express it makes everyone see that this is a door, and they can&#39;t help but open it. There is a space behind the door. This way everyone can participate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such an artistic work must have a certain degree of thought, a large amount of observation of experience, a very detailed and sincere appreciation, and then sublimate an image, a motif, and a core symbol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then why is anthropology, rather than general social sciences or psychology, communicating with art? Because anthropology is to see some problems and truths from very specific experiences. It is not like philosophy, which starts from an existing problem, such as &quot;What is a good person?&quot;; it is also not like sociology, Think from a macro social phenomenon. Anthropology uses daily behavior to see some of the problems behind it, so anthropology has a strong sense of recognition. People can tell at a glance that this is related to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you understand &quot;sense of recognition&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Recognition means that when you see something, it evokes your understanding of your own life experience, and it will produce a mutual projection. So recognition is very important. Our understanding of the world must be based on our own life experience. You mobilize your memory and then make a new interpretation of this thing. This is called recognition. If you don’t understand, you just don’t recognize it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, whether it is Kafka or Benjamin, if we do not have a good understanding of European culture, we cannot recognize them. In fact, what he said is very direct in his context, and it is easy for people with similar life experiences to recognize it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like when we look at Lu Xun, it is difficult for young people today to understand Lu Xun, also because they do not recognize it. This does not mean that you can solve it through knowledge and logic. Of course, it does not rule out that there is a purely literal and logical way. You think you understand it, but you are completely unable to mobilize your own experience. (This situation) actually happens a lot. We all feel this way when we read some documents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many people who engage in academic research and art. In fact, their understanding is not based on their own life experience, but on establishing relationships between texts, which can also form an understanding. Or logical interpretation, it feels like you understand it, but the effect of this understanding is very different from what we call &quot;recognition&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The participants of the workshop you met in Guangzhou this time, Most of them are very young. Did you encounter any new excitement while communicating with everyone? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course there is a lot of excitement. They are not willing to adopt the mainstream meritocracy (to live), and may not necessarily be successful in a secular sense. Some people have just resigned. Their backgrounds are quite diverse, including carpenters, civil servants, video makers, and marketers. There are also people who study art, not particularly many, but these people all have a certain sense of art. Artistic sense means that they are more sensitive to their own perceptions. They may not necessarily think about these sensitivities, but the &quot;sensitivity&quot; will stay on him or her, and it is a bit sticky and will not be easily brushed off. Artistic people are sensitive and adhesive people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The workshop was a great education for me. It made me softer and paid more attention to people&#39;s subjective emotions. As I just said, these young people are not very mainstream. Many of them are weak and not very confident. There were several people who could barely speak at the beginning of last year, couldn&#39;t sleep the day before the meeting, and were so nervous. Many young people I have interacted with before, such as students at Oxford, are very talkative. Oxford is a famous place for cultivating politicians. But many of the expressions of the young people in this workshop were inconsistent. This kind of difficult expression sometimes turns into awkward silence, but once he or she speaks, you can feel that there are very rich feelings behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to my previous habits, the efficiency of this kind of communication is very low. I am a relatively rational person and have been pursuing clarity. I now realize that I was actually very closed-minded and had a very single perception of the world. I need more patience, this is an education for me. I think that to promote many things here, we cannot all do them in a rational way. Art is a good tool. I listen more. Before, I didn’t pay enough attention to the richness and sensitivity of emotions, and the many mixed and unclear things, but now I pay more attention to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I am not a mentor, but an interlocutor”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you interact with the audience during lectures or online live broadcasts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After the speech, the questions asked by the public fell into two categories. The first type is to ask questions based on the concepts I proposed. To be honest, this kind of question is not particularly meaningful. In the end, it turned into me having to define and explain the concepts. What is really impactful are the second type of questions, which are very specific questions based on life experience. It&#39;s a difficult question to answer, but it gives me some punch. For example, some parents will ask me, saying that involution is not good. My child&#39;s grades are getting worse and worse. Should I send him to tutoring? No matter how I answer, this parent will most likely send their children to make up classes. Then my answer may be, how you define make-up lessons when you interact with your children is very critical. I can feel the parent&#39;s anxiety and entanglement. I can&#39;t change the objective environment, but the more useful and appropriate answer to him is how to define, state, and treat this matter. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We may need to distinguish between thinking and thoughts. Thinking is inferential and requires rigorous logic; thinking is divergent and multi-dimensional. This kind of dialogue allowed me to change from one-dimensional thinking to richer and more sensitive thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are the differences between the academic workshops you participated in? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That kind of workshop requires using very clear words to express, theoretically and conceptually speaking about life, and it takes a lot of time. Generally no more than three days. This &quot;Seeing the First 500 Meters&quot; is completely different. It is open, does not have a fixed theme, and is against conceptualization. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many young people like to communicate with you, and they are very Trust you. Do you consider yourself a mentor to young people? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was quite surprised when I returned to China this time. I found that I am more popular than I thought. How eager young people are. Beyond my imagination. But I don’t feel like a mentor to young people. I hate the role of mentor. When I was a young man, I didn’t pay much attention to life mentors, so I won’t become the character I hate. I am a conversationalist. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think the most important thing is not that I tell you what you should do, but that I inspire you to think more. I will raise some questions, highlight some paradoxes, do some analysis, make you think, and let us find that the original thinking may be a bit simple. This is my job. Even if I have some so-called advice, it&#39;s about how to think, not about what to do morally and behaviorally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;But it is true that when many young people ask you questions, they will ask about Regarding issues such as anxiety and involution, there is a feeling of expecting you to be a life mentor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think so. They would also ask each other these questions at friends&#39; gatherings. They would say that the involution has become like this, what should I do? These questions are not only asked among friends and relatives, but also asked by oneself at night when I can&#39;t sleep. I think maybe that question occupied his mind and it would come out naturally, so he would ask that question to everyone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s interesting is how I answer such a question. He knew I wouldn&#39;t give him an answer, couldn&#39;t show him a path. Most people don&#39;t think so. What he actually asked was how to face a problem that is known to have no solution. So I put myself in his situation, understand his situation, and respond with sincerity, which may be more effective. This is completely a friendship-like communication, not a mentor-mentee relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The book &quot;Use Yourself as a Method&quot; is a best-seller, maybe That’s why young people are inspired by you. As an anthropologist, why have you been more willing to give interviews or appear in mass media in recent years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the 19th and 20th centuries, when social science first emerged, the world was very different from today. The difference between scholars and non-scholars at that time Very big at the time. For example, a European scholar needs to learn ancient Greek, Latin, and various philosophies. Chinese scholars like Liang Qichao and Yan Fu first introduced social sciences, and most of the people are illiterate. But in the 21st century, our youth’s level of education, their ability to think and master knowledge, and their information are no different from those of scholars. And we often think that the experts are among the people. Some of the things on site B are actually more interesting than those written by scholars in many academies. This means that academic research cannot start from its own academic propositions like it did in the 19th and 20th centuries, and write an article for two to three hundred people to read it. The public will not know what is going on. That will not work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So my work in Germany is to advocate a new research style, which does not start from academic propositions, but from public anxiety itself, using &quot;anxiety&quot; as the title, Come and study together. In other words, it is conversational research. Everyone has their own life and their own struggles, and the taste inside is different from what we see outside. Our output should be about how to deal with the world, giving thinking methods, concepts and theoretical perspectives, and triggering more discussions. For conversational research, communication in the public media is very important. This is my working method, not a supplementary one, but a fundamental working method. It’s not that I have any conclusions to tell you, but that they collide and deepen in the constant back and forth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What forms of communication have you received during this kind of dialogue and back-and-forth? feedback? After all, you haven’t opened an account at station B, so feedback is not given through barrage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I find that contemporary art is particularly sensitive. In 2020, there will be four domestic exhibitions with the title &quot;Nearby&quot;. In fact, &quot;nearby&quot; is a very vague thing in academic terms. I didn&#39;t find it very interesting myself, I just mentioned it in a general way. The “nearby” concept received enthusiastic feedback. When I proposed the term “country squire,” the feedback I received was less enthusiastic and more questioning and critical. There are also some topics that I find interesting but receive a mediocre response from the public. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Someone will find my email online and write to me. It&#39;s not that the question he raised is meaningful in itself, but I will think about why he raised such a question. I know that some issues are universal, and I will have to observe them over a period of time. So feedback is not given directly to me, it requires a process. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Common Anxiety and Type 16 Personality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; During your return to China, you chatted intensively with various people almost every day. Have you always been so talkative? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I haven’t tested it yet. I am not a very extroverted person. Sometimes I am a little socially anxious, and I have been insensitive to people&#39;s subjective emotions for a long time. I have always felt that I have mild autism. I read the biography of an analytical philosopher in Oxford. He often talked to others, but everyone found that he was indifferent to many common sense things and had no interest in interpersonal relationships. The understanding is very simple, but the analysis of some things can be very profound. I think this is very similar to me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, I am quite introverted and afraid of eating with many people. When chatting on that occasion, few people can tell the complete story of their experiences. The content of the conversation can easily turn into various fragments, gossip, and extreme stories, many of which are hearsay. I&#39;m surprised that many intellectual elites also like to talk about this. In that environment, it was difficult for me to maintain myself. I became very quiet and wanted to end it quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Nowadays, it is very popular among Chinese young people to talk about type 16 personality. We often talk to each other Asked &quot;Are you an I person or an E person?&quot; What do you think of this phenomenon? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Personality classification is a very interesting phenomenon. It is not the same as young people’s original curiosity about psychology. If you want to understand your own mental state and understand yourself, it is now mainly a social tool. You know each other&#39;s type, and then you can profile each other, and then ask each other questions. But this question does not necessarily mean that you need to prescribe the right medicine (according to the other person&#39;s personality type). , but it means that there is no way to start communication with a natural word, and using personality classification can talk more safely. This has a lot to do with the role of social media. We are used to interacting with personas, that is, types of people and people in portraits, but we don’t quite know how to interact with the people themselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Most academic research now revolves around topics , do you consider yourself a lucky person for having conversations and researching shared anxieties in this way? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am very lucky. I was already very lucky in Oxford. When I arrived at the Max Planck Institute in Germany, the constraints on me became even more severe. Less, and it gives you a platform that encourages you to do weird things. In the direction of &quot;common anxiety&quot;, we have postdocs working on &quot;pressure&quot; in Africa, and some working on &quot;persistence&quot; in Latin America. In what specific life situations, what issues and in what ways do people make persistent investments? What can this teach us. This is different from a philosophical discussion; it is a very realistic observation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why do you pay special attention to &quot;anxiety&quot;? Why conduct conversational research starting from “shared anxieties” rather than, say, “shared concerns”? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Public concerns are often shaped by a mainstream discourse and can be easily expressed directly with some data. Concerns are integrated and conceptual. Anxiety is emotional and closer to the experience of life itself. For ordinary people, the purpose of life is not to criticize, but to live better. Of course, there are many things worthy of criticism, but only when they come out of the purpose of their lives can criticism be implemented and facilitate their actions, and then they can change lives and people&#39;s thinking under a seemingly unchangeable structure. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Studying anxiety is much more difficult than studying public concerns or a certain issue, because anxiety is a vague thing that cannot be explained clearly, let alone quantified. . This means that we must find new languages ​​and new ways of thinking. It is easy to follow the agenda, but it is also difficult to innovate. But starting from anxiety, we can better grasp the current new contradictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Anxiety&quot; has been a hot word for a long time in recent years. What are your observations on everyone’s anxiety? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Xiang Biao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The anxiety is more serious than I thought, and it is very pervasive. I could see the current high incidence of mental illness from reports. Then through conversations with young people, chatting and contacting various people, I saw more from experience how people describe anxiety and how anxiety is. Spreading, including in intimate relationships, anxiety is amplified or distorted. At the same time, everyone realizes that they are anxious, which means that everyone is looking forward to a change, or at least a better way to respond to their situation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One cause of anxiety is a disruption in our perception of life. When there is a huge swing in life, without adequate discussion and communication after the swing, ordinary people will not be able to form a complete understanding of the development of things. There must be various traumas involved. This trauma remains on ourselves. If we don’t handle it well, it will remain there forever and turn into fear, weakness, nervousness, violent reactions, etc. in our future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People often ask me, why don’t you criticize? In fact, criticism is still very important, but I focus more on analyzing the trauma on our bodies, how we treat it, and how to preserve our own strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[94岁“包租婆”邝肖卿成中国女首富 房地产仍是女企业家财富首要来源]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260670]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Kwong Siu-ching, the wife of 94-year-old Sun Hung Kai Properties (0016.HK) founder Guo Desheng, invested 72 billion yuan in Net worth, she became the richest woman in China for the first time; Yang Huiyan, the &quot;tenth consecutive winner&quot; as the richest woman, dropped to fifth place; nearly 60 of the 50 female entrepreneurs on the list started from scratch, and real estate is still their largest source of wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 14, Hurun Research Institute and the Business Women&#39;s Growth and Social Platform Hong Kong Beauty Club jointly released the &quot;2023 Hong Kong Beauty Club·Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List&quot;) as shown above information. This is the eighteenth consecutive time that Hurun Research Institute has released this list, and the deadline for wealth calculation is September 1, 2023. Unlike the Hurun Rich List, the list of female entrepreneurs separately calculates the personal wealth of female entrepreneurs that can be separated from family wealth. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;94-year-old &quot;No. 1 Tenant&quot; Kuang Xiaoqing became the richest woman in China&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &quot;In the past 18 years, the threshold for the top 50 Chinese female entrepreneurs has increased from 500 million to 13.5 billion , increased nearly 30 times.&quot; Hurun Report, chairman and chief research officer of Hurun Report, said above. However, judging from the Hurun Report&#39;s overall list, the proportion of female entrepreneurs dropped by 1.3 percentage points to 25.4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List shows that 94-year-old Kuang Xiaoqing became the richest woman in China for the first time with a wealth of 72 billion yuan. She is also the sixth richest woman in China in the past 18 years on the Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List. The top five are Zhang Yin (three times) ), Yang Huiyan (ten times), Wu Yajun (twice), Zhou Qunfei (once), Chen Lihua (once). Wu Yajun, the founder of Longfor Real Estate, remains the richest self-made woman in China with 66.5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3eaa8871e004d592302015eeabe4487e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3eaa8871e004d592302015eeabe4487e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258386&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;(Hurun Female Entrepreneurs List TOP10, Source: Hurun Report)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Kuang Xiaoqingsheng Born in Huashan Town, Huadu District, Guangdong Province in 1929, she is the wife of Hong Kong entrepreneur and founder of Sun Hung Kai Properties, Kwok Desheng, with a total wealth of 72 billion yuan. She is also the largest shareholder of Sun Hung Kai Properties. She is highly respected in the family and is the soul of Sun Hung Kai Properties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Hung Kai Properties is one of the largest real estate developers in Hong Kong. According to data from Sun Hung Kai Properties in fiscal year 2023 (July 1, 2022 to June 30, 2023), the company’s operating income was HK$71.2 billion. Net profit attributable to the parent company was HK$23.91 billion, with a net profit margin of 34.52%, a year-on-year increase of 2.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kuang Xiaoqing is known as &quot;China&#39;s No. 1 Housekeeper&quot;. Judging from the financial reports of Sun Hung Kai Properties in the past five years, property rental has always contributed the largest proportion of revenue, about one-third. Judging from the latest financial report, as of June 30, 2023, Sun Hung Kai Properties&#39; land bank in Hong Kong is approximately 58 million square feet (approximately 5.38 million square meters), of which more than 60% are diversified properties, most of which are used for Leasing and long-term investment bring considerable recurring income to the group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hurun Report, Kuang Xiaoqing became the richest woman in China for the first time, mainly benefiting from the rise in the Hong Kong dollar exchange rate this year and company dividends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the rise in the Hong Kong dollar exchange rate, since the beginning of this year, the RMB exchange rate against the Hong Kong dollar has risen from around 0.8 to around 0.9, with a maximum of around 0.93. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the company&#39;s dividends, Flush shows that Sun Hung Kai Properties is one of the blue-chip stocks that have been purchased the most by domestic investors, with a cumulative cash distribution of HK$71.72 billion in the past five years. In fiscal year 2023 (July 1, 2022 to June 30, 2023), the company will distribute cash twice, with an amount of HK$14.34 billion, and a dividend payout ratio of 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that in the latest fiscal year (dividend payment date is November 16), Sun Hung Kai Properties paid a dividend of HK$3.7 per share, which was three times the dividend of the previous fiscal year. Kwong Xiaoqing personally holds less than 0.01% of Sun Hung Kai Properties, which is 25,020 shares. Kwong Xiaoqing and his immediate family members jointly hold 19.5% of Sun Hung Kai Properties&#39; shares, totaling 565 million shares. Based on a dividend payout of HK$3.7 per share, Kuang Xiaoqing’s personal shareholding and the shareholding jointly held with others will make a profit of approximately HK$2.091 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The ranking of &quot;Ten Crowns&quot; Yang Huiyan dropped to fifth place&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In this list, another major focus is the substantial wealth of Yang Huiyan, who has won the title of the richest woman ten times. Shrunk, ranking fell to fifth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the changes in the Hurun Women Entrepreneurs list, Country Garden Chairman and Executive Director Yang Huiyan’s wealth has shrunk the most in 2023 compared to last year (27 billion yuan), ranking 5th with 48 billion yuan; followed by It is Cheng Xue, CEO of Haitian Flavor Industry, whose performance has declined due to the additive incident, and his wealth has shrunk by 16.5 billion yuan; and Zhao Yan, chairman of Bloomage International Investment Group, the &quot;Queen of Hyaluronic Acid&quot;, whose wealth has shrunk by 14.5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Born in 1981, Yang Huiyan is the second daughter of Country Garden founder Yang Guoqiang. In 2005, Yang Huiyan returned to China after graduating from the Ohio State University majoring in marketing and logistics, and joined Country Garden as Yang Guoqiang&#39;s personal assistant and served as purchasing manager. She has held important positions in Country Garden Investment Center, Procurement Department, Human Resources Center, Digital Management Center and other departments. In March 2023, Yang Huiyan officially became the successor of the family business and served as the chairman of the board of directors of Country Garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2007, Country Garden was listed in Hong Kong, and Yang Guoqiang transferred all his shares to Yang Huiyan. 26-year-old Yang Huiyan topped the 2007 Forbes rich list with $16.02 billion, and became China&#39;s new richest woman. In the 16 years from 2007 to 2022, Yang Huiyan aspired to be the richest woman in China ten times. It is worth noting that Yang Huiyan’s wealth has shrunk by nearly 60% year-on-year in 2022, but she still ranks first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/e2b3c063491daeb6cf2b77ab07539ef4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;577&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/e2b3c063491daeb6cf2b77ab07539ef4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258388&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;(Yang Huiyan aspired to be the richest woman in China ten times, source: Hurun Report)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Huiyan’s wealth has shrunk and Country Garden Crisis is closely related. In 2023, due to increasing uncertainty in the macro economy and real estate, Country Garden&#39;s debt has frequently shown red lights. &quot;Faced with the two-way tightening on the consumer side and the financing side, the group&#39;s liquidity is under unprecedented pressure.&quot; Country Garden said in its 2023 mid-term report. From Country Garden&#39;s annual and interim reports for the past five years, we can find that Country Garden&#39;s strategic goals have changed from prudent and pragmatic replenishment of high-quality land reserves to &quot;guaranteing the delivery of buildings&quot; and making every effort to arrange debt repayments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 30, 2023, Country Garden Services (6098.HK) announced that Yang Huiyan, the company’s controlling shareholder, non-executive director and chairman of the board of directors, donated RMB 64 million to Guoqiang Charity Foundation (Hong Kong) Co., Ltd. HK$100 million worth of stocks will be used for charity. But this move caused controversy in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Hurun Women Entrepreneurs List shows that the number of new female billionaires on the list is 8, which is the lowest in 18 years and 3 less than last year. Among the newcomers, the top one is Zhou Chaonan of Runze Technology, which is engaged in the big data center and computing infrastructure industry, with a wealth of 20 billion yuan; followed by Shu Ping, one of the founders of Haidilao, with a wealth of 18 billion yuan; and then Yulon of Taiwan. Car boss Yan Chen Lillian has a wealth of 16 billion yuan. Newcomers also include Ye Qiongjiu, director and deputy general manager of Tonghuashun, with a wealth of 13.5 billion yuan. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Nearly 60% of female entrepreneurs started from scratch. Real estate is still the largest source of wealth&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of wealth sources, nearly 60% of female entrepreneurs started from scratch, and nearly 40% inherited it. . &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, the Hurun Female Entrepreneurs List shows that there are 34 self-made female entrepreneurs in 2023, accounting for 59%, which is basically the same as last year; 24 are not self-made, 2 fewer than last year position, accounting for 41%, compared with 43% last year. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Self-made female entrepreneurs mainly start their own businesses or start businesses with their husbands. For example, Wu Yajun of Longhu, Chen Lihua of Fuhua and Wang Laichun of Luxshare Precision, Fan Hongwei of Hengli, Guan Yamei of Tongwei and Pan Dong of Blue Moon, etc. Non-self-made female entrepreneurs, on the one hand, inherit wealth, such as Zong Fuli of Wahaha, Yang Huiyan of Country Garden, etc.; on the other hand, they are the widows of entrepreneurs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of age, the average age of self-made female entrepreneurs is about 59 years old, and the average age of successors is 54 years old. &amp;nbsp;The wealth of the 7 post-80s generation on the list is all inherited. They are: Yang Huiyan, 42, from Country Garden, Yan Xin, 40, from Sushang, Zong Fuli, 41, from Wahaha, and 40-year-old Dali Foods. Xu Yangyang, 36-year-old Ruan Zeyun of Flat Glass, 39-year-old Luo Yi of Hesheng and 35-year-old Jin Junmiao of JA Solar Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of the industries in which female entrepreneurs work, real estate is still the largest source of wealth for female entrepreneurs, accounting for 17% of the people on the list, the same as last year; energy and consumer goods tied for second, accounting for 13%; food and beverage, non-ferrous metals, health and other industries all increased, while the chemical industry and investment industry declined. &lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f7cacbc072e830304eff09b6e09ce447.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;413&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f7cacbc072e830304eff09b6e09ce447.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;258387&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;(Distribution of industries engaged in by male and female entrepreneurs, source: Hurun Report)&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; &quot;Relatively speaking, Chinese female entrepreneurs are better in the real estate and consumer goods industries, while male entrepreneurs are better in the food and beverage, media, entertainment and automobile industries.&quot; Hurun said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Hurun said: &quot;The female entrepreneurs who performed well this year mainly come from the Apple industry chain, including Zhou Qunfei of Lens Technology and Zeng Fangqin of Lingyi Intelligent Manufacturing; secondly, thanks to the post-epidemic The entertainment and catering industries are recovering, such as He Chaoqiong of MGM China, Li Haiyan and Shu Ping of Haidilao; the third is Ma Dongmin of Baidu, etc. driven by ChatGPT.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[教育不是功名利禄的“油门”，而是做人做事的“把门”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260571]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;三叔来找我诉苦，说又帮堂弟还了一万元的债务，然后照例感慨一句“还是你们念书好啊”，这个“啊”字是一声长叹，包含着三叔很多思绪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时光倒回二十年，三叔对于念书的态度并非一个“好”字，而是有他自己的判断。他自身是个能人，力气大，脑子灵，各种农活手拿把掐不在话下，到城里打工也能立刻适应，从技能到人际，游刃有余，既赚钱，也赚人缘。因此，他家的日子在本村最殷实，称得上“首富”，属于“村东头跺跺脚，村西头颤三颤”的人物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他常说，自己没读几天书，没接受过啥高深的教育，但日子过得比别人都强。上学念书，最终还是要过日子，只要日子过得好，受不受教育不要太在乎。因此，在别人家都为孩子成绩不好着急的时候，三叔很淡然，对堂弟的成绩不关心，考了100分不表扬，考个不及格也不打骂，并告诉自己的儿子，挣多少分不算本事，关键是会挣钱。三叔对于学校教育是这个态度，对于家庭教育是这样灌输——只要掌握了挣钱的本事，你就赢了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三叔对那些在教育上投入太多钱和精力的家庭很不屑，尤其是对我家。那个时候的学费虽不算高，但对于农村家庭仍是不小的负担，每到开学前，很多父母都为学费犯愁，甚至开学后好长时间，才会凑齐。三叔对凑学费的做法表示不理解，既然没钱，为啥还要去上，上了小学，要上中学，还要上大学，毕业之后如果没找到工作或者工作不好，那投了十多年的钱不就打了水漂？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来我中考发挥失常，觉得够不着录取线，很沮丧失落，亲戚朋友不好来安慰，只有三叔过来告诉我，别着急，大不了和他一起去学修车，比念书简单，还能挣钱。搞得我哭笑不得，好在只是虚惊，一个月后我成功进入高中读书。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为有教育观念的分歧，父亲和三叔的关系很微妙，兄弟二人经常会在吃饭喝酒时，为了这个分歧吵起来，闹个不欢而散。父亲开始是坚定的，也一直给我打气，说砸锅卖铁也要念书。但随着堂弟进入社会，父亲的心有些动摇了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;堂弟在三叔的不管之下，勉强挨到初中毕业，就再也不肯上学，想出去城市里闯一闯，三叔表示支持，并把他托付给一个做生意的亲戚照料。三叔给了堂弟一笔钱，让他自己去赚第一桶金。堂弟年纪不大，但继承了三叔的才干，不到18岁就已在城里混个风生水起，起码开始往家里拿钱了。而我那时还在大学里“烧钱”呢。每次放假回家，父亲总是说着堂弟致富的传奇，口气里都是惊羡，后来渐渐表达对我读书见效慢的责备，从叹息到抱怨，搞得我不敢和堂弟同时出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;反转出现在我工作的第二年。堂弟开始欠债，他做生意喜欢猛进，加之很早进入社会摸爬滚打，有了固执的自信，对老人的劝诫当耳旁风。东处挪钱，西处洽谈，成了常态，渐渐入不敷出。开始三叔觉得家资雄厚，亏点本不算什么，等发现势头不对为时已晚，堂弟的债务横跨黑白两道，涵盖亲戚朋友，他无力偿还，就摊在了要强的三叔头上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;倾家荡产之后，债务只填上十分之一，已经当了爷爷可颐享天年的三叔决定从头再来，他把年轻时的手艺操持起来，同时打着两三份工，以惊人的毅力赚钱还债。亲戚的债务、银行的贷款……一笔又一笔，全靠他和三婶两个人支撑偿还。而习惯于在钱堆里打滚的堂弟，无法接受没钱的日子，在欠债之后直接躺平，天大的事情让父母顶着，就连他自己的儿子都是老人一边打工一边照料。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的日子已持续十年，债务总算还得差不多。我没多大变化，就是亦步亦趋上班下班，变化的是父亲和三叔。父亲开始庆幸当年自己对于教育的投入，虽然我没挣什么大钱，但学会了稳重，不易“学坏”，对我也比从前多了肯定。三叔开始重复着说“念书多好”，教育是要花钱，但这个钱值得花，因为念了书的人就有“把门的”，做事就有东西拉着，不会一直“踩油门”，不管不顾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来我渐渐明白，教育固然不是万能的，可能无法直接解决就业、赚钱等这些很现实的问题。但没有教育是万万不能的，我们常常会将教育和社会想成因果关系，教育必须对进入社会能做什么负责，否则便是无用的。其实，教育的一大功能是对进入社会不做什么负责，不能只盯着“有所为”，还要注重“有所不为”。透过三叔的话，我想无论家庭教育、学校教育、社会教育，如果专注于将教育当成利禄的“油门”，那么注定会失控，越来越“快”的时代，需要教育作为“刹车”的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为长春媒体人）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目期待您的来稿。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[千年造像被“毁容”，只为他们还个愿？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260666]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 16:29:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently, a cliff was excavated in Nanjiang County, Bazhong, Sichuan more than 1,400 years ago in the late Northern Wei Dynasty. The statues were defaced and vandalized, causing concern. After seeing the pictures, netizens lamented: &quot;It makes me want to cry. The protection of cultural relics has a long way to go.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The daubed statue is a new discovery in 2021&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Pictures posted by netizens show that the statue has been painted colorfully. The rosettes, clothes, headdresses, and utensils in the hands of some statues are painted in different colors. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ffe3c063109a418dd2eedacb2e70eb9b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;773&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ffe3c063109a418dd2eedacb2e70eb9b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258373 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ff121ba98253a1dc0f5db6fc41a74a2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;458&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ff121ba98253a1dc0f5db6fc41a74a2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258371&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A cliff statue in Nanjiang County after it was daubed (top picture) and before it was daubed (bottom picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1ac7a7a97d55273821119a68f82869d3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1ac7a7a97d55273821119a68f82869d3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Relevant archaeological survey reports show that the statues here are newly discovered in 2021. In February 2022, the Bazhong Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau, the School of Archeology and Museum of Sichuan University, the Xi&#39;an Forest of Steles Museum and the Nanjiang County Cultural Relics Protection Research Center jointly conducted an investigation of the cliff statues. The subsequent report concluded that:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>; &quot;Cliff statues were rarely excavated in the late Northern Wei Dynasty, and were continued in the early Tang &lt;span>;, Wu Zhou and middle and late Tang dynasties. The excavation date was early and the formation process was complicated. The entire natural stone package on the ground was excavated into a stele for the statue. The characteristic practice is an isolated example in Sichuan. These materials have very important academic value in completing the development sequence of Sichuan grottoes and revealing the Buddhist culture and art exchanges between Sichuan and the northern Central Plains.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bba7b257b7a0b0b11359cbf62d37a1f6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;740&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bba7b257b7a0b0b11359cbf62d37a1f6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f853a85bd792a1975d1d34c3a761dd02.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;688&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/f853a85bd792a1975d1d34c3a761dd02.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;After another local cliff statue was daubed (top picture) and before it was daubed (bottom picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; The cultural protection staff did not have time to stop it after discovering it&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reporter called the Bazhong Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau. A staff member said that the incident happened two days ago, and he went to stop it after discovering it through surveillance. &quot;Because it is in a barren mountain, they had already finished painting it when we arrived. The statue was discovered only two years ago and has not yet been included in the cultural protection unit. We have built a cultural relic shed and surveillance, but it is too far away.&quot; Inside the mountains, local protection capabilities are also limited. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The staff said that those who daubed the statues were all old men in their 70s and 80s, saying that they were &quot;clothing the Bodhisattva and fulfilling his vows.&quot; &quot;It is not easy for us to deal with it, we can only criticize and educate. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As to whether the statue can be restored to its original appearance, staff from the Bazhong Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau said that the paint used on the statue is mainly acrylic. Relevant experts have been invited to demonstrate, &quot;It should be possible to restore it, and we will Strengthen publicity and education on cultural relics protection, and also call on everyone to increase awareness of cultural relics protection through the media. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;Local report: The public security organs have intervened in the investigation&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the early morning of the 15th, the Nanjiang County Cultural Relics Protection Research Center issued a report on the &quot;Shifei River Cliff&quot; Report on the situation of &quot;the statues were painted&quot;:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 13, some of the cliff statues in Shifeihe County were painted, which aroused widespread concern among netizens. After preliminary investigation, in November On the 6th, Li Mouhua, a resident of Langzhong City, Sichuan Province, entrusted Wang Mouguo, a villager of Jinyin Village, Chixi Town, Nanjiang County, Bazhong City (Li Mouhua’s mother) to ask Yue Moubang, a villager of Shehongzhai, Gaota Town, to investigate Some of the cliff statues in Shifeihe were painted with the words &quot;dress to make a wish&quot;. After the incident, the local area immediately added protective measures to the site to prevent secondary damage caused by inappropriate behavior. At the same time, the public security organs are conducting investigations in accordance with the law.&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;On November 14, experts from the Sichuan Provincial Cultural Relics Bureau, the Institute of Cultural Relics and Archeology and the Bazhong Municipal Cultural Relics Bureau conducted on-site inspections and studied and formulated a protection and restoration plan. The Nanjiang County Cultural Relics Protection Research Center&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; has Contact an institution with cultural relics appraisal qualifications to evaluate the value of the cliff statues and the losses caused by smearing. In the next step, our center will promptly announce the investigation, disposal and restoration status to the public.&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;Some &quot;unpopular&quot; cultural relics are fading&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, due to&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;grassroots cultural relics protection&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;power&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;The quantity is relatively weak, and similar damage to cultural relics across the country&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is not uncommon.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the Forbidden City, the Summer Palace, and the Terracotta Warriors and Horses of Qin Shi Huang’s Mausoleum In addition to other famous scenic spots, ancient tombs in the mountains and forests, the Great Wall in the wilderness, Buddhist caves on the cliffs... In places we can&#39;t see, some &quot;unpopular&quot; cultural relics are fading, weathering, collapsing, and disappearing.&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ce507c82b8b7fa9ff0ead260d16c3678.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1 ;&quot; width=&quot;696&quot; height=&quot;462&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ce507c82b8b7fa9ff0ead260d16c3678.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258379&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;B station UP owner @Heritage Jun was deeply touched by this. “In 2015, I visited nearly 20 ancient buildings in Shanxi, and most of them were dilapidated. Some wooden buildings in the Song and Yuan Dynasties had their entire roofs collapsed and their walls also collapsed. ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;That’s when he decided to become a cultural relic sharing blogger. In the past 8 years, he visited more than 2,000 cultural relics and historic sites across the country and published more than 25,000 cultural relics Post.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/901a46703586733096a575be26dbe445.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;1244&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/901a46703586733096a575be26dbe445.png&quot; data-key =&quot;258380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In recent years, the country’s efforts to protect cultural relics have gradually increased. “I went to Shanxi again in the past two years and saw that the situation has improved a lot. As long as it is a &#39;national security unit&#39;, it has basically been restored and I can hardly recognize it anymore. &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;National Protection Units&quot;, that is, key cultural relics protection units in the country, are directly allocated by the State Administration of Cultural Heritage for protection and are the strongest. However, 767,000 places in our country cannot be protected. Among the movable cultural relics, only 5,058 are protected by the state, less than 0.7%.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those low-level cultural relics scattered in the countryside and mountains are more worrying.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, the Great Wall of Shanxi was excavated. &lt;span>; Hot search: In order to &quot;take a shortcut&quot;, two workers used an excavator to dig a large gap in a section of the Ming Dynasty Great Wall.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/d29fd6d458b2e88c9451e89efef8ea9c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width= &quot;463&quot; height=&quot;774&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/d29fd6d458b2e88c9451e89efef8ea9c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258382&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;The tragedy of the Ming Great Wall in Shanxi was not an accident. In 2018, when the blogger Heritage Jun was traveling in Dunhuang, on his way back to the city from Yangguan, he saw a private car running straight over a section of the Han Great Wall. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/c4dcf40358bb7a5ec5a2e99748948b4e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;788&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/c4dcf40358bb7a5ec5a2e99748948b4e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258381 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Many less popular cultural relics have experienced similar destruction. &quot;Zhu Zhanyun, a special researcher at the School of History and Cultural Heritage of Xiamen University, said that in recent years, there have been fewer large-scale and organized thefts of cultural relics, but there are still many &quot;unintentional losses&quot;.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/290f9a466b3f682a9e94d2a596b97b72.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/290f9a466b3f682a9e94d2a596b97b72.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;A Tanhua Mansion in Qing Dynasty in Shanxi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;We can’t help but ask why these cultural relics that should be protected are Most of them cannot escape decline?&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[药品还是毒品？女子网上转售父亲遗留止疼药一审判贩毒罪]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260629]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73519&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70321&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/847db34e88.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3217.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;In July 2023, Liao Hua was a patient Photos of drugs released by Yaozhuanqun. Pictures provided by interviewees&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/15/847db34e88.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258309&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In July 2023, Liao Hua Photos of medicines posted by patients’ medicine transfer group. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, Guangzhou woman Liao Hua (pseudonym) was pursued across provinces by Shandong police on suspicion of drug trafficking, which attracted attention. Liao Hua repeatedly stated that the analgesic drugs she resold for 260 yuan were left behind by her father after his death. With the idea of ​​saving and not wasting, she transferred the drugs among her patients, not knowing that they were &quot;drugs.&quot; &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Yangxin County Court of Shandong Province held in the first instance that Liao Hua violated national regulations on drug management and, for the purpose of profit, trafficked drugs controlled by national regulations. Psychotropic drugs that make humanoids addictive constitute the crime of drug trafficking. In the first instance, he was sentenced to two months&#39; detention, suspended for three months, and fined RMB 1,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liao Hua said that after the verdict of the first instance was announced, the more she thought about it, the more aggrieved she became. Previously, she only thought that she was violating laws and regulations by selling prescription drugs, but she did not expect that it would be a serious criminal charge such as &quot;drug trafficking&quot;. Since her job is administrative accounting, the criminal stain will greatly affect her career development. Liao Hua chose to appeal. At the end of October 2023, the second instance of the case was heard in Binzhou Intermediate Court, and no verdict has been announced yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, the judge in charge of the Binzhou Intermediate Court case told Southern Weekend reporters that the court will conduct an investigation in accordance with legal provisions, and the direction and progress of the investigation will be determined during the trial. It won&#39;t be announced until it&#39;s over. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Both drugs and drugs&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liao Hua said that the drugs he sold were all leftovers taken by his father before his death. Liao Hua&#39;s father suffered from advanced rectal cancer. During the treatment, he often suffered fractures and suffered severe pain. The hospital prescribed many types of painkillers. After his father died of a serious illness, Liao Hua didn&#39;t know what to do with the leftover medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2023, Liao Hua entered a &quot;patients exchange residual medicine transfer group&quot; through the introduction of patients, and transferred his father&#39;s remaining 15 medicines to treat COVID-19, joint pain, etc. Put the medicines together, take photos and send them to the WeChat group. At that time, a person nicknamed &quot;Xiao Wang&quot; in the group quickly added Liao Hua and sent a private message to inquire about purchasing tramalin hydrochloride and telenine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liao Hua told Southern Weekend reporters that after the accident, she noticed that although people in the group often switched drugs, most of them were anti-cancer and chemotherapy drugs. Painkillers are less common. The three boxes of tramalin hydrochloride and two boxes of Telenine that she resold to Xiao Wang for 260 yuan were &quot;other narcotic drugs and psychotropic drugs controlled by the state that can induce humanoid addiction.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On July 14, 2023, after receiving the express delivery, Xiao Wang drove to the local police station, reporting that he had purchased the national drug online without a prescription. Controlled drugs, “These are narcotics and can also be regarded as drugs.” The police&#39;s transcript of their inquiry showed that Xiao Wang was a drug addict in Yangxin County, Shandong Province. He had &quot;skated on the ice&quot; (smoked methamphetamine) before and wanted to use these drugs as a substitute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Jianbin, a lawyer at Beijing Jingdu Law Firm who has long represented drug criminal cases, told Southern Weekend reporters that the national drug control targets include traditional drugs such as heroin, methamphetamine, and marijuana. In addition, there is also a type of &quot;narcotic drugs&quot; that have both medicinal properties and drug properties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Jianbin introduced that in judicial practice, to judge whether it is a &quot;drug&quot;, we must first check whether the substance is in the list of anesthetic drugs controlled by the state, that is, the state The latest &quot;Catalogue of Narcotic Drugs&quot;, &quot;Catalog of Psychotropic Drugs&quot; and &quot;Supplementary Catalog of Controlled Varieties of Non-Medicinal Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Drugs&quot; released by the Food and Drug Administration, the Ministry of Public Security and the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporter checked and found that these lists are dynamically updated. For example, codeine in cough drops is an analgesic, but due to its addiction Sex, as early as 2000, there was an addiction to cough drops. Relevant departments have successively issued a series of regulations, requiring &quot;sales based on prescriptions&quot;, &quot;sales and purchases in appropriate amounts&quot; and &quot;monitoring of flows&quot;; in 2015, codeine-containing compound oral liquid preparations were included in the second category of psychotropic drug control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The tramalin hydrochloride resold by Liao Hua this time is a central analgesic, mostly used for various postoperative pain relief, cancer pain, labor pain, etc. treat. Excessive use can cause bradycardia, convulsions, respiratory depression and coma, and is addictive. In 2008, tramadol (including its salts, single preparations and possible isomers) was included in the Class II psychotropic drugs for control. However, tramadol’s compound preparations will only be included in the Class II psychotropic drugs on July 1, 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tylenine (oxycodone tablets), another drug resold by Liao Hua, is a compound preparation of oxycodone and is also widely used clinically. Analgesic drugs were included in the management of Class II psychotropic drugs on September 1, 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After July 1, 2023, the nationally controlled varieties of anesthetic drugs and non-medicinal anesthetic drugs have reached 456 types and 2 entire categories (fentanyl, nicotine and synthetic cannabinoids). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Listed&quot; means that tramalin hydrochloride and oxycodone paracetamol have dual properties of drugs and drugs. &quot;The first is the nature of drugs,&quot; Tang Jianbin explained. The listing of these anesthetic drugs does not automatically equate to drugs. They will only become &quot;drugs&quot; if they flow into the illegal drug market or are smoked by drug addicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;2023 National Court Drug Crime Trial Work Conference Minutes&quot; (Kunming Conference Minutes) issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court on June 26, 2023, knowingly Criminals or drug addicts who smuggle or sell drugs and sell narcotic drugs or psychotropic drugs that are controlled by the state and have legal medical or other uses shall be convicted and punished for the crime of drug trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the minutes of the Kunming meeting, &quot;there is definite evidence to prove that for the purpose of treating diseases and other related purposes&quot;, those who privately operate anesthetic drugs with legal medical purposes are not allowed to Punished as a drug crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, whether Liao Hua still sold tramalin hydrochloride and paracetamol and oxycodone even though he knew that the other party was a drug addict has become the key to the case. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73518&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70320&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/15/3af0ad6d97.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG3215.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Chat records between Liao Hua and drug buyers. Picture provided by the interviewee&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3af0ad6d97.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258310&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liao Hua’s chat history with drug buyers. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Is it &quot;fishing for law enforcement&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the process of purchasing drugs online, Xiao Wang once revealed that he was a drug addict. The chat records between the two parties show that Xiao Wang once said: &quot;I used to skate, but now I can&#39;t buy it. I use these medicines instead! I&#39;m still a little addicted now! It&#39;s too hard to quit.&quot; Liao Hua did not reply immediately, and Xiao Wang later mentioned To: &quot;I&#39;m not sick. I used to play music and smoke marijuana, but it&#39;s hard to find it now! Use this medicine to replace it!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liao Hua argued, She didn’t know what “skating” meant, and her understanding of tramalin hydrochloride and telenine had always been limited to painkillers. She didn&#39;t pay attention to the words Xiao Wang said about addiction and difficulty in quitting. After sending the medicine, she also suggested that if Xiao Wang had pain, he could try acupuncture of traditional Chinese medicine. This was her previous pain relief experience when taking care of her father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fu Chengchen, a lawyer at Hubei Today Law Firm, believes that the key to this case is whether it can be determined that &quot;drugs&quot; were knowingly committed. Liao Hua&#39;s above statement can be used as a defense reason, but objectively Liao Hua has carried out the act of selling &quot;drugs&quot;, and what she resold is the medicine that her father has used. She is very clear about the effects of the medicine, and may even prescribe medicine before the doctor During the process, you will have a certain understanding of the nature of controlled prescription drugs. To determine that he &quot;did not know&quot; it was a drug, further evidence and the judge&#39;s discretion are needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to another chat record provided by Liao Hua, she also donated fentanyl pain relief patches to a gastric cancer patient who had undergone surgery, and the other party expressed her gratitude. . Liao Hua said that his original intention was to help patients, not to sell medicine specifically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​month after the incident, Xiao Wang, who had contacted Liao Hua to buy medicine, once again added friends in the WeChat group who wanted to transfer medicine. . Liao Hua noticed that the group photo of drugs transferred also included Tramalin Hydrochloride Sustained Release Tablets. She suspected that the man was &quot;fishing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Jianbin analyzed that when drug addicts purchase alternative drugs in drug switching groups, they actively indicate that their drug taking behavior is not consistent with common sense. In this case, these few sentences constitute the key to Liao Hua&#39;s drug trafficking crime. It is necessary to consider whether this approach is suspected of &quot;criminal inducement&quot;, that is, the party himself does not have the intention to commit the crime, and special personnel induce him to commit the crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the minutes of the Kunming meeting, evidence materials obtained when there is &quot;criminal inducement&quot; by persons who conceal their identity should be excluded. After excluding the above evidence, if the evidence in the case does not meet the standard of proof to find the seduced person guilty, a not guilty verdict shall be made in accordance with the law because the evidence is insufficient and the alleged crime cannot be established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But currently, there is no definite evidence for the &quot;fishing law enforcement&quot; questioned by Liao Hua. In the relevant transcripts, the reporter took the initiative to drive to the police station to report the crime, and did not mention his identity as a police informant. Southern Weekend reporters contacted Xiao Wang several times but received no reply. On November 13, staff from the Yangxin County Public Security Bureau stated that because the case was in the second instance, it was inconvenient to disclose relevant information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fu Chengchen reminded that private resale of drugs is not allowed without a drug business license; reselling controlled drugs involves criminal penalties, and reselling general drugs also involves serious crimes. If the amount does not meet the standard for filing a criminal case, you will also face administrative penalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the patient group, after someone forwarded Liao Hua’s case report, the group announcement read: “Dear patients and family members of patients, the country has strict regulations on painkillers. Control, contains drug content, and private trading is an illegal crime. In the light case, the person will be detained on bail pending trial, and in the serious case, he will be sentenced. Please abide by the law!&quot;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[校准航向再出发——新华社五论中美关系如何重返正轨]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260645]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 15:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At the invitation of US President Biden, President Xi Jinping will go to San Francisco, the United States from November 14th to 17th. The heads of state of China and the United States met and were invited to attend the 30th APEC Economic Leaders’ Meeting. The two heads of state will have in-depth communication on strategic, overall and directional issues related to China-US relations, as well as major issues related to world peace and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Heads of State diplomacy is the &quot;compass&quot; and &quot;fixing star&quot; of Sino-US relations. Therefore, all walks of life in China and the United States and the international community are looking forward to this meeting in San Francisco. They look forward to Sino-US relations under the guidance of the heads of state&#39;s diplomacy strategy. Get back on the right track of healthy and stable development as soon as possible. At this critical juncture, Xinhua News Agency launched a series of commentary reports on &quot;Pushing China-U.S. Relations Back on Track&quot;, calling on the United States to work with China to meet each other halfway, overcome interference, eliminate obstacles, accumulate results, create an atmosphere, and jointly promote China-U.S. relations to return to healthy and stable development. track. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;On the return to the consensus of the heads of state: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Return to Bali, to San Francisco&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81189d3f04a246747fbb029002acbbe4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81189d3f04a246747fbb029002acbbe4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258349&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;To make expectations for stable and developed Sino-US relations a reality, China and the United States need to meet each other halfway. The action road map is also very clear, which is to return to Bali and lead to San Francisco, truly implement the consensus reached by the Chinese and US presidents at the Bali meeting, expand the positive agenda of bilateral relations, reduce the negative agenda, create conditions for the San Francisco meeting, eliminate interference, and accumulate results and create an atmosphere. There is no doubt that the journey back to Bali and to San Francisco will not be smooth sailing, and we cannot rely on &quot;automatic driving&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only by returning to Bali can we lead to San Francisco. Returning to Bali is the foundation and prerequisite. In recent times, China-US relations have shown some positive signs precisely because the follow-up and implementation of the consensus reached by the two heads of state in Bali has been accelerated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We hope that the positive stance shown by the United States in recent interactions between China and the United States is not political calculation and tactical speculation, and that the verbal commitments made can become concrete policies and substantive actions. We also hope that the United States will not be fettered by domestic party disputes and the selfish interests of politicians, and will work together with China to make long-term efforts to accumulate good news and momentum in China-U.S. relations and promote the real stabilization and improvement of bilateral relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the most important set of bilateral relations in the world, Sino-US relations affect the future and destiny of mankind. During the meeting in Bali, President Xi Jinping emphasized that Sino-US relations should be viewed and handled from the perspective of grasping the general trend of the world. What is the general trend of the world? It is peace, development, cooperation, and win-win that have become the trend of the times, and no country or group of countries can dominate world affairs alone; it is the era of the &quot;Great Awakening&quot; in the global South, and human society is accelerating into a multi-polar world; it is the time for humankind to transcend We are increasingly becoming a community with a shared future in which we are among you and you are among us. At the same time, we are also facing many global challenges. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Second Discussion on Calibrating the Course of Relationship:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;China and the United States must find the right way to get along&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ac4418ea1390505b89c25926818c887.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0ac4418ea1390505b89c25926818c887.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258351&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;As two world powers, whether China and the United States can establish a correct way to get along is crucial to world peace and development and the future and destiny of mankind. For some time, the changes in the relationship between the two countries have affected the hearts of the world. Its ups and downs have shown the seriousness and complexity of Sino-US relations. It is not easy to establish a correct way for major countries to get along with each other. It will be affected by various factors. On the other hand, the two sides finally eliminated the interference and reached the important consensus of &quot;returning to Bali&quot; and &quot;facing San Francisco&quot;, which once again proved that as long as we have a responsible attitude towards history, the world and the people, we can establish a correct attitude towards each other. With rational understanding and the greatest sincerity in improving relations, Sino-US relations can develop in a positive direction, truly stabilize and get better, and return to the right track of healthy and stable development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for how China and the United States can get along correctly, President Xi Jinping has already given a clear answer, which is mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation. These three principles are important conclusions drawn from examining the ups and downs of Sino-US relations for more than half a century. They are the correct way for major countries to interact with each other in today&#39;s era. They are the key to ensuring that the two giant ships of China and the United States do not yaw, stall, or interact with each other. hit an important beacon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Without respect, there is no trust; without trust, there is no way to avoid conflicts and no real cooperation. This is an important experience accumulated in Sino-US exchanges and a basic prerequisite for bilateral relations to get back on track. Keeping the bottom line of peace is the right choice that China and the United States must make. Win-win cooperation has been the true narrative of Sino-US relations for half a century, and it is also the common goal that both sides should continue to strive for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Along the way from Bali, the recovery of Sino-US relations has been hard-won and deserves to be cherished. Facing San Francisco, both sides should draw inspiration from the past, gather forces that work toward each other, jointly explore and build a new era of Sino-US relations, and create a bright future for both China and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Three discussions on correctly defining relationships: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Competition and confrontation are not in line with the trend of the times&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3d831fec756e7799ca88717c940571ca.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width= &quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/3d831fec756e7799ca88717c940571ca.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258350&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;How Sino-US relations develop ultimately depends on the two major countries’ understanding of each other. If cooperation dominates the perception, bilateral relations will develop in a good direction; if competition dominates the perception or even defines the entire relationship by competition, antagonism will continue to increase, and there is a risk of slipping into the abyss of a &quot;new cold war.&quot; At present, the key for the United States to straighten out its relations with China is to establish a correct understanding of China, get out of zero-sum game thinking, accumulate and expand cooperation, and continue to promote the stabilization and improvement of Sino-US relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As two major countries, China and the United States have both cooperation and competition in trade, technology, diplomacy and other fields. It is not about you losing and me winning, or life and death, but you should be catching up with each other and making progress together. China does not shy away from competition nor is it afraid of competition, but competition should be fair, reasonable, and benign, with red lines and restricted areas. We cannot ignore market economic rules and basic norms of international relations, let alone use issues of core interests as a tool of competition or a means of provocation. Competition in China should be track and field events. There are tracks and rules, and you can improve your own performance while chasing each other. Just like what athletes pursue in competition is to constantly improve themselves, break through themselves, and achieve better results, rather than giving other athletes &quot;Stumbling&quot; or malicious interference, otherwise you will only be ejected for violating the rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competition is not the whole story of Sino-US relations. The economies of China and the United States are more complementary than competitive. The essence of China-US economic and trade cooperation is mutual benefit and win-win results. Under the current situation, the common interests between China and the United States have not decreased, but have increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As two major countries, China and the United States bear important responsibilities for the prosperity and development of mankind. Whether we will jointly open a new era of human development through cooperation or slide into the abyss of conflict and confrontation between major powers is the question of the century that the two countries must answer. Breaking out of the narrow perspective of who wins and who loses and pursuing the noble goal of winning together for mankind should become the common pursuit of China and the United States in the new era. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Four Discussions on Improving Cooperation Consensus: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;The earth can accommodate China and the United States’ respective development and common prosperity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bbf6559966456f470c67eaca5d5e8e57.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/bbf6559966456f470c67eaca5d5e8e57.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258348&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent times, the trend of positive interaction between China and the United States has been increasing. On the one hand, the United States continues to introduce restrictive measures on China&#39;s science and technology, economic and trade cooperation, driven by the consciousness of &quot;competition&quot;. On the other hand, it also seeks to contact China through various channels, showing signs of &quot;seeking common ground&quot; that has been rare in recent years. Fundamentally, China and the United States are the two largest economies in the world. Sino-US relations are the most important bilateral relations in the world. The economic ties between the two countries are deep and wide. Neither the two countries nor the world can afford miscalculation of intentions and confrontation and conflict. heavy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development and progress of China and the United States can become opportunities rather than challenges for each other. The economies of the two countries are more complementary than competitive. China and the United States should be mutually beneficial and win-win rather than a zero-sum game. Both sides can achieve each other&#39;s achievements. Make the pie of common interests bigger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China-US cooperation not only has existing advantages, but also has incremental advantages. Although China and the United States are each other&#39;s important trading partners, with an annual trade volume of hundreds of billions of dollars, there is still room for growth in bilateral trade, which is unmatched by bilateral economic and trade relations between the United States and other countries. Cooperation will open up more room for growth in a wider range of areas for both parties. Technology research and development exchanges and joint investments in the field of &quot;carbon neutrality&quot; will benefit both parties; the demand for medical services by the aging population in China and the United States will increase significantly in the future, and the exchange of medical technology and data will bring great value to both parties; China&#39;s ultra-large-scale medium Income groups provide immeasurable potential markets for U.S. agricultural products; both the United States and China benefit from two-way investment flows, and encouraging mutual investment will feed back the economies of both countries from multiple angles... The list of cooperation between the two sides can be very long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The vast earth can fully accommodate the respective development and common prosperity of China and the United States. The Chinese people, like the American people, are self-respecting, confident and self-reliant people, and both have the right to pursue a better life. The common interests existing between the two countries should be taken seriously. The success of each is an opportunity rather than a threat to the other. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Five arguments to consolidate the foundation of public opinion: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Gather the positive energy of Sino-US exchanges and cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/817b7b6597dfe47c2b5300188083c049.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/817b7b6597dfe47c2b5300188083c049.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258352&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Although China and the United States are separated by vast oceans, the people of China and the United States have a long history of exchanges and cooperation. &quot;The relationship between countries lies in the mutual affinity between people.&quot; Looking back on the past, the friendly people-to-people exchanges between China and the United States have never been interrupted, and the people of the two countries have also forged a deep friendship during the exchanges, which has played an important role in the development of Sino-US relations. History has fully proved that the people of China and the United States can transcend differences in systems, cultures, and languages ​​and establish a profound friendship. Mutually beneficial and win-win non-governmental exchanges between China and the United States are not only an independent choice made by the two peoples, but also an unstoppable historical trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a time when Sino-US relations are at a critical crossroads, continuous people-to-people exchanges and people-to-people exchanges and cooperation are particularly valuable, injecting a steady stream of positive energy into the healthy development of bilateral relations. The more flights, cargo ships, tourists, and students and scholars across the Pacific, the more solid the public opinion foundation, the broader the space, and the stronger the impetus for the development of China-U.S. relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both China and the United States should handle, manage, and develop bilateral relations with a responsible attitude towards the people of both countries and proceed from the well-being of the two peoples, so as to inherit and carry forward the precious values ​​for the two peoples. The legacy of friendship creates favorable atmosphere and conditions and builds a solid public opinion foundation for friendship and cooperation between the two countries. Recently, the &quot;general climate&quot; of Sino-US relations has been warming up. More and more people from all walks of life in China and the United States are calling for the two countries to expand exchanges and cooperation, working hard to promote mutual understanding and mutual understanding between the two peoples, and sending out a positive message of Sino-US people-to-people friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China-US relations still face many difficulties and challenges, and there is a long way to go to stabilize and improve relations between the two countries. Fortunately, these fundamental people-to-people ties from history still exist, and positive energy to promote the development of Sino-US relations is constantly gathering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“去中国躲一下”，缅北战区逃生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260631]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;There is a war in our hometown, let&#39;s go to China to hide.&quot; Alan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of November 10, Myanmar&#39;s &quot;post-90s generation&quot; Alan queued up at Ruili Port in Yunnan, waiting to enter the country. Compared with 7 days ago, the speed this time is much faster. &quot;On the Chinese side, it can be done in one hour.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alan’s family is in Guikai Town, Muse City, Shan State, Myanmar, and his ancestral home is Yunnan, China. In late October this year, when Alan returned to his hometown for a short stay, he unexpectedly encountered a sudden war. &quot;You could hear gunfire in the first few days, and the road to China was also blocked.&quot; It wasn&#39;t until November 4 that Alan returned to Muse Port again, where she saw many people like her queuing up to go to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the Ming and Qing Dynasties, a large number of Han immigrants have moved into northern Myanmar, gradually forming an important Chinese settlement area. It is closely connected with Yunnan, China. Many residents speak Chinese and write Chinese characters, and have a natural affinity for Chinese culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the conflict in northern Myanmar broke out, there were not a few Chinese in northern Myanmar who &quot;took refuge in China&quot; like Alan. Along the thousands-kilometer border, they either enter China or enter the China-Myanmar border refugee rescue point, hoping to experience a moment of peace here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73514&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70316&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/15/4f8ecd78b4.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Ruili.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ruili National Gate, Dehong Prefecture, Yunnan Province, China. When the entry-exit channel is open, the border residents of China and Myanmar can trade with each other across the border with the convenience of passers-by. (Li Chunhua /Picture)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/4f8ecd78b4.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;258311&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ruili National Gate, Dehong Prefecture, Yunnan Province, China. When the entry and exit channels are open, residents on the China-Myanmar border can conveniently trade across the border with their passes. (Li Chunhua/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Witnessed the fighting,&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;There were gunshots from all directions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the early morning of October 27, the Qingshuihe Brothers, formerly controlled by the Myanmar government forces, Gunfire rang out from the bridge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Kokang Voice of the Nation, a media affiliated with the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army, the Allied Forces successfully occupied the Brothers Bridge that morning. On the following 29th, the Allied Army flag was raised at the Qingshui River National Gate in Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xing’s home is a four-story building, only a hundred meters away from the Qingshui River Brothers Bridge. This bridge spans the Qingshui River Special Zone in Myanmar&#39;s Kokang and the Nandeng Special Zone in Myanmar&#39;s Wa State. It is also close to the Mengding Port in Gengma County, Yunnan, China. It is an important transportation artery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xing said that on weekdays, soldiers of the Myanmar government army can be seen patrolling and guarding the bridge, and the other side of the bridge is the territory of the Wa State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73515&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70317&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/15/1b92d02e95.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Brothers Bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In the early morning of October 27, an armed conflict broke out in the Qingshuihe Special Zone in Kokang, northern Myanmar. The Qingshuihe Brothers Bridge was one of the crossfire points. ( Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1974&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/1b92d02e95.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;258312&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the early morning of October 27, 2023, an incident occurred in the Qingshui River Special Zone in Kokang, northern Myanmar armed conflict. Qingshuihe Brothers Bridge is one of the crossfire points. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I don’t know how the fight started, but there were gunfire from all directions.” Wu Xing and her husband witnessed the firefight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was about 3 a.m. when she and her husband were awakened. Looking out the window, it was still dark outside. She felt that the sound of gunfire this time was different from before, and the sound was more powerful. They hid in the corridor for safety, and there was a firefight just outside the wall. &quot;The fighting was fierce on the bridge at that time, and I heard someone screaming.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are more than 20 families of Bamar people working here living near Wu Xing’s home. As the daylight grew brighter and the sound of gunfire faded, some workers came to explore the streets and were discovered by armed soldiers occupying the area. &quot;There is still a group of old Burmese there!&quot; Wu Xing heard someone shouting, and then intensive gunshots suddenly rang out again, and her heart skipped a beat again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Here, many Chinese refer to the Burmese as ‘Lao Burmese’.” Wu Xing saw that at the request of armed soldiers, these workers put their hands on their heads and separated men and women to check whether they were carrying weapons. After discovering that they were civilians, the workers were released. &quot;I didn&#39;t actually shoot anyone, I just wanted to scare them,&quot; Wu Xing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After dawn, soldiers in military uniforms went from door to door calling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she arrived at the door of Wu Xing&#39;s house, she quickly explained that she was a local citizen. &quot;They asked people to leave quickly, saying that Burmese military planes might come to bomb later.&quot; Wu Xing and her husband immediately set off as quickly as possible. &quot;Each person has one set of clothes and some cash. I didn&#39;t bring anything else.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the conflict, Wu Xing, who heard the news, sent his daughter and mother to Mengding in advance, and She and her husband stayed with a sense of luck. After the thrill, Wu Xing couldn&#39;t help but sigh: &quot;I really didn&#39;t expect to survive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Wu Xing and her husband have temporarily settled down in Nandeng, Wa State. It&#39;s very close to home, it only takes 10 minutes to drive back. For several days in a row, Wu Xing drove home during the day and returned to South Deng District in the afternoon. She said the home was largely undamaged, with a car and a motorcycle parked in the yard. When I went back, they were still in the same place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A few houses were bombed, but most of them are still in good condition.&quot; After finishing speaking, Wu Xing added, &quot;I don&#39;t know if they will be bombed again in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Border refuge,&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;The road was once congested&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At about 6 o&#39;clock in the morning on November 9, pale white fog enveloped the Kokang 125 refugee relief site in Myanmar. Dark blue and light green waterproof tents are lined up on the dirt floor, and a small yellow building stands tall not far away. &quot;This place was originally designed as an economic cooperation zone, but it was not developed. Now there are some unfinished buildings left,&quot; said A Wei, a volunteer at the rescue site. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Awei, the 125 refugee relief site is located in Kokang 125 Industrial Park, covering an area of ​​more than 100 acres. Soon after the conflict in northern Myanmar broke out, more than 2,000 people rushed to the rescue site. Pictures taken at the rescue site show that many children and the elderly live in simple tents outdoors. A mat is spread on the yellow mud floor to form a bed. Some families set up earthen stoves at the door to light a fire for cooking, and use colorful plastic low stools as dining tables. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Refugees who come early can live in the iron tents indoors, while those who come late can only set up tents outside.&quot; A Wei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73517&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70319&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/15/23181e76b0.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Refugee 4.png&quot; alt=&quot;In the Kokang 125 refugee relief site in Myanmar, many Burmese people only carry a small amount of luggage with them. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1434&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/23181e76b0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258313&quot; style =&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the Kokang 125 refugee rescue site in Myanmar, many Myanmar people only carry a small amount of luggage with them. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The materials at the relief site are distributed on a household basis. Each household can receive a 50-jin bag of rice, and one bag is distributed every two or three days. However, this does not meet refugee needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Kolkang is not like China. Each family here has an average of 4-5 children.” Awei said that some families pretend to receive supplies, and the management staff of the rescue points are limited, so they are often fooled. &quot;Some people ask their sons to collect it once, and their father collects it again. Some people collect it and sell it to others at a high price.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The stored rice is basically gone.&quot; Ah Wei told a Southern Weekend reporter on November 9 , the materials at the rescue site come from donations from caring people from other places, local purchases, imports from China, etc. Affected by local conflicts, the road from Lower Burma to Lao Cai is blocked, relief supplies including food cannot be transported in, and tents, rice and other supplies are in urgent need. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rescue station is close to the 125 boundary marker between China and Myanmar, and is only separated by a wall from China&#39;s Nanshan Port. For a long time, this was the main channel for Kokang border residents to enter China. &quot;The most convenient place to go from Kokang to China is Nanxian.&quot; A Wei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that Nanshan Port is located in Nanshan Town, Zhenkang County, Lincang City, Yunnan Province, China. It is only about 10 kilometers away from Laojie, the capital of Kokang. However, the entry and exit of China&#39;s Nanshan Port is temporarily closed, and many Kokang people holding passes are unable to pass through the port. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since November 13, Zhenkang has issued an announcement to promote the normalization of mutual trade between border residents. According to the announced process, starting from that day, border residents and enterprises in Zhenkang can declare in advance and receive vehicles and goods at the port. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After China&#39;s national door is opened, materials can come in from China, and the shortage of materials should be improved. However, Myanmar personnel are still unable to enter and exit through the Nanshan Port. At present, it is still only currency, not people. &quot;Awei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Chinese border, the Wa State adjacent to Kokang has also become a refuge choice for many Myanmar people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73516&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70318&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 + Picture)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1766&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/05c118ff2b.png&quot; data-key =&quot;258314&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the conflict broke out in northern Myanmar on October 27, there was an influx of people from the South Deng District of Wa State in northern Myanmar. A large number of people fled. (Photo courtesy of the interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Gong’s hometown is Qujing, Yunnan, and he is currently engaged in clothing wholesale business in the Wa State and Xiaomengla areas in northern Myanmar. After the conflict in northern Myanmar broke out, he witnessed the influx of many Burmese people from the war zone in the South Deng District of Wa State. In the video he showed to Southern Weekend reporters, a large number of people gathered at the rescue point in Nandeng, waiting for the distribution of supplies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The fighting started on the morning of the 27th, and many people ran to Nandeng on the afternoon of the 27th.&quot; Mr. Gong said that the fleeing people were placed in an open square, and Wa State Army soldiers were responsible for registration personnel, maintain order, and distribute supplies free of charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People come by car if they can, and ordinary people ride motorcycles or walk. Maybe because of the sudden incident, many people are empty-handed. Some people go out with only a blanket.&quot; Mr. Gong said. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the large number of people fleeing from the Kokang war zone, roads in the neighboring Wa State were once congested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Voice of the Kokang Nation&quot; on November 7, there have been at least 400 vehicles on the road from Shiyuanzi to Changjie Street in the past few days. About 500 to 600 people wanted to seek refuge in neighboring areas but were trapped. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the graphic and text materials it released, a winding &quot;vehicle train&quot; was driving towards the Wa State on a cement road about three to four meters wide. Eager people opened the car doors and stood on the road in groups of three or three, stretching their necks to look at the &quot;dragon head&quot; in the distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xing, who also moved to Wa State, lamented, &quot;Fortunately we left early, otherwise we would have been stuck on the road.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;I will get passes for my parents in the future.&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Alan has eight brothers and sisters, ranking second in the family. When he was a child, Alan&#39;s father burned charcoal to feed his family and lived in the mountains all year round. Alan and his brothers and sisters helped their father carry charcoal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are no protective measures. For example, you go in first and hand out the charcoal piece by piece. If you can&#39;t hold it anymore, let me go in instead.&quot; Alan remembered that when he came out of the charcoal kiln, his whole body was filled with excitement. Stained black by charcoal ash, &quot;even the phlegm coughed out is black.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because his family was poor, Alan only went to elementary school and worked in Ruili since he was 16 years old. In her hometown, many girls of the same age choose to work in China. Compared with big cities in Myanmar such as Yangon and Naypyitaw, Ruili is “closer and has higher wages.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Alan is the only one in the family who has a China-Myanmar border pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After one entry and exit, she can stay in Ruili for seven days; after seven days, she will return to Muse, Myanmar. After completing one entry and exit, she can stay for another seven days. By continually &quot;renewing&quot; the pass, Alan can travel across borders without having to apply for a passport, which has a more cumbersome process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is only a few tens of meters between China’s Ruili National Gate and Myanmar’s Muse National Gate. You can see the China-Myanmar boundary monument No. 81 on the way. For Alan, this road is all too familiar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;First pass through the Chinese gate, go to Myanmar (national gate) to get a stamp. Then come to China (national gate) to get a stamp, and it&#39;s done.&quot; Alan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While working in Ruili, Alan initially worked as a waiter in a Chinese-run restaurant. Because she knows Chinese characters and speaks Chinese, her salary is always higher than that of other fellow Burmese who came with her. Over the past ten years, her salary has increased from 200 yuan per month to 2,000 yuan per month. Most of the money earned goes to support the family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the rise of live streaming platforms in recent years, Alan began to share his life on social platforms and at the same time sell e-commerce products. Every once in a while, she sends orders for tea, honey, souvenirs and other products from Myanmar to all parts of the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many Chinese brothers and sisters support me. I am especially grateful to them.” Alan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the entry and exit channels are open, residents on the China-Myanmar border can conveniently trade across the border with their passes. Myanmar&#39;s rice, sugar, rubber, beef, tea and other agricultural and sideline products are sold to the mainland, and businessmen earn the price difference. Myanmar’s jadeite and other mineral deposits are also distributed here. For residents on the China-Myanmar border, this represents unlimited business opportunities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it costs about hundreds of thousands to 500,000 kyats to get a pass, which amounts to a few hundred to a thousand yuan in total. Due to financial difficulties at home, Alan&#39;s family has never applied for additional documents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing in his hometown due to the war, Alan felt very tortured. When I was sleeping, I was worried whether a gun would suddenly fall on my head. It wasn&#39;t until she returned to Ruili that she could have a good night&#39;s sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the conflict in northern Myanmar, Alan firmly decided to apply for certificates for his parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m thinking of a way to spend money this time.&quot; Alan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“No party can afford to offend”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the ethnic list of Myanmar formulated in 1983, the Kokang ethnic group was listed as one of the 135 ethnic groups by the Myanmar government. Specifically refers to people living in the Kokang area in northern Shan State, Myanmar, adjacent to Zhenkang and Gengma counties in Lincang City, Yunnan Province, China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Shilu, a scholar of Chinese Burmese studies, pointed out in the article &quot;The &quot;Kokang Tribe&quot; in Myanmar: Ethnic Name, Origin, Situation and Transnational Interaction&quot; that the name &quot;Kokang Tribe&quot; is very unscientific from an ethnological perspective. Yes, these overseas Chinese and Chinese people called the &quot;Kokang ethnic group&quot; should actually be the &quot;Yunnan Gang&quot; among overseas Chinese and Chinese people in Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the private sector, many Chinese in northern Myanmar habitually call themselves &quot;Han people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Alan’s hometown still sees familiar Han customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, there are couplets with gold characters on a red background on the door frame of the house, a tablet with the words &quot;Lord of Heaven and Earth, Lord, Prince and Master&quot; stands prominently in the middle hall, and there is an incense burner in front of the stage. Alan said that every lunar month and half, the Spring Festival, etc., the whole family would place tributes and solemnly kneel down and pray here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alan’s grandfather passed away very early, and his grandmother told Alan that their ancestral home was Longling County, Baoshan, Yunnan, China. Alan has never been to Longling, his ancestral home, and has no impression of it. She said that the Chinese city she most wanted to visit was Beijing, and one day she wanted to see Tiananmen Square. &quot;We all read Chinese books, and we have been yearning for them since we were young.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Myanmar formally became independent from the British Commonwealth in 1948, dozens of local armed groups in the country engaged in long-term armed confrontation with the central government in border areas, seeking independence. The Kokang, Wa State, Myanmar Kachin State Second Special Administrative Region and Myanmar Eastern Shan State Fourth Special Administrative Region on the northern China-Myanmar border are controlled by four powerful armed forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, the central government of Myanmar did not really control the region. Amid multiple conflicts, local armed forces in northern Myanmar have taken turns taking charge, and fighting continues in the region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the Myanmar government has launched attacks on local ethnic armed forces in northern Myanmar, and its regional control has gradually increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 25, 2011, the Kokang region was officially renamed &quot;Kokang Autonomous Region in Northern Shan State, Myanmar&quot;. On March 26, 2015, the Myanmar military announced that it controlled the entire Kokang region and adopted a policy of integrating the Kokang region into Myanmar, vigorously introducing Burmese teachers and using Burmese language teaching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We have read Chinese books and spoken Chinese since we were young. But we are Burmese and we must listen to the Burmese government.” Wu Xing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just eight years later, artillery fire broke out again in the Kokang area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Voice of the Kokang Nation&quot; on November 13, 18 days since the start of the &quot;10.27 Military Operation&quot;, the coalition forces have captured towns such as Qingshuihe, Menggu, Gunong and recaptured large and small military strongholds. 141, and a batch of weapons and ammunition were seized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Frequent wars and changes in local political power have kept the people secretive about the forces of all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Kokang area fights a small war every three years and a major war every five years.&quot; Ah Wei is less than 50 years old and has experienced four or five wars. He hoped that the media would remain neutral when reporting on refugee relief sites, because “no one can afford to offend any party.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In our place, dying of a person is like stepping on an ant. If you have no power and no friends, you are nothing.&quot; A Wei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;【Overview of Shan State】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Shan State is located in eastern Myanmar, bordering Xishuangbanna, Yunnan Province, China to the north, Laos and Thailand to the east, and Kachin State and Kachin State to the west. Kayah State, Karen State, Mandalay Province, and Sagaing Province are connected. Shan State is the largest and most populous state in Myanmar, and its capital is Taunggyi City. Historically, Chinese immigrants from Yunnan, China, immigrated in large numbers, gradually forming a Chinese settlement in northern Myanmar. There are armed forces advocating independence in southern Shan State. The eastern border with Thailand and Laos is the famous Golden Triangle area. The northern border with China is the main settlement area of ​​the Kokang (Han) ethnic group in Myanmar. From 1986 to 1989, the area formerly under the jurisdiction of the armed forces was divided into four parts, becoming the Shan State First Special Administrative Region of Myanmar (Kokang), the Shan State Second Special Administrative Region of Myanmar (Wa State), the Kachin State First Special Administrative Region of Myanmar, and the eastern part of Shan State of Myanmar. The Fourth Special Zone (Mongla). In recent years, a large influx of new Chinese immigrants has made the social ecology more complex. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“不清剿电诈决不收兵”，揭秘中国警方通缉的缅北电诈家族]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At noon on November 12, the Criminal Investigation Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security issued a notice to publicly arrest Ming Xuechang, an important leader of a fraud group in northern Myanmar. , Ming Guoping, Ming Julan and Ming Zhenzhen have attracted great attention from domestic and foreign public opinion. The reason why this news is attracting attention is related to Ming Xuechang’s identity. According to public reports, Ming Xuechang is an &quot;old leader&quot; of the Kokang Autonomous Region in northern Myanmar. He has held important positions in Kokang for a long time. He once served as the county magistrate of Kokang. In 2011, he was appointed as a member of the Shan State Parliament, Vice Chairman of the Kokang Autonomous Region, and the Daily Working Committee and Leadership Committee of the Kokang Autonomous Region. committee member. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/8d368b52f3d66b9c9f41a4c1854a62a7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/8d368b52f3d66b9c9f41a4c1854a62a7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258337&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; Also wanted by the police this time are Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen, all children of Ming Xuechang. The Ming family is huge in Kokang and is said to be second only to the four major Kokang families (one theory One of the four major families). In the past few days, news about the Ming family has continued to ferment. It has been circulated on the Internet that multiple people were shot and buried alive in Kokang on October 20. The location was located in the Crouching Mountain Manor area controlled by the Ming Xuechang family in Laojie, the capital of Kokang. At the same time, photos of Ming Xuechang’s grandson Ming Guangzhong receiving the admission notice from Peking University and many celebration pictures of Ming Xuechang and Ming Guangzhong at the university entrance banquet were circulated online. The Publicity Department of Peking University responded on the 13th that Ming Guangzhong was not a Peking University student, and there was no record of his application to Peking University on the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Ming Xuechang and the Ming family behind him&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Kokang Autonomous Region in northern Myanmar borders Yunnan Province, with a population of about 140,000, mostly Han Chinese. Historically, it has a deep connection with China. In 2011, the Kokang Autonomous Region was formally established as part of Shan State and is now controlled by the Myanmar military junta. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the 69-year-old Ming Xuechang joined the Communist Party of Myanmar following the Kokang warlord Peng Jiasheng in his early days and participated in the founding of the Myanmar National Democratic Alliance Army. After the internal affairs of Myanmar changed, he was appointed by the Myanmar military government as the head of Kokang County. In 2011, he served as a member of the Shan State Parliament, Vice Chairman of the Kokang Autonomous Region, and a member of the Daily Work Committee and Leadership Committee of the Kokang Autonomous Region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the Chinese Ministry of Public Security issued the wanted order, Ming Xuechang attended a local meeting to deal with telecommunications network fraud as a senior leader in the Kokang area. According to local media reports on October 26, “In order to further implement work requirements and strengthen the crackdown on various derivative illegal activities such as telecommunications fraud, the autonomous region held a special working meeting. Autonomous Region Chairman Li Zhengfu, committee members Lieutenant Colonel Jue Juewu, Bai Yingneng, Wu Musuodan, Sheriff Nulunwu, and heads of departments at all levels, security units, and township/community heads attended the meeting. In addition, veteran regional leaders Ming Xuechang, Zhao Deqiang, and Liu Zhengxiang attended the meeting.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;This was also the last time Ming Xuechang appeared in public reports. According to the arrest warrant issued by the Ministry of Public Security of China, three people from the Ming family are also wanted this time. 42-year-old Ming Guoping is the son of Ming Xuechang and is the captain of the militia squadron of Shiyuanzi Township, Kokang Autonomous Region. Ming Julan, who is the same age as Ming Xuechang, is the daughter of Ming Xuechang. There is also a member of the Ming family, 27-year-old Ming Zhenzhen. Some media reported that she is Ming Xuechang&#39;s granddaughter. It is worth mentioning that the registered residences of Ming Julan and Ming Zhenzhen are both in Lincang, Yunnan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81afe7325cd8d48ecb33865a1cd59709.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;592&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/81afe7325cd8d48ecb33865a1cd59709.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258336&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ming Xuechang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Kokang area, the Ming family is very powerful. Local media in Myanmar reported that Ming Xuechang is One of the richest men in the area, the Ming family has close ties with the four major families. Kokang is known as the four major families, referring to the Bai Suocheng family, Wei Chaoren family, Liu Guoxi family and Liu Abao family. The Ming family is considered a &quot;rising star&quot;. Media reports stated that the mining, casino, and real estate operations in Kokang Old Street are all controlled by four major families, and the four major families are also the backers of electronic fraud groups in the Kokang area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The arrest warrant issued by the Ministry of Public Security of China directly pointed out that the criminal group headed by Ming Xuechang has long organized and opened fraud dens, openly armed fraud, and carried out telecommunications network fraud criminal activities targeting Chinese citizens. The amount of fraud was Huge, and also suspected of multiple serious violent crimes such as intentional homicide, intentional injury, and illegal detention. The notice urged him to recognize the situation clearly, step back from the brink, voluntarily surrender, and strive for leniency. The police wanted order also stated that a reward of 100,000 to 500,000 yuan will be given to those who provide effective clues and assist in the arrest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just after the wanted order was issued, it was circulated on the Internet that multiple people were shot and buried alive in Kokang on October 20. The location was located in the Crouching Mountain Manor area controlled by the Ming Xuechang family in Laojie, the capital of Kokang. At the same time, the confession clips of many arrested telecom fraud leaders have attracted attention on the Internet, including Wei Qingtao, the second son of the Wei family, a member of the four major Kokang families, Liu Zhengqi, Liu Abao&#39;s brother, and Bi Huijun, the son-in-law of Ming Xuechang, who all went abroad to confess and urged their families to voluntarily surrender. , saying that China “will never withdraw its troops until it eliminates telecommunications fraud.” The Information Bureau of Myanmar&#39;s Wa State responded to media reporters on the 13th and stated that the above three people were indeed members of electronic fraud and were currently under the control of judicial agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The civil war broke out in northern Myanmar and the situation was tense. The Myanmar authorities promised to completely eliminate e-mail fraud by the end of the year&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, some ethnic Chinese minorities in northern Myanmar Ethnic armed forces are fighting the military junta, and the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs said that at least 6,000 people have been displaced since the conflict broke out on October 27. The leader of the Chinese ethnic minority armed forces, Peng Deren, is the son of Peng Jiasheng. He claimed that the war was to eliminate telecommunications network fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said that China is highly concerned about the conflict situation in northern Myanmar and urges all parties to immediately cease fire and end the war. &quot;Insist on resolving differences through dialogue and consultation through peaceful means to avoid escalation of the situation, and Take practical and effective measures to ensure the security and stability of the China-Myanmar border.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the video circulated on the Internet, Wei Qingtao, the second son of the Wei family of the four major families, also said in his confession that war is currently breaking out in Myanmar and may cause disaster at any time. He suffered serious casualties and urged his family to seize the last opportunity to open the park and return the Chinese people in the park to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV News, since February 2021, domestic tensions in Myanmar have intensified, providing more opportunities for telecom fraud groups to settle in northern and eastern Myanmar and form a &quot;community of interests&quot; with local forces. space. In Myawaddy on the Myanmar-Thailand border alone, there are hundreds of fraud parks. Including fraud groups entrenched in parts of northern Myanmar, there are at least 1,000 parks in total, and more than 100,000 people commit telecom fraud every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The areas where telecom fraud groups gather in northern and eastern Myanmar are only a very small part of Myanmar’s land area, and are mostly areas controlled by ethnic minority local armed forces. However, they have dealt a fatal blow to Myanmar’s national image. &quot;CCTV reported this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the Chinese government has continuously increased cooperation and carried out joint law enforcement operations with Myanmar, Thailand and other countries to severely crack down on telecommunications network fraud in accordance with the law. Especially since this year, China has been even more aggressive. Recently, the police of China, Thailand, Myanmar and Laos launched a special joint operation to combat gambling fraud groups, aiming to severely crack down on telecommunications network fraud and online gambling crimes in the region, and resolutely reverse the high incidence of human trafficking, kidnapping, detention and other crimes. According to incomplete statistics, since September this year, many batches of telecom fraudsters have been escorted back to China from Myanmar, Cambodia and other overseas countries. On October 14, 2,349 telecom fraudsters were transferred from Myanmar to China, setting a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as the war broke out, on October 31, Min Aung Hlaing, Chairman of the National Governing Council of Myanmar, met with State Councilor and Minister of Public Security Wang Xiaohong in Nay Pyi Taw. Wang Xiaohong mentioned that the law enforcement and security departments of the two countries will strengthen cooperation in the fields of combating online gambling fraud, counter-terrorism, drug control, law enforcement in the Mekong River Basin, and the security of major projects, so as to safeguard the security and development interests of the two countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some analysts believe that this series of actions demonstrates China’s determination to crack down on telecommunications network fraud. Recently, Zaw Min Tun, spokesperson of the Myanmar National Governing Council, also stated that the Myanmar authorities are determined to completely eliminate online gambling and online fraud in northern Myanmar by the end of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[食品还是药品？争议中医院药膳“生意”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260623]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/5a2c29f80e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/15/5a2c29f80e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258298&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;TCM hospitals are competing to expand The business field and entry into the &quot;business&quot; of medicinal diet are related to the traditional Chinese medicine theory of &quot;medicine and food come from the same source&quot; that has been passed down for thousands of years and people&#39;s increasing awareness of &quot;health blood&quot;. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;I didn&#39;t expect that the one that beats milk tea is the sour plum soup in a traditional Chinese medicine hospital&quot; &quot;Who wouldn&#39;t know how to make sour plum soup that only costs one yuan a post&quot;... Social The &quot;Amway posts&quot; posted by netizens on the platform paralyzed the convenient online dispensing system of the Zhejiang Provincial Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine overnight - the 1.34 yuan per post of sour plum soup tea bags were sold out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Go to a Chinese medicine pharmacy to prepare sour plum soup.&quot; This craze set off on social platforms in the autumn of 2023 is not the first time that Chinese herbal tea drinks have made an appearance. As early as 2020, Guangxi Liuzhou Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital attracted attention with the traditional Chinese medicine milk tea launched by the East Hospital Medicinal Food Shop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;After becoming popular on the Internet, Zhejiang Provincial Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital has successively launched Qiuzao Moistening Drink, Three Treasures for Soup, and Winter Tonic Paste Recipes. Among them, the tea soup recipe has a single price Within 20 yuan; Liuzhou Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital has updated the menu of the medicated diet shop and developed six categories of medicated diet, including medicated soup, stir-fry, porridge, herbal tea, pastries, and noodles, with prices ranging from 2 to 55 yuan. wait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The difference is that the former’s medicated diet products are sold online in the form of medicinal material packages on the Internet hospital platform and are subject to drug management; the latter’s medicated diet products are sold by the Sanfang Catering Company sells offline and operates as a food business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to Southern Weekend reporters, in addition to the above two traditional Chinese medicine hospitals, a large number of domestic traditional Chinese medicine hospitals have sold traditional Chinese medicine teas, ointments and other in-hospital agreements on the Internet hospital platform. . These prescriptions are usually labeled with clear efficacy and contraindications, and consumers can place orders by themselves without the need for a face-to-face consultation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Traditional Chinese medicine hospitals are competing to expand their business areas and enter the &quot;business&quot; of medicinal diet. This is in line with the traditional Chinese medicine theory of &quot;medicine and food come from the same source&quot; that has been passed down for thousands of years and people&#39;s increasing awareness of &quot;health preservation&quot;. &quot;bloodline&quot;. The expansion of the medicated diet business has objectively driven an increase in the number of offline TCM clinic visits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, in reality, the business of medicated diet also faces an embarrassing situation due to the &quot;individuation of medicine and food&quot; - whether the product is positioned as a medicine or a food, it affects different business entities. , material selection and regulatory standards also affect consumer expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Health-preserving medicated diet is different from clinical medicated diet. It must use medicinal materials with the same source of medicine and food approved by the National Health Commission, and the efficacy cannot be discussed. Strictly speaking &quot;It cannot be a clinical medicated diet that has clear therapeutic effects without a doctor&#39;s consultation and syndrome differentiation.&quot; Song Lucheng, chairman of the Medicinal Diet Branch of the Chinese Society of Chinese Medicine and director of the Department of Traditional Chinese Medicine at the First Affiliated Hospital of Shandong First Medical University, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Suddenly popular a year after its launch, with 80% of female users&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Sour Plum Soup was caught off guard by its popularity &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;On the day before it was removed from the shelves, the single-day sales of sour plum soup even exceeded 40,000 posts.&quot; Lu Xiaoai, director of the medical department of Zhejiang Provincial Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, told Southern Weekend reporters. You must know that before leaving the circle, the hospital’s average daily orders for sour plum soup were only a few hundred orders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In fact, as early as a year ago, on May 31, 2022, Zhejiang Provincial Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine began to launch traditional Chinese medicine tea drinks on the Internet hospital platform, including health care products. There are many tea-based prescriptions for dispelling dampness in the spleen, calming the liver and lowering lipids, improving eyesight and moisturizing the eyes. The prescriptions are developed by the studio of famous doctors in the hospital, and the price of a single prescription ranges from 2 to 17 yuan. Sour plum soup will be launched in the summer of 2022. It is composed of four medicinal materials: black plum, hawthorn, licorice and tangerine peel. The prescription details page shows that the prescription has the effects of relieving heat, promoting body fluids and appetizing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;It suddenly became popular a year after its launch. Lu Xiaoai believes that this reflects the current increase in enthusiasm among young people for health care. Sleep disorders, low back pain, cough, irregular menstruation, and fatigue syndrome are the top five diseases treated by Zhejiang Provincial Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine in September 2023. They are all common sub-health problems for office workers. Traditional Chinese medicine teas are launched to target common diseases and meet the health needs of young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Data provided by Zhejiang Provincial Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine shows that the users rushing to buy sour plum soup this time are mainly young women, with over 80% of female users aged 17-30 years old. Users account for 71.25%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Wang Ci, who lives in Hangzhou, immediately bought the sour plum soup from the Zhejiang Provincial Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, &quot;I thought it could be used as a substitute for milk tea, which is healthy and delicious.&quot; Two years ago, 28-year-old Wang Ci was diagnosed with hyperthyroidism due to endocrine disorders. Since then, she has been making tea, making soups, and using medicinal foods to maintain her health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Hua Bichun, vice president of the Medicinal Diet Research Professional Committee of the World Federation of Chinese Medicine Societies, professor and MD of Fujian University of Chinese Medicine, told Southern Weekend reporters that traditional Chinese medicine Medicinal diet has always been one of the application forms of traditional Chinese medicine. Under the guidance of traditional Chinese medicine theory and through the differentiation of syndromes and diet by TCM doctors, it is often popular in different forms in different regions in different eras, and has penetrated into people&#39;s daily life and the methods of disease prevention, treatment, rehabilitation and health preservation. In every aspect. &quot;The basic characteristics of traditional Chinese medicine are holistic view and syndrome differentiation and treatment. Traditional Chinese Medicine Dietetics is guided by the theory of Traditional Chinese Medicine, studying the theories and experiences of traditional Chinese medicinal diets and dietary nutrition, and sorting and improving them to make them compatible with modern nutritional therapy and nutritional hygiene. A practical science in medical care that combines science and technology.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;The basic method of treating diseases in traditional Chinese medicine is to use appropriate combinations of drugs, food properties and flavors to form a certain Use prescriptions to treat diseases. In addition to issuing clinical prescriptions, doctors also need to tell patients what they should and should not eat,&quot; Song Lucheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;From online to offline&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;TCM hospitals are engaged in the &quot;business&quot; of medicinal diet and It’s not new. What’s new is the business model. Currently, there are two main business models: Internet hospitals and catering stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The promotion of medicated diets on the Internet hospital platform has a lot to do with the development of Internet medical services in public hospitals across the country during the epidemic.当时，全国大批中医院利用互联网医院平台推出新冠预防制剂，打通了线上开单、配送到家的在线购药流程，并将其沿用至药膳业务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;比如，河北省中医院曾在2022年12月推出“防疫食疗方”系列“药膳包”“发酵膏”；厦门市中医院在2022年11月推出中药防疫方，并于2023年4月上线健脾祛脂茶；推出酸梅汤之前，浙江省中医院也曾在互联网医院平台上线两个防疫药方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;除了线上开方，药膳推广更贴近市场化经营的路径，是在线下打造药膳餐饮品牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;柳州市中医医院治未病中心主任刘静告诉南方周末记者，“食药同园”药膳坊开业三年以来，结合广西道地药材和地方气候特色，推出了菜、汤、粥、糕点、饮品、面点等不同形式的药膳产品，其中中药奶茶最受年轻人好评。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“中医院不能直接经营餐饮业务盈利，因此我们委托有资质的第三方餐饮企业生产药膳产品，所有产品配方都由治未病中心药膳团队研发，药材也由医院申领，保证药材质量。”刘静说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;刘静介绍，“食药同园”药膳坊的对面是柳州中医医院的营养科门诊，提供营养筛查与评估、营养咨询与指导等服务，“前来就餐的消费者如果追求适合个人体质、更有针对性的药膳，可以来门诊进一步咨询”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;线上购药膳，规定不一&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;药膳的定位不同，经营路径亦不同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;互联网医院平台推出的药膳产品定位为药品。以浙江省中医院为例，中药茶饮的药方详情页明确标注了药品名称、适应症、用法用量、禁忌和注意事项。在药材选用上，为保证药方的安全性和普适性，以药食同源物质为主，但也会选择相对平和的临床药材。消费者下单茶饮时，系统自动跳转在线复诊处方，由便捷配药门诊医师开具相关诊断信息后方能进入支付页面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;作为药品的药膳，如何辨证施治？浙江省中医院为每款协定方设置包含三道问题的问卷，用于判断消费者体质。如勾选项与答案不符，则会弹出“暂时不推荐购买，建议去医院就诊”的提示信息。不过，南方周末记者发现，用户可不限次数进入页面重新作答。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;对此，浙江省中医院在产品宣传文章中曾提示消费者“设置题目的初衷是为了辨别是否适合这个药方，不要为了跟风而去尝试各种答案，按需选择合适的就好”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0c6134d93a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1989&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/0c6134d93a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258299&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;浙江省中医院线上购买中药茶饮，需先回答三道问题辨认体质。浙江省中医院互联网平台便捷购药系统截图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;南方周末记者发现，目前不同中医院对于线上购买药膳的管理规定并不统一。如广州中医药大学附属清远中医院的自助购药系统就要求“仅复诊者才能进行线上购药”，如系统未能读取近三个月的院内就诊记录，则无法线上开具药膳方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;食品药膳：药材受限、不提功效&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;相比中医院里定位为药品的药膳，市场更为广阔的药膳产业中，药膳通常作为食品经营。以北京同仁堂、郑州东济堂、上海童涵春堂为代表的中药房是药膳产业的主体，少数中医院则借助第三方公司开拓食品药膳业务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;无论中药房或中医院，经营食品药膳都面临药材选用和疗效宣传的限制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;a>;2002&lt;/a>;年以来，国家卫健委曾多次更新“按照传统既是食品又是中药材的物质目录”，确定了共计102种“药食同源”物质（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;其中包含9种试点物质&lt;/span>;）。按照规定，面向大众的药膳食品只能选用药食同源目录内的药材作为原料。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中国药膳研究会会长杨锐在接受中国小康网专访时曾指出，药膳是一个“常在河边走”的产业，一不小心就容易触碰“食品中添加药品”或者“非法行医”的法律红线，但目前“按照传统既是食品又是中药材的物质目录”还不够健全和完善，很多既符合老百姓传统食用习惯又属于中药材的物质，例如辣椒、大蒜、黑豆等列入了《中国药典》，但却没有进入食药物质目录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;此外，养生药膳食品不同于药品，不能标注疗效。北京市海淀区市场监督管理局广告监督管理科副科长徐莹向南方周末记者表示，根据《中华人民共和国广告法》第十七条、第四十六条，以及《药品、医疗器械、保健食品、特殊医学用途配方食品广告审查管理暂行办法》第二条规定，药品不能随便做广告，药品广告必须经药监部门审查后发布，非药品的食品则禁止宣传疗效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;柳州市中医医院药膳坊营业之初，曾在菜单上标注了药膳的对应功效，经有关部门提醒后，目前的菜单仅保留主要成分，菜品名称也删除了涉及功效的词汇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;刘静认为，药膳的科普宣传和广告宣传应有所区别，找到平衡点。医疗机构对于药膳的科普宣传无法提及功效，可能让药膳推广陷入尴尬的境地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;宋鲁成注意到，有些药膳餐饮商为了规避监管，会巧妙地改变说法，“比如针对宫寒症状的药膳产品，就通过&#39;关心大姨妈&#39;这样的词汇暗示消费者”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;广东省食品安全保障促进会副会长、食品产业分析师朱丹蓬向南方周末记者表示，虽然以酸梅汤为代表的中药茶饮消费频次提升，但药膳餐饮产业目前尚无国标出台，以目前的发展水平很难形成大规模市场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/07ef06f8e4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;818&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/07ef06f8e4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258300&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;2022年10月29日，南宁，药膳展示现场。黄艳梅(广西分社)/中新社/视觉中国&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“一个人的美食，可能是另一人的毒药”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;既是食品又是药品的药膳，也需要消费者正确认识和对待。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;中药酸梅汤走红后，顾华跟风在浙江省中医院下单了健脾祛湿饮，服用完10帖20包，顾华发现自己全身乏力、脾胃虚弱的症状并未得到改善，“原本以为喝完会健康一点，没想到毫无效果”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“这些药膳产品虽然定位为药品，实际上仍以养生效果为主。就好比打仗，药膳和临床用药都朝着同一个目标，但一个是步枪，一个是大炮，打击的效果不一样。”浙江省中医院中医内科主任、中医师夏永良说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;多位中医师向南方周末记者表示，中医药膳讲求“因时、因地、因人制宜”，切忌盲目跟风。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;比如，同样是睡眠不好，有人需要清热安神，有人需要补气血，有人需要活血化瘀&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;，只有明确自身体质后服用合适药材的茶饮，才能改善症状。四川和浙江两地同样湿气深重，但人在四川吃麻辣食物可以祛湿，到了浙江就不行，这是地域湿寒和湿热的区别。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;酸梅汤风行时，“喝中药茶饮能不能加冰”曾被广泛讨论，夏永良认为，这需要根据个人体质和茶饮用药的药性来决定，“如果是体热人群服用凉茶这样清热去火的饮料，可以适当放冰。但如果茶饮性温而个人体质偏寒，加冰就会降低药效”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;“一个人的美食，可能是另一人的毒药。”宋鲁成说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，王慈、顾华为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[育人集团贷款上班：企业巧立名目规避非法集资，员工贪图“利息差”难洗合谋嫌疑丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260591]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;今年9月，河南郑州育人教育集团“让员工贷款养企业”一事曾引发广泛关注。当时集团多名员工向《红星新闻》反映，该集团从2019年起，一直让员工向郑州市农村商业银行以“装修贷”的名义每人贷款10万到15万元供企业使用，贷款总额2000余万元。另据9月央视财经频道报道，该集团财务发布的统计表格显示，2021年1月，集团有181人共贷款2602万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;育人集团曾向员工承诺以校舍与土地提供抵押担保，借来的钱用于“共渡难关”，提出的优厚条件是以1.33%的标准向员工支付每月贷款利息，高于银行的0.66%，同时在子女上学、房产购买上给予员工福利。而从2021年底以来，集团经常停发利息，导致一部分贷款已经逾期、征信受损，还有一部分员工的贷款也将到期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年8月2日，7名员工代表就违法放贷问题向国家金融监管总局河南监管局进行了举报。近日，国家金融监管总局河南监管局出具回复员工代表的调查意见书。经调查，郑州农商行在发放郑州育人教育集团员工消费贷款过程中，存在违反贷款“三查”规定和信贷管理不到位问题。部分员工违反合同约定改变贷款用途，协助育人集团挪用贷款资金并获取一定的经济收益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这并不是“贷款上班”第一次成为新闻。 2022年9月，兰州公交集团提出要员工以个人名义向银行贷款用于解决6到9月份工资，公交公司提供连带担保，负责按月结息、到期还本；2023年3月，国美也推出了“员工贷款”计划，引入民生银行信用贷缓解员工的欠薪压力，在公司发薪之前，每月为员工报销3万元以内的贷款利息，超出部分员工自行负责。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兰州公交“贷款上班”是为了给员工发工资，国美集团的“员工贷款”是为了缓解欠薪压力，育人集团的“贷款上班”则是笼统的“供集团使用”：让员工以个人名义贷款，然后员工将贷来的钱又交给企业，企业承诺以高于银行的利息向员工偿还这笔钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纵观事件全过程，首先要问的就是，为何企业不以自身名义进行社会融资，反而却要找员工借钱？这里面可能有经营风险较大、缺乏有效担保抵押品、企业信用低等问题。而如果企业直接向员工借钱，那么就是纯粹的民间借贷关系，企业需要承担偿还责任，还可能涉嫌非法集资罪。育人集团鼓动员工以个人名义向银行申请“装修贷”，等于是利用员工有正式工作单位、信用记录完整的条件，将员工的个人贷款资格拿来供自己使用，不仅成功地向银行贷到了钱，借款人还是员工而非企业，可谓“用心良苦”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，员工为何愿意帮助企业贷款“共渡难关”？ “部分员工违反合同约定改变贷款用途，协助育人集团挪用贷款资金并获取一定的经济收益”，金融监管局在调查意见书中的这句话显示，事件中的员工并非完全是浑然不觉的“被贷款”，至少有部分员工了解贷款资金的去向，但仍然与企业合谋完成了贷款。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些员工是为了贪图那点“利息差”，还是为了保住公司也保住自己的职位，或两者兼而有之，目前看都有可能，员工与企业之间形成了实质上的共谋关系。金融监管局在意见书中“举报人提出的将借款主体变更为郑州育人教育集团的诉求属于民事纠纷，应按照民事法律法规规定通过协商或诉讼途径解决”的表述，也等于是在表明，员工既然在借款合同上签字盖章，就应承担责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅如此，当事员工甚至可能涉嫌违法犯罪。根据《中华人民共和国刑法》第175条，以转贷牟利为目的，套取金融机构信贷资金高利转贷他人，构成高利转贷罪，处以拘役、徒刑或罚金；而根据最高法《关于审理民间借贷案件适用法律若干问题的规定》第13条，育人集团与员工之间签订的“专项贷款使用协议”恐怕也有很大概率属于无效合同，双方的纠纷还需要通过协商或诉讼途径解决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纵观这起事件，企业巧立名目让员工以个人信用为企业贷款，银行疏于审核借贷人资格与贷款用途，员工贪图所谓“利差”与目前的职位，监管方疏于把关，各方在事件中均负有责任。 “贷款上班”事件也显示，育人集团员工与企业之间的关系出现了问题。试问，一家企业已经窘迫到需要拿员工的名义贷款来救活自己，员工保住这份工作的意义又在哪里？ &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除非有员工持股计划或是期权计划，否则员工与企业之间仅仅只存在普通的雇佣关系。育人集团的“贷款上班”称得上是巧立名目，这种行为既规避了非法集资，也不是公司内部的理财产品，也不算企业直接向员工借款，更不是什么员工持股计划或是期权计划，倒像是员工负债计划，结果也是呈现出企业与员工双输的局面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这起事件中“员工贷款养企业”的行为更像是让自己沦为了企业的人质，贪图“利息差”的表现也称得上是“利令智昏”。员工与企业之间应是权责对等的雇佣关系，超越法定权责之外的“谈钱”或“谈感情”，都是站不住脚的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>