<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[中美两国发表关于加强合作应对气候危机的阳光之乡声明]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260627]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 10:33:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 15, China and the United States issued the Sunshine Land Statement on Strengthening Cooperation to Address the Climate Crisis. Statement The full text is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Sunshine Land Statement on Strengthening Cooperation to Address the Climate Crisis&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Revisit President Xi Jinping and President Joseph Biden met in Bali, Indonesia, and China and the United States reaffirmed their commitment to cooperation and working with other countries to address the climate crisis. To this end, China’s Special Envoy for Climate Change Xie Zhenhua and the U.S. President’s Special Envoy for Climate Issues John Kerry held talks in Beijing from July 16 to 19, and in Sunshine Country, California from November 4 to 7, 2023, and issued the following statement: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. China and the United States review, reaffirm and commit to further effective and sustained implementation of the April 2021 China-US Joint Statement on Addressing the Climate Crisis and the November 2021 China-US Agreement on Strengthening Climate Change in the 21st Century20s. Glasgow Joint Declaration of Action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. China and the United States recognize that the climate crisis has an increasingly significant impact on countries around the world. In the face of warnings from the best available scientific findings such as the Sixth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC), the two countries are committed to effectively implementing the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change and the Paris Agreement, reflecting fairness and common but differentiated responsibilities. and their respective capabilities, taking into account different national conditions, and in accordance with Article 2 of the Paris Agreement, it is achievable to control the increase in global average temperature below 2°C and strive to limit it to 1.5°C, including efforts to maintain 1.5°C, and achieve this goal. purpose of the agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. China and the United States are committed to the effective implementation of the Paris Agreement and its decisions, including the Glasgow Climate Agreement and the Sharm el-Sheikh Implementation Plan. The two countries emphasized that the 28th Conference of the Parties (COP28) to the Convention is critical to meaningfully address the climate crisis during this critical decade and beyond. The two countries recognize that both countries play an important role in implementing the goals of the Paris Agreement and promoting multilateralism, both in terms of domestic response measures and joint cooperative actions. For the sake of current and future generations of humanity, the two countries will cooperate and join with other parties to the Convention and the Paris Agreement to face one of the most serious challenges in the world today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. China and the United States decided to launch the &quot;Working Group on Strengthening Climate Action in the 2120s&quot; to carry out dialogue and cooperation to accelerate specific climate actions in the 21st century. The working group will focus on the joint statement and areas of cooperation identified in the joint declaration, including energy transition, methane, circular economy and resource efficiency, low-carbon sustainable provinces/states and cities, deforestation, and other topics agreed by both parties. The working group will exchange information on policies, measures and technologies to control and reduce emissions, share their respective experiences, identify and implement cooperation projects, and evaluate the implementation of the joint statement, the joint declaration and this statement. The working group is co-led by the climate change envoys of the two countries, and officials from relevant ministries and government agencies of the two countries participate in appropriate ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5. China and the United States will focus on accelerating the following specific actions under the working group before and after COP28, especially practical and practical cooperation plans and projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Energy Transition&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;6. In the critical decade of the 2120s, the two countries support the efforts stated in the G20 Leaders’ Declaration to achieve Global renewable energy installed capacity will triple in 2030, and it is planned to fully accelerate the deployment of renewable energy in the two countries from now to 2030 at the 2020 level to accelerate the replacement of kerosene and gas power generation, so that emissions from the power industry can be expected to peak after Achieve meaningful absolute reductions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7. The two sides agreed to restart the China-US Energy Efficiency Forum to deepen exchanges on energy conservation and carbon reduction policies in key areas such as industry, construction, transportation and equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8. China and the United States plan to restart bilateral energy policy and strategic dialogue, conduct exchanges on mutually agreed issues, promote track two activities, and strengthen practical cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9. The two countries strive to promote at least five large-scale cooperation projects in carbon capture, utilization and storage (CCUS) in industry and energy by 2030. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Methane and other non-carbon dioxide greenhouse gas emissions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10. The two countries will implement their respective national methane action plans and plan to refine further measures as appropriate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11. The two countries will immediately launch technical working group cooperation to carry out policy dialogue, exchange of technical solutions and capacity building, and formulate their own nationally determined contributions in 2035 based on their respective national methane action plans. methane emission reduction actions/targets, and support the progress of both countries in methane emission reduction/control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;12. The two countries plan to cooperate on their respective measures to manage nitrous oxide emissions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;13. The two countries plan to work together to gradually reduce HFCs under the Kigali Amendment and are committed to ensuring that all refrigeration equipment produced adopts strong minimum energy efficiency standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Circular economy and resource utilization efficiency&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;14. Recognizing the important role of circular economy development and resource utilization efficiency in addressing the climate crisis, the two countries have The government departments plan to launch a policy dialogue on these issues as soon as possible and support enterprises, universities and research institutions on both sides to carry out exchange discussions and cooperation projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;15. China and the United States are determined to end plastic pollution and will work with all parties to develop a legally binding international instrument on plastic pollution (including plastic pollution in the marine environment). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Local Cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;16. China and the United States will support provinces, states and cities in climate change in areas such as electricity, transportation, construction and waste. cooperate. Both parties will promote local governments, enterprises, think tanks and other relevant parties to actively participate in cooperation. The two countries will conduct policy dialogue, share best practices, exchange information and promote project cooperation through agreed regular meetings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;17. China and the United States plan to hold high-level events on local climate action in the first half of 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18. Both sides welcome and appreciate the local cooperation that the two countries have carried out, and encourage provinces, states and cities to carry out practical climate cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Forest&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;19. Both sides commit to further efforts to halt and reverse forest loss by 2030, including comprehensive implementation and implementation through regulatory and policy means. Effectively enforce their respective laws prohibiting illegal imports. Plans include discussions under the working group on how exchanges can enhance efforts to strengthen implementation of this commitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Coordinated emission reduction of greenhouse gases and air pollutants&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;20. The two countries plan to cooperate to promote relevant policy measures and technology deployment to strengthen greenhouse gas and atmospheric pollutant emission reduction. Coordinated control of atmospheric pollutant emissions such as nitrogen oxides, volatile organic compounds and other tropospheric ozone precursors. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Nationally Determined Contributions in 2035&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;21. Reaffirm the nature of nationally determined contributions determined by countries, and recall Article 4, paragraph 4, of the Paris Agreement , the two countries’ nationally determined contributions in 2035 will be economy-wide, including all greenhouse gases. The emission reductions reflected are in line with the Paris temperature control target of controlling the rise in global average temperature below 2°C and striving to limit it to 1.5°C. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;COP28&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;22. China and the United States will, together with the United Arab Emirates, invite all countries to participate in the &quot;Methane and Non-Carbon dioxide Greenhouse Gases&quot; Conference held during COP28. Summit”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;23. China and the United States will actively participate in the first global stocktake of the Paris Agreement. This is an important opportunity for the parties to review the intensity, implementation and cooperation in order to comply with the temperature control goals of the Paris Agreement. Control the increase in global average temperature below 2°C and strive to limit it to 1.5°C, consistent with the Parties’ determination to keep the 1.5°C temperature control target achievable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;24. The two countries are committed to working together and working with other Parties to reach a global stocktake decision by consensus. The two countries believe that the decision:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—should reflect substantial positive progress towards achieving the goals of the Paris Agreement, including actions facilitated by the Agreement by both parties and non-party stakeholders, and The world is clearly in a better position on the trajectory of temperature rise than without an agreement;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—Equity should be considered and informed by the best available science, including the latest IPCC report;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ——It should maintain a balance in various thematic areas, include retrospective and responsive elements, and be consistent with the design of the Paris Agreement;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——It should reflect the need to combine different national conditions in action and support to achieve the goals of the Paris Agreement Significantly increase ambition and strengthen implementation;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Energy transition (renewable energy, coal/oil/gas), carbon sinks such as forests, non-carbon dioxide gases such as methane, and low-carbon technologies should be Send a signal;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—Recognizing the nationally determined nature of NDCs and recalling Article 4, paragraph 4, of the Paris Agreement, economy-wide NDCs in 2035 should be encouraged to cover all greenhouse gases;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>; - Should reflect the critical importance of adaptation and be supported by a strong decision to propose a strong global adaptation goal framework - to accelerate adaptation, including the development of targets/indicators to strengthen adaptation effectiveness; Provide early warning systems for developing country Parties; strengthen adaptation efforts in key areas (such as food, water, infrastructure, health and ecosystems);&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; - It should be noted that developed countries are expected to achieve 1000 by 2023 US$100 million climate finance target, reaffirming the urge for developed country parties to at least double the adaptation finance they provide; looking forward to COP29 adopting a new collective quantified finance target; and making financial flows consistent with the goals of the Paris Agreement;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—— The proposal of the Transitional Council to establish financial arrangements to address loss and damage, including the establishment of a fund for this purpose, should be welcomed and appreciated;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;—The important role of international cooperation, including the global nature of the climate crisis, should be emphasized The broadest possible cooperation is required as a key enabler for strong mitigation action and climate-resilient development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;25. China and the United States are committed to further strengthening dialogue and collaborative efforts and supporting the UAE, the UAE chairmanship, in successfully hosting COP28. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[千人托位数仅1.3，北京托育如何提速“补课”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260589]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the past six months, Beijing childcare has finally begun to speed up “make-up classes”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of March 2023, the Beijing Municipal Government issued a document stating that it plans to have 4.5 childcare centers for infants and young children under the age of 3 per 1,000 people by 2025, of which inclusive childcare spaces will account for no less than 60 %. In October, two sub-district nurseries were unveiled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, Beijing was a &quot;poor student&quot; in childcare: as of the end of 2022, the number of childcare centers per 1,000 students was only 1.3, far behind the national average (2.03) and not as good as Shenzhen (2.0 ), Shanghai (2.12) and Guangzhou (3.58). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, 95% of childcare institutions in Beijing are for-profit, and there are only 2 public nurseries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is childcare so scarce in Beijing? How to keep up with the pace of the country? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Finding a venue is not easy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to find a venue for children. An insider in Beijing&#39;s health care system described to Southern Weekend reporters that of the two streets that were the first to open nurseries, one was &quot;squeezed&quot; and the other was &quot;borrowed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Known as the first street-run nursery in Beijing, it is located in Xiaojing Automobile Station, a remote parking lot in Liuliqiao, Beijing. The Liuliqiao Sub-district Office is located in the corner of this parking lot, and the nursery is also squeezed out of the Sub-district Office&#39;s premises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a house of about 80 square meters, compactly equipped with a toilet, pantry, doll house, reading corner and a mini slide. Outdoor activities are held on the football field on the other side of the parking lot. This artificial turf formerly belonged to a badminton hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After one month of operation, only 5 children have been enrolled out of a total of 18 places. The teachers’ explanation is that every new student needs to be assigned a teacher to follow him throughout the whole process. Counting the principal, there are 4 teachers in total. , &quot;Actually, our admission schedule has been until next month.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, its location is not ideal. It is backed by a highway. There is only one community within one kilometer nearby, and there is a main car road in front of the parking lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a parent, a reporter from Southern Weekend participated in an enrollment meeting of a Liuliqiao subdistrict nursery school. Many of the parents who came to visit were not residents of the neighborhood. The advantage here is that it is cheap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Nursery outside costs 7,000 to 8,000 yuan a month, but here it only costs 3,600 yuan.” A pair of “Beijing drifter” parents from Hunan told Southern Weekend reporters that the elderly at home could not help take care of their children, so they had to I found a nursery near the company, and including meals, the monthly cost was 4,200 yuan. This is almost the cheapest nursery in Beijing. &quot;Except for a public physical fitness classroom, the classroom where children usually stay is only 30 square meters.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the end, they failed to make up their mind to deliver it. &quot;If you come here, you need to deliver it in advance in the morning. Counting the delay fee of 50 yuan/hour, the prices on both sides are almost the same.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A person in charge of a childcare institution told Southern Weekend reporters that childcare centers are more sensitive to distance. “Kindergartens can also radiate to nurseries within three kilometers of the surrounding area. It must be at the doorstep. It’s so cold in Beijing in winter, how many people would be willing to hold such a small baby and go out for more than ten minutes?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Desheng Children’s Center, located in No. 1 Xinfeng Street, Xicheng District, Beijing, is The second childcare center run by a street in Beijing is located in the core area where land is at a premium - Desheng Street. A two-story building with an independent courtyard, the first floor has been transformed into a nursery, and the second floor is still reserved as an early education center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person responsible for operating this nursery is Han Xiaoliang, the founder of Huayu Tiancheng (Beijing) Childcare Service Co., Ltd. They originally opened a nursery in Desheng Street, which was a model park in Xicheng District . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, Desheng Street introduced Han Xiaoliang’s agency through bidding to operate the Desheng Children’s Center. Han Xiaoliang told a reporter from Southern Weekend, &quot;As long as I don&#39;t lose money, I am willing to participate. It can be regarded as making some contributions to the streets.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing’s guide price for inclusive childcare institutions is no more than 20% of the disposable income of residents in the district in the previous year. “The price is no more than 3,900 yuan.” The price of this nursery It is 3,600 yuan per month. Han Xiaoliang said that Beijing requires a teacher-student ratio of 1:7 for kindergartens over two years old. Under normal circumstances, there are 15 to 18 children with five teachers. &quot;We have just maintained a balance of income and expenditure, and still have a slight loss.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last week of September, Desheng Street held a round of enrollment briefings. “On-site applications were made for 18 full-day cares and 12 half-day cares,” Han Xiaoliang said, including those who signed up later. , currently more than 50 support spaces are basically full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The venue for this nursery does not belong to Desheng Street, but is borrowed from other communities. An insider in Beijing’s health system told Southern Weekend reporters, “This used to be a boiler room in a community that was renovated.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The for-profit nursery that Han Xiaoliang previously opened in Xicheng District also had to wait three or four years for the venue. &quot;It happened that a training school was not available during the epidemic.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of a chain kindergarten brand told Southern Weekend reporters that many districts in Beijing no longer approve new kindergartens. The Xicheng District Education Commission is one of the few that actively welcomes everyone to open kindergartens. Even if I have money, I can&#39;t find a suitable place.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned person familiar with the Beijing health care system said that even a venue like Liuliqiao is difficult to find, &quot;because we require that the venue must be rent-free.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Xiaoliang has also communicated with some streets before, and everyone is generally faced with the problem of space shortage. &quot;Some streets said that they are not enough for office space. Where can I find a house?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt=&quot;The first street-run nursery in Beijing. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Luo Huanhuan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/2cfbdac886.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/2cfbdac886.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258236 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The first street-run nursery in Beijing. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Luo Huanhuan&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Of the 102 streets, 96 have no plans&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to Beijing’s plan, every street will have an inclusive nursery by 2025. In this regard, Southern Weekend reporters contacted a total of 121 streets in the five urban districts of Beijing, Xicheng, Dongcheng, Haidian, Chaoyang, and Fengtai. In addition to 19 streets that still received no answer after repeated calls, 102 of the streets that answered the call 3 are in planning, 3 are under construction, and 96 streets are still unplanned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qinglongqiao Street in Haidian District, Longtan Street and Dongsi Street in Dongcheng District are the three streets where nurseries will be opened after Liuliqiao and Desheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the site in Qinglongqiao Street, Haidian District has been completed and is being filed. Longtan Street is speeding up construction and is expected to be completed in early December. Dongsi Street has found a place and is &quot;waiting for approval from above.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Chaoyangmen Street in Chaoyang District said, &quot;The street has no place to do it now, and we are waiting for the next plan from above.&quot; Panjiayuan Street also said, &quot;The space is tight,&quot; and Zuojiazhuang Street is planning middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No matter how tight the venue is, the street can find ways to solve it.&quot; The above-mentioned insiders of the Beijing health care system said that they all know that this matter is not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another worrying issue is how many children will be attracted once the nursery is built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member from the sub-district office told a reporter from Southern Weekend, &quot;Private childcare institutions only have 7-9 children, and it seems that the market demand is not very strong at the moment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to survey data from the Social Affairs Department of the Beijing Municipal Development and Reform Commission, as of 2022, the average utilization rate of support seats in Beijing is 35.4%, with the highest being 64.9% and the lowest being only 13%. Most childcare facilities are vacant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Xiaoliang said that another for-profit nursery he runs has a monthly childcare fee of more than 8,000, and the occupancy rate is only 50%. Even the current inclusive nursery on Desheng Street is just full. There was no “hard-to-find” person as imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;There are so many worries about sending children to kindergarten after the age of three, let alone younger babies.&quot; Han Xiaoliang believes that the bigger issue now than building a nursery is how to change parents&#39; perceptions. &quot; We always regard two- and three-year-old children as incompetent and ignorant babies, and fail to realize that children also need a space to develop skills.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Beijing has launched a pilot program for inclusive childcare and announced that it will subsidize childcare institutions based on the policy of inclusive kindergartens, the specific details are still awaited. The above-mentioned person familiar with the Beijing Municipal Health Commission said that after the city issues the document, the specific details will still be determined by the district government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The park has been open for more than a month, and Han Xiaoliang has not received any subsidies yet. &quot;They say they will be subsidized, but how? How much? We can only wait now.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Shanghai has already &quot;handed in the papers&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Shanghai, which is a few steps ahead of Beijing, has already seen a phenomenon where it is hard to find a job. In November 2023, data released by the Shanghai Municipal Education Department showed that the utilization rate of inclusive care seats in Shanghai kindergartens has reached as high as 90%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the total fertility rates of Shanghai and Beijing will be only 0.74 and 0.87 respectively. The total fertility rate refers to the total number of children a woman gives birth to in her lifetime. A woman has an average of 2.1 children to ensure that the total population of the next generation does not decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The construction of inclusive childcare has just started in Beijing and has already been handed in in Shanghai. In 2017, Shanghai began to build inclusive child care centers, and the goal set at that time was to add 50 new centers every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Shanghai took the lead in the country in releasing the &quot;Shanghai Childcare Service Action Plan (2020-2022)&quot;, with the goal of opening at least one inclusive childcare center in every street and town in the central city by 2022. The coverage rate of universal child care centers in the city’s streets and towns shall not be less than 85%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The implementation of this action plan has been included in the supervision and evaluation of the district government’s performance of educational responsibilities, and key indicators have been included in the annual self-evaluation bulletin, becoming an important criterion for assessing the district government’s performance of its duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Shanghai has overfulfilled its task. At least one inclusive childcare center has been opened in every street in the central city, with the city-wide coverage reaching 95%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai, the founder of &quot;Nursing School&quot;, is also the deputy secretary-general of the Shanghai Infant Care Services Committee, a professional committee under the Shanghai Early Population Development Association to assist the government in promoting infant care. Service is one of its functions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai recalled to the Southern Weekend reporter that Shanghai conducted many pilot projects at the beginning, “from the earliest independent childcare institutions, to integrated early childhood care, and even community childcare such as ‘baby houses’. Do it. With a hundred flowers blooming, from the final practice point of view, it is most cost-effective to run kindergartens to solve the problem of parents sending care.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Across the country, Shanghai is the only one where the Education Commission is in charge of child care. In other places, the health commission is in charge of child care. To this end, the Shanghai Municipal Education Commission has specially established a &quot;Child Care Work Office&quot; to encourage kindergartens to extend downwards to open child care classes, requiring &quot;to open as many kindergartens as possible and as many as possible.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai said that Shanghai’s publicization of preschool education is also the best in the country. “In the process of solving the problem of universal preschool education, childcare is also solved.” Data from the Shanghai Municipal Education Commission shows that nearly 1,000 kindergartens in the city have opened day care classes, accounting for 60% of all kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai requires that newly built, renovated and expanded kindergartens all plan to provide childcare classes. Existing public kindergartens will consolidate resources and strive to add more childcare classes, and private kindergartens will actively offer inclusive childcare classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public kindergartens enjoy the same per-student subsidy as a kindergarten degree—31,000 yuan per student per year. Inclusive private kindergartens offer daycare classes with a subsidy of 1,200 yuan per student per year. The Shanghai Municipal Education Commission also provides a one-time start-up fund of 100,000 yuan for each inclusive childcare center to support the purchase of toys, teaching aids, facilities and equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This makes Shanghai almost the city with the lowest childcare fees in the country. Monthly childcare fees for demonstration kindergartens are 700-800 yuan, first-level kindergartens are 270 yuan, and second-level kindergartens are 220 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai said that in some core areas, kindergartens with the same academic qualifications have to queue up according to age, giving priority to older children. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Kindergarten is the main channel&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among the four first-tier cities in Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou and Shenzhen, Beijing’s action plan was the latest to be introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen and Guangzhou issued action plans in 2020 and 2021 respectively. The &quot;Three-Year Action Plan for the Construction of Beijing&#39;s Childcare Service System (2023-2025)&quot; will be released in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beijing’s goal is to have 4.5 childcare centers for infants and young children under the age of 3 per 1,000 people by 2025, of which inclusive childcare spaces will account for no less than 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above action plan, Beijing will add no less than 62,000 inclusive child care places in the future, of which 30,000 will be provided by kindergartens and another 32,000 will come from streets, companies and other places. form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned person familiar with the Beijing Municipal Health Commission told Southern Weekend reporters that this plan is dynamically adjusted. “When we made the plan, it was not clear how much preschool resources could be extended to child care classes. I made some estimates. The whole of Beijing is dynamically adjusted, and there will be no restrictions on which part can handle 32,000 and which part can handle 30,000.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with various forms of childcare such as streets and enterprises, kindergartens have obvious advantages. &quot;Of course, this will save manpower, material and resources than building an institution from scratch. The venue is ready-made, it can be approved quickly, and it is standardized. Moreover, parents have gained more trust in the kindergarten after so many years.&quot; The person familiar with the matter said. Classes must be the main channel.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The integration of child care is seen as a shortcut to inclusive child care, and its resistance mainly comes from the kindergarten itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many industry insiders told Southern Weekend reporters that kindergarten teachers generally lack enthusiasm for opening day care classes. Compared with children over 3 years old, the work of children under 3 years old is more demanding and more difficult. Especially for public kindergarten teachers, the salary will remain unchanged and the workload will increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Weikai analyzed that since Shanghai’s Education Commission takes the lead in promoting day care, it has stronger execution capabilities than other cities led by the Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For many places, kindergartens need to give priority to solving the problem of &quot;large class sizes&quot; when running daycare classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2022, when responding to the proposal to promote qualified kindergartens to open inclusive nursery classes to enroll children aged 2-3, Vice Minister of Education Zheng Fuzhi said that it has not yet been fully popularized across the country. In preschool education, although the problem of children aged 3-6 years old having difficulty enrolling in kindergarten has been alleviated, it has not been fundamentally solved. At present, kindergartens in various places have a relatively high proportion of &quot;large class sizes&quot;, and there are still millions of children studying in kindergartens across the country who exceed the class quota. &quot;In this case, areas that have achieved full universal access to preschool education must create conditions to add nursery classes. Areas that have not yet fully popularized preschool education, especially those with a low penetration rate, must provide kindergartens for those aged 3-6 and 0-3 years old. The relationship between admission and day care issues should be properly handled and promoted step by step.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Opportunities for professional institutions? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A Shanghai childcare industry entrepreneur told a Southern Weekend reporter that after attending some industry exhibitions recently, he clearly felt that private capital was withdrawing from the childcare industry. “There are only some toy and teaching aid manufacturers participating. , almost no childcare companies can be seen.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How can 7,000 yuan and 700 yuan compete?&quot; This entrepreneur has persuaded many friends who wanted to join the game in recent years. &quot;Now capital no longer cares about this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Youer Academy is a national daycare chain brand. Founder Su Dezhong told Southern Weekend reporters, “In the future, inclusive schools will account for the majority. Starting from 2020, Youer Academy will be more closely related to the government and local state-owned enterprises. Business cooperation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, kindergartens do not solve the problem of childcare by running daycare classes. “It actually solves the problem of kindergartens. Now kindergartens are facing a transition from ‘hard to find one child’ to ‘hard to find one child’” &#39;The problem&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The national “14th Five-Year Plan” requires that by 2025, there will be 4.5 nurseries for infants and young children under the age of 3 per 1,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Dezhong made some calculations. Even if there are only 10 million births in the country every year, there will be 30 million people under the age of 3. By 2025, 4.5 places per 1,000 people will be achieved, which is about 6 million places. The actual enrollment rate is only 20%. Today, the enrollment rate in developed countries has reached 50%-60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, he believes that the development of inclusive childcare is an opportunity for professional institutions. “The kindergarten system is very mature, but the childcare system is still in a blank period. Many kindergarten teachers don’t know how to get there. For children under 3 years old. What kindergartens save is the initial investment, but the challenges faced by kindergartens in terms of talent training and refined management are no different from those of corporate childcare and medical education.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The question now is, &quot;Can the childcare services keep up? Can the price be reduced?&quot; At this stage, many childcare centers have not reached full capacity. Some people think that childcare is a false demand, and they are not satisfied with the demand. Su Dezhong gave an example, &quot;For example, if you open a restaurant or a nursing home, when your quality is not good enough or your service is not up to standard, people will not be able to actively go to the restaurant to eat, and the nursing home will not be full. But this is not a false demand, but a service. The quality is not good enough.&quot; He pointed out that many voices are now discussing how to open daycare centers, &quot;but the most fundamental thing is how to do a good job in daycare centers and how to improve service quality. Only when the service quality is good can this thing generate value. Only the urgent needs can be met.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of November, Beijing will have 6,000 kindergarten places to start enrolling students. For Beijing&#39;s first childcare center run by a street, the coming winter will bring a difficult test for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[与南方周末读者交换一本书，你要来玩吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260552]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Who in the clouds sends brocade books? Let’s sell it first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;British writer Bernard Shaw said, &quot;If you have an apple and I have an apple and exchange them with each other, each of us still has only one apple; you have an idea and I have an idea, exchange it with each other and everyone There are two thoughts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We believe that the same is true for books. Words are like fireworks, and they can create wonderful connections in the vast universe and the vast sea of ​​people. Interesting souls will always intersect. If your book starts a wonderful unknown journey, do you want to play? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/sGDyrmL6k5KEbXsHsnXBE0cU2rfW8ico8gtSiWIS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height= &quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/sGDyrmL6k5KEbXsHsnXBE0cU2rfW8ico8gtSiWIS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258276&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Exchange with Southern Weekend readers A book&lt;/strong>;. It can be your collection, travel readers, or recent reading publications. In short, you are welcome to share. Let us work together to make words cross mountains and seas, let stories drift with the waves, and let your tastes and interests find a close friend in Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have never met each other, but we see each other as if they were face to face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The event rules are very simple&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●Click &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://h5s.infzm.com /6EaxEe5F/&quot;>;I want to participate&lt;/a>;&quot; Submit your contact information and the books you plan to exchange. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Be sure to leave it to ensure you can receive the express delivery&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;● Share your desires with strangers The books to be exchanged (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Please note: at least one, maximum three&lt;/span>;), and include your receiving information and send them together Go to the Southern Weekend Collection Office. We will open all express packages and exchange them according to your wishes and the condition and type of the books. &lt;strong>;Choose a book that best suits you and send it to you, and give your book to the most suitable person&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●You will be responsible for the shipping fee for this event. Click &quot;I want free shipping&quot; in the event, and after completing the assistance, we will provide free shipping for the books you exchange. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Invite friends to help, otherwise you will have to pay&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //h5s.infzm.com/6EaxEe5F/&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5R5vLVylaCdMzltsiLfMwtMrGpHgamn1HAUV9dE3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;750&quot; height=&quot;1334&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/5R5vLVylaCdMzltsiLfMwtMrGpHgamn1HAUV9dE3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258267&quot; data-mce- width=&quot;750&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;1334&quot;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Please also pay attention to these details:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●Activity time 11 November 15th - November 22nd. &lt;strong>;Express delivery address:&lt;/strong>;Southern Newspaper Cainiao Station (collection), No. 289 Guangzhou Avenue Middle, Guangzhou, &lt;strong>;Contact person:&lt;/strong>;Xiaonan, &lt;strong>;Tel:&lt;/strong>;18028553727 . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●To participate in this event, it must be a public and official publication with healthy content, good quality, no missing pages, no serious damage, and a certain reading value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;●Books are subject to &quot;equivalent exchange&quot;. For example, if you send three copies, you will eventually receive three copies. The preferences we guess may not be exactly what you expect, but we hope to bring you surprise and pleasure this winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a stranger’s book reaches the hands of another stranger, isn’t that the joy of exchange—unknown expectations and surprises. The moment you gently open the package, two interesting people meet in the air, and you also have the opportunity to say to him: Hi, I have finished reading your favorite book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti , italics_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;After receiving the exchanged books, you are welcome to share your activity experience and reading experience on the Southern Weekend APP, and you will have a chance to win a mysterious blind box from us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[鸡蛋的坏名声从何而来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260593]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Eggs are one of the most easily available and commonly consumed animal-source foods for humans. At present, the global per capita consumption of eggs is about 150 eggs per year, with more than 210 eggs in Europe and 300 eggs in China. In ancient times, eggs were not only food, but also a medicine for treating diseases. Since the 1960s, eggs have had a bad reputation for being unhealthy. For a time, many people were wondering whether they should eat eggs. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A warning from a cardiologist&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Eggs’ “bad” reputation comes from cholesterol. As early as the early 20th century, scientists discovered through animal experiments that increasing the cholesterol in feed could increase the serum cholesterol levels of animals and promote the development of atherosclerosis in animals. Given that cardiovascular disease has become the leading cause of death in the United States, on June 16, 1948, U.S. President Harry Truman signed the National Heart Act and allocated $500,000 to launch a 20-year study on the epidemiology of heart disease. study, the Framingham Heart Study. In 1957, the Framingham Heart Research Team published a blockbuster study that concluded that elevated serum cholesterol levels were closely related to the risk of cardiovascular disease. In the 1960s and 1970s, scientists successively observed a certain correlation between dietary cholesterol intake, serum cholesterol concentration, and the incidence of cardiovascular disease. Unfortunately, since one egg (about 50 grams) contains about 200 mg of cholesterol, and eggs had become a daily food in the United States at that time, eggs inevitably became one of the &quot;culprits&quot; in the high incidence of cardiovascular disease in the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1968年，美国心脏协会首次明确提出，为了降低心血管疾病发病率，建议限制膳食胆固醇的摄入，并首次提出将鸡蛋消费限制在每周不超过三个的建议，这可能是后来全世界营养专家或医生提出每周三个鸡蛋限制建议的源头。这份来自美国心脏科医生群体关于鸡蛋消费的限制建议，貌似符合逻辑，而且易于操作，竟然得到了诸多认可，逐渐成为美国乃至世界其他国家制定国民膳食营养指南的重要依据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;媒体的推波助澜加深了公众对鸡蛋的误解，最典型的例子是美国《时代》杂志关于胆固醇的两篇封面报道。 1984年，时代杂志头版文章以《胆固醇和现在的坏消息》为题，并在杂志封面配了一张悲伤的大圆脸图片，眼睛是由两个煎蛋构成，表示悲伤表情的嘴巴则是用一根两头向下弯曲的培根。虽然时代杂志并非鸡蛋坏名声的始作俑者，但是鉴于其巨大影响力，无疑进一步加深了公众对鸡蛋与“坏”胆固醇的联系。 15年后，《时代》杂志再次将鸡蛋放在了封面上，煎蛋仍然是大圆脸的眼睛，不过嘴巴已换成了一块两边上翘的甜瓜，呈现欢快的笑容形象，而对应的头版文章标题则是《胆固醇，现在是好消息》。虽然这篇文章标志着医生和营养学家对胆固醇有了更科学全面的认识，但是也没能迅速消除之前给公众灌输的错误观念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在医学界和媒体的共同推动下，鸡蛋坏名声持续了五十多年，受影响最大的无疑是蛋鸡产业。从1968年到20世纪90年初期，美国鸡蛋产量基本停滞不前，徘徊在400万吨左右，而同期美国人口增长了20%以上，显然这段时间美国鸡蛋人均消费量其实是持续下降的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3wGetBG43ptbpUG1Vj1VHnQbf0cdR4trlEeWXiIN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;687&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/3wGetBG43ptbpUG1Vj1VHnQbf0cdR4trlEeWXiIN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258239&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1984年《时代》杂志以《胆固醇和现在的坏消息》为题进行报道，并在封面配了一张悲伤的大圆脸图片。 15年后，鸡蛋再次出现在封面，嘴巴换成两边上翘的甜瓜，对应的文章是《胆固醇，现在是好消息》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;相反的证据越来越多&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;令人难以置信的是，关于多吃富含胆固醇的鸡蛋增加心血管疾病风险的说法竟然缺乏直接的科学证据。美国心脏协会和其他机构作出限制鸡蛋消费的建议，主要基于三个并不完美的证据，第一个证据是动物模型表明摄入过多的胆固醇会增加血清胆固醇水平和动物粥样动脉硬化的发展，第二个证据是流行病学调查说明高胆固醇饮食与心血管疾病高发病率相关，第三个证据是临床观察显示高胆固醇摄入导致血清胆固醇水平升高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这三个看似环环相扣的证据却存在致命漏洞。科学家一般采用大鼠、豚鼠、兔子等动物来开展动物胆固醇饲喂试验，胆固醇添加量远远高于日常膳食的胆固醇摄入量，往往需要达到药理学水平才会引发血清胆固醇水平的变化。例如，美国亚利桑那大学的研究人员曾经给一群豚鼠饲喂0（对照）、0.08%（相当于人类600 毫克/天）、0.17%（相当于人类1275毫克/天）或0.33%（相当于人类2475 毫克/天）膳食胆固醇，结果发现膳食胆固醇摄入量与血清低密度脂蛋白胆固醇之间存在正相关关系。不过在该研究中，豚鼠在饲喂0膳食胆固醇和含有0.08%胆固醇的饲料后，血清胆固醇浓度并没有显著差异，只有当饲喂更高剂量的胆固醇时，血清胆固醇浓度才会显著升高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于膳食胆固醇与心血管疾病发病率相关性的流行病学调查结果更是经常“打架”，让公众一头雾水，无所适从。早期流行病学调查研究大多依靠简单的相关性分析来得出结论，比如只是记录了鸡蛋的消费量，但是并没有考虑其他膳食成分的影响，甚至也没有考虑抽烟、喝酒等其他可能造成心血管疾病的因素，因此这类研究的结论并不可靠。但是这类研究由于涉及的受试者人数众多，随访时间较长，往往更能吸引“眼球”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从20世纪90年代以来，越来越多的研究表明鸡蛋消费量、膳食胆固醇与心血管疾病发病率几乎没有关联。 1999年，哈佛公共卫生学院的研究人员在《美国医学会杂志》上发表了一项重磅研究，研究人员对超过11.7万人开展了长达8-14年的随访研究，在剔除了年龄、吸烟和心血管疾病其他影响因素之后，结果显示每周吃一个鸡蛋与每天吃一个鸡蛋的人在心血管疾病风险方面没有显著差异。 2015年，瑞典卡罗林斯卡学院的研究人员对超过6万人进行长达13年随访研究，同样认为每天的鸡蛋摄入量与心血管疾病发病率没有关联。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一些研究甚至认为适当吃鸡蛋会降低心血管疾病风险。 2018年，北京大学、中国中医科学院、牛津大学等机构的研究人员开展了一项涉及50万人的队列研究，发现与基本不吃鸡蛋相比，中等水平的鸡蛋消费量（平均0.79个/天）的心血管疾病死亡风险降低了18%，出血性中风死亡的风险降低了28%。这与2003年日本广岛辐射效应研究基金会的研究结果相似。日本研究人员在对4万多人进行了16年随访后，发现每天都吃鸡蛋的人中风死亡风险比不吃鸡蛋的要低30%，每周吃1-4个鸡蛋的中风死亡风险也相应降低。一项针对韩国13多万名40-69岁成年受试者的研究中，韩国国立首尔大学的研究人员发现，在女性受试者中，与每周摄入少于1个鸡蛋相比，每周摄入超过7个鸡蛋的代谢综合征风险较低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;理论上，随机对照试验是验证膳食胆固醇与心血管疾病风险相关性的最有效，也是最可靠的方法。大多数随机对照试验都证明每天吃1-3个鸡蛋对血清胆固醇水平影响不大，即使一些糖尿病患者也不用担心。在一项为期1年的随机对照试验中，荷兰马斯特里赫特大学的研究人员让实验组志愿者每天饮用含有1.5个富含叶黄素的蛋黄的酪乳饮料，对照组则饮用不含蛋黄的安慰剂，结果发现一年后两组之间的总胆固醇、低密度脂蛋白、高密度脂蛋白胆固醇以及总胆固醇与高密度脂蛋白胆固醇的比率都基本没有差异。相反，有一些随机对照试验证明食用鸡蛋反而会降低代谢综合征的风险。不过，目前这类随机对照试验存在样本少、观察时间短等问题，仍需进一步完善。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1995 年，美国心脏协会指南、美国国家胆固醇教育计划指南、美国膳食指南和美国食品药品监督管理局营养成分表都不约而同地将膳食胆固醇建议设定为低于300毫克/天，而且建议减少含胆固醇高的鸡蛋等动物源食物的摄入。但是，由于缺少足够的科学证据证明摄入正常水平的鸡蛋或其他膳食胆固醇对人体有害，进入新千年以来，制定膳食指南的相关机构相继取消了关于鸡蛋和膳食胆固醇摄入量的限制建议。 2002年，美国心脏协会取消了每周3-4个鸡蛋的具体限制，同时保持低于300 毫克/天的膳食胆固醇指南。 2013年，美国心脏协会才正式宣布“没有足够的证据来确定降低膳食胆固醇是否会降低低密度脂蛋白胆固醇”，取消了关于不超过300毫克/天的膳食胆固醇建议。 2015-2020年版以及2020-2025年版的《美国居民膳食指南》都取消了膳食胆固醇消费量低于300毫克/天的建议。据《中国居民膳食指南科学研究报告（2021）》，目前全球只有印度、澳大利亚等少数国家单独对鸡蛋进行推荐，大多数国家推荐的鸡蛋消费量为每周3个左右。 《中国居民膳食指南2022年》推荐的鸡蛋消费量为1个/天，同时提出“鸡蛋营养丰富，吃鸡蛋不弃蛋黄”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;原来体内存在反馈机制&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;虽然目前大多数膳食指南都取消了鸡蛋和膳食胆固醇的摄入限制建议，但是公众对富含胆固醇的鸡蛋仍然心存疑虑，担心长期吃鸡蛋会导致体内胆固醇水平升高，心血管疾病风险也会随之增加。多摄入膳食胆固醇是否就意味着血清胆固醇水平高呢？并不完全如此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究表明，人体的胆固醇只有约25%来自饮食摄入，其他主要依靠自身生物合成。由于胆固醇在人体发挥重要作用，因此人体几乎所有细胞都能合成胆固醇，其中肝脏和肠道负责合成人体每日所需的约80%胆固醇，大脑、肾上腺和生殖器官也能高效地合成胆固醇。体重70公斤的成年人每天合成约850毫克胆固醇。临床喂养研究表明，膳食胆固醇每天变化100毫克，血浆总胆固醇水平平均会变化2.2-2.5 毫克/分升，相当于吃一个鸡蛋只会引起2%-3%的血清胆固醇变化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原来，科学家发现人体存在一种针对胆固醇的反馈代偿机制，即当人体摄入过多的膳食胆固醇时，机体吸收和合成胆固醇的能力将受到限制，而且也将加速多余胆固醇的排泄和清除，从而维持血清胆固醇水平的平衡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1991年，《新英格兰医学杂志》报道了一个吃鸡蛋“成瘾”的极端案例。一位88岁的男性老年人每天要吃20-30枚鸡蛋，持续时间至少有15年，但是医生发现他的血脂水平基本正常，其中血清总胆固醇竟然也维持在正常水平，平均值为5.18毫摩尔/升（正常范围3.12-5.72毫摩尔/升），而且患者也没有出现动脉粥样硬化等与胆固醇过量摄入相关的疾病。为了进一步研究这一特殊病例，研究人员进行了随机对照试验，实验组在常规饮食基础上每天每人加餐5个鸡蛋，不加鸡蛋的作为对照组，结果发现在常规饮食时，对照组摄入胆固醇的吸收率达53%，而在高胆固醇饮食即加餐5个鸡蛋期间，对照组摄入胆固醇的吸收率降至46%，但是88岁的老年人只吸收了18%的摄入胆固醇。与此同时，该患者的总胆汁酸合成速率是对照组的两倍，这说明该患者体内存在非常有效的代偿机制，在大量摄入鸡蛋胆固醇的情况下，一方面会减少摄入胆固醇的吸收，另一方面则降低人体胆固醇合成能力，从而维持总胆固醇的平衡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，并非所有人对膳食胆固醇的反应都一样，一般会随着遗传、个体代谢水平、性别、年龄等多种因素表现出不同。研究表明，大约有2/3的人摄入过多胆固醇后，血清总胆固醇不会或只会轻微升高。这些人与上述88岁老人一样具有有效的胆固醇代偿机制，能根据膳食胆固醇摄入量，对胆固醇的吸收、排泄和合成进行相应的调整。但是另一些人则可能缺乏类似的代偿机制，摄入过多的膳食胆固醇，将会引发血清胆固醇较大幅度的升高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;越来越多的证据表明鸡蛋或饮食中的胆固醇摄入与心血管疾病风险增加无关，而鸡蛋摄入可解决许多营养不足的问题，并且可为整个生命周期的整体健康作出重要贡献，因此大多数人都可放心吃鸡蛋，即使一些代谢综合征或心血管疾病患者也可正常食用，但是不能长期过多食用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[河南武陟一中学发生踩踏事故，已致1死5伤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 00:41:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;2023年11月13日上午10时许，武陟县兴华中学初一初二部分男生在期中考试间隙如厕时，因上下楼梯发生拥挤摔倒受伤，涉及的学生第一时间送往医院接受检查治疗。目前，1名学生经全力抢救无效死亡，1名受伤较重学生正在全力救治，4名受轻微伤学生住院观察治疗、近日即可出院。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;事发后，市县立即开展现场救援，组织省内医疗专家进行救治。同时，成立调查组尽快查明原因，对相关责任人依法依规严肃处理。我县将深刻汲取教训，举一反三，全面开展学校风险隐患排查整治，确保学生安全。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;武陟县人民政府&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;2023年11月14日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 01:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[香港屋宇署：没有针对霓虹灯招牌的大型执法行动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260603]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;11月14日，香港特区政府屋宇署回复南方+记者查询表示，&lt;strong>;该署并没有针对霓虹灯招牌的大规模执法行动。 &lt;/strong>;同时该署还表示，香港特区政府容许包括霓虹灯招牌在内，规模较小、风险较低的小型招牌，在经过安全检查、巩固以及核证后继续保留使用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;屋宇署表示，特区政府一直重视户外招牌安全，并以“风险为本”为原则，多管齐下处理违例、危险或弃置招牌。对生命财产明显构成威胁的招牌，屋宇署会采取执法行动实时取缔，也会优先执法取缔正在建造或新竖设的违例招牌。针对大量现存违例招牌，屋宇署会每年拣选若干存在较多违例招牌的繁忙街道路段进行“目标街道大规模行动”，就违例、危险及弃置招牌进行全面的清拆行动。此外，屋宇署也会针对对公众构成较大风险的大型违例招牌展开大规模行动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而考虑到大部分现存招牌正由商户使用，并有助促进本地商业活动，屋宇署自2013年9月2日起开始实施“招牌检核计划”。该计划容许规模较小、风险较低，并于检核计划实施当日之前已经竖设并符合相关小型工程项目技术规格的招牌，在经订明建筑专业人士及／或订明注册承建商进行安全检查、巩固（如有需要）及向屋宇署核证后，可继续保留使用，其后须每隔五年重新进行安全检核或将该等招牌拆除。有关检核计划亦适用于霓虹灯招牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;屋宇署还告诉南方+记者，该署工作人员曾到九龙庙街63号视察，发现一个附建于该楼宇面向众坊街1字楼至3字楼外墙的现存违例招牌，其主要字眼为“美都餐室”。按照现行的执法政策，有关招牌属须予以取缔类别，屋宇署遂通过“大型招牌大规模行动”于去年10月19日根据《建筑物条例》第24条向招牌拥有人发出清拆令，着令其拆除有关招牌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其后，根据有关招牌拥有人委任的注册小型工程承建商呈交的工程展开通知书，有关拆卸工程已在今年11月展开，屋宇署会继续跟进有关清拆令的遵办情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;此前报道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;香港要拆光霓虹招牌？假的！ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;13日，有内地网友发文称，香港引入内地城管的管理办法，将霓虹招牌统统拆掉，并配上多个霓虹招牌被装车运走的图片，引发网络关注。记者查证后发现，三张配图中有两张都是经后期处理的图片，并非真实照片。根据香港特区政府屋宇署资料显示，小型招牌（含霓虹招牌）只要符合相关安全要求，是可以保留使用的。相关人士透露，&lt;strong>;有关部门并无集中清理现存招牌的计划，更不存在“引入内地城管的管理办法”一说。 &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/c67ab3f2ae81a8d40205b81abe6ce266.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/c67ab3f2ae81a8d40205b81abe6ce266.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258277&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;13日，有内地网友发文称，香港引入内地城管的管理办法，将霓虹招牌统统拆掉，引发网络关注。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该网友发布的一张图片显示，两辆正在行驶的货车装着十多个霓虹招牌。据记者查证，这张图片不是真实照片，而是香港摄影师兼平面设计师Tommy Fung通过PS创作的作品，Tommy Fung在社交平台上也发布了这张图片。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/8f77ed5b36ca3c165898f9853aa2b66b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/8f77ed5b36ca3c165898f9853aa2b66b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258278&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;香港摄影师兼平面设计师Tommy Fung通过PS创作了这张图片，并发布在社交平台上。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一张配图中满是五光十色的霓虹招牌，招牌下车流穿梭。这张图片是英国摄影师Keith MacGregor的作品。据Keith MacGregor个人网站介绍，这幅作品是将香港各地的多张霓虹招牌照片拼接后制作而成，并加入了九龙尖沙咀弥敦道的照片，并非单个的真实场景。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/7673d3fb33466a7e395ae148bf6a8da5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;458&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/7673d3fb33466a7e395ae148bf6a8da5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258280&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;据Keith MacGregor个人网站介绍，这幅作品是将香港各地的多张霓虹招牌照片拼接后制作而成，并加入了九龙尖沙咀弥敦道的照片，并非单个的真实场景。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其余一张配图中的“美都餐室”招牌确实近日被拆除了。美都餐室经营者黄醒芬早前已收到香港特区政府屋宇署发出的拆卸要求。施工当天，黄醒芬与其丈夫一同见证拆卸，并与招牌进行最后合照。公开资料显示，美都餐室开业于1950年，至今已有73年历史，因其旧式装修风格成为香港油麻地的“打卡”点，有不少电视剧、电影在此取景，如电影《九龙冰室》《追龙》等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/05d743f63a67bbfa463a1db75684ce10.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/05d743f63a67bbfa463a1db75684ce10.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258279&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;施工当天，美都餐室经营者黄醒芬与其丈夫一同见证拆卸，并与招牌进行最后合照。 （图片来源：U Lifestyle）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据记者了解，香港特区政府屋宇署目前采用自2013年执行的“招牌检核计划”，小型招牌（含霓虹招牌）只要符合安全要求便可以保留使用。相关人士透露，“招牌检核计划”一直行之有效，因此有关部门并无集中清理现存招牌的计划，更不存在“引入内地城管的管理办法”一说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为消除可能带来的公众安全风险，香港特区政府屋宇署自2014年起对未参加“招牌检核计划”的违例招牌发出法定清拆命令，以敦促有关招牌拥有人尽早参加检核计划，也会针对不合资格而参加检核计划的违例招牌或危险／弃置招牌发出法定清拆命令或拆除危险构筑物通知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“重返巴厘岛，通往旧金山”中美元首会晤开启“史诗级APEC”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260607]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年11月14日至17日，应美国总统拜登邀请，中国国家主席习近平赴旧金山举行中美元首会晤，同时应邀出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这将是一次重要的外交对话。”11月初，美国白宫新闻秘书卡琳·让-皮埃尔如此评价，“拜登总统对此充满期待”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“史诗级&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;的APEC&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;自11月11日起，旧金山APEC峰会将持续一周。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本届APEC的重头戏是11月15日的“习拜会”。旧金山市中心高挂标语：“APEC将是一场史诗级事件”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者从主办方网站看到，从11月11日至17日，峰会将依次举办高级官员会议、财长会议、工商界领袖会议和领导人非正式会议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“两国元首将就事关中美关系的战略性、全局性、方向性问题，以及事关世界和平与发展的重大问题深入沟通。”2023年11月13日，外交部新闻发言人毛宁表示，中方始终按照习近平主席提出的相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢三原则，看待和处理中美关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月15日习近平主席将出席APEC领导人非正式会议。当晚，习近平主席将作为主宾，出席美中关系全国委员会、美中贸易全国委员会主办的晚宴，向美国商界领袖发表讲话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;APEC成立于1989年，是一个促进区域经济一体化的非正式对话论坛。 APEC成员国包括环太平洋的21个经济体，该地区占世界人口的近40%，以及全球贸易额的60%以上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本届APEC峰会是自1945年政要齐聚签署《联合国宪章》后，旧金山市举办的最大规模国际会议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一周里，APEC的21个经济体领导人、部长、企业高管及记者等将齐聚在主会场莫斯康中心（Moscone Center），人数高达近三万人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;莫斯康中心位于旧金山市中心，它由三栋大楼拼接而成，相互间有天桥和地下通道。南方周末记者从旧金山APEC主办方获悉，2019年，旧金山政府斥资5.51亿美元扩建莫斯康中心，增加了21%的空间，现总面积达到50多万平方英尺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;旧金山有着历史悠久的唐人街、亚洲以外最大的华人聚集地和北美最古老的华人聚集地。在美国人口普查中，旧金山拥有18万华人，仅次于纽约。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“通往旧金山不&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;会&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;是一马平川”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;进入10月，中美两国高层频繁互访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月26日至28日，外交部长王毅赴美进行了为期三天的访问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三天的行程短暂且紧张。在华盛顿，王毅先后与美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯、美国总统国家安全事务助理杰克·沙利文举行会谈，与拜登会见，同美国战略界人士、工商业代表交流。其中，10月26日首访日，王毅与美国国务卿安东尼·布林肯进行了两轮、共计7小时的会谈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在三场活动中，王毅外长都提及了关键词“旧金山”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“重返巴厘岛，通往旧金山”，据央视报道，最近这个表述广为人知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“&#39;重返巴厘岛&#39;是指去年在20国集团会议上，习近平主席跟拜登总统在印尼的巴厘岛进行了非常好的会晤，也达成了重要的共识。”中国原驻美大使崔天凯在10月29日的第十届北京香山论坛上解释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一年前的巴厘岛G20峰会上，拜登总统多次重申“四不一无意”。 “四不一无意”即美方不寻求打“新冷战”，不寻求改变中国体制，不寻求通过强化同盟关系反对中国，不支持“台独”，无意同中国发生冲突。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;“&#39;通往旧金山&#39;不会是一马平川，不能靠&#39;自动驾驶&#39;。” 10月28日，王毅在华盛顿同美国战略界人士举行座谈会时表示，为此，双方要切实“重回巴厘岛”，把两国元首的共识真正落到实处，排除干扰，克服障碍，增进共识，积累成果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这场座谈会由官方色彩浓厚的“美国阿斯彭战略小组”主办。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中美经贸关系是两国关系的“压舱石”。作为全球前两大经济体，中美两国经济总量超过世界三分之一、人口总数占世界近四分之一、双边贸易额约占世界五分之一。数据显示，2022年中美贸易额达到近7600亿美元，创历史新高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;临近APEC前的11月8日至12日，中共中央政治局委员、国务院副总理、中美经贸牵头人何立峰访美。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;访美期间，何立峰副总理与耶伦财长举行多轮会谈并共进工作晚餐，会谈时间累计超过10小时。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“目的是在7月双方北京会谈基础上，持续落实两国元首重要共识，为两国元首旧金山会晤做好经济成果准备，推动中美经贸关系回到健康稳定发展轨道。”11月10日，财政部副部长廖岷在美国旧金山的吹风会上说，其中达成如推动成立中美经济、金融工作组并举行会议等共识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月耶伦一行人飞抵北京时，天空出现彩虹。国务院总理李强会见耶伦时提到，“中美关系经历过一轮风雨以后，我们一定会见到更多的彩虹。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“有一千个理由让中美关系搞好”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“我们有一千个理由让中美关系搞好，没有一个理由让中美关系搞坏。”10月9日，习近平主席在会见美国国会参议院多数党领袖查克·舒默时表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;旧金山“习拜会”前夕，美方10月初派出国会参议院代表团查克·舒默一行访华；10月底，加州州长加文·纽森一行23人访华。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月7日，美国参议院舒默在内的3名民主党人和3名共和党人国会代表团飞抵上海。这是四年来首次访华的美国国会参议院两党代表团。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中美关系错综复杂，既有合作又有竞争。我们必须建立危机管控机制，恢复对话。”美国昆西国家事务研究所东亚项目首席主任迈克尔·史文告诉南方周末记者，随着美国选举年的到来，许多政客会利用反华议题为政治加分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美国国会关键议员在涉华议题上拥有重要影响力。访华前，舒默曾多次敦促拜登政府采取对华强硬态势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“美国无意和中国脱钩，但希望美国公司能在中国获得公平待遇。”10月7日，舒默会见上海市委书记陈吉宁时提到，美国并非为了挑起冲突，而是希望在美中经济竞争的情况下，获得公平竞争的环境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;史文认为，美国应该明确遵守“一个中国政策”，表达让中国参与经济合作的意愿，努力提高亚太经济的稳定性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;美中贸易全国委员会发布的《2023美国对华出口报告》显示，超过7万家美企在华投资兴业，近90%在华业务实现盈利。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“去风险化并不是指彻底断开（与中国）经济联系，只是说有限制的。”美国哈佛大学教授约瑟夫·奈告诉南方周末记者，美国国家战略改用“小院高墙”去形容对华战略，但“我们不应该让这个小院扩大”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近一个月来，中美在农业经贸方面发生了明显变化。 11月7日，美国农业部派出17家参展商参加第六届上海进博会，同时为美国带回了60万吨的大豆订单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在10月25日，中国驻美大使谢峰来到“美国粮仓”艾奥瓦州，参加中美可持续农产品贸易论坛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢峰提到，金伯利农场的瑞克告诉他投资达5000万元的现代农业示范项目在浙江落户，而今天参加采购签约的中国企业代表将签署十余项农产品订单，价值数十亿美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;加州航道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;加州州长纽森的访华行程更加多元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加州州长办公室声明称，纽森团队的七天行程包括香港、深圳、广州、北京、盐城、上海，聚焦生态环境、应对气候变化以及清洁能源等主题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月24日，纽森率团抵达深圳。他们一行前往深圳巴士集团安托山智慧场站，试乘比亚迪电动汽车。 “这是跨越性技术！我想买两辆，我们得想办法把它引进美国。”体验了仰望U8的原地掉头功能后，纽森赞叹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同日纽森访问广州时，他与广东相关部门讨论了两省州多年来成功的气候合作。两省州相关部门还签署深化绿色发展合作谅解备忘录。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加州州长办公室方面表示，这份新的谅解备忘录是两省州于2013年签署的相关谅解备忘录的补充。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月25日下午，习近平主席在人民大会堂会见了纽森。习近平主席再次强调，“中美关系基础在民间，希望在人民，未来在青年，活力在地方。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了气候问题，纽森的中国行还有两大目的，一是“促进经济发展和旅游业以及加强文化联系”，二是“打击针对亚裔的仇恨”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在加州从政多年，纽森是中美两国地方经贸合作的亲历者和推动者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纽森担任旧金山市市长时曾三次访华。 2005年，纽森与已故联邦国会参议员黛安·范因斯坦访华时，正逢上海与旧金山结成友好城市25周年。 2008年，纽森专门设立了旧金山对华办公室，以服务中国企业赴当地投资合作和当地企业迈向中国市场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，加州连起中美交流的航道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据美国人口普查数据显示，超过4%的加州人和超过10%的旧金山湾区人拥有华裔血统。洛杉矶港是美国参与中美贸易的最大港口，上海-洛杉矶航线是全球最繁忙的海运航线之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“中国越成功，世界就越成功。”纽森在回答央视采访时表示，他不认同所谓的“去风险”和“脱钩”，他说可以从世界“多元化”和正面竞争的角度来看待。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一处回水丨事关告别]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260546]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/pOFXgYDzOTEV7i3fl7ax1TpBauQnnpPMM4B9TPhc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/pOFXgYDzOTEV7i3fl7ax1TpBauQnnpPMM4B9TPhc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258154&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;金沙江。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长江一夜变色。昨天傍晚从宜宾金沙江大桥经过时，望着还带绿，今天上午在李庄，趴在江边湿地的栏杆上看，已是一片浑黄，上游冲下来的浮萍载浮载沉，我的游泳计划暂时泡汤。不知为什么，这个夏天特别想游泳，去开阔的、没有天花板的水域游泳，来宜宾一大半原因就是游长江，之前看朋友发的照片，岷江淡黄，金沙江青碧，在宜宾交而不融，拉出一条长长分界线，我想到分界线上去看一看。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李庄早已整饬一新，除了个别幽静的庭院（譬如同济医学院旧址），不容易唤起对历史现场的想象，倒是几公里外板栗坳的“中研院”史语所旧址，因为和村民没有谈拢安置条件，保持了某种程度的“原汁原味”，当然你也可以说是破败。那个叫“田𡎚上”的杂院儿，左手屋顶塌了，就势圈几只大鹅，与躲在暗处的狗儿一起，对陌生人发出不耐烦的警告。往里走是个合院，青石地板，堆着柴火、竹竿和杂物，破旧电线横七竖八缠绕着黑瓦木墙，一只珍珠鸡站在高高的门槛上，墙上贴着好几张“此处危险，请勿靠近”的警示牌。住在这里的大哥告诉我，院子里有四五户人，上面让他们搬，但补偿标准只有750米一平，这个价格在别的地方买不起房，所以只要老屋不塌，他们就会一直住下去。要不是门口一块牌子的介绍，我断不知这里曾是史语所图书馆——还是“战时最好的中国文科图书馆”，啊，我想起来了，当时北大文科研究所之所以要离开昆明，跟史语所来李庄，就是因为他们丰富的古籍藏书。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老屋外面正对一亩荷塘，荷叶拥叠，荷花星点，配上对岸密密的竹，淡蓝的天，有几分雅致，当年这里可曾“谈笑有鸿儒”？但鸿儒大概和我一样，“汗出如浆”。雨后阳光毒辣，地表万物蒸腾，川南的溽热露了真章。 1941年夏天，梅贻琦、郑天挺、罗常培三人由昆明飞重庆，向国民政府教育部接洽西南联大校务，又顺江而上去四川，拜访迁到大后方的学术机构，走到李庄时，日记里处处喊热：“晚上温度表始终没降到九十度（摄氏32.22度）以下，热得我通宵没睡着”，“中午到镇上吃了一次饭，刚吹干了的汗衫又湿透了”（罗常培），“汗湿遍体，非只一次矣”，“去外衣打赤膊，并不更凉爽，只汗流较方便耳”（梅贻琦）。他们没有留下纳凉长江的记录，倒是和朋友们的交谈——听梁方仲谈陕北的考察，听凌纯声谈滇缅勘界的故事——“好像服了清凉散一样，给我们祛除了不少的暑气”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我坐车回宜宾，在老城区下车，所谓“古街”十分无聊，转到戎州大桥上看金沙江与岷江汇合，金沙江更浑了。闷热难耐，我浑身湿透，跟桥上的看桥人（竟忘了问他的职责）聊哪里适合游泳，他给我指桥下某处水岸，提醒我游的时候要小心XX——他说了一个我听不懂的双音节词，大概就是分水处吧，过了XX会被水流带到远离岸边的地方，不容易回来了。我下桥，沿着窄窄石梯走到水边，刚游完泳的两男一女独享这里，他们带了盒饭准备野餐，我问水急吗，他们似乎被这个显而易见的问题冒犯到了，半晌，用生气的四川话说：不是急，是很急！再往下就是合江门，岷江汇入金沙江处，也是“万里长江起点”，看介绍，汇流处水深30米，好家伙。合江处建有广场和“长江之珠”纪念球，最下方是一片和缓回水，以浅黄的岷江水为主，偶尔冲来几条细细的金沙江红色水流，一些人在下面游泳，看起来很安全，但实在激不起我下水的欲望，这里更像城市内涝时一个被淹的立交桥，谁想在立交桥下面游泳呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我决定在宜宾多待一天，等金沙江变清。白天去博物馆看展，见画家陆俨少的《岩栖待访图》，那位隐居山中的打坐者，他的山屋实在像个防空掩体，再看落款，1941年3月绘于重庆南坪，正是日军集中轰炸之时。创作者是如何感受和经验现实，然后完成作品的构思与想象的呢？我好奇地搜来陆俨少的回忆录，1938年2月，他从上海撤到重庆，“在城内怕轰炸，在乡下怕土匪，计无所出”，辗转到兵工厂农场任职，负责记工记账，闲时写字、看书、访友，他曾经去沙坪坝拜访丰子恺，后者在平冈上造了几间草屋，前后矮篱遮护，还养了几只鹅，“因无人介绍，我便自己闯进去，他不以我冒昧，后来还和我通过信。”1941年，陆俨少33岁，第四个孩子出生，他养鸡喂猪种菜补贴家用，但因井水不洁，饮水困难，好在后来兵工厂把长江水抽上来供职员饮用，让他体会了杜甫写的“斗水何值百忧宽”——入川时，他的行李里只带了一本书，就是钱注杜诗，“闲时吟咏，眺望巴山蜀水，眼前景物，一经杜公点出，更觉亲切……东归无日，心抱烦忧，和当年杜公旅蜀情怀无二，因之对于杜诗，耽习尤至。”1945年8月抗战胜利，各方人士纷纷复原东归，陆俨少思乡心切，但买不到船票，恰好有友人做木材生意，遂搭木筏出峡，虽然险阻，但也有了近距离观察水势的机会，“可以细审其势，得谙水性，而传统山水，各家各派，无不尽备，诚非轮船急驶所能仿佛一二。在三峡之中，走了一个多月，比读十年书得益更多……也因有了三峡看水的生活体验，用勾线办法创造出峡江险水的独特风格，只行海内，为他家所无。从而得出结论，画山水必须到山水中去。自文沈四王以下，类在故纸堆中讨生活，陈陈相因，以致每况愈下。但是眼睛看了，必须用脑子想，大之所谓看其神气，小则一树一石，怎样表现，都要有个琢磨……必须带些新方法回来……否则是白去一趟。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下午5点多，长江的水更浑更急了。水幕广场附近，长长的亲水平台红泥汤拍岸，水清时大概是绝佳天然泳道吧。我脱鞋下去感受流速，不及膝深，但撞击力量明显。一艘货轮逆流而上，浪头向两边扩散开来，几个带着跟屁虫从上游漂流下来的泳者一边避让一边高声大笑，大概是爽到了。我沿江往上游走，回到两江汇合处，岷江在对岸直冲过来，反而在这里造就了又一片回水，两水并未充分混合，泥浆中悬浮着许多丝状半清水。一位大哥坐在墩子上，他也是来游泳的，但嫌水脏，“以前一个晚上就变清了，今天还是很浑，可能是上游水库排沙”，又说几天前这里淹死了三个人，有两个人是他眼看着躲避不及被大船拍到水底下的，“到现在还没有找到”。我问他在两江江水交界处游泳是什么感觉，“一会凉一会暖和”——金沙江水冬暖夏凉，岷江则相反，所以本地人喜欢游金沙江，尤其冬天，水很暖和，“泡在里面不想上来”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三天，长江仍不见清，我决定不再苦等，去上游的水富看看。水富属云南昭通，但离四川宜宾要近得多，载我的顺风车司机和我聊天，说水富和宜宾口音差不多，吃的也差不多，“但没有我们那么爱吃爱玩”。我请她尽可能沿江行，于是她选择了南岸一条坑坑洼洼的老路，滴滴小程序死命不肯接受这条满是大货车的老路，一路叫唤，“您已偏航，请在适当位置掉头”。一开始还有点烦，听久了我突然高兴起来：偏航不就是旅行的目的之一吗？没有偏航哪有惊喜呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;惊喜随后就到。车近水富，我在颠簸中望见浑浊江面上有不规则的蓝绿色，以为自己看错了，毕竟阳光刺眼，又不断被灌木遮挡。但司机说她也看见到了。不一会儿，我俩都确认了：对岸，也就是江的北岸，确实有一条细细的蓝色。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是因为北岸有清澈支流注入吗？车往前开，那条蓝色越长越大，直到和这浑黄势均力敌。我点开手机地图，终于意识到，金沙江一直是蓝的，只因前方有一条大支流横江自南岸注入，带来滚滚泥沙，以至于把整条干流都染黄了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过川滇界时，司机紧张起来，她的微信群里有人提醒：前方有运管，查网约车。说是逮着一个车要罚三千到一万，虽然只跑了十几天滴滴，她已经感到了“好大的压力”。我们七绕八绕，躲开了，到终点时，她长舒一口气，“你到了我就安全了”，又跑到后备箱给我拿了两个大鸭梨，说是老家种的。在酒店办理入住，我选了正对向家坝水电站的房型，但并没有看到想象中的高峡平湖——大坝162米高，我所在的10层，连坝顶都远不可能窥见，若以水库湖面为基准，我此刻身处水下一百多米的地方，这让人有一种头顶水盆的奇怪感觉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坝下河水碧蓝得令人心醉，十来只白鹭在岸边觅食。吃了只梨子，我也出门觅食，这儿果然和宜宾口味接近，一两素燃面、一两口蘑面、一碗冰镇银耳汤，一共16元。心满意足去看江，最近的是向家坝大桥。上桥就被小小震撼。今日35度高温，水富树不多，整个城市被晒得白花花的，可一到桥头就凉下来了。这应该也是头顶水盆的功劳：水库深水区常年温度较低，坝下出水寒凉，下游河谷自然就成了冷柜。站久了我甚至觉得两腿冰凉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由桥往下一公里多，红泥色的横江在右岸注入，于是这之前的一公里多碧蓝金沙江，就成了水富人的大泳池。我踩着被太阳晒得滚烫的大石头下到水边，一位好心的大哥见我跟屁虫，又多番提醒注意安全。这里水深且急，是游泳协会的地盘，都是高手在中流击水，大人会质问来玩水的小孩：你的家长在哪里？我贴着岸边游了会儿，水确实急，游了半天还在原地，但总算拥抱了这可爱的江水。凉，但没有想象中凉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我谢过大哥，继续往下游走，经过了一处真正的回水区，近岸的水以极快的速度逆流而上，又经过一处滩涂，水里是成群小鱼，受惊后变换出不同形状。再往下，是一个人工修筑的水泥平台，被江水没至齐腰深，刚好用作浅滩，这里水流缓慢，游泳的人也最多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在桥上和高处，你很容易看见河中间因为流速最快，像滚开一样，许多白色的漩儿，从内往外画着圆圈，大大小小的圆圈。但下到水中，视线与水齐平，你看到的更多的就是线条，或明或暗的线条，扰动的波纹，还有水光，洒满金粉的水光是多么迷人啊。等你整个人泡在这清凉的碧蓝的水中，意识就好像消失了一般，只感到极大的自由和快乐，过了许久，我的脑海里才兀的冒出一句无厘头的话：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我愿意大口大口喝水。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我闻到了小时候在湘江游泳时熟悉的淡淡水草味，从水里看天空的粼粼波光也似曾相识，河中间有呼啸声，像是神灵在筛豆子，偶有水流冲过来，让你身体一激灵。自由。自由从周围无尽伸展开来。越往深处越感到自由。可惜我不会写诗——我在水里想——只有诗歌才配得上这里的韵律。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“让人们游泳吧！”这是住在柏林的作家PaulHockenos给《纽约时报》一篇专栏文章的标题。这个炎热的夏天，他造访了慕尼黑，发现全城的人几乎都在伊萨尔河纳凉游泳。这条多瑙河支流曾经污染严重，2000年，彼时气候危机还未加剧，欧洲的夏天不算难熬，慕尼黑有先见之明地对伊萨尔河进行了大规模修复，这项历时11年、耗资3800万美元的工程包括净化河水、扩大河漫滩、改造河岸以适应春季来自阿尔卑斯山区的汹涌融雪洪水。如今，这条河成了一个重要的公共空间，为人们提供避暑场所。 “我没有阳台，没有花园，但我有伊萨尔河。”Paul Hockenos的一位朋友说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是后来才意识到，我这么想要到一条真正的河流里去游泳，是为了告别一种害怕的感受，一种过去几年累积起来的自己吓唬自己的感受。在水里感受到的纯然的自由和快乐，实在是久违了。 “疗愈”如今已经被过度使用，但它仍然是真实的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想起前些年大量研习西南联大时，对那段历史当然有千般观感，但印象最深的无非三字：“不害怕”。我也想起好多好多年前初当记者时，采访一位学者，他谈起“听喝”，“听喝那是奴才，结果现在有人自愿听喝，一挥手大家全走，就这样。”那时候我经历太浅，只能在字面上理解“听喝”对一个人完整性的破坏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;游泳后的一整天我都沉浸在快乐和幸福之中，傍晚又沿着金沙江走了半天。好像整个城市的人都在江边散步，有大河的城市确实是被祝福的。回酒店的路上，我远远看到大坝上头一排灯光，像是城墙。我吃着4.99元的香辣鸡腿堡看完了游泳世锦赛最后一日比赛，脑子里不断重现下午看到的、摸到的、置身其中的碧蓝。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[校领导被举报收实习回扣应调查，职校不能把学生当“猪仔”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260573]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，打假人王海通过网络公开举报江西某职业学校领导从学生实习中牟取巨额收入，引起公众极大关注。11月13日，涉事职业学校所在的江西省新余市通报：已由市教育局、人社局等组成联合调查组调查核实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据极目新闻报道，王海在网络发文称，江西新能源科技职业学院的张老师无意中发现同在该校负责学生实习工作的前妻颜某某有600万元巨额存款，同时还发现了一个涉及金额数千万元的账本，记录了多家人力资源机构转账给学校多名领导的资金明细和分配比例。其中一页显示，仅一个39名学生、为期4个月的实习，就收到“管理费”近13万元，其前妻分了1.4万多元，另一名领导则分了11.4万多元。爆料人提供的银行流水也显示，从2017年来，有多家人力资源公司以“用工企业支付培养费用”的名义，频频向颜某一关系人的账户转账，金额从数千元到数万元不等。这些钱最终到了颜某某手里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;600多万的数字有点骇人听闻，从文中看这还只是院长助理分到的小头。王海的举报是否属实，有待相关部门的调查结果。不过，职业学校以组织学生实习为名，行“劳务输出”之实，从实习企业处收取费用，甚至克扣学生的实习报酬，早就不是什么秘密。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几年前，由于一些制造业企业招工难，职业学校学生成为一些劳务中介公司的目标。职业学校于是找到生财之道：与劳务中介合作，以实习的名义，组织学生到企业工作，收取管理费、培养费等。极目新闻的报道中，江西新能源科技职业学院一名前副院长就坦承，学生到企业实习工作，学校确实能收到一笔管理费用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些钱，企业当然不会白出。在一些地方，除了学校收钱，学校领导和实习带队老师个人也能分到回扣。这次事件中，爆料人提供的一页账本显示，该校学生到苏州某企业实习，每工作一小时，学生的报酬是15元，学校则可以得到4元，院长助理个人也能收到5毛钱。当然事件真相究竟如何，还有待调查。不过类似事件此前已有先例，2021年，贵州铝业技师学院被曝通过中介公司安排学生实习，从实习单位给学生的报酬中收取每生每月1500元至2000元不等的费用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;职校学生到企业“实习”，报酬低，劳动强度却不低。2021年，湖南临武县职中组织学生到该县一家公司实习，每天要干活11个小时。同年，湖北丹江口市汉江科技学校部分学生被学校安排到某科技企业实习，每天工作十几个小时。而这些“实习”工作，往往与他们所学的专业没什么关系。计算机专业学生被安排“搬箱子”，学护理专业的被安排到美容院、发廊。这些所谓实习，其实就是纯粹的体力劳动，完全起不到提升职业技能的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长时间繁重的劳动，就是成年人也受不了，更别说刚成年甚至还未成年的职校生了。不少人的身心受到严重的摧残，甚至有人因为疲劳工作等原因导致工伤致残。临武县职中的学生小鹏就在实习中被机器夹伤了手，导致两根手指被截肢。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在人们的印象里，普通高校大学生毕业前也都会实习，但学校通常不会组织安排，最多是提供相关信息，要学生自己联系实习单位。但职业学校不同。职业教育法规要求学生“应当”参加实习实训，实习经历就成了职校学生毕业的必要条件。一些职校拿着毕业证这一尚方宝剑，逼着学生参加学校组织的“实习”，“不去实习就不给毕业证”，实习时间太短，不能为学校带来足够“价值“”，也不行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;职业学校大多数是中专层次，招收初中毕业生。因为中考“五五分流”，有大约一半初中毕业生要上职校。这些学生大多才十五六岁，刚刚结束更侧重管束的教育阶段，心智并没有完全发育成熟。相对于这些稚嫩的学生，学校、老师无疑处于绝对的优势地位。这些权力，在一些学校和老师手里就异变成了割学生韭菜的镰刀。这些学校，不是想着怎么提高教学质量，教会学生真正的职业技能，而是挖空心思想怎么能在学生身上压榨出更多的油水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的职业教育，难怪家长和学生们弃之如敝履。要搞好职业教育，首先要打破这种畸形的权力格局，让职业学校回归教育服务提供者的角色。学生则可以来去自由，不被学籍束缚，如果觉得某所学校、某个专业不好，可以随时离开去其他学校或专业，只要学满足够的课程、学会足够的技能，都可以毕业。这样才会促使职业学校在教育市场展开竞争。以教学、就业质量等指标赢得学生和家长的青睐，而不是把学生当成摇钱树和待割的羔羊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说 | 朱勇：历史研究联系现实要恰如其分，不能过于牵强]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260581]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;博士档案：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;朱勇，1955年生，安徽无为人。新中国第一位法制史博士，中国政法大学第一位博士&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1974年-1978年，高中毕业后，在安徽省合肥市郊区蜀山园林场插队；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978年-1982年，在安徽大学哲学系学习；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1982年-1985年，在安徽大学法律系，攻读中国法制史硕士学位；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1985年-1987年，在中国政法大学研究生院，攻读中国法制史博士学位；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1987年毕业留校任教；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1990年晋升为副教授；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1993年晋升为教授；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1995年任中国法律史研究所所长；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1996年任法律史学博士生导师；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2001年9月-2015年5月，任中国政法大学副校长兼研究生院院长&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现为中国法学会法治文化研究会副会长、中国法律史学会中国法制史专业研究会会长，教育部司法文明协同创新中心“中华司法文明研究创新团队”首席科学家，享受国务院政府特殊津贴。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月12日，朱勇在中国政法大学办公室。（南方周末记者杜寒三/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/94ccde942a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/94ccde942a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258196&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月12日，朱勇在中国政法大学办公室。（南方周末记者杜寒三/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在新中国首批自主培养的博士中，现年68岁的朱勇算是年轻的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1974年高中毕业，朱勇在园林场插了4年队，原以为会一辈子和果树打交道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;三年后，高考恢复，23岁的朱勇进入安徽大学政教系学习。如今，这个年纪或许已经本科毕业，但在当时，朱勇班里最大的同学已经31岁，别的系还有父子同时入学。用他自己的话说，“耽误了四年，但不算太久”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;改革开放的序曲已经奏响，经济领域春潮涌动。1978年底，安徽大学将1977级政教系，改为哲学和经济学系。朱勇想调到经济系，未果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;后来，他继续在安徽大学攻读中国法制史硕士学位，并进入中国政法大学，攻读中国法制史博士学位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1987年6月，中国政法大学学位评定委员会正式决定，授予朱勇法学博士学位——学位证编号是“博87001”，他是新中国第一位法制史博士，也是中国政法大学培养的第一位法学博士。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月12日。中国政法大学的校园里，行人步履匆匆。走进朱勇的办公室，看到整面墙的书籍，时间&lt;span>;仿&lt;/span>;佛又慢了下来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在采访中，他两次提到，自己的经历比较平淡，希望能写得“低调一点”“平实一点”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;朱勇说，几年前，他接受了《（新编）中国通史》“中国法制史卷”的编写组织任务。他现在的愿望是，编写出一部真实再现中国法律演变的专门史，并得到法学界和史学界的共同认可。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“隐隐约约感觉到社会风向要变了”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1974年，你18岁刚高中毕业，在合肥市郊区蜀山园林场插队。当时干了哪些活？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;主要围绕果树干活。包括给果树松土上肥、除草剪枝、打药排水、采摘看护等，果树季节性强，比农活还要累。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;吃桃子的感觉很好，但夏天采摘桃子特别难受。衣服穿多了热；穿少了，桃毛沾到身上又很痒。桃园里树枝低矮，地上都是沟沟坎坎，只能弯着腰把一筐筐桃子扛出去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过，园林场聚着几百号年轻人，总能找出乐子。果子成熟时，需要24小时看管。如果值夜班，晚上8个小时都不能睡觉。有人来偷果子，大伙兴致高涨，分兵把守，力图把人抓住。没有人来偷，反倒觉得夜晚枯燥无味。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在园林场待了4年，有机会看书吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;基本上没有我们喜欢看的书。有一些学习材料，一般也不太爱看。当时“批林批孔”，把孔子叫成“孔老二”，翻出他的言论以供批判。大家觉得孔子的话挺有道理，但听了专家分析，觉得专家说的也有道理。这才有兴趣读一读，读了之后跟人聊天可以显摆。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;也有少数读物在私下流传，拿到书之后如饥似渴。比如《三侠五义》，讲的是包公和一干好汉行侠天下，这本书翻过的人太多，有几十页要么破损了，要么打着卷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;想过自己还有机会上大学吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;插队的时候没有想过这个问题。当时也有工农兵大学生，但名额非常少，在我们农场几乎没有这种可能。我的个性就两个字：随缘。我就觉得，既然大家都能承受得了，那就好好干，以后进入管理层就没有那么累了，还是有个盼头。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那时想不到那么远。如果没有改革开放，我肯定就在农场干一辈子了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你从什么时候觉察到社会风向变化了？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1976年年底，有一天我们正在水库会战劳动。高音喇叭突然转到了别的频道，放起了《洪湖水浪打浪》这首歌。虽然杂音特别大，但旋律悠扬。好几百人都放下了手里的活，安静地站在原地聆听。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当时，“文革”前的很多歌曲不能播放。大家都觉得不可思议，这首歌怎么会播放出来？隐隐约约感觉到社会风向要变了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;正是在那个时候，新华书店开始卖《红楼梦》《三国演义》《水浒传》《西游记》等古典小说，但买书要排很长的队。知青里我有个很要好的朋友，家人在合肥市新华书店工作，我托她买了一套。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你是怎么知道恢复高考消息的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1977年夏天，正是水果成熟的季节，官方还没有正式公布恢复高考，但私下里已有人在传。传得多了，大家就信以为真。在果园里，男青年上夜班，凌晨四五点下班后，先睡一觉，然后就复习看书。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我有段时间在犹豫，觉得学习丢了这么长时间，不想参加高考。我母亲当时在外地住院，通过各种渠道托人传话，话说得很绝，要是我不参加高考，她就不回家了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一开始大家看书劲头并不太高，只觉得别人在复习，自己不复习不合适。1977年10月，《人民日报》正式发布恢复高考的消息，大家就全力以赴了，想改变现状。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我们农场有不少知青报名参加高考。后来很多人找各种理由请假。起初，农场要求知青一律不得请假，上班时间不准看书。但农场各级领导也比较质朴善良，他们也有孩子，理解我们高考的迫切心情，管理上还是有一定的宽松度。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;本科上了哲学系&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;南京大学文学院的莫砺锋教授，和你经历相似，都曾在安徽插队，且都考入安徽大学，后来他成为第一位文学博士。他曾说，下乡之前野心勃勃，前3个志愿都填了清华大学，但在农村待了10年后，只敢填安徽大学。你觉得4年的插队生活对你有什么影响？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;报志愿时，眼界不够开阔，没有想到要去外省上学。我报考文科，感觉安徽大学就是认知范围内最好的学校，就报考了。后来得知，我的分数也只能上安徽大学。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;安徽省1977年的高考，在12月10日至11日进行。春节后不久，就收到了安徽大学录取通知书。虽然很快就要到大学报到，但春节假期后，我还是回农场二大队上班，觉得应该站好最后一班岗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当时我们二大队有一部手扶拖拉机，每天从公共厕所收集粪便，给果树施肥。拖拉机后面的车斗坏了，大队书记让我送到修理厂维修。天寒地冻，车斗上残余的粪便都冻住了，修理之前要用热水化冻，再擦洗干净。这时我想，反正下周就离开农场，到大学报到了，就放下了这件事。之后，我开启读书、从教的学术生涯。不过，未能将拖拉机车斗修好，这件事长期是我的一个心结。后来，回农场看望当年的大队老书记，我还专门向他道歉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我是幸运的。蜀山园林场作为我进入社会的第一个落脚点，让我以积极、知足的原则规划人生，以善意、乐观的态度与人相处，受益良多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;到了安徽大学后，为什么选择哲学系？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;填报志愿时，我报的是安徽大学政教系。大概是1978年年底，学校调整专业，将我们政教系77级学生，分别改作哲学和经济学。那时，国家改革开放的序曲已奏响，经济领域春潮涌动。同学们多数希望进入经济系，我也想调整到经济系。但可能是因为我的高考数学成绩不好，因此进入哲学系。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;大家学习的劲头怎么样？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当时大家确实很珍惜时间。我们班同学年龄差距比较大，最大的1947年生人，最小的1962年出生，相差15岁。别的系还有父亲和孩子同时考入的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;晚上11点宿舍熄灯，很多同学到路灯底下看书。凌晨&lt;span>;四五&lt;/span>;点，路灯灭了，食堂灯亮了。食堂窗外总有一排捧着书的同学。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2000年，朱勇（中）与硕士导师陈盛清（左一）、博士导师张晋藩（右一）在安徽大学参加学术会议。（受访者/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f6e62aad90.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1603&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/f6e62aad90.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258197&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2000年，朱勇（中）与硕士导师陈盛清（左一）、博士导师张晋藩（右一）在安徽大学参加学术会议。（受访者/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么在1982年选择继续攻读硕士，而且硕士从哲学系跨考法律系，开始研究中国法律史？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1982年1月，我本科毕业。那时学校统一分配工作，而且都是不错的单位。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;80年代初，国家法制建设初步启动。大家都觉得法制是国家治理的有效手段，但对“法制”都说不清楚。越是这样，对法制越有期待，认为法律人才很有发展前景。我父母不明白什么是法制史，但他们知道我念的是法律，所以全力支持我报考中国法制史硕士研究生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;硕士三年级时，得知中国政法大学张晋藩教授招收中国法制史专业博士研究生，于是决定报名考试。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;煮面条，谈学术&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1985年2月，你到中国政法大学攻读中国法制史博士，这所学校给你的第一印象是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;第一印象是法大人的规则意识。我刚来的时候，学校北门附近正在修三环路。有一次坐公交车，看到一位法大学生和司机就公交车的停车问题发生争议。司机觉得差不多就可以了，不要较真。但学生说司机不讲规则。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那时的人在经历“文革”后，规则意识普遍不强。法大学生的规则意识，让人耳目一新。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你是中国政法大学招收的第一批博士，是不是受到了“特殊优待”？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;学校给我和同门师兄郑秦、怀效锋，每人发了一台收录机，让我们学习外语。那时候收录机很贵，一台要四百多块钱。第二届博士生就不发了。管理层对我们很重视，但有点用力过猛，可能他们也不知道应该给博士生提供什么样的学习条件。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我学习的语种是英语，学校觉得博士比硕士要高一个层次，和硕士生一起上课不合适，又很难单独给我们开外语课。于是让我去长春参加一个培训班，学习外语，费用报销。培训班收费很高，外教上课，学员住酒店。回到学校，不需要再考试，开一个培训证明就算外语课通过了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;上世纪80年代，博士培养制度尚在探索阶段。你是张晋藩先生的“开门弟子”，他是怎么指导博士的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那时中国政法大学关于博士生的课程设置、授课方式、课时要求、阶段性考核等，尚无明确规定。整个培养过程，基本由导师本人全面负责。有点类似于中国传统社会师父带徒弟的师徒制。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我们读书时，张先生任副校长兼研究生院院长，时间安排非常满，但午餐时间是固定的。我们提议，让他工作日中午来我们宿舍，用电热杯为他煮一杯面条，打一个鸡蛋，一边吃饭，一边授课指导。师徒4人，关门私语，煮面条，谈学术，其乐融融。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;虽然我硕士念的是法制史，但本科期间没有经过系统的法学训练，法学的基本理论相对欠缺。张先生因材施教，认为我应当重视法学知识体系的建构，让我旁听硕士生的民法、刑法、诉讼法等课程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;另外，从导师到研究生院，都鼓励我们充分利用北京地区学术人才荟萃的优势。我们先后到北京大学、人民大学、中国社科院法学所等单位，选听课程，参与讨论，拜访名师。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;朱勇的博士学位证书，编号是“博87001”。（受访者/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/9216f69100.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/9216f69100.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;朱勇的博士学位证书，编号是“博87001”。（受访者/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你的博士论文题目是《清代宗族法研究》，当时没有法制史的博士论文借鉴参考。能不能谈谈博士论文的写作过程？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的博士论文是硕士论文的延续。当时基础性的研究比较弱，很多研究都没有进行，选题不容易重复。在这种情况下，我的论文选题研究难度并不大，关键是要找到第一手的资料，就容易出成果。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在安徽大学读硕士期间，学校给硕士300元学位论文调查费。我用了差不多两个月时间，跑了十几个省，主要任务是查阅各地族谱中记载的家法族规。那时在南方各省，族谱主要不是作为书籍，而是作为文物来管理的。因此族谱多存放在博物馆。各地族谱多已存世100至300年，纸张泛黄，布满虫眼，得小心翼翼地翻阅，不留神容易碎。这些原始资料之前都没人用过。两个月的时间，在十几个省的博物馆，我手抄了关于家法族规的几千张卡片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;读博士的时候，我花了大量时间在位于国子监的北京图书馆古籍库、位于故宫西华门的中国第一历史档案馆查阅资料。那时各个学术机构对于查阅资料的学生，都很友好。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“就学术谈学术”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1980年前，世界上曾经召开过3次中国法制史国际研讨会，但都没有邀请中国大陆学者参加。对于这一点，你怎么看？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有一次张先生给我们讲课，提到其他国家学者的中国法制史学术成果超于中国本土学者，而且相关主题的国际学术研讨会，甚至没有中国学者参加。先生从学术责任的角度，希望我们奋发努力，改变现状，把中国法制史研究的中心牢牢置放在中国本土学术界。先生这一番话语，让我们深受触动。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有一种声音认为，与部门法相比，法制史不太有对现实的话语权。但也有学者认为，真正的史学要为现实作贡献，史学要参与社会的进程。你是怎么看的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;关于历史研究，应该允许在目的与方法方面的多元化存在。可以注重联系现实，也可以注重学术本身。我看到，有些博士生确定学位论文选题，总是想如何对现实有直接的指导作用。我对学生的创新是鼓励的，但也会跟他们说，学者的任务首先是做学术，把学术问题理清楚。古代法律的制定与实施，有古代社会特定的背景条件。联系现实要恰如其分，顺理成章，不能过于牵强。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我自己也有类似的经历。一个刊物约稿，我将稿件寄去后，编辑发回专家审读意见。专家建议，希望我在文章中以我提出的观点为基础，联系一下当代社会现实。我回复编辑说，我的兴趣在于就学术谈学术，就历史谈历史。这位编辑很善解人意，接受了我的意见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;学者或许可以分为两类，一类在象牙塔中做纯粹的学问，另一类有强烈现实关怀，你应该是前者？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我认为学者的价值在学术本身，我的研究一般不直接与现实相联系。我们可以详细梳理中国历史上法律制度、法律理论的发展过程，并就其规律、特色、作用提出自己的见解。如果能够再现它们的真实状态，展现其在国家管理、社会治理过程中发挥的真实作用，我们的学术目标就完成了。至于这一研究成果，能否在当代国家治理和法治建设中发挥作用，我相信读者有足够的智慧，从中筛选分拣。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;人文学科的研究往往与学者的现实际遇和生命体验有关，是非常个人化的。你觉得过去的经历，对你的科研工作产生了什么影响？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的性格，属于守成型，开拓性有所欠缺。即便插队4年，物质条件较差，劳动强度较大。但在那4年，并没有不愉快的感觉。用现在的话说，对现状基本满足。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从1977年到1987年，连续读书10年，先后经历了考本科、考硕士、考博士三次选择。这3次道路选择，难度都不算太大。如果难度大，当时也许就退缩了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自我评价，我的学术研究，批判性不强，创造性不够。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;从“师徒制”到“师生制”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当下的研究生教育，和你读书的时代相比，发生了什么变化？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们读书时，是较为典型的“师徒制”。类似于传统社会手工作坊师父带徒弟的方式。其特点是个性化指导、综合性培养。张先生可以按照他自己对于青年学者的定位与期待，对我们进行个性化指导与综合性培养。指导的内容，因人而异，因材施教。同时注重综合培养，学术研究的所有环节，包括阅读书目、论文选题、资料甄别、观点凝练、论文结构、文字表达等，先生都给我们详细指导。学术之外的社会交往、为人处世等方面，也多有涉及。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“师徒制”的培养方式更有利于因材施教，但解决不了规模化教育的问题。研究生扩招后，逐渐发展完善老师带学生的“师生制”。其特点是在教育过程中更注重标准化培养、数字化管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;和张先生的经历相似，2001年起你担任了近14年中国政法大学副校长和研究生院院长，标准化培养、数字化管理的“师生制”是怎样发展的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在这14年中，我们确实致力于研究生培养的标准化和数字化管理。例如，无论是博士生，还是硕士生，在6个学期的培养过程中，学生要读哪些书，听哪些课，完成哪些教学环节，培养方案中有统一规定，每一名学生都必须完成。博士生要修满多少学分，听几门课，提交几篇读书报告、学期论文、学年论文，进行多少天社会实践，需要正式发表几篇何种级别刊物的学术论文，学位论文要达到几万字等等，都有明确的数字规定。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;标准化培养、数字化管理的优点在于，培养结果可评估，培养过程可监控，特别是能够有效适应研究生规模化教育的新形势。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你会在博士培养过程中，保留“师徒制”的风格吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;从1997年招收第一届博士生，我已指导培养八十余名博士生。在博士生培养过程中，一定程度上保留一些“师徒制”习惯。我招收的学生，其本科、硕士教育背景有法学，有历史，还有中文。对他们的培养，在完成数量化的规定动作之外，就需要补齐欠缺的知识结构。有些学生读书、研究能力较好，但社会交往有所欠缺。对这些学生，也需要有针对性地补齐短板。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在的学生很焦虑、很内卷，为找到一份理想的工作犯愁。你对大学生有什么建议？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;朱勇：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在年轻人面对的竞争更加激烈，好的就业机会更加难得。个人的事业发展，既需要有良好的自我素质，也需要合适的外部机会。自我素质的培养与提升，无需多说。如何面对外部机会，基于我自己的经历和对人生的理解，我曾给我的学生提出建议：积极进取，随遇而安。在规划自己的事业蓝图时，如果面对多个机会，应该积极进取，设计最佳方案，力争最佳选择。在选择机会较少、改变现状难度很大时，则应珍惜当下，随遇而安。在不同岗位，把本职工作做好，也能展示才华，取得成就。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[预防糖尿病，摆脱“甜蜜负担”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260553]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;今天是一年一度的“世界糖尿病日”。据国际糖尿病联盟（IDF）发布的第10版《全球糖尿病地图》，中国糖尿病患者人数居全球首位，达1.41亿人，发病率高达12.8％。糖尿病是一种以高血糖为特征的代谢性疾病。任何年龄段的人，都可能患上糖尿病。</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 19:25:13 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>