<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[成败张炘炀：忘掉神童的人设，找回生命的意义]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257543]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, some media released a video interview with the topic of the current situation of &quot;16-year-old PhD student&quot; prodigy Zhang Xinyang. Zhang Xinyang is 28 years old. After graduating with a doctorate, he worked as an external teacher at Ningxia Normal University. He resigned in August 2021. He is currently working on projects with friends to earn money. He said that he currently only has a few thousand yuan on his card. In the eyes of many people, this does not match his &quot;prodigy&quot; persona. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The video begins with a splice of two paragraphs. The first paragraph is what he said to his parents when he was 16: &quot;It was you who wanted me to stay in Beijing the most. You should work hard for this (buying a house).&quot; The second paragraph is that he now says, &quot;I am already very satisfied in life and have no desires. If I really need anything, I can just call my dad. They still owe me a house in Beijing. It should be worth more than 10 million now, (Reporter: Are they willing to give it to you?) So what if you don’t want to, you have to be willing if you don’t want to.” Then he grinned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The intention of the splicing is somewhat obvious. Sure enough, after reading it, many people criticized Zhang Xinyang&#39;s remarks and values. As the discussion deepened, more and more people discovered that there were many secrets to the matter, and they felt more sympathy and regret for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, the reporter asked him if he was a child prodigy. He said no and seemed very humble. However, the reporter asked him what his IQ was like and how it compared with Wei Shen and Liu Jiyu. He said it was around 140, &quot;should be at the same level, slightly lower than them.&quot; He was still very confident in his intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is Zhang Xinyang a child prodigy? I think so. He showed extraordinary intellectual talent since he was a child, and then continued to skip grades. He was admitted to university at the age of 10, but his test scores could only pass two books. And his father seems to have an obsession. He wants to prove that his son is a child prodigy, and he wants his son to maintain his character as a child prodigy. He actually did not allow him to repeat the above 985 university. It seems that if he went to college a year later, the glory of the child prodigy would be dimmed. , this character cannot be saved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter asked &quot;If you had not taken the college entrance examination at such a young age, would it be possible for you to get into Tsinghua University and Peking University?&quot; He replied, &quot;It is unlikely, precisely because according to my intelligence, even in an ideal world Under the current situation, there is a high probability that it is a 985 university.&quot; This answer is very modest. If he waits a few years later to take the college entrance examination when his mind is more mature, it would be possible to get into Tsinghua University and Peking University, or it would be a good choice to go to the junior class of the University of Science and Technology of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, in this way, you can make your knowledge system more complete and solid, and you can do better in the exam. Secondly, people with high IQ can be much better than their peers in terms of knowledge. However, their understanding of world affairs and human nature and social survival skills generally cannot be learned in advance and can only be gradually improved with age. This is not only important for interpersonal relationships. Relationships are crucial to personal mental health, and they are not irrelevant to the college entrance examination. For example, you need to have this understanding to write a good college entrance examination essay. No matter how high the IQ of a 10-year-old child is, the degree of socialization is incomparable with that of other 18-year-old classmates. It is difficult to write a high-scoring essay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xinyang went to college at the age of 10, and went to Tianjin Engineer College; when he was 13, he went to Beijing University of Technology for his master&#39;s degree; and when he was 16, he went to Beijing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics for his doctorate. The undergraduate school was very responsible and focused on cultivating him. The tutor helped him contact a German school to study for graduate school. “They may be better at cultivating geniuses than us.” Because German schools stipulate that 14-year-olds can go to school alone. “We advised him to &quot;Father (wait one year)&quot;, but it seems that in his father&#39;s opinion, waiting one year will disqualify the child prodigy, and insisted that he should go directly to graduate school after his junior year. Just imagine, if Zhang Xinyang went to Germany when he was 14 years old, his life path would be completely different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, he asked his parents to buy a house and studied for a doctorate at the age of 16. In 2011, his father asked him to stay in Beijing after graduation, so he asked his parents to buy a house instead. &quot;Originally, he wanted me to stay in Beijing the most. You, you should work hard for this (buying a house)&quot; caused an uproar in the public opinion. Everyone thought that a genius&#39;s ideological level was so low. Saying this reflects that Zhang Xinyang&#39;s understanding of human nature is not as good as his intelligence. Making counter-requests was actually a form of rebellion against his father&#39;s excessive control over his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the backlash, rebellion and backlash against my father’s actions have been out of control, and it took me 8 years to complete my PhD. If he had enough motivation, he might have finished reading it long ago. His resentment towards his father and his mentality of giving up and lying down made him lose the motivation to make progress. This is Zhang Xinyang&#39;s own tragedy and the tragedy of his family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Zhang Xinyang said this: &quot;Twelve years ago, I was keen on the household registration house in Beijing, but now it is completely the opposite, that is, I have no idea of ​​buying a house at all. Is it not good to have no job, no house and no mortgage? Do you think that because the name on the house book belongs to you, this house is really your home?&quot; The flat and angry mentality is clearly visible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the interview, he complained about his father&#39;s extreme control over him and expressed how he would raise his children in the future: &quot;I don&#39;t want children easily. Once I decide to have children, I will support them throughout my life. As long as they do not violate national laws, he will You can do whatever you want to do. If he strongly expresses what I did at that time, then I will let him take this path.&quot; This is not so much a look into the future, but an indictment of his father and his mind. A portrait of an ideal father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yaohui, Zhang Xinyang’s doctoral supervisor, once said: Zhang Xinyang is indeed the best among his students, but he entered school too quickly, resulting in that his mind and psychology are not very mature. If he can determine If you are determined to learn and work hard in a certain field, you will definitely achieve great achievements in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yaohui felt that Zhang Xinyang had suffered too many setbacks, and felt pity for him, and gave him a piece of advice: &quot;At this age, you can no longer hesitate and make decisions about what to do. If you don&#39;t do anything else, just do (mathematics) ) This big problem has been solved. If you run out of talents, you can go into business, and maybe you can make a career. Don’t just lie down.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem is that Zhang Xinyang’s super high IQ is still there , but the enthusiasm is gone. Humans are animals of meaning. Without spirit, it is like losing their soul. I hope that Zhang Xinyang can let go of all the misfortunes of the past, find the meaning of his existence, and re-energize his strong motivation to make a difference without wasting his talents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, I also hope that parents all over the world will give their children the space to grow freely and be wary of that kind of pathological control. Whether a child is a genius or a human being, every child has a purpose for coming into this world. Don’t interfere or manipulate too much. Only in this way can the child&#39;s personality and soul be protected from harm and shine with the beauty they deserve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[模特踩八仙桌拍宣传照惹争议，涉事方道歉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257499]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Shenzhen fashion is powerful &quot;The project team&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;released a set of promotional photos&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, this set of photos caused a stir&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many netizens are strongly dissatisfied&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The organizers of the project have encountered a wave of dissatisfaction&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;Unexpected public opinion storm&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Recently, a set of promotional photos released by the &quot;Shenzhen Fashion Power&quot; project team caused Netizens are hotly discussing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0a2a397842c44445b0c68ed2aabf0bf7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;661&quot; height=&quot;956&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0a2a397842c44445b0c68ed2aabf0bf7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251734 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the photo, &quot;the model stepped on the Eight Immortals Table of the Chaoshan Ancestral Hall to take a promotional photo&quot;, which aroused dissatisfaction among netizens, and the related topic once became a hot search topic on Weibo. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0c87c834990b8752664db9a4bc014209.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;326&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/0c87c834990b8752664db9a4bc014209.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251735 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Many Chaoshan netizens said that this is an ancestral hall where Chaoshan people recall their ancestral merits and unite the people of the clan. The models scratching their heads and posing and stepping on the Eight Immortals Table is a trampling on the culture that has been passed down for thousands of years. , cannot be forgiven. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/924a193445b5da72872ba39b0979662d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;658&quot; height=&quot;1055&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/924a193445b5da72872ba39b0979662d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251733 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;What is Chaoshan Ancestral Hall? &lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ancestral halls, also known as ancestral temples and ancestral halls, are also called family temples and ancestral halls. They are halls and places for worshiping ancestors, worshiping gods, or establishing images of meritorious sages. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ancestral halls first appeared in the Warring States Period. In the Han Dynasty, they were only tomb temples. From the Wei and Jin Dynasties to the Sui and Tang Dynasties, family ancestral halls appeared in the Song Dynasty, and after the Yuan Dynasty, ancestral halls for worshiping ancestors appeared. Ancestral halls are common throughout our country. As temples of blood worship, they have a long history and an indelible status. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Deeply influenced by Chinese traditional culture, there is also an obvious clan tradition in the Chaoshan area. Throughout the ages, Chaoshan people have built a large number of ancestral halls, which is the Chaoshan people&#39;s &quot;return to the original&quot; heart. The expression of &quot;respecting ancestors and respecting ancestors&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There are many ancestral halls in Chaoshan area, including private ancestral halls, ancestral halls, family temples, and ancestral halls of famous sages and officials, represented by Hanwengong ancestral hall, distributed in four villages and six miles. An ancestral hall has a history, a culture, feelings, and rich and colorful stories. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The architecture, stone carvings, Chaozhou wood carvings, porcelain inlays and other crafts of Chaoshan ancestral halls are exquisite and exquisite. The genealogy and family history carried in the ancestral halls are closely related to the Chaoshan ethnic groups. In the hearts of tens of millions of Chaoshan people around the world, Chaoshan Ancestral Hall is the most important spiritual holy place to &quot;remember nostalgia&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;What is the &quot;Eight Immortals Table&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Eight Immortals Table is also called the Square Table. When worshiping, Chaoshan people use it to place offerings and incense candles, and when doing happy events, it becomes a dining table. The Eight Immortals Table often appears in Chaoshan weddings, gardening, giving birth to boys and other happy events. The Eight Immortals table placed in the Chaoshan ancestral hall is mainly used to place sacrifices. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;The project party urgently apologized&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Faced with the strong anger caused by the promotional photos&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;CIQICHINA, the party involved, responded&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 21, the organizer of the project issued an apology statement on the Internet, apologizing The statement mentioned: All published content has been deleted and content rectification and reflection are being carried out. I accept everyone’s criticism and solemnly apologize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/316f8cd0bb1c85f9b34f838f0f7b6f47.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1057&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/316f8cd0bb1c85f9b34f838f0f7b6f47.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251737&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/3650890747aa8bdb472bfef4ca7f330f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1694&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/3650890747aa8bdb472bfef4ca7f330f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251738&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/226123ce0d9f20bc1b3afa0d1d3d89a3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/226123ce0d9f20bc1b3afa0d1d3d89a3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251736&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Netizens believe that&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;it is necessary to do cultural homework to promote the &quot;national trend&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Netizens have expressed their opinions on the promotional photos involved&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some netizens said that the ancestral hall is &quot;Chongzong &quot;Ancestor Worship&quot; place, and the model in the promotional photo is stepping on the &quot;Eight Immortals Table&quot;. Making such uncivilized behavior in such a place not only fails to let people understand the fashion elements, but also cannot tolerate this kind of behavior. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/9f5efd8604c93d18163e4ce50516a045.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/9f5efd8604c93d18163e4ce50516a045.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251741 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/5482651b79e8416236f4e30a50aa1a58.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;198&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/5482651b79e8416236f4e30a50aa1a58.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251739&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some netizens have also reflected on this matter. They believe that &quot;national trend&quot; has become a fashion trend in recent years, and literary and artistic creators have an obligation to first promote the &quot;national trend&quot; in new and innovative ways. &lt;/span>;Do your homework, respect and inherit traditional culture, so that the public can understand the creator&#39;s intention to promote &quot;national trends&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/df9a8f64b595413602375280201f4f9d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;165&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/df9a8f64b595413602375280201f4f9d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251742&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f1364ab10c8fe300422e5a5082855533.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;1077&quot; height=&quot;144&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/f1364ab10c8fe300422e5a5082855533.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251740&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/661d176a1b3b98e29fc90ed48054b975.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/23/661d176a1b3b98e29fc90ed48054b975.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt; br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不健康的零食正在打败正餐]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257535]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/LZfngpA9mLXPD7TQd3qljGCP8fD8aLQnmkSsrBQn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;642&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/LZfngpA9ml aLQnmkSsrBQn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this world, there are almost no people who don’t like snacks. For children, childhood without snacks is bleak, and for adults, life without snacks is incomplete. Simply put, snacks are all foods other than meals. On September 15, 2023, a study published in the &quot;European Journal of Nutrition&quot; pointed out that unhealthy snacks are counteracting the effect of healthy meals, thereby increasing the risk of obesity, stroke, cardiovascular and other diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A research team from King&#39;s College London in the UK studied the snacking habits of 854 people and came to two-quarter conclusions. A quarter of people&#39;s daily energy intake comes from snacks, but a quarter of people offset the benefits of a healthy meal with unhealthy snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, the UK is a country that loves snacking, with 24% of people’s daily energy intake coming from snacks such as cereal bars, pastries and fruits. Snack eaters (95%) eat an average of 2.28 snacks per day, of which 47% eat two snacks per day and 29% eat more than two snacks per day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A quarter (26%) of those who took part in the study reported eating healthy meals but poor quality snacks such as biscuits, crisps and cakes. Just cancel out their healthy meals. The so-called healthy meals refer to foods recommended according to dietary guidelines, such as a balanced diet based on cereals. The daily meal should include cereals and potatoes, vegetables and fruits, livestock, poultry, fish, eggs, milk and legumes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unhealthy (poor quality) snacks are highly processed and sugary snacks. The classification of snacks is now roughly divided into original product snacks, initially processed snacks and deeply processed snacks. The first two are healthy snacks and the latter are unhealthy snacks. Take the potato chips that Westerners like to eat as an example. If they are cooked potatoes or potato chips with a little salt, they are original and primarily processed snacks. If they are fried and baked with various seasonings and made into potato chips, they are deeply processed snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although highly processed snacks account for only 1/3 of the average person’s daily food intake, their impact on the body can offset healthy meals, resulting in higher body mass index (BMI) and higher visceral fat. and higher triglyceride concentrations, all of which are associated with metabolic diseases such as obesity, stroke, cardiovascular disease, and diabetes. This is a classic example of bad money beating good money when it comes to nutrition and health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Brits, popular snacks are biscuits, fruit, nuts and seeds, cheese and butter, cakes and pies, granola or cereal bars. Among them, unhealthy foods are cakes, cookies, pies, donuts, pastries, candies, ice cream and frozen dairy desserts, while nuts and seeds are among the healthier snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese people also like to eat snacks. In 2018, the &quot;Report on the Development of the Snack Industry in the Context of Consumption Upgrading&quot; released by the Ministry of Commerce of China pointed out that the total annual output value of China&#39;s snack industry has reached 2.21564 billion yuan. Although in recent years, snack manufacturers and sellers have promoted natural, whole grain, sugar-free, and additive-free snacks as popular labels for healthy snacks, unhealthy snacks are still flooding the market, including fried foods and pickled foods. , processed meat products (dried meat, floss, sausage, ham, etc.), biscuit foods (including all processed biscuits), soda and cola drinks, convenience foods (mainly instant noodles and puffed foods), canned foods, plums Candied fruit foods, frozen dessert foods (ice cream, popsicles, ice cream, etc.), barbecue foods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spice strips, a famous Chinese snack that is widely loved by people at home and abroad, is an unhealthy snack (famous diver Quan Hongchan said that she likes spicy strips the most, and some manufacturers even sent her snacks. A cart of spicy strips). This is a type of cooked food product close to gluten type. It is made from wheat flour and/or other cereal flours as raw materials, added with salt, oil and other auxiliary materials, and processed through ingredients, extrusion cooking, molding, seasoning, packaging and other processes. There are less than 10 kinds of ingredients, but more than 10 kinds of food additives, and some even 20 kinds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This snack is high in oil and salt. A pack of spicy strips has a net content of 100 grams, of which fat accounts for 25 grams. According to the recommendations of the &quot;Dietary Guidelines for Chinese Residents&quot;, the average daily edible oil intake per person is 25-30 grams. The oil content in a pack of spicy strips is equivalent to people&#39;s daily fat intake. At the same time, a pack of spicy strips contains 7.3 grams of salt. Also according to the guidelines, the daily salt intake of healthy adults should not exceed 6 grams, children aged 2-3 should not exceed 2 grams, and children aged 4-6 should not exceed 3 grams. Children aged 7-10 years old should not exceed 4 grams. Elderly people over 65 years old should not exceed 5 grams. The salt content in a pack of spicy strips exceeds the recommended salt intake for adults and far exceeds the recommended amount for children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For children, it is this kind of unhealthy snacks that develops their later eating habits and tastes, lays the foundation for year-round intake of unhealthy diets, and also contributes to cardiovascular disease, kidney disease, obesity, and diabetes. Hidden dangers have been laid. Of course, unhealthy snacks also rely on their addictive properties to attract people and affect their health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another recently published study shows that highly processed foods, whether snacks or meals, rewire the brain&#39;s reward circuitry and activate the brain in a manner similar to cravings for cocaine. Highly processed foods can trigger addiction related to drugs or alcohol. One mechanism is that highly processed foods cause the release of dopamine in the brain (similar to amphetamine) and can lead to withdrawal symptoms (at least in children and teenagers), two hallmarks of addiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Highly processed foods contain large amounts of sugar, salt, fat, artificial colors or preservatives, and contain other ingredients such as hydrogenated fats, fillers and starches to maximize flavor (called optimal taste point), thereby attracting people to continue eating. Moreover, hydrogenated fat or non-dairy creamer (creamer) tastes better than natural milk. Many people like to add it to their coffee. This delicious agent is also widely used in processed beverages and makes people addicted. This kind of fat is more harmful and difficult for the human body to decompose, and will aggravate the development of vascular diseases such as arteriosclerosis. Processed fructose, which is sweet and delicious, is also commonly used in beverages such as hydrogenated fat or non-dairy creamer, which can increase the occurrence of metabolic diseases and lead to addiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course you have to eat snacks. The easiest way is to replace unhealthy snacks such as biscuits, potato chips and cakes with healthy snacks such as fruits and nuts. There are many healthy snack options, including fresh, natural foods. Vegetables such as cucumbers, tomatoes, cherry tomatoes, etc.; fruits such as strawberries, mangos, apples, pears, etc.; milks such as pure milk, sugar-free yogurt, low-salt cheese, etc.; beans such as sugar-free soy milk, tofu pudding, edamame, etc.; Original nuts such as walnuts, almonds, cashews, hazelnuts, pine nuts, dried fruits, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not impossible to eat biscuits and pastries, but you should choose those made with low sugar, salt and grains. The time when you eat snacks is also crucial to your health. If you eat snacks after 9 pm, your blood indicators will be worse and it will have a greater negative impact on your health. Therefore, you should not eat or eat less snacks after 9 pm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[叙利亚总统19年后再访华：加深两国政治互信，寻求经济合作]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257517]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 21, there was a gentle breeze in Hangzhou. As the plane landed at Hangzhou Xiaoshan International Airport, Syrian President Bashar Assad&#39;s visit to China officially began. This is Assad’s first visit to China in 19 years since 2004. During this trip, Bashar will also attend the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China and Syria are both countries with ancient civilizations. From their connection through the “Silk Road” to the connection between the “Belt and Road” initiative and Syria’s “Look East” strategy, economic and cultural exchanges between China and Syria have continued to deepen. In fact, friendly relations will become stronger over time. What is the deep meaning behind Assad’s visit to China? How can China-Syria relations be further developed? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, Sun Degang, director of the Center for Middle East Studies at Fudan University, and Wang Jin, associate professor at the Institute of Middle East Studies at Northwest University, pointed out to Nandu and N video reporters that Bashar’s visit to China not only hopes that China will continue to work on the reconstruction process of Syria There are also economic considerations in playing an active role. Wang Jin also emphasized that future exchanges and mutual learning between civilizations will be an important basis for people-to-people exchanges between China and Syria and an important guarantee for the development of bilateral relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“This visit to China will help deepen political mutual trust between the two countries”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the Syrian National News Agency, Bashar led a high-level delegation in On September 21, he set off for a visit to China and participated in relevant activities in Beijing and Hangzhou. Nandu reporters noticed that Bashar’s last visit to China was in 2004, which was also the first visit to China by a Syrian head of state since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Syria in 1956. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/c2fb9eec2add497b898cc7fa7ac85d2d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/c2fb9eec2add497b898cc7fa7ac85d2d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251764&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Syrian President Bashar al-Assad. Xinhua News Agency/AP&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China and Syria have a profound friendship. Syria was one of the first Arab countries to establish diplomatic relations with the People&#39;s Republic of China and one of the sponsors of the restoration of China&#39;s lawful seat in the United Nations. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations 67 years ago, China-Syria relations have maintained healthy and stable development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The diplomacy of the heads of state plays a leading role in the development of China-Syria relations.” Sun Degang believes that China and Syria have the same views on safeguarding national sovereignty and territorial integrity, and also have a common understanding of the multi-polar pattern. Diplomacy has played an overt role in deepening practical cooperation between the two sides in many fields.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this visit to China, Bashar had already visited Iran last year, and this year visited Oman, Russia, the United Arab Emirates and Saudi Arabia and China are the sixth stop of his visit since the civil war broke out in 2011. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 19 years, Assad visits China again. What is the deep meaning behind it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the world is undergoing major changes unprecedented in a century, and global peace and development are facing increasing uncertainties and unstable factors. Against the background of the &quot;reconciliation wave&quot; emerging in the Middle East, Sun Degang believes that the Syrian President&#39;s visit to China will help deepen political mutual trust between the two countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Bashar’s visit to China is first of all hoping to receive political support from China, including continuing to support Syria in safeguarding national sovereignty and territorial integrity, and continuing to play an active and constructive role in Syria’s reconstruction process. , to properly promote the reconstruction process in Syria.&quot; Wang Jin analyzed to the Nandu reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, the Syrian civil war broke out. Iran firmly supported the Bashar al-Assad government. The League of Arab States (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Arab League&quot;) suspended Syria&#39;s membership. Saudi Arabia and many other Arab countries closed their offices in Syria. embassy, ​​Syrian diplomacy has entered a state of relative isolation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0fdbc92fb640cd041da104ad87aabb0d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/0fdbc92fb640cd041da104ad87aabb0d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251765&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The war-torn town of Deir ez-Zor in eastern Syria, taken on September 10, 2013. Xinhua News Agency/AFP&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this situation, China has always maintained relations with Syria and defended fairness and justice in global human rights governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“China and Syria have a very solid foundation of political mutual trust.” This year marks the tenth anniversary of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. Sun Degang told Nandu reporters that Syria has always supported China’s “Belt and Road” initiative and the global development initiatives and global security initiatives, and firmly supports China on the South China Sea, Xinjiang-related issues and other issues; China also firmly supports Syria in safeguarding national sovereignty and territorial integrity, has upheld justice on many occasions in relevant votes of the United Nations Security Council, and defended Syria&#39;s national sovereignty and territorial integrity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Nandu reporter learned that as a permanent member of the Security Council, most of the vetoes used by China in relevant votes of the Security Council are related to the Syrian issue. China has always spoken out fairly and acted in accordance with the merits and in safeguarding the interests of the Syrian people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The &#39;reconciliation tide&#39; in the Middle East has brought peace dividends to Syria&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On March 10 this year, Saudi Arabia and Iran reached the &quot;Beijing Agreement&quot;. The three parties signed and issued a joint statement announcing that Saudi Arabia and Iran agreed to resume diplomatic relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China is a sincere friend of Arab countries, and Chinese wisdom is constantly recognized by Arab countries. On April 29, when meeting with Zhai Jun, the Chinese government’s special envoy for the Middle East, Assad congratulated China on successfully mediating the resumption of diplomatic relations between Saudi Arabia and Iran, and believed that reconciliation between Saudi Arabia and Iran would have an important and positive impact on the international pattern and regional situation. Syria thanks China for its active work in promoting Syria to improve relations with other Arab countries, and welcomes China to play a greater role in maintaining regional peace and stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Syrian civil war, Saudi Arabia announced its severing of diplomatic relations with Syria in 2012 due to its opposition to the Assad government. Two months after Saudi Arabia resumed diplomatic relations with Iran this year, Saudi Arabia and Syria also announced on May 9 that the two countries had resumed diplomatic relations. Sun Degang told Nandu reporters that China has promoted the normalization of relations between Saudi Arabia and Iran, driving a &quot;tide of reconciliation&quot; in the Middle East and bringing peace dividends to Syria. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“With the resumption of diplomatic relations between Saudi Arabia and Iran, Syria’s relations with Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates, Egypt, Turkey and other countries have further improved, and Syria’s external living space has been greatly improved. This will also help to enhance China-Syria relations, Deepen bilateral cooperation,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 10, Bashar was invited to attend the Arab League Summit Council meeting in Saudi Arabia. On May 22, Foreign Ministry spokesperson Mao Ning said that China congratulated President Bashar on attending the Arab League Summit Council meeting and on the reunion of the Arab family. Syria&#39;s return to the Arab League fully demonstrates that Arab countries&#39; strengthening of unity and cooperation through dialogue and consultation is the aspiration of the people and the general trend. It also fully demonstrates that Arab countries have the ability to take their future and destiny into their own hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jin believes that China’s global security initiative has effectively promoted world peace and development. “We hope to form a new security concept around the world that does not sacrifice mutual security. Rather, they are concerned about each other&#39;s security and form a bond of common interests in cooperation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;China and Syria have economic cooperation advantages&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2011 After the turmoil in Syria, the economic and trade cooperation between China and Syria was affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the bilateral trade volume between China and Syria will be US$427 million, a year-on-year decrease of 11.65%. Among them, China’s imports were US$20 million, a year-on-year increase of 124%; China’s exports were US$425 million, a year-on-year decrease of 11.93%. China mainly exports mechanical and electrical products, light industrial products, etc. to Syria. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jin admitted to Nandu reporters that due to the long-term sanctions imposed by Western countries, there are certain difficulties in cooperation between Syria and China, and it is necessary to understand rationally and steadily promote economic and trade cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to his observation, the prospects for China-Syria economic and trade cooperation are very broad. &quot;Syria is rich in natural resources such as oil and has a superior geographical location. It is adjacent to the Mediterranean Sea and is an important bridge connecting Europe and Asia. Therefore, China and Syria have very great economic cooperation advantages.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters noted that previous meetings There is no shortage of products from Syria at the CIIE. Damask rose is one of the oldest rose species in the world, and the essential oil extracted from it is called &quot;liquid gold&quot; by locals. At the CIIE booths, in addition to the fragrance of rose essential oil, there are also Syrian products such as olive oil and castile soap. Many Syrian companies feel the potential of the Chinese market at the CIIE. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China-Syria relations have a long history. Aleppo and Palmyra in Syria were important cities on the ancient Silk Road. On January 12, 2022 local time, China and Syria formally signed the &quot;Memorandum of Understanding on Jointly Promoting the Construction of the Silk Road Economic Belt and the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot;, and Syria officially joined the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Syrian political analyst and author Kosay Abido believes that the cooperation agreement between the two countries can be expanded to areas such as food, pharmaceuticals and technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the new historical conditions, China’s “One Belt, One Road” initiative is aligned with Syria’s “Look East” strategy. China’s participation in Syria’s economic reconstruction has become deeper and more substantial, and China-Syria relations have reached a new level. steps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Currently, the Syrian government forces have controlled most of the land, and post-war reconstruction is on the agenda. I think the Syrian President&#39;s visit to China will focus on cooperation with China in practical fields.&quot; Sun Degang analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters noticed that the Syrian Minister of Economy and Foreign Trade was also among the Syrian delegation visiting China. In this regard, Sun Degang believes that this reflects Syria&#39;s hope that China will leverage its infrastructure advantages in the reconstruction process of Syria, including transportation, electricity and other infrastructure construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the economically powerful Gulf Arab countries are willing to provide financial support to Syria, and China leverages its infrastructure advantages, relevant cooperation can steadily promote Syria&#39;s economic and social reconstruction.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Syria had already shown its willingness to seek economic cooperation with China before visiting China. According to reports from the Syrian Arab News Agency and the Russian Satellite News Agency, on April 29 this year, when Bashar met with Zhai Jun, he specifically mentioned that it was becoming increasingly necessary to abandon the use of the U.S. dollar and that trade between countries could be settled in RMB. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jin analyzed to reporters from Nandu that Syria’s visit to China also has economic considerations. &quot;Syria also hopes that China will provide more economic support and assistance, especially welcoming more Chinese investors to invest in Syria and participate in Syria&#39;s socio-economic reconstruction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 6 this year, southern Turkey approached Two strong earthquakes occurred in the Syrian border area within 12 hours, and China actively provided assistance. &quot;China will also be an important force in improving people&#39;s livelihood in Syria in the future.&quot; Sun Degang believes that the Syrian President&#39;s visit to China, in addition to deepening political mutual trust and strengthening economic and trade exchanges, will also help China and Syria strengthen cooperation in health, education, sports and other fields. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Exchanges and mutual learning between civilizations will be an important basis for people-to-people exchanges between China and Syria”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson Hua Chunying said on 9 It was announced on March 21 that Syrian President Bashar al-Assad will attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Asian Games is a sports event for Asian youth and an important platform for cultural exchanges. &quot;This is a very important moment.&quot; Wang Jin believes that Assad&#39;s attendance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games will bring important opportunities for people-to-people diplomacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Leaders gather at this international cultural and sports event to share each other’s views, and head-of-state diplomacy also adds luster to this international event.” He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sports represents youth, health, and vitality, and is related to people&#39;s happiness and the future of the nation. It is reported that the Syrian team will participate in six competitions including wrestling, boxing, and weightlifting at this Asian Games. Athletes from China and Syria gathered together to add color to the diversity of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Syrian president&#39;s coming to China to attend the opening ceremony of the Asian Games has sent a signal - he hopes that China and Syria can strengthen cooperation in the humanities field.&quot; Sun Degang told the Nandu reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China and Syria are both ancient civilizations. The exchanges between the two countries were connected by the &quot;Silk Road&quot; and continue to this day. The &quot;Silk Road&quot;, called the &quot;Road of Semiramis&quot; by the ancient Assyrians, started in China and passed through the land of Syria to Europe and the Maghreb region. The Syrian Minister of Culture once said that this road has enabled the Syrian people and the Chinese people to get to know each other and established a bridge for cultural exchanges. Customs, beliefs, and lifestyles have also influenced each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, ancient Chinese silk fabrics and ancient porcelain are collected in museums in Syria. The &quot;Stele of Popular Chinese Nestorianism in the Qin Dynasty&quot; collected by the Xi&#39;an Forest of Steles Museum in China has ancient Syrian inscriptions... each piece is precious. Cultural relics bear witness to the long history of cultural exchanges and mutual learning between the two countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/cf852266838b78b9744c286623c27e8d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/cf852266838b78b9744c286623c27e8d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251766&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Recently, the &quot;Syrian Ancient Cultural Relics Exhibition&quot; was displayed at the Guangdong Provincial Museum. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 20 this year, the &quot;Syrian Ancient Cultural Relics Exhibition&quot; co-organized by the Guangdong Provincial Museum and the China Cultural Relics Exchange Center was displayed at the Guangdong Provincial Museum. The exhibition brings together 210 pieces/sets of exquisite cultural relics from 9 Syrian museums including the National Museum in Damascus and the Aleppo Museum, as well as 4 Chinese museums including the Dunhuang Academy, the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region Museum, the Xi&#39;an Forest of Steles Museum and the Guangdong Provincial Museum. It paints a picture of the magnificent civilization and history of ancient Syria. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jin told reporters from Nandu that China and Syria are both countries with ancient civilizations, and exchanges and mutual learning between civilizations are of great significance to China and Syria. &quot;Both countries advocate dialogue among civilizations. In recent years, China has proposed the principle of exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations, which has been welcomed and supported by Syria and recognized by the Syrian government and people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China-Syria relations have been affected by the rise of Eastern civilization. The common attributes are closely linked, and the two countries have great potential for cultural cooperation. Syria actively appreciates China&#39;s global civilization initiative, which promotes mutual respect among different civilizations and breaks down the &quot;clash of civilizations theory&quot;, &quot;civilization superiority theory&quot; and &quot;Western civilization-centered theory&quot;. In Sun Degang’s view, China-Syria cultural exchanges are a vivid reflection of China’s global civilization initiative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the future, exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations will be an important basis for people-to-people exchanges between China and Syria, and an important guarantee for the development of relations between the two countries. They will add luster to exchanges and mutual learning among world civilizations,&quot; Wang Jin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[羊奶、牦牛奶、骆驼奶……小众奶有号称的那么神奇吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257529]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Shanghai Consumer Protection Commission selected 32 liquid milks with high sales for evaluation, including I don’t know if the results of some niche milk products may surprise you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, with the development of the economy and the diversification of consumer demand, there are more and more milk varieties on the market. In addition to cow&#39;s milk, there are also goat milk, and the uncommon buffalo milk, &quot;Niche milk&quot; such as yak milk and camel milk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social media, these &quot;niche milks&quot; are claimed to have miraculous properties. For example, camel milk is said to be rich in high-quality protein, vitamins, calcium, iron, amino acids, taurine and folic acid. Regular consumption of camel milk can enhance human immunity and delay aging. The drinks of centenarians in Xinjiang are indispensable for camel milk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example is yak milk. Because yaks are distributed in high-altitude areas in Tibet, Sichuan, and Qinghai and are resistant to cold, low temperatures, and hypoxia, the dairy products they produce are known as &quot;natural concentrated milk.&quot; It is said that yak milk is rich in nutrients, such as lactoferrin, A2 protein, conjugated linoleic acid, etc. In short, it is higher than other cow&#39;s milk. It is said that &quot;drinking one cup of yak milk is worth drinking several cups of ordinary milk.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under these publicity, &quot;niche milk&quot; has gradually become a new consumer favorite in the dairy market. On an e-commerce platform, the transaction volume of imported plant milk increased by 176% year-on-year in 2019, and the imported goat milk powder increased by more than 50% year-on-year. The market size of yak milk products has increased from 400 million yuan in 2014 to about 1.45 billion yuan in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, are these niche milks so magical? This evaluation by the Shanghai Consumer Protection Commission answers this question to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nutrition refers to the biotin that can be obtained from food and is necessary for the body. When people eat, food enters the body, is digested by the gastrointestinal tract, and absorbs the nutrients in it, supplying energy to the body, forming and renewing body tissues. Nutrition is divided into seven major nutrients: carbohydrates, proteins, fats, vitamins, minerals, water, and dietary fiber. In 1973, an expert committee organized by the WHO confirmed a total of 42 essential nutrients for the human body. Any one of these 42 species cannot be deficient, otherwise related nutritional deficiency diseases will occur. Therefore, whether something is nutritious can be quantified. For dairy products, the main function of drinking milk is to supplement protein and calcium, which are indicators that dairy products must be labeled. Then, the nutritional content of dairy products can be quantified through experiments and quantitative comparisons can be made. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This experiment by the Shanghai Consumer Protection Commission compared 32 niche milks, including 6 buffalo milk, 7 yak milk, 6 camel milk, 6 goat milk and 7 cow milk ( Milk is mostly mid- to high-end products), with prices ranging from 1.5 yuan/100mL to 25.4 yuan/100mL. The results show that the protein content of 32 samples is 3.0g/100mL-4.3g/100mL. Among them, buffalo milk and cow&#39;s milk ranked first and second in protein content, with average values ​​of 4.2g/100mL and 4.0g/100mL respectively. Goat milk had the lowest protein content, with an average value of 3.2g/100mL. In terms of calcium content, camel milk has the highest calcium content, with an average value of 164.0mg/100mL; followed by buffalo milk, with an average value of 152.3mg/100mL; goat milk has the lowest calcium content, with an average value of 123.3mg/100mL. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since it is a commodity, a very important indicator is cost performance. The average price of camel milk is relatively high, reaching 22 yuan/100ml, which is nearly eight times the price of buffalo milk, but there is no obvious advantage in nutritional value. Generally speaking, buffalo milk and cow&#39;s milk have relatively high calcium and protein contents, making them the most cost-effective products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This result may be unexpected by many people, but it is reasonable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the modern dairy industry, the breeds of dairy cows are slowly developed through long-term industrial production and technology; the breeding methods are also constantly developing towards improving the nutrition of milk; the cost of feeding is also Gradually reduced in the fierce market competition. This ensures that the milk we usually drink is the most cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the niche milk industry is small in scale, relatively backward in development, and naturally not cost-effective. For example, yaks have a low degree of artificial selection and are primitive cattle breeds. Their reproduction mainly relies on free mating within the group, which may lead to population degradation and reduced production performance. The daily milk production of yaks is low and the lactation period is short. The average annual milk production is mainly for feeding calves. Although there is also scientific research and improvement, the investment in a small industry is definitely not much. So, to some extent, yak milk is destined to be expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, to a certain extent, the nutrition of milk is not important, because the same protein and calcium can be obtained in lower-cost ways, such as eating eggs to obtain protein. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there is a traditional understanding in China that the nutrients are all in the soup. Following this idea, one would think that liquid milk is rich in nutrients. But actually, the nutrients are in the solids. Under normal circumstances, the human body needs about 50 to 60 grams of protein a day. The protein content of 100 grams of protein powder is about 75 grams. In natural food, a pound of pork contains about 100 to 120 grams of protein; a pound of chicken breast has 150 grams of protein; and each ordinary egg contains about 6 grams of protein. In other words, 5 pounds of milk is equivalent to 1 pound of pork, and 7 pounds of milk is equivalent to 1 pound of chicken breast. Milk itself may not be a cost-effective nutritional product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, for a healthy person with normal financial status, protein deficiency will not occur. This small difference in the protein content of dairy products is simply unimportant and not worth the extra money. What&#39;s more, the nutritional needs of the human body in different eras are different. In the era of poverty, people lacked protein, fat, and sugar; in the current era of abundance, protein, fat, and sugar may exceed standards. What people lack are vitamins, minerals, and fiber, and what they focus on is nutritional balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, there is nothing wrong with drinking niche milk, but don’t place unrealistic hopes on it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会盛大开幕，电子烟花、数字点火仪式让人耳目一新]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257523]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the five-star red flag was displayed at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games The lighting effect when entering is Chinese red.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/4ef85dd71d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/4ef85dd71d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251794&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;On September 23, 2023, in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games, the lighting effect when the five-star red flag entered the venue was Chinese red. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At about 20 pm on September 23, 2023, the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou was held in the main gymnasium of Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, eight people including Sun Haiping and Guo Jingjing will serve as flag bearers of the Olympic Council of Asia.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/24/26640b53ec.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/26640b53ec.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251795&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, eight people including Sun Haiping and Guo Jingjing served as flag bearers of the Olympic Council of Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, artistic performance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. 1&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/b307bc106c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ b307bc106c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251796&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a cultural performance was performed at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The opening ceremony was themed &quot;Tide from Asia&quot; and was divided into three major chapters: &quot;National Style and Elegance&quot;, &quot;Qiantang Tide&quot; and &quot;Hand in Hand&quot;, which symbolized In the new era, China is integrating with Asia and the world, rushing forward like a wave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, artistic performance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. 2&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/d8fc4e904c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ d8fc4e904c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251797&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a cultural performance was performed at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​of the highlights of the opening ceremony of this Asian Games is that no physical fireworks will be set off throughout the event, and instead electronic fireworks will be set off through digital technology. At the opening ceremony, the fireworks on the central three-dimensional screen and the ground screen were dazzling. The rumbling explosions and the enthusiastic applause and shouts of the audience resounded on both sides of the Qiantang River. Previously, the opening ceremony chief director Sha Xiaolan told the media: &quot;With the setting off of physical fireworks, a large amount of smoke, dust and other pollutants will be produced in the air, which is not conducive to environmental protection. We have made great determination to cancel the physical fireworks show.&quot; The team. It was decided to convey the concept of environmental protection to the world at the opening ceremony, a moment that attracted much attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, the electronic fireworks set off through digital technology at the Hangzhou Asian Games are a green expression of the sense of ritual.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/24/854ec36666.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/24/854ec36666.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251798&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, the electronic fireworks set off through digital technology at the Hangzhou Asian Games were a green expression of the sense of ritual. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, on the three-dimensional net screen spanning the entire venue, the &quot;digital torchbearers&quot; carrying the enthusiasm of hundreds of millions of people slowly ran through the venue and met with the final Torch bearer Wang Shun jointly lit the main torch tower of the Hangzhou Asian Games named &quot;Tide&quot;. The glory that symbolizes lighting the Asian Games flame does not only belong to a specific person, but to the hundreds of millions of ordinary people who care about the Asian Games. This is the first digital lighting ceremony in the history of the Asian Games, leaving a wonderful and classic memory for the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, the huge digital torch bearer and athlete Wang Shun lit the main torch of the Hangzhou Asian Games together.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/24/6d8f1d2745.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/6d8f1d2745.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251799&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, the huge digital torchbearer and athlete Wang Shun lit the main torch of the Hangzhou Asian Games together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the Chinese sports delegation entered the Asian Games.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/24/4fc7fd346a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24 /4fc7fd346a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251800&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the Chinese sports delegation entered the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, basketball player Yang Liwei and swimmer Qin Haiyang served as the flag bearers of the Chinese sports delegation at the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/da141cab3b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/24/da141cab3b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251801&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, basketball player Yang Liwei and swimmer Qin Haiyang served as the opening ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Games in China Flag bearer of sports delegation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that the Hangzhou Asian Games is based on the concept of &quot;green, smart, frugal and civilized&quot;. In addition to the host city of Hangzhou, five co-hosting cities including Ningbo, Wenzhou, Huzhou, Shaoxing and Jinhua have also been set up. Among them, the Chinese sports delegation consists of 1,329 people and will participate in 38 major events and 407 minor events. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, artistic performance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. 3&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/24/d21731e4e6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/d21731e4e6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251802&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the opening ceremony of the Asian Games was performed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, artistic performance at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. 4&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/24/c665c31fe8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/ c665c31fe8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251803&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 23, 2023, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, a cultural performance was performed at the opening ceremony of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[交友软件和心理咨询流行，我们对爱和自由却更迷茫？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257442]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/XAVJTAyaS1jmJuYTnvk1hphirbXo9dezQQZw2tEJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1438&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/XAVJTAyaS1jmJuYTnvk1hphirbXo9dezQQZ w2tEJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common question asked by a sociologist who studies love and emotion is: Why is this a sociological topic? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eva Yiros has long experienced this, &quot;Love is accompanied by modernity. In this sense, it is of extremely important significance to sociology. The famous sociologist Tu Ergan discussed the relationship between bachelors and suicide, Marx and Engels wrote about the relationship between marriage and profit, love and profit, and Max Weber studied sex, even if these are not the core of their works.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Leave aside society. Study’s persistence in modernity. In fact, Eva Iros&#39;s works are all about her own confusion. A few years ago, when she was still studying for a Ph.D. in the United States, it was her boyfriend&#39;s birthday. However, she was financially strapped and could not afford to invite her boyfriend to a restaurant, so she had to do it herself. &quot;But when I wanted to cook for him, I realized I needed to buy candles, cook some fancy food, and I didn&#39;t even have a tablecloth. To create a romantic dinner atmosphere, I needed to spend money, and I didn&#39;t have any money at the time .&quot; Her first book later published, &quot;The Utopia of Consumer Romance: Love and the Cultural Paradox of Capitalism,&quot; was related to this experience. In the book, she focuses on the close connection between romantic love and consumer culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/wO6qeoIC9QkxpJ1sO1z55d0m29hmfIdYK68V3NV0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1563&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/wO6qeoIC9QkxpJ1sO1z55d0m29hmfIdYK68V3NV0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251366&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an Emotional Society Scientist, Eva Yilos has always been curious about changes in emotional practices and related ideas. In the 19th century, when love entered the public sphere from the family sphere, dating culture also emerged. At that time, European and American romantic literary works focused on describing people&#39;s unremitting pursuit of romantic love - &quot;Madame Bovary&quot; depicts a woman who pursues Romantic love escapes the family several times, but in the end the woman is in debt and has no choice; &quot;Wuthering Heights&quot; writes about a pair of childhood sweethearts, Heathcliff and Catherine. Catherine decided to marry Edgar out of the consideration of being well-matched, and Heathcliff felt humiliated. He ran away in anger and returned to the manor a few years later for revenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Very different from this, contemporary love is often filled with more rational calculations. Eva Iros believes that the development of Internet technology has destroyed people’s pursuit of romantic love. “We no longer rely on bounty hunters or good luck harvested on Ferris wheels to find love, as we did before, but through cost-benefit analysis. Looking for a match.&quot; Today&#39;s popular dating software is probably the best example, as she wrote in &quot;Cold Intimacy&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Chinese translation in 2023 Published in April), &quot;Most of the magic of love is related to the scarcity of the partner&#39;s resources. As the saying goes, scarcity is the most valuable thing. This scarcity will in turn bring surprise and excitement. Compared with Under the circumstances, what dominates the current Internet is a surplus economic system and too many options, which forces the self to make choices and make optimal choices. Internet technology happens to integrate two ways of finding oneself: psychology and consumerism—fueling the need for people to find the best (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;financially and psychologically&lt;/span>;) deal for themselves.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/SyjPK1W4qQR6A6dtbCgz5qYOb9FGYSkoWlffmOpX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 1596&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/SyjPK1W4qQR6A6dtbCgz5qYOb9FGYSkoWlffmOpX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251365&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our The interview started from the phenomenon of psychological counseling craze, and talked about the impact of the popularity of dating software on intimate relationships, as well as her role in &quot;The End of Love&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;Chinese translation published in September 2023&lt;/span>;) refers to the &quot;negative structure of contemporary relationships&quot;, that is, &quot;whether freedom undermines the formation of meaningful romantic bonds.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She does not intend to point out that modern love is always unhappy. On the contrary, she summarizes the manifestations of fulfilling the promise of modern love and intimacy - &quot;equality, freedom, the pursuit of sexual satisfaction, gender-neutral care and autonomy&quot; Sex,&quot; arguing that as long as people fulfill the above promise &quot;in heterosexual or homosexual intimate relationships,&quot; their intimate relationships must be happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s just that,” said Eva Iros, “what is more urgent for a scholar to pay attention to is unhappiness.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/lshhUuojPVwn97OODu7Ev8YHkfdFWAF2oEgkq28q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/20/lshhUuojPVwn97OODu7Ev8YHkfdFWAF2oEgkq28q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251378&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Eva· Yilos sociologist, professor of sociology and anthropology at the Hebrew University of Israel. He has taught at Northwestern University, Princeton University in the United States, and Ecole Supérieure des Sciences Sociales in Paris, France. He has won the EMET Award, Israel&#39;s highest scientific achievement award. He was hailed as &quot;one of the 12 most influential thinkers in the world&quot; by Germany&#39;s Die Zeit. He is the author of &quot;Utopia of Consumer Romance&quot;, &quot;Why Does Love Hurt&quot;, &quot;Cold Intimacy&quot;, &quot;The End of Love&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Psychology is a practice of coping with uncertainty&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In recent years, psychological counseling has become very popular among the younger generation in China, and many people have entered the psychological counseling room. The opportunity is often a breakup or setbacks at work or school. They expect to gain a better self through psychotherapy. But this often points to individuals blaming themselves - if the goal is not achieved, then I didn&#39;t work hard enough. You also mentioned in &quot;Cold Intimacy&quot;, &quot;If a woman keeps falling in love with those unpredictable or loveless men, then she can only blame herself. If she does not blame herself, she must at least learn to change herself. &quot;Why do everyone believe in this logic? What does this have to do with neoliberalism? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Ilos: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You asked a very good question. Why do some narratives have more adherents than others? Why are some narratives so powerful that it is difficult for us to think beyond them or explain what is happening to us? Let me try to give a few different explanations: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, psychologists and psychoanalysts have long known about organizing themselves into experts through degrees, certifications, and university courses. Through their organizational capabilities, they quickly gained legitimacy as a discipline that sought to heal, improve, and overcome disorders and deficits, perfectly suited to the core missions of modern institutions: to promote progress, promote moral reform, alleviate suffering, Increase happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, modern institutions are fundamentally utilitarian, and psychology applies this utilitarian philosophy to the mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third reason lies in the profound changes in society. All social relations tend to be democratized, which sociologists call social roles (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti ;&quot;>;Reporter&#39;s Note: In sociological theory, &quot;social role&quot; stipulates a specific scope of a person&#39;s activities and the rights, obligations, and behavioral norms that are commensurate with the person&#39;s status. It is society&#39;s behavioral expectations for a person in a specific position&lt; /span>;) no longer plays a fundamental role. That is, people are fathers and husbands, mothers and wives, girlfriends and friends, but they don&#39;t know how to play their roles in them, and all of these roles come with people&#39;s personalities and true selves. This means we no longer have guidelines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The demand for psychology comes not only from the disappearance of social roles, but also from the disappearance of clear guidelines and authority. Individuals should know from within who they are and what they should do. But the problem is, they often don&#39;t know what to do. Psychology is a practice of dealing with uncertainties: Who am I? what should I do? Should I prioritize happiness or responsibility? In a world pre-ordained by society and the divine universe, the answers to these questions are obvious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/5RXnjGIsyIRQfkM8GJTfAJCw9jZOMTpqad9p4akl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;961&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/5RXnjGIsyIRQfkM8GJTfAJCw9jZOMTpqad9p4akl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the movie &quot;Love in the Evening&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The demise of traditional romantic love&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​of the changes in modern love is the popularity of dating software, such as Tinder and Hinge , similar software is also very popular in China. People who use dating apps to date often complain about how instrumental it is—you have to introduce yourself and ask the same questions every time you meet someone new. You also mentioned in &quot;Cold Intimacy&quot; that some interviewees expressed a certain boredom and cynicism. Do you think this cynicism marks a radical departure from traditional romantic culture in modern online love? Could you please explain it in detail? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Ilos:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2016, dating app Hinge found that 1 in 500 swipes on the app exchanged phone numbers . That same year, the company further surveyed 300 of its users, revealing that 81% had never found a long-term relationship on any swipe-based dating app ( ;&quot;>;Data comes from &quot;The Atlantic Monthly&quot;&lt;/span>;). However, Internet dating sites have always been extremely profitable because of their ability to commodify the hope of meeting someone, and that hope keeps people willing to continue using them despite feelings of disillusionment. I think this oscillation between disappointment and resilience is at the heart of people&#39;s use of online dating. Yes, I think it does represent some departure from the traditional model of love, but it also wants to preserve the traditional model. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Objectively speaking, traditional romantic love occurs in a small social network. Many times, people know each other, either through their parents or reputation, and belong to the same circle. In comparison, the social relationships of online encounters are more diffuse. Another change is that people’s choices have become incredibly wide. This is completely new and changes the ecology of human relationships. Generally speaking, we develop emotional attachments to others based on what we think is possible. If you live in a village you can only choose from this range. But if the choices expand, you think you have a better choice and quickly move on to the next person. Breaking up is also much less expensive because you think you can find someone who is your equal or better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is this departure just influenced by the Internet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Technology cannot operate in a cultural vacuum. Without sexual liberation, people wouldn&#39;t have a variety of partners, and this departure wouldn&#39;t happen. Dating software has achieved and completed sexual liberation, changing the way people used taboos and morals to define sexual behavior in the past. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Imagination has always been a part of romantic love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;People who use social software to make friends have a more detailed definition of relationships and have developed many terms, such as hookups and FWB (friends with benefit), which refer to relationships that are both friendships and include sexual relations. They There are no commitments and constraints, and there is no emotional attachment), situationship (referring to the relationship between two people being closer than friends, but not to the level of lovers), etc. Why are modern people’s relationships more fragile and uncertain than in the past? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Simply put, it’s because we have the freedom to do what we want with our relationships and ourselves. Individuals are no longer defined by social roles and rules; they must create them themselves, which also creates chaos and uncertainty. Chaos and uncertainty are considered psychological categories, but I think they should also be sociological categories, because many situations in chaos and uncertainty are defined by individuals, and the rules of behavior of individuals are different from those of traditional society. The way things work is often very different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The traditional imagination of romantic love is based on the body The attraction is also based on accumulated experience in the past; and the Internet separates imagination from people&#39;s real encounters, allowing the two to occur at different points in time. Therefore, some people often face the dilemma of &quot;turning up as quickly as possible&quot; and then give up the idea of ​​using dating apps to find love. What kind of person can establish a private romantic relationship on the Internet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Ilos: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I’m not sure we can determine who can establish relationships in the network. Are you talking about being in a relationship with someone you have never met and will never meet? Or is it a relationship that begins online and continues offline? Imagination has always been a part of romantic love, and you will attribute many fictional virtues to the one you love. Sometimes people fall in love with someone they&#39;ve never spoken to. Laura and Petrarch are one of the most famous lovers in the history of the Western Renaissance, but in fact they almost never communicated. Petrarch loved Laura as one would love the Virgin Mary, or, in other words, he loved Laura as a teenager falls in love with a pop singer. The difference with the Internet is this - you already know a lot about this person, except for the most important thing: how their physical presence affects you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Love, freedom, commitment phobia&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Another dilemma of dating software is the difficulty in establishing a relationship between both parties. In &quot;Love, Why Does It Hurt?&quot; &quot;Although commitment phobia seems to apply to both men and women, no matter from a time perspective or a cultural perspective, commitment phobia is unique to men. In comparison, women are more willing to enter into relationships.&quot; committed relationship.&quot; What makes this difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Men cultivate power and control, which means they cannot allow themselves to be vulnerable. Women, on the other hand, are responsible for almost all of the caregiving work in society. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the above context, those who advocate sexual freedom Is the dating market exacerbating gender inequality? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Ilos: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It goes in contradictory directions. Encounters between opposite sexes became more sexualized, that is, sex was the goal and people&#39;s worth was largely determined based on their sexual attraction. A very attractive woman will have more power in the sexual realm than many men. But overall, the sexual realm is still dominated by powerful men who have control over young, attractive women. Trump and Melania are a classic example of what scholar Paola Tabet calls a heterosexual bargain: women STKaiti;&quot;>;preferably beautiful&lt;/span>;) provides sex, and the man gives her power (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;in the form of money or social connections&lt; /span>;). Traditionally, in the realm of sex, men have power and women have sex, and they trade. In a sexually free marketplace, the situation becomes even more complicated when there are no taboos or prohibitions on people accessing sex. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Modern love advocates love, marriage, and sex Freedom, which emphasizes that people have the freedom to enter into relationships, actually means that people have the freedom to leave relationships. You call it the negative structure of contemporary relationships. Although freedom is often given a positive connotation, this is not necessarily the case in intimate relationships. How do you view the relationship between love and freedom? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The history of freedom is complex. When we talk about freedom, it is mostly seen in terms of political and economic aspects, such as natural human rights. Capitalist markets provide a lot of freedom for the circulation of goods and contracts between workers and capitalists. But there is also a history of emotional freedom that perhaps predates both previous histories: that of the individual&#39;s claim to autonomy from fatherhood, monarchy, and community, in which love plays an important role. Tristan and Isolde or Romeo and Juliet survive in our classics precisely because they illustrate the process by which individuals gain freedom from community. In the West, love and freedom are synonymous, an affirmation of individual autonomy. But this freedom has become what I call the “negative structure of contemporary relationships,” which is the freedom for people to say no and refuse to enter a relationship. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Having studied the sociology of emotions for many years, do you think intimacy Is the only direction for relationships to become more negative and alienated? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Eva Iros:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think we have higher demands on intimacy now: respect; expression of our true selves; education us; pique our interest. This far exceeds what we expected from it in the past. We get more intimacy from our relationships than we did in the past, but we’re also more attentive to our own emotions and whether we’re being respected—which can make relationships more fluid and easier to ignite ( explosive). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Thanks to Chen Meiyi and Huang Qiuye for their help with this article. Reference sources: France Culture, GUERNICA.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国代表团夺得杭州亚运会首枚金牌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257521]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 09:15:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/24/de131f0c0533d7f014cf4bd26920a3b9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1974&quot; height=&quot;1125&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/de131f0c0533d7f014cf4bd26920a3b 9. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251793&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 24, the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou, women&#39;s rowing In the lightweight double sculls final, the Chinese pair Zou Jiaqi/Qiu Xiuping won the gold medal. This was the first gold medal produced in this Asian Games and the first gold medal won by the Chinese delegation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[曹禺：现代话剧艺术的高峰丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256384]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-24 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 24 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蒙冤入狱29年获787万多元国家赔偿：“追责必须落到责任主体”丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257505]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Tan Xiuyi, who was wrongfully raped and murdered and imprisoned for 29 years, recently received more than 7.87 million yuan in state compensation. Examining this case, which was selected for inclusion in the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate&#39;s work report to the National People&#39;s Congress, may help prevent unjust, false and wrong cases from recurring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Red Star News, what led to Tan Xiuyi’s injustice was a massacre that occurred in the summer of 1993: On the evening of July 16, 1993, Tan Hong, a villager in Qiantan Village, Tanzhuang Town, Shangshui County, Zhoukou, Henan Province ( A family of three (pseudonym) and his parents were murdered, and Tan Xiuyi, a 39-year-old fellow villager at the time, was identified as a suspect. At the end of 1999, the Zhoukou Intermediate Court made a first-instance verdict on the case and sentenced Tan Xiuyi to a suspended death sentence for intentional homicide. The first-instance verdict shows that the court found that: at about 22:00 on the evening of July 16, 1993, when Tan Xiuyi went home to relieve himself in the toilet, he saw Tan Hong, who was staying at his home that night, and became malicious and raped her. Fearing that the matter would be exposed, Tan Xiuyi had the idea of ​​killing Tan Hong&#39;s parents. At 1 a.m. on July 17, Tan Xiuyi sneaked into Tan Hong&#39;s home with the tools of the crime and killed his parents. Later, Tan Xiuyi was afraid that Tan Hong would doubt him after learning that his parents had been killed, so he killed Tan Hong after she got up and returned home, and hung her body from the beam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Tan Xiuyi appealed, in May 2000, the Henan High Court ruled to revoke the original verdict and remand the case for retrial on the grounds that the facts were unclear. In January 2002, the Zhoukou City Intermediate People&#39;s Court made a retrial judgment. In addition to intentional homicide, Tan Xiuyi was also found guilty of rape, and his sentence was maintained with a suspended death penalty. Tan Xiuyi appealed again, but this time the Henan High Court rejected the appeal in 2003 and upheld the original verdict. Ten years later, this tragedy seems to have become an &quot;iron case&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Tan Xiuyi did not give up. He kept appealing and had his experience rejected: In December 2017, the Henan Provincial High Court ruled that &quot;the facts found in the original judgment were clear, the evidence was indeed sufficient, and the conviction and sentencing were not inappropriate.&quot; dismissed the complaint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until 2018, after the Henan Provincial Procuratorate filed the case for review, it believed that the facts determined in the original trial were unclear, the evidence was unreliable and insufficient, and the judgment was wrong. On June 18, 2020, it filed a protest with the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate lodged a protest with the Supreme People&#39;s Court on March 16, 2022. Four months later, the Supreme People&#39;s Court made a retrial decision and ordered the Henan High Court to retrial. This time, the Henan High Court changed the verdict of Tan Xiuyi to not guilty. At this time, Tan Xiuyi had been &quot;released&quot; two months ago and had been imprisoned for more than 29 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The trial process of this case is full of doubts. The case occurred in 1993, but the first-instance verdict was issued more than six years later, and the second-instance verdict was found to be &quot;unclear.&quot; It can be inferred that the investigation process of the case was not smooth and the evidence based on which the case was decided was not sufficient. In this regard, the criminal protest letter of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate also stated: In this case, except for Tan Xiuyi&#39;s partial guilty confession, which is consistent with the investigation transcripts and autopsy reports, there is no objective evidence to prove that Tan Xiuyi committed the crime; for the crime of rape, the time of Tan Xiuyi&#39;s rape cannot be determined, and the rape behavior It is also impossible to prove; regarding the crime of intentional homicide, some of the crime tools are unclear and the conclusions of criminal technical appraisal are not unique. In addition, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate also found that Tan Xiuyi&#39;s several guilty confessions were inconsistent and contradicted other evidence. The Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate believes that the case also contains problems such as guilty confessions and interrogation transcripts that violate legal provisions and whose authenticity is questionable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, the evidence in the case basically only consists of Tan Xiuyi’s confession, and there is no objective evidence. Even the authenticity of the confession is doubtful, and the confession may have been illegally coerced. During the second trial, the Henan High Court determined that the facts of the case were unclear and remanded the case for retrial. It can be seen that the second instance also believed that there were problems with the evidence. However, it took just over a year for the retrial to reach another verdict, which not only upheld the crime of intentional homicide, but also added the crime of rape (this is also a doubtful point: since Tan Xiuyi was found to have raped Tan Hong in the first trial in 1999, why was he not punished? Convicted of rape?), and the retrial second instance also upheld the first instance judgment of the retrial. It took six years to obtain enough evidence, but why did it take just over a year to add new evidence that was sufficient to establish the crime? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not to mention that homicide cases require sufficient evidence to be determined, rape cases only rely on oral confessions, which is difficult to understand. Regardless of whether it was forced, at least it must be proven that there was sexual intercourse between the victim and the suspect. Although the victim was dead, the rape and murder were only a few hours apart. At that time, the police also mastered DNA comparison technology. Through forensic identification, it was completely possible to find out whether the victim had had sex with the suspect before his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did the Henan Provincial High Court find that the facts were unclear in the initial second instance, but the second instance of the retrial, as well as the subsequent appeal, all believed that &quot;the facts were clearly found and the evidence was indeed sufficient&quot;? Are the judges who handle retrials, second trials and appeals under pressure from other parties? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case occurred in 1993, and many trials were held around 2000. Although the Internet was not very developed at that time, a major extermination case that killed a family of three still had a very large impact, and the public prosecutor and the law were bound to be under considerable pressure. What is particularly noteworthy is that Henan was one of the first provinces to propose &quot;murder cases must be solved&quot; at the beginning of this century. In 2004, it was recognized by the Ministry of Public Security as a national slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the 2023 National People’s Congress, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate stated in a report that in the past five years, 26 major criminal wrongful convictions, including the Wuzhou case and the Zhang Yuhuan case, had been corrected in accordance with the law; Protests or prosecutorial recommendations for retrials were made in 10 major unjust cases in which the original verdict lasted for more than ten years, and the court changed the verdict to not guilty in all cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For these unjust, false and wrong cases, in addition to redressing the grievances and compensating the parties concerned, should the investigators at the time also bear responsibility? In 2013, the Central Political and Legal Affairs Commission issued guidance on effectively preventing unjust, false and wrongful convictions, requiring judges, prosecutors, and people&#39;s police to be lifelong responsible for the quality of case handling within the scope of their duties, and to establish and improve the accountability mechanism for unjust, false and wrongly convicted cases. In 2021, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, Zhang Jun, once stated that at the beginning of 2021, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate launched a comprehensive investigation into the cases of correction of wrongful convictions since 2018, and has listed and supervised 22 cases of wrongful convictions that were wrongfully detained for more than 10 years, and all proposed serious accountability. Opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just as the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate put forward, &quot;Correction cannot stop at state compensation, and accountability must fall on the responsible party.&quot; Correcting unjust, false and wrong cases cannot stop at overturned cases and compensation, so that there is a sense of justice in the investigation and trial process of the case. Only when responsible personnel take responsibility can judicial fairness and justice be demonstrated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[换个角度看大学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-23 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Why does school start on September 1st? What does an Olympic champion’s academic profile look like? Do you still need to make a resume when looking for roommates in college? There is another group of &quot;special&quot; freshmen this year, have you seen them? Come, look at college from a different perspective today.</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>