<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[18亿元起拍，衡阳政务数据资源特许经营权转让为何暂停？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260897]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;This round of transfers in Hengyang is considered the &quot;first sale&quot; of government data and has attracted widespread attention. Visual China/Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/17a4e58168.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/17a4e58168.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This round of transfers in Hengyang is considered the &quot;first sale&quot; of government data and has attracted widespread attention. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 15, 2023, the Hengyang Municipal Public Resources Trading Center issued a notice stating that according to the request from the transferor Hengyang Municipal Administrative Approval Service Bureau, the &quot;Hengyang Municipal Government Data Resources and Intelligence&quot; is now suspended. &quot;Urban franchise rights transfer project&quot; transaction activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Five days ago, the official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center announced that it would sell Hengyang municipal government data resources and smart city franchise rights through online bidding, with a starting price of 1.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowhere has previously auctioned and transferred government data resources in the form of a franchise. Therefore, this round of transfer is considered the &quot;first auction&quot; of government data and has attracted widespread attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After receiving a letter from the Hengyang Administrative Approval Service Bureau, the transaction was suspended, but the letter did not explain the specific reasons.” A staff member of the Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center told Southern Weekend reporters that there had been The company called to inquire about the project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two staff members of the Hengyang Municipal Administrative Approval Service Bureau confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that the above-mentioned franchise transfer project was suspended because they received notification from the superior department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The state is coordinating this (public data) work, and they will give some guidance before proceeding.&quot; A staff member of the Hengyang Municipal Administrative Approval Service Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters that the project is on hold. , the plan still needs to be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Does not involve national security, business secrets or personal privacy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center, the transfer was approved by the Hengyang Municipal Government, and the subject matter is divided into two parts: government affairs data resources and smart cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, Hengyang, Hunan Province issued the &quot;Hengyang Municipal Government Data Sharing and Open Management Measures&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the Management Measures). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The management measures clearly state that government data refers to various types of information such as documents, materials, charts, pictures, videos and data produced or obtained by government departments in the course of performing their duties and recorded and saved in a certain form. Resources include information resources collected by various government departments directly or through third parties in accordance with the law, authorized and managed in accordance with the law, and information resources formed by relying on the government information system to perform their duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Encourage the open utilization of information under the conditions of ensuring data security, personal privacy and corporate commercial confidentiality.&quot; The management measures state that it is necessary to promote the registration and confirmation of open data, value assessment and other work, and actively explore the data market operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The management measures state that public data that involves national security, business secrets and personal privacy, or that is not allowed to be opened in accordance with laws, regulations and other regulations, are parts that are not allowed to be opened. Any leakage of state secrets, work secrets, business secrets and personal privacy will be dealt with in accordance with the National Secrets Law and relevant regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, Guizhou issued a document requiring that big data authorities at all levels authorize qualified market entities to operate government data at the same level and develop data that does not involve state secrets, commercial secrets, or personal privacy. Data services and products and trade through Guiyang Big Data Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned management measures of Hengyang state that the data rights belong to the government, and Hengyang Development Investment Group Co., Ltd. is authorized to develop and operate it through a franchise. According to the Enterprise Alert, the company is the largest urban investment platform in Hengyang, with assets exceeding 140 billion yuan, and is 100% owned by the Hengyang Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Hengyang Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government believe that the government data operation effect of Hengyang Development Investment Group needs to be improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 27, 2023, the official website of the Hengyang Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision released the &quot;Notice on the Progress of Inspection and Rectification by the Committee of the Communist Party of China Hengyang Development Investment Group Co., Ltd.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second issue reported is &quot;Ineffective implementation of the decisions and arrangements of the municipal party committee and municipal government.&quot; In this regard, the rectification situation reads, &quot;Accelerate the injection of some asset resources that have been expressly determined by the municipal party committee and government... Actively strive to complete the joint review of the implementation plan of government data resources (including Hengyang Mass App) and smart city franchise rights.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;What content is involved in smart cities is not mentioned on the official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center and the transaction attachments. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The pricing method for public data is not yet clear&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center, the transfer of government data resources adopts a bidding method, with a starting price of 1.8 billion yuan, each time The price increase is 10 million yuan. It is disclosed in the transaction attachment that the starting price is the appraisal price of the target, but the columns for the appraisal agency and the appraisal base date are both blank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why did the project evaluation price reach 1.8 billion yuan? Staff from the Hengyang Administrative Approval Service Bureau did not respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the pricing of data resources is an industry problem. In February 2023, Zhao Jingwu, associate professor at Beihang University School of Law, wrote an article stating that data valuation indicators are not unified and data quality standards are difficult to determine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that even in general data trading activities, the so-called market pricing is just the result of self-negotiation between the parties to the transaction. This &quot;one thing, one discussion&quot; data valuation model is difficult to achieve for digital purposes. The market provides sufficient reference basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Government data faces the same problem. On November 16, at the main forum of the 2023 China Data Element Industry Innovation Conference, Wang Jiandong, deputy director of the Price Monitoring Center of the National Development and Reform Commission, said, “Before the end of this year or early next year, management measures for government-guided pricing of public data may be introduced. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official website of Hengyang Public Resources Trading Center shows that the return mechanism of the government data resource franchise project is “user pays”. During the franchise period, the franchisee can charge fees from users within the scope of the franchise in return for project construction. However, the official website did not announce the specific number of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One interviewee’s company is responsible for building a government data platform for a southern province. He explained to Southern Weekend reporters that users who will pay mainly refer to enterprises in various places that have information business needs, rather than individuals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Prior to this, Hangzhou, Qingdao and other places have also tried to authorize operations for public data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Hangzhou released the &quot;Public Data Authorized Operation Implementation Plan (Trial)&quot;. The document states that the next step is to determine the operating entity of the authorized operation platform, and with the consent of the municipal government, will be specifically responsible for the construction and operation, data management, operation and maintenance, and security of the authorized operation platform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hangzhou’s plan states that priority will be given to supporting the development of public data authorization operations in the fields of credit, transportation, medical care, health, employment, social security, education, technology, finance, enterprise registration and supervision, housing construction, provident funds, and public security. , led by the competent departments in the field. Public data that is prohibited from being opened shall not be authorized for operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说 | 卞建林：刑诉法要保障个人权利]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260865]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Bian Jianlin, the first litigation jurist in New China PhD. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1953 Born in Taixing, Jiangsu Province in October. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1960 -1965, Jinjiang Primary School, Taixing Town, Taixing County, Jiangsu Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1965 -1971, junior high school and high school department of Taixing Middle School in Jiangsu Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1972 -In 1979, a worker at the commercial refrigerated ship repair and manufacturing plant in Jiangsu Province. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1979 From September to July 1983, he was an undergraduate student in the Law Department of China University of Political Science and Law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;September 1983-July 1986 In September, he graduated from the Graduate School of China University of Political Science and Law, majoring in criminal procedure law, and received a master&#39;s degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In August 1986, he stayed at the school and served as a full-time researcher at the China Legal Research Institute. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In September 1987, he studied for an on-the-job doctoral degree in litigation law at the Graduate School of China University of Political Science and Law; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In July 1991, he was awarded a doctorate in litigation law, becoming the country&#39;s first doctorate in litigation law. Professional doctorate;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Associate professor in 1992 and professor in July 1997;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;In May 2000, he served as a doctoral supervisor in criminal procedure law;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Served as deputy director of the China Legal Research Institute of China University of Political Science and Law in 1991 and director in 1995;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 2001 to 2006, he served as Executive Vice Dean of the Graduate School of China University of Political Science and Law;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;August 1993-August 1994, served as a visiting scholar at New York University School of Law;&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;August 1999-August 2000, served as a senior visiting scholar at Harvard Law School and Yale Law School Scholar;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;From 2006 to 2022, he served as the Chairman of the Criminal Procedure Law Research Association of the China Law Society Chairman, President of China Criminal Procedure Law Research Association;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;2006-2019, served as Dean of the Institute of Litigation Law, China University of Political Science and Law;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;2003 to 2013, served as the State Council Member of the fourth and fifth legal discipline evaluation groups of the Academic Degree Committee. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bian Jianlin, the first doctor of litigation law in New China. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/18/728ed89d3b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;745&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /18/728ed89d3b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258737&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bian Jianlin, the first doctor of litigation law in New China. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Enrolled into university at the age of 26 and graduated with a doctorate at the age of 38. This year, Bian Jianlin turns 70. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At two o&#39;clock in the afternoon on October 18, 2023, Bian Jianlin appeared at the door of the office of China University of Political Science and Law on time. He was tall and thin, wearing a fitted black casual suit and a trousers. He was wearing trousers and holding a red paper bag in his hand, which contained three volumes of &quot;Governing the Country by Law and Criminal Procedure - Collected Works of Bian Jianlin&#39;s Legal Studies&quot;. For his 70th birthday this month, the publisher specially planned this collection of essays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1979, eight years after graduating from high school, Bian Jianlin left his hometown in Jiangsu and entered Beijing Political Science and Law School, which had just resumed school after the Cultural Revolution. College, which is now China University of Political Science and Law. Relying on employee scholarships provided by the state, Bian Jianlin completed his bachelor&#39;s and master&#39;s degrees. Just before life was about to reach another fork in the road, &quot;a major event happened.&quot; In 1986, the third batch of law doctoral programs in the country was confirmed, and two law professors from China University of Political Science and Law were appointed as doctoral supervisors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1987, Bian Jianlin studied under Professor Chen Guangzhong, who is recognized as the &quot;founder of criminal procedure law&quot; in China. Four years later, he became the first doctoral student in criminal procedural law independently trained by the People&#39;s Republic of China, and embarked on a career development path similar to that of his mentor. To date, Bian Jianlin has trained 87 doctors and 11 postdoctoral fellows. He also serves as the honorary dean of the Procedural Law Institute of China University of Political Science and Law, the executive director and academic committee member of the China Law Society, and the honorary president of the China Criminal Procedural Law Research Association. He works as a professor at Jilin University, Wuhan University, Zhongnan University of Economics and Law, East China University of Political Science and Law, Northwest University of Political Science and Law, People&#39;s Public Security University of China, and National Prosecutor&#39;s College. On social media, he always actively participates in various seminars and academic lectures to share his understanding and suggestions on the construction of the criminal procedure system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unwilling to flaunt himself, Bian Jianlin almost never talks about his past experiences in public. Even in this two-hour interview, the topic never got around to his mentor. And he himself seemed to be just an ordinary student who was &quot;older and started school late&quot;, and he was lucky enough to get to where he is now by accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Accidentally became the &quot;first&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the preface of the anthology, it seems that this is the first time you mentioned your experiences as a student. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t like to talk about my resume. This collection of essays has a profound impact on my academic work. It means life summary, so I said a few words in the preface. I was admitted early at the University of Political Science and Law, and was in the first class after the school was re-established. However, compared with other scholars who entered earlier, I was still relatively older when I entered. Fortunately, I completed my bachelor&#39;s degree, master&#39;s degree and Ph.D. in one go, so I gained some time back. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; What were you doing before you were admitted to the Beijing University of Political Science and Law in 1979? How did you think of studying law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After graduating from high school in 1971, I went to work in a provincial factory. Later, the college entrance examination was resumed, but after all, it was not a required option. Very few of my high school classmates went on to college. At that time, everyone had a job and even got married and had children. But I still have a little bit of ambition, and I have such an ambition to take the exam. As for studying law, it is almost an inevitable choice. First of all, during the ten years of turmoil, our generation was wasted. Basically, we did not learn mathematics, physics and chemistry, and we were seriously partial to subjects. It was not easy to take the science and engineering exams, so we had to choose from liberal arts. Foreign languages, Chinese, history and law, among which law is definitely the most attractive. The main reason is that many of the books I read in the past were about solving crimes, about identifying doubts and clearing grievances, punishing evil and eradicating evil, and upholding justice, so I naturally developed a legal feeling. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Why study Criminal Procedure Law? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was an undergraduate, the school had only one law major, and there was no further subdivision. major. When I was about to graduate, I decided to take the postgraduate entrance examination. According to my personality and interests, I didn’t really like civil law. What I liked most was the “study of criminal justice”, so my major choice should be criminal law. However, there is a certain degree of chance in choosing criminal procedure law. The school&#39;s master&#39;s entrance exams for Criminal Procedure Law and Criminal Law only differed in one subject, Criminal Procedure Archeology Chinese, while Criminal Law was the history of the legal system. In the year of the postgraduate entrance examination, I went home to celebrate the Spring Festival. After the Spring Festival, I had to take the exam. I thought that I would have to work hard to prepare for the legal history course, and there is always some basic knowledge in ancient Chinese, so it was just a matter of thought. The choice of exam subjects suddenly determined the direction of my major, so it was not that I realized the procedure from that time on. value and importance, because in fact substantive law was still ranked ahead of procedural law at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Law is a practical subject. During your studies, didn’t you ever think about getting into practice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To learn the law, you must use it. Logically speaking, you have to work in the practical department , plus I was relatively old when I entered school. At that time, a bachelor&#39;s degree was enough, and I also studied for a master&#39;s degree. So I faced two choices at the time. One was to follow my family&#39;s wishes and return to Jiangsu. The Provincial High School wanted to recruit a Mature judges are more interested in me; if they stay in Beijing, they want to go to the Interpol China National Central Bureau through an old leader of the Ministry of Public Security. I did have some thoughts, but in the end both options were given up, and they were not implemented to the extent of signing a contract. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Why gave up? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1986, before I graduated with my master’s degree, the school was approved for two doctoral programs, including Two teachers were identified as doctoral supervisors, namely Professor Wang Xuan and Professor Chen Guangzhong. Teacher Chen is responsible for the litigation law major. They are also the first batch of doctoral supervisors at China University of Political Science and Law. After receiving the PhD approval, Teacher Chen once talked to me. First, he told me that I had the opportunity to continue my studies; second, he expressed his affirmation to me. After Teacher Chen chatted with me, I was more tempted, although I didn’t fully appreciate the school’s advantages at the time. The most important thing is that my nature is that I am always uneasy about the status quo and have an upward spirit. I have never thought of being rich and settling down. In this way, I decided to continue studying for a Ph.D. after graduating with a master’s degree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; You obtained your master&#39;s degree in 1986 and your doctoral program was approved in the same year. How come it was only a year later that you started studying for your Ph.D.? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I started preparing for the Ph.D. exam before and after I graduated with my master’s degree. However, although the doctoral program was approved at that time, there were insufficient preparations for public announcements and enrollment listings. Due to various reasons, neither doctoral program enrolled students that year. However, Teacher Chen happened to be the deputy dean of the Graduate School at the time, and the school established a new research institution, the Chinese Legal Research Institute, with Teacher Chen also serving as the director. So I stayed in school and worked at the China Legal Research Institute, doing full-time research, doing projects, and writing articles. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; How many doctoral students studied with you under Professor Chen? Why were you the first doctoral student to graduate? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Frankly speaking, in the first year of enrollment, the instructor has candidates in mind , but you still have to follow the formal process when applying. At that time, unlike now, the papers were basically judged on the spot after the exam, and the results were known quickly. Finally, Teacher Chen recruited me, and also recruited someone from our school. He was a master&#39;s student in criminal law in 1984, just one class after me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Speaking of this, it is also a coincidence. If the school had recruited doctors in 1986, he had not graduated with a master&#39;s degree at that time, and we would not be classmates. . However, although we are both in the first batch of doctoral students, he is a full-time student, while I am a part-time PhD student because I have already stayed in school to work. According to the country&#39;s degree regulations at that time, those studying for a PhD on the job would have to study longer than those studying full-time. As for how long, there is no clear regulation. So I extended my studies by one year and graduated in 4 years. If calculated according to this time, it is possible that he graduated before me, then I will not become the first doctorate in criminal procedural law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But the students in the same class later went to study in the United States and never came back, leaving me alone to hold on. Later, I joked that if he didn&#39;t leave, he would definitely graduate before me, and the title of the first doctor of litigation law would belong to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Follow the teacher&#39;s steps&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekends:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first batch of 18 Ph.D.s was produced in 1983, but the first recipient of a doctorate in law was graduated in 1987. Among all disciplines, law is not a niche, and it is not too early to cultivate a doctorate in law. What do you think?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the reason for getting a doctorate in law is a little later. First, the doctoral program was of high value at that time. At that time, the approval of the doctoral program and the determination of the doctoral supervisor required the approval of the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council, which was very strictly controlled. The second reason is that from the perspective of faculty and research level, law was still a discipline with relatively scarce talents and did not have the conditions to train doctoral students. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; In 1988, Professor Chen Guangzhong edited the book &quot;Comparative Research on Foreign Criminal Proceedings&quot;. Three years later, your doctoral thesis &quot;Comparative Research on Criminal Prosecution Systems&quot; was approved. From a professional research perspective, did Professor Chen have a great influence on you? big? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Teacher Chen has always attached great importance to understanding and learning from foreign litigation systems. When we were still studying for master&#39;s degrees, there was a very lack of teaching materials. Basically, each school compiled and printed its own teaching materials. It happened that when Mr. Chen was the deputy dean of graduate students, he brought a topic from the Institute of Law of the Academy of Social Sciences on foreign criminal litigation. A comparative study of procedures. At that time, reform and opening up had already begun, and we were encouraged to study China&#39;s issues from a global perspective. Based on a group of experts from the Law Institute, Teacher Chen recruited some scholars from our school and other schools who studied this field to work together on this work. . Several of our classmates who are still studying for master&#39;s degrees also participated in part of it. I participated in writing a chapter, that is, compulsory medical measures, but I did not sign my name separately. I completed it under the guidance of my supervisor. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, this book was the first domestic comparative and systematic study of foreign criminal procedure. It was both authoritative and precious. If you want to know more about it, If you know something about it abroad, you must read this book. For those of us who participated in writing this book, because writing required research on foreign materials, only the University of Political Science and Law had this condition at the time, so it was the first step for me to broaden my academic horizons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the previous In an article, you called Professor Chen &quot;the leading figure in criminal procedure law in New China.&quot; Do you have any observations about his academic studies and his conduct as a person? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Teacher Chen is a recognized master and an important founder and leader of our discipline. people. I feel that my husband&#39;s biggest specialty in learning is to learn from the best of other schools, to be open to all rivers, and to be tolerant, so later on he suddenly surpassed other teachers of his generation and was beyond the reach of others; the second is to know people and make good use of them, and make full use of their talents. Every time he writes something or works on a project, he can always hand over the relevant content to the most suitable person; the third thing is to be able to pay attention to and accept new things, and constantly improve himself by guiding students. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to learning, the teacher also has a strong sense of responsibility and mission. He cares about current affairs and is now 93 years old. He is still paying attention to social phenomena and judicial practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Professor Chen’s Do personal traits influence you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mr. Chen has had a great influence on me. Over the years, I can say that I have been closely related to him. He followed suit every step of the way. In addition to the master-disciple relationship, my position also determines why my behavior, knowledge and knowledge are closer to those of my husband. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; You and Professor Chen have been promoting the localization and application of some overseas experiences. In this process, what impact has reform and opening up had? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mr. Chen is an iconic figure in the field of criminal procedure law in my country. The development and improvement of the criminal procedure system can be said to have made a great contribution and deserved the most credit. In terms of participation in legislation, when the Criminal Procedure Law was formulated in 1979, there were relatively few scholars involved. Mr. Chen was still in Guangxi at that time. I feel that this was his regret. The revision of the Criminal Procedure Law in 1996 was an opportunity to make amends, and Mr. Chen played a great role in the revision of the law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I still remember that in the winter of 1992, after Mr. Chen became the president of China University of Political Science and Law, his first symposium was held at the school. In the now demolished international student building, the director of the Criminal Law Office of the Legal Affairs Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress came with the director. At that time, the law was being revised. In 1993, because I assisted Mr. Chen in promoting the first revision of the Criminal Procedure Law, I was sent to study at New York University as a core member of the research team. Later, I participated in an inspection delegation led by Mr. Chen to several European countries. The director of the Criminal Law Office of the Legal Affairs Commission also participated in the inspection. After returning to China, the Legal Affairs Committee formally sent a letter to the school, entrusting Mr. Chen to lead a research team to provide opinions on the revision of the law. A year later, Mr. Chen’s research team submitted a 350,000-word “Recommendation Draft for the Criminal Procedure Law of the People’s Republic of China” to the Legal Affairs Commission, of which 65% of the provisions were absorbed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to domestic projects, I assisted Mr. Chen in conducting some international exchanges and cooperation and conducting some comparative law research. For example, it selects students to study abroad, translates and publishes the criminal procedure codes of some representative countries, promotes the implementation of international human rights conventions and United Nations criminal justice guidelines in China, etc. It should be said that it has done a lot of useful things to promote the development and improvement of my country&#39;s criminal procedure system, and also promoted the discipline construction and talent cultivation of procedural law at China University of Political Science and Law. These were unique to the University of Political Science and Law at that time. Other schools neither had this team strength nor the necessary conditions and capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Amending the Constitution in 2004 At that time, Professor Chen proposed that &quot;the state respects and protects human rights&quot; be written into the Constitution; in 2012, when the Criminal Procedure Law was revised for the second time, this article was written into the Criminal Procedure Law. As his student, you have always advocated that criminal procedure law should protect individual rights. Why have you been so concerned about this issue? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Human rights protection is very closely related to criminal proceedings. Criminal procedure law is a typical field where public power operates and an important tool for national governance. For a long time, influenced by concepts, systems and even ideologies, we have regarded criminal proceedings as a contest between the state and crime, emphasizing the punishment of crimes, resulting in the lack of effective restrictions on the power of specialized state agencies in litigation activities. Correspondingly, the rights and interests of criminal suspects, defendants and other litigation participants cannot be fully protected. From the perspective of social development trends, the country&#39;s comprehensive promotion of governing the country according to law and building a country ruled by law means regulating public power through the rule of law and procedures to prevent power from being alienated and abused. Mr. Chen has a full understanding of this and has done a lot of work , through their own efforts to strengthen human rights protection in the judiciary, influence legislation, and improve the judiciary. Under the leadership of Mr. Chen, we have also made our own efforts and contributions to this end. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;It is not enough to do it yourself&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In a previous school lecture, you and the students discussed the vindication of unjust, false and wrongful convictions. Judging from past news reports, lawyers representing many cases are known as &quot;hard-nosed lawyers&quot;. What do you think of this group? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The defense system and the lawyer profession reflect the level of the rule of law in a country. If the level of lawyers in a country is very weak and the defense system is not perfect, it is impossible to progress in criminal litigation. When the Criminal Procedure Law was formulated in 1979, there were basically no lawyers. Interim Regulations on Lawyers were only introduced in 1980. Therefore, the legislative provisions on lawyer defense are relatively backward. However, several revisions to the Criminal Procedure Law since 1996 have improved the lawyer defense system. Overall, the progress of the defense system is obvious to all. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But at the same time, it should be noted that there are still many problems in the legal provisions regarding lawyer defense, especially in judicial practice. I think one of the important reasons is that we have not found an accurate positioning of the lawyer profession and lawyer defense. In criminal proceedings, the defense lawyer&#39;s duty is to defend the defendant, find faults and discover problems from various angles such as facts, evidence, legal application, procedural operation, etc., so as to promote the fair handling of the case and thereby improve the level of the rule of law. By nature, lawyers do not exercise public power and are not members of the case-handling agency. Our management of lawyers is different. Lawyers are managed by judicial administrative agencies, which are part of the specialized state agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In judicial practice, in order to provide effective defense, to protect the legitimate rights and interests of the parties, or to ensure that legal procedures are complied with, lawyers need to be more truthful when performing their defense duties. Sometimes there are conflicts with the case-handling agencies, so some lawyers are called &quot;die-hard lawyers.&quot; But if they are not serious and fight to the death, they will not be able to protect the interests of the parties involved, and they will not be able to carry out defense work normally. Recently, some extreme examples have occurred, such as a court in Laibin, Guangxi, which forced lawyers to undergo security checks, made things difficult for them, and violated their legitimate rights and interests. This had a very bad impact, which attracted the attention of people across the country and was named by the Supreme Court. I think after such an extreme thing happens, the entire court system should take a warning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Seems like this contradiction This is found in many of our legal systems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is not enough to do it yourself. It does take time for the law on paper to become law in action, and various problems will arise during the implementation process. In a certain sense, many of the problems or difficulties faced in my country&#39;s current judicial practice are caused by the development of the system. Some things that seem good are actually very difficult to do. It may touch the interests of some people and even intensify conflicts. I believe that problems in development must still be solved by development. On the one hand, we must know more about the situation and pay attention to practice when designing the system; on the other hand, once the law is revised, the authority of the law must be maintained, and the case-handling agencies must strictly enforce the law. Take the lead in abiding by the law and earnestly abide by the procedures prescribed by law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; In the past, everyone said that law is a humanities and social science, but now it is said that law is an engineering discipline within the humanities and social sciences. What do you think of this view? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no doubt that law is a humanities and social science, at least a discipline, or It is science, and it does have some attributes of engineering. Especially our discipline is very applicable and operable. When we studied in the past, we studied &quot;Criminal Procedure Law&quot;, but now it is called &quot;Criminal Procedure Law&quot;. The addition of the word &quot;study&quot; actually means that we realize that this is a science and a knowledge system. It is not just about interpreting the meaning of the law, but also using it to govern society and achieve good results. Taking the ascertainment of case facts as an example, it is not only an epistemological issue, but also involves axiology and methodology. Due procedures must be used to regulate the exercise of power by the case-handling agencies. Generally speaking, procedural law is an operational norm. It must have a specific set of principles, rules, methods, procedures and institutional norms, and it must be meticulous and operable, so that litigation activities can be followed by law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; With more than 40 years of study and academic experience, do you have any experience that you can share with young students? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bian Jianlin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Whether I am a scholar or a teacher, I actually learned from Mr. Chen , he set an example for us, teaching us to be patriotic and caring for the people, to have an open vision, and to have a spirit of research. This is what I strive to follow when doing academic work. In addition, I often remind students to care about current affairs and pay attention to the present. Many things happen around us every day, or there are examples closely related to our profession every day. Don&#39;t turn a deaf ear or be indifferent. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for how to learn and how to write articles, this is indeed not an easy task. I think that first of all, individuals need to work hard, and at the same time, they also need opportunities. When we were studying, we should say that there were more opportunities. There was a shortage of people in front of us because of the passing of generations, and the society was in urgent need of talents, so that we would be the first in this and the first in that way. Nowadays, law has become a prominent school. Young people are under great pressure, but there are not many opportunities. Then they need to be more diligent, redouble their efforts, be calm, endure loneliness, and never let go of their youth. If they really learn, they will achieve something. There are times when you can use force and give appropriate rewards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《等待戈多》作者最喜欢的戏剧来中国，观众看得很精神]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A black box stood on the stage. &quot;Endgame&quot; had not officially started, but the two characters were already inside. Extremely similar clips are repeated over and over again, as if the stage has turned into a machine that plays on a loop due to malfunction. The servant Clover wrung his fingers and walked the same route repeatedly with a strange gait. He stepped back from the door to the right of Master Ham&#39;s wheelchair, walked to the corner on the left, and then to the door on the right, taking fourteen precise steps, every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dialogue has not changed either. &quot;Do you want me to leave you?&quot; &quot;Of course.&quot; &quot;Then I will leave you.&quot; &quot;You can&#39;t leave me.&quot; &quot;Then I won&#39;t leave you.&quot; The door was opened and closed again and again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1953, &quot;Waiting for Godot&quot; brought Beckett worldwide fame, but his favorite work was &quot;Endgame&quot; written four years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/9nCi5R8eQ6GQ8MC2uGTpV2Pz4rT7J40RVwMq7Zrj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/9nCi5R8eQ6GQ8MC2uGTpV2Pz4rT7J40RVwMq7Zrj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258749&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beckett&#39;s play &quot;Endgame&quot; will be performed at the 10th Wuzhen International Theater Festival in 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the organizer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This play shows four deformed people in an empty house that is approaching the end of the world. : The master Ham is paralyzed from the lower body, blind, and has been sitting in a wheelchair; the servant Clover has a disease in his knees and cannot sit down. Ham&#39;s parents, Nag and Nell, have lost their lower limbs and live in two trash cans. The relationships between masters and servants, husbands and wives, and parents and children all show an extremely cruel side, but they are interdependent and inseparable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the impression of Tobias Bianconi, Director General of the International Theater Association, in the past, the audience&#39;s reaction to Beckett and even absurdist plays was sometimes &quot;very frustrating and unhappy&quot;, but After he walked out of the theater, he found that after watching this version of the Vienna Volkstheater&#39;s performance, the Chinese audience was full of energy and had lively discussions. They all felt that the play was very fresh. &quot;Why is there such a reaction? What is the background that makes the audience like this play so much?&quot; he was curious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 20th century, which experienced the ravages of two world wars and was immersed in industrialization and the post-industrial era, the rationalism admired by Western civilization fell into crisis, belief in God collapsed, and self-doubt and self-denial became the themes of the times. This also brought profound conceptual changes to drama. What Beckett&#39;s drama expresses is the antagonistic relationship between human beings and nature, society, self and others who are completely alienated in social crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Absurd drama, which was born in Paris, France, in the early 1950s, was echoed again in Wuzhen, China, seventy years later. &quot;At the beginning, we thought the most exciting thing was this very unhealthy and toxic relationship. Later we discovered that it had some parts related to war. As it slowly developed, we found that it might be related to climate change. Recently, We found that it was combined with the COVID-19 epidemic.&quot; During the dialogue, theater director and German director Kai Vogels said that this version of &quot;Endgame&quot; has been performed for eleven years. &quot;The point of it being constantly performed is that it is always new. , what we see from this drama keeps changing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18 /yJd8u4hbNeQQHztSBQk6L0OvaD60hZLYPPyafubF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/yJd8u4hbNeQQHztSBQk6L0OvaD60hZLYPPyafubF.j pg&quot; data -key=&quot;258748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beckett&#39;s play &quot;Endgame&quot; was written in the late 1950s. The version that came to China has already been sold in Europe Acted for eleven years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the organizer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vogels refined the four characters into two clown-like people, retaining the main theme A very tense contrast between servants: Ham is physically disabled, but has the power to control Clover; Clough is relatively able to move freely, but is always dominated by his master to do unnecessary trivial things, and his spirit tends to be paralyzed. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most eye-catching adaptation is Vogels’ emphasis on the sense of looping. The line, which was on an infinite loop before the show even started, only appeared once in the original script. Vogels uses this as the opening or closing line of every dialogue, repeating it a dozen times throughout the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A new plot in the play brings an &quot;anti-climax&quot;: after Clover struggled, he shot Hamm, but the expected relief brought by death did not happen. After the monologue, Ham suddenly answered and got up from the ground, as if nothing had happened. Clover and he returned to their usual endless conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Beckett actually demonstrated a ritual cycle on the stage. The ending of this ritual cycle is satisfaction, nothingness, or the end of the world. Everyone can see it differently. Each point has its own interpretation, and what I present on the stage also has this meaning.&quot; At the beginning of the rehearsal, Vogels hoped to show the inextricable cycle of repetition on the stage without making the audience feel bored. This balance Feeling is what he is looking for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1998 Vogels has been a theater and opera director in Austria and Germany. German theater is relatively lagging behind in digital innovation. From 2010 to 2020, while serving as the artistic director of the Dortmund Theater in Germany, Vogels began to try to combine digital media with theater and introduce digital thinking to the theater stage. He is a pioneer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among these works, digital techniques such as VR, real-time imaging, and on-site editing are emerging in endlessly. &quot;Endgame&quot; pursues Beckett&#39;s minimalist style. However, the artificially isolated cramped space, heavy metal-style amplified sound effects, The sudden switching of dazzling lights, the characters&#39; mechanically looping movements and lines, all give this picture of the human spiritual wasteland a cold science fiction color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The more traditional images such as &quot;desert&quot; and &quot;dead branches&quot; in Beckett&#39;s original work are missing. In terms of stage design, the play chose a form that abstracted away from reality. Like the door, the few sets and props are all outlined with white chalk lines. Three-dimensional life seems to be locked in two-dimensional space. Machine guns and toy dogs are just thin wooden boards hanging on the wall when they are not picked out by actors and held in their hands. The clock has no hands and the flowers in the vase are out of proportion. The only two real objects are the wooden chair with armrests in the center of the stage and the light bulb hanging in the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actors&#39; performances are consistent with German precision, and they achieve the ultimate in repetitive movements with slight changes. The actor who played Ham sat in a chair with his eyes closed throughout the performance, but still showed a strong sense of dominance and oppression in the relationship through his tone and gestures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The voice can be called the third &quot;starring&quot; of this drama, expanding the information and emotional density in the minimalist world. Clough&#39;s footsteps continued to echo in the space, powerful, but as flat as the scenery, with no specific sense of direction. Footsteps create a strong conflict with directionlessness. Every time Clover dropped something he was holding, there was a loud cracking sound, whether it was a telescope, a machine gun, or a toy dog. The laws of the physical world break down here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two people, who are both master and servant and father and son, are imprisoned in a lifeless atmosphere. The room they were in was, in a sense, like the final game board in a chess game. Ham is the general on the chessboard and needs to ensure that he is in the &quot;center&quot; of the room, controlling his pieces. The little soldier Clover could barely move a few steps, but under the command of blind Ham, the situation was certain to lose, but they could not and did not dare to leave the room, just like the chess pieces could not leave the chessboard. &quot;There is no nature anymore&quot; outside the house. Even when I opened the window, I saw &quot;ZERO&quot; written on the blackboard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They passed the time by teasing, controlling, and torturing each other, telling the old stories again, and looking at the window that they had looked at countless times, hoping that something would happen. What happened in front of my eyes was that other people passed by the window. However, their expectations were all in vain, and all their actions no longer made much sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the play, I realized that the beginning was the end. &quot;What time is it?&quot; &quot;Same as usual.&quot; They repeated the dialogue at the opening. Everything stopped suddenly, leaving silence and darkness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冒充专家行医十年，靠秘方自制抗癌药：无证“神医”的罪与罚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260877]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 08:59:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;Miracle Doctor&quot; sells a bunch of titles to patients. Nongjian illustration&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/7306a713b3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;953&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/7306a713b3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258746&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;&quot;Miracle doctors&quot; sell a bunch of titles to their patients. Nongjian Illustration&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingdao’s “old Chinese medicine doctor” Hou Yuanxiang, who pretended to be an expert and professor and practiced medicine illegally for more than ten years, fell for his homemade “anti-cancer drug” - in February 2023, Hou Yuanxiang was arrested by Qingdao at first instance The Huangdao District People&#39;s Court of the city sentenced him to 12 years in prison and fined him 12 million yuan for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Hou Yuanxiang, his daughter, son, wife and former son-in-law were also sentenced for &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; and were sentenced to prison terms ranging from 11 to 3 years respectively. In addition, the son of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s third sister was also involved in the case. He was sentenced to 11 years in prison for &quot;fraud&quot; and &quot;harboring&quot; in the first instance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total prison term for the above six people is 50 years, and the total fine is 29.8 million yuan. Southern Weekend reporters searched online for judgment documents and found that among counterfeit drug cases in recent years, the first-instance verdict in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s case was extremely rare in terms of heavy sentencing and high fines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the case has not yet been settled. After the first-instance verdict, as Hou Yuanxiang and others filed an appeal, many self-media appeared on the Internet to &quot;cry out injustice&quot; for them. Some associated the case with the &quot;folk traditional Chinese medicine&quot; group, believing that &quot;if this lawsuit is lost, almost all folk Chinese medicine practitioners must close their doors.&quot; (For details, please see the report &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/260879&quot;>;&quot;The Online Public Opinion War on the &quot;Miracle Cancer Doctor&quot;&lt;/a>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s agent The lawyer questioned the characterization of the drugs involved in the case, arguing that after the revision of the Drug Administration Law in 2019, the threshold for identification of counterfeit drugs has been raised. Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine is made of traditional Chinese medicinal materials and should not be identified as counterfeit drugs. Hou Yuanxiang does not constitute “production.” , the crime of selling counterfeit medicines.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 30, 2023, the Qingdao Intermediate People’s Court ruled to revoke the original judgment and remand the case for retrial on the grounds that the first-instance judgment “had unclear facts and insufficient evidence.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;old Chinese doctor&quot; who can&#39;t take the pulse&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After being criminally detained on February 17, 2022, Hou Yuanxiang only stayed in the detention center for more than 20 days. After that, the police changed the enforcement measures to &quot;residential surveillance&quot; because of his illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Gang, the second-instance attorney, met Hou Yuanxiang after the National Day in 2023. According to him, two policemen worked in three shifts, watching him 24 hours a day, &quot;maybe because there are more patients coming to him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, 66-year-old Hou Yuanxiang is from Shandong A native of Yishui County, Linyi City, the province, he once worked as a teacher in the county, but later took a leave of absence without pay and became a doctor. After that, he moved his family to Weifang and settled down. Around 2019, after purchasing real estate in Qingdao, Hou Yuanxiang and his wife and their daughter Hou Jing and his wife both moved their household registrations to Qingdao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang’s confession cited in the first-instance verdict did not explain his medical experience. Some self-media said that Hou Yuanxiang studied under two &quot;famous Chinese medicine doctors&quot; Zhang Moumou and Lou Moumou, but Southern Weekend reporters did not find any information about the latter two as &quot;famous Chinese medicine doctors&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it is certain that Hou Yuanxiang is not from a &quot;family of traditional Chinese medicine&quot; or &quot;six generations practicing medicine&quot; as some self-media said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to what Hou Yuanxiang’s wife and sister told China News Weekly, Hou Yuanxiang was originally a primary school teacher and started studying medicine when he was about 40 years old. He had “several teachers” but “all of them are gone.” This relative emphasized that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;excellent&quot; in taking his pulse - he could tell whether it was cancer or what kind of cancer it was by just touching it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a daughter-in-law, Li Jianying told Southern Weekend reporters that she did not know how Hou Yuanxiang learned Chinese medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most patients call Hou Yuanxiang &quot;Professor Hou&quot;, and Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s WeChat signature is also &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. The &quot;Central Health&quot; website, which claims to provide communication, display, and promotion services for &quot;folk doctors,&quot; still has Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s personal introduction, calling him an &quot;international doctor of medicine&quot; and &quot;an authoritative international cancer expert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, his online profiles, including “Professor of Chinese Medical College” and “Doctor of International Medicine”, “are all false” and “are intended to expand influence and make patients believe I&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Hou Yuanxiang did not even obtain a medical practicing certificate. Since the implementation of the Practicing Physician Law in 1999, regardless of whether it is traditional Chinese medicine or Western medicine, all practitioners must have a physician&#39;s practice certificate. Otherwise, it will be regarded as &quot;illegal practice of medicine&quot;, and they will be subject to administrative penalties in the lightest case and criminal liability in the worst case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A patient surnamed Xu testified that she began to seek medical treatment from Hou Yuanxiang in 2014. Since then, she has introduced many patients to Hou, and also asked Hou to attend a consultation at his winery. In 2019, she and Hou Yuanxiang co-organized When he went to the hospital, he found that Hou could not produce his medical license, so he doubted his identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only patients, but also some senior medical professionals had no doubts about Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s identity and ability. According to the first-instance verdict, Hou Yuanxiang had been a doctor at Deyi Hall, a private traditional Chinese medicine hospital in Qingdao for a long time. Later, the person in charge of Deyi Hall asked Hou Yuanxiang to attach his medical qualification to the hospital. However, Hou Yuanxiang refused, and the two parties terminated the cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the testimony of Shen Yufa, director of Zibo Yiyuan Ruikang Hospital, around 2010, he met Hou Yuanxiang at a medical academic conference in Beijing. “Many people attending the conference at that time said that Professor Hou was a doctor of traditional Chinese medicine. He is famous for tumors, cancer, and cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Shen Yufa’s wife got cancer and took Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade medicine. Shen Yufa also hired Hou as a &quot;part-time professor&quot; at Ruikang Hospital and sold Hou&#39;s medicine at the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, Shen Yufa once invited him to sit in Ruikang Hospital, but he refused because he did not have a medical license. The two parties only cooperated on selling medicines. However, Shen Yufa&#39;s son and another employee of the hospital confirmed that Hou Yuanxiang did not attend the hospital regularly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to private hospitals, Hou Yuanxiang has also worked with public hospitals. In 2016, Weifang Municipal Government Hospital, a public hospital, posted on its WeChat official account that Hou Yuanxiang was an &quot;authoritative expert in international cancer research&quot; and would conduct monthly consultations at the branch of traditional Chinese medicine. This article disappeared only recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Patients trust Hou Yuanxiang not only because of his impressive online resume, but also because of his “accurate” pulse numbering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dong Shijie is a relative of Hou Yuanxiang, a Jilin patient. According to him, Hou Yuanxiang once traveled to Changbai Mountain and hosted meals by himself. Hou Yuanxiang took his pulse on the spot. &quot;I have a friend who has high blood lipids and high blood pressure, and he can detect it,&quot; Dong Shijie told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to the first-instance verdict, Hou Yuanxiang admitted to the investigators that he actually could not take a pulse. The reason for pretending to know the pulse is &quot;to put it bluntly, it is to let the patient buy medicine.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he learned that Hou Yuanxiang could not check the pulse, Dong Shijie was shocked: &quot;He is a traditional Chinese medicine doctor. What kind of disease would he treat if he could not check the pulse?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The whole family went into hiding&quot; after the incident&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance judgment, since 2011, Hou Yuanxiang, Hou Jing and others, without obtaining a drug production license, a drug business license, etc., posted Hou Yuanxiang’s false personal profile on the Internet to spread information in many places in Shandong Consulting and selling drugs claiming to be anti-cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hou Yuanxiang’s counterfeit drug case, the first person to be involved was his daughter Hou Jing—like her father, she did not have a medical certificate. On January 16, 2022, after receiving complaints and reports, multiple departments in Huangdao District, Qingdao City jointly conducted law enforcement and captured Hou Jing on the spot. Later, Hou Jing confessed to Hou Yuanxiang, his brother Hou Lei and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, Hou Yuanxiang was at his home in Weifang at the time. He didn’t seem to care at first. It wasn’t until Hou Jing was detained and he was interrogated by the police that he realized the seriousness of the situation and transferred the self-made medicine to Qingdao Clinic overnight. and production tools, but it was too late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court of first instance found that after Hou Jing was detained, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s wife went to the police station handling the case to inquire about information, and &quot;hidden the whole family&quot; after returning home for an excuse. The police then pursued the Hou family online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Lei’s confession, Hou Yuanxiang called him the day after Hou Jing was arrested. &quot;Two or three days later, my father said that this was a serious matter and asked me not to use my current mobile phone and to go out and hide. After hanging up the phone, I took out the phone card and threw it in the trash.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for how Hou Lei participated in these businesses, Hou Lei said that in the winter of 2019, Hou Yuanxiang &quot;asked me to apply for a bank card in the name of my wife Li Jianying... and asked me to pretend Director Li of the hospital, if a patient wants to buy medicine, call me and ask me to give the patient a bank card so that the patient can transfer money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Yuanxiang’s confession, Hou Jing and Hou Lei had a bad relationship. After Hou Lei knew that Hou Jing was making money, he also wanted to sell medicine with his father. He asked him for the formula many times, but Hou Yuanxiang did not give it. He just asked Hou Lei to follow him and pay him a salary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jianying told Southern Weekend reporters that Hou Lei helped Hou Yuanxiang deliver goods in Weifang, &quot;equivalent to a courier.&quot; In the first-instance verdict, Hou Lei was sentenced to &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; according to law, and was sentenced to 8 years in prison and fined 5 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Lei&#39;s confession, after hiding for a few days, he received a call from Hou Yuanxiang from an unknown number, suggesting that he go to the third aunt&#39;s house in Qingdao to celebrate the New Year, and then the whole family went to the third aunt&#39;s house. According to Hou Lei&#39;s confession, because he felt that &quot;the matter was quite serious&quot;, he once suggested that his father surrender. &quot;My father was very angry and said that I was not his biological child.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shuai, the son of Hou Lei’s third aunt, told Hou Lei that he had the connections to settle the matter, but he would need 4 million yuan. After several communications, Hou Lei asked his ex-brother-in-law Fu Songjie to send 2 million yuan in cash to Li Shuai after he had already paid 500,000 yuan. Li Shuai confessed that when he saw Fu Songjie coming to the door with a sack of money, he was stunned: &quot;This is the first time I have seen so much money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Songjie was originally from a district in Weifang City In 2019, he resigned and went to Qingdao at the request of his ex-wife Hou Jing. Before resigning, Hou Yuanxiang approached him and asked him to serve as the legal representative of a private hospital in which Hou was a shareholder. After Fu Songjie arrived in Qingdao, he caught up with the epidemic and had no job, so he helped his father-in-law and his ex-wife, and ended up becoming an accomplice. Fu Songjie was sentenced to 3 years in prison and fined 500,000 yuan in the first instance. The sentence was the shortest among all those involved in the case, and Fu was the only one who did not appeal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Hou Lei was arrested, he confessed Li Shuai. In the next three days, Li Shuai, Fu Songjie and Hou Yuanxiang were arrested one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Hou Yuanxiang, in addition to the above 2.5 million yuan, Li Shuai also defrauded him of more than 2 million yuan. The first-instance judgment confirmed the matter and stated that &quot;it will be separately investigated and handled by the public security organs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Hou Yuanxiang counterfeit drug case, the police seized a total of 8 houses in the Hou family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In late February 2022, a week after Hou Yuanxiang was arrested, the Ministry of Public Security announced the first batch of eight major typical drug crime cases to be supervised, and Hou Yuanxiang’s fake drug case was among them. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Secret Recipes&quot; of Unknown Origin&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the Hou Yuanxiang case, the medicines that were classified as fake were four self-made medicines by Hou Yuanxiang and his daughter, two of which were named &quot; Anti-Cancer No. 1” and “Anti-Cancer No. 2”. According to Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s confession, these two medicines were made according to a &quot;secret recipe.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Hou Yuanxiang has different opinions on the origin of this &quot;secret recipe&quot;. During the investigation stage of the case, he said that the secret recipe came from one of his &quot;second grandfathers.&quot; This recipe originally contained five kinds of medicine. On this basis, Hou Yuanxiang added shiitake mushrooms, ganoderma lucidum, and cordyceps. &quot;Even if this recipe is my own creation, I I have always wanted to promote this prescription and sell the medicine to make money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, during the trial stage of the case, Hou Yuanxiang’s statement about the “secret recipe” changed—he claimed that the recipe was given to him by his “teacher” at the end of 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Yuanxiang’s different statements about the source of the secret recipe puzzled a second-instance attorney: “Perhaps only he himself knows the truth.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment quoted an attorney of the Hou family According to the lawyer, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s anti-cancer &quot;secret recipe&quot; contains many Chinese medicinal materials such as shiitake mushrooms, cordyceps, Ganoderma lucidum, Prunella vulgaris, black dates, kelp, burdock root, dandelion root, ginseng, astragalus, angelica and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Chinese medicine practitioner who has been practicing for more than 40 years told Southern Weekend reporters that the Chinese medicinal materials in Hou Yuanxiang’s prescription include both “tonifying” and “attacking” ingredients, such as ginseng, Astragalus, when cancer patients reach the middle and late stages, most of them are relatively weak, so it is beneficial to use some tonics; &quot;attack&quot; medicines such as kelp, which has the effect of clearing away heat and dissipating stagnation, is only suitable for some early-stage cancer patients and is not suitable for late-stage cancer patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among Hou Yuanxiang’s patients, there are many terminal cancer patients, and some came to Hou Yuanxiang because they were “sentenced to death by the hospital.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from traditional Chinese medicine (TCM), which treats patients according to prescriptions, Hou Yuanxiang’s anti-cancer drugs are prepared in advance, bagged and then sold to patients. According to his confession, around November 2020, Hou Jing purchased a decoction-making machine online. Since then, the father and daughter have taken turns using this machine to make decoctions, &quot;and can make about 80 bags a day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The price of &quot;Anti-cancer No. 1&quot; is 4,620 yuan per serving, and &quot;Anti-cancer No. 2&quot; is 1,920 yuan. One dose is taken for one course of treatment, and one course of treatment lasts for 12 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade anti-cancer drugs, Zhao Yin, a lawyer who graduated from the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine and has worked in the clinical department of traditional Chinese medicine in the hospital for many years, believes that it is definitely illegal. According to her, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self-made medicines are similar to &quot;medical institution (TCM) preparations&quot; in hospitals, which refer to fixed prescription preparations prepared by medical institutions for their own use after approval based on the clinical needs of the unit. However, hospital preparations, like medicines, generally need to be approved by the drug regulatory department before they can be produced and sold. In principle, they can only be produced by the hospital for their own use and cannot be sold externally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin said that after the promulgation of the Traditional Chinese Medicine Law in 2017, the state has relaxed its management of traditional Chinese medicine preparations. Traditional Chinese medicine preparations that only use traditional techniques do not need to obtain a preparation approval number and only need to apply for a preparation approval number. It can be prepared after registration with the provincial drug regulatory department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine has also not been registered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Traditional Chinese Medicine Law stipulates that medical institutions that prepare traditional Chinese medicine preparations that should be registered but fail to do so will be punished as producing counterfeit drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin also doubted whether Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade anti-cancer medicine really contained a sufficient amount of Chinese medicinal materials such as cordyceps claimed in the “secret recipe” because the medicine was made by Hou Yuanxiang and his daughter themselves and there was no formula. The production process standards lack proper supervision and supervision. However, quantitative detection of Cordyceps sinensis is very difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Fu Songjie’s confession, Hou Jing would send Liuwei Dihuang Pills and other Chinese patent medicines to patients together with the boiled Chinese medicine liquid. In Zhao Yin&#39;s view, in this way, even if the patient feels effective after taking the medicine, it may be the effect of the proprietary Chinese medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to avoid the characterization of &quot;fake medicine&quot;, Hou Yuanxiang once tried to defend himself by claiming that &quot;medicine and food have the same origin&quot;, which means that what he sells is food. However, due to the labeling of drug names such as &quot;Anti-cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti-cancer No. 2&quot;, his defense is difficult to establish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin believes that the drug names &quot;Anti-cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti-cancer No. 2&quot; are nondescript, because cancer is a concept of Western medicine, and traditional Chinese medicine generally does not have the term &quot;cancer&quot; or &quot;tumor&quot;. Instead, it is called &quot;accumulation of symptoms.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Hou Yuanxiang’s practice of making homemade anti-cancer drugs, the above-mentioned traditional Chinese medicine doctors interviewed by Southern Weekend reporters called him “too courageous”. In his opinion, many Chinese medicine practitioners have secret recipes. In order not to reveal the secret recipes, they usually only sell the medicinal materials to patients. At most, they cook them for the patients. They certainly dare not make their own medicines and sell them to patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Have any cancer patients been cured?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, supporters &quot;voted injustice&quot; against Hou Yuanxiang on the Internet because he cured many cancer patients. However, a Southern Weekend reporter&#39;s investigation found that it is questionable whether any cancer patients were actually cured by Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the first-instance verdict of the Hou Yuanxiang case, a list of cancer patients who claimed to be &quot;cured by Hou Yuanxiang&quot; leaked online. There were a total of 31 personal information of patients or patients&#39; family members on the list. This list is consistent with that provided to Southern Weekend reporters by Gong Feiyun, one of Hou Yuanxiang’s supporters. According to Gong Feiyun, at the end of June 2023, he went to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang, and it was Hou Yuanxiang himself who gave him this list. Gong Feiyun is a partner of a local traditional Chinese medicine clinic. A few years ago, he was involved in a controversy when self-made medicines were deemed to be counterfeit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters made all 31 calls on the list, of which 11 were not answered and 13 were refused. Of the 7 calls answered, 6 admitted that they were patients on the list or Family members, and another person denied that he was Che Moumou, the &quot;Director of the Provincial Environmental Protection Bureau&quot; written on the list, saying that he was &quot;running business.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 6 people, 3 people refused to be interviewed on the grounds of &quot;something happened&quot; and &quot;privacy involved&quot;, and only 3 people accepted the telephone interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The patient, Song Yuanjia, is from Qingdao, Shandong. He claimed that he was &quot;sentenced to death by the hospital.&quot; He approached Hou Yuanxiang with the mentality of giving it a try, and &quot;it was fine once he tried it.&quot; &quot;It has been 7 years now. Nothing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Yuan’s family told Southern Weekend reporters that Hou Yuanxiang’s medicine was an “ancestral medicine” and he spent more than 200,000 yuan without giving a prescription, first taking “Anti-Cancer No. 1” and “in the end he became poor. Feel better, take &#39;Anti-Cancer No. 2&#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance verdict, when Hou Yuanxiang moved his homemade medicine and production tools overnight, he asked the Song Yuan family for help, and the Song Yuan family found a warehouse for him to store the items Hou Yuanxiang moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Yuanjia told Southern Weekend reporters that he had read Hou Yuanxiang’s first-instance verdict, but he was more willing to believe the “crying out injustice” video on the self-media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another interviewee, Wang Jingjiang, is a villager in a village in Zibo, Shandong, and the patient is his mother-in-law. He said that Hou Yuanxiang once planned to build a sanatorium in the village. He was driving for the village party secretary and got to know Hou. Later, his mother-in-law got cancer and there was no possibility of surgery. After undergoing chemotherapy for a period of time, he contacted &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jingjiang said that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine was &quot;good&quot; and his mother-in-law felt &quot;strong&quot; after drinking it. However, she stopped drinking it because she couldn&#39;t stand the taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of lawyer Yang Fengzhu, one of the experts in drafting and demonstrating traditional Chinese medicine laws, Hou Yuanxiang’s “anti-cancer drugs” are several Chinese medicines mixed together. Although Chinese medicine treatments rarely have “immediate results”, they are not It has no effect. &quot;Once you take the (Chinese medicine) that replenishes qi, it will definitely have an effect.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jingjiang also emphasized that his mother-in-law was not &quot;cured&quot;, but &quot;has not (re) committed the crime or been transferred.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third interviewee, Li Cheng (pseudonym), is from Yanbian, Jilin. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the patient was his grandfather, and he had indeed seen Hou Yuanxiang for medical treatment and taken his homemade medicine. The old man passed away in September 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Cheng said that his grandfather was diagnosed with rectal cancer in July 2019 and had spread to the lymph nodes. Relatives introduced him to Hou Yuanxiang. He has never met Hou Yuanxiang so far, and the two mainly communicate through WeChat. He said that after adding WeChat, Hou Yuanxiang once sent his personal profile, &quot;I also searched on Baidu about world cancer, committees, and cancer treatment experts, and I could indeed find this person. I thought this person was quite good.&quot; sharp&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When receiving a call from a Southern Weekend reporter, Li Cheng still called Hou Yuanxiang &quot;Professor Hou.&quot; When he learned that Hou Yuanxiang was not a professor and did not even have a medical license, he was surprised and said that if he had known about this situation, he would &quot;definitely consider&quot; whether to seek medical treatment from Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Cheng said that in addition to drinking Hou Yuanxiang’s anti-cancer drugs, his grandfather also ate the “nutritious meals” recommended by Hou Yuanxiang. &quot;After about three courses of treatment, (grandpa) recovered very well.&quot; Li Cheng said, for this reason, he also introduced many patients to Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Li Cheng could not confirm whether his grandfather&#39;s condition improved for a time. &quot;Whether Professor Hou&#39;s medicine played a greater role or my grandfather&#39;s personal mentality played a greater role.&quot; Li Cheng said, &quot;We all say that (Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine) is effective and easy to use, and it may have played a supporting role in grandpa&#39;s mental state.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Fengzhu has participated in many clinical trial demonstrations of drugs. . In his opinion, when patients undergo treatment, &quot;psychological effects are very important and can affect 30% of the (treatment) effect.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Cheng also said that while his grandfather was taking Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine, he also underwent other treatments, including surgery, and &quot;Chinese and Western medicine worked simultaneously.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;After &quot;slimming down&quot; with fake medicine&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Neither the attorney nor Hou Yuanxiang himself expected that the first instance would impose such a severe sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to relevant legal provisions and the amount of money involved ascertained by the driver’s agency, once Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine is deemed to be counterfeit, the sentence will not be lenient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the first trial, many attorneys representing the Hou family argued that Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine did not cause any harm to the patient. Hou Yuanxiang himself also stated that &quot;children can drink&quot; his medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the lack of any harm does not mean that Hou Yuanxiang does not commit the crime of &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot;, nor does it mean that he cannot be severely sentenced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the criminal law before the 2011 revision, the crime of &quot;producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; requires &quot;serious harm to human health&quot; and causing death or serious injury in order to be sentenced to more than ten years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yin said that in order to increase the crackdown on counterfeit drugs, the Eighth Amendment to the Criminal Law in 2011 amended the &quot;crime of producing and selling counterfeit drugs&quot; and no longer included &quot;seriously endangering human health&quot;. &quot;As a threshold for criminalization, as long as the production and sale of counterfeit medicines constitutes a crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the Eighth Amendment to the Criminal Law no longer requires death or serious injury as the only condition for a heavy sentence. It stipulates that &quot;other particularly serious circumstances&quot; can also be harshly sentenced. In 2014, the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate issued a judicial interpretation that as long as the production and sale of counterfeit drugs reaches 500,000 yuan, it constitutes &quot;other particularly serious circumstances&quot; under the Eighth Amendment to the Criminal Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance court determined that Hou Yuanxiang’s production and sales of counterfeit drugs amounted to more than 14.36 million yuan, far exceeding 500,000 yuan. This means that once Hou Yuanxiang’s homemade medicine is determined to be counterfeit, he will be sentenced to more than ten years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether Hou Yuanxiang’s self-made medicine can be identified as counterfeit medicine must be based on the Drug Administration Law. Zhao Yin believes that before the law was revised in 2019, the identification of counterfeit drugs was relatively simple - as long as the drug did not obtain a batch number, it would be &quot;treated as a counterfeit drug&quot;, thus constituting a counterfeit drug in the sense of criminal law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Drug Administration Law revised in 2019 has made major changes to the definition of counterfeit drugs. Drugs without batch numbers are no longer automatically treated as counterfeit drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The industry generally believes that the above-mentioned modifications to the Drug Administration Law are related to the Hunan Lu Yong case. Lu Yong, a leukemia patient, purchased generic drugs from informal channels and helped his patients purchase the drugs. In 2018, the movie &quot;I&#39;m Not the God of Medicine&quot; based on it was released, triggering widespread public discussion on China&#39;s drug management system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The revised Drug Administration Law stipulates that counterfeit drugs can be classified as counterfeit drugs only under four circumstances (see the information link at the end of the article for details). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Cao Guoying, director of the Beijing Changjiang Pharmaceutical Development Foundation, who has long been engaged in anti-counterfeiting practice and research on drugs, after the revision of the Drug Administration Law, the number of counterfeit drug cases handled by the drug regulatory department showed a &quot;cliff-like decline.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the website of the State Food and Drug Administration, in 2019, the number of counterfeit drug cases investigated and dealt with by drug regulatory departments across the country was 14,041. In the following year after the revision of the Drug Administration Law, the number of such cases There were only 7,361 cases, a decrease of nearly half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from Southern Weekend searched the Judgment Documents Network using the keyword &quot;counterfeit drugs&quot; and found that based on the revision of the Drug Administration Law, the number of judgments in criminal cases of counterfeit drugs dropped sharply from 5,044 in 2019 to 2020. Of the 2,361 pieces, more than half were missing. There was also a downward trend in the following years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2019 version of the Drug Administration Law has significantly increased fines while &quot;slimming down&quot; counterfeit drugs. &quot;The starting point of the fine is 15 times the production and sales amount, and if it is less than 100,000, it will be calculated as 100,000.&quot; Zhao Yin said, &quot;As long as you are producing and selling counterfeit drugs, you will be fined at least 1.5 million, and you will be punished to death (for production, sales, etc.) Selling counterfeit medicines).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Are Chinese medicinal materials medicines? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In Cao Guoying&#39;s view, in the current overall environment of drugs, Qingdao can investigate and deal with the Hou Yuanxiang case &quot;very difficult&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, whether Hou Yuanxiang should be held criminally responsible for &quot;production and sales of fake medicines&quot;, but both in the legal and Chinese medicine community have caused controversy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The acting lawyer of the Hou family is based on the revised drug management law in 2019. It is believed that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s homemade drug is made of Chinese medicine materials as raw materials. The crime of selling fake medicines. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In fact, according to the first trial of the Hou Yuanxiang case, the public security organs were initially established by Hou Yuanxiang and others with &quot;illegal business crimes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One month after filing the case, the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau issued a fake medicine identification letter, which was identified as a fake medicine for the four homemade drugs of Hou Yuanxiang. According to the relevant judicial interpretations issued by the highest law and the highest detection in 2014, it is difficult to determine the &quot;fake drugs&quot; and &quot;inferior drugs&quot;, and the judicial organs can determine the determination opinions issued by the drug supervision and management departments above the city level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the above identification, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot;, &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot;, &quot;liver&quot; claiming to treat liver cancer, and &quot;wild heart brain soup&quot; used to treat heart disease The medicine is identified as a fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the case entered the review and prosecution stage, at the request of the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Huangdao District, the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau specially issued a supplementary explanation to explain why the products involved were identified as fake medicines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Instructions point out that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s four self -made products &quot;no drug registration certificate, no medical institution preparation filing, no drug production license, no medical institution preparation permit, no national standard, etc. Pharmaceuticals that promote the treatment of cancer, liver cancer, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, etc. are sold to patients to cure diseases. P>; &lt;p>; A second -instance agent lawyer pointed out that on the one hand, the above discussion said that the product involved in the case was &quot;in line with the definition of drugs&quot;, and on the other hand, it was &quot;non -drug&quot;. In its opinion, the reason why Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau discusses this is because according to the New Drug Management Law, &quot;the only thing that can be stuck is this one (non -pharmaceutical impersonation).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made medicine identification issues, the reporter from the southern weekend contacted the Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau. The bureau refused to interview on the grounds of the Hou Yuanxiang case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the first instance, almost all the acting lawyers of the Hou family questioned the false drug determination of the case. One of the lawyers pointed out that most of the medicinal materials used in &quot;Anti -Cancer 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; were in the 2020 version of &quot;Chinese Pharmacopoeia&quot;, which did not conform to &quot;impersonation of medicines with non -drug&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, in Zhao Yin&#39;s view, Chinese medicinal materials are not of course considered medicines -Chinese medicinal materials are only raw materials for making drugs and can be sold in the medicinal material market. Sale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Where is the medicinal materials used by Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s father and daughter&#39;s self -made medicine? There is no explanation in the relevant confession quoted in the first instance judgment, and Hou Jing cannot provide the purchase of the purchase and legal certification documents. According to Hou Jing&#39;s ex -husband Fu Songjie, Hou Jing&#39;s herbal medicines were sent through express delivery and logistics. The consignee generally used a pseudonym. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Gang, the acting lawyer of the second instance, questioned the fake drugs involved in the case involved in the case of the case, and questioned the fake drug identification letter based on the judgment of the first trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the newly introduced judicial interpretation of the highest law and the highest prosecution in 2022 (the old judicial interpretation of the old judicial interpretation in 2014), the situation of &quot;non -drug pretending to medicine&quot; can only be in the case where there is no controversy. Below, the municipal pharmaceutical regulatory department can be directly identified as fake medicine. For controversy, it is necessary to check or determine the pharmaceutical inspection agency set by the drug supervision and management department of the provincial level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In Li Gang&#39;s view, the identification of the fake drugs involved in the case of Hou Yuanxiang obviously controversial and should be tested. However, he believes that folk traditional Chinese medicine recipes lack national standards, and even if the results are tested, it lacks scientific and legitimacy. And Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s medicine was not tested at the time, and now it has been seized for more than a year. &quot;It has been deteriorated early, how to test it?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On November 5, 2023, another agent lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang told the Southern Weekend reporter that After the case was returned to the retrial, the procuratorial organs supplemented a lot of evidence to the court, including a inspection report on Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -pharmaceutical. According to this inspection report, Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s self -made drug detected the western medicine composition to treat diabetes. The Qingdao Municipal Supervision Bureau still determined that the product involved was a fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s above -mentioned acting lawyer said that this shows that the pharmaceutical regulatory department may no longer determine the product involved in the case in accordance with the &quot;non -pharmaceutical impersonation medicine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s charges, Yang Zhiwei, a lawyer of Guangdong Fa Quan Law Firm, put forward another point of view to reporters from the south weekend: if Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s &quot;Anti -Cancer No. 1&quot; and &quot;Anti -Cancer 2&quot; are clear and treating cancer &quot;Do not match the world&quot;, Hou Yuanxiang is entirely the purpose of selling medicines, so he may constitute a crime of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the Southern Weekend found such a case on the referee document network: In 2019, Li Mouxiang, who did not qualify for medicine, was arrested for production and sales of fake drugs, but the Procuratorate arrested and arrested him with fraud. The court was sentenced to 14 years in prison for fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Is Hou Yuanxiang suspected of fraud? A reporter from the Southern Weekend asked about a first -instance lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang. After a few seconds of silence, the lawyer asked: Scam? Isn&#39;t that heavier? Later, he said that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;unlikely&quot; to constitute a crime of fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another first -instance lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang believes that Hou Yuanxiang constitutes &quot;the crime of obstructing drug management&quot;. The crime was newly established in the 11th Amendment of the Criminal Law issued in 2020. It pointed to the criminal behavior of drugs that did not obtain a batch number but not obtained by the production and sales. light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lawyer did not accept interviews with reporters from the Southern Weekend, but said such a sentence: &quot;If he is sentenced to being innocently guilty of his (Hou Yuanxiang) family, then we can do anything in the name of traditional Chinese medicine to do traditional Chinese medicine. . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style =&quot; font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti; &quot;>; Data link: Different definition of&quot; fake medicine &quot;before and after the revision of the Drug Management Law: &lt; /span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; Before revision: one of the following situations, fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The ingredients contained in drugs are inconsistent with the ingredients specified by national drug standards; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) non-drug pretending to be medicine or pretending to be such medicines. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; A medicine with one of the following situations, according to fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The State Council&#39;s drug supervision and management department stipulates that it is prohibited; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) In accordance with this law, it must be approved without approved production and importing, or it must be tested in this law without testing without testing. ; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot; (3) deterioration; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p >; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (4) pollution; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body body body body , Kaiti_GB2312, SIMKAI, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (5) Use the raw material for the raw medicine of the approval number according to this law; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;FONT-FAMILY: Kai, Kaiti_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti;&quot; (6) Indications or functions marked or functional beyond the specified range. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; After the following situations: one of the following situations, fake medicine: &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, simkai, stkaiti;&quot;>; (1) The ingredients contained in drugs are inconsistent with national drug standards; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (2) non-drug pretending to medicine or impersonating such medicines in other medicines; &lt;/span>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; (3) spoiled medicine; &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;span style = &quot;font -Family: Kai, Kaidi_GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (4) Indications or functions indicated by drugs or functions beyond the specified range. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“抗癌神医”的网络舆论战]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260879]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 09:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Hou Yuanxiang was investigated, a large number of videos of&quot; shouting &quot;for them on the Internet appeared on the Internet. Nongjian illustration &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/a383d51fc2.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 953 &quot;data- SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/a383d51fc2.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;258747&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; Text -rign: center; &quot;>; During the investigation, Hou Yuanxiang appeared a large number of videos of&quot; shouting &quot;for him on the Internet. Nongjian Illustration &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A second -instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang admits to the reporter from the southern weekend that for Hou Yuanxiang, who was sentenced to the first instance, the second trial was a &quot;backwater battle.&quot; The second trial of the case can be returned to retrial, &quot;the media has played a great role.&quot; (Report on the Hou Yuanxiang case for details, please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/260877&quot;>; &quot;For ten years of medical practitioners, relying on the secret recipe&#39;s self -made anti &lt;/a>;) &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The lawyer&#39;s media refers to the Internet self -media. In fact, the media reports of the mainstream institutions reported Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine cases after the second instance ruling was returned to retrial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; With the help of the media, Hou Yuanxiang, who was originally unknown, was described as a &quot;cure doctor&quot; sentenced by injustice. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;Women with a public security background&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; In mid -March 2023, the Hou Yuanxiang fake medicine case was judged for more than a month later, and an article entitled &quot;Nine -year -old Xinxin for help: Mom Mom Articles of more than 3,000 cancer patients were sentenced to 11 years, and a fine of 30 million &quot;began to spread online. The article states that Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s daughter Hou Jing used the secret recipe of Chinese medicine to heal a lot of difficulty. , The whole family is implicated. There is also a photo of Hou Jing&#39;s 9 -year -old son asking for help: &quot;Why do you sin? Mom, do you have a sin? Let netizens from all over the country comment on you ...&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This article has aroused heated discussion among netizens. The reporter from the Southern Weekend noticed that this article emphasizes that Hou Jing graduated from the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine and was a Chinese medicine division, but he could not mention Hou Jing without a physician&#39;s practice certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s daughter -in -law Li Jianying told the southern weekend reporter that after the judgment of the first instance, Hou Yuanxiang wanted to use the Internet to &quot;call unjust&quot;. At that time, she asked her children&#39;s photos. She was worried that the child would be affected and did not give it. Later, I used the photos of Hou Jing&#39;s son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of June 2023, the media person Wu Pengfei began to intervene in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine. Wu Pengfei claims to be &quot;old journalists&quot; and &quot;well -known online writers&quot;. They have an account number on platforms such as Douyin, Kuaishou, and today&#39;s headlines. A reporter in the Southern Weekend found that Wu Pengfei worked in a media in Hubei Province in his early years and set up a planning marketing company after leaving the media. When he began to intervene in Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine, Wu Pengfei exposed a big news: a lady with a public security background had a price of 10 million. She wanted to buy Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s treatment secret recipe. Go to jail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Many self -media bloggers quoted Wu Pengfei&#39;s above statement, so that &quot;women with a public security background to buy medicines can not report to Hou Yuanxiang&quot; said that they became the mainstream online public opinion of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Li Gang, a second -instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang, told reporters from the southern weekend that although he heard Hou Yuanxiang said this, he did not see relevant evidence. Control. As a lawyer, he &quot;does not comment&quot; on this statement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yang Zining, the first instance acting lawyer of Hou Yuanxiang, also told the southern weekend reporter that the above statement &quot;cannot be reflected in the (case) volume.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The reporter of the Southern Weekend noticed that during the new crown epidemic in 2020, Wu Pengfei had picked up another &quot;divine doctor&quot; -Co Yuehua, who claimed that the injection phenol could cure the new crown, and released the news that Li Yuehua said Li Yuehua He was invited to resist with South Korea, but the news was denied by South Korea. Li Yuehua himself also told the media that he did not know the matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A reporter from the Southern Weekend tried to contact Wu Pengfei, but as of press time, the other party did not reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;How much is the reliability of folk investigation?&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; After issuing the above article, Wu Pengfei has continuously released short videos entitled &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine Injection Cases&quot; on multiple platforms. Now Episode 100 has been broadcast, of which the playback volume of the Douyin platform has exceeded 16 million. In these short videos, Wu Pengfei called Hou Yuanxiang as &quot;Hou Lao&quot;, saying that he was &quot;the first person in traditional Chinese medicine to treat cancer&quot;, with &quot;unique medical skills&quot; and &quot;shocking effect&quot;, &quot;a national treasure&quot;, &quot;on the body&quot;, &quot;on the body&quot; Each hair is gold. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition, Wu Pengfei also quoted a set of data to show that Hou Yuanxiang was &quot;cure cancer.&quot; He said that &quot;a national folk Chinese medicine organization&quot; investigated the efficacy of the top ten cancer names in China. Only 11 people were cured. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Li Jianying also told reporters from the south weekend that Hou Yuanxiang&quot; cured &quot;1166 cancer patients. &quot;He (Hou Yuanxiang) has records.&quot; She said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Wu Pengfei did not say which institution of &quot;National Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine Organization&quot;. In fact, even Li Gang held a question about the data that Wu Pengfei said: &quot;How much is the reliability of private investigations?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In another short video, Wu Pengfei said that Hou Yuanxiang cured more than 3,000 cancers. patient. In the personal introduction of &quot;Yangtze Health&quot; (a website that provides communication, display, and promotion services), Hou Yuanxiang is &quot;cured more than 20,000 cancer.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some media have questioned Hou Yuanxiang from the media, but the click volume is not the same as Wu Pengfei&#39;s short videos. Since the media &quot;Chinese Medicine Chen Lei&quot; posted a video, saying that Hou Yuanxiang was a &quot;liar for sale of fake medicines&quot;, calling on the public to calm down the case: &quot;If the facts are ignored, it is not love Chinese medicine, but it is harming Chinese medicine.&quot; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; After the video was released, &quot;Chinese Medicine Chen Lei&quot; was siege by many supporters of Hou Yuanxiang. Wu Pengfei released 8 short videos to refute. It didn&#39;t take long for the video of &quot;Chinese medicine Chen Lei&quot; to get off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After seeing Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s fake medicine on the Internet, Qian Hui, general manager of Nanjing Guishi Hall Traditional Chinese Medicine Museum, decided to support it. Qian Hui has experienced similar experiences to Hou Yuanxiang. According to media reports, Qian Hui did not have a physician&#39;s license. In order to avoid &quot;illegal medicine&quot;, his Chinese Medical Museum hired a regular doctor to prescribe prescriptions, and Qian Hui would &quot;guide&quot;. Self -making based on your own &quot;secret recipe&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of 2017, Guishi Hall was reported. Because the batch number was not obtained, its homemade medicine was identified as a fake medicine by the Nanjing Pharmaceutical Bureau. The crime of medicine was once detained by the police, and Qian Hui was locked for 28 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Why do we support Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s innocence? The main reason is from the perspective of protecting traditional Chinese medicine, because once Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s case is guilty, many traditional Chinese medicine can not do it anymore.&quot; To the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Gong Feiyun, one of Guishitang&#39;s &quot;partner&quot;, traditional Chinese medicine is &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;, and Hou Yuanxiang is one of many &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;. He defines &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot;: The collective name of Chinese medicine outside the system has not received formal Chinese medicine education in universities, and has no physician practicing certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the end of June 2013, Gong Feiyun went to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang. According to Gong Feiyun, although Hou Yuanxiang had been &quot;monitored and lived&quot; by the police at that time, he was not strict at that time. He tried to make an appointment and made a video. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Gong Feiyun also participated in the mediation of the Guishitang fake medicine. According to him, during the handling of the case, Guishi Hall had a &quot;public opinion war&quot; with Nanjing police: first a media in Nanjing stood on the police stand and exposed the case. the sound of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the end, the case stayed in the public security investigation stage and failed to enter the procuratorate for review and prosecution. After this robbery, Guishi Hall has since maintained the Shanghai market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before Qian Hui and Gong Feiyun, another &quot;folk Chinese medicine&quot; supporter Guan Le also supported Hou Yuanxiang online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Guanle claims to be &quot;the first principal of the University of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;, &quot;Great Wall inscription character&quot; and &quot;Chairman of the World Chinese Medicine Hall&quot;. He described &quot;the University of Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; as the &quot;Huangpu Military Academy&quot; of folk Chinese medicine. However, the university claimed to be established 3 years ago, but it has not been established so far. Guan Le once publicly said that after the university was established, he will select &quot;Academician of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;, &quot;Doctor of Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; and &quot;Professor of Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Related information shows that in June 2020, the slogan of the establishment of &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine&quot; just shouted, and Guan Le claimed to hold a establishment meeting of a branch of the university. The day after the meeting, Guan Le released an advertisement for a medical training course in multiple Chinese medicine groups, claiming that no medical foundation can learn on the spot, and the training fee is 18,000 yuan (preferential) for two days. Unexpectedly, this move with the &quot;Folk Traditional Chinese Medicine University&quot; was publicly questioned by Gu Jingyu, a doctor of a three -section of Jiangsu family in Jiangsu, and Guan Le responded: &quot;Civil Traditional Chinese Medicine University&quot; is innovation: &quot;Since it is innovation, there must be no certificate. Without a certificate, it must be illegal ... &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After going to Qingdao to meet Hou Yuanxiang, Gong Feiyun and Guan Le met in Shanghai. And ask him to speak up in the case of Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On September 9, 2023, the preparatory meeting of the Second Civil Medicine University planned by Guanle was held in Beijing. During the meeting, the Hou Yuanxiang case was discussed during the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;(Hou Yuanxiang case) is equivalent to uniting all folk Chinese medicine.&quot; Gong Feiyun told the southern weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the second trial of the Hou Yuanxiang fake medicine, after the re -review was returned, the supporters of Hou Yuanxiang were jubilant, and they released the &quot;good news&quot; online, thinking that the case had a &quot;major turnaround&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Soon after that, there was another news from the media -Hou Yuanxiang was on a hunger strike, and the news was &quot;true.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Wu Pengfei quickly posted a short video to clarify, saying that Hou Yuanxiang could not eat because he was weak, and his apprentice &quot;because he was afraid that someone would hurt Hou Lao and deliberately posted a hunger hunger strike in order to attract the attention of the whole society. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A few days later, Wu Pengfei posted a short video, saying that &quot;Hou Lao&quot; recovered, and began to &quot;drink a little wine&quot; every meal. … &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; According to Li Gang, a lawyer in the second instance, after the second trial retracement, because &quot;too many people who knew (Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s original surveillance residential place)&quot;, the police replaced Hou Yuanxiang for a place to perform surveillance and residence. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &quot;I no longer participate in this matter&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng (pseudonym) is the grandson of a patient with a Jilin cancer patient in Hou Yuanxiang. In the case, he also participated in the public opinion battle for Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On June 8, 2022, after Hou Yuanxiang filed a appeal, a WeChat person named &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; added Li Cheng&#39;s WeChat, claiming to be the daughter -in -law of &quot;Professor Hou&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Can you write a joint letter to Professor Hou for a love?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;What happened to Professor Hou?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I was reported by others , Now I still can&#39;t take my own medicine in the hospital. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng knew that Hou Yuanxiang had an accident. He told&quot; Meteor and sunset &quot;that he could help Hou Yuanxiang write a joint letter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Two months later, &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; pulled Li Cheng into a WeChat group that supported Hou Yuanxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng&#39;s mobile phone has a number marked as &quot;Director Li&#39;s anti -cancer&quot;, which was given by Hou Yuanxiang. He bought medicine for Grandpa to contact this &quot;Director Li&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before receiving a call from a reporter from the Southern Weekend, Li Cheng always thought that &quot;Director Li&quot; was called &quot;Li Jianying&quot; and was the person in charge of the medicine of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But in fact, &quot;Director Li&quot; is Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s son Hou Lei, &quot;Meteor and sunset&quot; is Li Jianying. She is also the only one among all the Hou family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the judgment of the first trial, in the case of Hou Yuanxiang, Hou Yuanxiang said that &quot;Professor Hou&quot; was responsible for providing formula, diagnosis and treatment of cancer diseases, and selling medicines. Chinese herbal medicine, boiled Chinese medicine, etc., his son Hou Lei was pretending to be responsible for taking the medicine and returned medicine &quot;Director Li&quot;, which is Li Jianying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After more than a month of WeChat with &quot;Meteor and Santa&quot;, Li Cheng and Hou Yuanxiang also contacted. &quot;He (Hou Yuanxiang) said that putting my information on the Internet, I said, as long as it is helpful to your case.&quot; Li Cheng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Cheng also suggested that Hou Yuanxiang talked about this on the self -media platform to increase attention. &quot;He said, let me let the family get it at home.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Later, Hou Yuanxiang sent some case materials to Li Cheng to help him contact the media. There have been no news since then. Li Cheng failed to help Hou Yuanxiang contact the media. Until late 2023, he sent a message to Hou Yuanxiang. &quot;He gave me a sentence and said that (second instance) was about to open the trial, the problem was not big.&quot; This is Li Cheng&#39;s last contact with Hou Yuanxiang. Prior to this, the Hou family proposed that Li Cheng&#39;s personal information was put on the Internet as one of the cases of Hou Yuanxiang&#39;s &quot;cure&quot; cancer patients, and he agreed. However, before the list was sent to the Internet, Li Cheng&#39;s grandfather died. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After knowing the truth, Li Cheng realized that things were &quot;not so simple&quot; - &quot;I don&#39;t know these, I don&#39;t know at all. Let&#39;s help, but the premise must be within the framework of the law ... I no longer participate in this matter. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[床虱危机或已蔓延至香港：为何太阳晒不倒，杀虫剂无效？丨硬核唠科]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260875]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[同性性行为进化的逻辑]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260881]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-18 22:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Sexual behavior between same sex can not directly produce offspring. . Because according to general understanding, in the natural world where the physical competition and the survival of the fittest, the same sexual behavior consumes valuable energy and time but cannot breed the offspring. There are many existences in nature and human society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Scientists have discovered homosexual behavior in more than 1,500 animals. Such behaviors are not affected by gender. They may occur between two males and may occur between two females. It appears in an artificial breeding environment, and it will also appear in the wild, not by accident under the extreme environment. This also raises a problem for scientists how to understand its evolutionary logic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In October 2023, researchers from the University of Granada and other institutions in Spain analyzed the same sexual behavior information of mammals through species, and tried to verify some related interpretation assumptions. The latest research on their published in Nature Communications shows that the evolution of homosexual behavior is likely to be an act of adapting to nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Maintain same -sex social relations &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &quot;Homosexual behavior occurs in many mammalian species, including large -scale human apes of our pro -animal animals. Behavior, our research shows that this sexual behavior of mammals is a convergence adaptation, which helps maintain social relations and reduce conflicts between same -sex. &quot; José M. Gómez, a professor at the University of Ecology and the University of Granada, told the southern weekend that although homosexual behavior appeared in many species, it is especially common in the long categories. It is precisely because psychoic animals are more social than many other mammalians. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the perspective of data, the research in more than 260 mammals found homosexual behavior. In more than 80% of the cases, its expression is in contact with the contact of the back or genitals, and there are less than 30%. Species even express homosexual behavior by seeking or pairing. In terms of age, homosexual behaviors mainly occur in adulthood mammals, and only young homosexual behaviors are found among 10 animals. In the environment, homosexual behavior in more than 80 % of the sample occurs in a wild or semi -wild environment. In terms of gender, the distribution of homosexual behaviors in the two sexes of mammals is relatively balanced. More than 160 species recorded female homosexual behavior. Among more than 190 species, male homosexual behaviors were found. There are two kinds of sexual behavior at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is worth noting that the latest research is based on the analysis of the same sexual behavior records of mammals, which does not represent the entire situation of mammals. In fact, because the discovery of homosexual behavior in nature depends on observation, and some species in some species are very similar to the male and male, and even the male and female are difficult to distinguish. Some scientists estimate that the current record of homosexual behavior of nature should be underestimated. Moreover, compared to mammals, birds, crawled animals, fish, insects, and other vertebrates, etc., either small size, or living away from the ground, and observing each other, but they all record similar sexual behaviors. Therefore, the mode of homosexual behavior in nature is far more complicated than observed in mammals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Earlier, many hypothesis understands homosexual behavior as adaptive or abnormal behavior. It is speculated that this behavior may be under specific conditions such as wrong gender identity, lack of heterosexuality, or frustration of heterosexual behaviors. Judging from the scene of sexual behavior, the latest research has found that the occurrence of homosexual behavior does not necessarily require extremely special occasions. Although the same sexual behavior in some species is very rare and can only be observed in extremely special cases, for about 40%of the mammals in the study, homosexual behavior can be called mid -to -high -frequency activities in a certain period of time. The season is easy to observe. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Hygens and opposite sex &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; And some behavior observations have shown very early that homosexual behavior may play a positive role in some populations. For example, some homosexual behaviors between male wide -kiss dolphins may help strengthen the alliance between small groups, and homosexual behaviors in female gorilla groups may promote reconciliation among members. However, the analysis of the latest research system does not focus on the mechanism of homogeneous behavior in specific species, but linked homosexual behavior with social behavior through large -scale statistics. This study shows that homosexual behavior is similar to many other behaviors that have evolved through natural selection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Professor Jose Gomez reminded that the significance of homosexual behavior here should be understood in the framework of evolutionary biology, which is still different from the current views of gender related issues such as gender. Because in the research of evolutionary biology, homosexual behavior is a short -term behavior of individuals in some periods, not permanent behavior or life choices, and they may also have heterosexual behaviors. Therefore, it cannot be directly related to human society. Behavioral analogy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In human society, problems related to homosexual behavior are rooted in different cultural environments and historical traditions in various places, and it is more complicated to understand. However, in recent years, the discussion that distinguish between human homosexual behavior has also attracted the attention of scientists. The core concern is to to what extent can people who have occurred in sexual behavior can be defined as homosexuality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2019, researchers at Harvard University and other institutions have published a large -scale genetic research in Science, trying to reveal the genetic characteristics of homosexual behavior, which is the so -called &quot;homosexuality Gene&quot;. Through the cooperation with the British Biological Bank and Gene Testing Analysis Company 23andme, the researchers finally identified multiple genetic sites related to homosexual behavior from hundreds of thousands of gene samples, indicating that &quot;homosexual genes&quot; are similar to other behavior characteristics. It is also genetic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But in 2021, scientists from the Institute of Gold, the University of Indiana, such as the Gold Research Institute of the University It is to mix the heterosexual, bisexual, and homosexuality, and does not accurately measure people&#39;s sexual behavior, sexual attraction and sexual recognition. Therefore, the genetic characteristics of the final discovery may not reveal the tendency of homosexual behavior, but only reveal it. Pursuit of freshness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Because of sexual researchers, heterosexuality should be a sustainable sexual attraction model. It cannot be determined that it is not heterosexual because a person has had homosexual behavior. Alfred Kinsey, a pioneer of sex research, is a person with a metering table to distinguish between homosexual behavior. According to the frequency of homosexual behavior, people can be divided into multiple types, not not Homosexual or heterosexuality. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; It may help breeding &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The controversy of human society about how to distinguish between homosexual behavior and homosexuality also reflects a difficulty to understand the logic of evolution to a certain extent. Compared with human society, the concepts such as &quot;homosexual behavior&quot;, &quot;homosexuality&quot;, and &quot;no offspring&quot; are highly bound, and homosexual behaviors may never mean &quot;no offspring&quot; in the long history of evolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Darwin&#39;s evolution paradox should be put aside, it no longer exists, because in various animal species, the existence of bisexual behavior can ensure that same -sex behavior does not hinder the success of reproduction.&quot; The empire of the empire. &quot; Professor Vincent Savolainen, a professor at the Department of Life Sciences of Institute of Technology, told the southern weekend that there are many concepts around homosexual behavior, but from the perspective of biology, homosexual behaviors, homosexuals, bisexuals, etc. There are some similar mechanisms and evolutionary logic, which is what biologists can continue to be studied in the future. At the same time, psychologists can also study other aspects of this complex behavior, such as sexual preferences, so as to better understand the evolution of homosexual behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From the historically point of view of homosexual behavior, the key to the difficulty of evolutionary logic is to speculate that it has high adaptation cost and the cost of behavior is too great. However, including the latest research, many studies have shown in recent years that homosexual behaviors do not mean &quot;broken descendants&quot; during the evolution, but may have a positive impact on bred offspring in other non -direct ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 2021, the scientist Brendan Zietsch, a scientist at the University of Queensland, Australia, used hundreds of thousands of samples of genetic data to simulate human evolution, which also contains a lot of heterosexuality Data from partner. Analysis shows that among people with heterosexual behaviors, genetic genes related to homosexual behavior can at the same time allow people to have more heterosexual partners, which means that they have obtained sexual mating advantages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Further analysis shows that behind this is also related to the characteristics of openness and adventure. People with more open personality will be more willing to try new things, and have stronger curiosity and imagination. Researchers speculate that genetically -related genes related to the tendency of homosexual behavior also give people related personality traits, which makes people with related genetic genes more advantageous in finding heterosexual partners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As a result, although homosexual behavior itself does not produce offspring, related genes can allow people to gain the advantages of fertility offspring, which leads to homosexual behavior to this day. However, Brundan Ziqi emphasized that although this study has the advantages of data, the relevant interpretation is still exploratory, and more research needs to understand the performance related to homosexual behavior to understand The foundation of its evolution. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; The hereditary of the long -term primary &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Professor Vincent Savolina has also carried out research on homosexual behavior, and obtained the conclusion of similar support for fertility advantages . In August 2023, through analysis of the three years of observation of data from the Ganges monkey, they found that homosexual behaviors in the Ganges monkey community were common, and they were basically not affected by age or community structure. What adaptability, instead, the same sexual behavior regulates the relationship between companions and improves the success rate of reproduction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Related research published in &quot;Nature Ecology &amp; Amp; Evolution&quot;, which observed the social and sexual behavior of more than 200 male Ganges monkeys. Combined with the bloodline data of decades ago, studies have shown that the same sexual behavior in the male Ganges monkeys is both duplicate and hereditary, with a genetic rate of 6.4%. The first evidence that can be inherited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Ganges monkey shared more than 70%of DNA with humans, tracing back to about 25 million years ago, and we also have a common ancestor with us. They are the main non -human long categories used in biomedical research. Animals are also an excellent model of ecological problems such as homosexual behavior. However, it is worth noting that there are still differences between the Ganges monkey and humans. We hope to study these intricate mysteries and find it. Our common behavior of evolutionary history. &quot;Professor Vincent Savarinen explained to the reporter from the south weekend that the latest research shows that homosexual behavior may be a common feature of the long -awaited ecology of spiritual long animals. Simplic behavior is inspired, but due to some unique social factors in human society, homosexual behavior in human society does have a great price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Humanity seems to be the only species that shows strict homosexuality.&quot; Professor Vincent Savolina said that cultural factors will affect this phenomenon. For example, in Samoa, although some gays have no descendants, they actually assume the role of women in the society and help children who support relatives. &quot;I hope that our research can play a role in cultivating more tolerant culture, and to inclusive gender diversity in nature and human society.&quot; >;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt; a href = &quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style = &quot;color: orange&quot; target = &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 22:25:23 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网购二手“人脉”真的靠谱吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260873]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-18 21:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[不在职业资格目录中的“律师经纪人”，3860元拿证]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260871]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-18 20:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt = &quot;&quot; Lawyer agent &quot;in lawsuits in many related contract disputes. Visual picture) &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;heart =&quot; 764 &quot;data dataa&quot; data dataa &quot;data&quot; data dataa data &quot;data dataa&quot; data dataa &quot;data dataa data&quot; data dataa &quot;data dataa dataa&quot; data &quot;dataa&quot; data dataa &quot;data dataa dataa&quot; data dataa &quot;data dataa&quot; data dataa &quot;data dataa dataa&quot; data dataa &quot;data dataa dataa&quot; data &quot;data dataa -SRC = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;258743&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>;&quot; Lawyers agent &quot;in lawsuits on contract disputes appeared. (Photo of the People&#39;s Visual) &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On November 14, 2023, a recommendation letter issued by the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association was circulated in the lawyer world. The letter shows that the association recommends a &quot;lawyer agent&quot; to the Haicheng People&#39;s Court as an agent entrusted by a litigation in a borrowing dispute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After the recommendation letter is made public, multiple lawyers posted on social media to express their concerns about the lawyer&#39;s agent that might break the industry&#39;s atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Lawyer agent&quot; is not the first time that it can be retrieved to 27 civil and executive cases on the referee document network. Among them, the 24 cases of lawyers agents, as litigants, were tried by courts at all levels of Liaoning Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is certain that the lawyer agent should be the &quot;created&quot; of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association. The association recommends others as litigants in the name of social groups. However, relevant legal persons pointed out that the operation of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association violated the relevant laws and regulations, and in the national vocational qualifications, there was no occupation related to the &quot;lawyer agent&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After the case is fermented in the legal community, there are already local law associations issuing a prompt: When lawyers perform their duties, they find &quot;lawyer agent&quot; and &quot;legal agent&quot;. Do not participate in the operation of related companies and institutions to the case handling agency. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; Each agent is together, you must pay 500 yuan to the association &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left; &quot;>; In the past jurisprudence, the&quot; lawyer agent &quot;mainly appeared in insurance disputes, contract disputes, and private lending disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;Text-Align: left;&quot;>; In the Disputes of a motor vehicle traffic accident liability in March 2023, Xiao Mou drove a passenger cars and riding an electric vehicle through the red light. Yang collided and Yang was injured. Yang subsequently sued the two insurance companies that Xiao Mou and Xiao Mou insured, demanding a total of about 250,000 yuan in compensation. Yang&#39;s two litigation agents are &quot;lawyers&#39; agents&quot;. In the end, Shenyang Yuhong District Court sentenced an insurance company to pay about 120,000 yuan in compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In a contract number (2022) Liaoning 14, Liaoning No. 1093, a contract dispute, Yang and Liu signed a transfer agreement for the tableware factory to agree to Yang After a period of payment of 170,000 transfers, but after the first payment payment period expired, Yang did not pay as agreed. Liu Mousung sued Yang to ask for performance and pay a liquidated damage for about 200,000 yuan. Yang defeated the case in the first instance, appealed to the Huludao Intermediate Court, and commissioned a &quot;lawyer agent&quot; to serve as his litigation agent. The Huludao Intermediate People&#39;s Court did not support Yang&#39;s demands, and the original judgment was maintained in the second instance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The similarities of these cases are that the &quot;lawyer agent&quot; of the agency case comes from the same social organization: Liaoning Provincial Broker Association Lawyer Agent Special Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The National Social Organization Credit Information Disclosure Platform shows that the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association was established in 2007. In order to guide the provincial brokerage industry, organize the business training of brokers, and provide legal, policy, information consulting services, etc. to brokers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lawyer broker specializing committee is the lower part of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association. With the Liaoning Provincial Broker Qualification Certificate, you can solve the qualifications of agency litigation: only 3860 yuan is required once, you can obtain a certificate after training and exams. Cases, engaging in court response and other related activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In addition, each person who obtains the person who obtains the broker&#39;s qualification certificate must pay 500 yuan to the association to issue a recommendation letter. In addition, the broker qualification certificate requires annual inspection at an annual inspection, cost 50 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; significantly different from citizen agent &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Lawyer agent After the incident was fermented, the citizen agent was placed under the spotlight again. However, the lawyer agency&#39;s agency case initiated by the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association is obviously different from the normal citizen agent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Before the amendment of the civil proceedings law in 2012, the law allows three types of citizens to represent civil litigation cases: the close relatives of the parties, the related social groups, or the unit where their units are located People; other citizens who are entrusted by the parties and approved by the People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wu Zhiwei, deputy director of the Applied Law Research Base of the Supreme People&#39;s Court of Southwest University of Political Science and Law, said that the quality of citizens&#39; agency services is poor and the charges are not standardized. When bribing judges and other issues, when the Civil Procedure Law was amended in 2012, they deleted the &quot;other citizens permitted by the court&quot; and limited the scope of citizens as entrusted litigation agents into two categories: the close relatives or staff of the parties; Units and citizens recommended by related social groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The further requirements for the recommendation of the community are seen in the explanation of the Supreme People&#39;s Court on the applicable civil procedure law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In it, if the relevant social organizations recommend citizens to act as litigants, the community shall be a non-profit legal person established in accordance with the law. The agent should be a member of the community, or the place where the parties live in the activity area of ​​the social group.此外，被推荐人还应该是社团的负责人或与社团有劳动关系的工作人员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;比照相关规定，吴志伟认为，严格来讲，辽宁省经纪人协会的行为，违反了司法解释第87条的规定，“这些人不具备代理法律事务的资格”，代理事务必须属于该社会团体章程载明的业务范围，经纪人协会的业务范围一般与经纪人有关，而从目前公开的裁判文书看，案件的被代理人并非是经纪人，“假如经纪人出现了相关民事纠纷，他们作为诉讼代理人，这才是符合规定的”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;另一个问题是，社会团体能否提供有偿服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;早在1993年，司法部就发布过《关于公民个人未经批准不得从事有偿法律服务的批复》明文要求，这意味着公民代理不能收取报酬。依据相关规定，公民代理中的差旅费可以要求当事人报销。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但律师经纪人显然是收取费用的。 2023年11月14日，辽宁省内一起合同纠纷的判决结果在律师界流传：一位律师经纪人因在此前代理的离婚诉讼中未履行出庭义务遭委托方起诉，诉请返还5000元法律服务fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;辽宁省民政厅社会组织管理局于2023年3月22日发布的《社会组织开展法律服务活动提示单》中已提到，个别社会组织违法推荐公民代理诉讼，谋取不正当的经济利益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这份提示单提到，按照相关规定，涉法类社会组织严格实行登记管理机关和业务主管单位双重负责的管理体制。社会组织应当依照章程规定的宗旨和业务范围开展活动，不得从事营利性经营活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;不在国家职业资格目录中&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;尽管辽宁省经纪人协会已向多人发授律师经纪人资格证，但“律师经纪”这一职业并不在人社部2021年公布的《国家职业资格目录》中。该目录规定的职业资格均明确了实施部门或单位，并要求除此之外任何机构或者单位不得再自行设置实施职业资格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月15日，南方周末记者就相关问题致电咨询辽宁省经纪人协会会长陈文成，其先表态称只能承接辽宁省内案件，后又表示，目前不直接做民事诉讼，也不做律师经纪人相关业务。截至发稿，该协会官网已无法正常显示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;11月16日，南方周末记者多次致电辽宁省司法厅，接线人员称对“律师经纪人”不了解，具体情况可咨询当地律协。南方周末记者多次致电辽宁省律师协会，截至发稿未获回复。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据上游新闻报道，辽宁省民政厅相关工作人员回应称，对辽宁省经纪人协会的相关情况，将介入调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月15日，北京市通州区律协发出提示，若律师履职时发现“律师经纪人”“法务经纪人”问题，应当向所在办案机关提出异议，切勿参与“法务经纪人”“律师经纪人”等相关公司、机构的运行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在辽宁省内，抚顺市民政局、铁岭市民政局等机构都已发出类似提示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国人的家当]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从2003年开始，我拍摄《家当》系列作品已经20年，一共148张作品。 I moved a family in different spaces into the same space and let them take photos with the owner. Most of these photos were taken outdoors and the home as the background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我过去的作品中有90%拍摄于中国，那是中国经济高速发展和实现现代化、全球化的时期，我用这种特殊的摆拍方式来记录，真实的内部空间被短暂地呈露在外部空间中，结合当下环境的变更、城市的扩张、科技的发展、人们生活方式的改变，以静态的纪实制造出一个动态的社会图景. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年，我开始拍摄美国的家庭。家是组成社会的最小单元，许多这样的单元组成了整个社会，我继续用“家当”系列，来反映美国当代社会的内部结构和多元化。 I observed that the American family, regardless of urban and rural areas, the basic material living standards are not much different, so I pay more attention to showing their spiritual attributes. I have a long preparation time before shooting each work. I understand the story of the characters in advance, visit their rooms, think about the idea of ​​shooting, and carefully choose items used for display. The choice of family not only covers the native Americans, but also the immigrants who miss their hometown, which is the idea of ​​love, occupation, identity and gender and time.每个画面里的物品都经过了精心布置，用物质来反映精神生活，我将这些带有精神属性的物品进行空间挪移，并摆放在同一个画面里叠加，将平时司空见惯的场景进行视觉强化，突出这个家庭或个体在当下的生活状态、信仰和情感记忆，用一张照片勾勒出一个现实状态与精神世界的结合。读者可以很直接地通过照片和他们的故事产生思考。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;非常感谢那些愿意面对我的镜头，展示他们的家当以及分享他们故事的家庭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;惠特妮·詹森（Whitney Jensen） 2022年8月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/cbb711c0c3.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/cbb711c0c3.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;惠特妮·詹森（Whitney Jensen）2022年8月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;惠特妮·詹森，36岁。 She is a very cheerful and enthusiastic woman. She was born and grew up in Gelsberg, Illinois, USA. She went to Iowa to travel and fell in love and got married during the trip. She worked in the hotel industry for many years.当婚姻结束，新冠疫情暴发，她搬到了皮奥里亚，并找到一份摄影师的工作，在公园拍照时还被杂志报道过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前她在宝马专卖店做销售员。 She also likes interior design and makes some small art devices by herself. In addition to the work of the BMW store, she also has other part -time jobs, including the help of a non -profit organization, and performed poems in the contemporary art center every Thursday night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;惠特妮的很多家当来自家人，比如奶奶的古董箱子和被枪杀的表哥的旧沙发，她对这些物品充满感情，与她一起长大的好友领了第一个月的薪水送她一条猫头鹰项链，从此她收集各种猫头鹰，她的名字Whitney本身的含义就是智慧的猫头鹰，这是她姨给她取的名字。她出生在歌星惠特尼·休斯顿最火的时代。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;乔治，擦鞋匠（George, the Shoeshine Man） 2023年2月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/bef1b74cca.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/bef1b74cca.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乔治，擦鞋匠（George, the Shoeshine Man）2023年2月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;乔治·马尼亚斯，92岁，与朋友、家人和顾客们一起庆祝了他76周年的工作纪念日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他曾经为美国总统杰拉尔德·福特、罗纳德·里根、乔治·W·布什、比尔·克林顿、巴拉克·奥巴马和乔·拜登，1952年以来每位伊利诺伊州州长，1957年以来每位皮奥里亚市长以及许多名人、外交官和商人擦过皮鞋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1931年，乔治在美国伊利诺伊州皮奥里亚出生，他的父母是希腊移民。他四岁时回到父母的故乡克里特岛，纳粹占领了这个岛。乔治被抓住，被迫赤脚为德国人提水、忍饥挨饿。二战后，乔治与家人1946年身无分文地回到皮奥里亚。乔治在15岁开始当擦鞋童获取收入来帮助家庭。通过辛勤工作，乔治用省下来的钱购买了一个店铺，命名为“乔治的擦鞋店和帽子店”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;乔治赢得过许多荣誉和奖章，他几十年的辛勤工作受到来自世界各地的访客的赞誉。乔治无论对待谁都一视同仁，对待鞋子也不论贵贱，他徒手把鞋油擦在皮革上，至于其他秘诀，他认为现在披露还为时过早。每年1月1日，乔治都会把年份写到一块砖上以求好运。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;现在他每天工作4个小时，每周5天，86岁的弟弟曼尼每天陪伴着他。他认为这个房间里的椅子是他最重要的家当；这是他与人们见面、团结社区的地方。摆在前面的除了他的擦鞋工具，还有他和六届美国总统及政要的合影。乔治从未结婚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;科琳·约翰逊（Colleen Johnson） 2023年6月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/5d4803a8f6.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/5d4803a8f6.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科琳·约翰逊（Colleen Johnson）2023年6月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;科琳，58岁，几年前丈夫因病去世，目前独居。她在皮奥里亚市中心的一家软件、网站设计和网络公司担任开发总监。她经常活跃于纪念历史事件的活动，尤其关注美国废奴运动和南北战争，她为种族平等发表演讲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;科琳喜欢古老的家具和祖传的物件，其中一些是祖母收藏的亚洲古董。她喜欢将自然带到房子里，收藏的艺术品和装饰品大多与植物和动物有关。她的装饰品经常成双成对，荷花、树叶、鸟的元素反复出现，她养的绿植和花卉也经常成双。她喜欢保留和回忆美好的东西，在这些纪念品中有祖母当年手工制作的布娃娃，妈妈做的被子，已故丈夫的衬衫。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;科琳在生活中是一位母亲和祖母，她的儿子和儿媳住在车程90分钟的另一个城市，他们的女儿3岁，还有一个即将出生的儿子。科琳有一只可爱的约克夏梗犬，名叫Toto，她享受新生命带来的喜悦。科琳喜欢在河边散步和锻炼，还参加帆船比赛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前她刚刚开始新的恋情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;普拉萨纳·吉尔（Prasanna Jeer） 2023年4&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 536232ce15.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/536232ce15.JPG&quot; data- key=&quot;258481&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;普拉萨纳·吉尔（Prasanna Jeer）2023年4月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;普拉萨纳·吉尔和妻子拉瓦亚（Lavanya）来自印度南部金奈, 他在印度完成了教育并工作几年后，于13年前怀抱许多梦想和希望来到U.S. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;普拉萨纳是一名IT职员，为卡特彼勒工作，工作之余他每天跳舞，舞蹈承载他的激情和梦想。他用业余时间创办了两所舞蹈学校，教印度传统舞蹈和宝莱坞舞蹈，七年来他的学生已经有一百多名，普拉萨纳和学生们成为皮奥里亚各大节日活动舞台的顶梁柱，他们还为慈善机构义务演出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;普拉萨纳的舞蹈家当有一些是从印度带过来，还有一些是他们手工制作。他们的女儿奥里雅（Oviya）和英妮亚（Iniya）从小就学会跳舞，舞蹈是这个印度家庭生活的不可缺少的一部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;普拉萨纳说他在美国实现了他的梦想，感激给他机会的人们，他愿意用自己的力量回报这个社区，用舞蹈把人们连接起来，分享快乐，分享爱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;亚历山大·马丁（Alexander Martin） 2023年5月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f7e76b5835.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f7e76b5835.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;亚历山大·马丁（Alexander Martin）2023年5月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;亚历山大·马丁是一位艺术家、表演者、教育工作者和社区倡导者。她出生并成长在西弗吉尼亚州的阿巴拉契亚山脉，大约9年前搬到伊利诺伊州攻读研究生学位，并一直居住在这里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;她努力在这个空间中真实、有力、愉悦地存在，而她的作品给予了她这样一个平台。它也让她分享个人叙事和她社区的故事，并庆祝它们的存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这个家是她有史以来第一栋自己拥有的房子，对她来说是一个非常重要的空间。她希望这个房子成为一个避难所，一个安全的存在空间，一个快乐的空间，一个宽松和幸福的神圣之地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;时尚和服装在她的生活中扮演着重要的角色。从表演用的服装到日常穿着，她的打扮和装饰都有着意义，并且对她来说拥有各种各样的物品来打造造型是很重要的。这是她每天表达和真实生活的方式。她深信，成为一名艺术家不仅仅在于你所创造的作品，还在于你如何生活。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;李檬和潘春晖（Meng Li &amp;amp; Chunhui Pan） 2023年4月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/d4a15b82ec.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/d4a15b82ec.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;李檬和潘春晖（Meng Li &amp;amp; Chunhui Pan）2023年4月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;潘春晖自北京大学毕业后出国留学，博士毕业后留在美国工作。他是非常具有代表性的当年中国高材生出国深造热潮的学生之一，一直在世界五百强企业卡特彼勒工作，已经在美国生活31年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;女主人李檬也拥有相似的经历，结婚后放弃了朝九晚五的工作，但是花很多时间做志愿者，尤其热衷于宣传Chinese culture.她是Global Fest的董事成员和中国展台负责人，华人春晚演出中也有她的身影。很多家具、家居用品和装饰品是从中国带过来，跟随他们多年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他们手中拿的书法作品《家》，是在他们结婚的时候与双方父母一起，每人用毛笔写了一两个笔划，组成了这个“家”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;伯特·拉贝和丽莎·拉贝（Burt Raabe &amp;amp; Lisa Raabe） 2023年4月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/16/61ddc6fa3c.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/61ddc6fa3c.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;伯特·拉贝和丽莎·拉贝（Burt Raabe &amp;amp; Lisa Raabe）2023年4月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;伯特和丽莎·拉贝结婚已经20年，他们在这所房子里住了10 years.丽莎在宾夕法尼亚西北部长大，并毕业于芝加哥艺术学院。她拥有伊利诺伊州立大学的艺术治疗硕士学位，并参与了15年的咨询工作，同时也是一名瑜伽教师。她现在是一名全职艺术家，拥有布拉德利大学的艺术硕士学位。她的作品在中西部地区展出，并获得了几个奖项。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;伯特的曾祖父1867年从德国来到美国务农，他在伊利诺伊州的核桃市长大，于1968年毕业于布拉德利大学，曾在印度的和平队任职，曾担任焊工、咨询师和导师。他现在从事写作诗歌，并出版了两本诗集，其中有几首诗歌也发表在杂志上。伯特和丽莎喜欢旅行，多次前往印度。在美国，他们喜欢芝加哥、华盛顿特区和莫特尔海滩。他们更喜欢乘坐火车，而不是飞行或者开车出行。照片中的许多物品是丽莎用于她的艺术作品的材料；还有来自两个家庭和二手商店的物品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;梅和乔纳森·赖特（Mae &amp;amp; Jonathan Wright） 2023年6月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4913f98a0a.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4913f98a0a.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258485&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;梅和乔纳森·赖特（Mae &amp;amp; Jonathan Wright）2023年6月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;梅是中伊利诺伊州艺术合作伙伴协会的执行主任，也是布拉德利大学公共历史协调员和附属教师。她在苏格兰爱丁堡大学获得神学硕士和博士学位，研究古希腊宗教手稿在时间上的变化，于2013年回到伊利诺伊州皮奥里亚，随后与乔纳森相爱并结婚。乔纳森是一位作家、编辑、传媒专家、黑胶唱片DJ，也是皮奥里亚音乐界的老将。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;乔纳森拥有超过一万张黑胶唱片；梅收集当地艺术家的艺术作品；他们两人都有大量的书籍收藏。乔纳森主要阅读非虚构类书籍。在他们的关系最初的几年里，梅更倾向于学术/古希腊书籍，以及宗教研究，但近年来她开始沉浸在小说中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他们有三只猫，分别叫做卢娜、赫敏和弗蕾嘉，但更大的家庭是社区。他们花了很多时间做志愿工作。梅是中伊利诺伊州妇女基金会和皮奥里亚市公共艺术咨询委员会的成员，以及中伊利诺伊州动物福利拨款委员会的成员。乔纳森则担任皮奥里亚交响乐团、中伊利诺伊州爵士乐协会、布拉德利大学特纳创业中心咨询委员会和皮奥里亚市/县种族正义与公平委员会的指导委员会成员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他们的房子讲述着作为一对夫妻的时光故事。这是一座建于1913年的老房子，当他们购买时需要进行大量维护工作。乔纳森和梅逐步将其打造成一个不想离开的美丽的空间，前院的树是他们夫妻共同种下的，与他们的婚姻一同成长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;艾丽卡·帕姆森（Erica Pamson） 2023年5月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/e6cf25f6a1.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/e6cf25f6a1.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258486&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;艾丽卡·帕姆森（Erica Pamson）2023年5月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;艾丽卡，29岁，刚刚在伊利诺伊州迪凯特的米利金大学完成了艺术治疗学士学位，并将前往马萨诸塞州剑桥的莱斯利大学攻读表达疗愈专业研究生课程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;她同时也是马戏团杂耍演员、视觉艺术家和表演艺术家。在舞台上，她以Hexli的名字为人所知。她在美国各地表演，作品结合了不同类型的表演艺术，包括舞踏、杂耍、火舞、仪式身体和现场绘画。 “Hexli”挂毯是她个人的杂耍旗帜，是好友和知名演员The Enigma亲手缝制的礼物，也是他给她取的艺名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;她在这间公寓里住了两年。她的家里有许多表演服装和道具，还有已完成和正在进行中的绘画作品。这个家是她第一个真正属于自己的地方，她对有机会在这个空间里成长和创作感到非常感激。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;王能和冯露曦（Neng Wang &amp;amp; Lucy Feng） 2023年4月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6ba90c1112.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6ba90c1112.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258487&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王能和冯露曦（Neng Wang &amp;amp; Lucy Feng）2023年4月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;王能和冯露曦是一对来自中国大陆的80后第一代移民。来美国十多年，一路过关斩将，先读书后工作，数次搬家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;两人从不同的城市，通过教会举办的活动相识，到相爱再到结婚，现居住在伊利诺伊州皮奥利亚小镇，两人也积累了一些属于自己的家当。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;柯克·佩里和芭比·佩里（Kirk Perry &amp;amp; Barbie Perry） 2023年5月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/a7a5fc9eb1.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/a7a5fc9eb1.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;柯克·佩里和芭比·佩里（Kirk Perry &amp;amp; Barbie Perry）2023年5月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;芭比出生在一个中西部家庭白人中，她的父母都经历过大萧条时期。她的父亲在二战中成为德国战俘18个月，战争对他造成了毁灭性的影响，并影响了整个家庭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;芭比经历了家庭暴力、心理疾病、药物和酒精问题，并多次因自杀意念而住院。生活缺乏结构，无法寻求帮助导致了她在整个童年和二十多岁时期过着艰难的生活。她生下了女儿斯蒂芬妮，作为单亲妈妈长达13年。女儿自1岁起先后进行过15次手术。女儿的出生成为芭比生活的转折点，她通过各种疗法开始拯救自己。她得以完成学业并找到工作，曾从事过各种工作，包括冰淇淋服务员、零售销售员、女招待等等。这段艰难的生活在1997年芭比遇到柯克·佩里并在一年后与他结婚后结束。自那时以来，得到了爱和耐心倾听，芭比过上了美丽、充实且充满爱的生活。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;柯克·佩里是一名退休的刑事情报分析师，曾在伊利诺伊州警察局工作。他拥有刑事司法副学士学位、行政司法学士学位和法学博士学位。在三十多年的职业生涯中，他不仅破解了许多犯罪案件，将许多坏人送入监狱。他在六岁时爱上了书籍，并从未停止阅读。他拥有超过一万本的漫画书收藏。芭比从2015年开始创作艺术，全部关于女权主义，而柯克则写了三本小说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对于这对夫妇来说，芭比娃娃收藏是他们爱情的见证。在婚姻中，芭比和柯克养过7只狗，而饼干是目前他们心爱的宠物狗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;布兰迪·森蒂-菲斯拉尔（Brandie Centi-Fislar） 2023年8月&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9294743f69.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9294743f69.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258489&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;布兰迪·森蒂-菲斯拉尔（Brandie Centi-Fislar）2023年8月&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;布兰迪·森蒂-菲斯拉尔，31岁，来自宾夕法尼亚州克利尔菲尔德，2010年高中毕业后，她获得游泳和足球奖学金，被伊利诺伊州林肯市的林肯学院录取。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2012年，她获得了艺术副学士学位，并转学到伊利诺伊州诺莫尔的伊利诺伊州立大学开始艺术学习。她从艺术教育开始，后来转专业为玻璃吹制。与此同时，她开始和现在的丈夫约会。在接下来的10年里，她和丈夫一起完成了学士学位，并打了很多份工，努力保持经济稳定。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;经历了很多美好的时光和一些糟糕的时光，他们现在拥有了一个梦想的房子，里面住满了他们的毛孩子（三只狗和两只猫），可以在压力较小的情况下享受生活。她仍然全职吹制玻璃，每天都享受创意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“从深度和广度推动中新合作” | 亚太群英荟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260859]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据外交部消息，2023年11月1日，外交部部长助理农融同新加坡贸工部常秘林明亮以视频方式举行中新双边合作机制会议高官会。 In March of this year, Singapore Prime Minister Li Xianlong visited China. Sino -new relations were promoted to a comprehensive and high -quality forward -looking partnership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中新合作再上一个台阶的契机下，南方周末研究员在新加坡采访了南洋理工大学协理副校长刘宏教授。 As alumni of Xiamen University and Fudan University, Liu Hong has studied and worked in many countries in Asia, North America, and Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘宏表示，在过去十多年，他从教学、研究和管理工作中注意到，中国和新加坡的关系正呈现出全方位、与时俱进和高质量几个特点.从早期的中国向新加坡学习，已改变成双向的互相学习、互相借鉴的趋势。随着中新关系进入新的发展阶段，南洋理工大学也在不断提升合作项目的水准，从深度和广度方面，进一步推动新加坡和中国的友好和合作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;刘宏&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/cac4375609.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1544&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/cac4375609.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258735&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;刘宏&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;娄晓希摄&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;到中国去，百闻不如一见&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你在世界多个国家的高校学习和工作过，感觉中国学生和其他国家的学生相比有什么特点？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘宏：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;中国大陆的学生总的特点是非常勤奋好学。每年毕业的大学生超过1000万，竞争非常大。 Among college students in various countries I have contacted, Chinese students can be said to be a leading degree.这一方面是因为中华民族具有热爱学习的传统，但另一方面也是因为社会竞争越来越激烈，所以大家都要脱颖而出。 College students&#39; employment is a big challenge. Chinese students are very concerned about the development of the world, and they also have a strong willingness to study abroad.我本人在荷兰和美国留学，然后在新加坡、英国工作，在日本京都大学和大阪大学待了快两年时间，有较多切身感受。 I think the characteristics of Chinese students&#39; diligence and learning are very obvious. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你认为东西方高等教育体系有什么不Same? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘宏：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我在荷兰学习了一年多、在美国留学也有五年多时间。西方国家有对知识追求的传统，它并不是以考试成绩作为主要的目标，而是一个比较发散型的、比较多元的目标。学生根据自己的兴趣来选一些科目，所以会多元化、多角度地来看一些问题，但是我觉得西方教育有一个较大的缺陷——对包括中国在内的发展中国家的了解比较欠缺。最近有学者分析，在2010年代的国际政治经济学的教科书和相关论文里，有关中国的比例不到只占11%，是很小的比例；但中国现在已经是全世界第二大的经济体，它的GDP总量已经接近世界的20%左右，可见大学教材中有关中国的知识十分缺乏。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如何通过教育让西方更好地了解中国? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘宏：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我在英国任职期间，曾组织好几次来自全英不同高校的数百名大学生到中国做两周至三周的游学和浸濡，我把这个项目取名为“体验动感中国”(Experience a Dynamic China)。很多英国人对中国的了解很缺乏，也很过时，而且大都是书本上看到的。通过我们组织他们到北京、上海、南京、广州、济南这些不同的城市，到不同的地方（包括农村），让他们感受到一个不断变化和发展中的中国。我觉得，在国际教育和交流中，我们可以有更多的中国故事，有更多中国声音。其中的一个来源是让外国人士自己来感受。我从这些浸濡活动的参与者所得到的反馈是，很多人回去之后，都讲到对中国的印象几乎发生了翻天覆地的变化，百闻不如一见。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;科研成果落地大湾区&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;南洋理工大学在粤港澳大湾区如何推动中新教育领域的合作？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘宏：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;大湾区现在是中国发展最具有潜力的一个地区。新加坡和中国合作建立了中新广州知识城，我们大学跟知识城、华南理工大学共同成立了中新国际联合研究院，进展非常好。除了产学研结合之外，知识城还安排一些政府官员到我们这里来培训。我自己目前在主持由广州市开发区和中新知识城委托的营商环境改进和提升的调研项目。我们希望，讲到中国的发展并不是纸上谈兵，而是对中国最新的发展有一个了解，然后把中国的发展跟世界的发展连在一起。在这个过程里，新加坡能够提供哪些有益的经验？又怎样共同进步？其实，我们项目的宗旨是推动新加坡和中国、东盟和中国的友好关系，这个大目标是我和我的同事共同努力的方向。这也是南洋理工大学新任校长何德华教授最近提出打造“南洋理工大学新加坡-中国知识枢纽”的主要目标。不管是新加坡政府还是南洋理工大学，都非常关注和重视大湾区的发展，比如我刚才讲到的中新广州知识城，它已成为中新两国之间的国家级项目之后，依托并得益于大湾区迅速发展的大背景。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;作为南洋理工大学协理副校长，对未来合作有哪些规划？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘宏：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;不管是在广州、香港，还是深圳，现在和未来我们都有很多的合作，这些合作不仅仅注重于人才的培养，我们也特别注重产学研结合。新中关系更多的是相互学习、相互借鉴，与时俱进的关系。我们主要目的是把世界各地特别是新加坡的最新科研成果，转化到大湾区这块肥沃的土壤上，并使之生根发芽并且推广。这也是为什么我们在广州设立国际联合研究院，也是为什么与深圳的合作中，很注重的一点就是创新。新加坡和深圳把合作建立智慧城市、数字经济这一系列新发展作为重点。深圳在创新方面引领的不仅仅是中国，也是引领世界。我们一直跟大湾区的高校有很多的合作。跟香港的高校在进行学生交流、科研合作，也会进一步深化。今后我们南洋公共管理研究生院可能会在广州和深圳等地进一步加大人才培养的力度。深圳越来越关注东盟，东盟当然也可以借助深圳或者广东的平台来进一步发展。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在公共治理领域方面，新加坡和中国有哪些可相互借鉴的经验？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘宏：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们的研究特别关注亚洲公共治理。现在，整个全球公共治理的一些理论、经验和模式，主要是建立在西方经验的基础上。我们希望通过深入分析新加坡、中国的发展和东盟其他国家的发展模式，来探索这些国家的经验，并分析它们对全球公共治理理论和实践有哪些帮助。我们有不少的研究项目，包括关注“一带一路”作为跨界治理的新模式，关注亚洲国家和非洲国家之间的互相学习和借鉴，也包括在“一带一路”的背景下，中国企业“走出去”以及和其他国家合作的不同模式，这是我本人以及我们学院的几个研究重点。我们希望未来继续跟中国政府、国企或者高校保持密切联系。随着中新关系进入新的发展阶段，我们也在不断地提升项目的水准，从深度和广度方面进一步推动新加坡和中国的友好合作。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;文明对话的精髓&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你怎么看待“一带一路”倡议？未来发展的重点方向是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘宏：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;今年是“一带一路”倡议提出10周年，是一个非常重要的发展里程碑。在过去这几个月，我应邀做了不下10次有关“一带一路”的演讲。看得出来，世界不同的国家，对“一带一路”都很关注，虽然它们的出发点有所不同。 “一带一路”倡议中的“五通”包括了民心相通和政策沟通，这也是我们学院及我本人都非常关注的两个方面。我把“五通”里面的民心相通和政策沟通看作一个软件；基础设施建设、贸易、投资这些是硬件，硬件跟软件要有机地结合，才能够发挥最好的作用。未来的发展，我们一方面要思考怎样在这10年取得的成就基础上，进一步提升“一带一路”项目的质量和影响力，包括注重数字经济、绿色发展、公共卫生这一系列的课题，这些会成为“一带一路”未来发展的重点。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在青年一代在中国文化“走出去”方面，可发挥什么作用？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;刘宏：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;中国文化“走出去”进行文明对话，需要我们进一步展开。在这个过程里，来自中国的年轻人，还有中国的国企，中国的科研人员、高校教师等等，都扮演了重要角色。我觉得，未来发展上，把握好中国文化发展的自身精髓很重要，包括中国文化传统的一些特点：守正不守旧，尊古不复古。首先要了解自己的文化，有自己文化的根，然后与其他的文化展开对话。其次，还是要以平等、包容、开放、尊重的心态来看待其他的文化。在文化方面，每一个国家的文化都有它自身的特点和优点，都是在不同国家自身环境下的产物，我们应该本着理解和尊重的态度，不能说这个事情中国这样做，你为什么不this way?只有理解和交流才能够真正地做到文化“走出去”。第三，还是要注重创新，不管中国文化也好，其他国家文化也好，都要反映新时代的发展特点，包括我们现在所处的第四次工业革命，全球化和逆全球化并行的时代，全球地缘政治也发生了很多的变化。在这样的情况下，应该看中国文化、世界文化的种创造性的转型，实现更有效的对话。中国政府提出的“全球发展倡议”和“全球文明倡议”，给世界的发展提供了中国智慧。中国智慧有非常深厚的内涵，但是在沟通和交流的方式上，我们还有更多的努力空间，让世界各国了解中华文化的精髓。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>