<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[男子被120公斤杠铃砸死，健身房内发生的意外谁来买单？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257938]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山东学生身高全国第一？黑龙江人挺直了腰板表示摇头]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257651]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;The average height of high school students in Shandong is 1.8 meters&quot; has caused heated discussion. However, netizens in Shandong have posted When the tall man next to him came out, Heilongjiang netizens were not idle either. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in the national height competition between boys and girls, the height of boys in Heilongjiang ranks first, while the height of girls ranks first in Shandong Province. With the development of economy and life As the level increases, the average heights of men and women are 174 cm and 161.4 cm respectively. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Height has always been a topic of public concern. What kind of height is best in the eyes of the opposite sex? According to Polish scientist Pokryka, the standard for a perfect woman is an average height of 1.74 meters, and the standard for a perfect man is an average height of no less than 1.82 meters, with leg length equal to the length of the upper body, and a ratio of 1:1 that makes a man Looks stronger. However, the so-called perfect body standard cannot be generalized. In the era of aesthetic diversity, health has a standard definition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what factors determine height? First of all, 70% of a person&#39;s final height depends on genetic factors, but in addition to genes, nutrition, exercise, environment, living habits, etc. all have a great impact on height. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this is only an ideal standard. In reality, there are still relatively few situations that can achieve this state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the current aesthetic trend of society pursuing height, many people will have height anxiety and try unconventional remedies to increase their height through injections, medicines, and surgeries. However, these methods have certain risks. . &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; kindly reminds you how we should treat the height issue rationally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/16cf2dcb0158e649e618c3473a1cca4b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/16cf2dcb0158e649e618c3473a1cca4b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252072&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/cac7600c61568750cf1f386f29749055.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/cac7600c61568750cf1f386f29749055.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252073&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/6845665a65be5d8656acc2e82b9870f3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/6845665a65be5d8656acc2e82b9870f3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252074&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/7499d3bd6e19e9fe5d1ed72624f40192.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/7499d3bd6e19e9fe5d1ed72624f40192.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252075&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/49969dc59efdd5d5c0defbdff8c53615.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/49969dc59efdd5d5c0defbdff8c53615.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252076&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/2522bcfd6ff43f2145542646209f877b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/2522bcfd6ff43f2145542646209f877b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252077&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot; https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c6f26de596a834b79b4e9c493189113a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/c6f26de596a834b79b4e9c493189113a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252078&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“身心灵导师”学霸猫从者如云：哪类人最容易被收割？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258010]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;New Weekly&quot; reported on the &quot;body, mind and soul mentor&quot; Xueba Mao, triggering an investigation into the so-called &quot; Controversies and discussions about &quot;Zero Limit Cleansing Method&quot; and spiritual practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xuebamao taught his followers, such as &quot;People don&#39;t have to work hard, everything will go naturally and smoothly&quot;, &quot;Whatever you do should be easy, don&#39;t endure hardship, don&#39;t get entangled, follow your own preferences&quot;, smell Is it a little bit Lao-Zhuang and Buddhist? According to reports, the theory of &quot;Zero Limit Cleansing Method&quot; comes from &quot;At Zero&quot; written by American Xiu Lan in 2007. It is translated as &quot;Zero Limit: Hawaiian Therapy for Creating Health, Calm and Wealth&quot;, and the mantra is &quot;Sorry, Please forgive me, thank you, I love you.” Doesn’t it sound very positive? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, a group of young people who were inexperienced in the world joined Xueba Mao&#39;s &quot;body, mind and soul community&quot;. &quot;There are thousands of people, and more than 70% of them are women.&quot; Ordinary spiritual practices often teach people to control or let go of desires. Xuebamao does the opposite, allowing students or believers to buy without asking the price or looking at the labels. Debt does not matter. Xuebamao believes that in order to “clear away the fear of money, one must choose a method of flowing large amounts of money to open up one’s own energy.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people believe in it and use their savings to buy or borrow money to buy what they like, and buy various courses and consultations from Xuebamao. &quot;With the expansion of the community one after another, there has been a trend of debt consumption among students. Living in a large flat, driving a luxury car, going to Xinrongji for afternoon tea, and constantly opening credit cards...Xueba Mao Dai With one bracelet, everyone will go to the same store to buy the bracelet. Not only that, everyone&#39;s speaking style is becoming more and more similar.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who is Xueba Mao? In 2015, Mao Mao, a top student who graduated from the sociology department of a certain university, tried to start a business; around 2017, she found &quot;body, mind and soul practice&quot;. In 2021, the price of courses began to increase, and Xuebamao changed its original simple style, and the community was renamed &quot;Xuebamao·Hogwarts Lady Branch&quot;. A student discovered that her course had experienced several rounds of price increases, from 199 yuan to 999 yuan in the first quarter, and the price increased to 9999 yuan in the third and fourth quarters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This true story makes people feel a lot of emotions when reading it: First, the students believe in Xueba Mao’s spiritual practice theory and spend their own money to buy and buy in order to gain spiritual freedom. Xueba Mao Whose money does it cost me to buy flowers? In this real-person game, who is the real financial freedom and spiritual freedom? Secondly, spiritual cultivation is really a good business. As long as the seller makes people believe in his theory and himself, he can make the buyer &quot;use his body and his arms, and his arms and his fingers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, there is supply only when there is demand. The various spiritual schools on the market actually reflect the spiritual crisis, spiritual crisis and value crisis faced by some people in the modern social environment. To put it simply, it is because it is too short to enter modern society, and many people have suffered from many mental discomforts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not to say that traditional societies do not have such crises, but that comparatively speaking, such crises are much less common in traditional societies. This is because traditional societies are basically in a state of scarcity, and people are busy working all day long to provide &quot;three meals a day&quot; for the whole family. In fact, &quot;three meals a day&quot; is just rhetoric here. Only in an era of abundant food can everyone live a healthy life. &quot;Three meals a day&quot; day. In this case, most people are mainly concerned about survival and have no leisure to pay attention to the so-called spiritual life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In modern society, everyone leaves the countryside where they are familiar and in their comfort zone and enters the city full of strangers. On the one hand, the income is much higher than that of their ancestors, and it is not a problem to have enough or even good food. Son, in addition to higher income, there is also more leisure. In fact, people cannot really let themselves be leisurely, so they will inevitably have spiritual thinking and pursuit. But on the other hand, natural blood communities such as families tend to disintegrate. Everyone in the city is atomized and scattered. We come into contact with many people every day at work, but how many people can we have close relationships with? Humans are social animals, which brings a lot of loneliness and insecurity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to get rid of it, some people will look for like-minded people online and offline. People with similar knowledge background or values ​​will come together, as well as common interests and hobbies such as fishing or playing games together. In short, we must &quot;talk with the same voice&quot; &quot;Response, seek each other with the same spirit&quot; to settle their own souls; some people throw themselves into the embrace of spiritual practice and the like. There are all kinds of methods, all of which are used by people to relieve or solve their spiritual atomism, loneliness and insecurity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From Chaoyang District Rinpoche to &quot;Master Wang Lin&quot; to various &quot;body, mind and spiritual teachers&quot;, the routines and profit models of these people are similar: I know that you are facing a spiritual crisis, a spiritual crisis and a crisis of values. , come on, lost lambs, children of lost souls, come to my arms and hand over your body and mind to me. I have the final and definite answer here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the so-called &quot;body-body-spiritual guru&quot; also went through a process of spiritual struggle and internal consumption to enlightenment. &quot;Human, too human&quot;. His personal experience increases the credibility of the narrative and the &quot;truth&quot; he preaches. Credibility. At a certain stage, everyone will be happy, the student will get illusory spiritual freedom, and the mentor will get real financial freedom. But ultimately, you may not be able to live with self-deception and lies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each of us must understand: Only by doing meaningful work and living a meaningful life can we discover the meaning itself, establish our own strong core of values, be simple and strong, and have the courage to explore. , to face and fight, for yourself and your family. All this depends on yourself and your family who truly love you. If you can&#39;t buy it, what you buy will be fakes and narcotics. It should be noted that spiritual weakness is the greatest weakness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[张艺谋——工作最happy，放假才emo]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257908]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[编剧陈宇：把剧本写到张艺谋舒适区以外]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257754]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 28, 2023, director Zhang Yimou’s first criminal police film &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; will be released nationwide . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This film is also the beginning of the cooperation between screenwriters Chen Yu and Zhang Yimou. The script was written by Chen Yu. He originally wanted to film it himself, but after writing it, he found that he could not handle such a complex subject matter, so he approached Zhang Yimou and hoped that he would film it. After reading the script, Zhang Yimou liked it very much and immediately pushed back other projects and concentrated on filming &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;. After filming &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot;, Zhang Yimou collaborated with Chen Yu in &quot;Amores&quot; and &quot;Sniper&quot;. The first one to be released was &quot;Sniper&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of his collaboration with Zhang Yimou in three blockbusters, Chen Yu was able to be seen by the public. In addition to being a screenwriter, Chen Yu is a professor at Peking University School of Arts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lwgrSQHcXlLOKJUyA3RzPbtaSIGCxsudpDfm5aRc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/lwgrSQHcXlLOKJUyA3RzPbtaSIGCxsudpDfm5aRc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252347&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Yu was interviewed by Southern Weekend in Beijing in late September 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Jia/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Yu majored in history as an undergraduate, and applied for a postgraduate degree in the Directing Department of the Beijing Film Academy. He works at 8 o&#39;clock every day When I wake up, I go to the movie studio to make movies and take classes. &quot;Three solid years.&quot; After graduating with a master&#39;s degree, Chen Yu applied for the Central Academy of Drama, where he studied under the famous theater director Cao Qijing and studied for a doctorate in drama principles and drama aesthetics. He is a typical academic school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his graduate studies, Chen Yu, together with several classmates, had some pioneering explorations of films with the CCTV Movie Channel. At that time, the movie channel was exploring the possibility of making some movies that could be shown on TV. This kind of style has already existed in the West. &quot;Film-made for TV&quot; is the so-called &quot;television movie&quot;, but in China , a TV movie has not yet appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, Chen Yu served as a screenwriter and created a fantasy film &quot;8:35&quot;. This film became one of the most popular digital films on CCTV Movie Channel at that time, and also Therefore, it won the Lily Award for Outstanding Film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Yu is also one of the earliest practitioners of Internet film and television. In 2009, he filmed China&#39;s first commercial micro-film, &quot;Always Online: Love·Online&quot;. In this short film created for Japan&#39;s Dentsu Advertising and China&#39;s Lenovo Group, Chen Yu is both a director and a screenwriter. He uses storytelling to incorporate product concepts into it. This short film is considered to be the Chinese online movie with the highest Internet click-through rate in 2008. It also won the international first-line advertising award - the British Crystal Award for Best Online Movie of the Year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, Chen Yu stayed away from the film industry. He plunged into various film and drama theories. In his own words, “In order to create his own methodology, he must &quot;The two things of film and drama are combined together.&quot; He spent about ten years &quot;thinking behind the wall&quot; and finally established a systematic methodology. After that, he felt that he could create. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; is a genre film that combines a police film + a crime film. For a while, Chen Yu was interested in anti-corruption cases. He saw an official performing his duties in the news, with his resume attached; and later saw news of his dismissal. Chen Yu would imagine this person&#39;s life course in his mind: In which period did he have a problem? What kind of problems could have led to such an ending in his fate? &quot;I think the certain qualities of human nature reflected behind them are very thoughtful and interesting.&quot; Thinking about it from this perspective, Chen Yu wrote &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TB5fUcxCl2n1HoSurtzMVrzmIU08T6zkWWt9UaAz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1920&quot; height=&quot;723&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/TB5fUcxCl2n1HoSurtzMVrzmIU08T6zkWWt9UaAz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Yu created the script &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; out of his concern for anti-corruption cases. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;To sum up, &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is about the alienation of people. People in a specific In the environment, in a specific period, in a specific location, he will become alienated over a long period of time. This is a tragedy in the ancient Greek sense, that is, people are watching inevitable collapse, and things are inevitably heading towards destruction.&quot; Chen Yu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Understanding the psychological activities of the audience when watching movies&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; and &quot;Sniper&quot; have obvious characteristics of genre films, but what about &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is also a genre film. It is not a single genre. I have been engaged in the research and creation of genre films. If you want to make a genre film, it doesn’t necessarily have to be one genre. For example, like &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;, I blended two genres. One is the police and gangster genre, which is a messenger of justice such as a police officer or a detective. The truth of a matter, the thematic value behind it is the victory of justice over evil; another type is the crime type, which actually talks about a crime or how a crime occurs. &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; I tried to fuse these two genres. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For me, the value of understanding and researching genre films is to be able to accurately understand the audience’s psychological process when watching a movie, including whether they can Get enough emotional and psychological satisfaction. So once we adopt genre film theory as the cornerstone and method of creation, we actually default to several things: first, the most important value and meaning is obtained from the perspective of the story; second, you identify with the audience. collusion&quot;. For example, when we make a horror film, we agree on some premises in advance - my film is a horror film, and it may not be so reasonable from the perspective of life principles, but do you agree with the assumptions I gave you? If you accept this hypothesis, I will definitely give you the psychological satisfaction that horror movies get. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/NZzdfPeAs03CqiLMUy9wuUvvM8uAmyDyYDkKrgTe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/NZzdfPeAs03CqiLMUy9wuUvvM8uAmyDyYDkKrgTe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252349&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Screenwriter Chen Yu believes that the movie &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; is a fusion of the two movie genres: police and crime. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are there many practical limitations in making crime films? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;He (the villain) must have a positive force to collide with him. It is not realistic to just write about how to commit crimes, because any Crime movies must be in a place where there is law and order, and he must be aware of his crime. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If it takes place in a place without order or in a place with semi-order, it is another type of film. For example, in a place with semi-order, it is a western. Westerns are set in a place where there is a little bit of order. For example, the Americans built railroads to the west, and then there was a small town with a police chief. The police chief was not strong enough and was often crushed by evil forces and criminal forces. Pressure, the conflicts and stories that arise in this semi-rule of law place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For creators, another problem they will face is , dealing with the ups and downs of the plot and taking care of the characters, which one comes first for you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I will change this question into structure and characters that are important to me. I feel like the plot is actually a way the structure unfolds. Of course, as an audience, what we see on the first level is the plot, but in fact the structure behind the plot is determined, so the structure and characters are very important starting points in our creation. Aristotle made a distinction: Which is more important, structure or characters? Aristotle himself thought that he would start from structure. I am a follower of Aristotle, and I feel that what he said is something I agree with, that is, I will start more from the structure, but in the end I will reach the same destination as the characters. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You often mention &quot;hard-core narratives&quot;, For example, you said that Korean movies are a combination of three major elements - mature genres, directors&#39; strong styles and social issues. Are these three elements present in &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I’m working hard. &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is a standard genre format. It has its own characteristics in terms of storytelling, imagery, and narrative, and even has a certain authorial quality. Authorship actually does not conflict with genre. For example, Christopher Nolan is a very good Hollywood director. He also makes blockbusters and genre films, but he still has a strong authorial style. This is true not only in movies with a strong sense of form like &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; and &quot;Dunkirk&quot;, but also in standard Hollywood blockbusters like &quot;Interstellar&quot;. You will feel that it is completely different from Marvel&#39;s blockbusters. It has a clear storytelling method and character treatment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have talked about Chinese academic directors. This is not a manufactured concept, it is a real phenomenon. In your opinion, which academic directors are worthy of attention right now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I will talk about some definitions of academic directors in my paper, but in fact we can broaden this concept a little bit, not necessarily He has to work in a university, because there are actually not that many people in this group, such as excellent directors like Director Cao Baoping and Director Xie Fei. To put it more broadly, an academic director is one who has strong self-awareness in film theory. The most prominent sign is that when he makes a film, he will place it in the history of film, the genre of film, and the status of film. There is a clear position in style, and he has a huge tree diagram in his mind. From the perspective of history, country, style, and form, he has the entire map. With this kind of consciousness in his mind, I think he can be Being called an academic director can also be equated with a scholar-type director to some extent. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He corresponds to another concept, that is, the studio director. A studio-type director means I don’t have to worry about that. I grew up on the studio. Many people have never even attended a professional film school. They just followed the master step by step. This was the case in the previous film industry, including films like Hitch. Directors like Kirk also used to draw background panels and do art work in studios, including Yasujiro Ozu. I think these two groups of people have different creative methods, working methods and even concepts, and both are likely to produce excellent authors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Which directors do you prefer and admire? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was in film school, I was most fascinated by Martin Scorsese. At that time, I was obsessed with audio-visual language and film forms. The forms of Martin Scorsese&#39;s early works were extremely wild and unconstrained, and they had their own style and characteristics, so my graduation thesis at that time was about Martin Scorsese&#39;s films. Research; For a long time after that, I was more fascinated by Hitchcock, who was a super master of telling stories; in recent years, I admired Orson Welles, whose &quot;Citizen Kane&quot; In the 1940s, narrative, profundity of thought, understanding of human social life, including politics, private life, and so many other things were perfectly put into one movie. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;My job is to say things outside your comfort zone&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; is the beginning of your collaboration with director Zhang Yimou. How big of a span is there between the end of &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; and &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Soon. The order was to do &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; first. At that time, director Yimou and I met and we worked together. Later, the director said that Chen Yu was good, so we continued to work on it, and proposed the motion &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot;. After the synopsis of &quot;River Red&quot; was written, &quot;Sniper&quot; was temporarily inserted. We finished &quot;Sniper&quot; first, shot it and released it, and then went back to expand the synopsis of &quot;River Red&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Generally speaking, during the cooperation, everyone may be familiar with each other and agree with each other&#39;s abilities and characteristics, so he said every day, &quot;We have a good script, and you have to hurry up. You have to work hard.&quot; In fact, I have been trying to keep up with him, but now I am not the only one who can&#39;t keep up, his pace is too fast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/oBeBMIn0wqFzyvd86WW2NgF8d4FE249Z4GtHmKpG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/oBeBMIn0wqFzyvd86WW2NgF8d4FE249Z4GtHmKpG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252348&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The movie &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; is the first police crime film directed by Zhang Yimou. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;With director Zhang Yimou’s pace, no one in the Chinese film industry can surpass him? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, he is the hardest-working person I have ever seen, not just in the film industry. The key is, it&#39;s not that he uses a strong will to force himself to work hard, but that he likes this thing. Doing this thing is happy, comfortable, resting and working for him. Sometimes I say we should go on vacation somewhere, let’s visit the country and abroad, and he says, “I won’t be happy there, it’s not a vacation for me.” It&#39;s basically impossible to leave him idle for more than a few days, so his (overall) tempo will be fast. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You and director Zhang Yimou’s narrative aesthetics or your impression of the film There must be differences in understanding. Will there be any disputes over this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, regarding my cooperation with him, I have a learner’s mentality. We learned movies by watching his movies, and we truly recognized his previous achievements from the bottom of our hearts, so in this state, I stole from him. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, we have different opinions on how to handle some scenes. At this time, he also mentioned it and I also mentioned it, and everyone pulled the bellows back and forth, but generally in the end The time is almost up. I will write a whole article about why I am like this on this issue, listing several possibilities, the advantages and problems, and give them to the director together, and the director will make the final decision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I told him that my job is to give you the possibility to say more, to say things outside your comfort zone. He has a very large comfort zone, much larger than that of ordinary people, and he can do all kinds of things very smoothly. But what is my responsibility? I said I have to give you something different. Maybe what I mentioned is not necessarily the best choice in my opinion, or maybe your own decision is the best choice, but I have to list this possibility. , in the end you make the choice, this is the director’s responsibility. I also believe that he will make the most appropriate choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the actors are selected for a movie, you will focus on the actors. Any changes to the script? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, we can basically do this work for such mainstream movies or large industrial-level movies. , including &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; too. Director Zhang Yimou said, &quot;Before you act, you will follow the play, and when you are acting, the play will follow you.&quot; I think he said it very well. I used to be a director myself and made some small films. I tried my best to imagine the actor&#39;s state in my mind very accurately. Even after counting for three seconds and asking him to say this sentence, the actor would be at a loss. Now that I think about it, I have a problem. Performance is an organism, and you cannot turn a person into a robot. He should have his own thoughts, his own coherence, and his own rhythm and beat. At this point, I was impressed by the director Yimou. I learned a lot from him. He has many tricks on how to present a scene. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will you change the lines on the spot? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If the script is still undergoing major changes by the time filming starts, it will not start filming, so basically it will be finalized when filming starts. More adjustments are the state of some performances, or the rhythm, or the changes in the tone of speaking. Sometimes there will be some small adjustments to the lines, but generally they won’t change much. This is also a kind of scientific nature of director Yimou’s work. We are similar in that we don’t believe in on-site or temporary inspiration. He even Intentionally reject such inspiration. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the filming started in a week, and I suddenly had a very good idea about this scene. I said that this scene would make a big difference. As a creator, Everyone would be very excited, but Director Yimou was very calm and said that your idea is a good idea. If you proposed it three months ago, you would start adjusting it immediately. But now that the filming starts in a week, there is not enough time for digestion. I&#39;d rather keep this thing now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a lesson I learned that had a great impact on me. I think this comes from a long experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After &quot;Amores&quot;, &quot;Sniper&quot; and &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot;, Will there be a next installment in the &quot;Chen Zhang Series&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We are working on it, planning and writing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This combination will become the only option for your creation ? Is there any movie of Chen Yu’s own? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think there will be. Of course, I particularly hope and am willing to continue my cooperation with Yimou, and I will try my best to follow in his footsteps. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“You don’t need to write a script”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Many movies in the past were adapted on the shoulders of literature, but now, the movies you make yourself, including the movies you collaborated with director Zhang Yimou, are all original scripts. Is this habit formed naturally? , or is it an option? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In fact, I think the creation of movies, specifically the creation of texts, has nothing to do with literature. I prefer movies and Literature is two things. We can draw nutrition from literature, but this nutrition may not be unique to literature, such as understanding of society, understanding of people, understanding of human emotions, and understanding of multiple models of character relationships. These things In fact, it can also come from life. It’s just that literature is doing this effectively and has been doing it for a long time, and it is most convenient for us to obtain these things from it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I think the form of literature itself and the text of a film are two completely different things. Even today when I recruit graduate students, students often say that I have been a literature lover since I was a child. The writing is very good. In my case, when I say that your writing is good, it is not an advantage of writing a script, but it is even a disadvantage of writing a script. Because your writing is good, you will use it to cover up the deficiencies in characters, plots and actions. It seems that you have written in a flashy way. Those things are of no use to our movie. I have to pick them up and take a look. What is the dry stuff? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I say that writing a script does not require writing or rhetoric. My own script has no adjectives. It is all about people, actions, and lines. A 30-year-old person, what kind of clothes he is wearing, comes over and sits down. Say...that&#39;s it, without any literary description. If a student comes to me, for example, a man is sitting there eating noodles, showing a melancholy mood. Then I say that melancholic emotions should be deleted. What does depression feel like? You have to show me what he did. Words like melancholy are all literary thoughts, and what I want is visible and concrete expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;We know that there are many models in the film industry that are very mature. Will it be replaced by ChatGPT and artificial intelligence one day? Is there anything in this that artificial intelligence cannot replace? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This question is also a question that everyone is thinking about recently. Will artificial intelligence replace some of the film industry after it comes out? My feeling is that it will, but the way it replaces is to replace it back from the terminal. In other words, things that are more technical and procedural, such as computer special effects and face-changing. Nowadays, AI is used to change faces, and calculations of computer special effects are gradually being mastered. I even think that in the next 5 to 10 years there may be some (smart) photography, where I say a few words and keywords, and the image is basically generated for you first, and then you can Make adjustments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I think going back to the earliest stage, the planning and production of the story, it is still very difficult to replace it. From a philosophical sense, the most basic things are difficult to produce by ChatGPT. It is impossible to create. It is just a patchwork and combination of existing information. As a creator, the greatest value of what you have to do is to bring this universe Take out something that has not been there before, and it has a specific meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once criticized Hollywood&#39;s high-concept movies, which are to create audio-visual spectacles of those movies. The Chinese market has indeed experienced a great change in recent years. Chinese audiences used to be very fond of this style, but now things have changed. Movies with classic narratives or themes that are more closely integrated with local elements have defeated the Hollywood model. Is this &quot;defeat&quot; due to a change in audience tastes, or is it that Chinese creators have really come up with something better? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Essentially, I think high-concept movies are generated by the thinking of the modern advertising industry. They use a specific element of the movie as a production Justification for a movie. For example, the earliest reason for making a movie is that the story is good, I enjoy watching the story, or the character is interesting. These are relatively classical psychological needs. But after high-concept movies, probably around the 1980s, the concept of blockbusters appeared, which was different. It was advertising thinking. For example, I made this movie not to tell a story, but to show clothes. I showed the clothes from a fashion perspective. This element is higher than the story and the characters. After watching my movie, you may I was not satisfied with the story, but I saw fashion and fashion in it. Gradually, high-concept movies have become. I have many reasons to make a movie, such as special effects and audio-visual shock. Even if the story and characters are a mess, it doesn&#39;t matter, as long as the special effects are good. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Advertising thinking is my own summary of the essence of these high-concept movies. Is this wrong? Yes, but what I am more disgusted with is that it is only this, or it is not enterprising, the originality is getting lower and lower, and it is constantly repeated. For example, I don’t particularly appreciate Marvel movies, including a large number of sequel movies. They essentially pursue extreme safety, cannot take any risks, and stifle originality. The current mainstream Hollywood movies make me very worried and disappointed. This is not to say that in our Chinese market today, our domestic films have far surpassed them. In fact, on the one hand, domestic films are improving, and on the other hand, it is their own fault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High-concept movies were popular for a long time from the 1980s to the 21st century, but now they are slowly changing. The Chinese film market, including the international film market, has gradually returned to a recognition of the value of narrative. This It&#39;s a change that I&#39;m very happy to see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[月亮山：风车、云海与斑斓霞光 | 眼睛在旅游③]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257599]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-01 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在新疆与银河“合影”丨指尖华夏②]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257581]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Hami City, Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region, the stars in the sky are like diamonds embedded in the sky, emitting bright light and beautiful. . There is an endless stream of tourists, looking up at the sky under the bright starry sky and &quot;taking photos&quot; with the Milky Way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/YcLi6BQ8Ypk7wKXKxktOXo04HZu33y7I2RWP3yZb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;655&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/YcLi6BQ8Ypk7wKXKxktOXo04HZu33y7I2RWP3yZb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252005&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The &quot;Galaxy Arch Bridge&quot; photographed at the Barkol Mountain in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Tan Chufan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/ZcPekkA774vhEtQ2eBOEMtsFeExIcUT5KoiyrQhy.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/ZcPekkA774vhEtQ2eBOEMtsFeExIcUT5KoiyrQhy.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252004&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Symphony Lake under the starry sky in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Dai Jianfeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/srgi0VASORkuAtMUbUGFHqUarPuLvqpqRiVijsOm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/srgi0VASORkuAtMUbUGFHqUarPuLvqpqRiVijsOm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252003&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang, a meteor streaked across the night sky . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Tan Chufan/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/pyathfqzuFA77EIIQkryq4pZ5odDknFdHEVdO8o0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/pyathfqzuFA77EIIQkryq4pZ5odDknFdHEVdO8o0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252002&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Strange rock mountain under the starry sky photographed in Barkol, Hami, Xinjiang . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Zhou Bo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/26dYJCr7iDD9mZqvY3mpi0kO8zX677bhCdGTwdWt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/26dYJCr7iDD9mZqvY3mpi0kO8zX677bhCdGTwdWt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252001&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Milky Way and Yadan taken at the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang landforms. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Wang Junfeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/eK5AanAgbbhFmSXMKswI2vQNFPz1qhcSAu56H7lB.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;733&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/eK5AanAgbbhFmSXMKswI2vQNFPz1qhcSAu56H7lB.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Milky Way taken at the Barkol Mountain in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Wang Kai/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/BqYwYhY910Je1ExFlUEqVXdjnDOBnawcpgdZ0tq4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/BqYwYhY910Je1ExFlUEqVXdjnDOBnawcpgdZ0tq4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251999&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take photos with the Milky Way at the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Dai Jianfeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/cN5zpB0eMamORlO38JnZ7Hx79n30VNkLTN3pOOfg.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;734&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/cN5zpB0eMamORlO38JnZ7Hx79n30VNkLTN3pOOfg.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251998&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take photos with the Milky Way in Yiwu Populus Forest in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Liu Bing/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/pOJfDMkc7TMFxFRmz7ZRIeVnkmRYVcYoDphi1iZf.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/pOJfDMkc7TMFxFRmz7ZRIeVnkmRYVcYoDphi1iZf.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251997&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take photos with the Milky Way at the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Dai Jianfeng/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/qJ3OKnSZUr80eRS41jHm78cvIU6cxZMSb9m3av8b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1144&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/qJ3OKnSZUr80eRS41jHm78cvIU6cxZMSb9m3av8b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251996&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists take photos with the Milky Way at the Hami Sea Channel in Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Qiu Bi/Photo）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/wySoblf04gubuKiBZpjKnyMikvUdf4l3rFgvv5fD.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1155&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/wySoblf04gubuKiBZpjKnyMikvUdf4l3rFgvv5fD.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251995&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Milky Way taken at the Barkol Mountain in Hami, Xinjiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Xie Lichun/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访导演李少红：“我就没想到过我自己，想自己是坏事吗？” | 影视大咖谈②]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257477]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/ 09/15/v8rznz8BoxLnZYL7kFtj5ttZSVzQyLPezQQ4CqXF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/15/v8rznz8BoxLnZYL7kFtj5ttZSVzQyLP ezQQ4CqXF. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;208821&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The situation of women is a theme that runs through almost all the film and television works of director Li Shaohong. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A mother-in-law who devotes herself wholeheartedly to her son and grandson and lives without self, a mother-in-law who works hard in life The daughter-in-law looking for herself in the cracks of the epidemic in 2020, the sudden epidemic, these &quot;natural enemies&quot; who were hit by the epidemic were isolated at home, and they had a rare closed space that only belonged to two people...&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;This is director Li Shaohong&#39;s presentation in the movie &quot;Her in the World&quot; to be released in September 2022. The original intention of the film was to tell the story of the impact of the epidemic on women at home. Li Shaohong recalled that in May 2020, the producer came to see her. At that time, everyone was still in the first wave of the epidemic, wearing masks, and did not know each other. It was difficult to find a coffee shop, but they did not dare to sit in it. We were talking in the corridor outside with the cold wind blowing - it was still cold in spring in Beijing at that time. The other two directors of the film are Chen Chong and Sylvia Chang. Li Shaohong said: &quot;Our combination has a bit of a Detachment of Women feeling. Me, Chen Chong, and Sylvia Chang, we are all women, and the producer is also a woman.&quot; In the end, the film uses three stories. , showing how ordinary people find love and hope in difficult situations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before &quot;Her in the World&quot;, in 2021, in the female monologue variety show &quot;Hear Her Say&quot;, &quot;Yun Zhongzhuan&quot; directed by Li Shaohong tells the story of a baby girl from a family of craftsmen who was forced to change her gender. , living as a boy. Because he was raised as a boy, he developed gender cognitive impairment and missed his love. She sacrificed herself and became a major contributor to the revival of her family&#39;s &quot;Guangcai culture&quot; (Guangzhou woven gold-colored porcelain, now a national intangible cultural heritage). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shaohong recalled that the prominence of the female perspective in his works went through a process from self-repression, unconsciousness to consciousness. The first film of her directorial career, &quot;Silver Snake Murder&quot;, is a genre film with strong personality and strong style. &quot;At that time, I felt from a certain perspective that I can do what men can do. This What the genre requires is my standard.&quot; She told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The emergence of her true female consciousness began with the filming of &quot;Bloody Morning&quot; in 1990. The inspiration for the story is taken from Marquez&#39;s novel &quot;A Premeditated Murder&quot;, but in fact, Marquez&#39;s story only provided an excuse for Li Shaohong. Human issues such as marriage and women&#39;s lack of self-awareness are what she really wants to show. In 1995, when he filmed &quot;Red Pink&quot; (adapted from Su Tong&#39;s novel of the same name), Li Shaohong used the perspective of two women with fireworks in the old era to tell the story of how they chose their own destiny and life path under the torrent of the times. The film was shortlisted for the main competition unit of the 45th Berlin Film Festival and eventually won the Silver Bear Award for &quot;Outstanding Achievement&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2000 &quot;Da Ming Gong Ci&quot;, to some extent, is the culmination of Li Shaohong&#39;s female perspective. This TV series has a score of 9.1 on Douban so far. Li Shaohong attributed this to &quot;considering the existence of historical figures from a female perspective&quot;, which also makes &quot;Ci of the Ming Dynasty&quot; different from previous historical dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After experiencing the reputation controversy of the TV series &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot; (2010 version), for nearly ten years, Li Shaohong, as a director, rarely appeared in the film and television industry. During this period, she served as the president of the Chinese Directors Association and launched the &quot;Green Green Project&quot; to shift the focus of her work to supporting new talents. Thanks to the &quot;Green Green Project&quot;, the works of a group of new directors, especially female directors, have surfaced. Director Bai Xue&#39;s debut film &quot;Spring&quot; is one of the representatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Rediscover the existence of the other party&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《世世&quot;With Her&quot; sets the timeline in the special year of 2020, showing the story of a mother-in-law and a daughter-in-law who fell ill during the epidemic. How could you think of setting such a time and such a female relationship? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was during that time that everyone returned to their families. Usually we seem to be trapped by external affairs, all the goals we strive for, and the pressure of various jobs in society, and we neglect our family. When you encounter such a difficult period, you suddenly face your life, your relatives, and your role in the family. You will feel how important they are, and the feeling of dependence on each other is particularly strong. I naturally thought that from a female perspective, the mother-in-law and daughter-in-law in the family are very representative. It is precisely because they themselves are ill that they can reflect a woman&#39;s sense of self-existence and the importance of her sense of family existence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Most of the relationships between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law in previous film and television dramas were Full of contradictions and hostility, the relationship between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law you showed in the film was not harmonious at the beginning. By the end, we saw a warm flow and understanding between women. How did this change occur? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Generally speaking, people think that in traditional and modern families, the two women are incompatible with each other. Many movies and TV shows The conflict between them is also expressed and reflected in the work. In fact, I think these two female characters have a lot of functional overlap: they are facing similar objects, son/husband, grandson/son, their ultimate goal is the same, they are all expressing an expression of love. , but if the expression is different and the focus of consideration is different, conflicts will arise. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I will give you an example of giving hairtail in the film, which is very typical. There are two families. The daughter-in-law played by Zhou Xun grew up eating fish without scaly eating, but in her husband&#39;s family, the mother-in-law grew up scaly, and there was a conflict between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law because of scaly eating. So while delivering hairtails, she called her husband to complain. Her husband didn&#39;t understand her complaints, so she was very angry and felt that she had nowhere to put her emotions. In fact, it is not about the hairtail, but the lack of sincere understanding between each other that causes conflicts between husband and wife and between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Xun repeatedly told her &quot;husband&quot;, &quot;You don&#39;t understand things between women.&quot; Later, she stood on the overpass in a daze, not knowing what to do. She wanted to be quiet and digest it by herself, and finally return to her family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have this kind of experience myself, especially when I don’t know what to do. But after you came back, you found that no one in the house, from the adults to the children to my husband, noticed that I had gone out. The few hours I left had no impact on the family, so I was very upset, but you can only digest it yourself. In the end, I couldn&#39;t help but say, &quot;Didn&#39;t you realize I wasn&#39;t here just now?&quot; It was very embarrassing. My husband said: &quot;Really, where have you been?&quot; With such a simple sentence, you feel that the value of this existence is not realized by others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of life experience may be experienced by every woman in life, but this time it is just seen on the screen. In fact, her husband was not aware of it, and no one was aware of her psychological changes. Later, when she returned home, her mother called, and she still used the state of saying that nothing had happened, like a little girl, to comfort her parents, &quot;Nothing happened, everything is fine.&quot; This touched her mother-in-law, and she realized how neglected they were towards each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“This is the feeling I want to express”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;As you said, there is a very important keyword in &quot;Her in the World&quot;, which is women&#39;s self-discovery, or self-understanding. This background runs through most of your works. In 1988, it was not obvious in your first film &quot;Silver Snake Murder&quot;. It was a very &quot;hard-core&quot; drama. Some even commented that it was more vigorous and spicy than the works of male directors. Many People speculate that among the male-dominated group of directors, did you deliberately hide your female identity? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, although it was already an era when women held up half the sky and advocated equality between men and women, it would allow you to put your The standard is to consider issues from a public perspective that downplays one’s own gender. In addition, &quot;Silver Snake Murder&quot; is a genre film. Genre films have no gender expression, so it must still have a genre perspective. At that time, I felt from a certain perspective that I could do anything a man could do, and the requirements of this genre were my standards. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This transformation from unconsciousness to consciousness is How did it happen? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I experienced a big, conscious change in my self-awareness when I was filming &quot;Pink&quot;. When we first adapted Su Tong&#39;s novel, we went through a collective creative process. The screenwriter was Mr. Ni Zhen, and basically all of our main creators were men. The creative perspective initially focused on society’s transformation of these two prostitutes. In the process, I felt that it seemed to be getting further and further away from my earliest interest in this novel. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was about to shoot, I looked back and thought about what was the first impact Su Tong’s novel had on me. The most original impact was not how to transform them, but how they accepted the times. changes and transformations, and then how they choose their own destiny and the path of their own lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the filming, I did a bold job, focusing all perspectives back on these two girls - how they were taken away by the boat one morning, how they How do they view the men they like, why Qiuyi chose to be a nun, how Xiaoe chose to live with this man, and how are their lives going? After the whole perspective was reversed, I suddenly felt that this was the feeling I wanted to express. All the experiences and feelings of the two women at that era have become the biggest feature of this film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the film was finished, it won the Silver Bear Award for Outstanding Achievement at the Berlin Film Festival. Then, in 1995, the World Congress on Women was held in China. After I participated in this conference as a representative, many The confusing question suddenly found the answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For example? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I realize that if your standard is set on a male standard, and you especially want to follow a public consciousness, When you think about problems, you don’t think about them with individual consciousness. What you think about is a collective sense of existence, not an individual sense of existence. All these questions seem to be gradually guiding you, asking you to measure yourself according to other people&#39;s ideas and social requirements, as if your own existence is not aware of and valued, and you should restrain yourself. I was really surprised. I was sweating. I thought, God, how did I think about problems in the first half of my life? I never thought about myself. Is it a bad thing to think about myself? It doesn&#39;t seem wrong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, I realized that when I was filming &quot;Pink&quot;, I had secretly thought about problems for women themselves, as if this was not wrong, and this inspiration and enlightenment was really right. I am too important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/15/fWOCPsR6IrUDsMVmhAdDVpIcNw3WzOqQRF6VmnUS.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1453&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/22/09/15/fWOCPsR6IrUDsMVmhAdDVpIcNw3WzOqQRF6VmnUS.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;208820&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhou Xun and Li Shaohong have collaborated many times. The picture shows Princess Taiping (right) played by Zhou Xun in &quot;Ci of the Ming Dynasty&quot; (2000) to avoid marriage with Turks. A scene of a shadow puppet show performed by a Taoist nun in the temple. Princess Taiping has only a few entries in history books, but in Li Shaohong&#39;s works she becomes the protagonist who observes history. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Considering the existence of historical figures from a female perspective&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Da Ming Gong Ci&quot; can be said to be a masterpiece of expression from your female perspective, because before it, all historical dramas were dominated by men. The protagonist. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, because most historical dramas are from a historical perspective, and history is written by men, so naturally you use Tell stories from this perspective. After I gained this awareness, I consciously spoke from a female perspective, so you can see that I am talking about Wu Zetian and her daughter Princess Taiping. How did these two women control their own destiny in that era? . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Daming Palace Ci&quot; actually starts from Wu Zetian as a mother. The first child she gave birth to was a girl, who was strangled to death. Later, when she was 38 years old, she became pregnant with Princess Taiping, and she insisted on giving birth to her. All her subsequent actions towards Taiping were all caused by her compensation for herself and the child she had strangled to death. Princess Taiping is described in only a few sentences in &quot;Zi Zhi Tong Jian&quot;, which can be summarized as &quot;arrogance, extravagance and lewdness&quot;. But I think her reason is caused by the doting given to her by her mother. It is the original sin caused by self-salvation and mother&#39;s guilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From all these angles, I think they consider the existence of historical figures from a female perspective, which also makes &quot;Ci of the Ming Dynasty&quot; different from previous historical dramas, which were rated as &quot;alternative&quot; at the time. . This shows that a historical figure has never been told from a female perspective. Maybe everyone did not recognize the existence of this drama at the time. This sentence saved me at the time, because when this show was first released, not everyone applauded it. Everyone is particularly questioning: Is this a historical drama? But its strong emotion and style make everyone find it refreshing, and they don’t know how to evaluate it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From your perspective, how do you interpret Wu Zetian? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We don’t care whether Wu Zetian was an emperor in the end. At the beginning, she did not have this dream. Ordinary women living a good life. At that time, they were sent to the city to participate in the draft. This path was what girls of that era aspired to. From this perspective, her experience is the struggle history of an ordinary woman. She wanted to find a more ideal emotion in it, and then she found it. She cherished it, otherwise she would have almost been buried with her. In fact, she had been assigned to a nunnery, where she almost had to spend her life in a life worse than death. She tried every means to let others discover her existence. I think as a woman, this instinct of begging for survival is not an exaggeration at all. After she gets the possibility of survival, does she have to hold on tightly? She must try her best to manage it well, otherwise, she is likely to return to a situation where life is worse than death. All of this, I think about from the perspective of this woman’s survival and struggle. She really uses all her wisdom and ability to manage her family and husband-wife relationship. This is not wrong at all, and it is not simply He judged her as a poisonous woman. When survival pushed her to a desperate situation, she was forced to do it. And when her position was truly stabilized, the first person she wanted to repay was her child who died young. This child has always existed in her life, so she put all her guilt on the 38-year-old Princess Taiping. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wu Zetian lamented about her male favorite, &quot;A As long as you put a man into a woman&#39;s situation, he will become a woman.&quot; This is also a line that has not been seen in previous historical films. Looking at the issue from a female perspective, where did this line come from? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Just think in other people’s shoes, Wu Zetian also needs to think in other people’s shoes - why do you say I am a poisonous woman, why do you say I am ruthless, you change Thinking about it, do you think I can stop doing this? In order to protect my husband, protect his power, protect my children, and protect my family, I can do anything. So in her later years, she was so miserable that she couldn&#39;t even sit down and have dinner with four generations like an ordinary woman, and even her own son didn&#39;t dare to come. She felt that she had given so much and received so little. Her emotion was a great irony. I think this is history, allowing us to see a lot of ourselves from them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“They are all very confident now”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;The female characters in the film have difficulties, and the actors themselves are no exception. Hai Qing and Yao Chen have previously expressed the &quot;workplace&quot; anxieties and dilemmas of middle-aged actresses, and Zhou Xun has also begun to play mothers. What do you think of these difficulties they face? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In fact, this kind of anxiety occurs at every stage of life, whether it is about work, family, or emotions. I think it’s not just married people like us, or people who are mothers, or people like Zhou Xun. For her age group, her experiences of marriage, family, and parents at different times must have existed. The accumulation of these experiences must have played a very sincere role in her portraying the roles of mother and wife. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think Zhou Xun is becoming more and more mature as she gets older. When we were filming &quot;Orange Is Red&quot;, it was difficult for her to find that kind of feeling when we were filming the fertility scene. It was hard to imagine, so we went through a process at that time and let her go into exile for a few days to slowly find this kind of feeling. Feel. Later, she lamented that the most important thing in performing is to express what you feel. You must first feel it before you can truly understand it and perform it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, I also filmed her playing the role of a mother. In &quot;Life and Death&quot;, I felt that she had grasped the character&#39;s pregnancy and childbirth very accurately. Now that she is filming &quot;Her&quot;, the role of mother is no longer difficult for her, so I think she has gone beyond whether she has done it when dealing with family relationships and the relationship between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law in the film. A simple question like mother, but an insight into two women of different eras and ages. She asked her mother-in-law: &quot;Who are you living for?&quot; In fact, when she asked her mother-in-law, she also asked herself. When a woman is in her own stage, she will reflect and discover the value of her own existence from others, which transforms into self-salvation and self-awareness. I think she has grasped this point very accurately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have always been a pioneer in female expression, but in the past few years, you have been a pioneer in female expression. Your expressions have become less. Is it because your desire to express yourself has decreased, or is there some other reason? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Shaohong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Overall, I feel that there is no decrease. I usually film one movie or one drama every two to three years. At the same time, We will also supervise and produce some of our own plays. But social work may be seen more by everyone, just because you want to support young directors. I have done the &quot;Green Green Project&quot; to support young directors, and I have also taken on some social work, such as the work of the Directors Association. It turns out that as a director, it is indeed an extra job. But gradually I still feel that supporting newcomers is very important for your own creation and movies. I am not doing the specific operations, I am just standing up for them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Green Onion Project&quot; will be its seventh edition in 2022. I have discovered many young female directors in it, and there are more and more of them. I think female directors are quite capable, and I really hope to be able to help them in this regard. And unlike us at that time, they still have a process of self-awareness and awakening. I think they are very confident now and know very well that they need to use a female perspective and the movies in their hands to express themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[29年后再夺冠，中国男网迎来最好时代]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257986]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/30/gfVFC4pa1mdxB4VV18sTxoCbTzVKqxsB8RxeqNjJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/gfVFC4pa1mdxB4VV18sTxoCb TzVKqxsB8RxeqNjJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252887&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Tennis Center in Hangzhou, Zhejiang In the Asian Games tennis men&#39;s singles final, Chinese player Zhang Zhizhen defeated Japanese player Yosuke Watanuki 2-0 and won the championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;After 29 years, a Chinese player once again won the Asian Games men&#39;s singles tennis gold medal. The champion was 26-year-old Zhang Zhizhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Asian Games championship, he has the highest ATP singles ranking of 52nd in the world. He has reached the top 8 of the Madrid Masters and the top 32 of the French Open and the US Open. These are all mainland Chinese men. The best result of the net. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last person to win the Asian Games men&#39;s singles tennis gold medal was Pan Bing. He won the 1990 Beijing Asian Games and won the title again at the Hiroshima Asian Games four years later. After 1990, China&#39;s women&#39;s tennis rose and gradually established its dominance in the Asian Games. However, China&#39;s men&#39;s tennis developed slowly. It was not until the last Asian Games, when 19-year-old Wu Yibing unexpectedly reached the finals and finally won the silver medal that the Chinese men&#39;s tennis team returned to the Asian Games finals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Zhizhen and Wu Yibing are both currently in the top 100 in the world in ATP rankings, and are the No. 1 and No. 3 seeds respectively in this Asian Games. After Wu Yibing stopped in the top eight, Zhang Zhizhen became the only one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/MqUATwgWZ1DluNirRdL5ZDvoKXM2pklSecNsA5fj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/MqUATwgWZ1DluNirRdL5ZDvoKXM2pklSecNsA5fj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252886&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Zhang Zhizhen returned the ball during the game&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The situation in the first five games was surprising. Judging from Zhang Zhizhen&#39;s expressions and movements, he was a little emotional and was not focused enough on the ball. The serve was broken in the first game and she made 4 double-serve errors. Zhan Jun and many other commentators believed that perhaps there was too much interference in the stands, and Zhang Zhizhen was unable to quickly enter the game state and played a bit casually. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also true that live broadcasts frequently broadcast: Please keep quiet, thank you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the sixth set of the first game, Zhang Zhizhen entered the state, kept serve, and then chased five consecutive games. Twisted from 1:4 to 6:4. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first set of the second game, Zhang Zhizhen scored 4 consecutive serves, with a 100% first-serve success rate. At the end of the seventh set, after Zhang Zhizhen led 4:3, he called an injury timeout and asked the caregiver to massage his waist. Subsequently, Yosuke Watanuki did not make many moves in the service game and gave up one game. After 4:4, Zhang Zhizhen scored 4 points in a row, held serve, and led 5:4. After that, the two sides guaranteed each other&#39;s serve and dragged the game into a tie-break. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both sides clung to the score in the tiebreaker, dragging it all the way to 7:7. On Zhang Zhizhen&#39;s third match point, Yosuke Watanuki hit the ball out of bounds, and Zhang Zhizhen won the 19th Asian Games men&#39;s singles tennis championship. He threw his wristband and ball to the audience and walked around the court wearing a national flag. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Serving is Zhang Zhizhen’s biggest advantage. He is also considered to have the best physical fitness among all Chinese men’s tennis players in the past. Zhang Zhizhen is 193cm tall and is considered a big man among tennis players. A big man is more likely to be a good serve, which he himself knows. He once said, &quot;The serve should be my biggest weapon, but sometimes my serve is still not on line, and sometimes the success rate of my first serve is suddenly very small. So I still I want to improve my serving skills and reduce first-serve errors, which is very important to me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/30/b00vwFWYnoAXklNCqnIsIh6W1mzAxUlM64O2SoR5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;611&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /30/b00vwFWYnoAXklNCqnIsIh6W1mzAxUlM64O2SoR5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252889&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Zhang Zhizhen (left) and Mian Yosuke Guan shakes hands after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;26-year-old Zhang Zhizhen started playing tennis at the age of 4 and entered Xuhui at the age of 10 District team, and entered the Shanghai team at the age of 12. His father was a professional tennis player and his mother was a shooter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The year Zhang Zhizhen was selected for the Shanghai team, a huge change occurred in the Chinese tennis world: the Network Management Center allowed four athletes including Li Na, Zheng Jie, and Yan Zi to &quot;fly solo&quot;. This move was considered to be the professionalization of my country&#39;s tennis. The &quot;ice-breaking move&quot; on the road has thus formed the current dual-track management model of the Chinese tennis team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After joining the Shanghai team, Zhang Zhizhen was sent to Nice, France for training. He has partnered with Daniil Medvedev to participate in ITF Hope Tournaments around the world, and also won the men&#39;s doubles runner-up in the Hope Tournament. Nine years later, Medvedev won the Australian Open runner-up for the second time and rose to No. 1 in the ATP rankings, becoming the first young man to end the 18-year monopoly of the &quot;Big Four&quot; on the world&#39;s No. 1 ranking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this moment, the China Tennis Open restarts after four years. Medvedev is participating in the China Open in Beijing, and Nishioka Yoshihito, the currently highest-ranked Asian player in the ATP ranking and the 2014 Asian Games champion, also chose the latter between the Asian Games and the China Open. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Zhizhen did not play much in youth competitions, with his highest ranking being 166th. In 2012, Zhang Zhizhen, who was not yet 16 years old, entered professional tennis. For the next four years, his performance stalled. The general manager of Zhang Zhizhen&#39;s Shanghai Pudong Tennis Team analyzed in an interview with the media that he has been stuck in the same place for four years, which is a mistake made by the club management. Firstly, he turned professional too early and did not realize that he, who was still in the developmental stage, would suffer injuries after playing consecutive adult games; secondly, he did not allow family members to accompany him during long-term overseas training. “A child abroad is very lonely. Yes, we failed to communicate in time and failed to accompany him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Zhizhen also believed that he turned professional too early. He turned professional just after winning the Hope Games. &quot;Actually, you can play more youth games to build up confidence, but if you keep losing, it would be a miserable loss.&quot; Zhang Zhizhen said, &quot;Although I play games every week, I lose every week. This feeling is very bad. . Only when you win more games will you feel it and be in good shape.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that it was not until 2015 that he achieved good results in the Asian season: he won his first career tour victory, and then After winning the TOP100 for the first time in his career, he felt that he could really play tennis for a lifetime. &quot;It was only then that I felt I had the ability to compete with them, and then I got there step by step.&quot; But at the end of that year, Zhang Zhizhen suffered a fracture in his left foot and had to undergo surgery after two months of conservative treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Zhizhen is a player who understands setbacks very well. When asked about past losses, he would laugh a few times and then answer candidly. After entering the top 100 of the ATP rankings - he is the first mainland male tennis player to enter the top 100 of the ATP - he has experienced repeated defeats for half a year. He admitted that at that time his mentality was very low, as long as he could win a set. But most of the time, he was a one-rounder. He thought maybe because he played less games, he had less control over the field. He also encountered a similar dilemma when he first turned professional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The state in that half year was very bad, and I don&#39;t know what happened. The state in that half year was completely different from now. The state at that time was very poor, no matter how hard I played, I couldn&#39;t.&quot; Zhang Zhizhen in 2023 Xia Tian recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/2uJidZhmCML30aNGVyGRadlQFyqSOWPELy9h3z9J.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/2uJidZhmCML30aNGVyGRadlQFyqSOWPELy9h3z9J.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252890&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 4, 2023, in the men&#39;s singles quarter-finals of the 2023 Madrid Tennis Open, Chinese player Zhang Zhizhen lost to Russian player Karatsev 0-2. Stopped in the top eight &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 is obviously a good year. Zhang Zhizhen reached the top 8 of the Madrid Masters and the top 32 of the French Open and the US Open. Many people asked him why his mentality was completely different from before. He won many five-set matches. His answer was quite candid and meaningful: “After losing so many games, your heart will actually become calmer. You will feel nervous or something.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He lost to Roode, a top 10 player in the ATP rankings, at the French Open, and eliminated Roode at the US Open four months later. Before the US Open match, he studied Ruud&#39;s hard court and training videos, and also rewatched his game with Ruud. He felt that he had a chance. &quot;Last time, it completely impacted his mentality. He was more panicked. This time, he felt more like there was a chance to compete and he was not so anxious.&quot; He knew that the key to victory was concentration. &quot;The second half of last time I have concerns about physical fitness and power, but not this time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/uViYg8Gq3wWo3PwlN7Ycovs4MDiLDmiWtWQw0yMN .jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;727&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/uViYg8Gq3wWo3PwlN7Ycovs4MDiLDmiWtWQw0yMN.jpg&quot; data-key =&quot;252888&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 30, 2023, Zhang Zhizhen celebrated after winning the championship&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He returned to China with the top 32 results of the US Open and bluntly stated that his goal in the Asian Games is to win gold. This is completely different from the mentality a year ago where I just wanted to win a round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, as long as Zhang Zhizhen regains his form, he will play better and better. Once you start winning, it&#39;s like a tiebreaker. &quot;Win a few games and your form will come back.&quot; Zhang Zhizhen said, &quot;Maybe you&#39;ll be lucky enough to keep winning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is a competitive player. The game is exciting. The night before the Madrid Masters against Fritz (ranked top 10 in the world), he slept only four hours and made up for two more hours during the day. &quot;I&#39;m very excited, and with the jet lag, the adrenaline hormones can&#39;t come down at all.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the Hangzhou Asian Games victory, Zhang Zhizhen has already won a ticket to the 2024 Paris Olympics. He and the entire Chinese men&#39;s network are ushering in the best era. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview before the Asian Games, when asked about the happiest moment in 2023, Zhang Zhizhen replied without thinking: &quot;Deng Ziqi replied to my Weibo!&quot; He said that tennis results can be better in the future, but The singer you like can reply only once. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 4, 2023, Zhang Zhizhen bid farewell to the Madrid Masters with a top 8 result. This is the first time that a Chinese male tennis player has reached the top 8 of the Masters. He posted a Weibo post with Deng Ziqi&#39;s lyrics: &quot;The sky has no limit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Your future is boundless.&quot; Deng Ziqi replied with the next sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[竞业限制是否阻碍劳动力自由流动？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257794]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 20:39:15&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the labor market, from small factories and workshops to large listed companies, they are all faced with the contradiction between cultivating employees and establishing competitors. . This leads to companies either being hesitant to teach the true scriptures or putting forward unreasonable restrictions when cultivating employees to pass on their skills. The reality is often a combination of both. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Non-compete restrictions, which originated from British common law, solve this problem very well: the company signs a contract with employees, and when employees leave, the company has the right to limit their employment options to eliminate competition risks. Such restrictions are conditional, and competition only applies to a certain period of time, specific regions and industries. Most importantly, money needs to be spent to compensate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Non-compete is an agreement outside the labor contract, and the company has to pay the cost, so it is not common at first. The provisions are activated only when technical secrets are a key factor in competition and only to a small number of people. Non-compete restrictions may seem to restrict employees&#39; right to choose employment, but considering that it is a free agreement and employees receive additional money, the law protects the validity of such contracts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Restrictions on non-compete are a common phenomenon in the modern workplace. As the largest common law country, the United States would accept it happily. However, there is a strong &quot;trust phobia&quot; in American society. Such contracts are considered to restrict labor mobility and eliminate corporate competition. Therefore, not only the blue states dominated by the Democratic Party prohibit non-competition contracts, but also the law in Republican states such as Florida. Prefer prohibition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competition contracts are a spontaneous product of the market. Explicitly prohibiting them cannot solve the dilemma of &quot;teaching apprentices and starving masters&quot;, and is actually not conducive to the free movement of workers. In order to eliminate the competitive threat after employees leave, the company will keep an eye on current employees and set up a long deconfidential period. Employees are required to sign a separate confidentiality agreement, which remains in effect even after leaving the company. Large companies have reached a tacit agreement not to &quot;poach&quot; each other. These measures not only increase uncertainty in the workplace, but also hinder the free movement of workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We originally did not have a culture of non-competition. This system was introduced from the West, recognized by law, and widely accepted. Non-competes are cost-bearing for the company, so they are usually only available to company executives or in certain industries. Contrary to the United States, non-competition restrictions in Chinese workplaces have not declined in recent years, but have increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the emerging Internet and electric vehicle industries, there are hundreds of companies whose employees are prohibited from re-employing, including peer companies, upstream and downstream suppliers and sellers. At first, only senior executives or key talents were allowed to compete for jobs, but now it has become a standard requirement for employees to join the company. &quot;No one is not competing for jobs, and competition is everywhere.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, for insignificant personnel movements, non-competition restrictions are just threats, and the company will not really stop them. As for the job-hopping of employees that the company values, they will start based on the situation. Some give money directly, while others wait and see and delay, giving a fatal blow to resigned employees at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This type of topic is often seen on workplace forums: After resigning from the company, the company has not discussed non-competition compensation. Can I still join a competing company? Some people gave a positive opinion. Since there is no non-competition compensation and the agreement is not effective, there should be no non-competition. At this time, people who have experienced it often give bloody advice: Don&#39;t step on the line easily, because the company may launch a surprise attack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 23 of the &quot;Labor Contract Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that &quot;the employer may agree with the employee on non-competition clauses in the labor contract or confidentiality agreement, and agree on the rescission or termination of the labor contract.&quot; Afterwards, workers will be given financial compensation on a monthly basis during the non-competition period.&quot; The so-called &quot;can be agreed upon&quot; is not only due to the autonomy of will, but also lays the foundation for non-competition disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The length of the non-competition restriction, the amount of compensation, and the labor contract law are not stipulated, but are clarified through judicial interpretations-if the contract is unclear, the longest period shall not exceed two years, and the average monthly amount shall not exceed Less than one-third of the original salary. There are no relevant regulations on the amount of employee default, which falls within the category of &quot;agreement&quot;. When employees draft non-compete agreements, they tend to increase the amount of liquidated damages. For positions with a monthly salary of 10,000 to 20,000 yuan, the liquidated damages are often as high as tens or even millions, a figure that is daunting to employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When should the company pay compensation? The judicial interpretation states: If the employer fails to pay non-compete compensation for three months and the employee requests to terminate the non-compete agreement, the people&#39;s court shall support it. It seems that it is only valid for three months, but it is not. The company had not paid for three months, and the non-competition restriction was actually still in effect—the requirement for its invalidity was that the workers petitioned for relief, the court ruled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reality is usually that once the company receives a request (through notification, labor arbitration or lawsuit) and the former employee wants to lift the non-compete restriction, the company responds calmly. If employees do not pose a competitive threat, the company will compensate them with up to 30% of their wages for three months and lift non-competition restrictions. If employees intend to join a competing company or join a competing company, they can directly remit a sum of money to the other party&#39;s account to initiate a block or claim. Judicial practice shows that at this time, the court tends to believe that the company is performing non-competition compensation and the non-competition restriction is activated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Contemporary non-competition restrictions mean that after employees leave their jobs, they cease to work and no longer join their peers, leaving the company with nothing to do. Once an employee believes that the agreement is not in effect, the onboarding constitutes a breach of contract and the company can launch an attack. With a small payment, the agreement is activated and the employee becomes involved in a &quot;competition trap.&quot; Not only is the new job not guaranteed, but a large amount of liquidated damages will also be paid. The company has full control over how it operates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of low-cost, high-return non-competition restriction is obviously beneficial to the company. This is the fundamental reason for the increase in non-competition restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The solution is simple, rebalancing the interests of both parties in the non-competition restriction. There should be an upper limit on the amount of an employee&#39;s breach of contract. The scope of non-competition restrictions should also be made clear - limited to a few competitors, rather than spreading all over the place. The activation of the non-competition agreement and the payment of compensation also need to be clarified. Both the company and its employees must draw clear boundaries in their relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In labor relations, the law needs to eliminate uncertainty and reduce conflicts. The increase in competition in China&#39;s workplace is creating privileges for companies and hindering the free flow of labor. The law should fill in the workplace traps caused by non-competition restrictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[导演王沐和他的“温柔壳”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257431]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/usCUxK3jSw78IL72kOF9sxCcVvD7D28475aHpO19.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/usCUxK3jSw78IL72kOF9sxCcVvD 7D28475aHpO19. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Not to be watched&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On June 11, 2023, during the Shanghai International Film Festival, director Wang Mu arrived at the cafe we ​​agreed on nearly an hour early, and happened to be in There was a queue behind me for coffee. His directorial debut &quot;The Gentle Shell&quot; was released in theaters across the country at the end of May. It was in theaters for 10 days and grossed more than 12 million yuan at the box office. This result is incomparable with the commercial films that became popular in the summer and often grossed billions at the box office, but as a small- to medium-cost literary film, the performance is really good. On August 2, &quot;Gentle Shell&quot; was released on streaming media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Preparations for the film began in 2018. Wang Mu has been to four mental rehabilitation institutions and had in-depth conversations with many friends who have emotional problems. In the final film, social issues became the background, and he focused on the emotions of two people -&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The girl Juexiao could not accept her mother&#39;s departure and kept searching. She suffered a mental breakdown and even committed suicide by cutting her wrists (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Attempt&lt;/span>;); The boy Dai Chun suffers from bipolar disorder. His father is an alcoholic, has left home, and is suffering from dementia in old age. Dai Chun and Jue Xiao, who were at a low point in their lives, met in a mental rehabilitation center. The two people, who had not been listened to or understood before, hugged each other for warmth in a closed environment and built a &quot;gentle shell&quot; to comfort their mental pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mid-June, the film’s promotion work came to an end. &quot;Too many people&#39;s attention makes me feel stressed.&quot; Wang Mu said with a smile. He is not a talkative creator. Regarding questions such as &quot;Has the director&#39;s debut experience accumulated experience for subsequent screenwriting and directing work?&quot; and &quot;Do you usually read books with a theme?&quot;, he answered &quot;yes&quot;, nodded, and then fell into silence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Mu was doing drama more than ten years ago, and his first play was performed in Chaoyang Jiu Theater. Since he couldn&#39;t find an actor, he played the role himself. On the stage, all he felt was darkness, and he couldn&#39;t see the audience. It was raining outside, seeping from the theater ceiling to the stage. In my memory, it looked like a water curtain hole. Wang Mu added an impromptu line, &quot;Look how rainy it is.&quot; The audience immediately responded with applause, and he caught what would have been a stage mishap. In the second game, more spectators and media came to attend, and two more rows of seats were added in front of the first row of seats. As soon as Wang Mu came on stage and saw &quot;so many viewers suddenly attracted&quot;, he realized that he was being watched and never went on stage again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He doesn&#39;t want to be watched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the COVID-19 epidemic has passed, road shows seem to have become very important whenever a movie is released. It has become a routine operation for the main creative staff to go to various cities to participate in post-screening activities of various movie fan viewing groups. Wang Mu and his &quot;Gentle Shell&quot; are no exception. It was okay, he said, at least we were talking about movies. As for the fashion magazine trend of dressing directors in branded clothes and taking photos in absurd man-made landscapes, he still doesn&#39;t feel comfortable with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It took me two years to write and rewrite the script. When he had further ideas for the script, he suddenly felt something in his heart and wrote a 7,000-word letter to Jue Xiao and Dai Chun in his home study, writing about his feelings for them and about himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What is it about,&quot; I asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My colleagues in publicity also asked me if I wanted to post it. I didn’t post it because I felt that it belonged to Dai Chunjuexiao at that time. From the bottom of my heart, I didn’t want people to know what I wrote.”&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In 2023, Wang Mu is 36 years old. A movie of his own is released and the response is good. What next? He wasn&#39;t sure. During the interview, he said several times that he would like to try to make commercial films in the future, so that the core of what he wants to express can reach the public in a more popular way. This is actually very difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago or more, Wang Mu thought about his ambition to be a professional screenwriter and strive to be the best? Is there still a chance to be a director? It seems like neither. When he was in his twenties or thirties, he thought, it would be great if he could be a person like Acheng. &quot;Study aesthetics when you want to study aesthetics, and write things when you want to. You can write scripts for other directors, but you don&#39;t have to think about any remuneration, you don&#39;t have to think about contracts, you don&#39;t have to meet with people every day, and you don&#39;t care much about reviews, or I care too much about the so-called award results, as if that state is particularly good. I live in a very free and willful state.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I can&#39;t do it. No one can do it, and there is no need for such people in this era, he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/MRHCGedYwYR2Mo7k4hGzUzRnJsHBxiWpjTqZGgrX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1707&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/MRHCGedYwYR2Mo7k4hGzUzRnJsHBxiWpjTqZGgrX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the movie &quot;Gentle Shell&quot;, Wang Ziwen and Yin Fang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;h4>;Consensus and Resonance&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Unlike many young directors, Wang Mu is not a cinephile, nor a believer of the New Wave or a certain film master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before taking the theater exam, he had no habit of watching movies. The first movie he actively watched in his life was &quot;The 400 Blows&quot;. He bought a pirated disc and watched it in a small hotel room. Antoine &quot;enshrined Balzac like a shrine&quot;, and this child in France in the 1950s seemed to be a reflection of his inner world. The movie ends abruptly when Antoine leaves home, and Wang Mu is greatly shocked. &quot;I still can&#39;t forget that touching feeling. It&#39;s an unprecedented feeling. It&#39;s very wonderful. It turns out that this is what the movie is like.&quot; After going to college, he watched &quot;The 400 Blows&quot; again at a classmate&#39;s house, only to find that the disc he had bought had an error in the recording. Without the famous long shot of Antoine running in film history, it would be different from the movie that shocked him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I know in my heart that movies are only a part of life, and part of what I want to express will still be put on the stage.&quot; Wang Mu said that his biggest wish is to continue reading dramas in this life. . He has also been writing, sometimes as fragments, sometimes as notes, without sticking to a strict framework. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Mu did well in Chinese in middle school, but he didn’t understand why writing a composition should have a definite central idea. The first scene of &quot;Waiting for Godot&quot; was selected in the Chinese textbook - Wang Mu didn&#39;t know who the two characters were waiting for, and the two characters themselves might not know. Is they waiting for hope, death, or some other end? The ambiguous interpretation space and endless implication struck him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Write even if you read too much. He later revised and re-wrote a play he wrote in high school. It was staged in 2007 and performed twice in Beijing. The core of the play is a bit like &quot;Waiting for Godot&quot;, the protagonist is also waiting for something. That year, Wang Mu was 20 years old. He was fascinated by the chemistry in the theater. The stage was set up before the performance and dismantled after the performance. He sat alone in the audience for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While working in the drama industry until 2010, Wang Mu only rehearsed that one play. He did not go into details about that experience, but he probably mentioned that it was not easy to do theater in Beijing, and that one had to endure poverty and accept the trap culture. &quot;Later on, I slowly got into movies. For work, I wrote scripts for others. When I got tired of writing one movie after another, I decided that I still wanted to make a movie myself, and that&#39;s where I am today.&quot; He concluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, a friend introduced him to a man named Li Xiaofeng. Li Xiaofeng read two novels written by Wang Mu. They were realistic, special in tone, and solemn in rhythm. Their literary skills left an impression on him. After getting acquainted, Li Xiaofeng learned that Wang Mu liked Chekhov the most. He went to Wang Mu&#39;s house and saw a heavy bust of Lu Xun placed on the desk. &quot;He is a very serious creator at heart.&quot; Li Xiaofeng commented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng said he wanted to make a movie, so he handed over the Green Demon&#39;s novel &quot;Girl Nezha&quot; and asked Wang Mu if he thought it could be made. The novel tells the adolescent worries of two girls in Baocheng in the form of letters. In Li Xiaofeng&#39;s memory, almost everyone around him opposed the revision of the novel and found it difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Mu said at the time, yes. Looking back now, Wang Mu said with a smile, &quot;I&#39;m not sure he can do it, but since he wants to shoot, I will at least have an income.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng emphasized that the creator must have a lot of personality and personality. Mutual trust is needed in terms of talent. &quot;Thinking about the world, love for people, and views on people in life&quot; are more important than agreement on specific creations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first draft of the script of &quot;Girl Nezha&quot; was written by Wang Mu, which &quot;brought the best foundation.&quot; Li Xiaofeng commented that there were not many details in the original work that could be used for film shooting, and Wang Mu Mu&#39;s script &quot;draws out all the characters&#39; dynamics of the two girls, very realistically.&quot; After that, another screenwriter Pan Yu joined and wrote another draft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Movies are supposed to be collective creations, but they happen to be not. &quot;This draft of the script was written by Wang Mu, and it is Wang Mu&#39;s characteristics. The next draft will have the characteristics of others. We will not necessarily discuss, quarrel, and finally reach an agreement. What is very important to me is that the movie is not about Twist everyone together and unify them into a certain specific pursuit, but let the light and brightness of these creators shine through their own work, and try to draw on each other&#39;s strengths as much as possible. This is the method I like.&quot; Li Xiaofeng said , they were young at that time, twenty-four or five years old, creative but not immature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last film &quot;Girl Nezha&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2015&lt;/span>;) was nominated for the Best of the 51st Taipei Golden Horse Film Festival Adapted Screenplay Award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You have to believe in the power of free creation. It may not be stable, but it will keep your body and mind healthy.” Li Xiaofeng said. He and Wang Mu also collaborated on &quot;Rebirth from the Ashes&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2017&lt;/span>;), about the impact of a murder case on two men many years later. Lasting impact. When the script reached the seventh draft, Wang Mu joined in, making it more literary. The collaborators have a consensus that they want to use the film to describe the state of the individual after &quot;all solid things have disappeared&quot; in fictional time and space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this industry that relies on seniority and charlatanism, Wang Mu described the congeniality between creators as unquantifiable as possible, &quot;He may feel some kind of sincerity in you. Or he will let you write the parts he needs.&quot; The directors who come into contact with him do not measure the screenwriter&#39;s ability by awards or box office, and they do not require that the script must be written like a script. Some people say that you can write novels. Another director allowed him to write the outline as a diary. &quot;It must be in a comfortable context,&quot; Wang Mu emphasized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Everyone will continue to move forward on his own creative path. We are different creators, but we can have a good consensus or resonance at the intersection of time and space. , I think it is very precious.&quot; Li Xiaofeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaofeng still remembers that &quot;Girl Nezha&quot; participated in the venture capital film festival for the first time, and Wang Mu drafted the outline. At that time, Li Xiaofeng had not yet become a director. Before giving a PPT lecture, in the office, Wang Mu gave Li Xiaofeng advice like a drama director giving a lecture to an actor: Director, I think you should give a speech like this. Li Xiaofeng didn&#39;t remember the specific suggestions, but he remembered the status of the two of them very clearly, &quot;There is no distinction between positions. It is the creator and the creator who are together. This feeling is quite rare today.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A movie of one&#39;s own&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the film &quot;Galaxy Writer&quot; won the Best Screenplay Award at the FIRST Youth Film Festival, vividly showing the screenwriter as a &quot;service industry&quot; (&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Lines in the film&lt;/span>;) The dilemma of practitioners: I am lucky enough to be favored by the producer, and I keep having meetings. Change, add roles, change people; the producer talks, the director talks, the investors talk; every link is tortured, and finally it returns to the starting point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Mu said that she used to not be the kind of professional screenwriter who could hold meetings and take jobs regularly. The most satisfactory way is to write a draft, revise it once you feel it, send it to the director after revising it, and then make no more revisions. If the director is not satisfied, he can overturn it. His job ends the moment he delivers the script. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also worked with other directors whom he admired very much, but those scripts were not produced in the end, so he felt that there was no need for him to mention them to the public. As a movie was aborted, Wang Mu knew that writing a drama would have a greater chance of being filmed and would earn a higher income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his years as a screenwriter for literary films, he seemed to be in a paradise, able to gain maximum freedom in a small world. Writing a play is different. A bunch of people have a meeting and try to solve script problems using theories or methods. He wasn&#39;t quite sure what the people he was meeting with wanted. Listening to everyone talking about the terminology in the screenwriting book, I felt bored and tired. &lt;p>; It is a 12-episode crime drama that carefully describes the relationship between two people who conspired to kidnap. It is quite special. When talking about character relationships and criminal motives during the interview, Wang Mu took &quot;Crime and Punishment&quot; as an example. Dostoevsky described in detail the long panorama of Raskolnikov&#39;s life before committing murder, &quot;writing crime to the bone.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, he decided to make a movie of his own. After paying attention to someone suffering from depression or bipolar disorder, he was surprised by the size of this group and wanted to photograph people suffering from mental distress. In August, at Dalian Guoli Hospital, he walked through the unlocked iron gate and saw a pretty girl and a boy keeping a fixed distance behind her. &quot;He always keeps a fixed distance from the girl and never disturbs her life.&quot; Wang Mu wrote in his diary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The appearance of Dai Chun and Jue Xiao in &quot;Gentle Shell&quot; is a bit like the boy and girl Wang Mu saw. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Many people think that when a writer turns to a director, you just finish the script and others do the rest for you. That’s impossible. You have to cooperate with different people to make them understand you. &quot;In general, a self-isolated creator must throw himself into an industrial structure, deal with different people, constantly persuade and compromise. To solve the problem, he can no longer escape from these. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the results, Wang Mu did a good job. The first draft of the script of &quot;Gentle Shell&quot; won the award in the venture capital section of the Pingyao Film Festival, with a bonus of 100,000. He tried filming footage, went to the Hainan Island International Film Festival for venture capital, won an award, and had start-up capital. Start looking for investors and talking about actors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The actor&#39;s past performance inertia needs to be respected, and a balance must be found between the actor&#39;s ideas and his own creation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I think the most awesome thing about directors and producers is that they can choose accurately. It&#39;s not as good as being accurate on the spot. Right?&quot; Baike said that the role that made him famous was comedy. The narcissistic and self-deprecating grassroots king Sledgehammer in &quot;Never Expected&quot;. Wang Mu asked him to play Dai Chun&#39;s younger brother Dai He, a middle-aged man who wants to break away from his cursed native family and work hard for his own future. He has a strong sense of worldly fatigue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Wang Ziwen’s birthday, he received a painting from Wang Mu, in which a little girl was holding a lantern and an elephant was beside her. &quot;He thought I was such a little girl.&quot; Wang Ziwen said. When Wang Mu asked her to play Jue Xiao, she thought, why would she let me play such a gentle person? &quot;Qu Xiaoxiao (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Wang Ziwen&#39;s character in &quot;Ode to Joy&quot;&lt;/span>;) is rebellious, powerful, or very sassy , Quirky, this is what most people think of me when they talk to me about roles.&quot; Wang Mu saw her vulnerability and tenacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Gentle Shell&quot; was shot in the order of the development of the story. Wang Mu almost never called for startup or interrupted, trying to capture the state of real life. Juexiao is reserved, Dai Chun is simple, and Dai He is depressed. Wang Ziwen, Yin Fang, and Baike supported each other and contributed delicate performances. At the beginning of 2023, &quot;Gentle Shell&quot; won three awards: &quot;Fei Mu Honor·Best Director&quot;, &quot;Fei Mu Honor·Best Actress&quot;, and &quot;Fei Mu Honor·Best Actor&quot; at the 6th Pingyao International Film Festival Grand prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For movies, from the feeling of pictures, rhythm and imagination to the specific production process. Wang Mu feels that it is a pity that he should be more patient and spend more time, &quot;I will tell each person more specifically - even if it is a person who has no lines and is just standing in the background - I will tell him myself. Play, communicate, and build a relationship with him.&quot; If we do this, there may not be many unsatisfactory things that need to be cut out in the later stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are too many problems.&quot; He even said so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told a story. After Dai Chun&#39;s father committed suicide, he walked to the overpass with blood on his body, waiting for Jue Xiao to appear. The original audio-visual focus was on Dai Chun. Looking back after half a year, Wang Mu realized that Juexiao also had to go through a very difficult journey. There should be a longer shot of Jue Xiao struggling through the crowd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He comforted himself that he would work hard on the next one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all this, a young director was born. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/f8KybXKqk3faRN5mcdz2o6FyEAX28htkyDSWinZj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/f8KybXKqk3faRN5mcdz2o6FyEAX28htkyDSWinZj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251383&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the movie &quot;Gentle Shell&quot;, Yin Fang and Baike&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;Be gentle&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;There are two short stories about Wang Mu, which happened before the filming and release of the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February and March 2020, at the beginning of the COVID-19 outbreak, Wang Mu found that he could not watch the news. Contemporary writers who write so well cannot withstand the impact of the present. Great suspicion hung over him. He immersed himself in ancient books, from &quot;Water Margin&quot; to &quot;Guanwen Guanzhi&quot;, &quot;Yuewei Caotang Notes&quot; and &quot;Xuanguailu&quot;. The past world was not connected with the present. &quot;It gave me a lot of healing and release, and I could escape inside.&quot; But he felt like a Taoist priest from Mount Laoshan, losing himself in the vast world of ancient literature and in danger of falling into historical nihilism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2020, Wang Mu’s son was born. In addition to letting him take the initiative to end this time as a Taoist priest in Laoshan (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;those He sold all the books&lt;/span>;), which also made &quot;Gentle Shell&quot; more gentle. &quot;Gentle Shell&quot; started filming in October 2020. The filming location was changed from the bleak Dalian in early spring to the gentle Quanzhou, and was completed 41 days later. What he wanted the film to do was to get closer and understand, rather than watch and observe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the movie was released, Wang Mu posted a self-report on Douban: &quot;My academic path was quite satisfactory, my career as a screenwriter was tepid, I loved theater, but I had no chance to rehearse plays in thirteen years, so I acted recklessly. I wanted to make a movie, but I had no idea that in the process, I might have brought burdens to others. As I approach my forties, looking back at these things, I feel lucky that there are always people in my life who are gentle to me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;At the end of the film, Dai Chun and Jue Xiao still have unresolved life problems, but in the shell they built, they finally have the happiness of ordinary people. After the end credits appeared, a childish voice called mom and dad. That was the voice of Wang Mu&#39;s son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the film is finished filming, it will be a long wait until it is released. When Wang Mu was anxious, he saw on Douyin that someone was cutting wood to build a house and make coffee in the wilderness. He watched it for a long time. It feels so good to accomplish something alone. He bought wood online and focused on it for six or seven hours, sawing the wood, sanding it into a shape, and applying wax. Very cool. He made a small wooden horse and a bird and gave them to his son. Of course, his son thought such toys were too boring and didn&#39;t know where to put them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During that time, he also carved seals, bought stones in an online store, and followed the book given by the store to learn to carve &quot;The best is like water.&quot; The operation is highly standardized, has nothing to do with art, and is very decompressive. Now Wang Mu has uncarved stones and uncarved wood in his house. This is all half-measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But he also knows very well that when it comes to other matters related to creation, he will not give up halfway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Thanks to Meng Yiyi and Yang Nan for their help with this article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>