<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[李尚福被免去国务委员、国防部部长职务，秦刚被免去国务委员职务]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259226]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 19:19:58&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011391102109&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Xi Jinping signed Presidential Order No. 12, No. 13, and No. 14.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud. com/48276b87vodtransgzp1251434507/35d229ad3270835011391102109/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp12514 34507/35d229ad3270835011391102109/DQLOOyhweoEA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640 &quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35d229ad3270835011391102109/DQLOOyhweoEA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;According to CCTV&#39;s &quot;News Network&quot;, Chairman&#39;s Order No. 14 said that according to the decision of the Sixth Meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress of the People&#39;s Republic of China on October 24, 2023:&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;1. Remove Li Shangfu from the posts of State Councilor and Minister of Defense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2. Remove Qin Gang from his post as State Councilor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3. Remove Wang Zhigang from the post of Minister of Science and Technology; appoint Yin Hejun as Minister of Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4. Remove Liu Kun from the post of Minister of Finance; appoint Lan Fo&#39;an as Minister of Finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[如何让老人在“家门口”幸福养老？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259157]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;Let rural elderly people have something to rely on in their old age&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the 2020 National Bulletin on the Development of Aging Causes, In 2020, my country&#39;s rural population aged 60 and above accounted for 23.81% of the total rural population, nearly 8 percentage points higher than that in urban areas. According to predictions from the National Office on Aging, by 2035, the proportion of people aged 60 and above in rural my country will rise to 37.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter&#39;s interview found that in the face of the aging and empty-nest problems of the rural population, various localities have adopted various measures based on local conditions to strive to provide rural elderly with something to rely on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Promote the culture of mutual aid in rural areas and develop mutual aid and elderly care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Aunt Wang, I&#39;m here to see you. How are you today?&quot; 54-year-old Li Yuqing is a neighborhood mutual aid worker in Zhuanghetun Village, Shilibao Town, Miyun District, Beijing. She often goes to the village 80 Visited Wang Xiulan, a 20-year-old man living alone, at his home. &quot;Every time I come to the door, I will help Aunt Wang measure her blood pressure and blood sugar, and ask her if she feels uncomfortable.&quot; Li Yuqing said that neighborhood mutual aid workers are equipped with a &quot;Neighbor Mutual Aid Treasure Box&quot;, which contains blood pressure monitors, blood glucose meters, etc. equipment and some commonly used medicines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/1246ac4b5caa9ef808c40e0c129fa4a8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/1246ac4b5caa9ef808c40e0c129fa4a8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255020&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Neighborhood mutual aid workers in Shilibao Town, Miyun District, Beijing, measure the blood pressure of Wang Xiulan (left). Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Tai Sicong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Zhang Hao, deputy director of the Social Child Welfare and Elderly Care Service Center of Miyun District Civil Affairs Bureau, said that in order to ensure the home safety of empty-nest elderly people living alone, Miyun District has vigorously promoted the pilot construction of neighbor mutual aid points. Local public-spirited &quot;4050&quot; villagers are hired as neighborhood mutual aid workers, and their residences are used as neighborhood mutual aid points. One point serves 10 elderly people living alone in the surrounding area, providing them with cleaning, laundry and sewing, shopping and payment services, and medicine prescriptions. Waiting for service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Do a good job in the &quot;key little things&quot; of rural elderly care and protect the safety of elderly people living alone in empty nests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the Chinese Disease Surveillance System, falls have become the leading cause of death from injuries among people over 65 years old in my country. More than 40 million elderly people in my country fall at least once every year, and bathrooms are the hardest hit area for elderly people to fall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to solve the problem of &quot;unsuitable for aging&quot; in some rural housing, Lishui City, Zhejiang Province has carried out aging-friendly renovations on more than 2,300 rural elderly households since 2021, allowing the elderly to have night lights to wake up at night and assistive devices to walk. , There are seats in the bath. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——Care services come into the home, allowing the elderly to have a peaceful life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Hanquan, a subsistence allowance recipient who lives in Guangfu Village, Qingshanpu Town, Changsha County, Hunan Province, has limited mobility in both lower limbs and can only rely on his wife to take care of him. The local government purchased home care services for him. Based on the needs of the elderly, caregivers at the local care center provide home care services more than 8 times a month, including haircuts, meal assistance, rehabilitation guidance, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Jiashan County, Zhejiang Province, the local government has explored and piloted a long-term care insurance system to accurately identify the needs of the elderly with disabilities and dementia, and has provided a total of more than 9,500 elderly people with life care, rehabilitation care and other services. Ensure the life of disabled and dementia elderly people in their later years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter found in interviews that rural elderly care services in some areas also face many practical difficulties. Some grassroots civil affairs cadres reported that due to the low population density in rural areas, the cost of providing meal assistance, medical assistance and other services is high. The supply of health care services in rural areas is insufficient, and some severely disabled and demented elderly people are prone to difficulty in providing care and poor quality of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The community elderly care service model continues to innovate&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Strengthening Aging Work in the New Era&quot; issued in 2021 proposed &quot;innovating the home community elderly care service model&quot;; in May this year , the &quot;Opinions on Promoting the Construction of Basic Elderly Care Service Systems&quot; issued by the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State stated that &quot;property service companies should be supported in providing home-based and community-based elderly care services according to local conditions&quot; and &quot;supported by elderly care institutions in operating community elderly care service facilities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter’s interview found that some cities rely on communities to develop diversified home-based elderly care services, allowing community services and home-based elderly care to be nested and integrated with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Gongshu District, Hangzhou City, there are 8 built-in elderly care institutions and more than 580 home elderly care beds, which can effectively meet the personalized needs of the elderly in the community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e443db73131a798f830e2b794e0c77db.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/e443db73131a798f830e2b794e0c77db.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Medical staff help the elderly with rehabilitation training in Desheng Community Nursing Home, Daguan Street, Gongshu District, Hangzhou City. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Ping&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Puyang Hua, a 77-year-old elderly man from Desheng Community, Daguan Street, Gongshu District, due to memory loss, her children did not trust her to be alone at home, so they placed her in a community nursing home. . Every morning around 8 a.m., the staff picks her up from the institution and takes her home in the afternoon after her children get off work. The day-care fee is 80 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Changsha, Hunan, the “elderly care + housekeeping” service model has achieved initial results. The reporter saw at the Comprehensive Elderly Care Service Center in Mapoling Street, Furong District, Changsha City that caregivers can not only provide basic services such as nutritious meal preparation, cleaning assistance, and bathing assistance, but also provide professional nursing services, such as health monitoring, rehabilitation exercises, Assisted medication, etc.; it can provide long-term residential services, or provide door-to-door services by &quot;ordering&quot; the elderly or their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Beijing, personalized services provided by “elderly care butlers” have become popular in some communities. The Beijing Civil Affairs Bureau divided the pilot streets into several areas. Each area established a &quot;2+N+X&quot; management unit, equipped with 2 high-quality chief elderly care service stewards, N professional elderly care service personnel and several volunteers. , responsible for the elderly care services in 2 to 3 communities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter’s interview found that some urban community elderly care services still have some shortcomings and insufficient service guarantee capabilities. Many old communities have few public spaces, making it difficult to build senior care canteens, care centers, etc.; most community senior care stations operate in a &quot;small workshop&quot; business model, lacking industry-influential business entities; there is still a shortage of senior care nursing talents, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Multiple parties share the responsibility to allow the elderly to spend their old age peacefully &quot;at home&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Strengthening the Work on Aging in the New Era&quot; proposed that &quot;building coordinated home-based community institutions , an elderly care service system and a health support system that combine medical care and health care” and “promote the gathering of various high-quality service resources to the elderly’s side, home and surroundings.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/acbb9f4950eac6f42eaf4ffa3216b614.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/23/acbb9f4950eac6f42eaf4ffa3216b614.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255021&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Elderly people are having lunch at the Comprehensive Elderly Care Service Center in Xijiao Street, Kongtong District, Pingliang City, Gansu Province. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wang Zixuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Where there are many elderly people, we will set up elderly care service institutions.” The Ministry of Civil Affairs and other departments stated that during the “14th Five-Year Plan” period, they will promote the development of old urban areas and completed residential areas. The (community) district has basically completed the community elderly care service facilities, and promoted the construction of a &quot;15-minute&quot; home elderly care service circle in urban communities, making home community elderly care services richer, more convenient, and of higher quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jiazeng, president of the Zhejiang Elderly Service Industry Association, believes that the focus of rural elderly care services should be on the provision of social services for people with disabilities and dementia. It is necessary to strengthen assistance and assistance to low-income groups, accelerate the establishment of a long-term care insurance system, give full play to the network advantages of township health centers and rural doctors, and encourage rural doctors to provide regular physical examinations, home visits, home hospital beds, etc. for the elderly, seriously ill, disabled and other elderly groups. Basic services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Hanqiao, deputy director of the Beijing Municipal Civil Affairs Bureau, suggested encouraging social capital to enter the elderly care industry, cultivating diversified business entities, and jointly making the elderly care service industry bigger and stronger. At present, Beijing has explored the establishment of a unified information platform for elderly care services to smooth resource docking, supply and demand matching, and support and guide business entities to actively participate in elderly care services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to problems such as the shortage of elderly care talents, Ding Fujun, director of the Civil Affairs Bureau of Shangyu District, Shaoxing City, Zhejiang Province, suggested improving the treatment of nursing staff and increasing the public’s recognition of nursing staff. At the same time, we will guide the majority of social welfare organizations, charities, and young volunteers to participate in elderly care services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, we must vigorously promote the application and digital management of smart devices to empower elderly care services. At present, some places are already exploring this aspect. For example, Hangzhou City has carried out a housing protection project, and installed intelligent monitoring equipment such as smoke alarms and emergency callers on demand for aging-appropriate renovation objects; Changsha City has carried out targeted aging-appropriate renovation projects. Some elderly people are equipped with &quot;anti-lost&quot; technology clothing, sleep monitors and other smart devices, and their health data are synchronized to the cloud in real time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[1840年以来的中国与美国（中）丨倬彼云汉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259193]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/24/t0J4qtLpFTF6UmbRCvw4UEB36ori63tp3iVUJbVg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;962&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/t0J4qtLpFTF6UmbRCvw4UEB36ori63tp 3iVUJbVg. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The international landscape under the &quot;containment policy&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1949, the Kuomintang retreated to Taiwan. During this period, the United States conducted an in-depth review and determined its national policy: How to prevent and block the joint front between the Soviet Union and China? How should the so-called &quot;free world&quot;, that is, Europe and the United States led by Britain and the United States, face the socialist lineup? Will countries advocating a capitalist free economy and countries pursuing a socialist planned economy coexist peacefully, or will they be in constant confrontation? This was something the U.S. government was very concerned about at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1947, President Truman adopted a containment policy after consulting Marshall, Eisenhower and MacArthur on the above issues. On February 22, 1946, George F. Kennan, Charge d&#39;Affaires of the U.S. Embassy in Moscow, sent the famous &quot;Long Telegram&quot; to the State Department. Kennan&#39;s suggestion established the United States&#39; plan for the postwar world: the &quot;Strategy of Containment.&quot; From the Truman era to the Nixon era, various diplomatic measures were taken in this direction. During the Nixon era, Kissinger planned the &quot;Engagement&quot; policy. However, from the overall principle, &quot;connection&quot; is only a means, trying to break out a gap in the &quot;containment&quot;. Therefore, the &quot;containment policy&quot; can be said to be the highest principle for the United States to deal with world affairs for decades. Until recently, this policy evolved into a frantic situation that was not anticipated at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back from 1947 to the present, for more than seventy years, most of the Western world has been ruled by this &quot;containment policy&quot;: the United States hopes that it should take on the role of &quot;free world&quot; and &quot;free economy&quot; defender&quot; responsibility. All possible &quot;gaps&quot; must be plugged as much as possible - extending from the North Sea to the Sea of ​​Okhotsk, and from Berlin to Sakhalin. This long front was dominated by the Soviet Union, and China, as an unspecified &quot;partner&quot; - which side China&#39;s &quot;partner&quot; status was on, was not stated in this cable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the implementation of this policy, the United States decided to use the three important figures mentioned above as the main executors. The first step was for Marshall, as Secretary of State, to preside over the &quot;Marshall Plan&quot; (officially known as the &quot;European Recovery Program&quot;) aimed at promoting European recovery, and at the same time use US dollars to assist Greece and Turkey - these two countries are The Soviet fleet entered the Mediterranean Sea from the Caspian Sea and the Black Sea. In the East, after Japan surrendered, MacArthur wanted to build Japan and South Korea into &quot;the democratic fortresses of the East&quot; and personally preside over the defense of the Eastern Front. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Truman retired, Eisenhower took over, and the three maintained this situation for decades. One of the episodes was that Truman could not stand that MacArthur &quot;would not be ordered by the king&quot; and recalled this warrior from South Korea. However, Marshall and Eisenhower faithfully implemented this policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first step of this policy in the East was that the U.S. Seventh Fleet began patrolling the Taiwan Strait, allowing Kinmen and Matsu, the two remaining bases of the Kuomintang Taiwan authorities, to be isolated on the coast of mainland China. preservation. Qingdao was originally a naval base for the US military stationed in China, but the Americans withdrew before they were actually involved in the battlefield on China&#39;s mainland. Otherwise, the US military stationed in Qingdao will echo the US military stationed in South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This decision triggered a series of changes in East Asia. The United States strengthens its bases in the Philippines and uses Japan and Ryukyu as important strongholds in the United States&#39; eastern defense line. Together with Taiwan, it forms the &quot;first island chain&quot; to contain mainland China. This policy has been maintained for a long time, implemented vigorously, and has far-reaching influence until today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the United States has refused to communicate with mainland China. Even though the &quot;Republic of China&quot; was forced to withdraw from the United Nations in 1971, the United States still maintained relations with it until 1978, when Beijing and Washington formally established diplomatic relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Cold War began, defending Taiwan became one of the tasks of the United States. As far as the Taiwan authorities are concerned, without the &quot;reassurance&quot; of the United States - the United States has drawn its defense line in the Taiwan Strait - the construction of this base in Taiwan would not have been possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The grievances and grievances between Taiwan and the mainland on the other side of the Taiwan Strait cannot be resolved to this day. How will these disputes be resolved in the future? How can we &quot;reunify&quot;? How can the results of Taiwan&#39;s construction, Taiwan&#39;s talents, Taiwan&#39;s economic foundation, and the mainland&#39;s economic construction support each other? This depends on the wisdom of us Chinese people, thinking about how to take into account the Chinese blood. Of course, the DPP and I have different ideas regarding the words &quot;Chinese blood.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the two sides of the Taiwan Strait have supported each other in economic construction, and this has not stopped since the 1970s. Mainland China&#39;s economic construction is about twenty years later than Taiwan&#39;s, because it experienced thirty years of bumps caused by trying various policies. From the time when Deng Xiaoping came to power to today, the cooperation and communication between the two sides has been carried out by the Straits Affairs Committee of both sides as the &quot;bridge&quot;, and by foreign heads of state such as Lee Kuan Yew as the &quot;middleman&quot;. Before Hong Kong and Macao returned to China, they were natural points of contact between the two sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second very important thing is the institutional reform of Taiwan initiated by Chiang Ching-kuo. He declared: &quot;We, the Chiang family, will no longer be involved in politics.&quot; Later, Lee Teng-hui changed Taiwan&#39;s basic law. But paradoxically, the U.S. government continues to promise to &quot;defend Taiwan with all its strength.&quot; This statement has become a rare example in the history of international relations. People familiar with international affairs once described this arrangement as &quot;intentional ambiguity.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Chinese history, from the Spring and Autumn Period to the Warring States Period, the Jin State was the de facto leader of the &quot;Five Hegemons&quot;. Jin took possession of the cognac of its ally Weiguo. The hegemony of the Jin State was already declining at that time, and its interior was eventually divided among the three families of Korea, Zhao, and Wei. Chinese history entered the &quot;Seven Heroes&quot; era of the Warring States Period. At that time, those who really had the strength to compete for hegemony were the two marginal powers, Qin and Chu. The two hegemons Wu and Yue that appeared in the gap were just short-lived. The two marginal powers, Qin and Chu, competed. In the end, Qin unified China and became the predecessor of the &quot;Chinese Empire&quot;. The process of Qin&#39;s unification of the Central Plains and the system it established actually restricted the form of the Chinese Empire for two thousand years, and it was only changed in 1911. Here, I use this example from Chinese history to foresee possible future changes in the hegemony of the United States over the past few decades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the establishment of U.S. hegemony, East Asia has encountered many crises: a Korean War and two Vietnam Wars - Japan and South Korea have become de facto &quot;dependencies&quot; of the United States, and Okinawa&#39;s status has become unclear. white. And these are all the consequences of the &quot;containment policy.&quot; The United States was so hegemonic that it could do the same thing in other countries that the Jin State obtained the cognac of the Wei State - Cognac was a stronghold in the eastern half of the Central Plains at that time, and the Jin State could not command the northern half. This situation is very similar to the &quot;island chain&quot; situation in East Asia. Paradoxically, the Zhao State, which was separated from the Jin State, finally took away the Cognac. We cannot predict whether the United States will transform Taiwan into an &quot;extension&quot; of Japan and South Korea in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Look at the situation in Europe. After the &quot;Marshall Plan&quot;, the United States established NATO and the European Union, focusing on the three countries of Britain, France, and Germany—the past enemy Germany—to guard the heart of Europe. Decades later, the European Union now feels that the United States was there to protect them, but now the United States has become their master. The United States spent a lot of effort to defend Europe. The &quot;Marshall Plan&quot; really rebuilt a world full of flowers and flowers from the ruins. Today&#39;s Germany has a prosperous economic foundation that is different from the United States we see today - Britain and France were defeated, and Germany came up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, the United States divided Germany into two: half occupied by the West and half occupied by the Soviet Union - just like North Korea was divided into South Korea, South Vietnam and North Vietnam. Berlin is an independent city, and a &quot;Berlin Wall&quot; was built in the middle. During the first Berlin Crisis in 1948, the Soviet Union blocked Berlin. The United States airdropped food, hamburgers, hot dogs, milk, eggs and even paper and other daily necessities for several months. The planes never stopped on the runway. That&#39;s a staggering expense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 25, 1963, Kennedy gave a speech in Berlin - &quot;As a free man, I am extremely proud to say: I am a Berliner.&quot; After becoming president, Kennedy also said: We Don&#39;t forget that Churchill and our old President Roosevelt once proposed that human beings should have &quot;four freedoms.&quot; (The &quot;Atlantic Charter&quot; signed by Roosevelt and Churchill actually has two &quot;versions&quot;: one is a long &quot;treaty&quot;, and the other is a short slogan of the &quot;Four Freedoms&quot; - freedom from fear, freedom from want , freedom of speech, freedom of belief.) It is our unshirkable duty to be the guardians of the world and safeguard these &quot;four freedoms.&quot; Back then, Kennedy swore an oath based on the &quot;Four Freedoms&quot;: Our mission is long and arduous. Don’t ask what the country can do for us, ask what we can do for the country. After President Roosevelt implemented the New Deal, the country fulfilled its responsibilities to its citizens and maintained their minimum standard of living. The responsibility of our government is to realize the &quot;four freedoms&quot; on American soil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These declarations are very touching, and Americans are indeed working very hard in practice. The boundaries drawn at the time still exist today - the recent conflict between Ukraine and Russia was caused by the US &quot;containment policy&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What I said above is to explain the cultural background of Kennan’s “containment policy”, the United States’ expectations of itself, and its efforts. From then to now, for more than seventy years, the hegemony of the United States has been presented under the discourse system of &quot;containment policy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There was also the Cuban Missile Crisis. The Soviet Union wanted to set up a missile base in Cuba, but the United States would not allow it. Kennedy and Khrushchev confronted each other and refused to give in. Eventually the Soviet Union gave in and withdrew its missiles from Cuba. The United States still occupies Guantánamo Bay in Cuba and refuses to give it up until death: it is a prison without legal control. The spies and prisoners the United States interrogates here are not protected by any human rights laws and are forced to water and whip. , electric shock and other torture, and the body was thrown away after death. I often use the word &quot;paradox&quot; to describe this kind of behavior: the United States claims to safeguard the &quot;four freedoms&quot;, but in fact there is always such a &quot;scar&quot;, but it turns a blind eye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1957, mankind’s first artificial satellite was successfully launched by the Soviet Union. The United States spent a lot of money and tried hard to maintain the balance of power in space. Finally, in 1969, during the Nixon era, American astronauts landed on the moon for the first time. The year before, 59 countries, including the United States, the Soviet Union, and the United Kingdom, jointly signed the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons. Restricting new countries from developing nuclear weapons is a good thing for the world. As for countries that already possess nuclear weapons, it is unknown whether someone will use nuclear bombs first. Until the Reagan era, the arms competition between the United States and the Soviet Union continued, and even developed to the point where satellites could be used to carry nuclear bombs into space. The United States crushed the Soviet economy with its huge space arms race. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The previous description of U.S. foreign policy in history is used as a background to illustrate that U.S. foreign policy is the most important &quot;medicine&quot; in Sino-U.S. relations and is also intended to maintain the hegemonic thinking of Western culture and &quot;Containment&quot; thoughts. This is a very important principle for us to understand the complex chess game of the world since World War II. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Chinese in the United States under &quot;McCarthyism&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since World War II, many Chinese students have studied in the United States, including me. We come here to study because the curriculum and equipment of American schools are among the best in the world. At this stage, the United States is indeed recruiting a large number of foreign students, and we take this opportunity to learn skills. Of course, Chinese people like to return fallen leaves to their roots. Most of the hundreds of international students who came to the United States through the &quot;Geng Geng&quot; funds in the early days returned to China, and their main jobs were either in education or industry. At that time, China&#39;s scientific and technological development was not yet mainstream, and scientific and technological talents were roughly distributed in the above two categories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, with the civil war between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party, China was divided into two and the straits were blocked. This became a big problem: under the &quot;containment policy&quot; stance of the &quot;containment policy&quot;, the United States would not allow students from mainland China to They return to the mainland. The most important example is Qian Xuesen. At that time, American physics was at the forefront of the world. If China wanted to develop modern technological weapons, Qian Xuesen&#39;s participation would definitely make a contribution. I believe Qian Xuesen did his best in inventing missiles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the &quot;Iron Curtain&quot; began to fall, the United States began to be suspicious of &quot;left-leaning&quot; people in the United States. This incident occurred during Truman&#39;s term. &quot;McCarthyism&quot; not only wanted to block those intellectuals who chose to return to China or Eastern European countries, but also wanted to eradicate &quot;left-leaning&quot; elements in the country. The so-called &quot;left leaning&quot; is defined as &quot;liberal elements&quot; - anyone who is not &quot;right&quot; is labeled as &quot;left&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person mainly responsible for this matter is the Pacific International Society. Their surveillance network is very wide and covers all the bases for China research-Pittsburgh is okay because it is not a big base. Such a situation has made Chinese people all over the United States fearful. One day, agents from the FBI or CIA will check your correspondence and check your tax payments. Everyone was in disbelief and fearful. When I came to Pittsburgh in 1970, I saw the remnants of this phenomenon. An old overseas Chinese named Yu - he changed his name to &quot;Lin Pan&quot; when he came here because he bought the Lin family&#39;s &quot;birth certificate&quot;; our current dentist belongs to the Yu family. The old gentleman came to my office to talk. He closed the door first, then gently talked to me about their fears, and asked me in a low voice: &quot;When will this situation end?&quot; Because they have many children from their hometown who want to come out. But the &quot;Iron Curtain&quot; has dropped; there are still dozens of fellow villagers who died in foreign lands, so they have to be cremated first and wait until one day to take them back to their hometowns. Recently, Quanzi also visited the location where the ashes are stored, and there were indeed dozens of jars there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, &quot;McCarthyism&quot; was subsided, and Taiwan resumed exchanges with the United States. I returned to Taiwan in 1962 and spent the next two or three years working in the History Department of my alma mater, National Taiwan University, arranging courses according to the modern scale and direction. My main job was to liaise with academic institutions and sinologists in the United States. My supervisors are Mr. Wang Shijie, president of Academia Sinica, and Mr. Li Ji, director of the Institute of History and Philology. This job is very difficult, and many people question my position: If we go to Taiwan, will it increase the United States&#39; suspicion of me? I said: &quot;I can&#39;t answer your question, but I went back, and I have no problem.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was not until 1971, after Nixon launched &quot;ping pong diplomacy&quot; with mainland China, that there were a large number of overseas Chinese Young people and international students returned to the mainland; subsequently, a large number of international students came from the mainland as well, more than ten times more than those from Taiwan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Wcb0MkQeDfGn11pLogqeywCkeBau6ADMYXoj9kSS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/Wcb0MkQeDfGn11pLogqeywCkeBau6ADMYXoj9kSS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1956, Mr. Yang Zhenning and Li Zhengdao proposed the &quot;law of non-conservation of parity&quot;; subsequently, Ms. Wu Jianxiong proved this theory through experiments - these three are world-famous physicists. Because Mr. Yang&#39;s father was still in the mainland, he went back as soon as Sino-US relations loosened, and has never cut off contacts with the mainland since then. He also worked very hard to introduce the research situation of modern physics in the United States to China and help domestic scholars. For decades, he has helped many students study abroad based on his original intention and done his best for the development of physics in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I had the honor to work with him and Liu Zunyi to help Mr. Yu Jizhong establish the &quot;Chinese-English Teaching Foundation&quot; in mainland China. The purpose is to help university teachers go abroad for as short as half a year or as long as one year. Further education. As long as they put forward the visiting unit, goals, plans, time, as well as an invitation letter or commitment from the United States, as well as a letter of recommendation from the school, we will try our best to prioritize them in a professional direction. It is a very pleasant job for me to see so many outstanding scholars lining up, ready to make further efforts. Unfortunately, there are too few people and we cannot satisfy everyone&#39;s wishes. Because of this work, Mr. Yang meets with us once a year. In addition to our lectures to various schools, I also had the opportunity to ask for advice from him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, we visited the Chinese University of Hong Kong at the same time, and we would often drink tea and chat together. With such a friendship, I admire him greatly: he is old but still childlike, smart but not overbearing. He has reached the pinnacle of his specialized knowledge and is very knowledgeable about general affairs. The most admirable thing: He is completely frank with juniors of my age, which makes me feel like I am sitting on a spring breeze when talking to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[再获雨果奖，中国科幻文学更进一步]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259145]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the evening of October 21, the 2023 Hugo Awards were announced at the 2023 Chengdu World Science Fiction Conference, with a total of 17 Hugo categories selected Awards and Category 2 non-Hugo Awards, Chinese writer Hai Miao won the Best Short Novella Award for &quot;The Painter of Time and Space&quot;. This is also the first time that the Hugo Awards are announced and awarded in China.</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[检察机关依法对李春生涉嫌受贿一案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259201]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Reporters learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate on October 24 that the former deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People’s Congress Li Chunsheng&#39;s suspected bribery case was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the case was reviewed and prosecuted by the Chenzhou City People&#39;s Procuratorate of Hunan Province. Recently, the Chenzhou City People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Chenzhou City Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ informed the defendant Li Chunsheng of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant, and listened to the opinions of the defender. Prosecution charges: Li Chunsheng used his position as county magistrate and county party committee secretary of Xin County in Henan Province, deputy director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security and director of the Personnel Training Bureau, deputy governor of Guangdong Province and director of the Provincial Public Security Department, and deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress. , deputy director and other positions, as well as the convenient conditions for the formation of powers and status, to seek benefits for relevant units and individuals in business operations, project promotion, project contracting, job promotion, etc., illegally accepting property from others, the amount is particularly huge, and should be legally accepted He will be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访经济学家吴晓求：“要把A股市场从融资市场转变为投资市场”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259197]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the Chinese capital market for more than thirty years, with more than 200 million investors and more than 5,300 listed companies, there is no A market that touches the nerves of all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the Political Bureau meeting of the CPC Central Committee proposed “activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence.” The China Securities Regulatory Commission and other departments subsequently launched a package of policies for “active capital markets”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges are the product of reform. They later underwent two historic reforms: shareholding split and registration system. But for a long time, every investor has suffered from short-term bullishness and bearishness. What loopholes have been left behind by the share-trading reform that once inspired the Long Bull market? How to fix blockage? What loopholes have arisen from the registration system? How to fix it quickly? How can the positioning of China&#39;s capital market mature through changes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the occasion of the 45th anniversary of the reform and opening up of China&#39;s financial industry, Wu Xiaoqiu, former vice president of Renmin University of China and director of the China Capital Market Research Institute, emphasized in an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend that the establishment of the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges and the split of shares Reform and comprehensive registration-based reform are three monuments in the more than 30 years since the establishment of China&#39;s capital market. While they have achieved great success, they have also left some loopholes. These loopholes are the important institutional constraints that have caused the capital market to stagnate over the past decade. At present, regulatory authorities have realized and stepped up efforts to improve system design and plug loopholes. In the longer term, the main function of China&#39;s capital market is to transform from financing enterprises to a wealth management platform for investors, and from a financing market to an investment market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xiaoqiu is the youngest professor of economics in the history of Renmin University of China and the first doctoral supervisor in the field of securities investment in China. He has been engaged in securities teaching and research for more than 30 years. He led the compilation of the first edition of China Securities Practitioner examination materials. He is also the promoter and witness of many major reforms in the capital market, such as the share-trading reform and the registration system reform. He has made many suggestions for active capital markets. Among them, his consistent assertion that &quot;the time is not ripe for the implementation of the T+0 trading system&quot; is in line with the China Securities Regulatory Commission. The current stance is consistent. The &quot;Phaseically Tightened Securities Lending and Strategic Investors Placement and Lending of Shares&quot; notice issued by the China Securities Regulatory Commission on October 14, 2023 is also related to the loopholes in the shareholding reduction rules and systems that Wu Xiaoqiu has been paying attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;569&quot; height= &quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/raTGJwAtxKIRGrHUUoBIlw9OS03pZ4c1M2TYy5Y4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Xiaoqiu: former vice president of Renmin University of China; currently dean of the National Institute of Financial Research and China Capital Market Research Institute of Renmin University of China, national first-class professor, and executive director of the China Society for Finance and Banking . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Engaged in the economy&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Financial and Capital Market Research&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Forty&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Years”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are a college student in the &quot;New Third Class&quot; (1977-1979). If the college entrance examination and reform and opening up had not been resumed, how would your life trajectory have evolved? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I never went to high school. Before college, he worked as a carpenter and later as a secretary in the county commerce bureau. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resumption of the college entrance examination and reform and opening up changed the destiny of my life, just as it changed the destiny of thousands of my contemporaries in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee was held in December 1978, but the college entrance examination was resumed in 1977. Putting the resumption of the college entrance examination before the Third Plenary Session of the Eleventh Central Committee, I think this is to prepare for reform and opening up in terms of ideology, talent, and public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The resumption of the college entrance examination is a reform in itself. It is equivalent to a fundamental adjustment of the talent training system during the ten-year &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; period, bringing order to things. Looking back on the past, without reform and opening up, a key move that determines the fate of contemporary China, China would not be what it is today, and neither would I be what I am today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you apply for the national economics major of Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I initially applied for the philosophy major at Jiangxi University because I like philosophy. When my father found out, he asked me to change my major. He believes that he should study at Jiangxi University of Finance and Economics. The major in national economic planning is very good and the economy may still be very important in the future. This change is also a &quot;decisive move&quot; for me personally. I later thought about my father&#39;s decision. He foresaw the future development direction of China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my first year of college, I got to know Sun Yefang, Yu Guangyuan, Xu Dixin, Song Tao, Dong Fuzhen and other seniors. They are monuments in my mind. The dream of a scholar and the dream of an economist have been with me since I was in college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the postgraduate entrance examination in 1983, I ranked second overall and was admitted to the National Economic Planning major of Renmin University of China. For the National Economic Planning major, Renmin University is a palace. Later, I studied for a Ph.D. and stayed at the school to teach after graduation, and I never left. I first did economic research for about 10 years. From 1993 to 1994, I officially switched to financial research and capital market research, which now has a history of almost 30 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;If you don&#39;t emancipate your mind, you can&#39;t find the right path to development&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the beginning of his studies (1983-1986), reform and opening up developed from rural areas to cities, urban economic system reform began, township enterprises began to sprout, and opening up to the outside world continued to expand. During this period, which reform events impressed you the most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are four things that impressed me deeply: The first time was attending an economic system reform seminar in Chaohu, Anhui. In 1985, the central government issued the &quot;Decision on Economic System Reform&quot; and launched the economic system reform that combined planning and market. It was a historic decision. I was a second-year graduate student at the time, and my supervisor, Mr. Hu Naowu, and I attended this seminar. That was my first time to participate in a national, high-level forum. It touched me greatly and expanded my horizons. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second time was in 1985, when I participated in the Second Youth and Middle-aged Economic Forum held in Tianjin. The young people participating in the forum were active in thinking, participating in various debates, thinking about China&#39;s future, and exploring the focus of reform. I was writing an article about corporate bankruptcy. Bankruptcy is a thing of the market economy. There was no such thing as bankruptcy in China under the planned economy at that time, only &quot;shut down and transfer&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third time in 1985, I participated in a forum held in the Great Hall of the People. That forum was hosted by Mr. Dong Fucheng, and my speech attracted the attention of Li Chengrui, then director of the National Bureau of Statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth time was in 1986, when I participated in another discussion meeting on economic leverage in Leshan, Sichuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was only in my twenties at the time. It can be seen that that era gave young people many platforms and opportunities to speak freely at high-level forums held in the Great Hall of the People. This activates your mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those were sparkling days, full of youthful dreams and pursuits of young people everywhere. Only when the mind is liberated can academics prosper and the country develop. Without emancipating our minds, we cannot find the right path to development. Everything must be explored, discussed and even debated before you know which is the right path. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Cracking the mystery of China&#39;s special economic phenomenon&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During your doctoral studies (1987-1990), the basic line of &quot;one center, two basic points&quot; and &quot;science and technology are the primary productive forces&quot; were proposed. In the meantime, what are your views on China&#39;s economic reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The most important thing when studying for a PhD is to learn advanced theories, study the Chinese economy, and how to solve the mystery of the special phenomena of the Chinese economy at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book that had the greatest impact on me at that time was &quot;The Economics of Shortage&quot; by the Hungarian economist János Korny. In the mid-to-late 1980s, many people read this work. &quot;Shortage Economics&quot; is a book that describes the basic characteristics of socialist economic operations under the traditional planned economic system. It is rich in strong theoretical logic, including soft budget constraints, paternalism, etc. Inspired by his thoughts, I started writing &quot;Theory of Compact Movement&quot; in 1987. &quot;The Theory of Tight Operation&quot; and my doctoral thesis &quot;Analysis of Socialist Economic Operation&quot; were published in 1991 and 1992 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did this book receive such special attention at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The real value of these two books is their attempt to explain the characteristics and laws of socialist economic operation under the traditional system. Because of these two books, as well as articles and papers published in People&#39;s Daily, Guangming Daily, Economic Research and Journal of Renmin University of China, I was promoted to professor by Renmin University in 1993. That year, Renmin University made an exception and promoted five professors, and I was the youngest among them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Transforming securities research and taking a road less traveled&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1994, you were transferred to the Department of Finance and Economics as a professor in the field of securities research in finance. The following year, you became the first doctoral supervisor in the field of securities investment in my country. Since then, you have been closely associated with China&#39;s securities industry. The relationship has been developing for thirty years. Why focus on securities research from now on? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was already studying finance at that time, so I offered to be transferred. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two opportunities: one is to alleviate poverty. In the early 1990s, I was about to become a professor and still lived in a Tongzi building with only 800 yuan in savings. At that time, someone gave me an idea, saying that you write a best-selling book, we will be responsible for selling it, and then give you a share. I thought of stocks and bonds. So I edited the &quot;Complete Book of Stocks and Bonds&quot;, which contained about 5 million words in two volumes. It was a great seller as soon as it was launched. Later, I was given some money, and I got out of poverty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because I am the editor-in-chief, people ask me to speak. This forced me to really learn securities knowledge and securities investment. This has begun to deviate from the direction of my economics research, which is entirely the study of capital markets and finance. At that time, people did not think it was a science, and even thought it was a bit &quot;crooked&quot;. An important scholar among my predecessors once talked to me. The core idea was that I should return to the mainstream track of economic research such as economic operation analysis, macroeconomics, macroeconomic management and inflation theory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The path of securities research was a sparsely traveled path at that time. There were few professional researchers, a lot of noise, and very little rational research. But in my opinion, the more in-depth securities research is, the more valuable it is. I am one of the few people left who has done research in the early stages and is still doing front-line research now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The then president of Renmin University, Mr. Huang Da, was a professor in the Department of Finance, so I applied to go to the Department of Finance. I taught a course on securities investment. At that time, there were not many securities investment courses offered in colleges and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;I first entered the stock market both for making money and for research&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There was a movie called &quot;Stock Crazy&quot; in 1994, which tells the story of the various crazes caused by mass speculation in the stock market in the early days of the stock market. Was the stock market back then really like in the movies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; (The craze for stock trading) has indeed begun. The stock market has begun to enter people&#39;s lives, more and more people are investing in the stock market, and various theories, methods and stock reviews have begun to appear. Because I wrote &quot;The Complete Book of Stocks and Bonds&quot;, I also started doing research on it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a research expert on securities investment, what will happen to you? Is stock trading practical? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It was only after 2000 that I really entered the stock market as an investor. After entering, I found that practice was more profoundly helpful to my theoretical research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What is the difference between securities research and stock trading? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My goal in entering this market is not only to make money, but also to do research. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I set two goals for myself at that time: first, not to lose money, and to see through practical operations whether what I learned theoretically would work in practice; second, to establish a direct perceptual understanding of the research object. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slowly, I understand the rules of securities investment and the market better. When I write textbooks, I will be more enriched and my writing will be more vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During that period, I presided over the compilation of the first set of teaching materials for the securities practitioner qualification examination in China. The first edition consisted of six volumes. The general structure of the later textbooks compiled by the China Securities Regulatory Commission did not deviate from this edition. It plays a very important role in the qualification examination for securities practitioners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Have the expectations of making money been met? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I also wanted to catch the bull market and make a fortune. The first one I remember was buying Sichuan Changhong, and one day I suddenly discovered that it was going up quite well. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;The loopholes left over from the split-share structure reform must be closed &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once said that China’s capital market has three monuments: Shanghai The establishment of the Shenzhen Stock Exchange, the share-trading reform, and the pilot registration system. What have you been involved in promoting? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I participated in the share-trading reform and promoted the pilot registration system. The share-trading reform was launched in May 2005. However, since the theoretical preparation failed in 2001 when the reduction of state-owned shares failed, we began to think about how to carry out share-trading reform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did the reduction of state-owned shares fail in 2001? What inspiration did it provide for the subsequent share-trading reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time, the regulatory agency believed that the reduction of state-owned shares could be reduced at market price, but it was hastily stopped due to the huge market reaction. Later analysis concluded that reducing state-owned stocks based on market prices lacked both logic and theoretical support, so it was bound to fail. As a result of this failure, we were reflecting on how to promote split-share reform. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During that period of reflection, the academic community organized many discussions, and I was probably one of the people who participated the most, whether in small-scale discussions hosted by the China Securities Regulatory Commission or in large-scale discussions. I participated in almost every discussion. Among them, the most impressive one was when Shang Fulin, then chairman of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, called me one day in 2004 and discussed with me alone how to change the split share structure. Later, I went to his office many times to participate in discussions, with about ten people in a small group and twenty or thirty people in a large group. After discussion, we reached a consensus on two points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first point is that the split share structure reform must be promoted. If we do not promote the reform, China&#39;s capital market will have no future. This is what I also emphasize; the second point is what method should be used to reform the split-share structure reform. The design of this path is very difficult. We slowly considered that consideration reform is appropriate. Consideration reform is only a direction. It becomes more difficult to determine the appropriate consideration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I clearly remember that during a meeting of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, Tu Guangshao, then vice chairman of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, asked me, what do you think is the appropriate proportion of the consideration? I said 30% or 30% off, because the price of additional issuance of stock is 30% off the circulating price. This provides a reference for the consideration of the share-trading reform. Later, practice proved that the consideration plans for the share-trading reform of various listed companies fluctuated around 30% off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the early days of the share-trading reform in 2005, the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets did not Too big a reaction. The big bull market seems to have started only after 2005. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes. The share-trading reform was launched in May 2005. At that time, the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets had been in the doldrums for more than four years since 2001, and the market response was lukewarm. Later, the market gradually learned that this thing was serious, and more and more people had a premonition that this was an opportunity for a big bull market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We judged at that time that the long bear market in the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets would be reversed during the share-trading reform process. After the reform is completed, it will lay a good foundation for the long-term healthy development of the capital market. From today&#39;s perspective, the general direction of the share-trading reform is correct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The share-trading reform took about two years. What shortcomings does it have? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From May 2005 to March 2007, 95% of listed companies completed the share-trading reform. It is a monument, but it does have flaws. This flaw is the lack of effective constraints on the reduction of major shareholders and actual controllers. This policy loophole had an important impact on the subsequent stagnation of the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock markets for more than ten years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have also said recently that the most important thing that seriously restricts the development of China’s capital market is the institutional design of the asset supply side. Among them, the asset supply side is mainly the reduction rules of existing assets, which is the actual Controllers and controlling shareholders do not have financial constraints to reduce their holdings, which makes it difficult for the market to grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you think this loophole is being fixed now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;On August 27, 2023, there have been some amendments in the China Securities Regulatory Commission policy. This is a loophole left by the share-trading reform, and we must make up for it. Because it seriously damages the ecological chain of capital supply and demand in the capital market and causes a serious imbalance in the capital supply relationship. At present, major loopholes are being patched, so at least we know where they are. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Registration reform has had mixed effects”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The third monument you mentioned in China’s capital market is the registration-based reform. Why start the registration system reform? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After 2007, the theoretical research, or policy formulation, that I participated in was mainly the registration system reform. Why should we carry out registration reform? Because the approval system has major flaws. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, the biggest problem with the approval system is that the choice of listing a company is not left to the market, but to the Issuance Review Committee and to visible hands. The second problem is that the pricing is not market-oriented, so there is a strange phenomenon of 20 daily limit after listing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third problem is that the regulatory body and the auditing body are not separated. The China Securities Regulatory Commission both audits and supervises. This is of course problematic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the fact that the approval system has at least these three problems, if we want to correct these three defects, we must carry out the registration system reform. In accordance with the principle of marketization, the exchange adopts a flexible system, and at the same time does not adhere to the requirement that companies to be listed must be profitable. Compared with the approval system, which requires companies to be listed to be profitable for three consecutive years, one of the biggest innovations of the registration system is that major high-tech companies that are planning to be listed are allowed to have losses in the past three years, but they must have sustainable operating capabilities. This is a major change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023 is the first year of the comprehensive registration system reform. As a promoter and policy participant of the registration system reform, are you satisfied with the current results of the reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Bittersweet. Fortunately, some unicorn companies and high-tech companies have become listed companies through this mechanism. Although they are losing money in the short term, they have the ability to operate sustainably. The registration system reform naturally serves specialized and high-tech innovative enterprises, and is naturally coupled with high-tech enterprises. Only under the registration system can technology and capital markets be coupled, and we will still work in this direction in the future. I think this is of great value and significance to us in promoting the development of high-tech enterprises, transforming my country&#39;s industrial structure and upgrading and iterating industries, improving the structure of listed companies, and enhancing the investment value of China&#39;s capital market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is worrying is the generalization of the definition of loss in the registration system. This is a serious misunderstanding, which damages market confidence and is not in line with the original meaning of the registration system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why does this vulnerability occur? What are the dangers of this vulnerability? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Like the share-trading reform, the registration-based reform also has a loophole. Frankly, no one realized it at the time. Just like designing a spacecraft, there are a lot of details and a lot of sparse details. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The loophole of the registration system is that it generalizes the market-oriented functions, or it generalizes the indicators that listed companies do not strictly require profitability. So later, some listed companies seized on such a loophole and established a so-called high-tech enterprise. Under the banner of the so-called &quot;breaking the bottleneck project&quot;, they hired dozens of researchers and started to apply for IPO after two or three years. . This has done huge damage to market confidence. They do not comply with the basic spirit of the registration system, and also exceed the requirements of the risk boundaries that a public market, exchange market, and public investors can bear. The financing of this type of enterprise should mainly be completed by PE and VC, and direct IPO is not allowed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I define this loophole as: a generalized understanding of the non-profit requirement under the registration system. This is a very serious misunderstanding, which is closely related to the subsequent stagnation of the stock market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Is this vulnerability currently being patched? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I once made it clear to the China Securities Regulatory Commission that the requirement that companies to be listed be unprofitable cannot be generalized. Judging from the recent IPO situation, the China Securities Regulatory Commission and exchanges have also paid special attention to the listing requirements of companies with negative financial indicators, especially those with negative net assets, negative cash flow, and negative profits. These major financial reporting indicators are all negative, and such companies cannot be listed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After fixing the loopholes, the registration system reform is completed What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Far from it. The registration-based reform is an all-round, whole-chain reform. The market-oriented reform of the issuance system is only its historical and logical starting point. It will also be followed by transactions, mergers and acquisitions, information disclosure, supervision, delisting, penalties for violations and illegal acts, legal models, etc. Adjustments in many other aspects must be incorporated into the model compatible with the registration system reform and continuously improved. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;Twin Peaks model is the ideal compromise&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 2022, you proposed the &quot;twin peaks model&quot; of China&#39;s financial system. What are the deep observations and thoughts behind it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Frankly speaking, the first thing I proposed was the &quot;single bee mode&quot;. Around 2002, I believed that China’s future financial model would be dominated by the capital market. Twenty years have passed, and I have found that the &quot;single bee model&quot; is very difficult to achieve in China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite this, in the past 20 years, the scale of China&#39;s capital market has expanded relatively rapidly. From a market capitalization of two to three trillion in the past to a market capitalization of more than eighty trillion today, its proportion in the financial system has increased significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, I finally realized that China’s commercial banks play a huge role in China’s economic life, and China can only implement the bimodal model-the banking system and the capital market jointly dominate. This is an ideal compromise and a realistic situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why is it difficult for the capital market to become dominant? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The development of the capital market has not changed the dependence of the Chinese economy on currency and credit. From the perspective of the capital market itself, the stock prices of listed companies have not increased in the past 20 years, and the market index has not increased. Only the market value has expanded. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the number of listed companies has increased from 1,000 to more than 5,300 in the past 20 years. Almost China’s largest and best companies have achieved IPOs, including many state-owned enterprises and central enterprises. and “unicorn” companies. In a sense, the function of China&#39;s stock market in facilitating enterprise financing has been realized, but it itself is a pie-spreading expansion, constantly expanding outwards without intensive cultivation, and the unit output rate of enterprises after obtaining financing is very low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is our index not growing? A very important reason is to go back to the two loopholes I just mentioned, especially the first loophole, which is the reduction rule, which has a huge inhibitory effect on growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;China’s stock market&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Why&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is still immature&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Our capital market has developed for more than 30 years. At the age of thirty, can it be considered a mature market? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China’s capital market has slowly found a basic direction in practice and reform, but it is still an immature market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first immaturity is that there are many loopholes in the system design. The second immaturity lies in the lack of a deep understanding of what the capital market means to China and what it means to financial reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, we often said that the main purpose of establishing the stock market was to facilitate corporate financing. This is an incorrect positioning and perception. The securities market appears to be financing, but is actually investment. If you don’t continuously strengthen your investment function, financing will be unsustainable, and people will vote with their feet. If you leave, how can you raise funds? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, we need to transform China’s capital market from a financing market that facilitates corporate financing to a wealth management platform and investment market for investors. Transforming from a financing market to an investment market is our future direction. It will take a long time to achieve this goal. For institutional effects to take effect, it will take time for corresponding institutional arrangements to be put in place. Our current institutional arrangements are closing loopholes and moving closer to this aspect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A-shares are bullish and bearish. The main problem is the loopholes in the system design and Don’t really understand the significance of the capital market to financial reform? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The reason for this phenomenon in China’s capital market is not only the profound cultural and legal background, but also the misalignment of rules at the meso level. For example, there are two loopholes in the share-trading reform and the registration-based reform mentioned earlier. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, part of the reason is that our entrepreneurs do not have a deep understanding of what going public means to them. Originally, going public was a means, but these company founders suddenly discovered that it was so easy to make a fortune by going public, which was much easier than working hard in the real economy. This corroded their original intention to start a business in the past. He will take listing as his goal and stop doing the real economy. He will find a way to cash out and leave as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To correct this misdirection, we can only guide it through institutional reform - only by doing a good job can you cash out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What specific suggestions do you have for this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;To achieve a fundamental transformation of the functions and orientation of the capital market, the first step is to transform the overall macro-system design. On the asset supply side, the system design must be conducive to the transformation of market functions, the introduction of transparent and growth-producing assets into the market, and the attraction of more and more new investors and the entry of new funds into the market. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, we should have certain restrictions on all pre-listing shareholders reducing their shareholdings, especially controlling shareholders and actual controllers, including second shareholders, third shareholders, etc. How to use Financial indicators constrain shareholding reductions and require innovative system designs to allow all shareholders to focus their attention and efforts on how to do a good job in the company, create profits, and improve distribution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, we must continue to improve the ecological environment of the capital market. Whether institutional investors or individual investors, in this market, they can obtain returns commensurate with their risks, and only then will the market grow. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;The stock market continues to not improve, and we need to come up with the right response&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the end of July, the central government clearly proposed to &quot;activate the capital market.&quot; What signal does this send? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It should be said that the supervisory authorities have seen the problem. No field in China covers such a large scope as the capital market. There are at least 200 million investors in the capital market, and behind them may be 200 million families. Almost half of the people in China have something to do with the capital market. Second, although the global capital markets have gone through the epidemic, China&#39;s capital markets among major economies have not performed well. We need to pay more attention to the problems behind it. Third, activating the capital market is also an important measure to boost market confidence. We need to come up with the right response. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are also many expert suggestions for activating the capital market A shares switch from T+1 to T+0. But regulators have long said the opportunity is premature. What do you think? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Xiaoqiu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The transaction reform has no substantive significance, T+0 is not conducive to the growth of the market, and the logical basis of the T+0 reform is unclear. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the biggest benefit of T+0 is to securities companies. T+0 will directly lead to an increase in brokerage commissions, thereby driving the rise of brokerage stocks. The goal of our reform is not to make securities companies prosperous, and the original intention of activating the capital market is not to increase commissions. An increase in commissions will instead mean the leakage of capital market funds. As for what some people say that T+0 has a correction mechanism for market prices, I think more empirical research is needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the trading rules based on T+1 were chosen in the early days of the birth of China’s capital market and against the background of many trials and errors of trading rules. After more than 30 years of practice, they have become very mature and more Suitable for China&#39;s national conditions. I like the T+1 system very much. Why do stocks bought in the morning have to be sold in the afternoon? Since you are going to sell in the afternoon, don’t buy in the morning. The logic is very clear. If you buy it wrong, it will be the same if you sell it tomorrow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the T+1 system is not unique to China and is also very mature internationally. Some countries may not use T+0, but we do too. Personally, I don’t like T+0 because this system will drive people crazy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend: Do you have confidence in the Chinese stock market? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xiaoqiu: The prerequisite for the Chinese stock market to improve is that the Chinese economy must improve. I have always said that as long as the Chinese economy wants to do well, it will definitely do well. In essence, China&#39;s economic foundation is good. As long as the market plays a leading role, adapts to historical trends, abides by market laws, respects enterprises and entrepreneurial spirit, promotes reform and opening up, and follows the road of market economy, China&#39;s economy will surely do well. How could it not do well? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current problems in China’s economy are not mainly caused by cyclical factors. I have always believed that as long as the proven successful experience of the past 45 years of reform and opening up is persisted and further improved, China&#39;s economy will continue to maintain a good trend, and China&#39;s capital market will have a foundation for growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安部：已缉捕电信网络诈骗集团重大头目和骨干387名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259195]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the morning of the 24th, the State Council Information Office held a series of press conferences on the theme of &quot;Authority Departments Start Talking&quot; According to the relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Public Security, since August this year, the number of telecom network fraud cases nationwide and the number of property losses caused have dropped by 24% and 20.5% respectively year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In accordance with the unified deployment of the Ministry of Public Security, local public security agencies have continued to strengthen their crackdowns and carried out in-depth special operations such as &quot;Cloud Sword&quot;, &quot;Card Break&quot;, &quot;Cut Off&quot; and &quot;Pull Out the Nail&quot;. As of the end of September this year, the arrests of telecommunications There are 387 major leaders and backbones of Internet fraud groups; jointly with the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate to supervise a number of major cases and publicly expose a number of typical cases; focusing on domestic crackdowns, we continue to organize and carry out regional battles, special projects, and cluster battles, and work closely with various departments , severely crack down on criminal gangs such as traffic promotion, transfer money laundering, and technology development, resolutely cut off the key chains of crime, and resolutely curb the high incidence of telecommunications network fraud crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Public Security insists on moving the border forward and putting prevention first, and adopts a variety of preventive measures to prevent the occurrence of cases to the greatest extent. Guide local public security agencies to establish hierarchical and classified early warning and dissuasion mechanisms, and promote the implementation of the &quot;Xiamen Experience&quot; nationwide. Since the beginning of this year, a total of 310 million early warning instructions have been pushed to various regions, and 130 million pieces of early warning information have been independently produced by various regions; in conjunction with the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the 12381 fraud early warning and dissuasion SMS system has been built, and a total of 640 million early warning SMS and flash messages have been sent; Together with the Cyberspace Administration of China, we built and promoted the National Anti-Fraud Center App, with a total of 15.785 million early warnings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Public Security and the Central Propaganda Department jointly launched the &quot;National Anti-Fraud in Action&quot; centralized publicity month activity with the theme of &quot;Don&#39;t ignore early warnings and dissuasion, pay attention to property safety&quot;. During this period, the National Anti-Fraud Center released the &quot;2023 Edition of the Telecommunications Network Fraud Prevention Brochure&quot;; together with relevant industry authorities, it urged financial institutions, telecom business operators, and Internet service providers to carry out in-depth anti-fraud propaganda for practitioners and service objects in the industry; jointly The China Association on Aging held a national anti-fraud and anti-fraud knowledge competition for the elderly; cooperated with the Ministry of Education to launch the &quot;anti-fraud publicity into campus&quot; activity; and cooperated with the China Film Group to organize public welfare screenings of outstanding anti-fraud films in rural areas and primary and secondary school campuses across the country, continuing to arouse nationwide publicity. A new upsurge in anti-fraud and the whole society’s anti-fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 15:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[情侣住酒店被偷拍勒索：应大力查办暗黑产业链丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259191]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A couple received an intimate video after staying in a hotel for a year. When they went to the hotel and took apart the chandelier, they found that the camera was still there, which shocked them. People are extremely frightened when they think about it carefully. If someone is secretly photographed while staying in a hotel, what responsibility should the hotel bear? Hidden photography has been banned for many times. How can we eradicate the industrial chain behind it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a recent report from Guangxi TV, Mr. Hu from Nanning recently received an intimate video of himself and his fiancée staying in a hotel a year ago. When he arrived at the hotel, he discovered that the two cameras hidden in the chandelier were still there. The hotel manager said that they were also victims. There was no abnormality in other rooms after checking, and they only wanted to refund the room fee. The report attracted a lot of attention online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;News about being secretly photographed while staying in a hotel appears frequently. Searching for &quot;hotel sneak shots&quot; on a certain search engine can yield tens of millions of related information. Recent news, in addition to the above mentioned, also appeared in Lianyungang, Jiangsu, Loudi, Hunan and other places. A few years ago, the person in charge of a hotel in Zhengzhou, Henan Province even claimed that 80% of hotels had secret cameras. In fact, hidden cameras are not only found in hotels, but also in fitting rooms of clothing stores, toilets in office buildings, and even in the toilets of high-speed trains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些隐藏的摄像头，严重侵犯了他人的隐私，毫无疑问是违法犯罪行为。如果是酒店私自安装了摄像头，酒店当然要承担责任。但如果是其他人在酒店不知情的情况下偷偷安装的，酒店需要承担责任吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的情况确实不少。据业内人士称，坏人可以伪装成客人住酒店，每次只要十几分钟就可以把摄像头装好，然后以各种理由换房间，一次就能偷装几个房间。在连云港酒店发现摄像头案件中，警方抓获的犯罪嫌疑人是无业人员，并非酒店员工。最高检2022年发布的一个指导性案例中，犯罪分子也是在多家酒店的客房内偷偷安装摄像头偷拍的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种情况下，难道真的像南宁那家酒店的经理所称，他们也是受害者，不需要对客人被侵害承担责任？当然不是，旅客入住酒店，当然是把酒店房间视为私密场所，对自己在房间里的隐私具有合理期待，酒店应该对客人的隐私尽到合理的保障义务。客人被偷拍，被侵犯隐私，与酒店没有尽到安全保障义务有脱不了的关系。而南宁这家酒店，一年多后摄像头还在，可见其多么疏于管理。出现偷拍事件，酒店除了要停业整顿，也要对客人进行赔偿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;酒店有义务保障客人的隐私。其实，现在市面上已经有专门针对针孔摄像头的便携式检测仪器，酒店只要给保洁或者保安人员配备一套，就可以在短时间内查出大多数隐藏的摄像头。这样做需要的成本并不高，关键是反偷拍要像打扫卫生一样，成为酒店行业标准，成为每家酒店都要做的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;酒店偷拍之所以屡禁不绝，还因为其背后有一条黑色的产业链。犯罪分子偷拍视频，并不是为了刺激，而是会把这些偷拍的视频放到暗网等非法网站去售卖。一些网站、社交账号打着“酒店偷拍”等旗号，吸引用户付费观看隐私视频。整个偷拍的黑色产业，每年可能有上千亿元规模。在前述最高检发布的指导案例中，犯罪分子就通过非法网站、即时通讯软件等发布信息贩卖偷拍的隐私视频。 2021年，辽宁警方也打掉了一条利用隐蔽摄像头在酒店偷拍、直播获利的黑色产业链。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了到暗网售卖，还有人利用拍到的隐私视频敲诈勒索。 2022年底，湖南娄底一名女子在酒店被偷拍后，就有人把视频发给她然后勒索钱财。这次广西南宁的胡先生收到偷拍视频，对方也很可能并不是好心提醒他被偷拍了，也有很大的可能是要对其敲诈勒索。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于偷拍行为必须加大打击力度。在各种通讯账号都实行实名制的当下，警方要找到犯罪分子应该并不太难。对于发信息敲诈勒索的，警方可以通过发信息的账号找到勒索者，然后顺藤摸瓜，查清勒索者是如何获得视频，以及客人的联系方式等隐私信息的，将整个链条都打掉，同时也可以查清酒店是否存在泄露客人隐私的问题。毕竟，就算犯罪分子偷偷安装摄像头，没有酒店的内鬼，也很难知道客人的联系方式，是没有办法敲诈勒索的。只找到偷拍摄像头的，警方也有手段找到安装者。连云港酒店的摄像头、天津某写字楼女厕的摄像头，警方都很快就抓到了犯罪嫌疑人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对猖獗的偷拍，一方面警方要加大对黑色产业链的打击力度。对偷拍偷录设备也要加强管理。现在网络上随处可以买到各种微型隐蔽摄像头，还有各种摄像头破解、漏洞利用等教学视频，这些都助长了偷拍的泛滥。酒店行业也应该制定标准，把反偷拍摄像头等纳入行业的日常管理中，尽最大可能保护客人的隐私安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“毛孩子”上幼儿园]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258991]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/V0LTOkR67vJedXXZb5clBZd8L6rjNgVAPLvRo1Tt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/V0LTOkR67vJedXXZb5clBZd8L6rjNgVAPLvRo1Tt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;两位“学员”参加幼儿园的敏捷性游戏课程&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;秋日的一个下午，三只不同种类的宠物狗在训犬师的指导下参与游戏，平衡板、滑板、数字识别、玩具分拣……这些适应性和益智类游戏是北京萌兽派宠物酒店（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以下简称“萌兽派”&lt;/span>;）开设的宠物幼儿园教学体系的一部分，此外还有游泳、嗅闻和脱敏等课程。幼儿园的托管时间是每天早八到晚八。除了上课，狗狗们还能享用营养配餐、午休、洗澡、毛发护理和按摩等服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/2wPb9QqtOnbVPZkOsdHUoZ5sjdlFX2Q1AjbzsXGP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/2wPb9QqtOnbVPZkOsdHUoZ5sjdlFX2Q1AjbzsXGP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“胖虎”今年两岁半。它的“家长”是一对95后夫妻，平时热爱旅游，每个月都会把“胖虎”送来宠物酒店寄养几天&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参加游戏课的三只狗依次进入教室，它们分别是小柴犬、贵宾犬和萨摩耶。课程开始，看到正在用相机拍摄的陌生人，三个学员马上给出了不同反馈：小柴犬专注于训犬师的口令；贵宾犬则一边不停狂吠一边试探着靠近陌生人，课程一度无法进行；萨摩耶也注意到了相机的存在，以一种友善的姿态试图靠近，当训犬师发出指令，它立即回到游戏中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/tO4JE0DuciA7OwPu0kt49VMpwuAlvYIgyGVyx3U4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/tO4JE0DuciA7OwPu0kt49VMpwuAlvYIgyGVyx3U4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“胖虎”参加幼儿园的益智类游戏课程&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/kZ21UuvWMsdCj28jPMXKyxiita4EsHe9PMhCctsW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/kZ21UuvWMsdCj28jPMXKyxiita4EsHe9PMhCctsW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“胖虎”在幼儿园体验萌兽影院&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“狗狗也有自己的性格，你看它们三只就截然不同，这跟体形没关系，首先是基因决定的，另外跟它的成长经历有关。贵宾犬警惕性非常强，它其实不是要攻击你，只不过是吓唬你——&#39;你别过来，不要伤害我，我很凶的，你听我叫得多厉害&#39;，但其实这恰恰反映出它的胆小和敏感。其他两只都能专注在自己的事情上，这说明它们社会化做得比较好，能规范自己的行为，不去影响别人，面对新鲜事物时表现得非常自信和勇敢。”萌兽派创始人李晨分析着学员们的表现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萌兽派开设幼儿园将近五年，中间经历了新冠疫情，业务几乎停滞。从2023年年初开始，李晨发现宠物寄养和参加幼儿园的需求出现了“井喷式的爆发”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/FC6KETtmuncBPDSPDhxTSAhX45uo5giBOXqwQhFk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/FC6KETtmuncBPDSPDhxTSAhX45uo5giBOXqwQhFk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;王姐和9岁的“咖啡豆”在萌兽派。今年是咖啡豆来幼儿园的第五年&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“年轻的养宠群体对幼儿园的接受度突然高了起来。他们不会以牺牲自己的生活方式（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;社交、出差、旅行等&lt;/span>;）为代价去养狗——我有我的生活，你有你的生活。我尽我所能让你的生活丰富多彩，送你去上学，让你每一天都过得充实快乐，并不需要每天只是在家等我。我在外出的时候也会很坦然，不用心怀愧疚，总觉得狗这一辈子只有一件事情，就是在家等我。”李晨认为随着社会的进步和养宠群体思想的变化，现在宠物主们关注的不再是自己的宠物吃的是不是进口狗粮，还会关注宠物的心理健康——你今天是不是快乐。狗狗也需要有自己的精神世界。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;幼儿园的口号是“让狗做回狗”，在很多课程的设置上通过训练帮助它们恢复作为动物的本能，比如嗅闻、捕猎和游泳，增强狗狗的信心和体能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/u4ADV0FJUMQxzOuo358BIoMpSQ2kBW2owRMc26Xs.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/u4ADV0FJUMQxzOuo358BIoMpSQ2kBW2owRMc26Xs.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;三三妈带着她收养的4只老年犬到萌兽派参加生日会&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据李晨介绍，目前幼儿园的家长以80后和90后为主，他们并非都是家境优渥的中产或白领，但很舍得给“毛孩子”花钱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不只是年轻人，有些老年人也不惜重金为“毛孩子”打造健康舒适的生活，李晨称之为“隔代亲”。她接待过一对退休夫妇，每年定期要去外地探望女儿，离京的两三个月，他们就把领养的两只“串串儿”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;杂交品种的狗&lt;/span>;）放到李晨这里。“在他们眼里，宠物跟家人是一样的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/HIhqM5okdFH3w15o1XUrPF20x55vH5IW5PIUdth0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/HIhqM5okdFH3w15o1XUrPF20x55vH5IW5PIUdth0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;3只哈士奇在餐厅等候&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;咖啡豆是一只泰迪犬，今年9岁。王姐记得第一次上完幼儿园，店员把它送下来，转身走了，咖啡豆还追着人家跑。“狗的反应特别真实，从那时起我就知道他们肯定对豆豆好。”今年是咖啡豆来幼儿园的第五年，从最初谁也不能碰，见人就狂吠，转变成现在时常扮可爱博得周围人的关注。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王姐和丈夫是丁克族，她把咖啡豆“当作儿子养”，从不吝惜在它身上花钱。每逢店里搞活动，王姐都想着再续点费。李晨看到她卡上充足的余额，总劝她要理性消费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小程之前爱旅游和买包，现在她把这些钱存下来都花在九万身上，每月大概四五千。每周带九万出去玩，让小程从一个宅女变成了熟知宠物友好场所的户外达人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ECkm98Du2wPcFJFTgUG11UqIWYNvulU7VsHxuvOQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ECkm98Du2wPcFJFTgUG11UqIWYNvulU7VsHxuvOQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;3岁的“十五”享用宠物生日蛋糕&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三年前，小程的儿子出生，她觉得养狗和养孩子各有各的好，但养孩子肯定更辛苦，而九万带给她的只有开心快乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于网上流传的一些不文明养犬的新闻，小程认为不应该是养狗与不养狗的对立，而是文明养狗与不文明养狗的对立。“养狗的人首先要做好自己：牵绳、捡屎、错峰遛狗、避让行人——尤其是老人和小孩。我也理解有些人天生就怕狗，那就互相离得远点，多等一趟电梯的事，大家相互理解。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/q84SEeNxwenqXKYtBpLZjacHK3QJahHbIPpIorxD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/q84SEeNxwenqXKYtBpLZjacHK3QJahHbIPpIorxD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“奶瓶儿”（上）游完泳，在宠物餐厅享用加餐。三年多前，“奶瓶儿”被现在的主人从路上捡回了家&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在萌兽派创建之初，李晨把二层一个将近300平米的空间设计成了视听室，满足主人和狗狗一起看电影的需求，对会员免费开放。这个规划当时受到一些股东的质疑，他们认为从收益率考虑，这是一种浪费。但李晨有自己的想法，虽然有一些宠物主题的电影会做包场，但影院里的音响都是给人设计的，不适合狗狗的听觉系统。“我希望能给主人和宠物提供一种多元化的选择，哪怕是满足一些非常小众的需求，但在别的地方没有办法体验得到。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fhNiWp9f8o5hBGPiBdk2Dwh4lEhelsNP5xoThX4Q.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fhNiWp9f8o5hBGPiBdk2Dwh4lEhelsNP5xoThX4Q.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这只哈士奇正在做惊吓测试——筛选、淘汰容易对跑动、尖叫、过度热情的人有过度害怕、攻击或过度兴奋问题的狗狗。这个测试模拟了治疗犬在服务场所可能遇到的情景，最大化地减少安全隐患。通过测评的狗狗经过培训，有机会上门服务特殊人群（老人、孤独症儿童等）&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;六年来，李晨身边一直能听到一些争议，主要是质疑她把相对高端和小众的服务当作噱头，形式大于内容。“其实我们大多数的服务是非常刚需的，有一些可能相对超前一点，但它是科学的，我相信也符合未来的发展趋势。宠物服务面对的是不同客户的需求，因此要提供不同的选择，没有一个统一的标准答案，也不需要有。”李晨说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年新冠疫情期间，萌兽派协助北京朝阳区政府做宠物集中转运，第一时间将店内改成宠物方舱，缓解了疫情期间的宠物安置问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/CK4QvzWosGyhf8RGYpIHZLlOhsWpBZwUbL1xIkpH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/CK4QvzWosGyhf8RGYpIHZLlOhsWpBZwUbL1xIkpH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“九万”在幼儿园上游泳课&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李晨对南新园社区那次大规模转运记忆犹新，120多只宠物，大部分是狗，也有猫、兔子、乌龟和小鸡等，一车车地往回拉，转运了整整两天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照常规操作，接寄养是要对宠物进行测评的：年龄、基础病、有没有攻击性……但那次没得选，时间紧迫，主人在现场把自己的联系方式和宠物基本信息写在一张纸条上，工作人员把纸条和宠物放在一起拍张照片，就算完成了登记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3PlP1CX4XisMazaYlQYQd2NIRd0igmjLFJGTAAV9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/3PlP1CX4XisMazaYlQYQd2NIRd0igmjLFJGTAAV9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;萌兽派宠物酒店一层的寄养房间都带有独立的院子。为避免分离焦虑，有些主人会带上宠物在家的玩具或坐垫帮它们尽快适应新环境&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到店里，李晨和店员再对不同类别的宠物分区管理，尽可能给主人们发去宠物的最新照片和视频，安抚他们的情绪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“刚开始并没有建立信任，有的主人看到视频说，虽然长得像，但从神情能认出来，这不是我的狗。没关系，我们给他再拍10个视频，让他再找一找感觉或者表情，判断是不是自己的狗。头三天我们每天都会接到主人们的电话，有质问的、有痛哭的、有谩骂的。到第四天大家才开始相信——你们真把我的狗安置在你那了，于是开始给我们网购食品和物资，以表谢意。”这次经历让李晨对人性有了更深的体察和认知。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/oxBwRwuqqXdMtN0VLrKbh46vWylDWBWByWq02nwR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/oxBwRwuqqXdMtN0VLrKbh46vWylDWBWByWq02nwR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;幼儿园的照片墙&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者梁辰/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;隔离期满，这120多只宠物在逐一做过核酸后，完好地回到各自的主人身边。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;做宠物酒店以来，李晨阅狗无数，也见证了很多感人的故事：游泳课上，本来狗狗不敢下水，当主人“掉进”水池，它却奋不顾身地跳水相救；家有孕妇或小孩的，遛狗时狗狗宁可自己不上厕所，也要确保主人在自己的视线内，不让陌生人靠近……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[烈犬伤童事件后，“失焦”的多地捕狗风波]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259173]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;一位广州居民在遛狗，路边有标语“遛狗牵狗绳，文明不掉链”。图文无关。视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5aa90d6adb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/5aa90d6adb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255050&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;一位广州居民在遛狗，路边有标语“遛狗牵狗绳，文明不掉链”。图文无关。视觉中国图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可不能说我们打狗，我们真没打过。”2023年10月20日，说起近期捕狗舆论，张勇有些紧张，特别强调他们是文明执法，全程都用执法记录仪记录，并进行台账登记。“得保证都是活的，不能有损伤。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位呼和浩特市赛罕区城市综合执法局宣传股股长担心的舆论，是罗威纳犬咬伤崇州4岁女童事件带来的连锁反应。一个烈犬咬人的视频席卷全网，进而在多地出现捕狗行动，网传有小区物业成立“打狗小队”，保安带着棍棒、捕网巡查；安徽亳州、河南郑州、江苏泰兴、山东青岛等地的城管部门陆续发布捕捉流浪狗的视频，网友们开始激烈讨论是否应当扑杀流浪狗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;争议案例也随之出现。一只生活在重庆对外经贸学院的流浪狗，被保安驱赶致死。10月20日该校通报称，有学生在归寝途中被流浪狗追赶，学校保安在驱赶中存在不当行为，已对涉事保安作停职处理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者发现，在此次事件后，多地均针对无主犬、烈性犬、不戴牵引绳的行为进行专项整治。但与此同时，各类谣言也正在网络平台不断流传。其实，在不少地方，捕捉流浪狗都是常态化开展的一项工作，抓捕后的流浪狗将送到流浪动物救助中心收容，不会进行打杀。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;物业该负什么责任&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;罗威纳犬咬人事件后，女童所住的恒大西辰绿洲小区多处挂上标语：“文明遛狗牵好绳，管住嘴巴勿伤人”“牵紧&#39;文明绳&#39;，做养犬文明人”……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月20日，住在受害女童楼上的一位妈妈告诉南方周末记者，女童被咬伤的当天，愤怒的业主便已在业主群里议论：“出这么大事，保安在哪？”“为什么外来的狗进来都不知道”。压力之下，物业开始每天巡逻，捕捉没有拴绳的狗。这些工作会一一发到群里，向业主报告，附上抓捕视频和照片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种紧张氛围很快传染到了其他小区。10月17日，媒体报道成都市府河御景小区成立“打狗小队”，视频中保安带着棍棒、捕网巡查，物业工作人员表示：“凡是流浪狗，没人管的，没套绳的，整个小区整改”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月18日下午，成都市三都汇朝外小区则以物业的名义挂上了“小区将对未拴绳的猫犬进行捕杀”的横幅。“捕杀”二字一下引起小区宠物主的担忧和指责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据该小区住户李明了解，“捕杀”的想法其实出自小区的妈妈群。娃妈们出于担忧，在群里提议“流浪犬只处理办法：首先是尽可能地打死或捕捉，其次是驱离小区再报警通知社区”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但反对扑杀的一方在18日晚上接连拨打政务服务便民热线12345投诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;次日早上，物业出面表示横幅言辞不当，已经撤下。“物业现在已经不敢接电话了，街道不让他们强行扑杀，早上警告了他们。”李明说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者多次拨打该小区物业及所在街道办电话，均未接通。20日，成都市住建局物业事务服务中心回复媒体称，该中心没接到通知称有小区成立打狗队。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市京都律师事务所律师常莎曾接触过狗伤人案件，她认为，小区物业对业主具有安全保障的义务，因此小区内出现无主狗，物业要承担驱离或管理责任，否则要为流浪狗伤人承担过错责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是另一方面，物业公司不具有执法权，因此对于有主人的狗，物业不能对其采取强制的管理措施，比如直接抓捕。非紧急情况下，物业只能采取劝说或者交给有执法权的城管、公安处理。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;多地整治，谣言同行&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在成都小区业主争议扑杀流浪狗与否的18日晚间，河南省郑州市金水区城管部门针对未拴绳养狗行为连夜执法，并进行了直播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;捕狗争论开始波及全国多地，形成执法行动。在郑州这次直播中，一位牵着法国斗牛犬的年轻人被追着跑了老远。根据直播录像，尽管城管人员一再强调不会伤害狗，只是带回去登记调查，但这位年轻人在一番交涉未果后，又尝试抱着黑狗逃跑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这段视频成为此次网络风波的又一传播点。同样在郑州养法斗的市民小真告诉南方周末记者，法斗在郑州的确是禁养的，平常不能办狗证，但执法并不严，“以前偶尔会查的”。同时，全国许多城市允许法斗饲养，包括北京、上海、西安、大连、哈尔滨、南京、杭州、长沙等。得知前述年轻人需要缴纳罚款5000元，法斗爱好者群里纷纷向其发红包，说要帮他把狗要回来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;武汉市小动物保护协会会长杜帆介绍，当下城市的犬类管理主要依据各地自行制定的条例，这样的行政管理条例效力不高，因此很多人不办狗证，也不按规定养狗。（详见&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/258846&quot;>;《多专家谈罗威纳犬咬伤女童：“关键在管理人，其次才是管理狗”》&lt;/a>;）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，城市里犬只管理的职权划分并不清晰，目前大部分城市由公安主管，有的归城管主管，而犬只管理还涉及工商、食品安全、治安管理等多个部门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在罗威纳犬伤童事件后，多地发布专项管理行动，安徽亳州、江苏泰兴、河南沈丘、四川射洪等地均针对无主犬、烈性犬、不戴牵引绳的行为进行专项整治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在其中，谣言与事实夹杂。南方周末记者发现，呼吁不要捕杀流浪狗的视频中，时常出现数十只狗的尸体照、被摔死画面等，但都没有时间标注，仅从画面背景看，公交车及建筑物应该是数年以前的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微博热议话题“小狗不觉得自己是在流浪”中，许多网民将一张被捕后仍在咧嘴“微笑”的小狗照片认做是重庆对外经贸学院涉事黄狗，配文“被抓时还在笑，它以为它要有家了”，并以此表示哀悼。但原图作者辟谣称微笑小狗拍摄于4月，与重庆的并非同一只狗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有些失焦了。”江苏省动物学会理事周威发现，随着事态发展，网友讨论逐渐变成爱狗还是不爱狗、扑杀还是不扑杀这样的对立问题，并未深入细节讨论。比如，许多视频标题里说“捕杀”流浪狗，但目前大部分视频仅仅呈现了“捕捉”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;城管常态化工作&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者通过检索发现，许多捕狗视频是由各地城管、公安的官方账号发布，如青岛市西海岸新区综合行政执法局便连续发布3条视频，介绍捕捉流浪狗是其常态化开展的一项工作，抓捕后的流浪狗将送到流浪动物救助中心收容，不会进行打杀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因发放牵狗绳、狗嘴套而引发关注，被网友认为文明执法范例的四川省射洪市综合行政执法局则向南方周末记者表示，他们自2021年设置犬只管理办公室，配备专业的捉狗设备及车辆，日常有5个工作人员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在呼和浩特市赛罕区，据城市综合执法局介绍，该局从2020年接手流浪狗捕捉工作，仅在2023年就接到1100多条相关的举报信息，已捕捉流浪狗三百多只，举报内容大都为犬吠扰民，尤其是凌晨及早上。该局宣传股股长张勇称，队员接到举报电话，就得及时与当事人联系，处置完毕后需要回复对方，如果逮不住，一周之内队员至少还得去3次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;听起来这并不是容易的工作。张勇称，他们为此专门制定长效机制，分为白班和晚班进行值班，“机动中队参与捕狗的有38人”。他们要巡查赛罕区管辖的1025平方公里，而当狗翻越栏杆、进入树丛，执法人员很难追上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更重要的是，流浪狗嗅觉灵敏，常年装流浪狗的执法车辆往一个地方一停，“这块就不会有狗出来了”。张勇说，他们曾有队员开着自己的车转悠时看到流浪狗，打电话叫来执法车，车辆还没到，流浪狗便开始躁动，“它能闻到车上的味道”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赛罕区每位捕狗队员都被狗咬过，还有的在抓狗过程中摔断腿。他们采用的工具是捞网，不同大小的狗采用不同型号的捞网，最大的要用拇指粗细的纤维绳网，“它们牙口很好，细的绳子一口咬断”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四川省射洪市综合行政执法局、青岛西海岸新区综合执法管理局均回复南方周末记者称，用来捕狗的工具主要为捞网。在网上流传的捕狗视频中，执法人员大都采用捞网，仅有一则出现车牌号为浙江台州的捕狗视频采用弯状夹钳。周威认为捞网是目前捕狗中比较合适的工具，本身质地较软，能困住犬只又不会带来太大伤害。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张勇称，流浪狗被捕后将送往公安部门管理的留检所收养，留检所在对狗进行检查后，交给城管队员回执单，上面会清楚写明接收数量和状况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者致电呼和浩特市公安局犬类留检所，对方回复称，该所建有50亩的犬舍，目前能将接收的流浪猫狗养至自然死亡。此外，该所对外开放领养，可以在开放日前往参观、领养或捐赠物资。至于目前留检所的流浪猫狗数量，该工作人员说暂时无法提供详细数据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;位于四川射洪的流浪毛孩子菩提护生园，则是一家民间运营的流浪猫狗基地，在深山里包下一块山头，分区域喂养流浪猫狗。2021年，该基地开始接收城管部门捕捉的流浪猫狗，每年20-30只，“零零星星地送过来，都是被投诉扰民以后被抓的。”该基地负责人任女士介绍，城管部门提供部分狗粮费用，猫狗送达之前会提前做好传染病检查，有伤病的则先到宠物医院医治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任女士说，射洪自10月20日起开展捕捉流浪猫狗的专项行动，仅一天便送来11只流浪狗。她有点担心短时间送来的猫狗太多，基地无法负荷。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;更精细、专业、科学&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月20日，郑州被抓的法斗已被带回老家领养，而郑州城管对媒体称该案还在走流程，罚款还未确定。关于法斗为何禁养的话题却在养狗圈里热烈地讨论，家养法斗多年的毛静从中看到城市在养狗方面的管理问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毛静称，上海的禁养名单中没有明确标注法斗，但法斗长期被视作斗牛犬的一种，在上海各区面临不同的管理办法。2014年她养第一只法斗，当时在杨浦区四平街道顺利办理犬证；2016年，毛静准备养第二只法斗，在同一区的江浦街道办理犬证时被驳回，毛静打电话申诉后才得以通过，“办理人员不太了解这个犬种”。2019年上海表示全市允许养法斗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在郑州法斗事件后，她特意对比了郑州和上海的禁养犬名单，发现上海明确禁养英国斗牛犬，但不禁养法斗；而郑州明确禁养法斗，但不禁养英斗。毛静说两种狗的体型、烈性不一样，相较之下英斗体型能长到60-80斤，“这样即使不咬人，撞人一下可能也比较严重”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们国内其实没有通行的犬类标准认定。”周威说，在早期引进国外犬种时，可能存在对犬种的习性认知不高或者翻译问题。“其中体现管理滞后性。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国的宠物行业在十余年里跨越式发展，人与动物如何在城市共处的问题不断凸显。《2021年中国宠物行业白皮书》显示，2021年全国城镇宠物狗和宠物猫总数超过1.12亿只。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周威认为，目前在犬类管理方面，需要一套从源头开始，更为精细化、专业科学化的管理机制，比如在繁殖时就应该注意其品种基因以及如何训练的问题，而现在上游繁育阶段缺乏监管，到了养宠阶段才开始卡紧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杜帆也持类似观点，他认为许多狗伤人事件可以追溯至源头：“为何被禁养的烈性犬仍然可以在市面上贩卖？”由此他建议从犬只出生到贩卖、饲养建立系列的监管机制，厘清部门责任主体和管理权责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周威则建议，当下破题可以从科普教育开始，例如给校园、物业提供专业的培训服务：如何应对小区内的烈犬，如何正确地安置和捕捉；可以给养狗人提供培训：如何科学认识及管束所养的宠物犬，等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杜帆所在的武汉市小动物协会与当地公安部门达成合作，每月25日左右从留检所选择部分被捕捉的流浪狗向社会开放领养，呼吁“以领养代替购买”。杜帆说此前的两次领养活动举办顺利，全部留检狗狗被领养成功，“目前在准备第三次”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末记者高伊琛对本文亦有贡献，文中李明、毛静为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中美经济工作组举行第一次会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259175]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-24 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to He Lifeng, Vice Premier of the State Council and Chinese leader of China-US Economic and Trade, and Janet. Following the consensus reached by Yellen during her talks in Beijing in July, the China-US Economic Working Group held its first meeting via video on October 24. The meeting was chaired by officials at the deputy ministerial level of finance from the two countries. The two sides had in-depth, candid and constructive communication on issues such as the macroeconomic situation and policies of the two countries and the world, bilateral economic relations, and cooperation in responding to global challenges. China expressed its concerns. Both parties will continue to maintain communication. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>