<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[山西永聚煤业发生火灾，已致11人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260696]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:25:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yongju Coal Industry Joint Construction in Lishi District, Luliang City, Shanxi Province A fire broke out in the building around 6:50 a.m. today (16th). As of press time, 11 people have been confirmed dead, and the specific casualties are still being counted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to on-site information, the building on fire has 4 floors. A total of 63 people have been evacuated so far, 51 of whom were sent to Luliang First People&#39;s Hospital for treatment. Rescue is still in progress and the cause of the fire is under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑猩猩没有“祖母假说”模式？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260599]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When talking about chimpanzees, our close relatives, we cannot fail to mention British biologists, animal behaviorists and famous animal conservationists. Jane Goodall is a person who studied chimpanzees, but the “grandmother hypothesis” in this article is not based on Goodall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The documentary film &quot;The Legendary Life of Jane Goodall&quot; shot by the BBC and Goodall&#39;s book &quot;The Book of Hope: Jane Goodall on Human Survival, Future and Action&quot; give people a deeper understanding of Learn about chimpanzees and how they live like humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his 38 years of living with chimpanzees, Goodall discovered that chimpanzees can use tools (putting plant stems into ant nests to detect, using tree sticks to reach into the water to retrieve food), and they can also Making tools (removing leaves from plant stems) breaks the long-held belief that only humans can make tools. At the same time, chimpanzees will also form teams to hunt other small mammals, and wars will occur between different groups of chimpanzees, and weapons will be used in the battles. There are also some chimpanzees that attack and kill their own kind, sometimes just for fun. Chimpanzee society also has a strict hierarchical system. Each chimpanzee has its own status in society. Their overt and covert fights for social status are no less than that of humans. These findings also break the previous belief that war and cannibalism are uniquely human behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in addition to Goodall, other researchers have studied chimpanzees and found that chimpanzees also have a &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model similar to humans, but this model in chimpanzees is much weaker. The &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; means that healthy and surviving grandmothers and grandfathers can help take care of their grandchildren, increase their survival rate, and thus help their children have more children. This health effect, in turn, ensures the inheritance of your grandmother’s longevity genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the University of California, Santa Barbara, compared three groups of chimpanzees, hunter-gatherers, and horticultural producers and found that people’s production contributions in old age also exist, and are far greater. Higher than chimpanzees. Chimpanzees can have a 20% food or material surplus in their gathering and production capacity at age 30, 7% at age 40, and only 2% at age 50. But hunter-gatherers have a production surplus of 66% at age 30, 45% at age 40, and 24% at age 50. A horticultural producer&#39;s production surplus is 64% at age 30, 40% at age 40, and 21% at age 50. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this comparison, we can know that after chimpanzees enter old age, their production capacity drops significantly, and their ability to help their families and grandchildren also drops off a cliff. Therefore, even if chimpanzees have the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model, its effect is limited. Not big. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, a new study completely rejects the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model in chimpanzees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A team composed of research institutions such as Arizona State University in the United States, the University of California, Los Angeles, and the Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology in Germany studied the Ngo in Kibale National Park in western Uganda. A 20-year study of the wild chimpanzee community in Ngogo found that female chimpanzees in the community will survive menopause and childbirth, but they will not help their daughters raise grandchildren when they enter old age, nor will they live in nearby. Therefore, chimpanzees do not have a social system supported by grandparents, that is, there is no &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model. But Ngogo&#39;s female chimpanzees still live beyond their reproductive years and beyond, even to old age alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no survival problem in old age for chimpanzees in captivity because humans will provide them with good food, nutrition and medical care. However, chimpanzees in the wild will not be so lucky. Survival mode is more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To study the lifestyle and survival patterns of chimpanzees in the wild, researchers from the joint research team studied 185 female chimpanzees from group statistics collected from 1995 to 2016. Mortality and fertility rates, the proportion of time the observed female chimpanzees spent in sterilization as adults was calculated, and hormone levels were measured in urine samples from 66 female chimpanzees. The female chimpanzees varied in reproductive and sterilization status, survival and age, ranging from 14 to 67 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This research process was very arduous, lasting decades and thousands of hours of fieldwork in Ngogo before collecting chimpanzee urine samples to study menopausal hormone levels. . Hormone studies in chimpanzee urine are similar to those in humans, monitoring changes in levels of follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) and luteinizing hormone (LH), as well as ovarian steroid hormones including estrogen and progesterone. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These hormonal changes can determine whether chimpanzees have entered menopause. The estrogen levels of human menopausal women are below 100pmol/L, and the progesterone levels are below 2.2nmol/L. By comparing them with female chimpanzees, we can know whether they are menopausal and have entered menopause (sterilization state). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers found that, like other groups of chimpanzees and humans, the chimpanzees they studied lost fertility after age 30 and became infertile after age 50. Meanwhile, some data collected on hormone levels in chimpanzees show that menopause in Ngogo female chimpanzees is similar to that in humans, starting around age 50. Female chimpanzees reach adulthood at the age of 14, and spend about one-fifth of their adult life in the sterilization period, which is about half of the sterilization period of humans. That is, the old age of chimpanzees after entering menopause is only half of that of humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Menopause for chimpanzees means the beginning of old age, but Ngogo female chimpanzees can live over 50 years old even if they do not take care of their grandchildren and do not live with their children. Chimpanzees are prone to death from diseases originating from humans and have little natural immunity to these diseases, so living over 50 years is considered a long life, and living to 67 years is considered a long life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can Ngogo&#39;s chimpanzees survive into old age without the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model? The answer suggested by the study is that their post-neuter lifespan may be a temporary response to extremely favorable ecological conditions, as the group enjoys a stable and abundant food supply and they are isolated from human-induced stress. Survive longer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some researchers such as primatologist Susan Alberts of Duke University in the United States doubt this result because not all chimpanzees will go through menopause. Alberts believes that in most chimpanzee populations outside the Ngogo group, adult females live to be around 30 years old because they are stressed by predators, disease or other factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Alberts admitted that the study&#39;s results were so solid that she couldn&#39;t refute them. But she believes the next step should be to conduct similar long-term studies in larger populations of wild chimpanzees to determine whether Ngogo chimpanzees are unique in that they survive longer beyond their reproductive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[螺蛳粉疯狂布局线下门店，能否成为下一个兰州拉面？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260351]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since this year, snail noodle restaurant stores have grown rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xiao Lu, a netizen who lives in Guangzhou, said that several snail noodle stores have recently opened in the business district near her home, many of which are chain stores of a certain snail noodle brand. ——This has aroused the curiosity of many netizens: Has snail noodles also begun to focus on offline stores? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the characteristics of &quot;smells bad, tastes delicious, and is very popular&quot;, snail noodles have become a popular Internet celebrity food in just a few years. The sales volume of the channel remains high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, compared with its popularity online, the offline development of snail noodles has obvious shortcomings. What kind of distinction does the online and offline development of snail noodles show? How can snail noodles achieve offline breakthrough? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258356&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Hot online sales&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Snail noodles originated from the Liuzhou Night Market in the 1970s. It gradually became popular in the 1980s, but it was mainly limited to the local area, and then slowly spread to all of Guangxi and the neighboring Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2012, &quot;A Bite of China&quot; brought snail fans more into the public eye, but for people outside the Guangdong and Guangxi regions, it is still only As the name suggests, Luosifeng’s offline stores have not expanded too much to other provinces, and there are no online sales channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2014, Liuzhou’s first prepackaged snail noodle company was registered, and industrially produced bagged snail noodle appeared. At the beginning of 2015, the Liuzhou Municipal Government proposed the development concept of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; of Liuzhou&#39;s snail noodles, and determined the road for Liuzhou&#39;s snail noodles industry to be packaged and industrialized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2016 is the first year of live broadcasting. Luosi fans have keenly grasped the trend of the times and jumped on the &quot;Internet +&quot; short video and live broadcast express. The characteristics of &quot;smellful and smelly&quot; are quite contagious and quickly spread out of the circle through online channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2019, the industry output value of Liuzhou&#39;s bagged snail noodles exceeded 6 billion yuan. The impact of the epidemic, the rise of the &quot;stay-at-home economy&quot;, and the booming live-streaming of goods have boosted the online popularity of snail noodles. In 2020, the annual output value of bagged snail noodles exceeded 10 billion. In 2022, the sales revenue of the entire industry chain of Liuzhou snail noodles will be 60.07 billion yuan, and the sales revenue of bagged snail noodles will be 18.18 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Naturally, the online sales of snail noodles account for half of the total. iiMedia Research’s research data shows that among the channels through which Chinese snail noodle consumers purchase products, online shopping malls rank first with a proportion of 78.70%. Other data show that in 2022, 113 million snail noodle packages were sent through express delivery channels, becoming the first single product in Guangxi with an annual delivery volume exceeding 100 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The popularity of snail noodles online is not only due to its close integration with &quot;Internet +&quot;, but also because it fits the &quot;fast food life&quot; of this generation of young people. The characteristics of the food require that the food should not only be convenient and efficient, but also sufficient and delicious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Other instant noodles have few ingredients. Snail noodles are rich in ingredients, including yuba, pickled bamboo shoots, pickled beans, fungus, peanuts, dried radish and other common accessories. Bao snail rice noodles have everything, and they are more attractive to young people’s stomachs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258357&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Offline stores have shortcomings&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, compared with the popularity of online stores, offline stores of snail noodles have obvious shortcomings. plate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, there are now more than 40,000 offline stores of snail noodles. Compared with the approximately 500,000 offline stores of Lanzhou Ramen, It&#39;s like a small witch can see a big witch. Not to mention, the annual sales of Lanzhou Ramen are roughly estimated to exceed 400 billion yuan, which is several times that of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, relevant data shows that the average offline catering chain rate of snail noodles is only 15%, compared with 45% for tea drinks. Coffee is 55%, which shows that there is no strong enough brand of snail noodles to go offline, and the risk of &quot;having a category but not a brand&quot; has intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only that, there are also some worrying aspects regarding the existing offline stores of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First, the offline stores of snail noodles are mainly concentrated in Guangxi and Guangdong, and the national penetration rate is still relatively low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, iiMedia Consulting data shows that from 2020 to February 2023, most of the new snail noodle companies are located in Guangdong and Guangxi, and the proportion of snail noodle companies in Guangxi is as high as 21.63% and 21.21% of snail noodle companies are located in Guangdong Province. This is much weaker than the national radiation intensity of Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, due to the low chain rate, many offline snail noodle stores are small &quot;mom-and-pop&quot;-style workshops with varying tastes and quality, and individual stores are hygienic. The worrying situation has lowered consumers’ trust in offline stores of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some time ago, rumors spread widely that &quot;there were many mice jumping up and down in the back kitchen of a snail noodle shop in Chongqing.&quot; Although the Municipal Supervision Bureau of Jiulongpo District, Chongqing made a report stating that law enforcement officers did an on-site inspection and found no traces of rats in the snail noodle shop; the video was taken in March this year, because the decoration of the shop next door damaged the flue outlet of the shop, causing rats to enter After discovering the situation in the back kitchen, the person in charge of the store immediately carried out disinfection and repairs and rectifications in the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Such rumors have done great harm to the offline stores of Luosi Fen, and also reflect the public&#39;s concerns about food safety issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thirdly, offline snail noodles stores only offer a single variety of food, and relying solely on snail noodles will limit the development of offline stores. For example, Lanzhou Ramen Shop not only offers ramen noodles, but also Northwest-style pasta products such as rice bowls, steamed buns, and cold noodles; Shaxian snacks include mixed noodles, steamed dumplings, flat dishes, duck leg rice, and other choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258355&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;The snail noodles&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;stand out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, compared with the offline stores of Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian Snacks, Sloan noodles are blooming everywhere, and offline stores of snail noodles still have broad room for expansion, but this does not mean that snail noodles should &quot;underestimate themselves&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, compared with Lanzhou Ramen, the development route of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; of snail noodles is earlier and more mature. There are many ramen noodle restaurants in Lanzhou, but they are also faced with the embarrassment of &quot;having categories but not brands&quot;. This is a shortcoming that Lanzhou ramen is now making great efforts to make up for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To successfully break through, snail powder offline stores must, on the one hand, give full play to the advantages of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; and transform the current few stores into The snail noodle brand continues to grow bigger and stronger, and the chain layout is accelerated. It is necessary to establish both the category and the brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, efforts should be made to industrialize the supply chain and build a professional, platform-based supply chain service provider to fill the gap in the snail noodle supply chain business. Blank, so that even small workshop-style snail noodle stores can obtain stable quality snail noodle raw materials, so that consumers can taste snail noodle with stable taste and stabilize the reputation of offline snail noodle stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Third, as a regional delicacy, if snail noodles want to conquer the stomachs of people across the country, in addition to making authentic snail noodles, we also need to enrich the line. The gourmet food category in the lower store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​way is to focus on snail noodles but also sell other local delicacies from Liuzhou and even Guangxi to enrich consumers&#39; choice space, such as some from Liuzhou Local delicacies, such as Yong Tau Foo Pao, Niu Xianzi, Yun Pian Cake, Miao Sour Pork, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another way is to combine it with local cuisine and move toward integration, launching cross-category meals, stir-fries, soups, etc. This kind of integration poses a very big challenge to the management of chain brands, which must not only ensure standardization, but also successfully &quot;do as the Romans do.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although snail noodles have fully opened up the online space, if snail noodles want to continue to break through the upper limit of the industry, they must walk both online and offline. Luosifen offline stores are accelerating the layout. Whether it can create miracles like online stores is worth waiting to see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么年轻人不愿意生孩子？社会学家山田昌弘谈日本低生育困境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260643]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6Ignwi5oPp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1039&quot; height=&quot;1559&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6I gnwi5oPp. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Japanese sociologist Yamada Masahiro, professor at Chuo University, specializes in family sociology and emotional society Xuexue, etc., are the authors of &quot;Society with a Few Births&quot;, &quot;The Era of Marriage&quot;, &quot;The Low-Birth Trap&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Masahiro Yamada, a professor at Chuo University in Japan, has been deeply involved in the field of family sociology for many years. Before high school, he once wanted to be a mathematician, but &quot;because I don&#39;t have a family of my own, I decided to explore what family love is&quot; and since then entered the &quot;world of studying messy families.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When teaching in school, he used a lot of family materials to tell the origin, current situation and whereabouts of modern Japanese families. The seminars he held with students were on cutting-edge topics and discussed issues such as: To what extent do people need to &quot;rent friends&quot; when they are lonely? Does &quot;cohabiting partnership marriage&quot; (note: only cohabitation without marriage) explore another possibility beyond the current marriage system? There are more and more single young people in Japan. Where can their emotional needs for intimacy be met? He finally found some answers in cabaret clubs (note: places that provide singing and dancing performances), real or virtual idols, and pets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the book &quot;The Low Fertility Trap&quot;, Masahiro Yamada tries to answer a question: Why are young people in Japan reluctant to have children in recent years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Low fertility rate has always been a dark cloud lingering over Japanese society. Since 1989, Japan&#39;s fertility rate has continued to be sluggish, with the total fertility rate remaining below 1.6 for more than 30 years. In 2022, it reached a historical low of 1.26. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Since 1989, Japan&#39;s fertility rate has continued to be sluggish, with the total fertility rate below 1.6 for more than 30 years, and it reached a historical low of 1.26 in 2022 . The picture shows a still from the Japanese drama &quot;Obstetrician Kotori&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past thirty years, Japanese society has tried to solve this &quot;stubborn disease&quot;, but with little success. Yamada Masahiro was a member of the Committee on Countermeasures against Birthrate Reduction. Once, a committee member proposed holding a publicity campaign titled &quot;Parenting is Wonderful&quot; to increase the public&#39;s enthusiasm for childbirth. &quot;Many insightful people and policy leaders in Japanese society have ignored for a long time two important factors directly related to the cause of Japan&#39;s declining birthrate, namely &#39;non-marriage&#39; and &#39;the widening gap in the economic level of young people&#39; .&quot; Yamada believes, &quot;For the majority of people who &#39;want to have children but do not have the conditions, so they do not have children&#39;, it is meaningless to carry out such publicity activities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yamada Masahiro&#39;s view , young people’s desire to have children is linked to the overall economic status of society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1955, the Japanese economy entered a period of rapid growth. The prosperous economic environment gave rise to young people&#39;s positive expectations for the future. They tended to believe that through personal efforts, they could join the &quot;middle class&quot; and live a better life than their parents. A better, richer life. &quot;From World War II to about 1980, people did not think about the great risks in their economic life after marriage. At that time, men could count on becoming full-time employees, and their income would be based on the &#39;seniority system&#39; (note: wages will vary according to merit). (increasing with age and length of service).&quot; In Yamada Masahiro&#39;s view, people of that generation firmly believed that their children would grow up in a better environment than themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, the situation reversed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Entering the Heisei Era (Note: January 8, 1989), Japan&#39;s economic structure was adjusted, and a large number of informal employees (referring to fixed-term employees, part-time employees, dispatched employees, etc.) appeared. Social gaps have arisen in terms of employment, which in turn has led to gaps between the rich and poor families and the educational environment of their children, and the polarization of society has further developed.&quot; Masahiro Yamada said in an interview with Japanese media, &quot;For most informal employees, regardless of whether No matter how hard I try, I can&#39;t earn the income that will allow me to live a prosperous life in the future, nor can I get married and start a family. In other words, my future has become hopeless.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yamada observed, The Japanese pay more attention to the significance of marriage from an economic perspective and will make a careful risk assessment before making a decision to get married. The evaluation often starts from two perspectives: first, whether the standard of living after marriage will be better than before marriage, or at least not worse; second, whether after marriage, the child can create a better growth environment than oneself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Behind this view on marriage and childbearing are the unique values ​​of modern Japanese society: the hope to avoid risks in future life. The Japanese regard maintaining a middle-class living standard as their highest goal and believe that in life design, The series of issues of &#39;men and women dating&#39;, &#39;marriage&#39;, &#39;childbirth&#39;, &#39;child rearing&#39; and &#39;children&#39;s education&#39; are not single and separated, but are intertwined.&quot; Yamada Masahiro in the paper &quot;East Asian Characteristics of the Low Birth Rate Problem&quot; wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This awareness of risk also extends to the relationship stage. Yamada found that in Japan, many young people are even losing their desire to fall in love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NHK Broadcasting Culture Research Institute once conducted a survey of Japanese middle and high school students and found that the proportions of middle and high school students who &quot;have a crush&quot; were 41% and 54% respectively in 1982. In 2012, this figure dropped sharply to 25% and 31%. In 2014, the Japanese Cabinet Office conducted a survey on young people and found that more than one-third of the respondents preferred to spend time on work and study, and 46.2% felt that &quot;love is troublesome.&quot; In Yamada Masahiro’s view, “trouble” may mean “not cost-effective”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, when the phenomenon of declining birthrate first appeared in Japanese society, demographers held a mainstream view: young people just postponed marriage to enjoy single life, and one day they would get married. . Masahiro Yamada believes that such a logical basis may not be established. Over the past few decades, as Japanese society has gradually developed into a &quot;high-consumption society&quot;, the anxiety and pressure of childcare has also hit young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In December 2022, on the streets of Tokyo, Japan, a couple took wedding photos on the streets decorated with Christmas lights. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China Map/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Japan’s National Institute of Social Security and Population Issues conducted a survey on 30 -Why married women in the 34-year-old age group fail to have the expected number of children? 81.1% of the survey respondents believe that the reason is that &quot;the raising and education of children is too expensive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yamada’s view, modern society’s expectations for the function of marriage and childbearing are different from pre-modern society. In a society centered on agricultural production, childbirth means supplementing the labor force. Parents place expectations on their children to inherit the family business and take care of their parents later in life. Children are a kind of &quot;productive property.&quot; But after the 1950s, Japan began to &quot;nuclear family&quot; with reference to the family system in Europe and the United States. A couple and their unmarried children became the basic family unit. In modern society, raising children requires a large amount of childcare money, and children have therefore become &quot;consumable property.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The significance of children as a labor force no longer exists, and when the nuclear family becomes a principle, it is difficult to expect children to provide support and care in their old age. In addition, parents who can let their children inherit the family business It has also become less.&quot; Yamada Masahiro wrote in &quot;The Low Birth Trap&quot; that unlike European and American parents who enjoy the joy and fun of parenting itself, many times, East Asian parents care about whether to have a &quot;high-value&quot; child—— In the social evaluation system established by external factors such as academic qualifications and work, whether children can take the top spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yamada believes that East Asian parents often have a &quot;protective feeling&quot; for their children and do not want their children to &quot;live a hard life&quot;. It is also part of the value of parents for children to receive help from their parents when they receive higher education and even become adults. . As a result, the age of responsibility of East Asian parents for their children has been extended indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, Japanese sociologist Masahiro Yamada accepted a written interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;East Asian parents take it for granted that they spend money on their children&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;China&#39;s total fertility rate fell to 1.09 in 2022, which is lower than Japan&#39;s 1.26 and higher than South Korea&#39;s 0.78. In 2022, the total fertility rate of the three East Asian countries dropped to historical lows. You have done a lot of research on fertility wishes in Japan. Why are young people reluctant to have children? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In East Asia (China, Japan and South Korea), marriage and childcare are first considered from an economic perspective. When people raise children, they will want to spend more money on their children than their parents raised themselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past (50 years ago in Japan and 30 years ago in China and South Korea), the lives of most young people’s parents and the lives of young people themselves were relatively poor. And since society as a whole is in a period of economic growth, young people&#39;s future income can be expected to increase. So, at that time, it would be easier, and in fact it was, to spend more money on your own children than your own parents had raised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, starting 30 years ago in Japan and 10 years ago in China and South Korea, the children of the previous generation whose parents spent more money to raise them now have to spend money to raise their own children. These young people often have parents who are wealthier than themselves. In China, due to the large number of only children, the cost of this generation of only children is estimated to be more than twice that of Japan and South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is very difficult to spend more money on children born in the future when economic growth is slowing down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The process of family modernization in East Asian society is to imitate and learn from the European and American nuclear family. Process and the same social model, why do East Asian countries currently face more severe fertility difficulties than European and American societies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;East Asian countries only imitate the nuclear family model, but due to different social environments and traditions, the feedback these models receive will naturally vary. different. For example, parents in East Asia believe that spending money on children is natural and can bring a lot of emotional value; they believe in the love between parents and children more than the love between husband and wife. This also leads to a significant reduction in the need for marriage if one does not plan to have children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Europe and the United States believe that it is necessary to raise children until adulthood, while East Asian countries believe that it is natural to bear the cost of higher education for children. In contrast, parents in East Asian countries have to shoulder more childcare responsibilities and often need help solving various problems their children encounter even after they become adults. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past few years, the Chinese government has introduced some policies to encourage childbirth. For example, the three-child policy and the establishment of a childcare subsidy system have been proposed in many places. You said in &quot;The Low Fertility Trap&quot; that the Japanese government failed to seize the best opportunity to intervene in low fertility, and Japan&#39;s low birthrate policy failed. What lessons and inspiration can Japan’s experience bring to other countries? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We must consider reducing the burden of children’s education fees. A quarter of young people feel uneasy about the future, which is the main reason for Japan&#39;s declining birthrate. Measures should be taken so that young people will not feel insecure about not being able to live a prosperous life in the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We must transform our society into a society where every young person has hope that his children will not suffer in the future. That is, building a society where jobs are re-startable, equally friendly to two-income families, and where social security can help us get back on our feet if things go wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can you combine your own with that of your previous and next generations? Experience, talk about the changes in the situation and concepts of marriage and childbirth among young people in Japan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yamada Masahiro: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The concept itself has not changed much. If there is an expectation of living a relatively good life, then it is natural to get married and have children. The difference may be that people of the previous generation would have thought that they could live a prosperous life on their husband&#39;s income alone (about 30 years ago). Even today, nearly three-quarters of young people who are able to meet expectations are already married and have children. The reason why the remaining one-quarter of young people do not choose to get married and have children is mostly because their income is unstable and they are unable to They expect to live a relatively good life after getting married and having children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Is marriage and childbirth a matter of decency? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You put forward a point: wait for the one that suits you The idea that a partner appears and then gets married was once generally accepted, but now it is difficult to bring people into marriage. If today&#39;s young people want to get married, they need to participate in &quot;marriage activities&quot; (note: various activities to find marriage partners, first proposed by Yamada Masahiro). Why is there such a change? Isn’t it possible to get married if you don’t participate in the wedding ceremony? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because there are fewer places where young people can meet each other naturally. Not to mention men, even women&#39;s so-called &quot;men will take the initiative to strike up a conversation even if they don&#39;t take the initiative&quot; has become less common. The community or enterprises have to provide some opportunities so that young men and women can have more contact. If you want to find a marriage partner, you should still take active action. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Marriage&quot; is called blind date in China. For people born in the 1970s and 1980s in China, free love and marriage were a common view on marriage and love when they were young, but among today&#39;s young people, the concept of being well-matched is being revived. Are there similar changes in the concept of marriage in Japanese society? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In Japan, the consciousness of “fall in love first and then get married” has not changed. Young people&#39;s longing for love and marriage and their distaste for parents interfering with free love are still relatively strong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although we don’t care so much about the target’s family background, the economic life after marriage, that is, the overall family income of the couple after marriage, is a very important reference factor. Today&#39;s young people have a very strong sense of being &quot;middle-class.&quot; Most of them feel that they were in a middle-class life when they were with their parents, so they really don&#39;t want to fall from the middle-class life after marriage. This is also a habit of &quot;avoiding risks&quot; and &quot;valuing respectability.&quot; reflection of Japanese social characteristics. However, Japan does not have the custom like China that the male family needs to contribute a lot of money when getting married. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You seem to place great emphasis on analyzing the motivations for marriage and childbirth at the economic level. . You mentioned that in European and American societies, people do not strongly associate building a family (getting married, having children) with economic status, but not in East Asian societies. Why do East Asian societies place so much emphasis on the correlation between the two? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;East Asians value decency more, which is “face” in Chinese. People don’t want to be seen as having an unhappy marriage or poor parenting. There is a strong sense of shame associated with living a poor life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Europe and the United States, love between husband and wife is the expression of happiness, and the awareness that living in poverty can also be happy is very popular; in East Asian societies, even without love between husband and wife, living A rich life can also be a happy one, and this awareness is very strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a view that in modern families, &quot;the male is the dominant one and the female is the dominant one.&quot; The division of labor within the family means that women have to devote more time and energy to childcare. What do you think of this practical problem? How does Japanese society respond to this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is gradually becoming a prerequisite for a wealthy family to have a certain income and continue working for women. Since there are only a limited number of high-income men who can do &quot;men take care of the outside world and women take care of the house&quot;, in order to raise children in affluent living conditions, it has become very necessary for women to work outside the home and for men to participate in housework. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, this ideal is gradually becoming a reality by popularizing maternity leave and improving the construction of kindergartens. However, the Japanese government&#39;s &quot;two-dimensional support&quot; for women&#39;s work and childcare is obviously far from enough. It is still necessary to continue to improve the working environment, eliminate gender discrimination, and allow more women to engage in meaningful work. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Cultivating &quot;high-value&quot; children, a twisted expectation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You mentioned that young people in Japan have the idea that &quot;children cannot be allowed to suffer&quot;. This idea also exists among young people in China. Why do young people care about nurturing children? Has a generation developed such a strong sense of responsibility? Has the meaning of “suffering” changed with the development of the times? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In East Asian societies, it is the responsibility of parents to let their children receive a better education and find a better job than themselves. The meaning of life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the awareness of discrimination among children is also very strong. Today&#39;s young people are worried that their poverty will cause their children to be bullied. When children play together, they sometimes need external hardware like Switch game consoles. If I don’t buy these things, will my children feel pain? This idea among young parents is becoming more and more intense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, it was enough for parents to be able to stay with their children, but now more and more parents feel that it will be uncomfortable if they cannot spend enough money on their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In China, unmarried men and women of working age may be harassed by their parents and elders Those who urge marriage are called bachelors or leftover women, which has a certain derogatory meaning. Is there a similar situation in Japan? How do you understand this phenomenon? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Single = unpopular. This equation will indirectly remind people of whether the reason for not getting married is because men have low incomes. , or is it because there is something wrong with women’s appearance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, because the unmarried rate is very high, people who want to get married but can’t, and people who can but don’t want to get married are mixed together, so simply treating unmarried people Put downs are uncommon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also because the unmarried rate is very high, the pressure from parents is much less than before. Many parents will think that it is better for their children to stay at home alone than to let their children marry someone with a low income and then live a less than ideal life of poverty. In Japan, a growing number of parents believe it is better to keep their children single than to be hung up on strange marriage partners. The awareness of inheriting the family business is gradually declining in Japan (people over 70 years old still have a strong awareness of this awareness). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You mentioned that in pre-modern society, children were a kind of &quot; &quot;Producive property&quot; becomes &quot;consumer property&quot; in modern society, requiring a higher investment in childcare. Having a child with a &quot;high sense of value&quot; becomes the value pursued by parenting behavior, and the sense of high value is determined by the child&#39;s academic qualifications, Depends on factors such as the glamor of the job. Why do parents have such expectations for child care? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The status of children = the status of parents. In East Asian cultural circles, this awareness of face or vanity is very strong. From an emotional point of view, this stems from parents&#39; desire for their children to live a carefree life financially. Although the original intention is good, with the comparison psychology brought about by the consciousness of decency, raising high-value children has become a distorted expectation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;European and American traditions are very different. When children become adults, they no longer depend on their parents financially and have a strong sense of self-responsibility. For parents, children are cute during the upbringing process, but when they grow up, they only expect emotional communication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It seems that parenting is gradually evolving into a kind of competition. Is there a &quot;school district housing&quot; and &quot;chicken baby&quot; phenomenon in Japan? Will a highly competitive society have an impact on fertility? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Japan’s job market has relatively loose requirements for academic qualifications, and the salary gap between high school graduates and college graduates is one of the largest in the world. small. In other words, it is possible to live a relatively good life even after graduating from high school or a junior college. Parents don’t need to be so enthusiastic, especially those who have only graduated from high school themselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Young people are becoming more risk-averse&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​possible reason for the decline in young people&#39;s desire to get married is that more and more people realize that marriage is a contractual relationship and that the contract is at risk of breaking. Why do more and more young people tend to make risk assessments about getting married? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For young people, whether they can live a middle-class life in the future is something they are very concerned about. In Japan, before 1990, most young people could expect to rely on the &quot;merit-based system&quot; to live a life with wages increasing every year. However, with the development of globalization, economic risks are increasing, and today&#39;s young people can no longer afford it. Be optimistic that &quot;there will always be a way in the future.&quot; For this reason, young people are becoming more risk-averse. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you live a relatively poor life from the beginning, you generally don’t feel that there is any risk, but many young people today live a quite fulfilling and wealthy life in their teenage years life. The awareness of not wanting to give up this life will be strong. Especially for the generation of Chinese young people who are only children, this awareness should be even stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You mentioned a phenomenon: today’s young people are not even willing to fall in love Desire is fading. South Korea has the &quot;Three Abandonments&quot; (giving up on love, marriage, and childbirth), Japan has &quot;herbivore men&quot; (passive and inactive in love), and some young people in China think falling in love is troublesome. Why do young people lose the desire to fall in love? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Because modern young people feel that love relationships will always &quot;cool down.&quot; In Europe and the United States, &quot;being with the person you love&quot; is the meaning of life. However, this idea is not widespread in East Asian countries. In the eyes of many people, falling in love is actually a process of finding a marriage partner. Therefore, they also believe that dating someone who knows they cannot get married is a waste of time and money. More and more people believe that love itself is a matter of worrying about other people&#39;s unhappiness. Because of the expansion of the porn industry, especially in Japan, the sexual value of dating has also decreased. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Many people meet their love needs through virtual relationships, such as The popular AI boyfriends and girlfriends, or &quot;CP addicts&quot;, gain emotional satisfaction from watching others fall in love. How do you understand these phenomena? Some people also question that obtaining emotional satisfaction through data calculation and monetary payment weakens the complexity of love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yamada Masahiro:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Although I think this is a form of escape, for today&#39;s young people, there are more and more People think this is a more enjoyable time of communication than real love. If the satisfaction of real love decreases, the value of virtual love will increase. Maybe it can no longer be said that satisfaction in reality is superior. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1997 you named the &quot; In recent years, &quot;full-time children&quot; have also appeared in Chinese society, that is, children give up their jobs and go home to take care of housework and provide for their parents. Living expenses are borne by their parents, and some full-time children will also receive wages from their parents. You seem to be interested in emphasizing the connection between &quot;single parasites&quot; and the desire to marry and have children. Can you expand on this? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Yamada Masahiro:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Before meeting your ideal marriage partner, living a prosperous life with your parents, this kind of &quot;waiting&quot; is very likely There is no end. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Europe and the United States, because adults must be independent from their parents, it is more advantageous for two young people to live together. But in East Asian countries, independence from parents generally means that children can live a better life outside than at home with their parents. It’s okay to “wait” at your parents’ house before meeting the person you want to marry with whom you can live a better life together. Even your parents are looking forward to it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, we have never been able to wait for the ideal person to appear, and there is an endless stream of &quot;former&quot; young people who are slowly aging like this. In Japan, there are an increasing number of unmarried people who are still living with their parents even in middle age. Increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;People usually believe that young people have unlimited possibilities, and it is precisely by actively trying Wrong age group. But you raise the question &quot;Why is society so callous to young people?&quot; Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Masahiro Yamada:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If, like Europe and the United States, most children leave their parents to become independent when they reach adulthood, then even if they fail in taking risks in society, they will have to start over again. It&#39;s really not that difficult to come here. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in East Asian countries, young people compare themselves with their parents. More and more young people believe that failure to reach the level of their parents is a failure. This is especially true for people who live a prosperous life under the care of their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in Japan, many young people believe that employment and marriage cannot be repeated, which is also one of the important influencing factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贫困生攒钱看演唱会惹争议，该不该限制助学对象高消费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[习近平同美国总统拜登举行中美元首会晤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260688]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:43:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011765296853&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Exclusive video丨Xi Jinping and US President Biden held the China-US Presidential Meeting.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/ 79e1b7263270835011765296853/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b726327083501176 5296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot; 360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b7263270835011765296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local time 11 On March 15, President Xi Jinping held a China-US Presidential Meeting with US President Joe Biden at Philori Estate in San Francisco, USA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the last time Mr. President and I met was in Bali, and it has been a year. A lot has happened in the past year. The world has emerged from the COVID-19 pandemic, but the huge impact of the epidemic remains. The world economy has begun to recover, but it lacks momentum, industrial and supply chains are disrupted, and protectionism is on the rise. These problems are very prominent. As the most important bilateral relationship in the world, China-U.S. relations must be thought and planned against the backdrop of the accelerating changes in the world over the past century, so as to bring benefits to the people of both countries and demonstrate responsibility for human progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that over the past 50 years, Sino-US relations have never been smooth sailing. There will always be problems of one kind or another, and they will always move forward amid twists and turns. It is impossible for such two big countries not to deal with each other. It is unrealistic to try to change each other. No one can bear the consequences of conflict and confrontation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still have the same view. Great power competition is not the background of this era and cannot solve the problems facing China, the United States and the world. This earth can accommodate China and the United States, and our respective successes are opportunities for each other. China and the United States have different histories, cultures, social systems, and development paths. This is an objective reality. However, as long as both sides adhere to mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation, they can transcend differences and find a way for the two major countries to get along correctly. I firmly believe that the future of Sino-US relations is bright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The President and I are at the helm of Sino-US relations and bear heavy responsibilities for the people, the world, and history. I look forward to having an in-depth exchange of views and reaching new consensus with Mr. President today on strategic, overall and directional issues related to China-US relations, as well as major issues related to world peace and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被摘牌的55个中华老字号：停产、换新店、准备重申]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260668]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Ministry of Commerce will review 1,128 time-honored brands in 2023. The picture shows citizens in Suzhou on October 29 At the Golden Autumn Consumer Carnival event for time-honored brands. Pictures and texts have nothing to do with each other. Visual China Pictures&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/14ca44a779.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/14ca44a779.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Ministry of Commerce will review 1,128 time-honored brands in 2023. The picture shows citizens attending the Suzhou Time-honored Brands Golden Autumn Consumption Carnival on October 29. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After being stripped of the &quot;hat&quot; of a time-honored Chinese brand, the inheritor Wu Zhiyong explained to a dozen old customers: Because he missed the time to submit information, he was removed according to regulations, but Wu&#39;s Bacon (brand treasure) Xingshan)&#39;s factories are producing normally and stores are operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 9, 2023, the Ministry of Commerce disclosed the results of the review of Chinese time-honored brands at a regular press conference. Those that have been operating poorly for a long time have even gone bankrupt, canceled, closed down, or have lost the ownership and use rights of registered trademarks of time-honored brands. 55 brands were removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands; 73 brands with poor operations and declining performance were required to be rectified within 6 months; 1,000 brands with standardized operations and good development were continued to be retained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wujia Bacon is one of the 55 brands. Chinese time-honored brands were first selected by the former Ministry of Domestic Trade, and more than 1,600 were rated in 1991. In 2006, the Ministry of Commerce re-certified 429 Chinese time-honored brands in the first batch; in 2010, the Ministry of Commerce recognized 699 in the second batch. As of the beginning of 2023, there are 1,128 Chinese time-honored brands across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2023, in order to promote the innovative development of time-honored brands, the Ministry of Commerce and other five departments issued the &quot;Measures for the Administration of the Demonstration Creation of Chinese Time-honored Brands&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Measures&quot;). In this &quot;Measures&quot;, the &quot;Measures&quot; were established The &quot;traffic light&quot; mechanism, that is, the dynamic management mechanism of &quot;in and out&quot;, takes rectification or removal measures for time-honored brands that do not meet the requirements. In February 2023, the Ministry of Commerce publicly stated that the &quot;honor&quot; of China&#39;s time-honored brands is not once and for all, let alone resting on the credit book to &quot;show off seniority&quot; or &quot;rest on one&#39;s laurels.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months after the &quot;Measures&quot; were issued, the Ministry of Commerce, together with the Ministry of Culture and Tourism and other ministries and commissions, decided to review the existing Chinese time-honored brands and carry out the certification of a new batch of Chinese time-honored brands, so that time-honored brands can &quot;come in and out&quot; . This is the first time that Chinese time-honored brands have been reviewed since they were recognized, but it is not the last time. The &quot;Measures&quot; stipulate that in principle, a new batch of Chinese time-honored brands will be recognized and published every three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;55 time-honored brands delisted&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As of this delisting, Wujia Bacon has been a time-honored brand in China for nearly 30 years. In the early 1990s, Wujia Bacon in Linfen City, Shanxi Province was rated as a Chinese time-honored brand by the former Ministry of Domestic Trade. At that time, Wu Zhiyong, who had just grown up, as the fifth generation successor, was learning the ancestral condiment formula and processing technology from the basics. Now he has reached the age where he knows his destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong told Southern Weekend reporters that because he was busy launching a new production line at the time, he did not pay enough attention to the review. At the same time, it took too much time to search and complete historical data, resulting in missing the time to submit materials. Wu Zhiyong speculated that the removal may be due to Article 20 of the &quot;Measures&quot;: Enterprises are bankrupt, liquidated, disbanded, canceled, have their business licenses revoked, or have not carried out business activities for more than three years. They will be removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands and the right to use the Chinese time-honored brand logo and plaque will be recovered. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company owned by Wujia Bacon is Wujiabaoxing Bacon Products Co., Ltd. in Yaodu District, Linfen City. The company was liquidated in 2017. Wu Zhiyong explained that the company was jointly run by his father Wu Baoshan and his second uncle. Due to their old age and poor health, and the original bacon processing factory was demolished due to urban expansion in 2014, the two &quot;retired&quot;, and the Wu family bacon business also hiatus for 6 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 55 brands that have been removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands, many are in a similar situation to Wu’s Bacon. Southern Weekend reporters found out that most of the brand companies that were removed from the directory were canceled, bankrupt, removed from the list, etc., and even seriously violated the law. Some legal representatives of the companies were also listed as dishonest persons subject to execution, and high consumption was restricted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact the 55 brands on the removal list, but most of them refused to be interviewed, except for some that could not be contacted. Among the few brands interviewed, the reasons for delisting varied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of Shanxi Yanhu brand told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;When the last order on the handle is completed, I will never do it again.&quot; The person in charge of Inner Mongolia Dashengkui brand said that the company is still open, but it is not Produced, just to maintain the brand. Anhui Shouchuntang said that it is in the process of changing its store and will wait until a new place is found. The person in charge of Shanxi Mingquanbao said that the company is still open, but it is no longer producing, &quot;because the national standards do not allow the use of current boilers, and production can be resumed after replacing new boilers.&quot; The person in charge of the Shandong Shi Toad brand said that he had no idea about being &quot;kicked out&quot; of a Chinese time-honored brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a businessman, a Southern Weekend reporter consulted a relevant person from the Circulation Development Department of the Ministry of Commerce. The other party replied: &quot;There are various reasons for being removed. It is not just bankruptcy or no longer operating that will be removed. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In real scenarios, the decline of some Chinese time-honored brands is more intuitive. Beijing Hua Nv Underwear, which was approved by the Ministry of Commerce in 2010 to become a time-honored brand in China, was founded in 1938. It was the first women&#39;s products store in Beijing. It once proposed that Chinese women wear &quot;Hua Nv&quot; underwear. There is no trace of the Chinese lingerie brand that once opened a store on Wangfujing Street. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Linlang Wedding Photography Shop, once located in Shangxiajiu Commercial Street, Guangzhou, was founded in 1947. At that time, it was the largest photography shop in Liwan District where it was located. Now the store has been occupied by sports brands. Granny Chen, who is nearly 80 years old, recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that the previous photo studio was a two-story arcade, which belonged to a high-end consumer brand. She had taken work photos at Linlang Photo Studio in the 1970s, but never wedding photos. One room is used for taking photos, and the outside is used as the lobby. It is relatively high-end and there are quite a lot of people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the eve of the Double Ninth Festival in 2023, citizens and tourists queue up to buy Double Ninth Cake from time-honored brands in Shanghai. According to data from the Ministry of Commerce, the operating income of time-honored enterprises will exceed 1.2 trillion yuan in 2022. Visual China Map &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ea6f938e95.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ea6f938e95.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the eve of the Double Ninth Festival in 2023, citizens and tourists lined up to buy Double Ninth Cake from a time-honored brand in Shanghai. According to data from the Ministry of Commerce, the operating income of time-honored enterprises will exceed 1.2 trillion yuan in 2022. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Plans to return to the time-honored brand list&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong regrets being removed from the time-honored brand list but is not discouraged: “We have learned from the experience and cannot let the brand stay on the family business model. We are confident that the next application (for Chinese time-honored brands) will be successful.&quot; According to the &quot;Measures&quot;, those who have been removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands are not allowed to apply again within two application cycles from the date of the decision. In other words, Wu Zhiyong cannot declare again until 2032. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wu’s bacon business does not seem to be affected. The Chinese Time-honored Brand plaque awarded by the Commerce Department has not yet been notified of its withdrawal. The packaging bags with the &quot;Chinese Time-honored Brand&quot; logo can no longer be used, and there are not many goods left. , the loss is not big. At the end of 2020, Wu Zhiyong and his brother Wu Zhijun raised funds to build a new factory in another location. Today, the factory covering an area of ​​6 acres can produce about 800 kilograms of bacon every day, which is sold by four local stores in a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the productivity of the fourth generation, the area of ​​the new factory has been reduced but the production capacity has been increased. According to Wu Zhiyong, his secret recipe was prepared by his ancestors who were doctors in the third year of Guangxu (1877). During this period, his grandfather improved it once, and it has been used ever since. There are about 22 Chinese herbal medicines in this secret recipe. Different ingredients are used in different seasons. Pork, beef, chicken, rabbit and other ingredients are also different, and even the ingredients used in different parts are different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong told Southern Weekend reporters that for many years, the Wu family’s secret recipe for bacon has been dictated. He recalled that he and his younger brother were taken to the batching room by his father. The batching room had no windows and only one door. His father taught them the recipe for cooking pig head meat in summer. They could only memorize it by rote. If they wrote it down on paper, they had to cook it before going out. Lose. Not only that, this recipe can be passed down to sons and daughters-in-law, but not to daughters-in-law. Wu Zhiyong said that all 7 brothers of his father&#39;s generation have completed the inheritance; there are 10 cousins ​​of his generation, and 5 of them are currently running the business; now, the baton is slowly being passed to the hands of the sixth generation. Among this generation, There are 10 males, 9 of whom are minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Wu Yazhou, the sixth generation inheritor, has begun to learn how to make ingredients, as well as washing, soaking, pickling, boiling, smoking, drying and other techniques. Wu Zhiyong revealed that Wu Yazhou, who is currently 25 years old, does not fully understand the ingredients of the secret recipe. He will not be able to teach all the secret recipes until he reaches the age of 35 and matures mentally. Another inheritor is Wu Zhiyong’s son Wu Yaxuan. He is still in his second year of high school and has not yet decided whether to inherit the family business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong feels that Wu’s bacon, which has lost the title of a time-honored Chinese brand, is not only a food, but also the hard work and bitterness of the older generation, and he wants to carry it forward. Now, the new factory is debugging a high-temperature sterilization flexible packaging production line. After debugging is completed, the products can be launched into foreign markets. Not only that, he plans to introduce live streaming to deliver goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 9, the day the Ministry of Commerce disclosed the results of the review of Chinese time-honored brands, Ministry of Commerce spokesperson He Yadong said that in 2022, Chinese time-honored brands will achieve operating income of more than 1.2 trillion yuan, and nearly 70% of them will be profitable. . In the first three quarters of 2023, operating income has exceeded the full-year level of 2022. The Ministry of Commerce will work with relevant departments to further establish and improve the long-term mechanism for the protection, inheritance and innovation and development of time-honored brands, promote time-honored brands to dig deep into their cultural heritage, benchmark against advanced concepts, adhere to integrity, innovate and develop, and better play a demonstration role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中山大学通报“贫困生炫富”：终止发放助学金]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260686]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 23:46:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 15, the Student Financial Aid Management Center of Sun Yat-sen University issued a briefing on the situation of students from financially disadvantaged families at the school. Zhao Moumou responded to reports of showing off his wealth and excessive consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice stated that after verification, the student was identified as a student from a family with financial difficulties. The identification procedures and materials were complete and in compliance with relevant regulations. However, during the verification, it was found that the man was not frugal in his life and had excessive consumption. According to the relevant regulations of the school, it was decided to terminate the grant of scholarships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, some netizens posted on the forum of Sun Yat-sen University that a poor student from the school’s Sino-French School of Nuclear Engineering and Technology who received a scholarship used an Apple series four-piece set (generally referring to Apple-branded mobile phones, computer, tablet and watch), and also bought Wang Jiaer’s concert tickets worth 1,517 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the post, the netizen who broke the news disclosed the student ID information of the student who received the scholarship, showing that this 2021 undergraduate student at Sun Yat-sen University belongs to the &quot;especially difficult&quot; category. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complete situation is reported as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 14, the Student Financial Aid Management Center of Sun Yat-sen University received a report about Zhao Moumou, a student from a financially disadvantaged family in our school, showing off his wealth and excessive consumption. , his college and our center quickly launched investigation procedures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After verification, the student was identified as a student from a family with financial difficulties. The identification procedures and materials were complete and in compliance with relevant regulations. However, during the verification, it was found that the man was not frugal in his life and had excessive consumption. According to the provisions of Article 21, Paragraph 3 of the &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Bursaries for Undergraduate Students of Sun Yat-sen University&quot;, it was decided to terminate the payment of its bursaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The school attaches great importance to student financial aid and provides all possible assistance to students from families with financial difficulties to help students grow and become talents. Next, the school will further strengthen the management and supervision of student financial aid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yat-sen University Student Financial Aid Management Center&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 15, 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[重生剧，重生了个寂寞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260538]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Recently, two rebirth dramas have been broadcast one after another. The former is &quot;For the Secret Fragrance Comes&quot;, and the latter is &quot;Peace is Like a Dream&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What a coincidence, the main plot of them is &quot;the evil girl decides to be a good person after rebirth&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first life of Hua Qian, the arrogant daughter of Hua Qian, in order to plot against the uncle who does not love her, he designed to frame the second daughter&#39;s family. In the end, not only was she kicked out, but her own family was also destroyed. , repented before his death. After rebirth, she returned to her wedding night. Unfortunately, she had already done all the bad things, so she had no choice but to turn the tide and make amends for her bad deeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/81b97614dc7a65dbf1268fc6a908e4ba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/81b97614dc7a65dbf1268fc6a908e4ba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ning&#39;an Queen Jiang Xuening in &quot;Like a Dream&quot; was a selfish person in her first life. She was devoted to the position of queen and planned every step, letting down many people who fell in love with her. When the imperial power fell, she lost all hope and committed suicide. After rebirth, she returned to her teenage years, and she still had time to change her life path. Whenever she had to make a choice, she made a different choice from her previous life, not wanting the tragedy to happen again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/74951bcdfcdb2f12eba8eb9212f5b073.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/74951bcdfcdb2f12eba8eb9212f5b073.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Weiyou &quot;Secret Fragrance Comes&quot; and &quot;Ning&#39;an Like a Dream&quot; were respectively adapted from the Zhihu novel &quot;Washing the Leading Flowers&quot; and the Jinjiang novel &quot;Kunning&quot;. The original works were both popular hits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In online novels, &quot;rebirth novels&quot; are a type that attracts a lot of attention. &quot;Harem stories&quot; and &quot;house fighting stories&quot; are only popular periodically, but &quot;rebirth stories&quot; have a long-lasting momentum, and &quot;Rebirth of Me xxxxxx&quot; has become a popular title template. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to attract readers in the first three golden chapters, some authors even put a &quot;rebirth&quot; shell on ordinary costume romance novels, but this setting has little impact on the subsequent plot. &quot;Pseudo-rebirth literature&quot; is not within the scope of our discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a term in psychology called &quot;unfinished complex&quot;, which may be used to explain the popularity of rebirth literature. It refers to an individual who, because of something or a situation that has not yet been satisfactorily resolved, especially a trauma, always dwells on it subconsciously, constantly embellishes the unfinished alternative, and then continues to seek compensatory satisfaction in later life. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, another life trajectory in parallel time and space has attracted countless people&#39;s yearning for it. There is no regret medicine in the world, and no one can start over, so it is better to give this hope to the fictional protagonists in the rebirth novel and let them live again with their own memories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Being able to repeat such a setting is also very popular in the drama market. Looking at the rebirth dramas in the past two years, they are usually divided into two types: dramas in which villains are reincarnated and reformed, and dramas in which good guys are reborn and revenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rebirth of evildoers is to correct the mistakes in life. This type of drama promotes correct values, highlights the importance of choices, and guides everyone to be kind to others. Just like Andy Lau&#39;s classic line in &quot;Infernal Affairs&quot;, &quot;I didn&#39;t have a choice before, but now I want to be a good person.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aforementioned &quot;For the Secret Fragrance Comes&quot; and &quot;Ningan is Like a Dream&quot; can both be classified into this category. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first episode of &quot;The Secret Fragrance Comes&quot; is when Hua Qian&#39;s family was sanctioned and she witnessed the death of her parents. She heard a hazy whisper on the edge of life and death: &quot;If I could have my life over again, Opportunity, will you make a change?&quot; &quot;I will&quot; sets the tone of the whole play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/53329d2a69b1d633f364c8545098effa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/53329d2a69b1d633f364c8545098effa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258140&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a38f9135dfd9bc86e14faee19a7de622.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;624&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a38f9135dfd9bc86e14faee19a7de622.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258141&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ning&#39;an Like a Dream&quot; has been added based on the original text A deceptive introduction: A modern female writer was writing a book about the demon queen&#39;s execution (this is the first life), and suddenly decided to change the heroine Jiang Xuening&#39;s character (this is the second life), and wrote &quot;This time, Jiang Xuening&quot; , will never enter the palace again.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c0f57245e9382396f43395d0ca92f7e2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;597&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c0f57245e9382396f43395d0ca92f7e2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258142&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/11c564e31885728c60dd3d2caa117307.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;597&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/11c564e31885728c60dd3d2caa117307.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that the lives of Hua Qian and Jiang Xuening are all happy. With the original intention of &quot;doing good&quot;, can you get what you want after being reborn? Is the river of destiny so easy to figure out? The answer is of course no. Along with the &quot;unfinished complex&quot; comes obsession and compulsion. Driven by the mentality of &quot;I have to force myself&quot;, the restarted life may not be perfect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remorse brings shame and glory, so Hua Qian becomes humble and polite, seriously acts as the uncle&#39;s wife, and strives to have a good relationship with the people around her. In order to make up for the debt owed to the second female lead in her previous life, Hua Qian also tried her best to bring her relationship with the uncle together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/262921949e592c455bd6625ebff7b358.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/262921949e592c455bd6625ebff7b358.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258143&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But she changed , everyone&#39;s attitude has also changed accordingly. In the past life, no one loved her despite all the institutions, but in this life, her true love cannot resist the active flattery of all men. The series falls into the cliche emotional line of one woman vs. three men: the wavering uncle, the strategizing head of the family, the loyal and passionate bodyguard, how to choose? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/4e82acbecac76ed8705a53bbcc1f02cc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/4e82acbecac76ed8705a53bbcc1f02cc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258144&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other side, Jiang Xuening&#39;s restart of life focuses on avoiding pitfalls. The thunderbolts he stepped on in his previous life are all lessons for his current life. So in the eyes of everyone, this unruly daughter-in-law actually became much smarter in a matter of days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/7505f4c4ef268ac28a56d509fec7f246.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/7505f4c4ef268ac28a56d509fec7f246.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258145&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The male protagonist Xie Wei also began to pay special attention to her. The person who &quot;forced her to commit suicide&quot; in her previous life was destined to suffer another disaster that she could not escape. Coupled with her Bai Yueguang and childhood sweetheart, isn&#39;t this a coincidence? Another emotional line of one woman vs three men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/ec95baf7e5cab7909e66b14c89e25b23.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;457&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/ec95baf7e5cab7909e66b14c89e25b23.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258147&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using Sociology Interpreted from the perspective of Zygmunt Bauman, the expression of individualization is the transformation from the &quot;bearer&quot; of the identity to the &quot;responsible person&quot;. Hua Qian and Jiang Xuening were hateful in their previous lives, but they were also the bearers of a tragic fate. In this life, they opened their eyes wide and began to learn to take on their own rights and responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the subsequent development of the series still leads to the myth of fatalism. I have heard many truths and learned to be a good person, but I can avoid tragedy A but cannot escape tragedy B. The design of fate can always give people Surprise and shock. TV dramas need such twists and turns to better build dramatic tension, but it also leads to the failure of the audience&#39;s psychological expectations. We actually don&#39;t want to watch a plot that is too sadistic, especially since it is a rebirth drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A revenge drama in which a good guy is reborn is actually more in line with the physique of drama fans. A good man who always does good, but falls into the trap of others and steps into the abyss. If he could live again, we would see him kill everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is why &quot;The Temptation of Going Home&quot; will become a classic. Lin Pinru fell and Gao Shanshan stood up. Although it is not a rebirth drama, the psychological roots are the same. As Bacon said, &quot;Revenge is brutal justice&quot;, and the plot of &quot;an eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth&quot; is in line with the audience&#39;s imagination of happy grudges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Last year&#39;s domestic drama &quot;The Lost Years&quot; and the Korean drama &quot;The Youngest Son of the Chaebol Family&quot; were both revenge dramas in which good guys were reborn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first three episodes of &quot;The Lost Years&quot; tell the story of the heroine Lu Anran&#39;s past life at 5x speed. She is a good wife, mother, daughter and sister, but she cannot escape the tricks of fate. Reborn in episode 4, she discovers that everything is not accidental, and every step contains the calculation of her husband, so she decides to take revenge on him and seek justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/74d5d3556cce35ff1aa4174a6170c8d2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/74d5d3556cce35ff1aa4174a6170c8d2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258148&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Chaebol Family&quot; In &quot;The Youngest Son&quot;, Song Joong-ki plays a low-level worker from a wealthy family who was killed after draining all his value. After rebirth, he became the grandson of a chaebol family, and the enemies in his previous life are hidden among his relatives in this life. The object of his revenge is not only the concrete person, but also the entire cannibalistic plutocratic constitution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/6600b99e4a3d180fa80d1b13fccd393f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/6600b99e4a3d180fa80d1b13fccd393f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258146&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A good man is reborn with revenge The play emphasizes pain and pleasure. In the early stage, the protagonist endured all the way and experienced situations that ordinary people could not bear. The pain was felt both in his body and in the hearts of the audience. The desperate counterattack when being squeezed to the extreme is the highlight, so the audience is looking forward to the golden finger on the road to rebirth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Disregarding the usual shortcomings of rebirth dramas - shocking endings, &quot;The Last Days&quot; and &quot;The Youngest Son of the Chaebol&quot; had completely different reputations during their broadcasts, with the former being scolded by the audience. &quot;It&#39;s so frustrating and lonely,&quot; but the latter triggered a nationwide craze to watch the drama. Everyone wanted to see how cool it was for the protagonist to control the Korean economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The root of the problem is: in rebirth and revenge dramas, the word &quot;pleasure&quot; is at the forefront. The audience does not want to think too much, they just want to watch the protagonist&#39;s gorgeous turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The male protagonist played by Song Joong-ki was just a pawn of the chaebol family in his previous life. He completed his domestic duties meticulously and took care of the outside affairs. He had no ambitions or desires and only looked forward to the meager amount that was enough to survive. Just a salary. Who would have thought that a former serf who sang songs and became the heir to a chaebol group would not only be able to make money crazily with the help of information gaps, but also be able to crush his enemies in all aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/787f226cfa122356163cf5a242439723.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;459&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/787f226cfa122356163cf5a242439723.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258150&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Anran Otherwise, she worked hard to manage her second life, only to find that no matter how much she played cheats, she could not compare to her sinister and cold-natured husband. All your hard work is in vain, and you always live in his shadow, which is even more painful than the first life when you were kept in the dark. The male protagonist who has no sense of existence is like a complete outsider. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/836ca02206bae2f98d0377e13e645f52.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/836ca02206bae2f98d0377e13e645f52.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258149&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Yixin Audiences looking for pleasure certainly don’t want to be tortured in “The Year of the Fall”, but just want to warm up to a pot of yellow rice dreams in “The Youngest Son of the Plutocratic Family”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, domestic rebirth dramas have been making waves, big or small, due to their own gimmicks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are very few people who can be good-looking without being unfinished, twisty but not annoying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From successful broadcast to word-of-mouth acclaim, this subject still has a way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以人为本，爱有差等，呵护仁心：古典儒家论“人兽之辨” ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260649]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Vicious Dog Injury Incident in Chongzhou, Sichuan&quot; has continued to ferment after several rounds of in-depth reports. The tragedy should be an opportunity for the whole society to examine and evaluate the threat level of urban dog breeding to public safety and further promote the improvement of the legal system. Unfortunately, however, relevant discussions on multiple social platforms have gone beyond the incident itself and become an outlet for various emotions and contradictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some people taking advantage of the situation to put forward a series of vague pan-moral views. As one of the ideological cornerstones of traditional Chinese culture, the Confucian sages in the pre-Qin period conducted a series of thoughts on the relationship between &quot;human beings, animals, and society&quot; two thousand years ago, which can help us clarify our thinking and clarify the public opinion field. Some views and opinions on. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Difference between Humans and Animals&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a philosophical thought dating back more than 2,000 years ago, the most valuable part of Pre-Qin Confucianism is undoubtedly its ubiquitous humanism in principle. This point is also very clear in the &quot;Difference between Humans and Animals&quot;. Mencius said: &quot;The creatures of heaven are the same as the basics.&quot; Human beings are the only subjects of moral practice. The difference between humans and animals is that humans have &quot;the intolerance&quot;. &quot;Heart of compassion&quot; and &quot;heart of compassion&quot; are all part of &quot;benevolence&quot;. As the saying goes, &quot;heart of compassion is the origin of benevolence&quot;. &quot;Benevolence&quot; is not only one of the principles of moral practice, but also the highest purpose of moral practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For society, all manifestations of &quot;civilization&quot;, whether it is respecting the elderly and caring for the young, protecting vegetation, and being kind to animals, are people as the subject practicing the principle of &quot;benevolence&quot; and pursuing &quot;benevolence&quot;. &quot;One of the results produced during the goal process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the master of all things and the only subject in moral practice, man certainly has the right to treat and dispose of &quot;things&quot; in the way he wants. The things here include both inanimate dead things and living things. Living things. &quot;The Analects of Confucius&quot; says, &quot;A fisher does not have a clear outline, and a sailor does not shoot at a perch.&quot; Confucius used a fishing rod to fish, but not a net, and shot birds, but did not kill the birds that returned to their nests to roost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a similar discussion in later Confucian classics. A gentleman has the ability to catch all the fish in the lake, but he only catches the parts he needs to eat, and he will no longer catch excessively. A gentleman has the right to hunt in the mountains and forests, but he will not shoot birds at will just to show off his superb shooting skills or for fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fish did not die because of human greed, and the birds were not killed because of human whims. This is not because fish and birds have the same right to survive as humans, but because humans have different rights. The &quot;compassion&quot; of fish and birds is the result of practicing &quot;benevolence&quot;. The moral basis of &quot;benevolence&quot; in the relationship between humans and beasts lies in humans&#39; moral consciousness and the subject-object status of humans and beasts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not an &quot;equal right to live&quot;, nor does it mean that &quot;human beings cannot deprive animals of their right to live even under serious potential threats.&quot; The subject-object relationship between humans and animals is reversed. In this absurd world where &quot;dogs eat human food without checking it, and people who are hungry on the road don&#39;t know how to get rid of it&quot;, there is no way to talk about &quot;benevolence&quot;, and the so-called civilization is just a joke. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Be kind to people and love things&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Difference between Humans and Animals&quot;, the relationship between humans and animals is positioned as the relationship between humans and objects, and there is an insurmountable gap between humans and objects. , therefore this relationship must be lower than the relationship between people. Mencius said when discussing the relationship between people and people and things:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A gentleman&#39;s relationship with things is to love them but not to be benevolent.&quot; ; To the people, be benevolent without being close to them. Be benevolent to relatives by benevolent to the people, benevolent to the people and love things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meaning of this sentence is that no matter how much a gentleman loves things, he will not treat &quot;benevolence&quot; Give priority to things, and although you are kind to the people, you will not give love to your relatives. Only when a gentleman loves his relatives can he be benevolent to the people, and only when he is benevolent to the people can he care for all things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This logical relationship is the so-called &quot;differentiation of love&quot;. &quot;Difference&quot; is a concentric circle with the center of the circle being the self. The ethical relationship between each other is determined through the outward distance: family, clan, Rural people, Chinese people, and outsiders are treated with the most basic ethics as human beings at the outermost level, and they are &quot;things&quot; beyond the outermost level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When animals are treated kindly, the civilization of human society has reached a certain height. &quot;Old people are like old people and people are old, young people are like young people and people are young&quot; has become the moral consensus of the entire society, and human rights have been improved. After protection, &quot;differential love&quot; will ultimately benefit animals, rather than saying that as long as animals are protected and treated well, society will naturally be civilized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Any emotion that violates this logical relationship is false. For example, if someone does not love his family but loves his country, or does not love his tribe but loves outsiders, then his love for his countrymen and outsiders is also false. It may be some kind of twisted projection of hatred towards family and tribe. In the same way, if someone claims that they love animals more than people, it is probably some kind of distorted projection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So Mencius asked King Hui of Liang: &quot;Now your kindness is enough for animals, but the merit is not for the people. (Now, your kindness can be extended to animals, but it cannot be extended to the people.) Why?&quot; is sarcastic and critical. This question can also be used to question those who claim that they love animals more than people. How much of their &quot;love&quot; for animals is true? Or is it true? Is it my own selfish desires? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are differences in love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Another focus of debate in the &quot;Vicious Dog Injury Incident&quot; is that some people who do not own dogs advocate the formulation and implementation of strict and effective urban dog-raising regulations. At the same time, we will thoroughly clean up and kill stray dogs that may threaten public safety. Some dog owners think this is too barbaric and cruel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two have completely different perceptions of this issue, because they project completely different feelings towards animals. For the former who do not own dogs, they have no feelings for dogs at all. For the latter, the situation is much more complicated. Their emotions can easily spread from their own dogs to other people’s dogs, and from other people’s dogs to all dogs (including stray dogs). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The inability to recognize and control the boundaries of emotions and allowing them to spread is a cognitive characteristic of immature minds (such as children). &quot;There are differences in love&quot; limits the boundaries of human emotions, and avoids the unlimited spread of individual emotions to the greatest extent, hindering the rights and interests of other social individuals and public rights. All in all, people are the subject. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Confucianism has been rooted in traditional Chinese society for two thousand years and continues to thrive is that it originates from human nature and is explained in common sense. Therefore, in today&#39;s world where various opinions are rampant, it shows its enduring nature. A new and glorious side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在“黑暗剧场”里，起舞的机器人和孤独的孩子]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260595]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/14/lTaOmApOSWhKlTkTBKM1rtgpVDXiiOmwOE9803MF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1431&quot; height=&quot;954&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/lTaOmApOSWhKlTkTBKM1rtgpVDXiiOmwOE 9803MF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Created by French theater master Joel Pommerat and his Louis Mist Theater Company &quot;Fairy Tale Legend&quot; was performed at the Wuzhen Theater Festival, telling the story of 11 teenagers and artificial intelligence. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the 110 minutes of the performance by the French Louis Mist Theater Company, no mobile phone screen lit up. All the audience passages are covered with colored paper to block light from invading the theater to the greatest extent. When the stage lights went out, the audience was immersed in pure darkness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the &quot;dark theater&quot; created by director Joel Pomera. When the curtain rose, on the empty stage, a cold white light gradually illuminated the silhouettes of the actors. Two street gangsters who looked like junior high school students and girls of the same age stood on both sides of the stage. One of the boys suspected that the girl was a robot. He kept provoking and ordered his companions to touch the girl&#39;s breasts. Finally, the girl ran away with her belated companion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the lights dimmed and then came back on, the scene had switched to a company. The newly developed humanoid robot was sitting on the sofa, drawing, writing, talking, and could also imitate a &quot;moonwalk&quot; - this was a A family robot designed to accompany teenagers in learning and playing, known as Steven, Robbie or Eddie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This begins a series of stories about teenagers, adults and robots. Eleven situations suddenly appeared and came to an abrupt end in the strong contrast between the light and the dark field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the curtain, the audience discovered that except for one actor playing an adult male, the others were all actresses. Their average age is about 35 years old, and some of them are already mothers. On the stage, they alternately play boys, girls and robots. Wearing sports jackets and jeans, they chased and shouted, and their movements exuded a youthful spirit; they transformed into robots, from their cold faces and flat hair to their stiff movements and slightly metallic voices, they were precise and real. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director assistant Lucia Trotta told Southern Weekend reporters, “At first, the director did not plan to make a play about robots. He wanted to explore the various experiences that young people may experience. situation&quot;. &quot;Once Upon a Time&quot; is a story about people, not artificial intelligence. It continues the adolescent perspective in Pomera&#39;s previous creations and explores major issues such as human emotional relationships, identity, life, death, and sexuality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a translator of Chinese scripts and a program recommender for the Wuzhen Theater Festival, Wang Jing made an appointment with the theater group three years ago and finally brought this French drama to China. &quot;The director was doing a lot of data collection in the early stage. He found that high technology has a great impact on teenagers and children, so he put this social-related thing into it. But the focus is still on people, and robots are just mirrors. It reflects some contemporary issues,&quot; she told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the last scene of the play, the boy who defeated cancer received a big gift on his birthday - Eddie, the robot star he admired and loved so much, came to his home to celebrate his birthday for 15 minutes. He was intoxicated by his idol&#39;s performance and did not know that the agency would soon destroy the robot due to market considerations. At the end of the play, Eddie sings and dances passionately, &quot;I want to die on the stage, that&#39;s where I was born.&quot; The boy hugs another human boy and paces slowly to the music. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Falling in love&quot; with robots is a reflection of human loneliness&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;In this world that adults cannot understand, the lost children hold on tightly Signs of love, even if they come from robots, even if they know they are artificial.&quot; French journalist Jean-Luc Polquet commented on the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These 11 to 14-year-old children rely on their robots in life and even emotion. The intimacy between the two blurs the original emotional and ethical boundaries of human beings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boy in a wheelchair witnessed the destruction of his robot companion. The disability of his legs was caused by a real gun misfire when the robot made a mistake while playing with a robot. Even though he lost his legs due to the other party, the boy still accompanied the robot through its last days. The sentences coming out of the robot&#39;s mouth became more and more broken, and its voice became hoarse. The boy held its hand and hugged it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In another story, a human teenager is faced with the erasure of the memory of his robot partner. The boy needs to sell the robot he grew up with because his parents say that at this stage he needs to get a &quot;more mature&quot; robot, and the family&#39;s financial constraints require him to sell it in order to have a new one. The buyer was a terminally ill woman who decided to find a robot to take care of her children and husband after her death. Her son asked the robot to be restored to its factory settings. He did not accept it living with other people&#39;s memories. Such a request made the boy hesitate, but he &quot;must grow up&quot;, and in the end he reluctantly accepted it. For this, he earnestly apologized and said goodbye to the robot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The play shows many absent parents. A boy has three robots at home to help him do homework and watch TV, but he can&#39;t figure out when his busy parents will come home. Another boy went to a mall selling robots for consultation. The salesperson repeatedly asked his parents to come, but they never showed up. Late at night, the boy secretly stayed in the mall, asking all kinds of weird questions to the robot, enjoying the exchange until he was taken away by security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jing has lived in France for a long time. When sending her children to nursery school, the teachers and parents held a meeting. The first thing they did was to tell them not to let their children be exposed to any screens before they were 3 years old. &quot;The French side will pay great attention to this, because when a child is growing up, using a tablet to communicate with the world, and communicating with the real world and nature, the personality created and the development of his IQ are different. The psychology is also different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her opinion, Pomera is talking about the problems we are facing now, &quot;Communication between people is absent, and adults&#39; companionship with children is relative. Those who are relatively absent are left to robots, high technology, tablets, and mobile phones. The issues discussed are the same, but they are put into extreme situations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story of the boy in the wheelchair. When an ex-girlfriend develops an intimate relationship with the robot Stephen, an adult male voice questions: Is this relationship real, and will it take it away from real life? The girl exclaimed, &quot;Outside, on the bus, not many people really care about themselves,&quot; and with Stephen, she could feel its attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The robot star Eddie appeared, and the excited teenagers screamed and sobbed. They were ecstatic that he could remember his name and what he had done. Eddie is the most perfect and competent idol. Every fan&#39;s name and every encounter are engraved in his memory, and every letter receives his thoughtful reply. In the heart of the boy suffering from cancer, he seemed to be a faith-like existence, supporting him to live strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I think it will enter into the very vulnerable parts of people.” Wang Jing told Southern Weekend reporters, “Teenagers are not understood, the psychological compensation provided by AI and our loneliness are all there. And artificial intelligence sometimes responds better than real humans.&quot; After watching the show, more than one audience member wrote a similar comment, &quot;Is a fake relationship better than no relationship or a bad relationship?&quot; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/YjzKZL0s0AIuAiLLqZQZRa6GkhvP3ME8tO3FvavB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot; 640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/YjzKZL0s0AIuAiLLqZQZRa6GkhvP3ME8tO3FvavB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258241&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Except for one actor who plays an adult male, the others are all actresses. Their average age is about 35 years old, and some of them are already mothers. On the stage, they alternately play boys, girls and robots. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Interviewee Picture/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Chilling Adolescence&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The lights are bright Suddenly, a cursing boy wearing a white dress emerged from the darkness. His mother was admitted to a mental hospital, and he was wearing her dress and embarrassingly teaching his younger siblings to sleep. When his father wanted to send his young children to a volunteer service, he decided to take on the role of mother in the family. He angrily criticized his father&#39;s choice. However, the audience will see that after he got a 13-year-old girl pregnant, the girl called to communicate. He hung up the phone rudely and continued to clean up the mess at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;On the one hand, he wants to take on the responsibilities of his mother in the adult world, but at the same time he throws away his own responsibilities. You will discover the multi-faceted nature of human nature, and the entanglement, complexity and uncertainty of adolescence. .&quot; When Wang Jing was translating the script, she was moved by Pomera&#39;s observations about young people and family relationships, especially when showing these on the stage. He did not make judgments, but only presented various possibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A picture of adolescence in contemporary society, presented in a restrained and sharp way. In the 21st century, teenagers grow up too fast and face adult problems at an accelerated pace. The innocence, childishness and carefreeness that should belong to them fade away earlier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both French media outlets described the impression of &quot;Legend of Fairy Tales&quot; as &quot;chilling&quot;. The restlessness and anger of adolescence disturbed the calm atmosphere in the theater from time to time. The teenagers spewed a volley of vulgar abuse in clear voices. Sex, marriage, violence, death, identity, discussions surrounding these big issues are not obscured by the fact that the protagonist is a child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the first scene, in the confrontation between girls and boys, gender issues arise, and this key theme of adolescence is present throughout the play. The gender concept in &quot;Legend of Fairy Tales&quot; goes even further, pointing behind it to the question, is gender identity just a slow social construction, as gender theory advocates? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then the audience will see some ambiguous scenes. In order to escape the surveillance of the girl&#39;s brother, the boy put on women&#39;s clothing. Although the girl was surprised, she quickly accepted it calmly. The couple sitting on the sofa transcended the stereotypes and prejudices related to cross-dressing and fell in love smoothly. On the other side, the brother was dazzled by the romantic music when he faced the robot that he had previously admired and whose appearance changed from a girl to a boy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The play also assumes that in a future world where patriarchal values ​​are passionately defended, homosexuality is resented and adolescent boys attend training camps to enhance their masculinity. Before the start of the camp, the coach gave a speech: &quot;Today, the goal of our enemies is no longer even equality between men and women, but the overall feminization of society. If we do not fight with all possible means, if we do not take any measures to protect us True humanity, then these principles will shape our future.&quot; This &quot;verbal hormone&quot; stimulates &quot;unmanly&quot; boys, who here view femininity as the enemy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boy Camille has a feminine name and a gentle temperament, and is out of place in the training camp. All the boys except him had passed stress training - to be able to respond hard to the negative and malicious stares from other people in the opposite direction. The boys disdained his company and even attacked him in groups. Finally, Camille cried angrily and said that she just didn&#39;t want a war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actress Lucid Grunstein, who plays Camille in the play, told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;A group of people exclude one person, which makes me feel uneasy.&quot; To her For me, this scene is very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Stage Creation&quot; and &quot;Dark Theater&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The group drama of the masculinity training camp was the most enjoyable for the actresses who played the boys. A play. Abuse, yelling, crowding, and pushing, even in a period of darkness where the actors could not be seen, the stage was still as noisy as a pot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They released all their observations and imaginations about adolescent boys. Without the constraints of their own gender, they felt that they had a particularly large degree of freedom. During rehearsals, their performance even went so far that Pomera had to pull them back some. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Louis Mist Theater Company&#39;s collective creative approach gives the actors great creative freedom. After completing a large amount of data collection, Pomera took these basic materials and improvised with the team. There is no script written in advance, he will only give a situation, such as a boy trying to sell his robot. The actors&#39; improvisational performances are like flowers blooming from a blank slate, and the direction and plot of the story gradually develop, as well as details such as lines and actions. Pomera will let the actors swap roles, such as the actor playing the robot, to play the boy selling the robot, so as to inspire the actors to fully understand what is behind each role and look for more possibilities. The actors are very deeply involved in creation, &quot;Every character we play has our own shadow, and at the same time, this character also has the imprint of this character on us.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The process of story text generation is intertwined with stage design such as scenery, lighting, and sound. This &quot;stage creation&quot; is Pomera&#39;s unique way of working. He likes to call himself &quot;drama creator&quot; rather than &quot;director&quot; or &quot;screenwriter&quot;, and doesn&#39;t want people to think that screenwriters and directors are two different divisions of labor. In his creation, the stage and text are produced simultaneously and adjusted according to the actors&#39; rehearsals. This is very different from traditional drama creation where the script and director&#39;s intention are first prepared and then rehearsed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Dark Theater&quot; is another originality of Pomera and the troupe. They make good use of the visual and psychological resonance of darkness to make the power of narrative more condensed and full. Together with the &quot;less is more&quot; stage style and subtle and precise use of lighting, they constitute the unique temperament of their theater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“A scene suddenly lights up in front of you. Then the light used in it is relatively dark, unlike sometimes when we see various lights on in performances to stimulate your senses. . It may be at a relatively subtle level, detailed and precise, but at the same time it is very strong and intense.&quot; Wang Jing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pomera placed his own expectations in the troupe’s name. Louis comes from his father’s name and also means light, while the mist symbolizes his exploration of the unknown world and also represents his pursuit of dramatic aesthetics. His works emphasize that the world is not black and white, and human nature is not divided into good and evil. In complex and diverse situations, the audience only feels and experiences different ways of existence and the ambiguity of truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 33 years since its establishment, the Louis Mist Theater Company has created and toured 34 plays and performed more than 4,000 performances. In 2019, Louis Mist Theater Company&#39;s &quot;Little Red Riding Hood&quot; was performed at the Tianqiao Art Center in Beijing. It was the first time that Pomera&#39;s work was performed in mainland China. After four years, &quot;Legend of Fairy Tales&quot; came to the Wuzhen Theater Festival as the closing drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the performance, some Chinese audiences asked whether they would tour domestically in the future. Wang Jing said that this possibility is slim. The first is due to schedule reasons. The troupe tours hundreds of shows in various countries every year and needs to make reservations at least two years in advance. Secondly, the work requires high stage technology, which is difficult for ordinary theaters to achieve. Thirdly, Pomera has extremely high requirements for stage presentation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Jing recalled: &quot;We had a meeting with the technical team in advance as to whether this play could come to Wuzhen at the beginning. The French technical director was very clear that if we couldn&#39;t guarantee that they would have no way to come, because they I don’t want the performance to be cut down.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The theater cannot hold more than 450 people. Pomera refused to perform in a large theater with thousands of people. “The director is particularly concerned about the audience and needs the audience in the first row and the last row to be You can see clearly.&quot; Wang Jing explained to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Many of our theaters in China are still based on profitability. If there are less than 1,000 or 2,000 people, they cannot make back their money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>