<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[茅台宣布涨价20%，你会考虑买吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/qL5DZI90cRcSNDnj5wu2J1eJR5qcV1BCEtlztjt7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;575&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/qL5DZI90cRcSNDnj5wu2J1eJR 5qcV1BCEtlztjt7. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256342&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 31, Moutai announced that it would increase the volume of Kweichow Moutai by 53% starting from November 1 (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Feitian, Five Star&lt;/span>;) ex-factory price, &lt;strong>;the average increase is about 20%&lt;/strong>;. This adjustment does not involve the market guidance price of the product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Moutai’s first price increase in the past six years. The last time was in January 2018, the ex-factory price of 53-degree Feitian Moutai 500ml was increased from 819 yuan to 969 yuan, and the retail price was adjusted to 1,499 yuan. According to this 20% increase estimate, the ex-factory price of Feitian Moutai may reach about 1,162.8 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moutai’s price increase also has a certain impact on the stock price. On November 1, Kweichow Moutai’s bidding opened 9.82% higher, with the stock price at 1,850 yuan, approaching the daily limit. Although it fell back quickly after the opening, as of 11 a.m., Kweichow Moutai was still up 4.74%, with an intraday turnover of 13.4 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June this year, Ding Xiongjun, chairman of Kweichow Moutai, said at the shareholders’ meeting that one must be wise when and how to raise prices. “If Feitian Moutai can raise prices, there will be more profits.” , the management thinks so too.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a price inversion in the famous liquor market, and Feitian Moutai is almost unique. Combing the ex-factory price and retail price of 53-degree Feitian Moutai from 2004 to 2020, it is not difficult to see that the ex-factory price has been rising all the way, and the retail price has increased by 757%. Among them, there are both the influence of market supply and demand, and consumers’ psychology of “hoarding goods to increase prices”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2020, Ji Keliang, former chairman of Kweichow Moutai, said, &quot;Young people don&#39;t drink Moutai because it&#39;s not time yet.&quot; Will the price increase announced this time have an impact on people’s purchasing intentions? When &quot;Moutai ice cream&quot;, &quot;sauce latte&quot; and &quot;wine-filled chocolate&quot; are released one after another, how many people will pay for that expensive sip of Moutai? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在3260米的香格里拉高山植物园，普通比浪漫重要]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259715]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/01/b1acc0ba09.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 01/b1acc0ba09.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden at an altitude of 3,260 meters. Visual China|Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is it like working in a botanical garden? This has intrigued me for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the countless late nights when I was incompetent in writing, I wanted to resign and go to the botanical garden to be a gardener. The dream soon came true, and the location was actually Shangri-La. In September 2023, I became an intern gardener at Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shangri-La, formerly known as Zhongdian, is located in Diqing Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture, Yunnan. At 3,260 meters, it is the highest botanical garden in the world. It protects about a thousand species of higher plants on land equivalent to 1/5 of the Summer Palace. There are many endemic species named after Zhongdian, such as Zhongdian rose, Zhongdian hawthorn, etc. Some of them are nationally protected wild plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The strange thing is that hundreds of plateau plants are bred here, and they are basically not exotic flowers and plants, or even &quot;ordinary and common&quot;; most botanical gardens belong to The Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden is a public institution with financial allocations, but it is a private non-enterprise organization with &quot;three noes&quot; - &quot;no money&quot;, &quot;no one&quot; and &quot;no establishment&quot;. It was planned to be established in 1999 and opened in 2005. It relies on itself to find a way to survive. road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;All this gives Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden an independent and romantic color. However, after the short internship and interview, the romance had long since dissipated for me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is a story about finding the meaning of ordinary seeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Romantic&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Along the Yunnan-Tibet Highway, starting from Shangri-La County and heading northwest, the buildings gradually recede, and large tracts of golden highland barley suddenly burst in. Come into view. In early September, the Napa Sea formed by the melting of summer snow is gradually turning into the green Yila grassland, with horses roaming and white Tibetan-style houses glowing under the clouds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2bd98486b7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2bd98486b7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;View of Napa Sea from Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden. Photo by Liang Jingyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a corner of this paradise-like scenery is the place where I want to intern: Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At 9 o&#39;clock on September 1st, I started from the east gate of the Botanical Garden, walked through the wild mountains, passed by fungi, climbed over the wooden fence, and almost fell, and I reached the mountainside. nursery. My task today is to move the indoor hypericum seedlings outdoors, and then transport the hypericum to the maze area of ​​the botanical garden on the top of the mountain with a tractor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/7dc6bc48e4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/7dc6bc48e4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tractor loading hypericum in the nursery. Photo by Liang Jingyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sounds so simple. The first step is to change equipment. I put on a red and black plaid bear apron that reached my ankles, put on plastic gloves, and held a big pink basin. The second step is to enter the nursery. A nursery is 24 meters long and 8 meters wide, which is equivalent to a classroom. There were hundreds of black bags on the ground, containing hypericum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/961698f128.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/961698f128.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256371&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 24, 2023, Huaian, Jiangsu Province, hypericum flowers were in full bloom in Jiulong Lake Park. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hypericum is a common flower in parks and greening projects. When it blooms in June and July, the slender bunch of stamens on the top are as bright as gold threads. The bottom petals look like butterfly wings, so they are also called golden thread butterflies. The hypericum I see now has been sown for two years and has not yet bloomed. It has slender branches and oval leaves. It is fragrant when you get close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I found that this botanical garden is different from the ones I have been to before. There are neither weird potted plants nor collections of treasures from around the world. On the contrary, there are many native plants similar to Hypericum in the botanical garden, including pink-flowered Zhongdian thorn rose, blue-purple Zhongdian aconitum, red-fruited Zhongdian hawthorn, standing Yunnan pine and alpine pine...their names Just carry local labels, such as &quot;Zhongdian&quot;, &quot;Yunnan&quot; and &quot;Gaoshan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/288ef03f89.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/288ef03f89.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhongdian Delphinium. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fang Zhendong, the founder and former director of the Botanic Garden, also has a picture of a native plant - Trichosanthes versicolor hanging in his office. He is 59 years old, of medium build, with drooping eyebrows, gray hair, and cheekbones that are black and red rendered by ultraviolet light from the plateau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fang Zhendong is from Weixi, Diqing. The local area lacks biological talents. His college entrance examination application was changed from the mathematics department to the biology department. After graduating from Yunnan University, he returned to Works at Diqing Institute of Plateau Biology. Later, he traveled throughout the mountains and valleys of Diqing and wrote the book &quot;Wild Flowers in the Hengduan Mountains of Yunnan, China&quot;. When he was almost 35 years old, Fang Zhendong wanted to build a world-class botanical garden in Shangri-La. This was also a romantic thing for him at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4975935dd1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4975935dd1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256373&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fang Zhendong was on an inspection trip to Niru High Mountain Area. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yunnan is the base camp of horticultural plants and has been known to foreign &quot;plant hunters&quot; more than a hundred years ago. There are at most 12,000 plant species in Europe, while Yunnan has 17,000 species, and Shangri-La alone has more than 5,000 species. Alpine valleys with large vertical elevation gradients became a refuge for plants during the Ice Age and a breeding ground for biodiversity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A Scotsman named George Forrester was sent to China by the Edinburgh Botanic Garden. Starting in 1904, he conducted seven botanical expeditions in the Hengduan Mountains. . He hired eight Naxi people in Baisha, Lijiang, to move a rhododendron with a diameter of more than one meter from Gaoligong Mountain out of the mountains and transport it to the British Museum for display; he used mules to transport 31,000 Yunnan plant seeds and wax leaf specimens, which were recommended To gardens around the world, specimens are used by taxonomists at the Royal Botanic Gardens in Edinburgh to rename and publish new species. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The azaleas and primroses brought back by Forrest from Yunnan are still being bred in the Edinburgh Botanic Garden, and the specimens are kept in the herbarium. In the 1990s, Fang Zhendong went to Edinburgh Botanic Garden. Looking back now, he is still very touched, &quot;Our local plant resources are valued by foreigners, but what about us?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While talking about this, Fang Zhendong suddenly stood up , found his copy of &quot;Wild Flowers in the Hengduan Mountains of Yunnan, China&quot;, pointed to a passage written by his mentor, the late botanist Mr. Qin Renchang, and read word for word:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yunnan The rich source of plants has contributed to the progress of European and American civilization far and wide. It is a pity that our country is backward in science. The Chinese people did not know how to use the treasures of talent to enrich their lives. Instead, they cultivated them in public and private courtyards in large cities and towns. The flowers that are being viewed are almost all imported and have been common in European and American gardens for hundreds of years. Once they enter the country, those who like them flock to them like birds of prey, sacrificing themselves for others, which is a shame. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This passage was written in the 1930s, but even in the 1990s, native species were not valued and were even threatened by alien species. The situation remains. Fang Zhendong still remembers that at that time, a kind of Eupatorium adenophora native to South America entered from southern Yunnan and approached Diqing along the Yunnan-Vietnam Railway. He worries about the impact of invasive alien species on the local ecosystem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Land use is also changing, with natural pastures being converted into cultivated land, and hillsides being exposed due to sand and stone quarrying. Fang Zhendong discovered that Diqing was originally the area with the richest wild orchid resources in China. In the 1980s, it was not difficult to find orchids every time he entered a ravine. But in the 1990s, the orchid craze took off, and outside owners bought the orchids by the truckload. Since then, wild orchids have been hard to find anywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So Fang Zhendong wants to build a botanical garden. &quot;The first is to conserve local species; the second is to develop and utilize local plant resources for garden construction and cultivation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1999, the Alpine Botanical Garden was approved as a project after discussion by the Yunnan Provincial Development and Reform Commission and the former Environmental Protection Department. A preparatory office was first set up, and Fang Zhendong was appointed as the director. In 2001, construction of the park started, and plants were planted on the exposed scars of sand and stone excavation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2c81e4e808.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2c81e4e808.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256374&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Today, green trees grow from the sand pit in the Alpine Botanic Garden. &amp;nbsp; Liang Jingyi/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Reality&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After I changed my clothes in the nursery, I said two words Don&#39;t talk, let&#39;s do it. I squatted down, used a shovel to dig Hypericum out of the bag, cut off the roots on the ground, and put it into the pot. One bag of Hypericum with seedlings and soil is about 4 pounds, and one pot can hold two bags. After installing it and getting up, I used the strength of my lower back to pick up the pot, walked 10 meters to the outside of the nursery, took out the seedlings, arranged them, and returned. Repeat this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a9dd2c7f83.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;811&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a9dd2c7f83.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Transporting Hypericum seedlings. &amp;nbsp; Liang Jingyi/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2, 4, 6... Every time I transport a pot, I count it silently. The number rises and I feel a sense of accomplishment. But starting from the 10th basin, it was a bit difficult to stand up, and my back began to strain. By the 16th pot, it was no longer a problem. I was gasping for air and my heart was pounding. Do you think I&#39;m weak? But I was doing weight-bearing exercises on a plateau three thousand meters above sea level, moving soil in a place where my speaking speed slowed down significantly and I avoided running and jumping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;20, 22, I can’t hold on anymore. At 10:36, it started to rain and the greenhouse leaked. More than an hour of moving work was stopped. I don’t know how grateful I am for this rain. When I stood up, my vision went dark. The light and the romantic imagination of the botanical garden disappeared in this moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;When building a botanical garden, will there be a moment when romance disappears?&quot; I asked Fang Zhendong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Yes, when it&#39;s time to find money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1999, the office to be built in the Botanical Garden was only It is a temporary agency and cannot pay insurance for newly hired employees. In 2004, the Botanical Garden Office invited relevant departments to a meeting to discuss the management system and came up with two options: one is to jointly build a public institution. The Xishuangbanna Tropical Botanical Garden of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the local government will each establish several establishments to jointly manage it, and it will be operated by central or local financial funds. , which is also a common system in domestic botanical gardens. The other type is private non-enterprise, which is responsible for its own profits and losses, has no financial budget and no establishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We recommended the first set of co-construction plans to the government, but at that time the government&#39;s finances were still relatively difficult and the staffing may be tight, so we proposed the second plan. Take care of it first.&quot; Fang Zhendong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This plan paved the way for subsequent operating pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the Botanical Garden was established as a private non-enterprise, the first board of directors was also established, and Fang Zhendong became the legal representative, chairman and executive director. The pressure came like a mountain, including finding construction funds, paying employees, and also needing to bear ecological compensation for the local community. In total, the annual cost of maintaining the botanical garden is no less than three million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although it is a tourist attraction, it is difficult to make money from tourists. At 17:28 on September 1st, there were still 2 minutes before the park closed. A total of six people bought tickets to enter the botanical garden throughout the day, two foreign tourists and four local tourists, and the total fee was 80 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some employees once felt that tourists now like to check in and take photos, and suggested that &quot;we should keep up with the times and create a cherry blossom avenue.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fang Zhendong denied it very directly, &quot;If you want to see cherry blossoms, go to the park to see them. We are not a park.&quot; He felt that the more important thing &quot;is to show the cherry blossoms.&quot; Domesticated local native species, (this is) our original intention.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Botanic gardens are often in debt. A friend of Fang Zhendong always lends him money. &quot;He is a scientist, not a businessman. He can only write scientific research reports and take on greening projects. Some (projects) still cannot collect money.&quot; Most people&#39;s stress lasts for a month or two at most, but Fang Zhendong persisted for twenty years, relying on scientific research and engineering projects to support it. The situation only eased two or three years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the 24 years since its establishment, the botanical garden, with the efforts of 20 employees, has built many plants including the Fragrant Snow Medicine Garden, Linzhi Spruce Seed Garden, and Alpine Pine Seed Garden. A specialized garden. Although the business situation has improved, some ideas still remain on paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The sign near the south gate of the Botanical Garden says &quot;dry heat type&quot; and &quot;humid type&quot; exhibition greenhouse. Follow the direction and you will see two exposed greenhouses. Crushed limestone. Fang Zhendong made a calculation and found that there are two major parts in greenhouse construction, first is infrastructure construction, and then is species collection and cultivation. The initial investment is estimated to be more than 10 million, and subsequent maintenance will be even more expensive. &quot;Warmth preservation, temperature control, and humidity control must all be considered.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/29ece74f96.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/29ece74f96.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256376&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The greenhouse is still stuck on street signs and planning. &amp;nbsp; Photo by Liang Jingyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Tired.&quot; Fang Ye, the current director of the Botanical Garden, had tired eyes. Three years ago, he took over the botanical garden from his father Fang Zhendong. He wanted to build a smart scenic spot and improve the explanation system, but he was stuck because there was no one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Local young people are more willing to work within the system, while outsiders find it too remote. Fang Ye finally found a person born in Guangxi in 1995 on Weibo. A college student who stayed for 4 years and left &quot;without saying anything&quot;. Four years is already a long time, and Fang Ye is recruiting people now and he doesn&#39;t expect to stay that long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fang Ye still hopes that the botanical garden can be merged into a public institution. Before the merger, this private non-corporate organization has to find its own way out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the rain stopped, I counted more than a hundred bags of hypericum on the wall. A master gardener took off his apron, I saw him wrapped around a white jockstrap. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Seeds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The first step in raising hypericum seedlings in the Alpine Botanical Garden Nursery is naturally to have seeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The gardener took me to see the seeds of Hypericum. As soon as I walked into the seed warehouse on the second floor of the nursery, the scent of rosin hit my face. This is the first time I have seen so many &quot;dry goods&quot;: the cones of alpine pine are like elastic brown balls, the seeds of lupine are like thumb-sized lotus pods, and the fruits of Nyingchi spruce are like hard and sun-dried roses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He grabbed a handful from a large sack and said, &quot;These are the seeds of Hypericum.&quot; I looked closer and saw that they were lighter than sand and smaller than sawdust. They ran away when the wind blew and multiplied with the wind. This is the natural law of survival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But it is difficult for humans to collect seeds. When hypericum planting season comes in November, the botanical garden will invite villagers to collect hypericum seeds in the wild. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But not all seeds can be obtained from villagers. Employees of the botanical garden also have to go to the wild to collect seeds, while also inspecting very small populations and collecting specimens. Extremely small populations refer to wild plants that have a narrow distribution area, are severely disturbed by the outside world, and are on the verge of extinction at any time. It&#39;s extremely difficult to find them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/59774e2679.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/59774e2679.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;256377&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Botanical Garden collects the seeds of S. truncatula. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The diary of an employee named Haixian recorded an &quot;ordinary day&quot; during the inspection:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;August 17, 2020, an ordinary day. Many major events happened in the world, but they have nothing to do with us for the time being. We walked in the back mountains of Naixia Village, Gyirong Town, Gyirong County, Shigatse Prefecture, the Pure Land of Tibet. We focused on field investigation work and were far away from the hustle and bustle of information. It seemed that all rumors had lost their carriers and became nameless islands. In such an environment, we seem to have a lot to say every day, and we seem to say the same thing every day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Are you hungry?&quot;... To be honest, I am also a little hungry, but This is nothing...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;It&#39;s just that the body is like a sponge absorbing the fog and water on the mountain top. It&#39;s full of water, so wet that it feels like it&#39;s been stuffed in a refrigerator when it&#39;s taken off. A cold chill shoots out from your spine. Then the stove was stuffed into the lungs, and the cold air was sucked in, which made the lungs hurt. foot? I don’t have much hope for it anymore, I just hope there won’t be a strike before returning to my residence...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Today I went too long and went too far. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Rising from an altitude of 2,800 meters to an altitude of 4,000 meters, just to look for Huopanglian. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If you can collect seeds, all this hard work will be reduced to a short line in the worksheet. For example:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Haixian, Fang Ye and other high mountain monitoring teams, In the back mountain of Jilong Town, Coptis chinensis seeds. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unlike ordinary seeds that are packed in sacks, those seeds that have been collected with great difficulty are locked in a small room and stored with dignity. In each glass jar or plastic box, here is a seed bank - &quot;Noah&#39;s Ark of plateau plants&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ee1e78f938.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ee1e78f938.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256378&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Seeds in the seed bank. &amp;nbsp; Liang Jingyi/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The green velvet seeds in the small box are like crushed sesame seeds, at the 4786-meter Mangdongda Mountain in Qamdo, Tibet on August 7, 2022 Picked from the pass. Green velvet, also known as &quot;alpine peony&quot; and &quot;dream flower&quot;, grows on flowstone beaches or on the front edge of glaciers at an altitude of more than three or four thousand meters. The whole plant is covered with downy or bristly hairs, and its color is clear and eye-catching. Three species of green velvet have been designated as national secondary key protected wild plants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a21754f83b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1646&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a21754f83b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Green velvet. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After harvesting, the seeds need to go through a process of soaking and seed selection. Empty or underfilled seeds will float up and be fished out and thrown away. . But Liu Lin was reluctant to soak the seeds of green velvet because it was too difficult to collect. &quot;It would be a pity to throw them away if the seedlings can emerge even if they float.&quot; The deputy director of the botanical garden is tall and has two blushes on her face. The table is full of plant tables. She manages the collection, breeding, domestication and utilization of seeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are very few examples of successful breeding of green velvet. On December 5, 2022, Liu Lin and her colleagues planted a batch of green velvet. One month later, the emergence rate was less than 50%. Green velvet &quot;is most likely to die when it grows two leaves. It will die if there is too much water, and it will die if there is too little water, so it is very difficult.&quot; I asked her how many seedlings survived in the end. She pointed to the pile of soil in the distance and said, &quot;Look, half of them are already dead.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After working for more than ten years, Liu Lin has long been accustomed to accepting the death of plants. After many battles and difficult passes, there is still the process of tempering the seedlings after they emerge - taking measures such as ventilation, cooling, and proper water control to train the seedlings. She still remembers the Nepalese yellow flowers she planted for the first time. They were raised in a nursery greenhouse for half a year and moved out to refine the seedlings. All of them died in one winter, and only two or three of the 20,000 trees were left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;We can only start over. They figured that maybe it was too cold and the transplanting season was wrong. So while the Nepalese yellow flower seedlings are still in the greenhouse, occasionally put them out to practice in the sun for a while, and then transplant them when they are firmer. There is no previous experience in the breeding of these plateau native plants, so &quot;we can only try to do it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Like the hypericum I moved today, the seedlings sprout easily, but for some reason, the seedlings tend to die when transplanted. So they came up with a new plan: fill the bag with soil, put the seeds in the soil, and when the seedlings grow up, just tear the bag open and plant it into the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Every slender Hypericum tree I can see is a miracle, having experienced life and death. However, Hypericum is not a rare species and has not been included in the protection list. Where will the native plants that Liu Lin and the master gardeners have worked so hard to breed end up going? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Repair&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 30, 2023, I followed the Greenpeace team in Shangri-La From a road not far away, I saw some mountains that had been blasted away for road construction. Neatly planted cedar trees were planted on the bare plots, but the leaves were wilted and yellow, drooping in the cold mountains. Greenpeace researchers said with regret, &quot;These trees are probably not going to survive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Lin said that many ecological restorations involve buying exotic tree species. , cheap and easy to cut, but difficult to adapt to the local environment, and later maintenance and management are also difficult, seriously affecting the survival rate. Fang Ye explained that many people think that ecological restoration is enough to turn green during inspection and acceptance within one or two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shangri-La suffered large-scale commercial logging in the 1980s and 1990s. After 2010, everyone realized the importance of ecological restoration. However, Fang Zhendong felt that the initial ecological restoration &quot;had no good concepts and ideas at all. The greening company found ready-made tree species based on ready-made plans, regardless of whether the plants could adapt to (the environment).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 28, I attended a seminar on ecological restoration in Shangri-La. Experts from Yunnan University and the Chinese Academy of Forestry also believed that True ecological restoration is not simply about planting trees and greening: planting trees at all costs on the Loess Plateau without allowing thinning, overly dense forests will make things worse for areas with little water; fire may not be the &quot;source of all evil&quot;, for some forests, fire is just Scorch the surface and give the seeds time after burning, and they will come back to life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the seminar, Fang Zhendong took us to see the large-fruited cypress, a tree of the genus Picea in the Pinaceae family, a national second-level protected plant. He said that the policy stipulates that whoever cuts down trees should restore them, and large-scale green trees with large fruits are used for afforestation. When the botanical garden was built, a research team also applied for a vegetation restoration project on degraded forest land and planted 300 acres of large-fruited green cypress in the botanical garden. It grows very slowly when first planted, but grows rapidly after reaching one meter. The fruit is red and smooth, and is very ornamental. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fang Zhendong suddenly stopped explaining, looked for reporters, and reminded me to write it down. He went on to say that a scenic spot in Shangri-La has a large-fruited green tree forest, and diseases and insect pests have appeared one after another. There is a spruce sawfly that eats all the needles off the tree. There is also a fungal disease in which the leaves start to turn yellow inexplicably, and then the entire trunk dries up and the tree dies in pieces. There was also an insect infestation in Shangri-La Alpine Botanical Garden, but it disappeared later, maybe it was controlled by other organisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But in many places, entire spruce trees have been eroded by disease and introduced to the local larch. However, native spruce trees do not develop this disease. &quot;We suggested to the forestry department that we should not use this (large-fruited green tree) species for afforestation in the future, but use our local spruce.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/073c891244.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/01/073c891244.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Big tree in the botanical garden Fruit green skewer Liang Jingyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2006, Fang Zhendong understood the theory of ecological restoration succession: plant communities change dynamically. As time goes by, a plant The community is replaced by another plant community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Starting from the bare surface, grass seeds flew in and evolved into herbaceous vegetation; birds and animals excreted shrub and tree seeds here through feces, evolving into shrubs; trees After more than ten years, it will grow into dominant vegetation and become a forest; different types of trees slowly mature through young and middle age, and become top-level vegetation after hundreds of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Logging and mining are bringing the top vegetation back to the original bare surface. Without human intervention, nature will still start a new cycle of succession. Fang Zhendong&#39;s team is trying to shorten the succession time of hundreds of years. For example, it takes decades to rely on wind birds and beasts to spread seeds, while artificial sowing and transplanting seedlings only take a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the process of succession, some plants are called &quot;pioneer plants&quot;. They sprout quickly and cover the ground surface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Like the Hypericum that I carried?&quot; I asked Fang Zhendong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Yes, it is a pioneer plant. It can grow naturally on burned land at an altitude of 2000-3300 meters.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The native plants in the Shangri-La Botanical Garden have adapted to the cold and harsh environment. During ecological restoration, subsequent maintenance costs are low and they are not susceptible to pests and diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In recent years, failed ecological restoration projects have come to the botanical garden for advice. The botanical garden, which was struggling to operate, also found a way to survive and no longer went into debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4462cf67f4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1129&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/4462cf67f4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256381&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ecological restoration case before and after restoration. &amp;nbsp; Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I went to an ecological restoration case site. This area was once an exposed wasteland due to the construction of a bridge, with limestone, debris, and gravel everywhere. Since 2006, with the help of the theory of natural succession, alpine pine seedlings, Nepalese goldenrod, ruffled-leaf primula, and Yunnan seabuckthorn cultivated in the botanical garden have gradually become pioneer plants, &quot;occupying&quot; the exposed surface. Now, the poplar catkins blown by the wind have taken root here and grown into poplar trees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the distance, the human bones in the sky burial platform have been broken into pieces, and the red-billed crow is circling in Songzanlin Temple. The wild plants in the mountains that were destroyed by people slowly recovered, and ordinary seeds took root and sprouted here for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马大勇：关于三部电影的回忆]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259586]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&quot;Four Weddings and a Funeral&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/sALtonw37jkUcz1EzbAPbtJSujus10HVlqo2d0Gf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;711&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/30/sALtonw37jkUcz1EzbAPbtJSujus10HVlqo2d0Gf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256017&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Four Weddings and A Funeral &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, I remembered Andy again. I&#39;m talking about Andie MacDowell, the heroine of Four Weddings and A Funeral. The poet Zhu Zhu once uniquely compared Juliette Binoche to &quot;the first bite of ice cream in spring.&quot; Yes, everyone has their own bite of ice cream. The difference is that his ice cream is French, while mine is from the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that &quot;Four Weddings and a Funeral&quot; is the representative of British comedy movies, but the overwhelming joy of it has been almost forgotten. What can&#39;t be washed away is Andy&#39;s eyes, which look tenderly and lovingly at Hugh Grant, who always looks hasty and clumsy, and at me, who is also hasty and clumsy. She is the kind of person who is very tolerant and restrained, allowing you to make mistakes and holding you lightly in her arms. During the time when I was in my twenties, Andy had been quietly watching my sadness, unobtrusively and undazzlingly, like the simple and strange flower in my youthful dreams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, she was forgotten. Time flies by, the soul is lost, the youthful mood gradually fades, and there are no more dreams at night. As a result, Andy became a coordinate of his youth, precipitated in the light and shadow of time, eroded and lost day by day. When the world of mortals rises, what is left in our hearts?曾读某些绮丽的小词，感慨良多，遂题一绝句：“饱食心溺笔头禅，滴粉搓酥事惘然。当年我亦钟情甚，曾对春风写缠绵。”当春天的冰淇淋一点点融化，梦里的奇花一丝丝凋零，安迪，我们都抵挡不住光阴的魔杖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“自古美人如名将，不许人间见白头”，一转眼，安迪有六十几岁了吧？在网上已不易找到她青春的底片。奥黛丽·赫本、凯瑟琳·泽塔·琼斯、苏菲·玛索、张曼玉、关之琳、钟丽缇、朱茵……午夜对镜，她们该是如何爱怜地想起自己灿放的红颜？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;《时光倒流七十年》&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/vpztrExXnh6Tp89qxkOGuwoYdapFWWvdWJCAtFYr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/vpztrExXnh6Tp89qxkOGuwoYdapFWWvdWJCAtFYr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256018&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Somewhere in Time &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“春天的花开秋天的风以及冬天的落阳，忧郁的青春年少的我曾经无知地这么想”，在二十世纪八九十年代的大学校园，再也没有另外的音乐比罗大佑的这首歌更能拨动我们的心弦。我是一个对时光颇为敏感的人，少年时候就会沉浸在她的魔力中不能自拔，再后来看过了穷途，看过了传奇，看过了浮沉，也看过了生死，终于明白时光可以治疗一切，雕刻一切，那就已经走向中年的沧桑了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是有很长一段时间狂热地关注时光电影。因为电影是认识时光的途径之一，它有无穷的假设能力，也有无穷的表现能力，带给我无穷的感动和哀愁。同样属于青春岁月的一部电影：《时光倒流七十年》（Somewhere in Time），当结尾处男主角看到硬币上镶嵌着今天的日月，而七十年前的美人瞬间向着时光的那一端飘落，那是怎样的天荒地老的惆怅，又何其令人悚然！时光题材的电影通常有惊人的视觉效果，像《回到未来》，像《黑洞频率》，像《时间机器》，这部没有，它是靠时光本身来制造效果的，如一杯纯正的苦丁茶，没有任何附加的味道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;《肖申克的救赎》&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kcje4CxpjUT7PJW6oRdUxKTdl0CK4IBNe9MBXEOL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;453&quot; height=&quot;664&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/kcje4CxpjUT7PJW6oRdUxKTdl0CK4IBNe9MBXEOL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256019&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Shawshank Redeption&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，什么才是时光的味道呢？对我来说，至少，那些画面模糊、跳动的黑白录像带算是一种吧。喜爱上了电影之后，有那么长一段时间是那些黑白光影在陪伴着我，朝夕晨昏，像是看不清也记不住的一个个幻梦。 《美国往事》《去年在马里昂巴》《芳芳》《红》《地下》，对了，还有那部永远跳不过去的《肖申克的救赎》（The Shawshank Redeption）。在看过了几十次之后，我至今也不大能说清它的魅力所在，或者，任何阐述和说明都是没必要的，如佛家所云，会成为“文字障”？但是，有些句子我仍可以随意在记忆的仓库中提取（感谢录像带版的字幕组，他们的中文版本比史蒂芬·金毫无逊色）：“我们听不懂里面唱的什么，但那好像是天使的声音，使厚重的石墙消失无踪。在此瞬间，鲨堡众囚重获自由”“忙啊，忙着活，或者忙着死”“有些鸟是关不住的，因为它们的羽翼太光辉了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;羽翼光辉的鸟儿们在我曾经黯淡的世界里盘桓，没有它们的鸣叫，我们将永远是绝望的囚徒。在那个夜晚盯着跳动的黑白光影，听着录像带“咝咝”的回响，我的牢笼也消失无踪，我来到了月亮和星辰之上，咀嚼着时光的味道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是电影。对我来说，它可能意味着一种生存的方法，风定尘落，天空降下了幸福和吉祥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网络实名制，在争论中从“幕后”走向“前台”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259710]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 11:45:10&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;大V们将面临一次前台实名制考验。农健插画&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d7b3195417.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d7b3195417.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256323&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;大V们将面临一次前台实名制考验。农健插画&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“全网自媒体要实施前台实名制了。”2023年10月中旬，拥有350多万粉丝的财经博主“洪榕”在微博发布了这则消息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几乎同时，微博CEO王高飞开始在其微博账号“来去之间”个人信息栏中展示本人真实姓名，标识“自媒体前台实名”，并多次与微博网友就相关话题留言互动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月31日晚间，微博发布公告称，将于近期引导社会时事、军事、财经、医疗、法律等专业领域100万以上粉丝的自媒体账号填写实名信息，后续拓展到50万粉丝以上的。 B站、微信、抖音、快手等平台亦发布类似消息，对“头部自媒体”施行前台实名制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在过去的十多年，网络实名制经历了从无到有、从局部到全面的发展历程。从2011年地方文件要求微博用户“后台实名、前台自愿”，2017年微博全面落地这一要求，再到此次，实名制逐步从幕后走向了前台。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这迅速引发了社会激辩。在过往，几乎每一次有关实名制的要求一出，都会伴随类似争论。支持者认为，网络实名制可以增强网络活动的规范性和责任意识，有助于肃清谣言、淫秽信息，减少网络暴力或者利用虚假信息发生的违法犯罪，提高网民生活的安全感等；反对者认为，实名制不仅影响了信息安全和公开表达的松弛感，还危及个人信息安全。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而前台实名制，使得个人信息由少部分平台集中采集变为暴露在广泛的公众视野里，其影响更为复杂多样，亦有学者公开建议：“兹事体大，不宜贸然推出”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;不只微博一家&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;南方周末观察到，至10月31日晚间，不少100万粉丝以上的微博大V，仍属前台“匿名”状态。在B站、抖音等平台，大部分相关领域的头部自媒体，也未见个人主页展示实名信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据微博公告，平台会引导用户填写需要在前台展示的信息。按照王高飞在其个人页面的内测信息，未来或要求展示的个人信息包括真实姓名、性别、星座、职业、IP属地等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末此前获取的微博发送给大V的私信显示，首批前台实名的自媒体账号需要在10月底之前进行前台实名，50万-100万粉丝的账号在12月底前完成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，前述私信中提到，此次实名制要求全网所有平台统一执行，“关于前台实名制，微博、抖音、腾讯等平台已经沟通争取过很多次，如果造成困扰，您可以将意见建议通过自己渠道反馈，也可以提交给我们代为转交”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从各大平台已发布的公告信息不难发现，头部自媒体前台实名制已成必然，平台间主要差别在于首批实名自媒体账号的粉丝数量。除了抖音从50万以上粉丝的账号开始推行，其余均是从100万以上粉丝的账号开始，后续逐步扩大到50万粉丝以上的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这次没有标准的、明确的执行文件，各个平台只能基于各自的平台属性和既往的审核重点，摸索推行。”某平台内部人士透露。据其介绍，前台实名与内容审核略有不同，后者有一定的“自由裁量空间”，前者达到一定量级必须执行，其所在平台将对粉丝量较大、对某一领域影响力较大的账号优先要求前台实名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于此次背景，前述私信中表示，是进一步落实国家网信办的“自媒体13条管理规定”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，国家网信办发布通知，为加强“自媒体”管理，压实网站平台信息内容管理主体责任，健全常态化管理制度机制，要求网站平台应当“对从事金融、教育、医疗卫生、司法等领域信息内容生产的&#39;自媒体&#39;进行严格核验，并在账号主页展示其服务资质、职业资格、专业背景等认证材料名称，加注所属领域标签”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“受多重因素影响，我觉得，应对目前日益严重的网暴问题、构建更良好网络内容生态，是重中之重。”中国传媒大学教授王四新说，近年来网暴问题频繁发生，从2022年开始，相关部门密集出台了多项针对性措施，平台方也是进一步落实各自责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王四新是国家网信办咨询专家，参与过包括网络安全法、《网络信息内容生态治理规定》等的立法工作。他解释，由于大V往往拥有更广泛的社会影响力，且不乏背景复杂、目的多样的，部分大V背后有自己的团队，其网络活动包括发言、代言等，都有商业利益诉求，实践中难以排除为了经济利益而误导公众的可能性，给信息生态良性发展带来不少负面影响。 “前台实名制有利于这些大V增强社会责任感和风险意识、规范他们在网络空间的行为。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于部分微博用户提出的不愿实名问题，王高飞在微博回应，用户可以通过清粉，把粉丝删到100万以下，或者把发帖内容更换到其它领域。前述私信也提到，可以协助用户“检测垃圾粉丝并帮助清理”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，微博公告还称，对于应实名而不愿实名的用户，将部分限制该账号的流量和收入，包括推荐流展示限制、热搜展示限制、广告分成限制、打赏收入限制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“目前相关细则还不清晰，平台方应该要平衡好前台实名和个人信息安全的问题，比如提前告知的义务，是否有必要在前台展示大V的工作单位和职务信息，其所在单位是否可以拒绝，个人如果不愿意是否有退出机制，需要设置好程序。”中国政法大学传播法研究中心副主任朱巍说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“前台展示什么样的个人信息，区别还是很大的。”朱巍举例，比如一个医生大V，披露其所属职业类型是某科医生，可能会比披露所在单位和职务信息更能减少网暴的发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微博前述公告中，涉及前台信息保护的内容为：对于未登录、未通过真实身份信息验证、行为异常以及近期被处置的用户，禁止查看其他用户前台实名信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;二十余年演进与变化&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;早在2002年，清华大学新闻学院（现为新闻与传播学院）教授李希光在接受电视台访谈中提到，建议人大应该禁止任何人网上匿名，引发公众热烈讨论。这被媒体认为是网络实名制第一次进入中国公众视野。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在随后十年间，网络实名制开始部分试水。 2004年，教育部发布《关于进一步加强高等学校校园网络管理工作的意见》，“网络实名制”被正式写进了官方文件，高校网络论坛开始执行用户实名注册；2005年，腾讯根据深圳公安《关于开展网络公共信息服务场所清理整治工作的通知》，对QQ群的创建者及管理员开展实名登记；2006年，国家新闻出版总署提出《网络游戏实名制方案》，要求网游玩家进行实名注册，以区分成年人与未成年人……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到2011年，实名制要求再次引发较高关注。当年，北京颁布《北京市微博客发展管理若干规定》，提出微博用户在注册时必须使用真实身份信息，实行“后台实名，前台自愿”。随后，微博公开表示，对新用户推行实名注册，并且逐步完善老用户的实名审核。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于为何要求微博用户实名，2012年，时任国家网信办主任王晨公开回应，表示微博具有传播快、影响大、覆盖广的特点，有很强的社会动员力。微博改变了既往舆论传播格局，在反映社情民意，丰富信息服务，进行舆论监督的同时，也使一些负面舆论、淫秽色情、编造谎言等有害信息迅速传播。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“微博从2009年开始，利用在平台产生的影响力，在许多涉及公共利益的问题上，对公共舆论的形成和走向产生了巨大影响。2011年前后中国发生的许多公共事件，都成为互联网的热炒素材。”王四新进一步阐释，后来形成的一系列管理措施当中，有许多要求是在吸取了这些教训的基础上形成的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王四新举例，在2011年7月，温州动车事故发生时，“网络上充斥着各种关于事故的谣言，后来逐渐离谱，演变到对中国高铁、国家经济发展模式的攻击”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现有的管理很不适应，对网络信息安全和社会和谐稳定提出了新挑战。”王晨在上述发言中提到。 “网络实名的监管要求，也是在这一大背景下提出并逐步开始实施的。”王四新说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年，《全国人民代表大会常务委员会关于加强网络信息保护的决定》公布并实施，以法律性文件的形式，明确要求网络服务平台需要对用户进行实名制登记。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一个有关网络实名制的关注高潮，发生在2016年前后。 2016年网络安全法出台，并于2017年施行。该法第二十四条规定：网络运营者在与用户签订协议或者确认提供服务时，应当要求用户提供真实身份信息，不提供真实身份信息的，不得为其提供服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年8月，国家网信办发布《互联网跟帖评论服务管理规定》，要求所有网络平台按照“后台实名、前台自愿”原则，对注册用户进行真实身份信息认证，否则不得向其提供跟帖评论服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同年，微博发布“关于微博推进完成账号实名制的公告”，要求所有用户必须在2017年9月15日之前完成实名验证，否则将无法再发送评论及新帖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;立法和相关规范性要求的颁布，也受一些事件的催动。王四新介绍，2013年发生的斯诺登“棱镜门”事件（美国实施的电子监听计划），引发了高层对国家网络信息安全的高度关注，有关网络安全的立法等相关工作也加快推进。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，电话实名制也给网络注册实名制提供了便利。 2013年，工信部要求用户办理固定电话、移动电话、宽带等入网过户业务时，必须提供真实身份信息。并在2015年下旬，停止运营商对非实名号码的服务。而网络服务平台，大多以手机号验证方式完成注册审核。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;国外实名制得失&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;目前，国际上对于网络环境监管较为普遍。比如，英国出台了通信数据法案，规定网络用户需要登记姓名、住址等个人信息；美国的手机网上通信服务需要绑定可识别个人信息的社会安全号；德国也出台了监管互联网的法律，对提供网上经营活动的商家、网络邮件、电话和手机用户实行实名登记。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也有地方要求公众向市场化服务平台提供个人身份信息。南方周末从美国、加拿大、英国、德国、澳大利亚等国的网民，以及数名曾有多国旅居经历的华人处获悉，目前许多国家的企业服务平台不需要直接进行实名注册，但也有国家要求绑定与个人信息关联的邮箱或手机号。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要求前台实名的并不多。在王四新看来，这次网络服务平台的前台实名制要求，“本质上还是前序网络实名制管理的细化规范，很多工作的开展都不是一步到位的，需要循序渐进，逐步推进。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;实际上，在中国的网络实名制既往进程上，几乎每进一步都引发高度关注，尤其是关于社交平台、资讯服务等市场化平台的实名制，往往会引起各方激辩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末检索既往文献和报道发现，实名制的支持者普遍认为，网络的匿名性催生了网络语言暴力、造谣诽谤、网络欺诈甚至违法犯罪等系列问题，近年来频发的网暴事件，也给一些社会事件的当事人，带来严重的身心伤害，而实名制是解决上述问题的良药。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在很多自媒体背后是一个团队在操作，往往裹挟一些商业诉求，海量粉丝的自媒体账号有必要公开自己的真实身份，为其网络发言负责。”朱巍说。他补充，有关网暴案件的诉讼，举证责任都在原告，但需要经过法院向平台调取才能取得涉嫌侵权主体的个人信息，而前台实名制也可以简化这个过程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而反对者大多认为，实名制抑制了公开讨论、表达真实想法、提出有价值观点的积极性，不利于宣泄情绪、疏导矛盾。近年来，亦有不少腐败案件是通过网络匿名举报的形式侦破的，而实名制会给举报者带来压力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无论是社会心理学还是传播学都证实了，在个人信息趋于透明的环境下，人的言行也倾向于从众，而从众的人往往鲜少具备创新意识。从社会发展的角度来说，前台实名不利于鼓励人们活跃思维、勇于创新。”清华大学法学院教授劳东燕说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劳东燕还认为，前台实名制未必能解决网暴问题，反而有可能催生某种“精准网暴”。 “我是2022年开始使用微博的，一直是实名，多次因参与公共话题的讨论而遭遇谩骂侮辱，有人不仅线上@我的单位举报我，甚至还发展到线下。前台实名制为这些人提供了方便。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有关实名制的担忧中，一个议题贯穿始终：网络实名制会影响个人信息安全。这种担心并非无中生有。 2017年，公安部曾有专家对媒体表示，网络实名制的泛化确实影响到了个人信息安全。个人身份证号、人脸识别等采集信息越多，泄露也越多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国内已有相关事件。 2016年，山东学生徐玉玉因被诈骗电话骗走上大学的费用，郁结于心，最终导致心脏骤停离世。据媒体报道，该案中学生信息泄露，就是不法分子攻击了当地教育局的考生信息系统所致。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国际上也不乏先例。 2005年，韩国一女孩因拒绝清理宠物粪便而遭遇网暴，导致女孩被迫退学并患上精神病。为治理网暴，从当年开始，韩国政府开始逐步要求公众落实网络实名，其间分梯度、分领域渐次推进，并辅以完善立法等措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到2010年，共有167家韩国网站执行网络实名制，主要是大型门户网站、新闻网站和购物平台。然而，2010—2012年间，多家平台发生大规模用户信息泄露事件，其中最大规模的波及3500万人，而韩国2010年的总人口仅4800余万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2012年8月，韩国网络实名制被叫停。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在电信诈骗分子非常猖獗，已经不是你拉黑个别手机号能解决的，因为对方往往用的是虚拟号，随时随地都可能接到诈骗电话。”劳东燕说，她本人曾多次在半夜被电诈电话吵醒，已经不堪其扰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关部门也在强化对个人信息安全的保护。 2012年全国人大关于网络信息安全的决定、2016年出台的网络安全法，均对平台采集、使用、保护公民个人信息作出了禁止性规范。 2021年，个人信息保护法也正式实施，对个人信息保护作出全方位规范性要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，公安部门打击境内、跨境电信诈骗的力度也在不断加强，除了常规侦破相关案件，还多次发起专项行动，集中打击电信诈骗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王四新表示，未来互联网信息传播的监管会更加规范，“依法管网、依法用网和依法提供服务，将成为网络文明建设过程中的常态”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州地铁要求乘客卸妆惊悚形象？南周记者实地探了探究竟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259708]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[除了上厕所不能随意活动？部分中小学生课间10分钟被约束现象调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259681]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;课间10分钟对学生来说十分宝贵。自由奔跑的身影和时时传来的欢声笑语，是校园充满活力的风景。但“新华视点”记者近期在一些地方调查发现，部分中小学生课间10分钟被约束，除喝水和上厕所外，不能走出教室活动，甚至不能随意离开座位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教育部制定的《未成年人学校保护规定》明确要求，不得对学生在课间及其他非教学时间的正当交流、游戏、出教室活动等言行自由设置不必要的约束。那么，为什么一些学校要严管学生的10分钟课间活动？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;小课间校园变得静悄悄&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;课间10分钟俗称小课间，是中小学生调节学习状态、缓解疲劳和相互交流的重要时段。记者日前在多所中小学走访看到，由于小课间学生被要求不能随意离开教室，校园里变得静悄悄。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;据了解，这一现象由来已久。2019年的一项针对1900余名家长的调查显示，75.2%的家长认为身边中小学“安静的小课间”现象普遍，且在小学最为突出。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;长春市多所小学的学生家长反映，学校要求孩子小课间不能去操场玩耍，只能上厕所或在走廊内安静地活动。一位家长说，孩子的班主任规定，课间除上厕所外，都要待在座位上。“有学生曾因课间在教室打闹被惩罚。从那以后，他们下课后再也不敢跑来跑去了。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;海口市多所小学安排值日老师在每层楼巡查，严禁学生在走廊追逐玩耍。有的学校还抽选少先队员组建值日团队，对各班学生课间的行为进行计分考核，一旦发现追逐打闹现象，就给班级扣分，考核与文明班级评选直接挂钩。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;河北、贵州等地一些中小学也存在类似现象。记者在河北省廊坊市一所小学看到，除了一些学生上厕所，大部分孩子在下课后都坐在教室聊天。贵州遵义某小学教师张栩（化名）说，有部分班主任不让学生小课间到操场玩，“这样做太压抑孩子的天性了”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;海口市多名小学生家长介绍，只有少数教师重视学生小课间的体育锻炼，大部分教师会以强调纪律为名，想方设法让好动的小学生安静下来，美其名曰“文明休息”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;过度约束&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;不利于&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;孩子健康成长&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;为何小课间学生被过度约束的现象频发？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;有受访教师表示，主要是因为场地有限、人员密集，学生在操场上玩耍时常常出现磕碰等意外情况。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;河北某县一所小学的教师说，一旦学生课间活动时出现磕碰等意外情况，校方不仅需要向家长道歉，还可能涉及经济赔偿。为此，学校干脆强调课间纪律，减少孩子外出活动，“多一事不如少一事”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;此外，场地的客观条件限制也是一个重要原因。多名受访教师反映，不少城区学校教学楼建得比较高，小课间只有10分钟，学生跑上跑下电梯不够用，楼道狭窄容易产生拥挤踩踏风险。而且，市区学校的操场规模小、孩子多，常常也跑动不开。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;不少家长认为，约束孩子课间活动，主要是学校和教师为了方便管理、减少麻烦。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;一些受访的基层教育工作者也认为，小课间被过分约束的做法违反教育部的规定，也是学校管理粗放、懒政的表现。严格限制中小学生课间活动范围、活动强度，虽可减少意外发生的几率，但不利于孩子健康成长。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这种做法会压抑孩子天性、不利于身体发育。心理专家认为，小课间走出教室适当运动，可以舒缓学习压力、促进人际交往。吉林大学第三医院脊柱外科副主任医师尹若峰说，较重的课业负担和日益减少的身体活动等，是影响中小学生身体姿态、脊柱健康的重要因素。小课间走出教室活动四肢，有利于学生的身体健康。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;国家卫健委数据显示，2022年我国儿童青少年总体近视率为53.6%。受访眼科专家介绍，参加户外运动是防控近视的重要手段，小课间被“挤占”会导致中小学生户外运动时间减少，近视概率增加。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;此外，这种做法也容易令学生产生厌学情绪。长春市外国语实验学校小学部副校长沈微指出，长时间待在教室可能会导致学生精神倦怠；学生利用课间调节、放松身体和头脑，有助于集中精力上好下节课。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;坚决落实国家保护&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;未成年人相关规定&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2021年9月1日正式施行的《未成年人学校保护规定》要求，学校不得设置侵犯学生人身自由的管理措施，不得对学生在课间及其他非教学时间的正当交流、游戏、出教室活动等言行自由设置不必要的约束；学校应当完善管理制度，保障学生在课间、课后使用学校的体育运动场地、设施开展体育锻炼。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/be1e0af9353df253306c927ce8cf3a43.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/be1e0af9353df253306c927ce8cf3a43.png&quot; data-key=&quot;256262&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;长春市外国语实验学校小学部学生课间在操场&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;跳绳。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（受访者供图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;记者采访了解到，有些学校利用小课间开展丰富多彩的户外活动。比如，长春市外国语实验学校小学部开辟了篮球、排球等活动区域，学生可根据个人兴趣选择。同时，在学校的支持下，班主任也鼓励学生尽量外出活动。河北省邯郸市丛台区连城小学不仅配有篮球、足球和羽毛球等运动设备，还在教室里配备了图书、象棋和五子棋等物品，便于学生课间取用。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;受访教师和家长认为，把小课间还给孩子，需要综合施策。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;作为校园安全管理中的重要一环，学校要常态化开展校园安全隐患排查，将校园安全工作做细致、做扎实。沈微介绍，长春市外国语实验学校小学部一至六年级共有学生1980人，为保障学生课间活动的安全和秩序，学校派出6名体育教师、6名各年级教师和学生干部在走廊、楼梯、操场进行巡查、值周，大多数学生能做到秩序井然地上下楼。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;专家建议，教育主管部门要出台指导意见，通过督导加强对学校的监督管理，把课间时间尽可能还给学生。学校还要加强对学生进行运动、游戏的技能指导和安全教育，降低意外发生的概率。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;受访对象认为，在校园管理规范、校内设施安全到位的情况下，出现校园安全问题时，社会和家长不能一味将责任推给学校和教师。可以建立由政府部门或第三方机构规范处理校园安全事件的工作机制，降低学校与家长产生直接矛盾的概率。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“年纪大了，玩芭比有点幼稚”：棉花娃娃寄托的情感生意]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259679]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年4月30日，昆明，市民带着棉花娃娃在蓝花楹大道拍照。（视觉中国/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/8f13252fa1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/8f13252fa1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256264&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年4月30日，昆明，市民带着棉花娃娃在蓝花楹大道拍照。 （视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当“海底捞拒绝给棉花娃娃过生日”的新闻传来，芝桃（网名）赶紧清空了发在QQ空间的照片。那是几个月前，她给自己的棉花娃娃“路飞”过生日时拍下的纪念——和普通公仔稍显不同，这个动漫《海贼王》里的角色，有一颗不成比例的大脑袋，眼睛炯炯有神，咧着嘴傻笑，标志性的月牙刘海一整个将其罩住。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;只见路飞正襟危坐，面前摆着一排小蛋糕，照片下方，芝桃情真意切地打出一行字：又长一岁啦，生日快乐！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“因为（海底捞）那个事嘛，害怕被别人说。”芝桃是一位棉花娃娃爱好者，按照这个圈子的通行玩法，玩家如同养孩子一般，给自己的娃娃添置衣服、饰品，带着它们出去旅游、聚会，甚至是过生日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过，也因为外界对这些行为不理解，互称“娃友”的玩家们遭到诸多非议。 “网友说这是神经病，话很难听。”芝桃刚刚升入大三，和很多娃友一样，性格偏于内向、敏感，为不善人际交往所困扰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;棉花娃娃是一种近来在年轻人当中悄然走红的潮流玩偶。 2023年10月16日，一位消费者带着自己的棉花娃娃到海底捞进餐时，被服务员拒绝提供给玩偶过生日的服务，此事发酵成为社交平台热搜话题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;棉花娃娃究竟有着何种魅力，能够让年轻消费者慷慨解囊？为何90后、00后们，会把自己的情感需求，寄托在一个毛绒玩具身上？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;娃友：“现实中没见过这么好的男生”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;给路飞过生日，是芝桃临时冒出来的想法。那天是“五一”假期的末尾，同寝室的舍友还没有返校。白天，她和妈妈吵了一下，电话里被反复询问，放假为什么不回家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;芝桃心情低落，在校园里漫无目的地走着，刷到同学在朋友圈祝贺路飞生日快乐，她情绪一下“支棱”起来，到小店里简单购置几个蛋糕，准备给这个陪伴自己成长的“小伙伴”过一下生日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;通常，漫画作者会在公司网站公布角色生日。路飞是日本热血动漫《海贼王》的主角，他勇敢无畏、执着乐观的性格，以及对待朋友纯真善良、重情重义的特质，让芝桃为之倾倒。 “可能，我也希望过自己是这样的人，或者希望有这样的朋友。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;宿舍里只有她一个人，从小到大已经习惯孤单生活的芝桃，把床头的棉花娃娃路飞放在桌上，再摆上小蛋糕，瞬间仿佛和这个小伙伴有了情感链接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;芝桃解释，对于棉花娃娃，她其实属于典型的“穷养”模式，即便如此，偶尔看到好看的饰品，还是忍不住买来给路飞配上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我算是富养娃。”19岁的周舟也是一位娃友，她养的棉花娃娃名叫丸子。刚入手的时候，丸子只是一个“裸娃”——没有什么装饰。看到好看的发卡、帽子和围巾，周舟就很想买回来给娃娃戴上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;她还会给丸子买衣服，刚开始只是淘一些婴儿服，感觉大小尺寸总是差了一点。后来，干脆像当初“团购”娃娃一样，去定制一些衣服，不过价格略贵，周期也会长一些。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;周舟说，除了打扮娃娃，她有时候还会“整活”。比如做作业的时候，让丸子在旁边陪着，然后把对话拍成视频传到网络平台，“一边做作业，一边问丸子，你爸爸不是医生吗，这题你会不会呀？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在圈子里，那些有角色原型的玩偶，被称为“有属性娃娃”。丸子的角色原型来自一款女性向网络游戏，在游戏里，周舟代入的一个女性角色和一个名叫查理苏的医生谈恋爱，丸子则是爱情的结晶。 “丸子娃娃，是三次元世界的宝宝，这种陪伴和寄托有一种实在感，让我感觉很幸福。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“现实生活中，没见过查理苏这么好的男生。”查理苏的人物设定是浪漫、善良，以及尊重女性。周舟说，游戏里有五个男主角，她刚开始没有关注到查理苏，但是渐渐被对方的细心所吸引，尤其是看到查理苏的书房里藏着一本《房思琪的初恋乐园》，瞬间被这个细节打动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;周舟是学生物专业的“理工女生”，在安徽合肥读大二，现实生活中还没有谈过恋爱。 “每天打开微博、抖音，全都是&#39;恐婚&#39;预警。”她说，作为女性，经常能感知到外界的不友好行为，这让她对步入一段感情保持谨慎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;棉花娃娃之于娃友，往往起到寄托感情的作用，这些情感的面向十分广泛。 “我从小就缺乏陪伴。”芝桃解释，她生长在单亲家庭，妈妈一个人开工厂，平时非常忙碌，每天要很晚才回家。在漫长的青少年时期，她都是一个人待在家里看电视、刷手机，以及翻阅漫画书度过。 “五一的时候，其实我也想回去，可是回去了，也是一个人在家，还不如在宿舍一个人待着。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除了路飞，芝桃还定做过一个原型叫影山茂夫的娃娃，这是日本动漫《灵能百分百》的男主角。影山茂夫具有超能力，可以帮助很多人，却因为不擅长和人打交道而感到自卑、忧郁，通过痛苦的成长，慢慢接纳了不完美的自己。 “路飞和影山茂夫就是我性格的一体两面。”芝桃说，把路飞和影山茂夫两个娃娃放在床头，自己感到很踏实。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;一些娃友会为棉花娃娃布置娃屋。（受访者供图/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/96e9831b87.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/96e9831b87.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256265&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;一些娃友会为棉花娃娃布置娃屋。 （受访者供图/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;娃妈：“没有人卖，就自己做”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;芝桃回忆，给路飞过完生日后，她悄悄把照片发在了少人关注的QQ空间，偶尔自己翻一下，“主要是害怕别人不理解，会说你”。所以，当海底捞事件的争议出来后，敏感的她赶快删除了这段痕迹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;她感谢棉花娃娃的出现，让她找到能够理解彼此行为的同类。芝桃解释，最热门的棉花娃娃是当下最火的动漫、游戏、剧集或者“爱豆”，因为刚流行起来，周边产品还不够完善，粉丝想要表达爱意，需要通过DIY的方式，制作寄托情感的棉花娃娃。 “就是表达情感的途径有点少，那就自己做。”其中，又分为养成系娃娃和爱豆娃娃，就是把娃娃当成孩子一样养育，或者当作明星那样去追捧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;和外界认知稍显不同，路飞这样的动漫“大众偶像”，虽然拥趸众多，但其实并不是最受追捧的娃娃，“因为《海贼王》火了很久了，各种周边非常多，选择多。”芝桃同样喜欢的影山茂夫，也不是热门娃娃，因为这部动漫时间有点久，却相对冷门，知道它、喜欢它的人并不多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以，当芝桃在社交媒体刷到自己喜爱角色的帖子或周边，就会感到很欣喜，“啊，没想到这种冷门的角色，也有娃娃”。她介绍，在社交平台会有同好者，发帖子征集粉丝，一起团购棉花娃娃。粉丝如果有意向便主动联系帖主，然后被拉到一个电商平台的团购群内交流，“至少拉够50个，才能成团”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这个发起人，就被娃友们称为“娃妈”。 “娃妈相当于饭圈的&#39;粉头&#39;，其实也是爱好者。”她解释，通常棉花娃娃是由娃妈先期找人或者自己亲自设计，会事先公布娃娃的图样、尺寸，征询大家的意见，如果对设计不满，可以提出修改意见。待到定稿之后，娃妈再到工厂做出来一个样品，样品满意便可以出货。这个周期，通常需要几个月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“一般九百多块打一个样。”同眠（网名）正是传说中的娃妈，她说，开团之前得先画草图，因为有一点绘画基础，所以自己出设计稿。画完之后，发到社交平台找人，行话叫做“蹲坑”，看感兴趣的人多不多，如果能蹲到一些人，就开始建群，陆续进群讨论之后，才找工厂打样，“满意的话就做货，不满意继续打样，最多可以打三次”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;同眠说，她是兼职做这项工作，相当于为爱发电。一开始，她非常喜欢游戏《光与夜之恋》里边齐司礼这个角色，所以想拥有一个玩偶，可是找遍各大电商平台一无所获，“没有人卖了，所以我决定自己做”。做好后，娃娃加邮费合计70元，同眠还会送一些小饰品。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在交流群里，除了交换对图纸、样品的意见外，娃妈还会公布制作进度、和工厂主的交流细节以及费用明细，整个过程，更像是粉丝爱好者的DIY。娃妈们看到自己的想法一点点变成现实，会收获成就感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;企业：“小众，批量太少”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;芝桃发现，有娃妈在群公告中明确表示，拒绝未成年人“开团”。 “一个娃娃几十块钱还蛮贵的，是害怕都已经下厂了，家长觉得贵找过来退货。”她解释，喜欢某个特定角色的娃友，人数本来就少，对于工厂而言，她们的单量实在太小，是能够开机生产的最小限度。 “娃妈本来就是用爱发电，如果退货的话，就要贴钱去做这个事了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以，虽然五六十元一个娃娃不算便宜，但是芝桃觉得合情合理。 “毕竟喜欢这个的人太少了。”她说，一些大IP的衍生品非常丰富，选择面很广，而小众爱好的周边，只能通过DIY的方式获取。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;创业者冯赫（化名）并非动漫迷或者饭圈人士，他留意到棉花娃娃不是出于爱好，而是本能的商业嗅觉。不过，在切入这个赛道之后，他渐渐领悟到，这一新鲜事物为什么是以粉丝开团的形式出现，“主要还是小众，比较特殊，没想象中那么好搞”。冯赫是广东中山一家棉花娃娃公司的创始人，刚开始他也是找工厂代工，后来购置了机器自己来做。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“最主要的难点，还是批量太少。”冯赫介绍，棉花娃娃的品类繁多，但是单一品类的生产数量却十分有限。珠三角有着大量玩具类代工工厂，但是对于他们而言，每一笔订单数实在过于微小。 “他们主要还是接外国的单，以出口为主。”刚刚介入这个行业时，他要频繁和工厂沟通，消耗大量时间和精力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过，冯赫还是不愿意错过这个新兴市场，于是成立公司、买了机器，决定开工厂自己干。 “最主要的成本是人员和管理成本。”他介绍，一位成熟的打样师傅月薪至少8000元，机床师傅需要6800元，还有绣花工、杂工每个月的工资都在6000元以上，而一个成熟的绣花工一天至多能缝合40个娃娃。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;即便是已经开起工厂，他们接单的方式，仍然是发帖子，凑够人数再开团。根据娃娃尺寸大小、开团数量的不同，定价会有不同，区间多为几十元波动。 “虽然现在很火，但是在玩偶这个大市场里，是一个很小的细分门类。”他说，棉花娃娃其实是对制造业的一次升级，之前大批量的出口贸易增长放缓后，只有承接这类小批量、多批次的需求才有出路，这对企业管理、成本管控提出了更高要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;即便是外部创业者陆续介入，灵活、微小仍然是这个行业的特征。一家电商平台的数据显示，有成交记录的棉花娃娃商家数量，从2017年的不到400家，到2020年底已经达到了近万家，3年间增长了20多倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;品牌&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;首要问题是&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;版权&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;小七（网名）也是一个棉花娃娃爱好者，她在一家小型棉花娃娃公司上班，近水楼台，收集到二十多个娃娃。作为重度玩家，她会给娃娃换不同的刘海、衣服，在脸上打腮红，到网红咖啡店打卡拍照。她还在衣柜上腾出空间盖了一间“娃屋”，按照社交媒体上的教程挂上挂钩、图画等道具，布置娃娃的房间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随着产业发展，棉花娃娃的配饰产业链发展起来。在电商平台，针对棉花娃娃的首饰、娃衣、鞋子、腮红，以及娃包、娃屋、家具等周边配套应有尽有。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;囿于有属性娃娃受众群体的专属性，很多棉花娃娃不能够实现大规模生产，但是配饰品很多则可以通用，且没有版权风险，反而更早实现批量化生产。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“年纪大了，玩芭比有点幼稚，棉花娃娃就刚刚好。”小七并不是饭圈或者动漫迷，她入坑棉花娃娃主要是为了满足小时候的公主梦。她的二十多个棉花娃娃全部是无属性娃娃，既没有对应的IP原型，也没有版权授权问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“走品牌化路线，首要解决的问题，就是版权。”Rua娃吧创始人叶映丹是最早注意到棉花娃娃有可能成长为一个行业的人之一。叶映丹原本是电商平台的一个市场总监，早在2019年，她在后台数据中监测到，“棉花娃娃”作为关键词成为热搜商品。细究下来发现，棉花娃娃是一个非常有趣的品类，产品软萌、可爱，无论设计者、制造者还是受众群体，都非常低龄化，大多为中学和大学生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2018年购入的棉花娃娃，原型为一韩国男团。（南方周末记者高伊琛/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/3aac636350.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/3aac636350.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256266&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2018年购入的棉花娃娃，原型为一韩国男团。 （南方周末记者高伊琛/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“整个还是处于比较粗糙的阶段。”叶映丹介绍，因为主要还是兴趣驱动的产物，早期开团DIY的棉花娃娃，性质属于同好分享，并不算严格意义上的商业行为，所以并不涉及严格的版权问题。当然，单个品类的数量也很有限，制作周期很长，甚至在开团几个月后，产品还没出来，一些娃友甚至已经将此事遗忘，出现过娃妈“卷款跑路”的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“供应链生态很落后，上游又无法解决正版授权的问题，整个市场发展很受限制。”叶映丹解释，尽管问题重重，可她还是看到了蓬勃发展的朝气。当年，棉花娃娃在她们平台一年的GMV（一段时间内的成交总额）增长达到300%以上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从起源于韩国的追星文化，到在国内悄然走红，并迅速扩展至动漫、影视、游戏各个圈层，且发展出属于自己的圈层文化。叶映丹觉得，这个行业大有可为，她要做一个棉花娃娃的品牌出来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;叶映丹发现，创业初期一大难点，是如何准确挑选出具有持续性商业价值的IP，“因为棉花娃娃本身有原型，产品并不是品牌去主导，而是角色粉丝共创出的产品”。经过摸索发现，相较于爱豆和动漫，影视剧的IP更为合适品牌化运作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我们到市面上待播的热剧中排查，尽量做到&#39;应签尽签&#39;，保证持续产出电视剧爆火角色的周边。”叶映丹介绍，品牌化的棉花娃娃，只能覆盖当下热门、大众识别度高的角色形象，而很多冷门IP仍然需要同好者靠兴趣DIY制作。所以将来，拼团式的小作坊模式，仍然会长期存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“直博生主动选择博转硕”背后：博士过剩正在愈演愈烈丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259693]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据《中国青年报》报道，“直博生主动选择博转硕”成为高校新现象。记者采访了几名直博生，他们选择“转硕”的理由各不相同：有的是不适应博士生活，有的是课题难度太大，还有的是担心毕业后的就业去向。转为硕士或干脆转战职场，对他们而言是“主动分流”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些博士生之所以选择急流勇退，自然是出于成本收益比的理性考量。如果课题难度太大，攻读数年都拿不下学位，那么由此产生的沉没成本是惊人的；即便是费尽艰辛啃下博士学位，如果毕业后找不到工作，那么他们付出的机会成本也势必大到无法承受；即便辛苦拿到教职，不少“青椒”仍需要奋力搏杀，才能逃离各种“非升即走”的考核泥沼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不难设想，一名博士生花费数年时间攻读学位，再拼尽全力找到稳定的科研教学岗位，这是一出不折不扣的“历险记”，而同龄人恐怕已用这几年时间成家立业了。两相对比之下，读博确实像是一场“赌博”。报道中几位当事人正是基于这些考虑，果断选择“杀跌止损”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一现象的背后，是国内博士生的选拔与培养出现了“错配”与“过剩”的问题。所谓“错配”，就是不少并不适合读博的学生误入博士之路，入学后惊觉自己不是这块料；所谓“过剩”，就是高校培养的博士生太多，呈现供过于求态势，社会无法提供充足的就业岗位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自1983年中国自主培养的首批博士获取学位以来，四十年来国内每年招收与毕业的博士生人数都在高速增长。据教育部《2022年全国教育事业发展统计公报》，2022年共有8.23万人博士毕业，这一年博士生招生人数突破13万大关，在读博士人数达到55.61万的规模。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纵向来看，中国博士生招生从1995年突破1万人，到2009年达到6万人，再到2022年的13万，不到三十年间的时间里狂飙十几倍；横向来看，中国早在2008年就超过美国成为世界最大的博士学位授予国，目前每年新授予的博士学位也超过了美国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一方面，中国每年博士入学与毕业的人数迭创新高；另一方面，“博士过剩”凸显并愈演愈烈。 “核物理博士当城管”“医学博士应聘校医”“博士生争当中小学教师”的新闻屡屡出现，“青椒集体焦虑”的困境，每每展现出博士生在就业市场上“大材小用”的尴尬。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;博士生为什么会过剩？这与社会需求、传统观念、政策引导都有关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社会对博士生的需求往往是随着经济形势与产业结构而变动的。一旦社会“需求端”不能创造足够多的科研教学岗位，那么就无法容纳足够多的博士就业。如果说理工科博士还可以在企业研发部门找到用武之地的话，人文社科博士恐怕只剩下公职与教职可以争取，而这些职位一个萝卜一个坑，增长速度毕竟有限。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国传统观念素有“学而优则仕”的说法，当代的博士似乎与古代的举人进士一样，属于公职人员的后备军。站在象牙塔入口的博一新生视“博士”为一种身份乃至护身符，像是“考中进士”一样“候缺”。现实中，博士生入职公务员的“定级优势”也在强化这一观念。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，现代社会毕竟不是古代，迅猛增长的博士生人数远远超过昔日一年只有几百人的科举名额，社会能够容纳的公职岗位名额也未必赶得上过剩的博士毕业人数。如果不能意识到“社会需求”与“博士供给”之间关系的话，那么学生读博的出发点就难免与博士学位的内涵产生脱节，距离博士学位的“初心”越来越远。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;博士学位，从一开始就与教育体系中的其他学位有所不同。攻读博士被称为是“在知识的最远边界独自钻研”的艰险之旅，获得博士学位的人也会被誉为“为人类创造了新的知识”，意味着可以独立完成研究，拓展人类的认知边界。一个形象的形容是，如果把人类知识体系视为一个不断向外扩展半径的同心圆，那么博士就是触及最外端圆周，并且向外做出了一点突破的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代社会对博士生的需求，往往是随着经济形势与产业结构而变动的。需求端的变动，自然应该倒逼供给端的调整。面对社会需求的变动，高校应主动调整博士生培养计划，公立大学要用好纳税人的高等教育经费，私立大学也要对得起校友的大额捐赠。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以美国为例，新冠冲击带来的财政压力，就让美国诸多名校减招乃至停招了不少博士项目，不挣钱的文科博士首当其冲。根据美国媒体统计，仅在2021年，美国数十所精英大学就暂停了140多个人文社科类博士项目的招生。而在大语言模型ChatGPT横空出世之后，人工智能领域的博士生专业赢得了新一轮的青睐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你是否适合读博士？博士生队伍又是否需要你？社会又是否需要你这个博士生？认真回答这些问题，攻读博士才称得上一场“双向奔赴”。同时，高校也应深入思考，如何面向社会需求，主动调整博士生的招生培养计划，而不是“像种蘑菇一样培养博士”，带来学位内卷与博士过剩的难题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[京津冀及周边地区多城市启动重污染天气预警]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259698]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-01 07:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;自10月22日起，京津冀及周边地区出现一次PM2.5污染过程。到10月30日，京津冀中南部、河南北部污染程度已达中至重度，多个城市启动重污染天气预警。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家大气污染防治攻关联合中心密切跟踪本次污染过程，组织专家团队解读污染成因。专家指出，10月22日起，区域气象条件转不利，PM2.5污染逐渐累积。截至10月30日8时，京津冀及周边地区共16个城市累计发生32天次PM2.5中度及以上污染。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;专家分析，从气象条件看，近期京津冀及周边地区气象条件较不利，容易造成污染累积与转化。 10月22日以来，区域内冷空气活动偏弱，地面气温、低层大气相对湿度较常年均偏高，易形成区域性污染。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从区域污染排放看，区域工业企业、重型货车活动水平和秸秆火点数量环比上升，污染排放呈增加趋势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在工业源方面，10月下旬以来，区域工业用电量较前期明显增长，其中水泥、砖瓦等行业用电量增幅更为明显，钢铁、焦化、石化等行业用电量基本持平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在移动源方面，近期京津冀及周边地区重型货车交通流量处于秋冬季以来的高位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在面源方面，10月21日至28日区域内累计发现火点325个，其中天津、河北（沧州、张家口）、河南（周口、驻马店、漯河）等地数量较多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者了解到，京津冀及周边地区多个城市启动重污染天气预警。其中，北京市，天津市，河北省石家庄、唐山等13个城市（包括定州、辛集、雄安新区），河南省安阳、鹤壁等5个城市启动橙色预警。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据预报情况，10月30日至11月1日，受偏南风叠加高相对湿度影响，京津冀及周边地区将持续中至重度污染；11月3日起，随着冷空气到来，污染过程将结束。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 01 Nov 2023 07:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[BMI：有缺陷的肥胖标准]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259643]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/LX9ZPUuWGXtRlmA1COEFSQUT9WT3baFW7ljpE6b2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/LX9ZPUuWGXtRlmA1COEFSQUT9WT3baFW7ljpE6b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256143&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期以来，人们都把身体质量指数（BMI）作为衡量肥胖的简明指标。 BMI是指体重（千克）除以身高（米）的平方，BMI小于18.5为消瘦，18.5至24.9为正常，大于等于25为超重，大于等于30为肥胖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过《自然》杂志近期发表文章称，这种诊断肥胖的标准存在缺陷。首先是，脂肪在人体内积累的总量和分布于不同部位的数量超过一定的量才算是肥胖，但是BMI并不测量人体的脂肪量和各部位的分布量，因此不能反映人们是否真的肥胖，肥胖的程度有多严重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，即便BMI相同，不同年龄和性别的人也有不同的脂肪，如老年人一般比年轻人有更多的脂肪和更少的肌肉，女性往往比男性拥有更多体脂。而且，即便年龄相似性别相同的成年人具有相同的BMI，他们也可能有不同的体脂以及分布在不同的身体部位和器官的脂肪量。研究发现，在内脏器官中堆积的脂肪伤害性更大，如肝脏、心脏，而在腰部堆积脂肪，要比在臀部、腿部堆积脂肪更有害。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，BMI具有种族差异。 BMI是根据对白人测量的数据制定的标准，并不适合其他种族。与白人相比，BMI指数较低的亚洲人患心脏病等疾病的风险更大，原因可能是由于体脂百分比和在体内不同部位的分布有差异。因此，世界卫生组织建议亚洲人使用较低的BMI来衡量超重和肥胖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于BMI指数的一些弊端，根据BMI指数制定的现行的肥胖标准有可能高估了全球的肥胖情况。 2023年8月17日，《糖尿病、肥胖与代谢》期刊发表一篇题为《中国肥胖患病率及相关并发症：1580万成年人的横断面真实世界研究》的文章，描绘了中国肥胖地图，在1580万成年受试者中超重人群占比34.8%，肥胖人群占比14.1%。此外，世界肥胖联合会发布的《2023世界肥胖图谱》则为全球描绘了肥胖地图，预测未来12年，将有4亿人超重或肥胖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，这两篇文章都用BMI作为衡量肥胖的标准来估计肥胖人数。显然，这样的判断可能会不太准确。而且，对于用BMI来衡量肥胖，也早就有人提出不同意见，并提出了补充和改善的标准，可以测定体脂率，将此与BMI共同用来衡量肥胖。但是，由于测量体脂率比较麻烦，迄今并没有广泛推广和应用。而用BMI则比较简单，同时还有一些人是简单以外观来评判自己是否肥胖，因而自行减肥，可能会造成一些后果。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个最大的后果是，减肥药的广泛使用和滥用，由此带来一系列问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最近，新的减肥药物陆续获得上市，如胰高血糖素样肽1（GLP-1）、索马鲁肽（semaglutide）和替西帕肽（Tirzepatide），服用者有的产生了较好的效果，体重大幅减轻，有的可减少21%的体重，而且索马鲁肽也被证明可以降低严重心血管问题的风险。但是，当初研发这类药物本来不是为了减肥，而是为了治疗糖尿病。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最新一代的抗肥胖药物模仿一种称为胰高血糖素样肽1（GLP-1）的激素，它与食欲调节有关。此后，与GLP-1同类的索马鲁肽于2017年被美国食品和药品监督管理局（FDA）批准（商品名Ozempic），用于治疗2型糖尿病，后来在2021年被批准用于治疗肥胖症（商品名Wegovy）。此后，FDA又于2022 年批准替西帕肽（商品名Mounjaro）销售，用于治疗糖尿病，但后来也被用于治疗肥胖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，逐渐增多的不良作用开始让人担心这些治疗肥胖的药物对人的副作用。现在发现的主要危害是胃肠道问题和肌肉质量损失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加拿大英属哥伦比亚大学的研究人员在2023年10月5日的《美国医学会杂志》（JAMA）上在线发表一篇文章指出，现在治疗肥胖的药物存在较大的潜在的有害性。研究人员对一个大型健康保险数据库的肥胖患者进行调查，有4144人服用利拉鲁肽（liraglutide，也是一种胰高血糖素样肽-1类似物，用于治疗2型糖尿病和肥胖）、613名服用索马鲁肽和654人服用安非他酮-纳曲酮（另一种减肥药）。服用索马鲁肽的胆道疾病发病率（每1000 人年）为11.7人，服用利拉鲁肽为18.6人，服用安非他酮-纳曲酮为12.6人，这三类药物服用者的胰腺炎发病率分别为4.6、7.9 和1.0人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结论是，与服用安非他酮-纳曲酮相比，服用胰高血糖素样肽-1药物的胰腺炎、肠梗阻和胃轻瘫（胃轻瘫是一种减缓或阻止食物从胃到肠道的移动的病症）的风险增加有关，但与胆道疾病无关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前的临床试验已经表明GLP-1药物与胃肠道副作用之间存在关联，包括恶心、便秘和罕见的胰腺炎病例。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于替西帕肽来说，比较明显的副作用是肌肉减少，导致肌无力。但这一情况还需要长期的监控和研究。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 23:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[个人信息泄露是电诈产业链一环：了解套路，提高警惕丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259685]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 21:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，有网友反映在某地图App上搜索航班信息并预定机票后，收到了诈骗电话。对方以航空公司客服的名义，声称机械故障航班取消，让其提供支付宝账号给予补偿。来电者能报出网友的姓名、电话、身份证号、航班信息等。网友认为，其个人信息遭到泄露并被用于电信诈骗，希望有关部门严查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，中国民航局答复表示，正在编制相关文件，进一步加强对重要数据的保护。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“航班取消补偿”近期已成为电信诈骗的热门手段，有旅客损失甚至超过200万元。诈骗分子能准确报出旅客的姓名、身份证号、航班信息，无疑是其订购机票的相关信息被泄露了。但机票预订流程繁琐、涉及方众多，在线旅游平台、航空公司、机票代理人，还有中航信、运营商等中间方及终端系统，任何一个环节都存在数据泄露的风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此类诈骗已成为近期多发的热门电诈手段，且旅客在订票后很快就能接到诈骗电话，说明旅客航班信息泄露已经成了规模。泄露旅客航班信息，不仅本身就是违法犯罪行为，而且会为电诈犯罪提供诈骗对象，是电信诈骗黑色产业链的上游。及时严打航班信息泄露，对铲断产业链上游、减少电信诈骗有重要意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;提起电信诈骗，人们首先想到的往往是“杀猪盘”“网上赌博”“刷单返利”等诈骗犯罪，以及缅北电诈园区泛滥等热门新闻。尤其是近期缅北数千名涉诈人员被移交给中国警方后，很多人以为电诈分子被一窝端了，以后电诈会大大减少。但这是一种误解，或者说只是一个美好的愿望。电信诈骗已经成为一个庞大的产业，不仅境外有，境内也有。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人们看到的这些电信诈骗其实只是这个庞大的犯罪产业链的一环，而上下游还有窃取个人信息、洗钱等违法犯罪。诈骗集团也有数据处理部门，收集到庞大的个人信息数据后，进行分析处理，找出“高价值”的目标，针对不同的诈骗对象，采用不同的诈骗剧本，最后实际执行剧本，让你上当受骗。而这一切的源头，就是个人信息。信息越详细，越具体，就越能套用个性化剧本进行“精准诈骗”。航班取消补偿的剧本，就是这种精准诈骗，利用了乘客对航班取消、行程受阻的焦虑，诈骗成功率更高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现实中，信息泄露的可能性几乎无处不在。上文中的航班信息泄露只是其中之一。买房、买车等大额消费领域也是信息泄露的重灾区。很多人在买房之后，就会收到装修、家具家电等推销电话，买车之后，则是推销保险、车品等等。只是推销，还算好，但这些个人信息既然可以被卖给推销家具家电和卖保险的，当然也可能被卖给电信诈骗分子，而且这些含有房产、车辆相关内容的信息，很容易被用来进行“精准诈骗”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，更严重的信息泄露可能是一些网站的大规模数据泄露。互联网应用普及，在带来极大便利的同时，也让个人信息泄露的风险急剧上升。寄快递、点外卖、坐网约车、开通会员，各平台都掌握了海量的用户个人信息。一旦这些平台在安全防护方面做得不到位，被黑客攻破，就有可能造成海量的用户信息泄露。此前，某短视频平台就发生过用户数据泄露事件，信息总量达到20亿条。这些信息被泄露之后，就会永久存在于暗网中，无法消除，不断被贩卖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;个人信息保护法对防范个人信息泄露做出了非常具体的规定。各大网站应该严格遵守规定“最小够用”原则，只收集和存储必要的用户个人信息，减少可能的信息泄露对用户造成的损害。毕竟，无论怎么防护，都很难保证万无一失，绝不泄露。就算技术上保证了安全，还有可能出现家贼难防的情况。警方已经破获了不止一起电信公司员工向诈骗集团提供用户电话号码等信息，甚至向诈骗集团提供电话线路的案件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刑法明确规定，向他人出售或者提供公民个人信息，情节严重的，构成犯罪。而根据相关司法解释，出售或者提供行踪轨迹信息，被他人用于犯罪的，或者明知他人利用公民个人信息实施犯罪，仍向其出售或者提供个人信息的，都属于“情节严重”。因此，旅客航班信息被泄露，无论是在哪个环节发生的，都已经涉嫌犯罪，警方应该立案侦查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公众也要提高个人信息保护意识，尽可能不在网络上提供个人信息，尤其是不要贪小便宜而向不明网站提供个人信息，不要随便扫不明二维码。其次还要提高防电诈的意识和能力。要多了解电信诈骗的套路，对网上赌博、刷单等常见的诈骗剧本提高警惕，对航班延误退票等信息，首先通过官方网站、社交账号、客服电话等进行核实。电信诈骗防不胜防，套路更新也很快，即使遇到“家人住院”之类足以扰乱心神的诈骗剧本，也要提高定力，不要轻信，先设法联系家人。很多人的个人信息可能已经在暗网流传了，未来遇到电信诈骗或难以避免，要防诈，可能更多要靠自己了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 21:55:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>