<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[个人养老金保险名单增加18款税延养老产品 总名单扩容至69款]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258865]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, according to the official website of China Banking and Insurance Information Technology Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;China Banking and Insurance&quot;), The list of personal pension insurance products has been expanded to 69 products, involving 22 insurance companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that this expansion not only added 3 new product types to the 48 at the end of July, but also added 18 personal tax-deferred pension annuity insurance (hereinafter referred to as &quot;tax &quot;Extended Pension Products&quot;) has been incorporated into the personal pension product system. After the expansion, the types of personal pension insurance products include exclusive commercial pension insurance, endowment insurance, annuity insurance and tax-deferred pension products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8eefa46488519beb1678d58511f85dc7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;556&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8eefa46488519beb1678d58511f85dc7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254620&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(Picture source:&amp;nbsp;China Bank &amp; Credit Insurance Co., Ltd.)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above 18 items are included in personal pension Financial tax-deferred pension products are provided by China Pacific Life Insurance Co., Ltd., Taiping Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., Ping An Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., Taikang Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., Taiping Life Insurance Co., Ltd. and Generali Life Insurance Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Kaiyuan Securities research report shows that the integration of tax-deferred commercial pension insurance into personal pensions mainly helps policyholders of tax-deferred pension insurance to coordinate and unify the third pillar tax preferential policies and reduce the personal income tax rate when receiving them. , which is conducive to the further improvement of the personal pension system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, on August 31, the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau issued the &quot;Notice on Matters Concerning the Connection between the Pilot Program of Personal Tax-Deferred Commercial Pension Insurance and Personal Pensions.&quot; The main content of the &quot;Notice&quot; includes clarifying the work requirements, business adjustments, product management, policy transfer, etc. in the process of connecting the tax-deferred pension insurance pilot and personal pensions, and also clarifies the customer information confirmation and strengthens system construction for China Banking and Credit Insurance Co., Ltd. , as well as requirements for business operations, announcements and information submissions of tax-deferred pension insurance pilot insurance companies. In principle, all work should be completed before the end of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders said that personal tax-deferred pension insurance highlights the &quot;burden reduction&quot; effect, and the tax burden after retirement is lighter. The expansion of the list means that the connection between the tax-deferred pension insurance business and the personal pension system is progressing in an orderly manner, in line with work expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2018, the Ministry of Finance and other departments jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Launching the Pilot of Personal Tax-Deferred Commercial Pension Insurance&quot;, launching the pilot business operation in the country. The pilot areas are Shanghai, Fujian and Suzhou Industrial Parks, and the maximum pre-tax deduction amount is 6% of personal taxable income or 12,000 yuan per year, whichever is lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ping An Securities stated that the pilot policy is not attractive to low-income people, and the tax benefits are limited for those who can enjoy tax benefits. Under the personal pension system, there are more product choices and simpler tax deduction procedures. The two types of products have similar attributes and share tax preferential quotas. The integration of tax-deferred commercial pension insurance into personal pensions will straighten out the relationship between tax-advantaged pension insurance. Relevant procedures will be simplified to make it easier for investors to understand. At the same time, it will further enrich the selection of personal pension products and increase investors&#39; willingness to insure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the official implementation of the personal pension system in November 2022, personal pension insurance products have continued to expand. According to the official website of China Banking and Insurance Corporation, by the end of July 2023, the number of personal pension insurance products has increased from The initial 7 models were expanded to 48 products, and currently it has been expanded to 69 products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ping An Securities stated that residents’ demand for retirement savings continues to expand under the background of an aging population. However, since this year, long-term interest rates have remained low and volatile, many commercial banks have lowered deposit interest rates, the equity market has fluctuated greatly, and the returns of competing products have Rates have declined, and insurance products follow pricing interest rates, have guaranteed yields, and can provide protection against risks such as death, total disability, and disability, further highlighting their differentiated advantages. As an important part of the third pillar of pension insurance, commercial pension insurance is expected to achieve rapid development under the personal pension system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[社会学家刘汶蓉：年轻人的很多选择无法成为“现实选择”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258959]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details of relevant reports, please see: &quot;&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/258684&quot; title=&quot;Documentary &quot;The Nest&quot;: Why do two generations who torture each other still live together&quot;>;Documentary &quot;The Nest&quot;: Two generations who torture each other Why do modern people still live together&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The documentary &quot;The Nest&quot; focuses on a family of three in Shanghai. A young man born in 1985 graduated from school many years ago and lives with his parents in a 30-square-meter apartment. Husband’s room. Liu Wenrong, a researcher at the Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences, paid attention to this documentary. She is very familiar with such families. 2016 was the year when the documentary started to be filmed. She was doing research on intergenerational relations at the time and discovered the group of families that “gnaw at the elderly”: “There were already many such cases in 2016, but now the employment situation of young people is more difficult. Severe, and their expectations are different, so there are more and more people. The earliest was in 2005 or 2006, Shanghai started to &#39;gnaw&#39;, because housing prices became more expensive, and the elderly felt more and more pressure to support their children. When I came to college, there was a wave of discussion about the issue of &#39;gnawing at the elderly.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Wenrong began to pay attention to and study the intergenerational relationship issues in Chinese society when she was studying for her Ph.D. In the first decade of the 21st century, scholars engaged in qualitative research devoted a lot of space to discussing issues such as the decline of filial piety, the pension crisis, and intergenerational imbalance. Her doctoral thesis that year also stemmed from wanting to test the theory of &quot;the decline of filial piety,&quot; but it led her in another direction. In 2008, when she analyzed survey data from Lanzhou and Shanghai, she found that intergenerational relationships were getting closer, and that younger people were more likely to agree with the concept of filial piety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2012 to 2019, she and the research team visited Shanghai, Lanzhou, Dalian and other places, collected 137 family cases, and collected 11 family cases in the United States. Combined with the sample survey data, she finally came to the conclusion: Social transformation has strengthened the emotional structure of &quot;parent-child integration&quot; in Chinese families. The tradition of intergenerational mutual aid has shown strong resilience. Intergenerational ties still play a community role in settling individual lives and motivating daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During field research, Liu Wenrong met many Chinese young people who were supported and supported by their families. During her research in the United States, she communicated with local scholars and saw the contrast between Eastern and Western families. touch. In addition, she has the identity and experience of a mother, and her mentality has changed. In the past, she was disgusted with China&#39;s family culture and believed that &quot;moral kidnapping&quot; was too heavy. Now she believes that this is a warm system design. Chinese urban families bear the burden of young people&#39;s unemployment, marriage and childbearing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/G1B26cwWmFMgurABuZhU54FAwqVtFsddRwNjeouX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2160&quot; height= &quot;1215&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/20/G1B26cwWmFMgurABuZhU54FAwqVtFsddRwNjeouX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254708&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;em>;In the documentary &quot;The Nest&quot;, the protagonist born in 1985 (left) lives with his parents who are over 70 years old. Photo courtesy of the film producer&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;)&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Although our previous cultural ideals were freedom and equality, the elimination of feudal filial piety and intergenerational patriarchy, etc., in reality Society, apart from these, has not established other cultural and spiritual foundations that can support people to settle down and live a life, so (family culture) has become a value demonstration. We must respect the inheritance of culture and transform it. This does not mean that transformation is What can be transformed requires profound ideological transformation, which is a relatively long process.&quot; Liu Wenrong told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Liu Wenrong has shifted her research focus to young people’s marriage and love, and is working on the topic “Research on the Trends, Dilemmas and Social Processes of Marriage and Love among Young People in Big Cities”. In an interview with Southern Weekend reporters, she talked about intergenerational conflicts in families in transition, the phenomenon of stay-at-home sons and daughters, and the plight of youth in the information society, among other topics. The following is his self-report:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Once children no longer get married and have children, it will be difficult for them to truly reconcile with their parents&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For those of us born in the 1970s, especially in our youth, we have very Strong motivation to leave home. why? Parental control is very painful, and the love we feel is very little, because when you have many children, your parents allocate very little time and energy, including financial resources. In this state, children do not need to be evaluated. It is almost a natural motivation, that is, they must study away from them at a very early age, and they must earn money to support themselves. This motivation is very strong. You must also get married, because once you get married, you can leave that family with confidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under this dynamic, it can be said that we were all a matter of survival at that time. We also want self-realization. Since childhood, we have thought about painting, singing, writing, etc., but most people just regard it as an ideal buried in their hearts. First of all, you must meet your own needs, find a job, get married, and have a support network of peers in society. Our support mainly relies on friends and classmates. This network is very important, and we are willing to spend time and energy to make such relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But today&#39;s young people have very little pressure to survive from their parents. They spend a lot of energy and thoughts on why their ideals cannot be realized, which makes them very powerless, because they The standard of self-realization is relatively high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I think young people will be unhappy if such words are said, I know that their experiences are different and they cannot understand. My research also found that it is difficult for generations to understand each other because they do not have similar experiences or similar social roles. They have to rely more on their parents because their parents are more mature than them. For example, a harmonious family relies on the compromises of the parents. Whether it is done naturally or shaped after reflection, it must have achieved profound ideological comfort and tolerance. Without this, it would be difficult, because the children do not have similar life paths and experiences, and it is difficult to reach spiritual reconciliation with their parents. Even if they also agree with filial piety and the importance of love, it is difficult to produce such a thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So this is also a dilemma that families have on people&#39;s spirits, especially now that after the transformation, the path of life is no longer standardized or copied, and each person is individualized. I later published a book specifically discussing the emotional transformation of intergenerational relationships in Chinese families. My final conclusion was to talk about the role of childbirth in the value recognition and emotional communication between two generations. Many young people only reach spiritual reconciliation with their parents after they get married and have children. If he has not become a parent, it will be difficult for him to truly understand his parents and let go of the harm his parents have done to him. Only when he stands in the same role and has his own emotional experience with his children, can he truly realize the difficulties of being a parent, and find that no matter how good his intentions are, there are still many dissatisfactions and many unsatisfactory things. He cannot control the situation and cannot be a perfect parent. At this time, he can let go of some things his parents did in his upbringing and understand that the upbringing process is not easy. This reconciliation is actually very subtle. During my investigation, parents will naturally feel the tacit understanding between them (and their children), and they will feel relieved mentally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do Chinese parents care so much about their children getting married and having children? The issue of carrying on the family line is basically not emphasized by Chinese parents nowadays. They think it is a feudal idea, especially educated parents. But why do I still pursue this thing? I always feel that there is something wrong with it, that is, the difficult path of becoming a parent is not recognized. This is a huge loss in their value, and this sense of loss cannot be expressed in the modern value system. Parents don’t talk about these things on the Internet, and even in daily life, they don’t know why they are like this. In fact, it&#39;s because I haven&#39;t been recognized, and I don&#39;t know what I have been busy with all my life. But when children give birth to children, they get a kind of spiritual understanding and relief, and a recognition of value. This is very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The vitality of Chinese family culture lies in inheritance, which is a cycle, not linear. But once children no longer get married and have children, it is actually difficult for them to understand the struggles in marriage and parenting, and it is difficult for them to truly reconcile with their parents psychologically. Therefore, I think the culture of voluntary non-marriage and childbearing that is emerging among young people is a very big challenge that Chinese families are currently facing in the social transformation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have all experienced a period of rapid economic development, and there was not such strong information dissemination in adolescence. We also naturally enjoyed the dividends of the development of this era without any deliberate reflection. But today&#39;s young people grow up in a completely different stage of social development, and they face very big spiritual challenges. We need more intergenerational understanding. We cannot say that today&#39;s teenagers are all hypocritical and nihilistic, that they are flat, have no ambition, or are lazy. In every era there are people who are unable to enter society because of some psychological or personality problems. But if this group of people is particularly large, it becomes a social problem. What we need is understanding and communication between generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, we are also worried about the issue of marriage and love among young people. The mainstream society is very worried, and the country is also very worried. Why are we not willing to get married? Why don&#39;t you want to have children? I think it is more important to understand that it is important to make young people recognize the path of marriage and having children from their hearts, and to tell them the significance of intimate relationships to people&#39;s mental health and long-term development. Because being unmarried and having children is mostly a form of self-protection for young people who are under a sense of risk. If they lack support, they can only focus on the present. Therefore, we need to think about the spirituality and psychology of family life in an all-round way culturally. Or, more society-wide discussions are needed so that everyone can have more understanding of the institution of marriage and intimate relationships, and create more possibilities and space for personal path choices. Our government has always said that it supports marriage and childbearing by providing money and time. I think there is also a need for more guidance on the value aspect, or for young people to recognize it more. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“What we worry about is that young people will never be able to leave the family”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In urban middle-class families, children born after 1995 are more likely to return to their parents. My article, &quot;The Return of Parental Rights and the Reconstruction of Filial Piety in Urban Families in the Transformation Period,&quot; is a response to the phenomenon that there are more and more &quot;mama&#39;s babies&quot; and children are willing to listen to their parents for many things and have a close relationship and emotional intimacy with their parents. In daily life, they are a little rebellious, but there is no conflict with their parents on major issues. Whether it is the concept of choosing a spouse, the concept of employment, or the concept of entering school, they seem to be very similar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For middle-class parents, they have completely changed the past &quot;paternalistic&quot; parenting model. In the article, I call it reflexive parenting practice, which is when parents reflect on the pain in their own growth experiences, form a parenting style based on love and emotion, and comprehensively plan and plan the growth path of their children. Help and hope your children will be happy and successful. On the other hand, even middle-class parents have different resources. Parents born in the 1980s and those born in the 1950s have not accumulated much wealth and are still under great financial pressure. But things are different after 1995. The economic situation of the entire society has developed greatly, especially those who are middle-class or above and have college-educated parents. They generally have better careers, better economic accumulation, and better knowledge accumulation. Socially The capital and economic capital are relatively good in all aspects, so I can devote myself to the upbringing of my children in an all-round way, and it is a kind of close parenting and intensive upbringing since childhood. This kind of intimate parenting uses emotional influence and guidance, and there is less brutal coercive control behavior. Therefore, children do not have so much tension and conflict with their parents when they grow up, and even in adolescence they still show a high degree of dependence on their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I feel that mental health problems are particularly serious among those born in the 2000s and 10s. This is of course related to academics, but it is also closely related to the long-term family structure, that is, the symbiosis between generations. The child was cared for and packed with love that took his breath away. Whether children are at school or at home, they are completely monitored. In this case, it will be difficult for children to be mentally healthy, and they will have a strong sense of powerlessness, so depression among teenagers is also increasing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our Chinese familism is the state of parent-child integration, which has a strong instrumental function in life support. For example, in the process of my country&#39;s economic transformation, there has not been a large number of young people living in poverty, all of whom are supported by their parents. There has not been a large number of young people who cannot get married, have fallen into poverty, or even become homeless. This is all because of the lack of parental support in Chinese families. On the bottom, so this is a benefit in a tool sense. But now that we are in the second decade of the 21st century, what we see is more mental pressure and pressure on the development of young people. What we are worried about is that young people will never be able to get out of their families and are trapped inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan also has a similar situation. When economic development slows down or even stagnates, young people have fewer opportunities to obtain stable and good jobs and good marriages. Parents protect their children. They call it the phenomenon of &quot;staying single&quot;. They just stay with their parents, never get married, and some of them don&#39;t even work. I read some information and found that these children who have been single until old age are likely to fall into a state of singlelessness after the death of their parents, which is also a very big social problem. Will we also reach this point? What should we do when human survival is no longer a problem and development faces bottlenecks? Is it a way out for parents to protect their children? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have no objection to children having full-time jobs, but parents should be smart parents and their children should be smart children. There is no problem with periodic gaps, because now you have the conditions to pursue a better career, a higher education, and a better marriage partner. The period of adulthood will inevitably become longer and longer, but you must realize that you cannot Always like this. Childhood status is indefinite, but as a full-time child, there is a concept of a contract. I can terminate the contract and change jobs. It is a profession, temporary, not lifelong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both parents and children must make their own preparations for changing jobs or changing professional status. They cannot just accept this state of mind by saying &quot;I am fine this way&quot; and keep it like this. Unless you are engaged in a creative job, (for example) writing at home, but you still have to have a way to support yourself, because if your source of value is not independent, your self-efficacy will definitely be very low, and it will definitely be from a mental health point of view. Not a long-term solution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Westerners summarize the Chinese family as a corporation model - thinking that the Chinese family is a cooperative. In fact, a corporation is also an organization based on a rational structure and a business. Organizations and careers need to develop, and development needs to continue to grow. But I think these young people have not inherited this familialist view. They have reduced their efforts to build a larger intimate circle because the risks from the outside world are too great. In fact, for their families, there is no development and no future. In other words, between these two generations, it is over when it is over. This is not our Chinese familism tradition. He is just satisfied with his simplest idea of ​​filial piety, that is, I am a good person, I honor my parents, my parents love me, and I love them too. I work hard to make my parents live a good life, and that&#39;s it. The moral value of my life. Therefore, this &quot;return to filial piety&quot; is indeed the true state of mind of today&#39;s young people, but it is by no means a simple return to tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;This trend makes people live a very abstract life&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, young people have relatively high demands, including the standards for marriage and love, which are very complicated. I support young people&#39;s spiritual pursuits and love pursuits, but it is difficult to add practical considerations to these pursuits. When I did research on marriage and love, I found that all the investigators had no way to avoid it. In the end, choosing a spouse was an economic indicator, but economics alone could not completely convince them, so they were very confused. The psychological complexity is very strong. Unlike those of us born in the 1970s who have a very strong drive to leave home, we really don’t think about it that much. Because families with many children at that time had limited resources and parents were generally impatient with their children, young people had to go to other places to go to school, get a job, get married, and build their own life network. Behind this was a motivation closer to survival needs, so they had to work hard. , the partner&#39;s pursuit of idealization and perfection is relatively weak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But now the information and reference standards of the entire society are different. The current network and information dissemination are too developed, giving people a strong sense of powerlessness. You always feel that there are endless possibilities, but the reality is not like that. The people he refers to are always the best ones. He cannot be satisfied with the people and things around him, including himself, and lives a very unhappy life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, it will be difficult for young people to live in the concrete life in front of them, causing them to fall into a great sense of powerlessness. &quot;I will not settle, I will work hard&quot; is both a personality statement and a risk aversion. In fact, they don&#39;t work hard because there is no way to work hard. Human energy and strength are limited, and you can only work hard near yourself. As the old saying goes, you have to do it step by step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was easy for us to do it back then, but why is it so difficult for young people to do it now? It’s not that young people are bad, it’s because changes in the entire society have led to changes in people’s psychological environment. Therefore, if you want to do some reverse self-training, you must do it through deliberate, conscious, and profound self-discipline. You cannot do it if you follow this trend. Because under this trend, there seems to be a cultural environment that makes people live very abstract and unrealistic lives. At that time, even if we were looking for a job, we didn&#39;t seem to feel uncomfortable or uncomfortable, because everyone was like this, it was not unacceptable, and most people were in this state. This is also the progress of a society. Survival is no longer a problem. Only now young people will think, &quot;I don&#39;t want to settle, I want to pursue my own most ideal state.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also the background of a risk society, which is caused by fear. This is also very important. We have to look at where a young person focuses his attention. The higher he focuses his attention, the more fearful he will be, and the stronger his sense of powerlessness will be. But this era is an attention economy, and what attracts people is always those lofty things. Consumerism and Internet culture are all like this. Most of them satisfy people&#39;s physiological stimulation and stimulate people&#39;s desires. This desire will temporarily make you excited or satisfied, or create a beautiful imagination, but it It will not support you step by step in life for a long time. That’s why I say that young people live very abstract lives. I don’t want to use other words, such as derogatory words such as impetuous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has become very difficult to &quot;adult&quot; now. It is very difficult to identify and stabilize oneself. Of course, people have to be in this process of getting to know themselves throughout their lives, but it is difficult for a young person to enter the next stage of growth because he cannot distinguish, cannot make a choice, and is always in this entangled state. And today&#39;s Internet culture, consumer culture, and games all make young people indulge in this stage more and more, and they remain underage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They have always been unable to distinguish between desires and ideals: in fact, they are satisfying their short-term desires, not walking on the ideal path, because they have not been implemented in reality. The atmosphere created by our culture makes them feel that they are on this road, creating the illusion that they are very pursuing, ideal, and struggling. In this way, they miss the best state of their life cycle and slowly and naturally slide. In fact, many studies have noticed, including Japanese research and surveys on youth, that it is not that young people plan to remain unmarried and have children. They firmly establish &quot;I am an unmarried and infertile person&quot; from the beginning. Yes, but it is not a big deal. most people. It&#39;s just that in the process of looking for a partner and exploring their own ideals, they slipped to the end of being single. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think young people still need to have a better understanding. It is indeed the influence of the entire environment. Social, cultural, psychological, and economic aspects are actually an oppression of the human spirit by the entire modernity. If you go further up, you will reach this (level), which is very obvious among young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Nowadays young people do not have the opportunity to fall in love for a long time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When you are in your twenties, you seem to have unlimited possibilities, and when you are forty, it seems that there are still many possibilities. But the fact that you are in reality and look around you and there seems to be no chance is very frustrating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I did research on marriage and love, and found that young people think there are many opportunities and there are many platforms on the Internet. There seem to be a lot of choices, but in the end, none of them are choices, or there is no way to become a realistic choice. This is the dilemma of young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This choice is different from what we had back then. Let me just talk about one point. It’s very interesting that college students don’t fall in love now, but high school students seem to still do it. But why don’t they fall in love in college? Moreover, they don’t seek help from their own units after they start working, because they will feel embarrassed if they fail! This reason sounds incredible at first, but when I think about it carefully, I think it is quite right. It is very rational. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Love requires time, emotional cultivation, and long-term contact with each other. My investigation revealed that they work very hard to go on blind dates every weekend and only once a week. They rack their brains to talk to people and even participate in various blind dates. But after the event is over, that person will no longer be around you. Even if you think this person is okay at the time, if he doesn&#39;t appear next to you within this week, you will see him again on the weekend at most. Many people will stick to it for two or three times and then it will be boring. And the key is that the conditions will not be so good that you will be desperate. The conditions may be okay, but if you think about it again, there are still many things you are not satisfied with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a rational measurement. If you measure based on conditions, you will always be dissatisfied. It is impossible for a person to be good at everything and fully meet all conditions. The long-term relationship does not depend on the conditions. Even if the conditions are average but there is love, they will be together. This is often the case. But now young people don&#39;t have this opportunity, they don&#39;t have the opportunity to develop feelings, because they have no daily contact at all, and even some events happen to touch you. In this case, if you don&#39;t have feelings, you will completely depend on the conditions, and you will always be dissatisfied depending on the conditions, so it will be difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This society seems to have a lot of choices, but in fact because you have no real contact, there are few opportunities and few options nearby. Moreover, they are afraid of entering specific relationships in real life. They are very afraid of the risk of relationship breakdown or unhappiness. They are worried about being hurt and entangled in the relationship. They are very worried and wary about investing in interpersonal relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know if this is a common problem among only children. That is, they have a strong sense of interpersonal boundaries. They are worried and afraid of complicated relationships, and naturally form a distance from others. They want to choose themselves wherever they go. come out. And in our era of having many children, we have been involved in various relationships since we were young, and we must have suffered a lot. However, it seems that we have naturally developed a lack of fear, thinking that this is a normal state, or developing a physiological response to cope with it. Okay, so are the skills. Nowadays, young people who are protected by their parents, or only children, do not have this ability, and they are not willing to get involved in interpersonal relationships. They think that is very low, they like to be alone, and they need their own space. So I think these are all changes of the times and a negative consequence of the progress of the times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of my students said that she just needs to be with her parents. There are indeed such children and such thoughts: I don’t need to establish such a strong and close relationship with anyone in this world. Because building a close relationship requires a lot of adjustment, a lot of discomfort, and very big challenges. Tolerance and various compromises between people, in short, they are not willing to do it. They think it is too complicated. They can play with it once or twice, but it is difficult to have in-depth communication. So I think they would rather go on a blind date. Some students even said, Teacher, it would be great if the country gave us a spouse. They are willing to follow dramas and have sex, and the sweetness of love is used up, and they no longer need to find the feeling of love in real life. Because there is no such perfect person, let him have that kind of emotion, thinking that two people are so sweet and in love with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at others falling in love, if you want to start a family, &quot;the country will send me one.&quot; So they are very receptive to introductions from their parents. Of course, their parents&#39; values ​​are relatively close to theirs, and they can coordinate their opinions on mate selection, so they accept their parents&#39; arrangements, which is completely different from what we expected at the time. What we originally thought was that with the development of modernization and the improvement of education, marriage must be a free love model. But it doesn&#39;t seem to be the case now. Love is love, but marriage is well arranged by parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this is not a large-scale survey, and it may be difficult to reflect it in a large-scale survey. But I have seen national survey data before, which shows that compared with the 1990s, the role of parents in their children&#39;s marriage decisions has increased after the 21st century. I think this is natural, mainly for economic reasons. Nowadays, when young people get married, they have to rely on their parents for every step of buying a house, giving gifts, and looking after children. In addition, young people&#39;s psychological dependence on their parents has also increased, so parents&#39; voice will definitely increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[改什么？怎么改？难在哪？超大特大城市城中村改造政策解读]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since this year, the transformation of urban villages has pressed the &quot;acceleration button&quot;. The Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development recently stated that very large and megacities are actively and steadily advancing the transformation of urban villages, and the implementation is divided into three categories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a systematic livelihood project and development project involving the interests of many parties, what is the current background for promoting the transformation of urban villages in very large and megacities? How to change it? What&#39;s the difficulty? &quot;Xinhua Viewpoint&quot; reporters interviewed experts and scholars in the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Why change? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since this year, the transformation of urban villages has attracted much attention. The Political Bureau meeting of the CPC Central Committee held on April 28 put forward the requirement to &quot;actively and steadily promote the transformation of urban villages in very large and megacities&quot;; in July, the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Actively and Steadily Promoting the Transformation of Urban Villages in Very Large and Megacities&quot; , and held a video and telephone conference for special deployment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development has proposed specific policy implementation measures for the transformation of urban villages, which are divided into three categories: one is to implement demolition and new construction if conditions are met, and the other is to carry out regular renovation and improvement , the third category is the combination of implementation and integration between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Urban villages are called &quot;villages in the city&quot;. They have the dual characteristics of rural and urban areas and are a historical product of the development process of urbanization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take Hongqi Village in Putuo District, the largest urban village in central Shanghai, as an example. On 586 acres of land, there were once gathered 90 printing factories, 207 cold storages, and 9 large primary markets. , more than 1,000 stalls, the population here is complex, rented by tenants all over the place, illegal buildings are densely covered, and the floating population is as high as 60,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to relevant standards, cities with an urban resident population of more than 10 million are considered megacities, such as Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Chengdu, Chongqing, Tianjin, Wuhan, etc.; cities with an urban resident population of more than 5 million are classified as megacities. The following cities are megacities, such as Qingdao, Hefei, Hangzhou, Changsha, Nanjing, Dongguan, etc. A total of more than 20 cities across the country belong to the category of megacities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“my country’s megacities have absorbed a large number of migrant populations, and a considerable number of these groups rent in urban villages. Although the cost of renting in urban villages is lower, they generally lack necessary infrastructure and public services, especially There are many hidden dangers in terms of health safety and social governance,&quot; said Yu Xiaofen, dean of the China Housing and Real Estate Research Institute of Zhejiang University of Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Rong, president of the Shanghai Academy of Real Estate Sciences, said that promoting the transformation of urban villages can play a positive role in stabilizing economic growth and become an important driver of expanding domestic demand, generating more than 10 trillion yuan. Direct investment and boost consumption of furniture, home appliances, catering services, textiles, etc.; on the other hand, it can optimize the urban spatial layout and further improve the level of urban governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;How to change it? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“The property rights structure, personnel composition, spatial distribution, historical relics, etc. of urban villages are highly complex. This reconstruction proposes three types of demolition and new construction, renovation and improvement, and combination of demolition and reorganization. Transformation model.&quot; Li Yujia, deputy director of the Guangdong Provincial Housing Policy Research Center, said that urban villages that meet the conditions, that is, have balanced funds, strong public willingness to transform, and clear land and property rights, will be demolished and built; those that do not meet the conditions will not be forced to build new ones. On the basis of the principle of keeping the bottom line of safety, rectification and improvement are carried out on a regular basis, and reforms are implemented after gradually solving problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of transformation methods, the current urban village transformation particularly emphasizes the need to combine the protection of villagers’ legitimate rights and interests with planning before taking action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Xiaofen said that the New Deal emphasizes that transformation can be implemented only with the consent of the majority of villagers. Before the transformation, local governments must first make preliminary planning work such as relocating industries, properly resettling personnel, protecting historical and cultural features, and securing funds. During renovation, the land supply and construction of the resettlement housing project should be arranged in advance to ensure that the resettlement housing is completed within a reasonable period of time, the quality is not lower than that of commercial housing, and the supporting infrastructure and public service facilities are in line with the planning, design, approval, construction, and delivery of the resettlement housing. Use the &quot;five synchronizations&quot; to effectively protect the interests of villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Urban villages are highly complex social complexes and should maintain diversified business formats after renovation.” Zhao Yanjing, vice president of the China Urban Planning Society, said that the urban village itself is an industrial space, and its business formats are not pre-planned. planning, but constantly changing as market demands change. The transformation of urban villages should focus on the introduction and cultivation of industries, and strive to develop various business formats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/42989bb71d383982a62565612bc4cc29.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1254&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/42989bb71d383982a62565612bc4cc29.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254585&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>; Imposition photo: The picture above shows the transformed Hefei, Anhui Province, taken on August 3, 2023 Renovation project of Antuodong Village and Xinzhuang Urban Village in Yaohai District of the city (drone photo); the picture below shows the old appearance of Antuodong Village and Xinzhuang Urban Village before renovation in March 2015. Xinhua News Agency (Photo by Xie Chen) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia said that in the past, urban village reconstruction was market-led, with selectivity and selection. Those with high economic value were included in the reconstruction plan, while there were many problems left over from history and safety issues. Those with high hidden risks were left alone. &quot;This time, all urban villages must be included in the scope of reconstruction. When expropriating and demolishing, we cannot only calculate the economic accounts and only expropriate land plots with high economic value and few problems. Instead, we must expropriate all the land regardless of whether it is good or bad, and completely solve the problem of urban villages. And prevent the emergence of new urban villages.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This urban village transformation requires that in principle, affordable housing should be built in a certain proportion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Zhao Yanjing said that one of the important functions of urban villages in the city is to provide rental affordable housing for the floating population. Urban villages have actually become an integral part of the affordable housing system. &quot;If the supply of affordable housing is reduced after the renovation, the living environment of the floating population deteriorates, and the rents are higher, then the original intention of urban village transformation will not be achieved. Therefore, affordable housing must be built in a certain proportion in the renovation plan as compensation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;What issues should be paid attention to during renovation? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In interviews, experts generally believed that special attention should be paid to three issues when promoting the transformation of urban villages:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the issue of demolition and resettlement. Yu Xiaofen said that urban villages left behind by megacities have many illegal buildings, dense populations, and complex property rights relationships, which are the &quot;hard bones&quot; that are difficult to transform. Issues such as demolition and compensation are very complicated, and there are many contradictions and uncertainties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter learned from interviews in various places that almost all kinds of economic activities are available in urban villages in very large and megacities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In reality, urban villages have formed complementary functions in the long-term interaction with other functions of the city. Simply &#39;cutting off&#39; the urban villages will cause other parts of the city to become disabled. We must be particularly cautious about this. .&quot; Zhao Yanjing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yanjing believes that at the beginning of the transformation, it is necessary to conduct careful research and analysis on the urban functions performed by urban villages. If you cannot find an alternative to these functions, do not rush to &quot;resection&quot; surgery. At this time, &quot;minimally invasive&quot; conservative treatment should be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is the issue of fund balance and financing. Yu Xiaofen said that the remaining urban villages have high building density and high resettlement costs, especially in the current environment where the real estate market outside megacities is still relatively sluggish. Compared with the past, the value of the land transferred after the transformation of urban villages has declined, which will inevitably increase the social impact. Difficulty in raising capital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The key to how to overcome the &#39;hard nut&#39; in urban village transformation is how to balance the transformation funds.&quot; Li Yujia said that the guidance issued by the General Office of the State Council proposed to encourage the implementation of regional coordination and development in large areas, and the land for transformation projects should be divided into four areas. The scope can be expanded to a small amount of surrounding low-efficiency land, allowing the integration and replacement of collective land and state-owned land. &quot;In other words, local governments can change the &#39;small balance&#39; of the past single urban village transformation into the &#39;big balance&#39; of comprehensive transformation of the area, using abundance to make up for the deficit, and using fat to make up for the thin.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Yanjing said , the urban village renovation must innovate the renovation model, seek diverse financing channels, encourage and support the participation of private capital, of which the participation of the original property owners is particularly important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is standards and normative constraints. Some urban villages that do not meet the conditions for demolition have implemented partial demolition and comprehensive renovation, requiring improvement and management in accordance with civilized city standards. This is a problem for some houses with poor quality, low standards, high renovation costs, and unclear property rights of some houses. Urban villages with incomplete procedures are challenging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The transformation of urban villages requires planning before action, overall planning, overall planning, and active and steady advancement. We must use new ideas and new methods to solve the problem of how to calculate the accounts, how to use money, how to acquire land, and how to recruit people in the transformation of urban villages. and how to relocate industries, and explore a new way to transform urban villages under the new situation.&quot; said Chai Qiang, president of the China Society of Real Estate Appraisers and Real Estate Agents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[城市排名，看看就行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258754]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the consulting company Resonance Consultancy released the &quot;Ranking of the World&#39;s Best Cities in 2024&quot;. 2024 has not arrived yet, but the ranking is so forward-looking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this ranking, the top ones are: London, Paris, New York, Tokyo, Singapore, Dubai, San Francisco, Barcelona, ​​Amsterdam, Seoul, Rome, Prague, Madrid, Berlin, Los Angeles, and Washington. Then there is Beijing, ranked 18th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some netizens sarcastically asked, did this list take into account the rarity of drug dealing, shootings, explosions, robberies, thefts, etc.? Nowadays, I increasingly don’t believe in the various rankings selected by foreigners. In some cities, local friends told me not to go out at night before I even went there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sarcasm of netizens has some truth to it. It is actually difficult to define what is the best city. In 2018, a research institution ranked 338 cities above the prefecture level in China and ranked 15 new first-tier cities. Some cities are convinced by this ranking, while others are dissatisfied. In fact, not to mention that the concept of &quot;best&quot; is too big to be defined, even the smaller &quot;urban livability&quot; is difficult to explain clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For ordinary people, whether a city is livable is nothing more than commuting to and from work, making money and development, and basic necessities, food, housing and transportation, that is, income, consumption, and public services. In terms of work, the more developed the city&#39;s economy and the higher the income, the more livable it is. In terms of life, the more convenient, higher comfort and lower the cost of living, the more livable it is. These two aspects are related to the market. Outside the market are the public services provided by the government. Among the public services provided by the government, education and medical care can be provided by the market, but public security can only be provided by the government. Public security is the foundation for a livable city. Otherwise, no matter how much money you make, you can&#39;t save your life, so what&#39;s the point? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times, these indicators are contradictory. The most typical example is that big cities have higher incomes and more development opportunities, but at the same time, housing prices and consumption in big cities are also more expensive, and the cost of living is very high. So, are big cities livable? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, there are more opportunities in big cities. Big cities have economies of scale. Under the economies of scale, there will be many services and jobs that cannot be maintained in small places. This is what many people say, they cannot find a job when they return to their hometown in a small town. Therefore, large cities with higher economic indicators can often provide more jobs and higher wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a consumption perspective, due to scale effects, big cities have richer ecosystems and many services will be cheaper. For example, if you want to see an expert account, living in a big city is just a matter of registration fee. You can find corresponding experts for all kinds of difficult and complicated diseases. But living in a small town also involves extra costs such as travel, accommodation and time off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although houses in big cities are expensive, houses are also an asset. Even if you spend millions to buy a house, the money can still be recovered and liquidated. What&#39;s more, the prices of industrial products such as mobile phones, TVs, and automobiles are almost the same. This means that as long as a person&#39;s income can offset, or partially offset, the rent in a big city, his living standard in a big city will be higher and richer, his children will have more opportunities, and he will be able to spend more in emergencies. money. This is roughly what the word livable refers to. More and more people are flocking to big cities, which also proves that big cities are more livable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, people&#39;s needs are complex and diverse. Some people want to live in a 200-square-meter house and play mahjong, but have no interest in opera or luxury goods. Some people are willing to live in a small house of 60 square meters in order for their children to receive a better education. Therefore, livability ultimately depends on the individual. Whether this is an abstract evaluation of the livability of large cities or small cities, we can only give one judgment principle. If we want to evaluate the livability comparison between specific cities, it is even more confusing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anyone with statistical knowledge and research experience knows that data can lie. Not to mention the authenticity of the data, even if the data is real, there are too many ways to control the final conclusion in terms of indicator settings, sampling methods, data processing, and data interpretation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, set up a consumption indicator, consisting of online shopping activity, overseas shopping activity, takeout activity, and movie viewing frequency. Movie watching seems to reflect cultural consumption, but movies have a lipstick effect, which means that when the economy is bad, people will still entertain themselves, and even use entertainment more to comfort themselves, but they will turn to relatively cheap ones. It is possible that tourism consumption has gone down while movie consumption has increased. Therefore, the movie viewing indicator may not be objective. At least, it is not as authoritative and direct as the indicator of total social consumer goods per capita. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many other indicators selection techniques. If public security is to be regarded as the most important indicator and a number of small indicators are set, then the world ranking of Chinese cities will definitely improve a lot, because Chinese people are kind-hearted and have omnipresent eyes. If you regard fireworks as indicators and set 10 small indicators, then New York&#39;s score may be improved a lot. After all, even Times Square is a mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, urban livability indicators are often not independent. If one indicator improves, other indicators will also improve. For example, if a city has more universities, its medical conditions will also improve. Because universities often have medical schools, there are naturally more experts in medical schools. But it seems impossible to exclude this independence. Because studying in a better university and seeking medical treatment from experts are essentially the educational needs and medical needs of citizens. These are indeed two aspects of needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, by setting indicators, the livability evaluation of a city can indeed be greatly affected. The same is true for other cities&#39; economic activity, urban development, best cities and other rankings. They can be used as a reference, but they do not need to be regarded as authoritative. Generally speaking, which city you decide to work and live in will be the most livable city for you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中职学校数量十年间大减，但“这不是坏事”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258931]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/zb9jBoBeAP8o00VOnloccqJY1Ts9ggT766tPBtXF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1263&quot; height=&quot;841&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/zb9jBoBeAP8o00VOnloccqJY1Ts9ggT766 tPBtXF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 16, 2023, Hohhot, a vocational and technical school teacher introduced the professional situation to students . &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A set of data on secondary vocational education once attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some media reported that in the past ten years, the number of secondary vocational schools has decreased by 3,039. Southern Weekend reporters combined data from the websites of the Ministry of Education and the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and found that from 2013 to 2022, the number of secondary vocational schools continued to decrease, with a cumulative decrease of 2,911. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the websites of the two ministries and commissions, the number of secondary vocational schools in China will be 9,752 in 2022, less than half of the peak in the 1990s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the country’s adjustment of vocational education policies is the main reason for the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools. In addition, the practical difficulties encountered in the development process of secondary vocational schools are also one of the reasons why various places have taken the initiative to merge and reduce schools. However, in recent years, with the changes in the layout of vocational education, secondary vocational schools have also ushered in new changes such as a substantial increase in the enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that, combined with the predictions of scholars, in the next few years, the gradual reduction, dissolution, merger and optimization of secondary vocational schools will continue to be a trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Anhui Province has the largest decrease&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;An easily confused concept is that in China, secondary vocational education is divided into four categories, including general technical secondary schools, vocational High schools, adult secondary schools and technical schools. In accordance with the Vocational Education Law and the current &quot;three determinations&quot; (functional configuration, internal organization and staffing) plan of the State Council, vocational high schools, general technical secondary schools and adult technical secondary schools are under the management of the education department, and technical schools are under the management of the human resources and social security department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be pointed out that the academic qualifications obtained after graduation from general technical secondary schools, vocational high schools, adult technical secondary schools and technical schools are all secondary education qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the Ministry of Education website shows that in 2013, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide was 12,300. By 2022, this number dropped to 7,201. In the past ten years, the number of secondary vocational schools has decreased by 5,100 overall. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A closer look at the year-by-year data on the Ministry of Education’s website will reveal that from 2013 to 2020, the number of secondary vocational schools decreased each year by between 151 and 676. In 2021, the number of secondary vocational schools decreased by 2,602 compared with 2020, and there were obvious abnormalities in the range of data changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, a note on the official website of the Ministry of Education shows that the statistics of secondary vocational colleges in 2021 and 2022 do not include technical schools managed by the human resources and social security departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the official website of the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and found that including data from 2021 and 2022, the number of technical schools increased by 69 and 59 respectively. Combined with the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools in the country from 2013 to 2022 compared with the previous year, the data shows that from 2013 to 2022, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide decreased by 2,911 in ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters inquired about the official data released by the education departments and statistics departments of 31 provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) across the country from 2012 to 2022. Whether each province (autonomous region and municipality) plans to collect data The standards for entering technical schools are not uniform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, looking at the overall situation, nationwide, except for the Tibet Autonomous Region, which has a slight increase in the number of secondary vocational colleges (an increase of 7) on the original basis, the remaining provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) are all. downward trend. The number of secondary vocational schools in Anhui Province has decreased the most, with a decrease of 216 in ten years, a decrease of approximately 44%. Henan Province followed, with a decrease of 198. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, the number of universities has decreased by more than 100 in 10 provinces. Except for Heilongjiang, Shandong, Guangdong, and Zhejiang, the rest are all in the central and western regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, Qinghai, Ningxia and other places have experienced single-digit declines over the past ten years due to factors such as insufficient construction of secondary vocational schools, and the change is not significant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/PxVW6rlgSziSm5VvI9A2ssWYVIZh23jljWzDL0bU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1155&quot; height= &quot;780&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/PxVW6rlgSziSm5VvI9A2ssWYVIZh23jljWzDL0bU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254656&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 25, 2022, in a clothing production company in Tongren, Guizhou, students majoring in clothing design at the Yuping Dong Autonomous County Secondary Vocational School were processing clothing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Policy adjustment is the main reason&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Secondary vocational school It once played an important role in China&#39;s economic development. Its number experienced explosive growth in the late 1980s, from 2,760 in 1978 to more than 20,000 in 1990, an increase of nearly eight times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, by the end of the 20th century, with the combined effects of multiple factors such as industrial restructuring, tightening of the employment environment, and expansion of college enrollment, the development of secondary vocational education gradually declined because it was difficult to adapt to the needs of the market and employers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Official data shows that since 1999, the number of secondary vocational schools has been declining year by year, with only a slight increase between 2004 and 2008. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, in 2007, the Ministry of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Further Improving the Enrollment Management of Various Types of Colleges and Universities&quot;, which stipulated that the corresponding enrollment plan for colleges and universities to recruit secondary vocational graduates should not exceed the number of fresh graduates of secondary vocational schools that year. 5% of students. This proportion limit actually clarifies the employment orientation of secondary vocational education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main reason for the decrease in the number of secondary vocational schools is the adjustment of national policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014 and 2019, the State Council issued the &quot;Decision on Accelerating the Development of Modern Vocational Education&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Decision&quot;) and the &quot;Notice on Issuing the National Vocational Education Reform Implementation Plan&quot; respectively. It is proposed to “encourage high-quality schools to integrate school resources and optimize the layout and structure of secondary vocational education through mergers, trusteeships, cooperative education, etc.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the &quot;Decision&quot; was promulgated, the Beijing Municipal Education Commission announced the corresponding implementation opinions of Beijing, requiring the number of secondary vocational schools in the city to be adjusted from 116 to about 60, a reduction of nearly half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henan started optimizing the layout of secondary vocational schools in 2015, and integrated a number of &quot;weak, small and scattered&quot; schools in the form of cancellation, merger, and transfer. Jiangxi also introduced a new policy for secondary vocational education in 2015, proposing to merge more than 200 secondary vocational schools within three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also in 2015, Guangxi proposed that &quot;by 2020, the number of secondary vocational schools in the region will be adjusted from the current 333 to about 240.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2020, nine departments including the Ministry of Education jointly issued the &quot;Action Plan for Improving the Quality of Vocational Education (2020-2023)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Plan&quot;). Based on the original policy It is further proposed to &quot;comprehensively verify the basic conditions for running secondary vocational schools, integrate &#39;empty, small, scattered and weak&#39; schools, and optimize the layout of secondary vocational schools.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the adjustment of national policies, the difficulties encountered by secondary vocational schools in their own development are also one of the reasons for the reduction in the number of schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, before the state promulgated relevant policies, local governments had already taken measures to reduce the number of secondary vocational schools, which directly pointed to practical problems in the development of secondary vocational education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as the beginning of the 21st century, in order to meet the needs of Beijing’s urban function adjustment and industrial structure upgrading, the Beijing Municipal Education Commission merged a number of small-scale, low-efficiency schools with unclear professional characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is not a bad thing. Only by merging schools with poor quality and low enrollment can we improve the quality and attractiveness of secondary vocational colleges.” Vice Chairman of China Development Research Foundation Fang Jin, the secretary-general, once said publicly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The transformation of secondary vocational schools pays more attention to quality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“The decrease in the number of secondary vocational colleges has a certain relationship with the transformation of secondary vocational education, because the government may China pays more attention to quality rather than quantity.&quot; Xu Hui, a doctoral candidate in sociology at the University of Jena in Germany and a researcher at the Sino-German Research Center for Skills and Social Development, told Southern Weekend reporters that this reduction in quantity may help concentrate resources and improve the quality of education. , to meet today’s ever-changing professional needs. According to Xu Hui’s observation, under the transformation, secondary vocational education has greatly improved in terms of curriculum diversity, technology upgrading, and career guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ensuing increase in attractiveness is also the result of policy changes. One of the key points is the substantial increase in the enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;PhD candidate Jiang Beijia and scientific research assistant Fan Yilin of the National Education Macro Policy Research Institute of East China Normal University published a paper &quot;Policy Changes in Vocational Education for Higher Education: Context, Logic and &quot;Mirror&quot;, sorted out relevant policy documents and found that since the &quot;National Medium and Long-term Education Reform and Development Plan (2010-2020)&quot; issued in 2010, it was first proposed to separate the enrollment of higher vocational examinations from the general college entrance examination. The &quot;National Vocational Education Reform Implementation Plan&quot; clearly states for the first time that &quot;the establishment of a vocational education college entrance examination system&quot; will be completely liberated from the previously restricted enrollment rate in secondary vocational schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, the main channels for secondary vocational school graduates to obtain undergraduate degrees include consistent training, vocational education college entrance examination, junior college to bachelor&#39;s degree, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The smooth flow of channels for further education has led to an increase in the admission rate of secondary vocational schools. Data released by education departments in many places show that the enrollment rate of secondary vocational schools in recent years has generally exceeded 80%. Taking Shenzhen, which has developed secondary vocational education, as an example, the &quot;Shenzhen Secondary Vocational Education Quality Report 2023&quot; shows that in 2022, the number of graduates from Shenzhen&#39;s secondary vocational schools will be 12,485, and the number of students entering higher education will be 11,173, with the enrollment rate reaching 89.49%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Xu Hui also pointed out that a high secondary vocational education promotion rate can provide students with more opportunities, but a careful balance is also needed to ensure that the quality and resources of secondary vocational education are not ignored. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2022, at a press conference held by the Ministry of Education to introduce the work related to promoting the high-quality development of modern vocational education, Chen Ziji, Director of the Department of Vocational Education and Adult Education of the Ministry of Education, further explained that optimizing the quality of secondary vocational education The layout structure is mainly achieved through measures such as cancellation, merger, transformation, trusteeship, land replacement, and group school running. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that in the future, the number of secondary vocational schools nationwide may continue to decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女童被狗咬伤事件中，伤人的罗威纳是种什么犬？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258939]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[普通人上播客讲故事：声波起伏间，听见人生一段]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258802]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;46-year-old excavator Wang Chunyan told her life story through a podcast. This time, her voice arrived In the ears of tens of thousands of people. On the construction site where the machines are roaring, she is silent most of the time. When faced with the foreman&#39;s scolding, she just pretends not to hear it and sometimes has to smile. With only one square meter in the cab, she would listen to her favorite music and sing loudly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DNEXw9iOruxL22YwlzaDlFPOCgz64j52FhUkjWP6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/DNEXw9iOruxL22YwlzaDlFPOCgz64j52FhUkjWP6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254358&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Women are in the minority among those who operate excavators. As one of them, Wang Chunyan’s experience is special. The picture shows the scene of drying chili peppers in Jiuquan, Gansu Province in September 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the collection of stories on the theme of &quot;My achievements have nothing to do with gender&quot; was issued, Kou Aizhe received a large number of submissions , he was first attracted by Wang Chunyan’s message, although she only briefly expressed that as a woman, “the excavator makes me very proud.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye, who is studying for graduate school in France, entered the podcast process as a narrator, which was full of drama. She learned that her father, whom she had not seen for many years, passed away in Cambodia. She wanted to go there, but she did not dare to leave rashly. She happened to find a podcast episode in which a Chinese man in Cambodia, Santiao, told his story about a foreign country. She finally contacted him through a message. With care, Xiaoye completed the &quot;journey to find his father&quot; with peace of mind, and later accepted the invitation to participate in the podcast recording with this story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On Xiaoyushu App, Xiaoye’s story has become one of the three most popular programs among all podcasts. This kind of spread effect was expected by the host Da Meng. What he didn’t expect was that as a Content workers can help some people solve real-life problems while making programs. This is the biggest healing and encouragement Xiaoye&#39;s story brings to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Xinran listened to his podcast outside the massage parlor where he worked. He was embarrassed to listen in front of his colleagues and felt that his voice was unpleasant. When he told his story, there was something &quot;very hard to explain&quot;. He is a blind marathon runner. In the show, he said: &quot;As long as you run, you can create the wind.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kou Aizhe and Dameng are the owners of two podcasts - Story FM and Genius respectively. Founder and anchor of Catcher FM. Story FM passed its seventh birthday, and Genius Catcher FM was born at the end of 2019. The former&#39;s guest self-narration format has become a signature, while the latter uses interviews to capture the inspiration of all kinds of life. The content narrators of podcasts are often industry experts, scholars, and media people, and these two podcasts provide a stage for lay people to talk and express themselves, and amplify their voices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/djz1BWwVeyn3H4uCHyx0M6YiDijOez8Jk340CNkQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/djz1BWwVeyn3H4uCHyx0M6YiDijOez8Jk340CNkQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254360&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There are currently relatively few Chinese podcasts where amateurs tell stories. The picture is a creative picture. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They host almost the only large-scale witness story podcast in China. Dameng saw that the podcast platform classified the two into the story category, which is not a problem in itself. What is strange is that other podcasts in the same category tell ghost stories and historical stories. &quot;They are not the same &#39;storytelling&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;From listener to narrator&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan had been listening to Story FM for five years before she opened her mouth to tell the story. At first, she was attracted by the eye-catching title of Story FM, but gradually she felt that it suited her very well, as it was an &quot;unconcealed, spiritual communication program that directly faces people&#39;s hearts.&quot; She is particularly interested in stories involving life, death and human emotions, and is keenly aware that the program &quot;focuses on more vulnerable groups.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she saw Story FM’s call for submissions to collect stories about women in gender-imbalanced industries, Wang Chunyan had a lot to say. &quot;As a female excavator master, I don&#39;t know if I have a firm foothold, but I have persisted for more than ten years and I feel quite proud.&quot; She left a message, &quot;I didn&#39;t expect Ai Zhe to really see it.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;When the epidemic broke out, Xiaoye developed the habit of listening to podcasts. She described that she had some obsessive-compulsive disorder at the time. After discovering Genius Catcher FM, she listened to every program from the beginning. Xiaoye, who already likes to listen to different life stories, is like finding a treasure. He keeps listening to it until now. The program invited many people from all walks of life to tell their career stories. She was deeply impressed by the psychiatrist Chen Baiyou among them, because what she told was very touching and different from the public perception. &quot;She said that only kind people will suffer from mental illness, which touched me very much.&quot; Xiaoye told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye’s parents went to Cambodia to work together. She was also born in Cambodia. After her parents divorced, her mother took Xiaoye back to China to develop, while her father stayed in Cambodia. In June 2022, Xiaoye learned about her father&#39;s death through relatives. On Father&#39;s Day a week later, she sent her blessings to her father&#39;s WeChat, but she did not expect a response from the other party. A strange Cambodian woman contacted Xiaoye and claimed to be her father&#39;s partner. Later, she invited Xiaoye to Phnom Penh to participate in her father&#39;s 100-day festival. When she was hesitating whether to go there, she happened to see Genius Catcher FM&#39;s push &quot;I collected corpses for Chinese people in Cambodia, but I didn&#39;t dare to show the faces of the corpses to their families.&quot; She left messages for Dameng on various platforms, hoping to get to know the narrator, Santiao, and Dameng set up a connection between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sanjou said to Xiaoye: &quot;Just come, I will pick you up at the airport.&quot; As soon as she left the airport gate, Xiaoye saw the woman holding a photo of her father, but she always felt that she would just go with this stranger , feeling panicked. At this time, Sanjou appeared. He grabbed Xiaoye&#39;s suitcase and protected her from behind. On the first day of Xiaoye&#39;s arrival, Sanjou drove with him all the way, and even called his girlfriend, who could speak English and Cambodian, to act as a translator for Xiaoye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye bought an urn at the local market and took away part of his father&#39;s ashes. Among his father&#39;s belongings, there was a small box containing several photos with Xiaoye. Xiaoye also discovered that although he had not seen his father since his second year in junior high school, his passport still had records of entering China several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Xiaoye returned to daily life, Dameng chatted with her for an hour or two and recorded this life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His father was absent when Xiaoye was growing up. Whether it was on the phone or via WeChat, Xiaoye felt that he could not truly communicate with each other. But within just two or three days of staying in a foreign land, Xiaoye realized that his father had been thinking about him. From a group of strange Cambodian people, she heard her relatives call her: baby, with an exaggerated pronunciation and mouth shape, which was unique to her father. She thought about how many times her father had to say it before everyone around him remembered it. Some listeners shed tears after hearing this detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/N6yoBn0rYEuKFsOCqtCknUHP4Y8clT3ww87UIy03.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/N6yoBn0rYEuKFsOCqtCknUHP4Y8clT3ww87UIy03.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254359&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The stories of the Chinese in Cambodia have been made into a series of podcasts, including the story of Xiaoye going to participate in his father&#39;s 100-day festival. The picture shows the Day of the Dead in Phnom Penh, Cambodia in October 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan has been driving excavators for more than ten years. When she talked about taking hormones to gain weight in order to collect bills more easily and avoid being sexually harassed, Kou Aizhe was shocked and confirmed again, did you really take hormones to gain weight? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many inconveniences for women working as excavators, such as the lack of toilets at the construction site. For this reason, Wang Chunyan would leave home at around 5 a.m. and get off work at around 8 p.m. without taking a sip of water. Sometimes she couldn&#39;t hold it in any longer, so she would dig a hole for emergencies. Not many people can persist. Wang Chunyan has built a &quot;National Queen Group&quot;, which has 99 female excavator operators, roughly 1/3 of which have mature skills. She has accepted three female apprentices, and they either changed careers or started working on their own. When you are the boss, you no longer do it yourself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan persisted mainly to make money. Doing other jobs cannot support this family. When she was 16 years old, her abducted sister returned home nine months pregnant. Both her mother and sister suffer from mental illness, and her father-in-law is careless. The family&#39;s livelihood depends entirely on Wang Chunyan. Later, her husband was in a car accident and became a vegetative state. After he woke up and was discharged from the hospital paralyzed, he owed a large amount of medical expenses, which Wang Chunyan has been paying over the years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than two months after the podcast was released, many listeners left messages and were moved by her tenacity, courage, and optimism. Wang Chunyan didn&#39;t pay much attention to this feedback. She was working every day in the past few days and &quot;didn&#39;t stop to review those things.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Speak out your worries and hear new knowledge&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan has never told her family about the hardships she experienced outside. Her sister, mother, and husband are all patients. Her parents-in-law have never wanted to see her because of her family background. She, there was almost no emotional communication between the two parties. &quot;I don&#39;t have an outlet to vent. Sometimes I feel very depressed and want a space to talk.&quot; Talking about her life in the podcast fulfilled her wish to talk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kou Aizhe understands this mentality very well, “Everyone needs to tell something that has been buried in his heart for a long time, or some obstacles that he cannot get over, or he is confused about this matter and wants to hear some people’s opinions. Feedback, but he may not want people around him to hear it, for example, he cannot accept these people judging him.&quot; Some of the more secretive stories are basically from the narrator&#39;s initiative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, if the narrator states that he does not want certain details to be disclosed, such as name, city, and industry, they will be blurred. This protection of anonymity also gives the narrator more courage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s anonymous anyway, no one knows who I am, so I can say whatever I want.&quot; Xiaoye received Da Meng&#39;s recording invitation and readily agreed. She was very happy to be on the podcast she often listens to. , at the same time, she felt that this story was &quot;quite bizarre, outrageous, and worth telling&quot; and wanted to share it with more people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Dameng’s view, recording a podcast is a process in which the narrator and the producer complement each other. &quot;Sometimes people experience some legendary things and want to record them. Some people are willing to write and some are willing to talk about it. It is also important for the guests to record their own experiences on our program. Let me help them complete it. Content editor.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Because everyone&#39;s life is boring and they are curious about what other people live, so they especially like to listen to such stories. For me, this is a way to see the world. The window is mainly for fun.&quot; Xiaoye explained why people love to listen to stories told by another ordinary person so much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For producers, the fun of doing programs is largely due to the ability to gain new knowledge and broaden their cognitive boundaries. When I first started doing a series of stories about Cambodian characters, almost every issue would refresh Da Meng’s understanding. The narrators all live in Phnom Penh and Sihanoukville, Cambodia, helping Chinese people in trouble in foreign lands. Santiao was the first one to share on the show. He volunteered to help Chinese people who died accidentally in Cambodia, process and cremate their bodies, and transport them back to China. Later, Dameng interviewed Jie Ge and Aaron one after another. They used their own methods to protect the Chinese wandering in Cambodia or guide them on their way home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Beijing Long Distance Running Festival in April 2023 made Dameng pay attention to He Yajun’s Blind Assistance Group. After contacting several blind runners in the group, he chose Song Xinran as the subject of his story. The theme of the program is about &quot;wind&quot;. Every Wednesday and Saturday morning, Song Xinran runs with nearly a hundred teammates in the Beijing Olympic Forest Park, passing through flowers, bamboo forests, and ponds. The blind friend and the running aid volunteer are connected by a running aid rope for the blind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v5xWL54vReWbjIi8ol9nJ4E7jtFpQz3b2eNNqLOk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/v5xWL54vReWbjIi8ol9nJ4E7jtFpQz3b2eNNqLOk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254357&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Song Xinran, a blind man, talked about his experience in long-distance running. The picture shows a blind running rope connecting a blind marathon runner (left) and a volunteer guiding him (right) in Tai&#39;an, Shandong in 2017. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The competition that Song Xinran is most proud of is the 2019 Beijing Long Distance Running Festival. He ran hard and ran within the prescribed time. He crossed the finish line and won the qualification for his runner to pass through to the &quot;Northern Marathon&quot; competition. Running has become an indispensable part of Song Xinran&#39;s life. The customers who come for massage are also infected by him and start practicing running. Sometimes when talking about pace, they praise it, it’s so fast. You have bad eyesight and you can run faster than us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Story FM has also invited some blind narrators. Although everyone has their own interests and hobbies, when it comes to employment, most of them can only go for massages. In a later episode, a group of blind employees from Xiaomi in Shanghai were invited to talk about how they worked as markers and trained the AI ​​Xiao Ai classmates. A blind listener in Xi&#39;an listened to the program and kept sending messages to Kou Aizhe, telling him how the program inspired him. Kou Aizhe witnessed his changes little by little. The latest news was that he came to report good news: Xiaomi was recruiting blind people to do similar work in Xi&#39;an, and he successfully applied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Listening to strangers’ stories sometimes has such a direct impact on the audience that they respond in their own lives. As the popularity of the program increased, Dameng discovered that many listeners regarded Genius Catcher FM as a career guide. A program by a space organizer inspired several listeners to start engaging in related work. A person passed the police civil service examination and sent a private message saying that he was not a police major. After listening to the program, he yearned for the honor and experience of this profession and had a belief. I was so moved and frightened that I turned on the program and listened to it again, &quot;Don&#39;t say anything nonsense.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let different people &quot;penetrate each other&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye likes to listen to podcasts in the shower and while commuting. Chatting podcasts rank first in her mind. “They are the kind where the host is chatting, and you listen and feel like you can join in, so you can’t help but join in the discussion.” One time while commuting, she heard something funny and stopped to stamp her feet on the street and burst into laughter. Life seemed to have a different color because her ears were plugged and she couldn&#39;t hear the sounds outside. At that moment, she felt happy and contented, &quot;This is my world.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When operating an excavator, if the construction site is large enough, has a good view, and the work is not too tight, Wang Chunyan will turn on the stereo and listen to something. Only in the one-square-meter cab of the excavator can she have some time of her own. The rest of the time belongs to others. &quot;Coming home is like fighting a war.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan also plays Douyin. Among the bloggers she follows, there are many ideological ones, but she believes that &quot;Douyin is just a kind of fast food, and the real nutritious meal is podcasts.&quot; Podcasts arouse her deep understanding. There is more to think about than short videos. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A podcast episode is usually tens of minutes long, or even as long as two or three hours. Unlike short videos and other content, Dameng pointed out that the main value that podcasts, long-form content that focuses on reality, can bring to listeners is &quot;companionship and recognition.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He interviewed the founders of transgender groups, social workers who helped female domestic workers, and niche professional or hobby groups, trying to reflect the situation of a group of people through their narration of their fate and experiences, and make many people who originally felt People who are very lonely are no longer so lonely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In podcasts where amateurs tell stories, the narrator’s expressive ability is not that important. Dameng believes that the value of stories to people, the scarcity of information, and the desire of guests to share are all more important than the ability to express themselves. Kou Aizhe bluntly said that the so-called ability to express well is actually a privilege. What Story FM wants to do is to break it rather than strengthen it. &quot;Those who are not so eloquent in expression have very good stories and very good experiences, but they It is a pity to remain silent.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kou Aizhe interviewed a contributor, a female worker on the assembly line. For many years, she tried to take her children with her and live with her in the city, but she encountered obstacles everywhere. Later, she also tried to return to her hometown. Find a job, but there are no good jobs in my hometown to support my family and give my children a better life. Although her education level is not high and her expression is simple and unpretentious, she resonates with many parents from middle-class families in first-tier cities. Parents&#39; love and devotion to their children and the struggles in raising children are common. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I don’t want people to use a certain label to evaluate a person. This may be what my story wants to show.” Kou Aizhe wants to use the podcast to let people of different classes or classes People &quot;penetrate each other&quot;, understand what their respective lives are like, and have a better understanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan once listened to the program &quot;Behind the 50 million blind date game, do billionaires still believe in love&quot; with curiosity. She concluded, &quot;The basic characteristics of us as a person are sincerity and sincerity, whether he is a multi-millionaire or an ordinary citizen. &lt;span>;&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; &quot;Whether it is a short video, or some short posts, pictures and texts, we will soon get a conclusion, but in the podcast, we can follow the people who have experienced it and retrace this person&#39;s growth and experience. , you will find that there is complexity behind everything and everyone.&quot; Dameng told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Just see this side of me&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Song Xinran&#39;s podcast was forwarded to the running group by the captain. His teammates praised him and told stories that were very true. I hope he will do it again in the future. I can hear the story told by him himself. He also mentioned in the podcast how he and his girlfriend met and fell in love. The two trained together in a running group and gradually developed a relationship. On the day he confessed his love, he hugged his girlfriend. Someone in the group heard it and teased, &quot;Young people today are so courageous. We didn&#39;t dare to do that back then.&quot; After listening to the show, his girlfriend also blamed Song Xinran for &quot;talking about the two of them&quot; So straightforward.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoye listened to that episode of her show to her friends. Several friends she was not familiar with sent her long essays on WeChat. The central idea was comfort and praise, &quot;You did a really good job with me.&quot; Goodbye&quot;. Xiaoye likes to ask friends who have listened to it, did you cry &lt;span>;? &lt;/span>;When the other party said he was crying, Xiaoye thought, &quot;Okay, I feel like I have earned something.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan is very low-key about recording podcasts, and her daughter is the only one she shares with. During the three years when Wang Chunyan accompanied her husband to the hospital in Zhejiang, her daughter was sent back to her hometown in Hubei. When she was in elementary school, she was bullied on campus and suffered from depression. She has always been rebellious and rarely communicated with her parents. Wang Chunyan didn&#39;t know how her daughter felt specifically after hearing this, because she didn&#39;t say anything and didn&#39;t contact him until a day later. But from then on, her daughter became willing to chat with Wang Chunyan and became more concerned about her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the trip to Cambodia, Xiaoye said nothing to his relatives, including his mother, and naturally did not let them know about the podcast he had recorded. Father is a topic that Xiaoye and her mother tacitly avoid talking about. Xiaoye also doesn’t want her mother to know that she went to Cambodia: “On the one hand, because she is a bit controlling, I still act like a more obedient daughter most of the time. , I will try my best to listen to her opinion on such a big matter. She told me very seriously before that she didn’t want me to go, but out of my own stubbornness, I went anyway. And I didn’t really want her to know that she was There is another lady in Cambodia who lives with my dad, and I don’t want her to be away from my dad for so long and have to think about my dad’s affairs.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Xiaoye also hopes that her mother will find out about this. Maybe the two of them will be more open to talking about it. Xiaoye decided not to tell her proactively, and recording the podcast was like burying a clue. Maybe she would find it, and maybe it would become a secret forever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Story FM invites producers to conduct a &quot;year-end summary&quot; in 2022. One of the producers mentioned that when he was producing a program, he was so moved by a confession from the interviewee that he thought of ending the program with this paragraph. However, the interviewee then asked: &quot;How is it? I So it can arouse the audience&#39;s emotions, right?&quot; The producer suddenly realized that even interviews that pursue documentary often only enlarge the fragments of a person&#39;s life, so he wanted to remind the audience: don&#39;t care so much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first few days after the show aired, Xiaoye paid attention to the comments. When she saw someone saying that they really wanted to follow Xiaoye&#39;s Weibo, she thought to herself, please don&#39;t. &quot;When you listen to my story, this is one side of me, but if you really pay attention to my life, it&#39;s the other side. People are multi-faceted. Just see this side of me. I don&#39;t want to show it in all directions. I don’t like it in front of the public.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The podcast condenses a small part of their life memories, and the real life continues, which is far more complicated than the story being told. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Chunyan said in the program that she made a wish in front of Bodhisattva at that time. If her husband wakes up, she is willing to give him half of his life span and only live to 50 years old. She will reach this age in a few years, and she hopes to travel and live a life for herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, Wang Chunyan, in addition to her passion and bravery, also has a level of sobriety and coldness that has been polished by her circumstances. She believes, &quot;I have seen too many things in the world, and it is of no use to live so much. Living to 50 years old is enough.&quot; When she went to the mental hospital to visit her sister, she no longer recognized her, and she needed others to hand her water and food before she could eat. She thought, in that state, what role did maintaining her sister&#39;s life play? It was just to make herself, a relative, feel at ease. She has read &quot;Dream of Red Mansions&quot; countless times, and is no stranger to the illusion of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the interview, she suddenly asked the Southern Weekend reporter whether bone marrow donation (commonly known as hematopoietic stem cell donation) would have any impact on the donor&#39;s health. She had applied for a voluntary donation of hematopoietic stem cells, and recently had an initial meeting with a patient. The match was successful, but my daughter disagreed. If it does not affect her work, she still hopes to contribute: &quot;A life is waiting, and it would be too cruel not to save it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;(Xiaoye and Santiao are pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[最高法发布国家公园司法保护典型案例]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258840]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;National parks are the most important in our country Natural ecological space is the most important part of the natural ecosystem, with the most unique natural landscape, the most essential natural heritage, and the richest biodiversity. The establishment of a national park system is something that General Secretary Xi Jinping personally planned, deployed, and promoted as a &quot;big man in the country.&quot; Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has stood at the strategic height of realizing the sustainable development of the Chinese nation and made a series of major strategic arrangements to promote the establishment of a national park system and accelerate the construction of natural protection with national parks as the main body. system, and effectively strengthen the protection of natural ecology. On October 12, 2021, President Xi Jinping announced at the 15th Leaders’ Summit of the Conference of the Parties to the Convention on Biological Diversity that my country has officially established the Sanjiangyuan, giant pandas, Siberian tigers and leopards, Hainan tropical rainforests, Wuyi Mountains, etc. The approval of the national park marks that this major innovative system of national parks has taken root and the construction of national parks has entered a new level. In November 2022, my country issued the &quot;National Park Spatial Layout Plan&quot;, which clarified the work process, main construction tasks and implementation safeguards for the establishment of national parks, selected 49 national park candidate areas, and outlined a plan for building the world&#39;s largest national park. The grand blueprint of the system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The construction of high-quality national parks is an important part of the construction of my country&#39;s ecological civilization system. It is important for promoting the scientific protection and rational utilization of natural resources, promoting the harmonious coexistence of man and nature, and promoting a beautiful China. Construction is of extremely important significance. In recent years, the People&#39;s Court has always adhered to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, deeply implemented Xi Jinping Thought on the Rule of Law and Xi Jinping Thought on Ecological Civilization, and thoroughly implemented the concept of dynamic judiciary. It persisted in serving the overall situation, administering justice for the people, and properly hearing cases in accordance with the law. Various environmental resource cases involving national parks, including environmental pollution prevention and control, ecological protection and restoration, and resource development and utilization, strive to promote the high-level protection and high-quality development of my country&#39;s national parks. In order to strengthen the publicity of the rule of law in national parks, cultivate national park culture, spread the concept of national parks, and demonstrate the effectiveness of the people&#39;s courts in protecting national parks, the Supreme People&#39;s Court released a series of typical cases on the judicial protection of national parks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ten typical cases are released this time, with the following highlights. First, there are many types of litigation involved and the scope of protection is wide. This batch of typical cases includes different types of litigation such as environmental resources criminal, civil and public interest litigation, covering the main scope of environmental resources trials; the national parks involved include Sanjiangyuan, Giant Panda, Siberian Tiger and Leopard, and Hainan Tropical Rainforest Five of the first national parks to be established, including Wuyi Mountain and Qianjiangyuan-&lt;/span>; Baishanzu National Park, were included in the National Park Spatial Layout Plan. There are many types of national park protection cases and lawsuits, and the scope of national park protection is wide. The second is to insist on active justice. Case 5: Wang Min and six others were involved in a criminal incidental public interest litigation case of indiscriminate logging of trees and endangering nationally protected plants, and case 9: Zhang Mouyan and Zhang Mouyi sued the Yangxian County Forestry Bureau over the right to life dispute. The People&#39;s Court found during the trial that We do not use mechanical justice to solve the loopholes and shortcomings in the management of national parks. Instead, we actively extend the environmental resources adjudication function, actively integrate into the process of ecological civilization construction, issue judicial suggestions to administrative departments, and urge relevant departments to identify and fill vacancies. It is a vivid practice of active justice. The third is to adhere to the concept of integrated protection and systematic governance. Case 3: The case of environmental pollution by Yang and other three persons, which reflects the people&#39;s court&#39;s strengthening of the management of environmental pollution in the area adjacent to the Giant Panda National Park; Case 4: Li and 11 other persons endangering precious and endangered wild animals, criminal incidental civil public interest litigation , the People&#39;s Court launched a full-chain crackdown on the &quot;hunting-acquisition-transportation-sales&quot; link of crimes that endanger precious and endangered wild animals, which is a vivid practice of integrated protection and systematic governance. The fourth is to adhere to the strictest rule of law principle. Case 1 &lt;span>; In the illegal mining cases of Zheng Moucheng, Gao Mojin, and Ye Moudong, for illegal mining of national strategic resources, severe punishment is required within the statutory range of punishment, and the application of suspended sentences is strictly controlled, and judicial use is used to The sword ensures the development and utilization of national strategic resources. Case 7: The First Branch of the Hainan Provincial People&#39;s Procuratorate sued Li Mouqing and Ye Mouqing for ecological damage civil public interest litigation. While the perpetrators had been sentenced to criminal liability in another case, their civil liability for compensation was seriously pursued, which reflected the responsibility for damage and the ultimate goal. The principle of strict rule of law. Case 8: The People’s Procuratorate of Kaihua County, Zhejiang Province sued Lu Mouyan and four others for ecological damage civil public interest litigation. The illegal purchase and sale of wild animals through recording of slaughtering videos for inspection, online payment, mail delivery, etc. shall be severely punished in accordance with the law. It demonstrates the attitude of protecting the ecological environment of the national park with the strictest system and strictest rule of law. Fifth, adhere to preventive justice. Case 4: Li Mouhua and 11 other persons were involved in a civil public interest litigation incidental to the crime of endangering precious and endangered wild animals. This case was implemented against criminals who are zoo operators in order to prevent them from taking advantage of the convenient conditions for acquiring, raising, selling, and transporting wild animals. For such crimes, the People&#39;s Court imposed a &quot;prohibition order&quot; on them, which reflects the concept of preventive justice. Sixth, properly handle the relationship between people&#39;s livelihood, development and protection. Case 2: In the case of Zhang Mouqiang’s illegal manufacturing of guns and illegal hunting, probation was applied to local villagers who had just escaped from poverty to prevent families who had just escaped from poverty from returning to poverty due to punishment, and better balanced the relationship between ecological environment protection and people’s livelihood security. Case 6: Li Mouliang, Yang Mouli’s fire, and Yang Mouli’s illegal hunting criminal incidental civil public interest litigation case. Taking into account the financial difficulties of the defendants, they were allowed to perform off-site ecological restoration obligations through labor compensation, which reflected the judicial emphasis on people’s livelihood protection. Concerned. Case 9: Zhang Mouyan and Zhang Mouyi sued the Yangxian County Forestry Bureau for a dispute over the right to life. In accordance with the relevant provisions of the Wildlife Protection Law, the family members of those injured or killed by wild animals were supported in their request for compensation from the relevant departments, which reflected a balanced consideration. The dual goals of wildlife protection and safeguarding the safety of people’s lives and property. Case 10: The bankruptcy and reorganization case of a hydropower development company in Qinghai, giving full play to the role of trial functions, strengthening coordination with relevant government departments, promoting the full resumption of work of the hydropower station involved in the case, effectively resolving corporate bankruptcy disputes, and properly handling social and economic development and ecological environmental protection Relationship. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The proper hearing of these ten typical cases of judicial protection of national parks in accordance with the law fully demonstrates the people&#39;s courts&#39; ability to play the role of trial of ecological environment resources and protect the integrity of the natural ecosystem of national parks in accordance with the law. The responsibility of maintaining national ecological security, protecting biodiversity, and promoting high-level protection and high-quality development of national parks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Typical cases of judicial protection of national parks&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1. Zheng Moucheng and Gao Mojin , Ye Moudong’s illegal mining case&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2. Zhang Mouqiang’s illegal manufacturing of guns and illegal hunting case&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;3. Yang The environmental pollution case of three persons including Li Mouhua&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;4. The criminal incidental civil public interest litigation case of Li Mouhua and eleven persons endangering precious and endangered wild animals&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;5. Criminal incidental civil public interest litigation case involving Wang Min and six others who deforestation and endangered national key protected plants&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;6. Li Mouliang , Yang Mouli caught fire, Yang Mouli illegal hunting criminal incidental civil public interest litigation case&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;7. The First Branch of Hainan Provincial People’s Procuratorate sued Li Mouqing and Ye Mouqing for ecological damage Civil public interest litigation case&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;8. Civil public interest litigation case of Kaihua County People’s Procuratorate of Zhejiang Province against Lu Mouyan and four others for ecological damage&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;9. Zhang Mouyan and Zhang Mouyi v. Yang County Forestry Bureau over the right to life dispute case&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;10. Bankruptcy and reorganization case of a hydropower development company in Qinghai &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;1. Illegal mining cases of Zheng Moucheng, Gao Moujin and Ye Moudong&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;[Basic facts of the case]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The defendant Zheng Moucheng jointly contracted with others the forest land located in a mountain farm in Luanfeng Township, Guangze County, Fujian Province. The mountain farm is located within the scope of Wuyishan National Park . Zheng Moucheng and the defendant Gao Moucheng became friends, and the two planned to jointly mine rare earths for profit in the mountain farm. From September 2016 to May 2017, Zheng Moucheng and Gao Mojin organized Feng Mouan, Zhong Mouming (all handled in separate cases) and defendant Ye Moudong and others to go to the mine without a mining license. The mountain farm mines rare earth minerals by digging caves in the mountain, injecting ammonium sulfate, etc., and then precipitating the precipitated liquid. 9,300 kilograms of suspected rare earth semi-finished products were seized on site. After identification, the rare earth minerals involved in the case are all ion-adsorbed rare earths, which are specific mineral types stipulated by the state for protective mining. The illegal mining behavior of Zheng Moucheng and others also caused damage to the mineral resources of rare earth mineral sites. In addition, it was also found that Ye Moudong had a dispute and fight with others over trivial matters in March 2018, and was guilty of intentional injury causing minor injuries. Guangze County, Fujian Province prosecuted Zheng Moucheng, Gao Mojin, and Ye Moudong for illegal mining, and Ye Moudong for intentional injury. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After trial, the People’s Court of Guangze County, Fujian Province held that the defendants Zheng Moucheng and Gao Moumou Jin, Ye Moudong and others violated the provisions of the Mineral Resources Law and exploited the ion adsorption rare earth mineral of a specific mineral type that the state implements protective mining without a mining license. The circumstances were particularly serious and constituted the crime of illegal mining. Zheng Moucheng and Gao Jin are the principal offenders, and Ye Moudong is an accessory. Zheng Moucheng and Gao Moujin were sentenced to four years and nine months in prison respectively for the crime of illegal mining and fined 150,000 yuan. Ye Moudong was sentenced to three years in prison for the crime of illegal mining and intentional injury. year, and be fined 100,000 yuan; the rare earth semi-finished products seized will be confiscated. After the verdict was pronounced, the defendant Gao Moujin refused to accept the verdict and filed an appeal. The second instance ruling of Nanping Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Fujian Province dismissed the appeal and upheld the original judgment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical significance]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wuyishan National Park is currently the only one in my country that is both a world man and biosphere reserve and a The national park, a world cultural and natural heritage, contains numerous non-renewable and valuable mineral resources. Among them, rare earths are important strategic resources for our country and are key elements in emerging industries, high-end manufacturing, and modern national defense science and technology industry. In recent years, criminal acts of illegal mining of rare earths have occurred in the areas around Wuyishan National Park, damaging the country&#39;s rare earth resource reserves and seriously threatening the security of the national park&#39;s environmental resources. The defendant in this case mined rare earth minerals using the in-situ leaching method, which endangered the ecological service functions and ecosystem stability of Wuyishan National Park, and easily led to vegetation destruction, mountain exposure, water source pollution, soil erosion, landslides, ground cracks and subsidence, etc. Serious consequences occur. When the value of the mined mineral products and the value of the damage caused to the mineral resources have been ascertained, the people&#39;s court determined that the defendant&#39;s illegal mining behavior was particularly serious based on the value of the damage caused to the mineral resources, and severely punished the crime of illegal mining of rare earths in accordance with the law. Strict punishment within the penalty range and strict control over the application of suspended sentences will help ensure the development and utilization of national strategic resources and protect the ecological security of national parks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;2. Zhang Mouqiang’s illegal manufacturing of firearms and illegal hunting case&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Basic case facts 】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;During 2017, the defendant Zhang Mouqiang went to a hardware store in Haikou City, Hainan Province to buy a nail gun, a barrel, iron sand, and nail bullets. , using its own tools to assemble a gun-shaped object. After identification, the gun-shaped object manufactured by Zhang Mouqiang was a gun that used gunpowder as its firing power. In the early morning of March 21, 2022, Zhang Mouqiang entered the Bawangling Branch of Hainan Tropical Rainforest National Park, which is designated as a protected hunting area, without permission from the wildlife administrative department, and without a hunting license or a gun license. During the hunting at the flood management station, a total of 3 red-bellied squirrels, 1 coconut cat, and 1 ferret badger were hunted using guns, and 30 big green stink frogs were hunted using headlights. Zhang Mouqiang was caught on the spot by the public security police on his way down the mountain the next day. After identification, the coconut cat involved in the case is a national second-level protected wild animal. The ferret badger and red-bellied squirrel are included in the &quot;List of Terrestrial Wild Animals Protected by the State as Beneficial or of Important Economic and Scientific Research Value.&quot; The smelly frog belongs to Hainan. The province focuses on protecting terrestrial wildlife. The Second Branch of the Hainan Provincial People&#39;s Procuratorate prosecuted Zhang for illegally manufacturing firearms and illegal hunting. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Hainan Provincial No. 2 Intermediate People’s Court held after trial that Zhang’s violent behavior constituted illegality The crimes of manufacturing firearms and illegal hunting should be punished concurrently. As a villager living in a national park area who has just emerged from poverty, Zhang Mouqiang still needs time to explore to change the local traditional production and lifestyle and take the road of green development to improve people&#39;s livelihood. Zhang Mouqiang is the main labor force in his family. His detention is not in compliance with the modesty principle of the criminal law and may also return his family to poverty. The authority of the law lies in the inevitability of punishment rather than its severity. When lighter punishment can be used to achieve the purpose of sanction, there is no need to use severe sanctions. In view of the fact that Zhang Mouqiang was a first-time offender, he truthfully confessed his crime after the incident, pleaded guilty and accepted punishment, and showed remorse. His place of residence was willing to cooperate with community corrections, and it was declared that the suspended sentence would have no major adverse impact on the community where he lived. The verdict was then given: Zhang Mouqiang was punished for several crimes, and it was decided to execute a three-year prison sentence, suspended for five years, and confiscate criminal tools. After the verdict was announced, the parties did not appeal or protest, and the first-instance judgment has become legally effective. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical significance]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In April 2022, General Secretary Xi Jinping clearly pointed out that tropical rainforest countries The park is a national treasure, a reservoir, a grain depot, a money storehouse, and even a carbon storehouse. It requires strict protection of the tropical rainforest to achieve the unity of ecological protection, green development, and improvement of people&#39;s livelihood. Although the protection of environmental resources continues to increase during the construction of the Hainan Tropical Rainforest National Park, harmful use of tropical rainforest and biodiversity resources by indigenous villagers near the national park still occurs from time to time. In this case, the defendant violated hunting regulations and used modified guns and other tools for hunting in the game reserve, which destroyed the value of wild animal resources and should be subject to criminal sanctions. At the same time, the people&#39;s court fully considered the individual factors of the defendant, gave him the opportunity to rehabilitate, and applied suspended sentences to prevent families who had just escaped from poverty from returning to poverty due to punishment, demonstrated the humanistic care of the judiciary, and achieved the purpose of combining punishment and crime prevention. , and also better balances the relationship between ecological environment protection and people&#39;s livelihood security. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;3. Case of environmental pollution by Yang and three others&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Basic case facts]&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From June to September 2020, the defendants Yang, Qu Moumin, and Gao Hu did not obtain a hazardous waste business license and did not take ground protection measures. , in the mountain forest of a village in Huaping Town, Anzhou District, Mianyang City, Sichuan Province, adjacent to the Giant Panda National Park protection area, 14.53 tons of waste engine oil grids were crushed and disposed using crushers and other equipment, and scrap iron and waste engine oil were separated and Sale. The three defendants made an illegal profit of 26,450 yuan from selling scrap iron and more than 6,000 yuan from selling waste engine oil. The Mianyang Municipal Ecological Environment Bureau determined that the waste oil grid involved in the case was a filter adsorption medium containing or contaminated with waste engine oil. It was included in the &quot;National Hazardous Waste List&quot;, with waste category HW49 and waste code 900-041-49, and was classified as hazardous waste. . After evaluation, the highest concentration of petroleum hydrocarbons in the soil of the plot involved in the case is 3080mg/Kg, which exceeds the screening value for the first type of land in Table 1 of the &quot;Soil Environmental Quality Standards for Soil Pollution Risk Management and Control of Construction Land (Trial)&quot; (GB36600-2018), and it is determined The land is contaminated by petroleum hydrocarbons, and this illegal production has caused damage to the soil ecological environment of the land. The three defendants all surrendered, voluntarily pleaded guilty and punished, signed a recognizance, and voluntarily returned the illegal income of 33,000 yuan. The People&#39;s Procuratorate of Anzhou District, Mianyang City, Sichuan Province launched a public prosecution against Yang, Qu and Gao for the crime of environmental pollution. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After hearing, the People’s Court of Anzhou District, Mianyang City, Sichuan Province held that Yang and Qu Min and Gao Hu violated national regulations and illegally disposed of hazardous waste, seriously polluting the environment and constituting the crime of environmental pollution. The three defendants committed a joint crime, and their criminal roles were equal, without distinguishing between the principal and the accomplice; the three defendants voluntarily surrendered and truthfully confessed their crimes, so they surrendered, and may be given a lighter or reduced punishment in accordance with the law; the three defendants voluntarily confessed and accepted punishment, and may be treated leniently ; The three defendants who voluntarily return all their illegal gains may be given a lighter punishment as appropriate. The verdict was then: Yang, Qu Min, and Gao Hu were each sentenced to nine months in prison and suspended for one year each. They were also fined 15,000 yuan each, and their illegal gains of 33,000 yuan were confiscated (already recovered). After the verdict was announced, the parties did not appeal or protest, and the first-instance judgment has become legally effective. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical meaning]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Forest soil is the material basis for the development of forestry production. In recent years, some lawless elements, motivated by profit, have invaded mountain farm forest land, illegally recycled waste engine oil, and dumped toxic and harmful substances, causing serious damage to forest land soil and its accompanying crops, disrupting the ecological balance of the forest, and harming public interests. The place where this case occurred is adjacent to the Giant Panda National Park protection area. Since the waste engine oil pollution medium is fluid and migratory, the environmental pollution incident caused by waste engine oil should not only be based on the boundaries of the national park, but also the borders of the national parks. Comprehensive and integrated regional protection. In this case, the People&#39;s Court punished criminal acts that polluted the environment in accordance with the law, comprehensively strengthened the protection of environmental resources, adhered to the harmonious coexistence of man and nature, and practiced the concept that clear waters and lush mountains are valuable assets. In order to accelerate the formation of green development methods, promote economic development and the environment Protecting a win-win situation provides legal protection. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;4. Li Mouhua and other 11 people’s criminal incidental civil public interest litigation case of endangering precious and endangered wild animals&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Basic Case Facts]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Since 2019, the defendant Li Mouhua contacted the defendant Long Moujun many times to hunt wild red pandas alive. From 2019 to April 2020, Long Moujun sold 15 live wild red pandas he captured to Li Mouhua and the defendant Li Mouqiu (Li Mouhua’s son); Li Mouhua and his son transported 14 of them to He went to Laizhou, Shandong, Nanjing, Jiangsu and other places, and sold 2 animals to the defendant Liu Moujia, and sold a total of 10 animals to three other zoo operators (handled separately), making an illegal profit of 290,000 yuan. From November to December 2020, Long Moujun purchased 4 live wild red pandas from the defendant Gao Moulin, released one of them with a defective ear, and drove the 3 red pandas to Sichuan. In Luding County, Sichuan Province, Li Mouhua, his son and the defendant Liu Mou B drove to purchase the three red pandas from Luding and were seized by the public security organs on their way back. Since April 2020, Li Mouhua and his son went to Suojiang Qiang Township, Pingwu County, Sichuan Province to purchase 18 live golden monkeys from defendant Ma Cao; 13 of them were hired by Li Mouhua and his son, defendants Zhang Mouhua and Liu Mouyi transported it to Tongling, Anhui Province and sold it to the defendants Xu Mouzhen, Shen Mou and others who ran the zoo, making an illegal profit of 560,000 yuan. After identification, the red pandas involved in the case are all national second-level protected wild animals, with a single value of 40,000 yuan; the golden monkeys are all Sichuan golden monkeys, which are national first-level protected wild animals, with a single value of 500,000 yuan. The Ya&#39;an Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate filed a public prosecution against Li Mouhua and 11 other people for the crime of endangering precious and endangered wild animals, and also filed an incidental civil public interest lawsuit, requesting compensation for the death of Li Mouhua, Li Mouqiu, Liu Moujia, and Long Moujun. The public welfare compensation for 11 wild red pandas totaled 440,000 yuan. Li Mouhua, Li Mouqiu, and Ma Cao compensated 500,000 yuan for the death of a wild golden monkey. Eleven defendants including Li Mouhua jointly disclosed it to the media. Make amends and apologize. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Intermediate People’s Court of Ya’an City, Sichuan Province held after trial that Li Mouhua and others illegally hunted The act of catching, selling, purchasing, and transporting rare and endangered wild animals under key state protection shall constitute the crime of endangering precious and endangered wild animals. Among them, Li Mouhua and Li Mouqiu illegally purchased, transported and sold 18 Sichuan golden monkeys, a national first-level protected wild animal, and 18 red pandas, a national second-level protected wild animal. The total value of the wild animals was 9.72 million yuan. The circumstances were particularly serious and comprehensive. Considering that Li Mouhua was a recidivist and confessed, and Li Mouqiu was guilty of meritorious service, Li Mouhua was sentenced to 14 years in prison and fined 500,000 yuan, and Li Mouqiu was sentenced to eight years in prison and fined 300,000 yuan. Ma Moucao illegally hunted and sold 18 Sichuan golden monkeys, a national first-level protected wild animal. The wild animals were worth 9 million yuan. The circumstances were particularly serious. Taking into account the circumstances such as his surrender and other circumstances, Ma Moucao was sentenced to 11 years in prison and fined. 300,000 yuan in gold. The remaining defendants were sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment ranging from three to six years and fines ranging from 50,000 yuan to 250,000 yuan. Zoo operators Liu A and Xu Zhen are also prohibited from engaging in all business activities related to wild animals for five years from the date of completion of the sentence or the date of parole. The court ordered the civil public interest litigation defendants Li Hua, Li Qiu, Liu Jia, and Long Jun to jointly pay public welfare compensation of 440,000 yuan, and Li Hua, Li Mouqiu, and Ma Cao to jointly pay public welfare compensation of 500,000 yuan. Li Mouhua and other eleven people publicly apologized in the media. After the verdict was announced, some of the defendants, including Ma Cao, were dissatisfied and appealed. After hearing the verdict, the Sichuan Higher People&#39;s Court ruled to reject the appeal and uphold the original verdict. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical meaning]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Pingwu County, Mianyang City, Sichuan Province, one of the places where the case occurred, is a giant panda. The core area of ​​the national park is known as &quot;the first county in the world for giant pandas&quot;. The Giant Panda National Park is of great significance for strengthening the overall protection of giant pandas and other species they protect and typical ecologically fragile areas, and creating an important national ecological barrier. In this case, the defendant hunted nationally protected wild animals for sale in the Giant Panda National Park, forming a complete industrial chain of &quot;hunting-acquisition-transportation-sales&quot; that endangers precious and endangered wild animals. Zoos are the end of the chain, and wild animals are &quot;whitewashed&quot; through zoo acquisitions and re-trades, seriously damaging the authenticity, integrity and systematicity of the natural ecosystem in the Giant Panda National Park. Some of the defendants in this case are zoo operators and have the facilities to engage in the acquisition, breeding, sale, and transportation of wild animals. They knew that the acquisition and transportation of precious and endangered wild animals must be approved in accordance with legal procedures, but they took advantage of their professional facilities to pursue economic interests. The crime of illegally purchasing and transporting wild animals has seriously violated professional ethics and professional obligations. In order to prevent him from committing such crimes again, the People&#39;s Court sentenced him to a &quot;prohibition order&quot;, prohibiting the criminal from engaging in wildlife business again, which reflects the fight against and prevention of We are determined to protect the ecological security of national parks with the strictest rule of law. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;5. A criminal incidental civil public interest litigation case involving Wang Min and six others who cut down trees and endangered national key protected plants&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Basic Case Facts]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In February 2022, the defendant Wang Min signed a &quot;Lin Rights Agreement&quot; with Qiao Moumou, an outsider in the case, in the name of his wife. &quot;Forest Land Transfer Contract&quot;, the land use rights and forest ownership rights of 3,785 acres of forest land in a village in Liangshui Town, Tumen City, Jilin Province were transferred. In April of the same year, Wang Min used the ID card of Wang, who was not involved in the case, to apply for a forest logging license. The logging locations were three logging areas of Liangshui Forest Farm. The total approved logging volume was 456 cubic meters, and the tree species was oak. From April to May of the same year, Wang Min hired the defendant Zhang Kui to organize multiple people to enter the site for operations. The defendants Sha, Liu Jun, Xu Ren and others were responsible for logging, and the defendant Yang was responsible for returning to the forest and loading the truck. . In addition to the above three approved logging areas, the actual logging area of ​​Wang Moumin and others also includes three unapproved logging areas such as the logging area on the east side of Lengchang, which are collective forest areas or state-owned forest areas; the felled trees include Oak trees, poplar trees, linden trees, etc. It was identified that Wang Min and others violated the tree species, quantity and logging methods specified in the forest logging permit, and illegally felled oak, poplar and other trees with a standing stock of 1,438 cubic meters worth more than 1.31 million yuan; they also felled 485 purple lindens, a national second-level protected plant. The standing timber storage is 257 cubic meters, worth more than 230,000 yuan. The People&#39;s Procuratorate of Hunchun Forest District of Jilin Province initiated a public prosecution for the above-mentioned behavior for the crime of deforestation and endangering national key protected plants; it also filed an incidental civil public interest lawsuit against Wang Min and other six defendants, claiming that Wang Min was responsible for comprehensive restoration of the ecological environment. The cost was more than 1.56 million yuan, for which Sha, Zhang Mokui and Yang were jointly and severally liable, Liu Jun and Xu Ren were jointly and severally liable for 140,000 yuan, and the six defendants jointly borne the appraisal fee of 5,000 yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After hearing, the Basic Court of Hunchun Forest District, Jilin Province held that Wang Min, Sha and others The six people violated the quantity, tree species and logging methods stipulated in the forest logging license and arbitrarily felled a huge amount of trees. Their behavior constituted the crime of indiscriminate logging. Wang Min and Sha violated national regulations and deliberately harvested Tilia, a nationally protected plant. The circumstances were serious and constituted a crime of endangering nationally protected plants. Wang Min and Sha should be punished for several crimes together with the crime of deforestation and the crime of endangering national key protected plants. The criminal acts of Wang Moumin and six others seriously damaged the ecological environment, endangered the protection of biological diversity, caused serious damage to social and public interests, and should bear civil tort liability. Therefore, Wang Min and six others were sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment ranging from two to seven years, and fines ranging from 10,000 yuan to 1.2 million yuan; Wang Min was responsible for the comprehensive cost of restoring the ecological environment of more than 1.56 million yuan, and Sha was , Zhang Moukui and Yang are jointly and severally liable for this, Liu Moujun and Xu Mouren are jointly and severally liable for 140,000 yuan, and the appraisal fee of 5,000 yuan is jointly borne by the six defendants. After the verdict was announced, the parties did not appeal or protest, and the first-instance judgment has become legally effective. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical significance]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This case occurred within the scope of the Northeast Tiger and Leopard National Park and endangered national key areas. The case for plant protection. The high-quality forest resources and complete biological chain in the Siberian Tiger and Leopard National Park provide a good ecological home for Siberian tigers, leopards and other rare wild animals. With the increased protection of national parks, in recent years, Siberian tigers and leopards, which had not been seen for decades, have returned to their hometowns to thrive. Tilia purpurea is known as &quot;ivory board&quot; and &quot;the world&#39;s four major street trees&quot;. It has great medicinal, ornamental and economic value. It is a national endangered species and a national second-level protected wild plant. In this case, the People&#39;s Court punished the indiscriminate logging of trees and the intentional logging of national key protected plants in accordance with the law, and increased the punishment and deterrence of crimes that destroyed forest resources; it also ordered the perpetrators to compensate for the ecological environment restoration costs, and to Protecting the biodiversity and ecosystem security of Amur tiger and leopard habitats has a positive effect. After the verdict of this case, the People&#39;s Court implemented the concept of active justice, based on the actual management and protection of ecological resources of the Northeast Tiger and Leopard National Park, issued judicial suggestions to relevant departments, and promoted the formation of a strong synergy for national park protection. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;6. Li Mouliang, Yang Mouli’s fire, and Yang Mouli’s illegal hunting criminal incidental civil public interest litigation case&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Basic facts of the case]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The defendant Li Mouliang and Yang Mouli made an appointment to smoke bees and collect wild honey in the forest, and recorded the process on video For sale in honey. On April 1, 2021, Li Mouliang and Yang Mouli met at the Hainan Tropical Rainforest National Park Management Station, and walked up the mountain with lighters, iron buckets, cameras and other tools to look for honey. Later, Li Mouliang accidentally ignited the thatch around the beehive while lighting a torch to smoke the bees. While Li Mouliang put out the fire, he called Yang Mouli to help put out the fire. Yang Mouli discovered that the fire was burning toward his location and fled the scene. Li Mouliang also fled the scene when he saw this. After identification, the area burned by the forest fire was 90 acres (all forested land), which is a first-level protected forest land (key public welfare forest). The tree species burned by the fire were pine and natural broad-leaved trees. After Yang Mouli and Li Mouliang were arrested and brought to justice, Yang Mouli truthfully confessed his criminal behavior of illegal hunting that the public security organs had not yet grasped. The Second Branch of the Hainan Provincial People&#39;s Procuratorate prosecuted Li Mouliang and Yang Mouli for the crime of fire, and Yang Mouli for the crime of illegal hunting; and filed an incidental civil public interest lawsuit against the two, claiming: Yang Mouli and Li Mouli Liang will jointly carry out off-site restoration of 90 acres of damaged woodland in accordance with the ecological environment restoration plan, or jointly bear the restoration cost of 267,000 yuan (performed through payment of fees or labor compensation, etc.), and jointly and severally compensate for the damage to the ecological environment of the destroyed woodland to The loss caused by the loss of service functions during the completion of the restoration was 698,736 yuan, and the cost of identification and repair plan preparation in this case was 30,000 yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Second Intermediate People’s Court of Hainan Province held that Li Mouliang and Yang Mouliang Violating forest protection and forest fire prevention regulations, smoking bees to collect honey caused forest fires, causing heavy losses to public and private property, constituting the crime of fire. Yang Mouli violated hunting regulations, used prohibited tools and methods for hunting in the hunting reserve, and destroyed wild animal resources. The circumstances were serious and constituted the crime of illegal hunting. Li Mouliang and Yang Mouli burned a large number of trees due to fire behavior, causing serious damage to local forestry resources and ecological environment, and should bear corresponding civil liability. Therefore, Yang was sentenced to concurrent punishment for the crime of rationalization, and it was decided to execute a fixed-term imprisonment of one year and six months, and Li Mouliang was sentenced to one year and two months; the court ordered Li Mouliang and Yang Mouli to jointly bear the cost of off-site restoration of 267,000 yuan (by paying fees or labor compensation, etc.), ecological service function loss identification and restoration plan preparation costs 30,000 yuan, and joint compensation of 698,736 yuan for losses caused by loss of service functions between the damage to the ecological environment of the destroyed woodland and the completion of restoration. After the verdict was announced, the parties did not appeal or protest, and the first-instance judgment has become legally effective. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical significance]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This case is a criminal incidental civil public interest litigation that occurred within the Hainan Tropical Rainforest National Park case. The area of ​​Hainan Tropical Rainforest National Park accounts for less than 0.046% of the country&#39;s land area, but it has about 20% of the country&#39;s amphibians, 33% of reptiles, 38.6% of birds and 20% of mammal wildlife resources, including national There are 145 species of wild animals under key protection, and 23 species are endemic to Hainan Province, which have extremely important biodiversity value. Protecting the good ecological environment of Hainan Tropical Rainforest National Park is an important mission of the People’s Court’s environmental resources trial work. In this case, the People&#39;s Court, while seriously cracking down on fires and illegal hunting crimes that have a serious impact on the ecological balance of tropical rainforests, ordered the infringer to bear ecological compensation liability in accordance with the law, practicing the strictest rule of law principles in the field of ecological and environmental protection. In addition, taking into account the defendant&#39;s financial difficulties, allowing him to perform off-site ecological restoration obligations through labor compensation not only reflects the judicial concern for people&#39;s livelihood protection, but also contributes to the actual implementation of the judgment and helps the defendant change his inherent &quot;backer dependence&quot;. The idea of ​​&quot;mountains, rely on the sea and eat from the sea&quot; is conducive to motivating surrounding relatives and friends to change their production and lifestyle and achieve harmonious coexistence between man and nature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;7. The First Branch of Hainan Provincial People’s Procuratorate v. Li Mouqing and Ye Mouqing for Ecological Damage Civil Public Interest Litigation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Basic facts of the case]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Since January 2020, the defendants Li Mouqing and Ye Mouqing have successively hired people to cut down trees in the area without administrative permission. The mazhan trees on both sides of a dirt road at the Yinggeao Branch of the Limu Mountain Forest Farm in Hainan Province within the scope of the Hainan Tropical Rainforest National Park were damaged during the felling process. The latter two took away the felled Mazhan tree and sold it for 18,450 yuan. After identification, the felled forest plot is a second-level protected forest land, the forest category is a provincial-level public welfare forest, and the forest species is a shelter forest; the standing stock of the felled forest trees is 171 cubic meters; the two destroyed philodendron trees are national second-level protected plants The total value of ecological service function loss caused by felled trees is 74,902.95 yuan/year, and the estimated investment in afforestation and restoration involved in the case is 49,501.8 yuan. The above-mentioned appraisal and evaluation fee is 30,000 yuan. Li Mouqing was sentenced to four years and six months in prison for another crime of illegal logging. The First Branch of the Hainan Provincial People&#39;s Procuratorate filed a civil public interest lawsuit for ecological damage against Li Mouqing and Ye Mouqing&#39;s illegal logging, and requested that Li Mouqing and Ye Mouqing jointly bear the cost of the loss of ecological service functions caused by illegal logging. 149,805.9 yuan, ecological environment damage repair cost 49,501.8 yuan, appraisal and evaluation fee 30,000 yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Hainan Province No. 1 Intermediate People’s Court held that Li Mouqing and Ye Mouqing The infringement caused damage to the ecological environment of the forest farm, and should bear corresponding civil liability for the ecological environmental damage caused. The judgment was then made: Li Mouqing and Ye Mouqing jointly and severally compensated 149,805.9 yuan for the loss of ecological service functions caused by illegal logging of forest trees, 49,501.8 yuan for ecological environment damage repair costs, and jointly and severally bear 30,000 yuan for the ecological environment damage appraisal and evaluation fee in this case. After the verdict was announced, neither party appealed, and the first-instance judgment has become legally effective. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical significance]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Limu Mountain forest area involved in the case is located in the middle of Hainan Island and is an important part of the Hainan Tropical Rainforest National Park. component. The defendant in this case felled and destroyed a large number of trees in key protected areas within the scope of the national park, causing the integrity of the natural forest ecosystem, biodiversity, soil and water conservation and other ecological functions and values ​​to be reduced, destroying the ecological environment of the tropical rainforest, and harming the public Benefit. The people&#39;s court ordered the infringer to compensate for the loss of ecological resources, which increased the illegal costs of the perpetrator, effectively deterred the occurrence of potential illegal acts, and was conducive to creating a social atmosphere in which all people protect tropical rainforest resources and maintain a beautiful ecological environment, and also provided public information to the public. It conveys the People&#39;s Court&#39;s attitude towards cracking down on behaviors that damage the ecological environment and safeguarding the construction of national parks with high quality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;8. Civil public interest litigation case of Kaihua County People’s Procuratorate of Zhejiang Province against Lu Mouyan and four others for ecological damage&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Basic facts of the case]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The defendants Lu Mouyan and Xu were husband and wife, and they ran a game shop at a farmer&#39;s market in Kaihua County, Zhejiang Province. In November 2018, after receiving a report from a public welfare volunteer, the Kaihua County Forestry Police Bureau seized and detained 3 suspected white pheasants, 11 wild boars, 42 hares, and 23 yellow muntjacs in their warehouse. After investigation, at the end of December 2017, the defendant Wang contacted Xu via WeChat through the defendant Cheng Moujun to purchase an owl, and completed the delivery by recording a slaughtering video for inspection and mailing delivery, and then Wang gave it to a friend for consumption. . After identification, the three suspected white pheasants involved in the case were white pheasants, a national second-level protected animal; the owl was an eagle owl, a national second-level protected animal. After evaluation, Lu Mouyan’s illegal purchase and sale of precious and endangered wild animals and illegal purchase of other wild animals caused damage worth 107,860 yuan to ecological and environmental resources. The act of purchasing other wild animals caused damage worth 97,860 yuan; the illegal purchase of precious and endangered wild animals by Cheng Moujun and Wang caused damage to ecological environment resources worth 15,000 yuan. Four persons, Lu Mouyan, Xu Mou, Wang Mou and Cheng Moujun, were held criminally responsible in another case. The People&#39;s Procuratorate of Kaihua County, Zhejiang Province filed a civil public interest litigation with Xu and four other defendants as defendants, claiming that Lu Mouyan should pay 107,860 yuan in compensation for damage to the ecological environment and resources, of which Xu Mou was jointly and severally liable for 97,860 yuan, and Cheng Moujun, Wang each bears joint liability for 15,000 yuan of the compensation; the four defendants apologized in the media. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After hearing, the Intermediate People’s Court of Quzhou City, Zhejiang Province held that Lu Mouyan and Xu Mou jointly In the process of operating a game shop, they illegally purchased and sold nationally protected wild animals and non-nationally protected wild animals without proof of legal origin. Wang and Cheng Moujun illegally purchased nationally protected wild animals for food purposes. The behavior of the four defendants was harmful to the ecology. Those who cause damage to the environment and resources should bear tort liability. Among them, Lu Mouyan is responsible for all the facts involved in the case and should pay 107,860 yuan in compensation for damage to the ecological environment and resources; Xu Mou is jointly and severally liable with Lu Mouyan for 97,860 yuan of it; Wang Mou and Cheng Moujun are responsible for 15,000 yuan of it. Yuan, Lu Mouyan and Xu bear joint liability for compensation. The judgment therefore supported all the claims of the public interest litigation plaintiff. The judgment has taken legal effect. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical significance]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This case occurred in the Qianjiangyuan-Qianjiangyuan Park of Baishanzu National Park. Civil public interest litigation cases involving ecological damage caused by the illegal acquisition and sale of nationally protected wild animals. Qianjiangyuan-Baishanzu National Park was included in the national park system pilot in 2016 and is one of the 49 candidate national parks selected by the &quot;National Park Spatial Layout Plan&quot;. Qianjiangyuan - Baishanzu National Park Qianjiangyuan Park completely preserves the world&#39;s rare and large-scale mid-subtropical low-altitude primary evergreen broad-leaved forest. It is known as &quot;the last ecological virgin land in the Yangtze River Delta&quot; and is also the site of many The last &quot;genetic protection area&quot; for rare and endangered wild animals. Among the wild animals violated in this case, the white pheasant and the eagle owl are rare birds and are national second-level protected animals. As the pattern of the five-rank official uniforms in the Ming and Qing Dynasties, the white pheasant is a symbol of honesty and integrity, and has excellent ornamental value and cultural connotation. The four defendants illegally purchased and sold wild animals, and attempted to evade supervision and accountability by recording slaughter videos for inspection, online payment, and mail delivery. This was an excessive seizure of nature for their own personal gain. The People&#39;s Court ordered the four defendants to pay compensation for damage to the ecological environment and resources and apologize in accordance with the law, and to recover ecological losses in addition to criminal liability. It demonstrated the determination to protect the ecological environment of the national park with the strictest system and the most stringent rule of law, and served as a warning to the national park area. Internal personnel carry out business activities in accordance with laws and regulations, promote the harmonious integration of modern civilization and primitive ecology, and jointly build a national park that shares the harmonious coexistence of man and nature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;9. Zhang Mouyan and Zhang Mouyi v. Yang County Forestry Bureau Right to Life Dispute Case&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;[Basic Case Facts]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On March 18, 2017, mountain patrol personnel discovered that Zheng, a villager from Group 12, Chaoyang Village, Maoping Town, Yangxian County, Hanzhong City, Shaanxi Province He died on the roadside of Xiaohegou in Chaoyang Village. After investigation and inspection by the Yangxian County Public Security Bureau and investigation by the Yangxian Forestry Bureau, it was confirmed that Zheng was injured and died by a takin, a national first-level protected animal. Houyang County Forestry Bureau and Finance Bureau jointly reported to the Hanzhong City Forestry Bureau and Finance Bureau, requesting that the Shaanxi Province Compensation Measures for Personal and Property Damage Caused by Keyly Protected Terrestrial Wild Animals (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Compensation Measures&quot;) and its implementation rules , a compensation fund of 187,820 yuan was provided for Zheng Mouhai’s death (the province’s per capita net income of farmers in 2016 was 9,396 yuan × 20 times), of which 150,336 yuan was shared by the provincial finance and 18,792 yuan was shared by the municipal and county finances. On December 12, 2018, the Hanzhong Municipal Finance Bureau allocated 150,336 yuan in provincial fiscal funds for the death of Zheng Mouhai, who was injured by a takin. Because Zheng&#39;s relatives did not reach an agreement on the distribution of the compensation, the compensation was not paid. Zheng Mouhai&#39;s parents are deceased. Zheng Mouhai and his ex-wife had two daughters, Zhang Mouyan and Zhang Mouyi, during his lifetime. Zhang Mouyan and Zhang Mouyi then filed a lawsuit on the grounds of dispute over the right to life, requesting the Yangxian County Forestry Bureau to compensate for the loss of 216,933 yuan. During the trial, both parties had no objection to the compensation amount of 187,820 yuan. The Yangxian County Forestry Bureau also recognized that the two plaintiffs were the first legal heirs of the deceased Zheng Mouhai. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The People&#39;s Court of Yangxian County, Hanzhong City, Shaanxi Province held that the second judgment of the &quot;Compensation Measures&quot; , Articles 8 and 9 stipulate that, as confirmed by the forestry administrative department of the people&#39;s government at or above the county level, if personal injury or property loss caused by nationally and provincially protected terrestrial wild animals in the administrative region of this province meets the prescribed circumstances, the victim shall have the right to comply with these Measures. The right to obtain government compensation; if death is caused, a one-time damage compensation (including funeral subsidies) will be given, with the standard being 20 times the per capita net income of farmers in the province in the previous year; 80% of the compensation for personal and property damage shall be borne by the provincial finance, set District, city, and county-level finances each bear 10%. Accordingly, as the daughter of Zheng Mouhai, the second plaintiff has the right to apply for compensation from the government in accordance with the law. As the forestry administrative unit of the Yangxian County People&#39;s Government, the Yangxian Forestry Bureau should perform its legal obligations in accordance with the &quot;Compensation Measures&quot;. It was then ruled that the Yangxian Forestry Bureau should pay Zhang Mouyan and Zhang Mouyi a compensation of 150,336 yuan that had been allocated by the provincial finance; the compensation of 18,792 yuan shared by the municipal and county finances should be paid by the Yangxian Forestry Bureau to the financial department. Pay after declaration; reject the plaintiff’s other claims. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical significance]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This case was caused by a nationally protected wild animal that occurred in the Giant Panda National Park area. Disputes arising from death. The takin is a national first-level protected animal and is known as the &quot;Four Treasures of the Qinling Mountains&quot; along with the giant panda, crested ibis, and golden monkey. They are all rare species living in the Giant Panda National Park. With the deepening of the construction of ecological civilization in my country, the habitats and living spaces of wild animals continue to expand, and incidents of wild animals hurting people occur from time to time. Article 19 of the &quot;Wild Animal Protection Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; stipulates that if the protection of wild animals protected by this law causes casualties, crops or other property losses, the local people&#39;s government shall provide compensation. The specific measures shall be determined by the provincial people&#39;s government. formulated. In this case, the People&#39;s Court referred to the province&#39;s compensation regulations and ruled that the defendant should pay corresponding compensation, which better balances the dual goals of wildlife protection and safeguarding the safety of people&#39;s lives and property, and has positive significance for building a good ecological environment where man and nature coexist harmoniously. . At the same time, the People&#39;s Court promptly issued judicial suggestions to the forestry authorities, urging them to effectively improve the prevention awareness of surrounding people and ensure the personal and property safety of surrounding people by setting up warning signs in wildlife reserves and strengthening patrols during animal active periods. The concrete embodiment of the concept of active justice in environmental resources trial work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;10. Bankruptcy and Reorganization Case of a Hydropower Development Company in Qinghai&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Basic Case Facts] &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Yellow River Mar Dam Hydropower Station constructed by a hydropower development company in Qinghai is one of the first projects included in the national infrastructure field to encourage social investment, and is an important node in realizing the west-to-east power transmission project. The project started the preliminary construction in October 2010, and completed the construction of diversion tunnels, upstream and downstream cofferdams, etc. Later, due to a break in the capital chain of a hydropower development company in Qinghai, the construction funds could not be received in full on time, resulting in Mal The water-blocking power station was shut down, national key projects were difficult to implement, resettlement was at a standstill, and flood control hazards became increasingly serious. After the out-of-court reorganization failed to attract investors, it applied for bankruptcy reorganization in the People&#39;s Court. In June 2020, the Intermediate People&#39;s Court of Xining City, Qinghai Province accepted the bankruptcy and reorganization case of a hydropower development company in Qinghai in accordance with the law. In November of the same year, an energy investment group company, as a strategic investor in the bankruptcy and reorganization of a hydropower development company in Qinghai, signed a bankruptcy reorganization agreement with the bankruptcy administrator. In April 2021, the Xining Intermediate People&#39;s Court organized the second creditors meeting and approved the draft reorganization plan and other documents. According to the reorganization plan, reorganization investors will continue to statically invest hundreds of billions of yuan to build a &quot;water, light and wind integration&quot; comprehensive energy base in Malda, driving the development of new energy sources such as pumped storage, photovoltaic, wind power and chemical energy storage. develop and use. The manager of a hydropower development company in Qinghai applied for court approval of a reorganization plan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Judgment Result]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After review, the Xining Intermediate People’s Court held that a hydropower development company in Qinghai cannot pay off its due debts Debt, and there is a clear possibility of losing its ability to repay. The bankruptcy reorganization of a hydropower development company in Qinghai will be more conducive to protecting the overall interests of creditors, debtors and company employees, and will also help solve the floods in the upper reaches of the Yellow River caused by the suspension of the project. Safety and ecological environment restoration and management problems. The preparation, voting procedures and content of the reorganization plan in this case are in compliance with legal requirements and are feasible. The ruling was then made to approve the reorganization plan of a hydropower development company in Qinghai and terminate the reorganization process. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;[Typical significance]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The hydropower station in this case is located at the junction of Tongde County, Hainan Prefecture, Qinghai Province and Maqin County, Guoluo Prefecture The main stream of the Yellow River is located within the scope of the Sanjiangyuan National Park. It is a key hydropower project planned and constructed in the national &quot;Twelfth Five-Year Plan&quot;. The suspension of the project involved in the case not only has a negative impact on economic development and resettlement, but also has a great impact on the safety of the upper reaches of the Yellow River during floods, ecological restoration, and environmental governance. After the People&#39;s Court accepted the case and carried out bankruptcy reorganization, it gave full play to its judicial functions, properly handled the relationship between protection and development, strengthened coordination with relevant government departments, promoted the full resumption of work of the hydropower station involved in the case, effectively resolved the corporate bankruptcy dispute, and also made Sanjiangyuan Flood control work in the upper reaches of the Yellow River in the national park has been strengthened, and the ecological environment management difficulties that may have been caused by the project suspension have also been solved. At the same time, the construction of the &quot;water, light and wind integration&quot; comprehensive energy base in Malda will also lead to the optimization of the energy structure in the area around Sanjiangyuan National Park, which will help promote the green and high-quality development of the local economy and society to a new level. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[科技部迎来重组后首位新任党组书记：直面基础研究和“卡脖子”问题两大挑战]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258919]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/LcL9VLJobzfTjb94ZRv9w50xgtafvr2FhYc2l0Kh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;631&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/LcL9VLJobzfTjb94ZRv9w50 xgtafvr2FhYc2l0Kh. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254642&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the afternoon of October 7, 2023, the Ministry of Science and Technology held a meeting of leading cadres and announced that Yin Hejun Served as Party Secretary. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 10, 2023, Yin Hejun, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Science and Technology, met with the visiting President of the Royal Academy of Engineering , Sir Jim Macdonald, Vice-Chancellor of the University of Strathclyde and his party. According to reports on the official website of the Ministry of Science and Technology, this is Yin Hejun’s first public event after taking office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 7, 2023, the Ministry of Science and Technology held a meeting of leading cadres and announced Yin Hejun as party secretary. Yin Hejun’s predecessor Wang Zhigang was born in 1957 and served as Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Ministry of Science and Technology for 11 years. In the State Council’s institutional reform plan released in March 2023, the Ministry of Science and Technology ushered in the second reorganization in five years. Yin Hejun became the first new party secretary after the reorganization of the Ministry of Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a scholar-type official, Yin Hejun has served in universities and scientific research institutions for many years. Many interviewed experts believe that compared with the institutional reform in 2018, after this reorganization, the Ministry of Science and Technology will focus on solving basic research and &quot;stuck&quot; problems. This is also a challenge that Yin Hejun has to face head-on. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Multiple times filled gaps in the fields of science and technology and military equipment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a member of the 20th Central Committee, Yin Hejun was born in Gujiao, Shanxi Province in 1963 January. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, Yin Hejun worked in Taiyuan Institute of Technology and Taiyuan University of Technology after graduating from Taiyuan Institute of Technology (now Taiyuan University of Technology). In September 1986, he went to Xi&#39;an University of Electronic Science and Technology to study for a master&#39;s degree, and in 1992 he went to the Institute of Electronics, Chinese Academy of Sciences to study for a doctoral degree. After graduation in 1995, Dr. Yin Hejun chose to stay at the Institute of Electronics, Chinese Academy of Sciences until November 2015. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his 20 years of working at the Chinese Academy of Sciences, Yin Hejun served as director of the Bureau of High Technology Research and Development of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and was promoted to vice president in January 2008. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2015, Yin Hejun was transferred to the position of Vice Minister of Science and Technology, responsible for high-tech and international cooperation. Sixteen months later, in March 2017, 54-year-old Yin Hejun was appointed as a member of the Standing Committee of the Beijing Municipal Party Committee, and a month later he was concurrently appointed as the deputy mayor of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, when introducing Yin Hejun to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, leaders of the Beijing Municipal Government mentioned that he was &quot;familiar with scientific research and technology management work, and has a relatively broad mind...mainly engaged in major national science and technology projects and strategic science and technology pilot projects&quot; , national defense science and technology innovation and other aspects of work... have repeatedly filled the gaps in my country&#39;s science and technology and military equipment fields.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After taking office at the local level, Yin Hejun’s work was still related to science and technology, and he was in charge of the Municipal Science and Technology Commission, Economic and Information Technology Commission, State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, Quality Supervision Bureau, Intellectual Property Office, Zhongguancun Management Committee, Economic and Technological Development District Management Committee, contact the Municipal Association for Science and Technology and the Municipal Communications Administration Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2016, before going to work in Beijing, Yin Hejun mentioned in a speech that it is necessary to &quot;center on expanding the space for innovation and development, coordinate both domestic and international situations, and support Beijing and Shanghai in building global influence. Science and Technology Innovation Center”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After taking office as the leader of Beijing Municipality, Yin Hejun emphasized the need to make full use of the capital&#39;s scientific and technological innovation resources and coordinate the participation of universities, research institutes, enterprises and other forces in Beijing in the construction of a scientific and technological innovation center when he visited the Municipal Science and Technology Commission. , to promote the formation of greater synergy for collaborative innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Six years later, on May 26, 2023, the &quot;Beijing International Science and Technology Innovation Center Construction Situation Assessment Report&quot; was released. The assessment believes that Beijing has improved its original innovation and science and technology source supply capabilities, made exemplary explorations in establishing a new national system, and &quot;preliminarily built a scientific and technological innovation center with global influence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than a year in Beijing, in October 2018, Yin Hejun was transferred across provinces to serve as deputy secretary of the Tianjin Municipal Party Committee. When working in Tianjin, Yin Hejun mentioned &quot;technological innovation&quot; many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2020, Yin Hejun returned to the Chinese Academy of Sciences and served as deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group and vice president of the Chinese Academy of Sciences. The director of a state key laboratory of the Chinese Academy of Sciences told Southern Weekend reporters that Yin Hejun attaches great importance to major national science and technology and military industry work and is in charge of the major task bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;The reorganization at the central level has basically been implemented&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Five days after Yin Hejun assumed the new Ministry of Science and Technology, on October 12, 2023, China Organization and Establishment Network Five notices were issued in succession, informing the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, the National Health Commission, the People&#39;s Bank of China, and the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences of the responsibilities, institutions, and staffing adjustments. Among the five notices, three were related to the Ministry of Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice shows that the responsibilities of the Ministry of Science and Technology for organizing the development of high-tech development and industrialization plans and policies will be assigned to the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology; the responsibilities of the Ministry of Science and Technology for organizing and formulating plans and policies for promoting the development of ecological environment through science and technology will be assigned to the Ecological Environment Ministry of Science and Technology; the Ministry of Science and Technology’s responsibility for organizing and formulating plans and policies for science and technology to promote health and health development will be assigned to the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the responsibilities divided into other departments, there are also corresponding staffing levels. Wang Futao, a professor at the School of Public Administration at South China University of Technology, has long been concerned about science and technology policy. In his view, the adjustment of the establishment also means that the Ministry of Science and Technology&#39;s &quot;reorganization at the central level has basically been implemented.&quot; &quot;This is completely consistent with the reform plan at the beginning of the year.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 10, 2023, the &quot;State Council Institutional Reform Plan&quot; was released, emphasizing the need to strengthen the optimization and adjustment of institutional responsibilities in six key areas including science and technology. The plan mentions thirteen specific subdivided tasks, among which &quot;reestablishing the Ministry of Science and Technology&quot; is the first of the thirteen tasks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 16, 2023, the &quot;Plan for the Reform of Party and State Institutions&quot; was announced, stating that the Central Science and Technology Commission will be established. The plan emphasized that the responsibilities of the Central Science and Technology Commission&#39;s office will be assumed by the reorganized Ministry of Science and Technology as a whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also in this reform plan, a time limit is given for the reorganization of the Ministry of Science and Technology: &quot;Reform tasks at the central level strive to be completed by the end of 2023, and reform tasks at the local level strive to be completed by 2024. To be completed before the end of the year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In summary, at the central level, the reform of the Ministry of Science and Technology involves the overlapping of functions between the Ministry of Science and Technology and other departments and the transformation of scientific and technological achievements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Sun Yutao, a professor at the School of Economics and Management of Dalian University of Technology, scientific and technological work covers many aspects such as economy, society, ecology, culture, etc., and the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Ministry of Ecology and Environment, the Health Commission and other departments also have their own Science and Technology Division, both of which include the application of science and technology in specific fields. Through the reform, this part of the Ministry of Science and Technology&#39;s functions has been returned to specific functional departments, and coupled with the establishment of the Central Science and Technology Commission, &quot;the overall overall planning and coordination has been strengthened.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of another scholar who has been paying attention to science and technology policy for a long time, the adjusted functions of the Ministry of Science and Technology have two typical characteristics: “First, these problems can basically rely on market mechanisms to solve the problems, or use It is more efficient to solve it through market mechanisms; secondly, these problems do not affect strategic issues.&quot; He added: &quot;For example, digitalization, of course, is better if it is faster, but if it is slower for a year and a half, it does not involve &#39;fatal matters&#39;. That is the &#39;stuck neck&#39; problem.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Major special projects such as &quot;stuck neck&quot; are still in&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;hands&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Put the timeline To stretch it a little further, in the past ten years, there have been three reforms and reorganizations involving the Ministry of Science and Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yutao has long been concerned about China’s scientific research funding policies. He explained that in 2014, the reform of the science and technology system was mainly related to scientific research funding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Xiaoxuan, a researcher at the Institute of Science and Technology Policy and Management Sciences of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, once wrote an article in Guangming Daily and pointed out that the &quot;Several Opinions on Improving and Strengthening the Management of Central Financial Scientific Research Projects and Funds&quot; directly addresses the oversides and deficiencies in fund management. The problem of coexistence of two places is the major reform measure in 2014. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The core content of this document is reflected in two aspects. First, in view of the duplication, dispersion, inefficiency, weak supervision and other problems existing in the original fund management, an overall reform idea aimed at promoting standardized management is proposed. The second is to follow the rules of scientific research activities, emphasize the preparation of budgets based on actual costs at the operational level, and cancel the requirement that personnel fees be simply set in proportion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Plan on Deepening the Management Reform of Central Fiscal Science and Technology Plans (Special Projects, Funds, etc.)&quot; indicates that China&#39;s science and technology planning system is about to undergo a &quot;major surgery.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearly a hundred competitive science and technology plans originally scattered in about 40 departments have been optimized and integrated into the National Natural Science Foundation, National Major Science and Technology Projects, National Key R&amp;D Plans, Technology Innovation Guidance Special Projects (Funds) and Bases and Talents 5 categories including special projects. Government management is limited to the macro level, and project review and management at the micro level are left to professional institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The original national science and technology plan was divided into many scientific research projects. At that time, many people said that these projects were too scattered. All ministries and commissions had money to support the development of science and technology, and &#39;Kowloon water control&#39;.&quot; Sun Yutao explained, &quot; After the reform, these projects were concentrated in the Ministry of Science and Technology, so some people called this reform a &#39;reform to expand power.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the reform of scientific research funding, in March 2018, the First Session of the 13th National People&#39;s Congress The first reorganization plan of the Ministry of Science and Technology was disclosed, and it was proposed to integrate the responsibilities of the Ministry of Science and Technology and the State Administration of Foreign Experts Affairs and reorganize the Ministry of Science and Technology as a component department of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of the aforementioned unnamed experts, compared with the reform promoted by the Central Organization Office, the reform in 2018 is more led by the Ministry of Science and Technology itself. In the opinion of this expert, the reform at that time can be seen as an attempt at this reform: “In the international environment at that time, we still advocated taking the line of open cooperation, but made some adjustments in the way of resource investment. But the effect was not ideal. So this time the reform was upgraded and involved in-depth adjustments to the organizational structure.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sun Yutao&#39;s view, the main purpose of the reform is to cope with the current challenges: &quot;Why Are we going to adjust like this now? This shows that the current problems we are encountering need to be solved through reform. In ten years, this problem will no longer exist. It is hard to say whether these functions will be transferred back to the Ministry of Science and Technology.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;What the Ministry of Science and Technology will focus on solving after this reform is basic research and &quot;stuck&quot; problems. The aforementioned expert explained: &quot;The &#39;stuck neck&#39; problem includes major special projects. This part of the work is still in the hands of the Ministry of Science and Technology after the reform, and it has been upgraded to be handled by the central government.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yutao also said that from now on From the perspective of scientific research, the importance of basic research is very high: &quot;From basic research, to applied research, to experimental development, the further you go, the more money you have to invest; but the further you go, the more important it is. Without basic research , how can we do the following things?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to basic research, major national science and technology projects come from the &quot;National Medium and Long-term Science and Technology Development Plan (2006-2020)&quot;, including large aircraft , manned spaceflight and lunar exploration projects and other 16 projects. It is worth noting that Yin Hejun has previously participated in major special projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that on September 25, 2008, the Shenzhou 7 manned spacecraft was successfully launched, and Yin Hejun was the deputy commander-in-chief of the Shenzhou 7 mission headquarters; in December 2013, Chang&#39;e 3 The launch was successful. Yin Hejun once accepted media interviews as the deputy commander-in-chief of the lunar exploration project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海滩失踪女童遗体发现：“疏忽父亲入刑论”应慎议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258929]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 19, 2023, Shanghai police reported: On the morning of October 18, Ningbo police received a report from Zhenhai, Ningbo City The body of a girl was found on a tidal flat in the district. Her clothing and other characteristics were similar to those of the missing girl from Nanhui Xincheng Beach in Pudong. A working team was quickly dispatched to the local area. After forensic examination and comparison of the deceased&#39;s biometrics and identification by her family members, it was confirmed that it was the missing girl Huang Moumou. &quot;The body was fully clothed and had no violent injuries. It is consistent with the characteristics of death by drowning and is excluded from criminal cases.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This touching case of missing children on the beach has a clear conclusion. It is sad that a beautiful life died like this. For a family that has suffered the loss of a daughter, this is an unbearable burden and is likely to become a wound that will never heal. The father of the child who was negligent in the whole incident will probably live with guilt and self-condemnation for a long time, and this kind of mental torture will be lifelong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the child disappeared on the beach, there was a lot of criticism of the family and the father on the Internet. For example, they falsely accused the father of being a stepfather, spread rumors that the family favored sons over daughters, and deliberately caused the death of the girl. This kind of malice and lies in the name of &quot;justice&quot; has inflicted greater harm on this family and should be condemned. In addition, there are also voices on the Internet calling for the father of the child to be jailed for &quot;negligent death&quot;, so as to deter irresponsible parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to understand the latter point of view? Nowadays, from the time a child enters kindergarten, there are various safety educations on preventing drowning every year. However, the number of children who drown in China every year is not large in absolute terms. According to statistics from the Chronic Disease Center of the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention and the Global Child Safety Organization, from 2010 to 2015, an average of 54,194 adolescents and children died due to injuries every year (148 people/day), with drowning, road traffic injuries and falls/falls being the top three causes. Bit injury cause of death. The &quot;2022 China Youth Drowning Prevention Big Data Report&quot; released by People&#39;s Daily pointed out that casualties caused by drowning rank first in China in the 0-17 age group, accounting for as high as 33%. &quot;As of the first half of 2022, many news reports have Instead of increasing, drowning accidents among teenagers occur frequently.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these incidents of drowning deaths of minors, some parents were present at the scene but were distracted and negligent, leading to tragedy; some swimming pools did not allow parents to enter but were unable to ensure the safety of their children; and others Older children go to rivers or reservoirs to play or swim without telling their parents and companions, and accidents occur. If the crime of &quot;negligent causing death&quot; is used to punish the first category of parents, I am afraid that there will be many cases, and it will be difficult to produce a significant &quot;deterrence and prevention&quot; effect. On the contrary, there will be many side effects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although China has implemented the &quot;comprehensive three-child&quot; policy, the current total fertility rate is very low, and the number of newborns born each year is still declining. Under such circumstances, those who are still willing to have one or two children often really do so because they love their children. Because they have inherited their own genes, parents have a very strong love for their children and a very high willingness to give to their children. It can be said that in this world, the people who love their children the most and care most about their well-being are their parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, it would be inhumane and inhumane to punish parents who caused the death of their children due to their own negligence. Children are the continuation of their parents’ lives, and most parents have no subjective intention to harm themselves. children or put their own children in danger. Of course, a very small number of beast fathers and beast mothers should be punished for intentionally harming their children. Secondly, it cannot improve the &quot;duty&quot; of parents. Are parents who carefully raise their children and are willing to do everything for their children? Are you afraid of being punished by criminal law when you create the best of everything? If this is the case, then his most rational consideration must be not to have children, instead of taking care of the children in front of the criminal law every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people take Western countries as an example: parents who leave their children alone at home or elsewhere will be deprived of custody rights. But objectively analyze the two possible situations: the child grows up with the parents and allows the parents to be occasionally neglectful; or the parents occasionally leave the child alone at home and then give the child to another family or a child welfare agency to raise the child. Which one is better? Beneficial to children’s physical and mental health and well-being? Respecting family ties is obviously better for children. Moreover, this approach is a gross interference and trampling on the family, a natural community of blood, and creates many more and bigger problems than the ones it claims to solve. Parents should only be deprived of custody rights when they intentionally harm their children and are clearly detrimental to the child&#39;s physical and mental health and well-being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called guardianship is not an arbitrary power. It is actually full of responsibility and dedication, with love behind it. There will be no financial gain until the child reaches adulthood. Parents should provide their children with all economic resources, including food, clothing, housing and transportation, so that their children can grow up healthily. They should also protect their children&#39;s safety from various natural and man-made risks. Don’t you see, how many parents don’t give up the pursuit of their children because they were kidnapped by traffickers? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although tragedy has occurred, we should not require parents to become gods and saints. They should never make mistakes in their actions: parents must absolutely ensure the safety of their children, and any harm to their children must be held accountable. . This is harsh on human nature and is not consistent with reality. In short, respecting family ties, respecting the family, having empathy and understanding for parents, and maintaining the necessary modesty of power over the family are not only more conducive to the growth and well-being of children, but also defend the family as the foundation of civilization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子遭邻居砸门近一年：数十次报警为何换不来警方追责]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258902]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>