<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[威马破产重整，车主面临“售后难”：购置电车须评估六大风险]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259689]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the National Enterprise Bankruptcy and Reorganization Case Information Network, WM Motor Technology Group Co., Ltd. has applied for bankruptcy and reorganization WM Motor&#39;s official Weibo issued a notification letter in response, saying that the company still has salvage value and hopes to actively save itself by adjusting corporate strategies, solving financial debt problems, and getting investors to participate in restructuring and development. However, according to feedback from many WM owners, in early 2023, WM supporting software frequently experienced failures such as &quot;unable to connect, network abnormality&quot; and so on. In response to this, WM Motor publicly responded: &quot;Currently, WM Motor&#39;s engine system has returned to normal, and we sincerely apologize for the inconvenience caused to everyone!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the current situation, if we cannot wait for the &quot;White Horse Rider&quot; &quot;Once WM Motor goes bankrupt, more than 100,000 car owners will face a &quot;complete shutdown&quot; of their vehicle systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The main components of electric vehicles have changed from the engine and gearbox of previous fuel vehicles to three-electric systems. In the electric vehicle maintenance market, new energy vehicle-related product technologies and parts supply are all mastered In the hands of OEMs and EMC manufacturers, independent repairers rarely participate. This means that when electric vehicle companies such as WM Motor are eliminated due to factors such as fierce market competition, the after-sales service chain will be broken, and car owners will not be able to find corresponding substitutes in the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experience of a Weimar owner is a typical example. The power battery of the WM EX5 car he purchased malfunctioned. When it was charged to 80%, it would automatically jump to 100%. When the remaining 20% ​​of power was used, the car would stop moving. Because it was still within the manufacturer&#39;s warranty period, the car owner drove the car to the Kuangshan store of Jinan Weima User Center for repair. It still has not been repaired in nearly half a year because the manufacturer did not provide spare parts. The car owner contacted the 4S store again, and the 4S store said that it could no longer operate and asked him to tow the car away and solve the problem himself. The car owner also complained to the manufacturer many times, but it has not been resolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Weima owners are facing &quot;after-sales difficulties&quot;, which reveals that electric cars are not as beautiful as the owners imagined. Due to strong policy support, China&#39;s electric vehicle industry has developed rapidly. The latest statistics released by the Ministry of Public Security show that the number of electric vehicles in China currently exceeds 18 million. However, with the rapid development of electric vehicles, there are still six major risks. In addition to the difficulties encountered by Weimar owners mentioned above, they also involve aspects such as cruising range, charging, vehicle safety, data and privacy, and assisted driving. When buying a car, car owners must not Not aware. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some electric vehicle manufacturers deliberately exaggerate the cruising range of their vehicles in order to promote sales. According to a report by China Times in March this year, most new energy vehicle 4S stores marked the NEDC comprehensive working condition (driving cycle test) cruising range and did not mark the actual cruising range. Mr. Liu, an online ride-hailing driver, told a reporter from China Times that an electric car he mentioned in May 2022 had a range of 505 kilometers, but in actual driving, whether it was driving on the highway or in the city, , the cruising range can only reach about 300 kilometers, and in winter it only has more than 200 kilometers, and once it even &quot;slumped down&quot; on the highway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cruising range is not worthy of its name, and electric vehicles charge slowly, often taking six to eight hours to fully charge. This greatly affects the consumer experience. Especially when there is an urgent need for a car, long charging time will make consumers feel very inconvenient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, electric vehicle companies have provided two options. One is the DC fast charging mode, which takes 1 to 1.5 hours. However, frequent use of fast charging mode will affect battery life. Therefore, current electric vehicles still mainly rely on AC slow charging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, some car companies provide battery swapping models, but the costs for car owners are high. At the same time, the investment cost of battery swapping stations is high and the number of built ones is limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The safety of electric vehicles is another major pain point that consumers are concerned about. In recent years, there have been many accidents involving spontaneous combustion of electric vehicles, posing a serious threat to the life and property safety of car owners. Statistics from the emergency management department show that in the first quarter of 2023 alone, the spontaneous combustion rate of electric vehicles increased by 32%, with an average of 8 electric vehicles catching fire (including spontaneous combustion) every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the directions for the intelligentization of electric vehicles is digitization. Electric vehicles can not only collect the owner’s face data through the in-car camera, but may also collect information such as the owner’s place of residence, whereabouts, and consumption places. , once such data is leaked by car companies or stolen by hackers, it will cause more serious consequences. According to a notice issued by the Maine Attorney General&#39;s Office in August this year, Tesla&#39;s data breach in May affected more than 75,000 people, including records related to employees. The incident originated from &quot;internal Employee misconduct”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The application of assisted driving technology in electric vehicles will bring more problems. Some car companies refer to assisted driving technology as &quot;assisted autonomous driving&quot; or &quot;autonomous assisted driving&quot;. Sales staff will hype it up when promoting, beautifying it as &quot;autonomous driving&quot;. If there is an accident, it will become &quot;assisted driving&quot;. . The assisted driving technology used by many electric vehicles currently has a paradox in itself. It not only advocates liberating the driver, but also requires the driver to supervise and be ready to take over anytime and anywhere. If an accident occurs, how to divide the responsibilities between the driver and the car company? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of the six major risks associated with electric vehicles may be improved as technology advances, while others may remain unresolved for a long time. Therefore, when people buy electric vehicles, they must not be concerned about the risks promoted by car companies. &quot;Environmental protection&quot; (the degree of environmental pollution caused by batteries is not low) and &quot;intelligence&quot; are fully accepted, but it is still necessary to evaluate rationally and objectively before deciding whether to place an order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国务院印发《关于取消和调整一批罚款事项的决定》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259818]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In order to further optimize the business environment, the State Council recently issued the &quot;Decision on Cancellation and Adjustment of a Group of Fines&quot; ( (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Decision&quot;), 33 fines were canceled and adjusted in the fields of industry, information technology, housing and urban-rural construction, among which 16 fines were canceled and 17 fines were adjusted. If fine matters are canceled, the relevant fine provisions in relevant administrative regulations and departmental rules will be temporarily suspended from the date of issuance of the &quot;Decision&quot;; if fines are adjusted, the relevant fine provisions in the revised relevant administrative regulations and departmental rules will be implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 16 fines canceled by the &quot;Decision&quot; include 2 from the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, 2 from the Ministry of Education, 5 from the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, 3 from the People&#39;s Bank of China, and 1 from the National Forestry and Grassland Administration. , 1 State Post Bureau, 2 National Bureau of Disease Control and Prevention; 17 fines adjusted, including 1 Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, 1 Ministry of Emergency Management, 13 National Press and Publication Administration, and 2 National Bureau of Disease Control and Prevention. These fines are mainly concentrated in areas closely related to the production and life of enterprises and the people. The purpose of cancellation and adjustment is to effectively reduce the burden on enterprises and the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cancellation and adjustment of fines involve a total of 7 administrative regulations and 6 departmental regulations. The &quot;Decision&quot; puts forward clear requirements for the legislative work after the cancellation and adjustment of fines. Relevant departments of the State Council must submit relevant administrative regulations modification plans to the State Council within 60 days from the date of issuance of the &quot;Decision&quot; and complete the modification and abolition of relevant departmental regulations. If departmental regulations need to be adjusted according to the revised administrative regulations, the modification and abolition must be completed within 60 days from the date of promulgation of the relevant administrative regulations. Considering that there is a 30-day period for soliciting opinions on the modification and abolition of departmental regulations, it is stipulated that if the modification or abolition of departmental regulations cannot be completed within the above period due to special reasons, it may be appropriately extended, but the extension period shall not exceed 30 days at most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Decision&quot; emphasizes that after the fines are cancelled, the relevant departments must study carefully in accordance with the law, strictly implement regulatory responsibilities, focus on strengthening supervision during and after the event, improve supervision methods, standardize supervision procedures, and improve the scientific and scientific nature of supervision. Simplicity and precision further enhance regulatory efficiency and provide strong support for promoting high-quality development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“丑小鸭”的生长：一所学校防治青少年抑郁的探索与思考]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259838]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 17:58:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/epeeemYXf9dkI727T4PbzTs2ff4ZarA2VMg8Hxh4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1578&quot; height=&quot;1106&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/epeeemYXf9dkI727T4PbzTs2ff4Z arA2VMg8Hxh4. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256486&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 19, 2023, girls confided and comforted each other on the playground of Ugly Duckling Middle School &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Did you want to come here on your own, or were you &#39;tricked&#39; by your parents?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Half and half. When I came here, I realized, hey, it&#39;s not at all what I thought.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the bright sun, more than a dozen buses and minibuses were parked here. The mountainside of Ruixing Village in Yiliang, Kunming. Hundreds of people filed in, lingering in the classrooms, student dormitories, book bars, and running tracks of this rural school, observing carefully, even the bathrooms painted with paint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visitors include principals, moral education directors, classroom teachers from all over the country, officials and entrepreneurs from the local education sector, social organizations engaged in family education and private innovative education, as well as some who “can’t figure it out” in their own families. Parents worried about their children. They were curious about how a school called &quot;Ugly Duckling Middle School&quot; could help a group of children who seemed to be surly, tired of studying, or even suffering from deep depression to blossom into a natural and brilliant life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For these questions, the &quot;ugly duckling&quot; principal Zhan Danian always smiles and does not answer immediately. In the 13 years since he founded this school, various questions and controversies have continued, which he no longer thinks is strange. But he did not expect that the youth depression problem that he had deeply realized in running the school would actually trigger a strong response after launching the &quot;First Youth Psychological Safety Forum&quot; (jointly with the China Education Thirty Forum), and the reverberation continues to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2023 China Mental Health&quot; Blue Book released on October 10, 2023 shows that 40% of Chinese teenagers feel lonely, the depression detection rate among high school students is 40%, and the depression detection rate among junior high school students is 40%. is 50%, and the risk of mild anxiety among college students is 38%. Peng Kaiping, dean of the Academy of Social Sciences of Tsinghua University, once wrote an article pointing out that today&#39;s Chinese teenagers have &quot;four no&#39;s&quot;: no interest in learning, no interest in the real world, no ability to deal with the real society, and no interest in life. Therefore, the theme of this forum has been upgraded from the previously mentioned &quot;youth mental health&quot; to &quot;psychological safety&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/BcDl53HOeKhBlcjWZsACyCKlrhO9mJTFm3q4LvX9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;546&quot; height= &quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/BcDl53HOeKhBlcjWZsACyCKlrhO9mJTFm3q4LvX9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the psychology room of Ugly Duckling Middle School, teacher Li Guihong (middle) performs sand table psychotherapy for students. Some students also sit quietly and relax here&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Zhan Danian’s view, depression is just a symptom, and behind it are the flaws in the current educational ecology. &quot;The essence of education is to develop students&#39; personalities, rather than using a ruler to measure students. The best and most equitable education should be education that adapts to students&#39; personalities, so that every student&#39;s potential can be developed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We have actually heard this argument too many times. The key is how to put it into practice. Therefore, in the &quot;wild education&quot; of the &quot;ugly duckling&quot;, is there really any experience that can be discovered and learned from to prevent and treat depression in teenagers? What kind of social and family symptoms are behind every depressed child? Are they definitely unsolvable? Our reporters went to Kunming and Yiliang to explore the possibility of dispelling the shadow of education under the sun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/cnGVQpHqsTRAN5BW8PNj5Om1pOjzY81isic8ZjO9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;545&quot; height= &quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/cnGVQpHqsTRAN5BW8PNj5Om1pOjzY81isic8ZjO9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At 11:30 in the morning, the students of Ugly Duckling Middle School were having physical education class. Students in this school have about 3 hours of outdoor exercise time every day&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; It’s all my fault”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Pu Pu actually loves to laugh. But in the crowd, with her dark face, ponytail, and big black-rimmed glasses, she didn&#39;t often make a sound. On a 30℃ day, my body is still huddled in a collared sweater and a jacket. When you open your mouth, the sound coming out of the braces is very soft, like a porcelain bowl that is afraid of breaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I noticed her in class. In the Chinese class of teacher Juanjuan in the second grade of junior high school, Pu Pu raised her hand, which surprised me, who initially thought she would not want to speak. But two minutes later, she lowered her head and body, and closed her eyes, as if everything around her had nothing to do with her. This state of affairs occurs constantly in the classroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s a reaction after taking medicine.&quot; Psychology teacher Li Guihong told me. When he first arrived at &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot;, Pu Pu had to take more than 20 pills of medication to treat mental illness at a time, but now the medication has been reduced by more than half. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than two years ago, Pu Pu was in the first grade of junior high school in Kunming, a middle school known for its academic performance. Like other branches of this education group, almost nothing is allowed here that is not related to study. It is strictly forbidden to move or talk during meals and lunch breaks. If you are &quot;disobedient&quot;, the dormitory aunt will record your name, deduct points, and scold you. Pu Pu once had his name recorded because he took a few minutes longer to take a shower. He got a little excited while chatting with his classmates at noon, so he was also recorded. &quot;The punishment is a slap on the palm, but it doesn&#39;t hurt. There is also running, which requires many laps.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t you think this kind of management is a bit strict?&quot; I asked her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It doesn&#39;t count. I broke the rules in the first place, and it&#39;s all my fault.&quot; She answered quietly in the rest area next to the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot; playground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After reading for a while, Pu Pu began to suffer from insomnia and developed delusional symptoms. &quot;Sometimes I feel happy, and sometimes I feel uncomfortable. When I feel uncomfortable, I can&#39;t control myself and scream loudly.&quot; She asked her parents to see a psychiatrist. Later, she was diagnosed with &quot;depression and anxiety disorder&quot; and was admitted to the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pu Pu’s parents run a dental clinic and are very caring towards her. &quot;During the time I was hospitalized, my father was at work and my mother often stayed with me in the hospital.&quot; She had undergone MECT (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;non-convulsive electroshock&lt;/span>; ) and transcranial magnetism (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;physical device that stimulates brain nerves&lt;/span>;) treatments, except for dizziness and numbness, did not have much effect. Pu Pu dropped out of school. In the past two years, she gained weight due to medication and other reasons. Her heaviest weight was close to 70 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/TJoN8oef5Juq9tWKgF4rQvSNw2dkpGJCEAFagyfE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;449&quot; height= &quot;337&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/TJoN8oef5Juq9tWKgF4rQvSNw2dkpGJCEAFagyfE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256485&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Aerial view of the Ugly Duckling Middle School campus&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Bad moods still came up from time to time like a tide. When she couldn&#39;t stand it anymore, Pu Pu would hit her head against the wall, cry, and pinch her throat with her hands... More than once, she wanted to open the window and jump. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are other ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Rolling up her sleeves, Pu Pu’s arms, from palm to elbow, were densely covered with new flesh that was a minute or two thicker than the original skin after twenty or thirty cuts with a knife, like a row. Light-colored thorns winding up. There are several more in the middle, which are longer, deeper, and redder in color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Does it hurt when you paddle?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;No.&quot; She shook her head and smiled. &quot;Seeing blood relieves stress.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In those late nights when she couldn&#39;t get through it, patients she met while she was in the hospital sent her messages and asked her to try other methods, such as scratching paper, throwing stuffed toys, and picking at the wall. &quot;They also advised me not to think about (suicide) so much. Some (symptoms) are milder than yours, and some are more severe than yours. You will definitely get better slowly.&quot; After hearing these kind words of comfort, Pu Pu would stop. &quot;I actually don&#39;t believe what they said. But when I think about how hard it was for my parents to give birth to and raise me, I can&#39;t just give up.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You still think that suffering from mental illness is all a matter of Is it my own problem?&quot; I asked her again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Well... I didn&#39;t adjust my mentality well. I used to have low self-esteem. I didn&#39;t like my skin being so dark. It turned out that my classmates at school called me &#39;black girl&#39;. I was unhappy and also I keep it in my heart.&quot; She raised her head and opened her eyes: &quot;But I am optimistic now. I don&#39;t think there is any problem with being black. And my mother said that there are many medical beauty methods now. If I want, I can also have whitening when I grow up. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A year ago, Pu Pu was sent as an &quot;ugly duckling&quot;. &quot;She didn&#39;t like to laugh very much and couldn&#39;t integrate into the group.&quot; During the &quot;attack&quot;, she trembled all over and pulled her hair, causing two people to suffer. Only then can she be held back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both Zhan Danian and Li Guihong said that adults need to pay attention to children&#39;s paddling and &quot;self-injury&quot;, but do not need to be too frightened. &quot;Some are seeking stimulation, some are subconscious, and some are emotional releases. They may want you to see it. What you have to do is to give them enough understanding and protection.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For various physical symptoms and stress In response, Li Guihong recorded her experience in the industry for more than ten years in a notebook, as well as some practices she learned from Liu Zhiyou, a special psychological consultant for &quot;The Ugly Duckling&quot; and a Taiwanese brain science expert: when dealing with children with trembling hands and feet, first touch them gently. If they have violent behaviors such as hitting the wall, you can give them electrolyte water and touch other parts of the body. After the child calmed down a little, she also taught the student the &quot;Flat Throwing Kung Fu&quot;: half-squatting, slowly shaking both hands up and down. Sometimes she would also give the children some lemon slices, &quot;I said eating this will make them feel better quickly, and psychological suggestions can also work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/CpuvdptotWQHlYpaDKBAVn7smjmQGGQ6cJciqfkk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;441&quot; height=&quot;294&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/01/CpuvdptotWQHlYpaDKBAVn7smjmQGGQ6cJciqfkk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ugly Duckling Middle School Boys Dormitory&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During class time and after class in the afternoon, students will always enter the first floor in twos and threes. This psych room on the left. They hugged the big furry bears on the sofas and cushions; some would chat with &quot;Lao Li&quot; - this is their pet name for Li Guihong; some spent half an hour drawing mandoles in the cubicle. Luo (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A painting therapy invented by psychologist Jung&lt;/span>;). &quot;Old Li, why haven&#39;t my paintings been hung up?&quot; A child said, half coquettishly and half angrily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How about you draw a more interesting one? I will consider it later.&quot; Li Guihong secretly told me, asking whether this child is a student specializing in art. &quot;I have to give other children more opportunities.&quot; I suddenly remembered that when I visited the girls&#39; dormitory on the first day, there were several girls on the upper bunk with their legs curled up and their heads raised, painting, and one of them was Pu Pu. In the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;, all greening and interior and exterior decorations are completed by students according to their own wishes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one seems to regard this psychological room with warm colors as a therapeutic place. It has naturally become a transfer station, chat room and tea room for emotional flow. &quot;They are willing to come here for no particular purpose. They can relax and clear their minds. That&#39;s good.&quot; Li Guihong said. When encountering a child like Pu Pu who needs special treatment, if she is willing to chat, she and her colleague Yang Haoming will divide the work; if not, the first thing to do is still: give time and wait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Only when the child&#39;s emotions are relatively intense and several people have &#39;attacks&#39; at the same time, I feel a little powerless.&quot; She smiled, &quot;But there are other teachers who can take turns to deal with it, so don&#39;t be afraid.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/vMJ3G8t4amWuAREHAtZnY6sTReZXiQLvcCYK1bfb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;441&quot; height=&quot;297 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/vMJ3G8t4amWuAREHAtZnY6sTReZXiQLvcCYK1bfb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: # 999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Students are reading beside the bookshelf at the entrance of the classroom. Students can freely read and borrow books in the school’s public spaces &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The entire The world is sick, and so am I.&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In Li Guihong&#39;s view, although Pu Pu&#39;s &quot;physical symptoms&quot; are severe, she is a very innocent, open and friendly child. &quot;If it weren&#39;t for taking too many pills, she would be in good condition. She is recovering well now.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When some children first arrived, they were arrogant and said, &quot;Thinking that everything is other people&#39;s.&quot; It’s their fault. They often feel excluded and isolated from the entire world, and tend to avoid social interactions.” Some of these students may have already constructed or are forming their own worldview and set of behavioral logic. They are like big rocks on the cliff, shining brightly, but also easy to fall, and need the support of the big trees on the cliff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Lan is one of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearing that I wanted to chat with him in the military training class, Tian Lam’s eyes lit up as he shuffled slowly: “YES!” Later I learned that as long as there was no class, he would secretly happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Entering the large conference room on the first floor, only the two of us were left. Tian Lan sat down in an almost &quot;Ge You lying&quot; posture without any restraint. When faced with many questions, he would pause for five or six seconds before slowly spitting out his answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the topic involved emotions and &quot;depression&quot;, he seemed to be waking up from a dream, &quot;Then why are you looking for me -&quot; I thought the conversation was about to reach a deadlock, but he said again: &quot; This needs to be traced back all the way...even though I am only 14 years old, it has already run through my short life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Lan grew up in a provincial capital city in the south of the Yangtze River. A year or two before coming to the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;, he dropped out of school for six months and was stuck at home without ever leaving the house. Watching videos and reading novels. The longest time I stayed awake was more than fifty hours. He originally weighed 140 pounds, but lost dozens of pounds because he only had one meal in a day or two. &quot;It&#39;s not nutritious, even my nails are only cut once a month.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unbeknownst to him, he refused to hear any sound at that time, would explode whenever he heard a sound, and would not let his father live at home. &quot;I just drove him away. They say &#39;filial piety comes first&#39;, but I actually beat my parents. I couldn&#39;t help it. After the beating, my mother cried, and I cried with her.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A psychiatrist was also found. Yes, come to see a doctor. Tian Lan didn&#39;t accept any of it. &quot;The questions they asked were very boring, and I couldn&#39;t see anything credible from them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Day and night are reversed, lifeless. At that time, Tian Lan&#39;s only thought was &quot;stay at home until the age of 18 and then die.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What happened before that? I asked him several times. He frowned and fell into memories, &quot;I can&#39;t tell.&quot; From childhood to junior high school, the memory puzzle was full of cracks. The description of the past is mixed with recognition, resentment, reflection, and more confusion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Lan’s father is a middle-level cadre of a state-owned enterprise, and his mother takes care of him full-time. The relationship with them cannot be said to be very bad, nor can it be said to be very good. When he was about 10 years old, his piano teacher scolded him fiercely because he made a mistake in practicing the piano, &quot;and even threw the milk out.&quot; After passing the level 10 piano test, he said, &quot;I never want to touch this thing again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just read it In the first year of junior high school, he was in a well-known foreign language school in the provincial capital, and his classmates seemed to be better than him. &quot;There were only 9 classes in the whole grade at that time, and I was in class 2109. But they said I was in class 10. Everyone was having fun, except me. I suspected that I had a neurological problem. Why can others socialize but I can&#39;t?&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Tian Lan longed for a friend, but the result was zero. Then he didn&#39;t want to do his homework anymore. &quot;My mother said you can do whatever you want.&quot; He didn&#39;t go to school for a month. Man, completely wilted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Half a year after dropping out of school, he entered a local &quot;closed school&quot; under military management (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Special Training School&lt;/p>; span>;). &quot;Yes, it&#39;s like XX Academy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Strict control is not important. I hate the underworld.&quot; He emphasized. In Tian Lan’s description, the school is very popular (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Two sounds, meaning deceitful&lt;/span>;), &quot;teachers, gangsters&quot; They all bully others and hit them wherever they want. The boys&#39; class doesn&#39;t treat others as human beings. There are surveillance cameras everywhere just for parents to see. Even if they wipe their noses during assembly, they can be pulled to the stairwell.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first arrived at the closed school, my limb functions deteriorated a bit because I stayed at home for too long: my fingers were weak and my eyes couldn’t focus. After a few periods of military class, he heard two &quot;clicks&quot; from his knees and fell to the playground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After five days like this, the instructor and classmates thought he was faking. &quot;I went to the village hospital to take a picture. I fractured my knee, and the doctor took a picture of my calf!&quot; He said with a &quot;bewildered&quot; expression. When he went to see the doctor for a follow-up visit, there were many teachers beside the car taking him to the hospital, but no one helped him pull the wheelchair or push him into the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The whole world is sick. I am also sick.&quot; He smiled habitually. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How could you stay in such an environment for 8 months? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I later learned to tolerate it. Not long after I arrived, I complained to my dad and begged him to take me away. He just smiled. But you know, I have been in a closed school for a long time. , I even feel a little warm! I have found a little feeling of home.&quot; He himself couldn&#39;t believe this mentality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before and after the school was closed, he attended several other schools. Tian Lan was amazed at &quot;How come the world has become so weird in just over a year&quot;: &quot;Some schools are eager to learn all the contents of junior high school as soon as they are promoted from primary school to junior high school. Some even don&#39;t have enough time to go to the toilet and don&#39;t understand. Every day before the exam They all talked about test papers. Didn’t my mother tell the teacher at the new school that I had a fracture? The frostbite pustules on my hands left in the closed school have not gone away for a year. The teacher asked, didn’t you have a fracture? You were resting at home, so what are you doing? Will there be frostbite?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This heart is not completely dead. What Tian Lan wants to learn most is Go. His best result is amateur fifth-dan: it is no exaggeration to say that 99% of ordinary people are no longer his opponents in Go. &quot;You don&#39;t have to think about sixth-dan. I will be among the top three in provincial and municipal competitions. I think I have some talent. But what&#39;s the use of passing the exam?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yb5knYK1H5M5xPYAGDUsjuZwJWyvrG62KRQXEuVY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;443&quot; height=&quot;297&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/01/yb5knYK1H5M5xPYAGDUsjuZwJWyvrG62KRQXEuVY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256487&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Students decorate with brushes Girls dormitory &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He liked Liu Cixin and listened to &quot;The Three-Body Problem&quot; using podcast software when he dropped out of school , I love reading &quot;Supernova Era&quot; and many other short stories. &quot;Have you ever heard of &quot;Genshin Impact&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;an open world role-playing game&lt;/span>;)? Others are just counting numbers (&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Combat damage value)&lt;/span>;, I study the culture inside. I always fantasize about many strange things, those data and my imagination , formed many different worlds belonging to me...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He tilted his head and fell into a fugue again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of all the people, his cousin who was five months older than him had the greatest influence on him. My uncle and aunt were very strict with my cousin, but during the COVID-19 epidemic, the two brothers still had fun in the countryside of their hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The house in my hometown is big, with a mountain behind it. The top of the mountain was cut in half, and a slope protruded from the cliff. We cut down the weeds, built steps, and dug many holes. After the grass grew, we repaired it ourselves. Let&#39;s call it the &#39;Temple of Earth&#39;, haha. That&#39;s our &#39;Hundred Garden&#39;.&quot; He grinned for the first time in the two hours of chatting. &quot;There is a big pond in the back mountain. We use a big net to catch fish, and there are a lot of shrimps and crabs. There are many flowers, plants and trees on the path over the pond, which is fun.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the last time I saw my cousin, In his eyes, the other person has &quot;grown up&quot;, his voice has changed, and he is a little unfamiliar, &quot;We can&#39;t play together anymore.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Guihong feels that Tian Lan&#39;s understanding of people and the world is narrow. &quot;But he is a child with a strong sense of justice and cannot hold a grain of sand in his eyes. So he will have his own expectations and requirements for the environment.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is why Tian Lan feels that, compared to others, The &quot;ugly duckling&quot; whose place is already much better will still have situations where &quot;small groups&quot; &quot;bully the weak&quot; that he can&#39;t stand. Vice-principal Xiang Guoyue and life teacher Long Chengtong (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Long Ge&quot;&lt;/span>;) neither deny that they have a naughty personality and a bit of a tad There are indeed children in the &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot; who are addicted to the world. &quot;We will observe and deal with it, and we will also let each child face his own problems.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Lao Li said that I have problems with my emotions and emotional expression. I also feel that I am a little confused. As the saying goes , only after you have experienced it will you feel more... precious? I can&#39;t describe it.&quot; Tian Lan let out a long sigh. &quot;Anyway, I feel that my life is not worth it and I hope to do it all over again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/ 471J7UgFwzxkHKyWZMNg9esZ9twVNQJ4swH9nKtU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;546&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/471J7UgFwzxkHKyWZMNg9esZ9twVNQJ4sw H9nKtU.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;256489&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhan Danian at school&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Weng Huan /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;At an altitude of 1,800 meters, waiting for the flowers to bloom&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Children like Pu Pu and Tian Lan, in the Ugly Duckling Middle School in mid-October 2023, a total of There are more than seventy people. Some of them had mild or obvious symptoms of depression when they entered school, and some had already been diagnosed with depression or anxiety and took medication to enroll. There are also some &quot;problem students&quot; who may have nothing to do with &quot;depression&quot; but are troublesome to the original school or parents and difficult to discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhan Danian, the founder of &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;, does not accept this labeling term. In his eyes, every child does not have any big problems. They just cannot adapt to the teaching methods and evaluation standards of traditional education, and encounter various obstacles in getting along with their families, teachers, and peers. &quot;I even feel that in the era of ChatGPT, these so-called &#39;problem children&#39; are more creative and more hopeful.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1981, Zhan Danian, a native of Yiyang, Hunan Province, graduated from a normal college at the age of 26. Became the youngest principal in Taojiang County. During his tenure, the rural school that originally had just over a hundred students expanded into a medium-sized school with over a thousand students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after working in the system for nearly 20 years, Zhan Danian decided to resign. After that, he came to Yunnan and participated in the establishment of two private schools. Until 2011, he founded the Ugly Duckling Middle School with his wife Yang Liufang and several colleagues, and made it his lifelong ambition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My leaving the system has nothing to do with courage, but with personal choice.&quot; He emphasized again and again. &quot;Our educational environment places too much emphasis on &#39;picking the best and chasing the poor&#39;. Once the children do not do well, they seem to have no future. The value of education is to develop people, how can it become the elimination of people? I want to give myself and those who are not valued and The caring children find a way out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhan Danian&#39;s Mandarin has a strong Yiyang accent, and he once said with a smile that &quot;the voice software cannot recognize it.&quot; But this man with a face like Maitreya and a slightly bulging belly has become a powerful activist in innovative education. Over the years, he has blazed a path that seems to be a &quot;deviant path&quot; but is actually a &quot;passenger path&quot; that is extremely difficult to imitate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;, students generally enroll for as little as 5 months and as long as more than two years, and will study courses from the first to the third grade of junior high school. Zhan Danian hopes that after they study here for about 10 months, their behavior and habits will return to normal and they can handle their interpersonal relationships normally, and then he will persuade them to return to their original school. &quot;After all, it is more convenient to go back to study with your parents. Its mission is not to let the children enter high school first, but to live a normal life or even survive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the year when the school was founded, Zhan Danian&#39;s good friend, Wang Yeju, deputy director of the Culture and History Committee of the Yunnan Provincial Committee of the CPPCC, named the school &quot;Ugly Duckling&quot;. Many people couldn&#39;t understand it. Some freshmen also thought it was &quot;very earthy&quot;, but Zhan Danian felt like he had found a treasure: &quot;The duckling may be eaten by others, but the ugly duckling may be eaten by others.&quot; I will definitely be able to fly in one day!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of the so-called &quot;problem children&quot; are accompanied by social and psychological problems.但在最初一些年里，詹大年和同事们并未发觉和意识到问题的严重。直到2021年，学校内部的一次心理测评，九十多名在校学生里，有71名被评定为“重度抑郁”。他开始认真地审视这一问题，并多次在私人公众号和其他场合发声。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我想让更多人了解青少年抑郁，抑郁是可以治疗的。但我们更应该去了解孩子的心声。他们不应该被边缘化。”来宜良前，他在电话里郑重地告诉我。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出行前，我曾拜托他先分享几个抑郁学生的“案例”。他笑了笑，“讲谁合适呢？还是你来后随意和孩子们交谈吧。他们每个人的经历都可以书写百万字的小说。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;深秋的季节，从昆明出发不到一个小时车程后进入宜良县，沿南盘江逆流而上，经过一路的三角梅和灌木丛，鼻间开始弥漫着鸡鸭屎的“香味”和满村烧秸秆的烟气。岔路口立着一块“丑小鸭中学”的路牌指向目的地的方向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;丑小鸭的原址就坐落在宜良北古城镇，交通便利。但因校舍年久失修，两年多前，詹大年带领大家将学校迁到了海拔1800多米的新址。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;步入教学楼，一层走廊的木质栏窗、书柜和满墙斜挂着的吉他映入眼帘。木头取自本地的杉树，木材不贵，却挺拔好看。 “都是孩子们跟我们一起建造的。”詹大年介绍。窗外的樟树、天竺葵，窗台上的珊瑚樱、观音莲、绿公主、铂金蔓绿绒，一盆盆层层叠叠的绿，甚为喜人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看似普通，却有着全中国多数学校望尘莫及的“优越”条件：年均2100多小时的日照。 10月份的白天，背对太阳不过几分钟便觉微热。来此参观的教育界人士朱小毛没忍住，拿着三本书作枕头，直接躺在了操场的地上。 “不躺都是一种浪费。一所有阳光的学校，才能真正温暖人心。”朱小毛慨叹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/q3ntqxMMAWsWkelyuY6CHwcPdvtJ1WtIcSCfdPUa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;401&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/q3ntqxMMAWsWkelyuY6CHwcPdvtJ1WtIcSCfdPUa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256490&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月，丑小鸭中学的一节心理课，学生在就“青春萌动”话题发表看法&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者翁洹/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早上的晨跑，上午40分钟的体育课，加上下午40分钟的军训课，“每天我们至少保证三个小时的户外运动，还不包括孩子们的自由活动时间。”詹大年自豪地说起，副校长杨柳芳接着介绍：“到冬天大中午的时候，孩子们经常就躺在这里（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;操场的防腐木舞台&lt;/span>;）看书聊天，可舒服了。学校会安排人把这些木板拖洗干净，方便他们&#39;躺平&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;走廊上的钢琴，学生们下课可随意弹奏。教室集中在二层，一共只有七、八、九年级共三间，每间都很开阔：前半部分是课堂，后半部被书架做成的玄关隔开，只放了一两排桌子，供学生讨论、活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了校长夫妇、创校不久便来的向国跃、李桂红和“龙哥”，老师们都很年轻，好几次我都把老师错当成了学生交谈。 “在这儿看不到多少老师的痕迹。没有校服，也没有制服。”詹大年说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但教室墙面上用水笔书写的课表上，却活脱脱全是“老师”的存在：娟娟、波波、自富——教授者的昵称取代了课程名。黑板也被几乎整面墙的白板代替，顺滑，超大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“丑小鸭”倡导全科教学。这里的文化课只有三门：文科、理科和英语。文科老师负责语文、历史、政治三科教学；理科老师负责数理化三科。 “大多数来的孩子，就是自信被伤害，关系被破坏，甚至人格被解体。如果科目老师一周只有一两节课的时间和学生接触，一个学期下来都没法熟悉学生，很难有我们期待的那种生命交融。只有尽可能多地接触孩子，才能够建立教育应有的&#39;关系&#39;。”詹大年解释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初二的语文课上，有同学提问，“娟娟，今天我们能开&#39;小火车&#39;吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“可以啊！”接下来，学生们一个个次第起立，如多米诺一般，每人朗读完一句刚学过的古文《与朱元思书》便自行翻译，下一个亦复如是——这是大家乐此不疲的游戏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“嘿，你怎么抢断别人车厢？”娟娟嗤的一笑，却并无责怪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那个谁，你今天刚到是吧？”她对一位坐在最后排、有些扭捏的新生讲，“我们有&#39;新生保护期&#39;，这个问题你可以不回答。期待你后面的表现哦。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“丑小鸭”，学生几乎每节文化课都会用平板电脑查资料，接着再交还老师；下课后，可以用教室的触摸屏欣赏音乐、看看短视频；一周还有一两天晚上有自由上网的“福利”——当然，还是平板。手机，除非请假回家探亲，平时严禁使用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“网瘾大，不用手机受不了？”似乎没人这么觉得。每天下午两节文化课后，学生除了参加军训，还有两节兴趣课和社团活动：吉他、舞蹈、声乐、篮球。不用固定，想上哪个都可以。实在没有感兴趣的，打牌、弹琴、看书，和人聊天，打打沙袋，在操场遛弯儿，都行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个月的3日、13日和23日，是村里的“街天”（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;赶集日&lt;/span>;）。生活老师会带着学生走出校门，出去赶集。 “什么豆浆油条，米饼、苦荞饼、葱油饼，饼干山楂卷，酸辣凤爪，百香果味道的，什么好吃的都有。”初二女生季果儿跟我描述着，馋虫仿佛已顺着嘴边冒了出来。 “有时周末，老师还会带我们去县城泡温泉，吃烧烤、火锅，还有露营。可好玩呢。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/87mzFhHs2aAVvAn0lrtqpq7ngfD3U1EC1lnciydw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;538&quot; height=&quot;348&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/87mzFhHs2aAVvAn0lrtqpq7ngfD3U1EC1lnciydw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256491&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;教学楼走廊墙壁上，学生们的自画像&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者翁洹/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;好关系的营造&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“教育是急不得的。好的关系才是好的教育。”这是詹大年在教育圈里最广为人知的一句“箴言”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位曾就读于“丑小鸭”的学生这么形容他心目中的“詹式治校”：“我看你也没有什么别的招数呀，就是对那些容易惹祸的学生，先不惹他们；然后呢，让他们吃好喝好玩好，就行了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;詹大年朗声大笑，“你看得很准啊。就是这样。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前，每每听到詹大年强调“理解”、“信任”、“关系就是一切”，讲求“科学管理”的教育专家李镇西总觉得“太玄乎”，现在他越来越明白了詹大年。 “教育不能仅仅规范行为，更应该关注心灵。&#39;丑小鸭&#39;是把孩子当人，着眼于每一个人的人格尊严、精神自由。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在成人眼中“有问题”的孩子，也会成为彼此心灵的照护者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“丑小鸭”，除了行政班和宿舍的生活班，每位新生还会被分配一名学长“师傅”，帮他们熟悉校园生活，克服生活中的负面情绪。有的孩子刚来时不吃饭、不洗漱、不洗衣服，说什么都不听。 “师傅”会带他们到心理室，但老李小杨并不一定立马介入，而是由学长陪其玩游戏，“有的学生是游戏高手，有的老师打游戏也很厉害，我们就给他介绍，他们可以聊很久。喜欢追番的，喜欢二次元和漫画的，喜欢唱歌、玩乐器的，都会慢慢凑到一起……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Sqc4Q0JTj4fIrtsrkp9D6kpi2OdyCkXc8K3mkGpV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;538&quot; height=&quot;348&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Sqc4Q0JTj4fIrtsrkp9D6kpi2OdyCkXc8K3mkGpV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256492&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;阳光下的书吧，大家最常驻足的空间。摆放的几架钢琴，课间和课后学生可自由弹奏&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者翁洹/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“丑小鸭”一度最红火的学生社团是心理社。 2014年8月3日，云南昭通发生地震。震后第二天，詹大年带领几个孩子驱车三百余公里，把救灾物资送到受灾村民手中。但他发现，灾区儿童的心理亟需干预和辅导，这恰恰是“丑小鸭”学生们可以着力的地方。很快，对心理辅导完全陌生的学生们查阅地震资料，请教心理老师：怎样帮助灾区哭泣和绝望的孩子？第二次进灾区，一群不到15岁的半大孩子，被一群更小的孩子唤作“老师”，一起做游戏，聊家常，带给了他们难得的欢笑。 “对我们的孩子，这也是一次极好的自我教育。”詹大年甚是欣慰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;采访中，几位师生都向我提起一个叫罗亭的“学霸”男孩。 “有国外生活经历，家境好，人也帅，可一点都不显摆。”来丑小鸭之前，罗亭先后就读于上海一所国际学校和公立学校，因为对学校教学的不适应和疫情长期居家，最后干脆不去学校。每天大门不出，一言不发，把从小看着他长大的爷爷给愁坏了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了千里之外的“丑小鸭”，他觉出这学校“挺不一样”，却也没有“一见倾心”。头一两个月，罗亭到哪儿都埋头做题，不与任何人说话。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不知从哪天开始，他弹起走廊里那架珠江钢琴，像变了个人。 “小学二年级的时候学过半年，已经荒了四五年，相当于从头开始自学。”他不求速成，一首《卡农》和《花之舞》，照着搜到的曲谱来回弹上一学期，同学不时凑过来听，他也安然继续。 “那种愉悦，很难用言语表达。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，罗亭和趣味相投的之寒、嘉渝成了死党。他们会凑在一起谈论中美贸易、俄乌冲突。初三下学期，几个人成立了学习小组，纷纷利用宝贵的“军训课免修”时间自习备考。 “在&#39;丑小鸭&#39;，我还喜欢上了跑步。”罗亭微笑着说。 “之寒原本体重超过100公斤，跑步以后，他瘦了40公斤，成了学校的传奇！”之寒的“励志跑”把罗亭也带成了跑步达人。学校的跑道接近125米一圈，他们每天跑上40圈，几乎“雷打不动”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;季果儿是个大大咧咧、“外粗内细”的女生。聊天时，她时不时地将视线转开，最后终于指着篮球架边一个人影，“小邓老师，我有个闺蜜在那边，她也好想和你聊聊。”于是，我和季果儿、她的闺蜜何蔓，手挽着手绕着操场走了一圈又一圈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;季果儿说，何蔓有阵儿爱哭，她也不问那么多，就逗她笑。 “我跟她说，你哭起来可丑。她说你真讨厌。哈哈，这招儿管用。”季果儿笑得没心没肺。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那对有些不爱说话的同学呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们都在一个生活班，住在一个屋檐下，再不爱说话的人，久了都会说些各自的小秘密。你要是天天跟她念叨，她自然会来找你。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她掰着指头和我说起同学的好：晓星老大方，不记仇；景雯喜欢看书、弹钢琴；何蔓开朗，性格好……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你刚说她爱哭？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“嘿，她一看到我哭，又把自己眼泪憋回去，把我安慰好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们乐成一团。她却严肃起来：“其实像我们这么大的人都好面子，不希望显得弱，希望自己强。那得让他们（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;同学&lt;/span>;）慢慢接受这个世界。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看起来做事积极、待人周到、能指出他人问题的季果儿，在老师们眼中也会出言不逊，容易失去表达的边界。向国跃说，青春期的孩子常会表现出刺猬的特征。 “丑小鸭”的学生在原来学校和家庭里个人意志可能被强压着，到了这里就会反应出来。从2011年便加入学校的李桂红，原来也觉得孩子们“不守规矩”，总会用一些类似恶作剧的方式宣告他们的存在。 “詹校说，对孩子们要用放大镜看优点、老花镜看缺点。于是我也学会了欣赏他们。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在&#39;丑小鸭&#39;，爱说话就让你接待新同学，会钢琴就尽可能地给机会弹；文章写得好会被张贴。我们有位C诗人，写了一篇关于爱情，一篇谈人生的，大家都可崇拜他了……不管是文艺演出还是演讲比赛，学校要求每个人都得上场，打酱油也要上台，演成什么样都给你鼓掌呵呵。”季果儿的话像袋子打开口的豆子，倾泻而出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“对，还有小英。”从警校毕业的生活老师龙金英刚满二十，一头长发挡不住浑身的英气。采访那几天，她不是在拾掇买来的盆栽，就是拿着锯子锯木条、垒花架。 “小英太厉害了。生病帮你配药，装修、刷墙，火把节跳傣族舞，全能！她对情绪爆发的孩子很有一套，会让你出去走走。等冷静下来，再和你聊。”季果儿与何蔓心目中的小英，俨然已是女生们共同的“偶像”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FXAdGQ7EL1u9qNNPEzEj4kyufjey5KUhzOnecwsB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;546&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FXAdGQ7EL1u9qNNPEzEj4kyufjey5KUhzOnecwsB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256493&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;午间就餐的学生&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者翁洹/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“把他们送到丑老鸭”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;但能干如小英、向国跃，也有不太使得上劲的时候。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“像朴朴和田榄，他们的父母虽然也和他们发生过争执，但总体还是能平复下来，接受孩子当下的状态，与学校配合。”向国跃指出，最难办的是，有的家长把孩子送过来，是希望“你按照他们的方式来教育孩子，只关心成绩，不关心背后是什么”；或者意识不到自己的问题，很难沟通；更有甚者，对孩子几乎不闻不问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“孩子心里缺爱，父母却很少回应，甚至带给他们一次次的伤害。于是亲子之间彼此伤害。有的孩子还会被迫卷入成年人的关系之中，学会了暴力、疏离和冷漠。”李桂红说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有感于亲情教育的重要，詹大年从办学不久便开设了家长课堂。他的私人公号长年以一天两条消息的频率持续传播教育理念。许多家长在孩子抑郁、厌学、和父母停止交流后，从詹大年的公号上获得精神力量。有的，则直接将孩子送来这里。但转变却非朝夕之功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大脸庞、眸子明亮的何蔓，生长在中越边境的H城。她对童年印象最深的画面便是，爸爸骑着摩托车带她上学，妈妈晚上忙于美容院的生意，白天在睡觉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四年级转学到Q城，爸爸没时间照看她，便找了她原来的数学老师，花钱请她跨城过来做“保姆+辅导老师”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从六年级到初二，何蔓辗转换了五六次学校。 “当时我当啦啦操副队长，跑步也跑第一。高年级的男生加我微信和QQ，同年级女生看我不爽，骂我绿茶。初二的学生威胁我交保护费，我只好拼命往后门跑，痞子挺多。老师说我学习不好，不让其他人跟我玩。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她在墙角抽烟，被人举报。 “其实大家都抽，但他们只说我。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她和爸爸哭诉，没用。 “没好好听我说。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“妈妈呢？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“妈妈连我初一下学期学校在哪里、住哪里都不知道。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她吞过二十来颗布洛芬，都是感冒时去学校医务室一点点存下的。 “跳楼也不行，都围着栏杆，没条件。就吃药了。活着真的没意义。妈妈跟老师说我鬼迷眼，故意吓他们。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她再次从学校逃开。到底被爸妈逮住，在H城老家的地下车库关了一个晚上。 “用铁丝打我，扇我，掐我脖子，拉着我洗文身。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她又回到Q城。去手机店上班，又被爸妈带回。 “他们只想抓我回去。我太多太多的人生，他们都没有参与。我只想逃脱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说到这儿，有个请了几天假的女生回到学校，何蔓看着大门口，露出一丝开心：“我们好多同学休假回来，常常带一大袋话梅薯片果冻、披萨给我们吃。有的会给生活班每个人都带杯奶茶，可美咯。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在“丑小鸭”，娟娟让她当班长；杨校让她接待来访客人；小英会安慰她，好好听她说话。刚来这里不久就赶上了夏令营，“从早到晚我们都在操场聊天，天黑了一起看电影、吃烧烤……”她原以为，到“丑小鸭”以后第一次给父母打电话自己会哭，结果竟然全程欢笑。 “我本来对前男友很执着，老李说，我其实对恋爱一窍不通。哈哈。不过我真的知道了，外面虚虚渺渺，我现在学会看人了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为课程落下太多，15岁的她在“丑小鸭”重修初二。她不着急，慢慢地体恤起总是对她“恨铁不成钢”的爸爸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;爷爷奶奶老家不在云南，过来几十年，在镇上还是不受待见。五十开外的爸爸，早年在H城做会计，在何蔓眼里其实是家族中最懂事的一个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“他是家里最正经做事的，可小时候吃到一块糖都奢侈。他恨家里人，觉得不公平，什么烂摊子都是他去擦屁股。所以他希望我有出息，能留在身边。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来“丑小鸭”前，何蔓曾去昆明看过心理医生。 “医生说，你们两代人之间隔阂太深。反正我好多事情，爸妈不问，我也不说。有时候我调皮，就是想故意气他们一下。”她顿了顿，语气柔和下来：“我爸有糖尿病，我现在不会再故意气他了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小野的故事里，则几乎只有她和母亲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“今天是我来到丑小鸭的第136天。”刚坐下，她清晰地说出这个日子。每过一天，她都会在日历上划掉一杠——“感觉又离回家近了一天。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和另外几个女生迫不及待的分享欲不同，小野的眼神和嘴角都带着一分打量。她擅长美术，最近学校的“班级文化”，从楼梯间到宿舍墙壁再到走廊的装饰画，她全有贡献；唱歌、跳舞，样样拿得出手。但好像这些还不够满足她的渴望。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“她经常自伤，拿尺子、石头，中性笔掰断，什么都用。手和腿抓得跟鱼鳞似的。”李桂红说，朴朴的自残更多是一种情绪宣泄，小野的行为里还多了一份“求得关注”的意图。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在小野的描述里，妈妈会觉得离婚是因为女儿的缘故，“所以老带着私人情绪怨怼我。”从很小起，妈妈越是不许她干什么，她就越来越想做。一吵架，两人总是拿出恶毒的语言互相指责，“她说我有妄想症。我说你也去看看，肯定你有问题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小野曾经很爱给妈妈写信，写微信，或者手写几百字的信，再拍照发给“老李”。 “其实是希望我转发给她妈妈。有的外省的父母可能来三四次了，她觉得妈妈怎么老不来。不来就是不爱我。要立刻实现才是爱我。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“等我们长大了，要把那些叛逆的家长送到一间叫&#39;丑老鸭&#39;的学校去，或者叫&#39;丑小鸡&#39;，哈哈！”说起和同学瞎聊时的提议，小野耸肩大笑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可妈妈知道她想买“洛丽塔”服饰，爱看漫展，都会全力支持。 “我不是个合格的女儿……对不起我妈。”小野眼眶有点泛红。她希望自己早点独立，能挣钱，“出去了给我妈打钱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“亲爸？没见过，因为我是女孩就不要我了。他现在想见我？没可能。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于“丑小鸭”，她来之前查过这地方，学校名字怪怪的。 “过一种幸福完整的教育生活……”她喃喃念起引自教育家朱永新的这句“丑小鸭”校训，“能实现吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她拒绝上到初三毕业，希望早点离开，因为外头有好多好玩的等着她。在老家，她小学四五年级就跑去KTV，“那些加微信的姐姐都好漂亮。”她们称赞她“会唱歌跳舞，化妆也好，不会惹事”，还有大人教她“不要太在乎别人看法”这样的人生道理，她都觉得可长见识、可快活了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她希望老李和妈妈沟通，让她回去。但妈妈不放心，“在宜良能够切断她和老家的社会关系。”李桂红说，她曾婉转地提醒小野，社会上的人讲义气，但小恩小惠后面很可能有对未成年人的利用。 “这些道理她暂时还不太能听进去，但我们总得要一点一点和她讲。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/BYA0RMGelbZiZ46SxJFr4d0fM8KD2hJpXWFgFPnw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;545&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/BYA0RMGelbZiZ46SxJFr4d0fM8KD2hJpXWFgFPnw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256494&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月21日，首届青少年心理安全论坛讲座现场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方人物周刊记者翁洹/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;新的教育哲学&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;怀揣着更多个朴朴和小野的故事，我暂别待了三天的“丑小鸭”，前往昆明。关于青少年抑郁，各种专题讨论早已屡见不鲜，但10月21-22日在昆明举办的首届青少年心理安全论坛的热度还是超出了主办方的预料。踊跃发言者，从写纸条、抢话筒，到有人直接冲到大舞台边，要“带着冒犯”地直抒胸臆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位詹大年的读者表示，自己从小学习顺利，一直就读本地最好的学校，但从来不快乐也没有成就感，三十好几还在迷茫；几位老师和家长带着孩子遇到的校园霸凌、心理疾病问题现场求助；还有几位来自不同学校的老师提出，想要去关怀学生，却势单力薄，“我们也是问题老师，谁来帮助我们？！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“既说明大家有巨大的表达欲和想要解决问题的热忱，也说明，无论是教育工作者还是孩子家长，很多人本身也都存在着心理问题需要被看到，被疏导。”一位与会嘉宾感叹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年6月修订实施的《未成年人保护法》明确规定：教育行政部门应当加强未成年人的心理健康教育，建立未成年人心理问题的早期发现和及时干预机制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在论坛内外，大家讨论更多的，是那些引发抑郁或者因抑郁导致的现实生活中的问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;著名教育专家冯恩洪指出，构筑青少年心理安全教育防线所面对的，是当今社会在教育问题上的全体性迷失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈瑜是家庭教育平台“少年大不同”创始人，曾深度访谈过上百个抑郁、厌学、挣扎绝望的中小学生。今年找她当面和电话咨询的学生里，数量激增的是高一新生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“有的孩子上高一第一天，做作业到夜里11点。老师说，你都上高中了，还指望睡好觉吗？有北京&#39;六小强&#39;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;海淀名校&lt;/span>;）的学生问我，我为什么需要学到滴水不漏、一字不差的程度？这是很多孩子的困惑。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有学生告诉陈瑜，开学第一天，学校里做如是动员：“拥有成绩，就拥有一切。坐在你身边的同学，都是中考考场的敌人。”她遇到一位深圳名校的女生，凌晨4点起来读书，渐渐地例假也不来了。她问女孩，“一切都要为分数让道吗？成绩比身体还重要吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“女孩说，是的。&#39;这样也好，我再不用担心考试撞上生理期了。&#39;还有辽宁一位排名年级第一的孩子觉得自己&#39;像窃取了皇帝桂冠的窃贼&#39;，好像坐在高台上，一阵风吹来，就会倒掉。”陈瑜总结，这一代的孩子，厌学更早，休学更长，复学更难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果孩子视力下降、睡眠不足、体质羸弱、心理畸形，乃至生命夭折，所有教育的辉煌成就都毫无意义！”李镇西在他的演讲中疾呼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当学生有抑郁倾向或被确诊，会遭遇截然不同的境遇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈瑜访谈过的一个孩子，确诊抑郁症之后被同学排挤，课桌里塞满了垃圾和矿泉水瓶。后来新的班主任约她出来在咖啡馆聊，复学的时候，她牵着小姑娘的手走进学校，到班级门口的时候，全班同学鼓掌欢迎她，孩子心理发生了剧变。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在江浙某地，有学校给临近高三的学生做了心理测评和评估，“校方对其中一些孩子说，你目前的情绪状态没有办法适应学校接下来的学业。就把他们退学了。很多抑郁症的孩子也会说，我回到家里以后就没有任何的老师和学生来联系我。他觉得我从此被这个组织抛弃了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;解决之道在哪里？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教育家杨东平的回答是，教育部门不断推出“减负”新政，然而如何摆脱教育方针与教育现实长期两张皮、素质教育缺乏生命力的状态？答案只有一个：中国需要新的教育哲学，要从头做起自上而下的顶层设计。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他进一步提出：要从源头上减少课程教学时数，降低教学浓度、考试难度，推行小学的全科教师模式，改善教育生态；取消重点学校，试点学科分层，有利于学生之间的交流，减少因教育分流制度而造成的贴标签或受歧视的现象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当你把孩子当作一个人来尊重，跟他相处，你就会得到一个正常健康的人；如果你把孩子当作学习机器，那你得到的就是一个物件。”杨东平的掷地有声和詹大年的朴素语言都引起了听众的强烈共鸣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来丑小鸭中学参观和阅读詹大年公号的读者感受到，“问题孩子”在这里找回了自己，也认识了生活，他们可以重新起航。 “那么，一所普通学校能办成&#39;丑小鸭&#39;吗？假如对正常的孩子也是以这种方式教育会怎样？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而詹大年一直强调，丑小鸭中学是一种预防型的学校，是为不适应传统教育体制的孩子提供适合的教育方式，而非提供一种解困的方法论。 “我们今天碰到的所有教育症结，都不是一个论坛能改变的。但它能提供一种思考：我们的教学，我们的家庭教育，是不是出了什么问题？这就是这些探讨和发声能起到的作用。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在人前似乎“难不倒”的詹大年，坦承他面对抑郁和其他表现的孩子常有束手无策的时刻。曾经有一个父母分开的混血女生，一根脚趾被自己用皮筋缠到坏死，来了“丑小鸭”又想缠另一根。来了好几个月依然头也不抬，进展缓慢。 “这孩子后来我们只好劝退了，因为已经超出了我们的能力范围，需要医疗机构的干预。”詹大年的语调里有一种少见的失落与无力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我问陈瑜，假如学校环境很难改变，有的父母又像嘉宾们说的“冥顽不灵”，她会给访谈的那些孩子怎样的建议？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我期待国内的职高和技术学校现状有所转变，让有一技之长的普通人都能过上体面的生活。一个孩子但凡有那么一点闪光的部分，他就不会全然否定自己。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个泉州的妈妈曾向她求助：儿子智商略有缺陷，她很希望孩子能跟上同学学习的节奏，但孩子已经开始厌学。陈瑜了解到男孩非常喜欢饲养宠物，“我说你跟着我想象一下，在你们生活的这条街上有爸爸开的海鲜店，有你开的影楼，有你孩子开的花鸟鱼虫店，不是很美好吗？她说陈老师，以前别人都劝我也要&#39;卷&#39;，听你这么一说，我就很开心了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在当下，看懂孩子和时代尤为重要。每个孩子都自带粮草和地图。我们要为孩子全面托底，不要让他们举目四望，寂寥无人。”陈瑜打着比方。 “一位理解你的补课老师，一个值得信任的男朋友/女朋友，都可以是支点。”如果身边就是没有托底的人，我会告诉他们，挺一挺，18岁以后你就有机会疗愈自己，要成为自己滋养自己的人。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结束在“丑小鸭”的采访前，朴朴告诉我，她希望回到那所“高质量严管控”的中学参加中考，因为姑父开出租车，刚念初一的堂弟要一边做作业、一边带两岁的小弟弟，还要给姑父做饭，如果她长大有份好工作，“可以让堂弟不那么辛苦”；何蔓说，以前老和爸爸吵架，现在隔几天会念叨，爸爸怎么不发消息；一直在自学日语、过了N2的小野长大想当插画师，“妈妈支持我去日本留学”；季果儿的妈妈则希望她能上警校，“可我想当幼师，教小朋友。詹校也觉得我可以哈。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（参考资料：詹大年私人公号，首届青少年心理安全论坛嘉宾发言。文中学生名字皆为化名。实习记者杨宇熙对本文亦有贡献。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[善缘丨台上台下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259771]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Nle67mKR4B6FkOMYlKkteesTzDZ3VO6uK4rFizQR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;948&quot; height=&quot;1001&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Nle67mKR4B6FkOMYlKkteesTzDZ3VO6uK4rFizQR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256568&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;林青霞与高锟慈善基金主席黄美芸。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（作者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所有聚在这个厅里面的人，所有听到我们傅达脑退化症信息的你们，都是因为一个“缘”字，我们结的是善缘。而这个善缘始于二十多年前的一场颁奖典礼，我先生和善衡书院的前院长辛世文教授，同时获奖，因此我和辛院长有了一面之缘，2018年我又荣获辛院长颁赠善衡书院荣誉院士的荣衔，从此就跟中文大学结了缘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我和赵夏瀛医生的缘分始于新冠病毒入侵的初期，我与好友金圣华商量想在新冠战役中为社会尽点心意，圣华介绍了雷兆辉医生和赵夏瀛医生夫妇给我认识，因此我们成了朋友。去年圣诞节期间，我们在半岛酒店喝下午茶，听到赵医生跟圣华讨论脑退化症的项目，我认为这是刻不容缓的，因此主动要求参与其事，希望能略尽绵力帮助推动这项义举，使隐形和轻度脑退化症的人，得以预防和延缓病症，减轻自己和家人的痛苦，减轻社会的负担。赵医生介绍了善衡书院莫仲棠院长和高锟慈善基金主席黄美芸女士（高锟夫人）跟我认识，我们四方面一拍即合，很快就推动起脑退化这个项目，善缘因而由此延续下去。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fKBkxMNAJHPLlLJLOCBGNJXAZemQybB8FTsbONQC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fKBkxMNAJHPLlLJLOCBGNJXAZemQybB8FTsbONQC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256569&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;林青霞与赵夏瀛医生（左）、香港中文大学善衡书院院长莫仲棠。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（作者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参与脑智同护活动之后，跟脑神经科专家莫院长及赵医生上了几堂课，学到许多平常接触不到的知识。你知道大脑有几磅吗？三磅；你知道大脑有多少个神经细胞吗？一千亿个；每一个神经细胞透过分支跟其他几千个神经细胞相连，形成通讯网络，这些分支的联系超过一百万亿个点，整个联系形成一个复杂的网络。你知道七十岁以上每十个人就有一个脑退化症吗？我有许多朋友都是七八九十多岁，脑筋灵光得很，我很喜欢亲近他们，他们人生经历丰富，他们在生命中得到的感悟，那些宝藏，值得我们学习的地方很多，所以一定要好好保护年纪大的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说件有趣的事，我因为想亲近九十岁的昔日巨星葛兰姐，跟她一起去票京戏，对票戏也有些好奇心，票友七个人，有三个是九十岁以上，其中一位高寿九十九，不用拐杖、不坐轮椅、不带看护，西装笔挺地一个人走进来，三个九十以上唱起京戏中气十足令人惊叹，聊起天来也毫无顾忌地畅所欲言，真不能称呼他们老先生老太太，他们活得潇洒自在。其间大家开玩笑，把葛兰姐和九十九凑成一对，我觉得好可爱，举起相机起哄“亲一个！亲一个！”九十九大大方方地在葛兰姐脸上亲了一下，大家拍手鼓掌好不快乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2SjvLoqlT1cN4qPjbZZWN2sycGh0x5BoJde52tEA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2SjvLoqlT1cN4qPjbZZWN2sycGh0x5BoJde52tEA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256570&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;作为赞助人、项目大使的林青霞在“脑智同护”服务计划启动仪式上。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（作者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我今年六十八，十一月就六十九了，我的记性和反应比六十岁以前都好。我看书、写作、画画、唱戏、参加正能量的社交活动，还有就是每天保持运动，除了行山，几乎天天打乒乓球，偶尔做瑜珈，对天下万事万物都有好奇心，最重要是培养爱的能力，这些活动在我六十岁以前几乎很少做。现在的我仿佛过着另外一个人的生活。原来所有这些都是脑退化的良药。如果六十归零，从新开始，我现在才八岁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说了这么多，言归正传，在此呼吁六十岁以上的小朋友踊跃报名，测试你的脑子还是不是像以前那么灵光，如果不是，让我们携手击退脑退化症。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（本文为林青霞在香港“脑智同护”服务计划启动仪式上的致辞）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[违规的清滩养蛏：边滑“泥橇”边下农药]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259757]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73271&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70087&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bc8efa1ae6.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;蛏子1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bc8efa1ae6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256460&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蛏子是广受欢迎的平价海鲜，为提高蛏子产量，有渔民在滩涂违规使用农药，以杀死、驱赶蛏子在滩涂上的天敌。视觉中国|图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刘明还在等待一个说法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;几个月前，他鱼塘里的水产品在一夜之间忽然死了不少，损失惨重。他的鱼塘靠近海边，每逢农历初一和十五涨大潮，引海水入塘换水。遭受损失的还有另外三位养殖户邻居，他们都是在2023年7月2日——农历五月十五这天换水的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;向大海索取馈赠的不仅有刘明等鱼塘养殖户，还有一两公里外滩涂地带的缢蛏（俗称“蛏子”）养殖户。刘明等人怀疑，养蛏人在滩涂上投放农药，涨潮后形成“毒水”，正好赶上换水被引入鱼塘，毒死了水产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刘明表示，他们已经报案，目前还未有调查结果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不同生物体质不同，只要掌握合适剂量，农药可以杀死、驱赶蛏子在滩涂上的天敌，而不影响蛏子。长期研究蛏子养殖的厦门海洋职业技术学院海洋生物学院高级实验师黄标武告诉南方周末记者，在滩涂使用农药的养蛏方式，目前存在于我国部分沿海地区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这些农药最常见的是三唑磷，主要用于防治果树、棉花、粮食类作物害虫，但用于蛏子养殖则属违规。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;使用农药提高了蛏子单一物种的存活率，却牺牲了生物多样性。滩涂是全球百万候鸟的中转站，丰富的贝类等是它们的食物。目前，农药在蛏子体内的残留情况、代谢规律及对人体健康的影响，尚未有充分研究。由于监管难度较高等原因，这种养殖方法在部分沿海地区未得到有效管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;杀死天敌又不毒死蛏子&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;蛏子是广受欢迎的平价海鲜，黄标武告诉南方周末记者，目前市面上售卖的蛏子基本为养殖产品，主要有池塘养殖和滩涂养殖两种方法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;早期养殖蛏苗来源于野生苗，而野生蛏苗只产于浙江和福建，数量有限。十几年前，蛏子人工育苗技术取得突破后，大面积的滩涂养殖方法才兴起。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73272&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70088&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d678c245b9.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;蛏子2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;725&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d678c245b9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256461&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年3月，福建泉州。早晨利用潮汐涨落间歇，渔民去滩涂打捞野生蛏苗售卖。（图文无关）视觉中国|图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随着滩涂养蛏的推广，三唑磷等清滩药物也开始流行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;潮水涨落形成了一片宽达数千米的潮间带，是生物多样性宝库，除了蛏子，这里栖息着藻类、螺类、虾蟹类、小型鱼类等丰富生物，也吸引鸟类觅食。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;黄标武解释，蛏苗刚投放时，还无法钻入泥土很深，容易成为滩涂上其他生物的食物，严重时蛏农甚至颗粒无收。而三唑磷可以杀死蟹类、螺类、虾虎鱼等蛏子的天敌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如何使用三唑磷等药物有不少讲究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;曾在滩涂上养过蛏子的李成向南方周末记者介绍，首先要解决交通问题。在广袤的滩涂，蛏子养殖场成千上万亩，一眼望不到边。单凭双脚无法活动，马上会陷入泥沼。为此养蛏人乘坐一种类似滑板车的自制工具，称为“泥橇”。它是一块两头微翘的长条木板，中间立着扶手，驾驶者一腿跪在板上，另一腿蹬地，可以在泥滩上迅速滑行。四百年前，它曾是戚家军战胜倭寇的“秘密武器”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;三唑磷撒在滩涂上的剂量、区域需要严格控制——达到既杀死天敌又不能毒死蛏子的目的。养蛏场地类似田埂，每条约150米宽，两条梗之间相距约50米，便于行船。养蛏人把约50斤的农药桶倾斜放在泥橇后方，匀速直线前进，农药从桶身上的小眼缓缓流出，1小时前进约2公里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;李成透露，这些三唑磷并非购自市场，“有专门批发的，直接联系人家就能给你送过来”。撒药时间一般选在大潮来临之前，涨潮后，滩涂上的药物随着海水蔓延开来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;正是这种养殖“潜规则”让刘明他们怀疑，自家鱼塘在大潮换水后突遭损失与养蛏撒药有关。类似事件在当地并非首次发生。养殖户甚至总结出了经验，换水前先问海边赶海的人，是否发现死鱼，以判断海水是否“含毒”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当地蛏苗在3月开始播撒，来年3月收获。因为天气变冷后，近岸蛏子的天敌比较少，撒药时间从3月持续到9月，每个月通常最多撒两次。“三唑磷的味道可呛人了，刺激性特别强。”李成说，有次他把三唑磷放在车里，那种令人难受的味道好几天都没有消散。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据媒体报道，2018年，在江苏盐城大丰养了18年蛏子的老王突然出现胸闷、头晕、乏力，医生找到元凶是老王使用的有机磷农药，能杀死破坏蛏子生长环境的蜾蠃蜚（一种小型生物，俗称“海革子”）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除了三唑磷，李成还使用过敌敌畏和吡虫啉两种农药，它们也是为了毒杀蛏子的天敌，但三唑磷的用量最大。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;明令禁止但监管难&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;三唑磷、敌敌畏和吡虫啉等农药在水产养殖中使用并不合规。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一位水产、渔药领域专家在接受南方周末记者采访时表示，我国水产养殖用药实行白名单制度。“白名单内的水产养殖用兽药，均经过了严格的药效学、毒理学、食品安全和环境影响等方面的研究，对使用效果和在水产品体内的代谢残留规律等有较为深入的认知。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;白名单外化学药物，不得非法使用。养蛏人使用的三唑磷等农药，并不在白名单内。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;关于三唑磷已有一些研究。浙江省海洋水产研究所等机构的专家于2007年发表的一篇文章提到，在养蛏过程中使用的三唑磷，能在可食组织中残留，实验模拟数据表明，三唑磷在蛏子中的积累和消除速度均较快，在用药24小时后，缢蛏体内三唑磷浓度达2.97mg/kg，100小时后，降至0.021mg/kg。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前我国仅制定了三唑磷在植物性食品中限量标准，水产品中没有标准可循。参考《食品安全国家标准食品中农药最大残留限量》(GB 2763-2021)，最高限量是水果，为0.2mg/kg，最小限量为小麦、燕麦等谷物，为0.05mg/kg。上述研究的24小时数据严重超标，100小时数据未超标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过，因三唑磷易造成蔬菜农残超标，三唑磷在蔬菜种植中也不受欢迎，2013年，原农村部规定，在2016年12月31日以后禁止其在蔬菜上使用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一些地方已明确禁用三唑磷养蛏。例如，2017年，野生蛏苗主产地之一浙江省乐清市发布《关于禁止在浅海滩涂养殖中使用农药的通告》，严禁在浅海滩涂养殖中使用三唑磷、敌敌畏、五氯酚钠、氯氰菊酯、吡虫啉等农药，鼓励居民制止并举报违规现象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;也有处罚案例。2017年，浙江宁波宁海县渔政渔港监督管理站执法人员发现有人在养殖蛏子过程中使用三唑磷，罚款一万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但三唑磷等农药使用的监管难度很高。一些沿海养殖户告诉南方周末记者，这种养殖方式隐秘多年，为避人耳目，养蛏人一般会在深夜撒农药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;早在2014年，环保组织“青岛市海洋生态研究会”理事长王松林就曾目睹滩涂上一群养蛏人正在播撒三唑磷。研究会在2019年发布的《蛏：中国近海养殖评估报告》指出，进入养殖滩涂湿地交通不便，给监管工作带来诸多困难。例如，人、车辆、船舶都无法在泥泞的滩涂上前行，监管人员难以锁定证据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73273&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70089&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fb36a6570f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;蛏子3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fb36a6570f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256462&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年1月，浙江温州，养殖户在乐清湾的滩涂养殖区收刮蛏子苗。（图文无关）视觉中国|图&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;农田管理的惯性思维&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;王松林表示，不仅蛏子，有的经济型贝类如杂色蛤的滩涂增养殖、黄渤海沿岸规模较大的海参围堰养殖产业，也有违规使用化学药品现象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;青岛市海洋生态研究会于2019年发布的《海参：中国近海池塘及围堰养殖评估报告》提到，海参的围堰养殖滥用化学品问题较为严重。例如，为预防和治疗病害，育苗阶段违规使用抗生素；为清塘和杀死海参的天敌，养殖过程违法使用杀虫剂和除草剂；海参的加工、销售环节还可能过量添加明矾、违法使用甲醛，导致海参中铝含量和甲醛超标。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在滩涂养蛏，不仅使用农药会破坏生物多样性，搭设防鸟网也会导致鸟类死亡。普林斯顿大学副研究员梁丹等新发表的一项研究发现，2021年4月和5月候鸟的春季迁徙高峰期，在福建兴化湾和浙江乐清湾两地，为养殖蛏子而架设的防鸟网困住了1.3万余只鸻鹬类候鸟，其中不乏国家重点保护的物种。课题组在浙江和福建的其他17个地点也发现了类似的防鸟网。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;梁丹告诉南方周末记者，上述两地滩涂专门养殖蛏苗，蛏苗一般从11月左右下苗，长到第二年3、4月份便可以收获。如果在3、4月蛏苗收获后立即拆除这些防鸟网，就可以拯救春季迁徙的上万只鸟类，也可避免部分防鸟网进入大海伤害海洋生物。但由于在滩涂拆网需较高的人工费，养殖户在售卖完蛏苗后仍将网继续留在滩涂上，等到6、7月让台风将网卷走。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;自然状态下，蛏子只是滨田湿地生物多样性的组成部分。在受到法律保护的天然滩涂湿地上开展增养殖，王松林认为，渔民得接受蛏子的高自然死亡率——被天敌捕食、与其他底栖动物竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但这很难。无论是蛏子还是海参，养殖过程使用有机磷、菊酯类农药等违禁化学品，都体现出养殖户的惯性思维：将自然滩涂和海岸带当作农田管理，把养殖产品当作单一类型的“农作物”。“我询问的一对打药回来的老夫妻，他们非常热情，直言海滩跟棉花田没有区别，要确保蛏子高产，就得用药打死其他鱼虾蟹贝，还得赶走长嘴的水鸟。”王松林说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;古语有云：“四月蛏肥美，莫负西施舌。”四月份是蛏子最肥美的时节，但却不是生态友好的食用时间。因为春、秋季节也是候鸟过境高峰期，减少天然滩涂湿地上的打药清滩、放炮驱鸟等人为活动干扰，对生态保护意义重大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如何解决这些矛盾，浙江省乐清市提倡使用船耕机、生石灰、漂白粉、晾晒等方法清滩清塘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;黄标武则建议养殖户回到池塘养殖的老方法。池塘养殖可以用生态友好的生石灰、中药材代替三唑磷清塘。池塘养蛏需要肥水，原理相当于庄稼施肥，池塘养蛏还可以利用其他鱼塘排放的尾水作为肥水，净化这些尾水中富含的氮、磷等有机质，变废为宝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;（刘明、李成为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄罗斯铝业公司创始人奥列格·德里帕斯卡：没有特斯拉汽车，大家还是会活下去的]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259777]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;文华东方酒店位于北京王府井大街，可以远眺故宫。2023年10月25日晚，在其五楼的豪华会议厅包厢里，俄罗斯铝业公司创始人奥列格·德里帕斯卡正在等待来访的媒体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡曾经是全球最大铝业公司的创始人。他在采访中自称是一名“苏联时期的物理学家”，早年毕业于莫斯科国立大学物理学系，苏联解体之后学术经费锐减，没有津贴和助学金，导致他无法继续物理研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;离开学校之后，他和同事们成立了一家贸易公司，从俄罗斯出口金属，之后他用赚来的第一桶金收购了俄罗斯第三大电解铝厂，这也成为他事业的起点。之后，通过资产合并的方式，他建立了全世界最大的铝业公司——俄罗斯铝业公司，这家企业2015年在香港上市，成为首个在中国上市的俄罗斯企业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年4月，美国对德里帕斯卡和其他23名俄罗斯富豪和官员实施制裁，他被列入了美国的特别指定国民名单（SDN）。进入这个名单之后，美国财政部下属的外国资产控制办公室会对其在美国司法管辖范围内的财产和财产权益进行冻结。美国公民和在美国境内的实体通常被禁止与SDN名单上的个人或实体进行任何形式的交易或业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份名单不仅影响到被列入的个人或实体，还影响到与他们有业务往来的第三方，与名单上的实体进行交易可能会导致违反美国的制裁法规，从而面临法律后果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡在俄乌冲突开始之后又遭到澳大利亚、加拿大、欧盟诸国、英国等多个国家制裁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fQStqglwidgSDAi5dVMiyvWSx6s8WSQcKTMpNnVC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1589&quot; height=&quot;1192&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fQStqglwidgSDAi5dVMiyvWSx6s8WSQcKTMpNnVC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;俄罗斯铝业大王奥列格·德里帕斯卡。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（周煜博/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你这次来中国的目的是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我是莫斯科国立罗蒙诺索夫大学董事会成员，我们在深圳参观了北理莫斯科大学，这是一所莫斯科国立罗蒙诺索夫大学和北京理工大学创办的联合大学。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们已经开办了一个国际商务学院，以及数学物理学院。之前，莫斯科大学办过一个国际班，大概二三十个不同国家的学生来到了莫大学习数学物理专业，其中30%是中国学生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俄罗斯的数学教育在全世界都是最好的，我们希望能够促进这样的学术交流。同时中国学生可以学俄语，俄罗斯学生可以学会中文。我们要投资于交通设施、金融设施，但是我们也要投资于科学教育，一些科学项目现在看起来不是很重要，但是二十年或者五十年之后，会成为人类社会发展的关键。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如何看待目前卢布的波动？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;卢布波动这个问题当然存在，因为我们现在有一个军事冲突，但是俄罗斯的结算平衡还是很强。只要未来两三年不出现某些很大的冲突，卢布波动就没有很大的问题，因为俄罗斯的资源产业还是挺好的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您在年初认为俄罗斯需要欢迎更多来自友好国家的投资，那么，促进中俄企业合作还有哪些事情可以做？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;第一，需要时间，两国之间的经济合作基础就是信任，我们已经有了信任基础。之前俄罗斯工业70%是靠欧洲的技术，现在还需要时间进行转型，改变我们的国家标准，和我们的友好国家进行合作。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有了问题就一定要及时解决，不要后来积重难返。包括我在内的企业家，之前都提出过这个问题，为什么俄罗斯对外贸易这么不平衡？80%来自欧洲，20%来自亚洲，我们需要找到一个平衡点。未来两三年内，我们会努力解决好之前一直没有解决的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，我们一定要投资于基础设施，不仅仅是物流设施，也包括金融平台。金融平台不仅仅是结算问题，两国已经学会了怎样进行本币结算，但是债务市场还没有得到我们想要的那些成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10年之前，俄罗斯汽车工业就开始说要做进口替代，但是他们并没有开始做，直到问题已经出现了才开始解决。5年、10年之前，我们都难以想象美国会这样做。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;美国对你的制裁是不是严重影响了你的生活？会影响你的心理吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;从心理方面来看，我觉得没有很大的影响。苏联时期，我曾在军队服过役，遇到过更加严峻的形势。从那时起，我对危险就有了另外一种态度和认识。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你为什么会被美国财政部制裁？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;2017年，我有一家公司在伦敦上市，成功吸引了20亿美元的投资，结果过了5个月，我和我的公司就被列入制裁清单。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们提到各种借口，但事实上并没有合法理由把我列入制裁名单上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个借口是在大连召开的达沃斯论坛上，我发表了一个演讲，提到建立东方统一能源市场，可我演讲真正的主题是要推动核能的发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时候铝价格上涨70%，投机者赚了很多钱。这表明，如果你不考虑到危险，寄望于良好的合作关系，早晚危险会变为现实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wySfdXOpFXcb8LK6lKyGfYeQo7MMy0kXzuUYlkpF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wySfdXOpFXcb8LK6lKyGfYeQo7MMy0kXzuUYlkpF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256470&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年10月19日，美国华盛顿特区，美国联邦调查局（FBI）搜查了奥列格·德里帕斯卡的几处房产。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;制裁会对您和家人的生活造成影响吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对我个人来说，没有任何的影响。从年轻的时候，我就没有很多物质上的需求。对其他人来说，特别如果是孩子在国外留学的话，影响还是挺大的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您算是很早就遭到了制裁，会有朋友来向你请教经验吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是的，我对于应对西方国家的制裁有很丰富的经验。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我的结论是，要投资一些不依赖西方金融系统的国家。假如哪个国家和美国之间发生极端冲突，没有人会遵守法律，这些不动产、项目都会被拿走。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当财产被拿走时，您感到难过吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;说实话，没有任何特别的感受，我不是一个很眷念物质的人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;如何才能不担心遭到制裁?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;如果没有独立自主，这永远是一个问题。如果仅仅是缺乏某些物资，五年十年时间，还是可以活下去的。我觉得全世界已经意识到了这种危险。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您说的独立自主是一种孤立主义吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;奥列格·德里帕斯卡：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当然不是。我们面临着全球性的问题，比如说是气候变化、贫困、疾病等等。但是，制裁不会促进某个国家的发展，只有国与国之间的信任，只有国与国之间的经济合作、互利共赢的发展，才可以解决好这些全球性的问题。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;难道西方制裁会让被制裁的国家改变自己的政策吗？不会的。没有特斯拉汽车，大家还是会活下去的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相反这些制裁会让我们重新去思考促进自己的发展，填补一些漏洞和缺点。比如促进交通物流的发展，完善我们的金融市场，以本币进行结算。我们要构建一个新的国际安全体系，新的国际关系体系，避免新的危机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之前的世界就是以西方为中心，就是所有的技术、所有的投资都是由西方国家最初决定的，也导致了许多地区冲突。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[不清楚孩子上了什么学，回家陪读三年仅是一次情感弥补？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259687]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在我办公的楼下，有一圈商铺，开着饭馆、小超市、蔬果店、早摊铺……周遭是工业园区，四周只有这一处商业地方，每到饭点和上下班，这里很热闹，这些商铺在很好地运营着。自从楼建起来，我就在这里办公，这些商铺也多是一开始就在这里经营的，于是我和很多商户都认识，常在买东西的时候和他们聊天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三年以前，楼下沙县小吃店的老板娘回福建给上高中的孩子陪读。最近，我到沙县小吃店吃东西时看见了她，便问：“陪读回来了？”她说：“回来了！”我又问：“孩子高考完考到了哪所大学？”她挠头，回答：“不知道！”我疑问了：“你整整给孩子陪读三年，三年后出成果了，你不知道你的成果是啥？”她还是摇头，说：“我真不知道……反正……好像是我们那边的……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过了两天，我又到一旁的小超市去买东西，经营小超市的是一对夫妻，他们是安徽人，男主人正在给女主人交待，不要忘记给孩子转生活费。我便提了一句：“孩子在上大学吗？”他们点头，说今年刚上大学。我继续问：“孩子在哪所大学？”男主人低头想，片刻，他说：“我也想不起来了。”我看往女主人，女主人说：“你不要问我，我也不知道……”男主人插话，“说是在成都……学什么设计……还是其他什么……”我不禁哑然，开玩笑说：“啥东西重要你俩都不知道！你俩只知道给孩子转生活费！”他们俩互相看着对方，没搞明白我在笑着说什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，多有夫妻双方或一方在外工作，孩子在家乡读书。夫妻有一方在外工作的，在家里的一方的生活便以孩子学业为重点，过着陪读的日子。夫妻二人都在外工作的，很多人会选择在一些重要的阶段、时刻，回去陪孩子读书，比如初三、高三等。这都是希望通过陪读，辅助孩子学习，从而考上理想的学校。但是，当我听到沙县小吃店的老板娘在陪孩子读了三年高中而不知孩子最终考上了什么大学的时候，我想，陪读的效力是值得商榷的，陪读或不陪读应该也就差不多，她所进行的三年陪读可能只是一次情感的弥补。当我又听到小超市的夫妇不知道孩子就读的院校和专业的时候，我在想，这似乎是旁人的事，这个大学教育的实质就是蒙着头转生活费，是不知所措的教育投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前天，我打电话给楼下的一个水站，请店家帮我送一桶桶装水。店家回应，送不了了，店里没人，孩子马上升高中了，老婆回家给孩子陪读去了，要水的话自己来拎。本来，我可以打电话给别的水站让送水，但有了前面两次的经历以及我的思考，我当即决定下楼拎水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我去水站，问店主：“你爱人为啥要回家陪读？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那人家都陪呢，咱也不可能不陪！”店主回答。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“回去陪读能干什么？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那还能干什么，做饭、洗衣服，监督孩子不要玩手机……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这样陪读有意思吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;店主哂笑：“那咱也不知道……都说现在高中难考……害怕上不了……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我自己不是搞教育的，但我觉得有一些基本智识的东西应该是相通的。我对店主说，你拿笔记，我给你说几点。我掰着指头告诉他：一、明确你孩子的学习目标，可以具体为想考哪所学校，去了解这个学校的招生计划、招生要求、成绩要求，你爱人陪读期间的陪读计划，要以招生要求、成绩要求为纲领；二、和学校老师保持紧密联系，掌握学校的学习进度和孩子的学习情况，及时解决可能出现的学习问题，该抓基础的问题要抓基础，该攻克的难题要攻克；三、你爱人自己要建立良好作息制度，督导孩子学习过程中劳逸结合，该学学、该休息休息，要孩子不玩手机，首先她要做到在孩子学习期间不玩手机；四、不要把你们的情感弥补当成道德标准来要求孩子，要鼓励孩子学习，但也要尊重孩子的学习意愿；五、对孩子的关怀是长期的，不是将来考上高中就完了，孩子是独立的，但是孩子的学习生活不是独立的，是你们一家人共同意愿的表达，是和你们每天的生活息息相关的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我说完了，店主也记完了，但他眨巴着眼睛，不知道听懂没听懂。我告诉他，下次我再来拎水的时候我们继续探讨。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;给孩子陪读，不只是洗衣、做饭，更不是自己坐在一旁玩手机然后要求孩子写作业、答模拟试卷那么轻松的活计。目标是什么，为达成目标做出的计划是什么，在实施计划的过程中如何纠偏，计划得以实现后怎么样做到长期情感互动，计划未实现时如何弥补等问题都应该是陪读父母要考量的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;楼下还有一家蔬果店，蔬果店的老板娘也是陪读回来不久，我问她：“孩子考得如何？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她回答：“考上了，但是学校不太好，孩子要复读一年。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我问：“复读这一年你不再去陪读了？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她说：“不陪了，陪够了，接下来这一年考得怎么样就凭他自己了，由他去吧！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到饭点了，工业园区的人们、楼上的人们都到楼下吃饭和消费了，商户们又忙碌起来了。看着忙忙碌碌的他们，想着他们背后的仍在求学的孩子，也不知道那些孩子都在哪些大学、高中或其他学习场所，只希望他们：身心健康、天天向上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为上海果品行业从业者）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目期待您的来稿。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[李佳琦直播间卖假和田玉？谈谈玉的文化、国标及科学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;网络主播李佳琦在被京东采购人员指责强制“二选一”、质疑涉嫌垄断后，职业打假人王海又质疑李佳琦直播间卖的和田玉为假货。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玉是中国独特的一种文化，华夏先民从各种石头中筛选出来的“石之美者”，玉温润莹泽、缜密坚韧，因此也被中国人认为有仁、义、智、勇、洁，五种品德，佩戴玉，有防妖避邪的作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国先民对玉的认识，最早要追溯到新石器时代。人类磨制石器当作砍砸、刮削的工具，用来狩猎、割肉。有些磨制的石器，呈现出光滑而漂亮的模样，人类开始对玉有了初步认识。这也标志着人类，开始从物质需求向精神需求转变。考古研究发现，新石器时代晚期，出现许多玉制品与玉饰品，这时的古人，已认识到玉与石完全不同的作用和美感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公元前3000年前后，玉器工艺从石器加工工艺中分离出来，成为独立的工艺门类。根据红山文化遗址和良渚文化遗址出土的玉器上留下的制作痕迹，专家们推断当时已经出现了一种能够旋转的玉器加工工具——砣机。这与我们现在所看到的加工玉石机器，在原理上已经没有差别。商周时期是中国玉器艺术的成长阶段，玉器使用范围扩大，数量和种类明显增多，但造型仍然很简单，只有零星纹饰。和田玉也是第一次出现在这个时代。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了春秋战国时期，玉雕艺术发展起来。当时的士大夫，全身都有一系列的玉佩饰。当时能体现时代精神的是大量龙、凤、虎形玉佩，造型复杂优美，具有浓厚的中国气派和民族特色。唐代玉器件件都是珍品，工艺进一步发展，琢磨精细，质地温润，光泽柔和，金玉互为衬托，富丽高雅。到了宋代，玉器逐渐进入老百姓的生活，受到当时书画的影响，风格趋于写实，富有生活气息。到了明清时期，玉器艺术达到顶峰，各类精致的玉器层出不穷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国历史上在用玉制度方面早已体现出真玉、非真玉的界定。和田玉是最高阶的玉，是真玉，帝王用玉。经过无数的岁月，和田玉方才走入民间。此次发生争议的就是和田玉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对王海质疑，李佳琦直播间的货主鸳鸯金楼晒出的鉴定证书，包括国家珠宝玉石质量监督检验中心（NGTC)、广东省金银珠宝检测中心有限公司、国家金银制品质量检验检测中心（南京）机构、深圳中地大珠宝检测有限公司。这些机构不可谓不权威，那么，问题出在哪里呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先是是否造假问题。根据王海的说法，GB/T38821-2020规定鉴定证书必须具有总质量和实物照片，而消费者收到项链附带的18份鉴定证书，不仅每张都是40g，而且是共用一张项链的照片，那么就涉嫌造假。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，造假的问题好解决，不好解决的是第二个层面的问题，也就是标准问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些机构使用的标准，是国家和田玉检测标准GB/T16552-2017与GB/T16553-2017。这个2017年的标准，未明确规定透闪石的具体含量，只要主要成分为透闪石，就能命名为“和田玉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王海采用的是另一个标准，即GB/T 38831-2020。2020年推出的GB/T38821-2020《和田玉鉴定与分类》，是由国家市场监督管理总局、中国国家标准化管理委员会发布的，是和田玉行业的最新国标。其中对和田玉的矿物成分描述为：“主要由透闪石组成，次要矿物可为阳起石，可含少量方解石、透辉石、石愚、黄铁矿、铬铁矿、磁铁矿、石英、蛇纹石、绿泥石、绿帘石、硅灰石、磷灰石和石榴石等”。根据这个标准，其命名规则是：同一件玉石中其他矿物百分比为5%以下时，可直接使用和田玉命名。其他矿物百分比为5%以上（墨玉除外）时，如所含其他矿物均匀分布，矿物颗粒界限清晰，使用“透闪石质玉”并附注说明含其他矿物的方式命名，例如：透闪石质玉（含碳酸盐）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，事情就很明白了。这两个标准业内都在用，2017年的标准更宽松，而2020年的标准更严格，但这个标准为非强制性，仅为推荐使用标准。卖玉的采取2017年推出的宽松标准，说自己的东西是和田玉；而打假的王海则采取了一个更严格的2020年标准，说李佳琦卖的玉是假货，不达标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;客观地说，玉这个东西，自古以来就很难辨个清楚。玉石到底是什么东西？其实很多人都不明白。我们说一个东西到底是什么，其实这是一个化学问题。化学是一门研究物质组成的学问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从化学的角度，玉石其实是一种混合物。我们谈到黄金，那么就是指黄金原子构成的物质；谈到石英，就是指二氧化硅；谈到冰，就是指一氧化二氢。当然，矿物都会混有其他杂质，但抽象意义上，这些东西都是由单一原子或单一化合物分子构成。但玉石，从抽象意义上就是一种混合物。打个比方，就像我们说中药汤、罗宋汤，哪怕抽象意义上的，必定是多种成分混合在一起的。所以，玉是一种混合物，是由两种或多种化合物、单质混合而成的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有了这个概念，就比较好认识玉了。玉石的化学成分不同，颜色会不一样，划分的种类不同。硬玉的化学成分是硅酸盐铝钠，其中最具代表性的是翡翠。软玉的化学成分是含水钙镁硅酸盐，其中最具代表性的是和田玉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;具体到和田玉，主要矿物成分有硅、铝、铁和镁四种。硅元素在和田玉中占比较大，主要形式有硅酸钙（CaSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;)、硅酸镁（MgSiO&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;）、二硅酸钠（Na&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;Si&lt;sub>;2&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>;5&lt;/sub>;)等；铝元素则主要以钠长石（NaAlSi&lt;sub>;3&lt;/sub>;O&lt;sub>;8&lt;/sub>;）的形式存在，同时也含有少量的硅酸铝；铁主要以硅铁铝酸钾和硅酸铁的形式存在。可见和田玉的成分非常多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;玉的魅力，观感、触觉上对人们的吸引力，就源于玉化学成分上的这个特点。这也造成了玉在命名、鉴别，乃至价格上的各种迷惑。有人说，李佳琦卖的玉，批发价只有几十块钱。不过话又说回来，那些旅游景区，珠宝店里上万的玉，批发价可能也只有几百块甚至更少。这就是玉这个行业的特征。古话说“黄金有价，玉无价”，并不是说黄金价值不如玉，玉是无价之宝，而是说，玉的价格从古至今，都很混乱，让人迷惑，往往利润畸高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李佳琦的直播间号称全网最低价，消费者相信了，不过他们的预期和现实有落差。其实，真正的要买到性价比高的玉，直播间不是一个好地方。要有懂行的人，带着仪器，才能鉴别，有了鉴别能力，才能谈到一个好价格。显然，多数消费者是做不到这一点的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[过度加工食物可能成瘾并严重影响健康]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259641]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCyJ69RpVgzEp0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/hEVw2oEow9miHUpCQ5S72i8Yf9OCy J69RpVgzEp0. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256141&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Over-processing of food refers to industrial production and the addition of at least 5 or more ingredients, additives (usually sugar, stabilizers, preservatives, preservatives, pigments), etc., in this way Processed foods are called ultra-processed foods. Their purpose is to make them delicious and convenient, and more importantly, manufacturers can earn higher profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excessively processed foods include soft drinks such as cola, bread, cakes, potato chips, pizza, biscuits, candies, burgers, instant noodles, ice cream, spicy sticks, etc. More and more research results show that the intake of overly processed foods may be harmful to human health and increase the risk of various diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;巴西研究人员最近的一项研究指出，过度加工食品可能损害大脑功能。 The reason is that overly processed foods contain many added and unhealthy ingredients such as sugar, salt, fat, artificial colors and preservatives. Past research has shown that overly processed foods are directly linked to an increased risk of heart disease, metabolic syndrome, and obesity, and now research is linking overly processed foods to a risk of decreased brain function. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers collected data on nearly 11,000 men and women in Brazil with an average age of 52 who participated in the Brazilian Longitudinal Study of Adult Health. The researchers followed them for a long time, with a median follow-up time of 8 years. The results found that participants who consumed more than 20% of their daily calories from ultra-processed foods experienced a 28% faster decline in overall cognitive function and a 25% faster decline in executive function compared to adults over 59 years old. In other words, the decline in cognitive function and executive function is more obvious among adults aged 35-59. Overall, overall cognitive functions include learning ability and memory, while executive functions include language fluency and behavioral agility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the researchers admit that they cannot yet explain the mechanism by which excessively processed foods lead to reduced brain function, and there is no neuroimaging to confirm their results. Therefore, future research is to explore which overly processed foods lead to cognitive decline in the body and the molecular mechanisms behind it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One possible explanation, however, is that when people regularly consume overly processed foods, they are less likely to get the fiber, microbes, minerals, and plants they need to stay healthy, fight off disease, and reduce inflammation. Nutrients. Ultimately, this may affect a person&#39;s brain function and functioning, as the brain requires a steady supply of these nutrients to function properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed foods have also been linked to cancer. Researchers from Imperial College London have found that high intakes of ultra-processed foods may increase an individual&#39;s risk of developing cancer and dying from cancer. Previously, a large number of studies have revealed that consuming large amounts of overly processed food will increase the incidence of obesity, type 2 diabetes, and cardiovascular disease. Now, British researchers have used the British Biobank to collect dietary information from 200,000 young people to study the relationship between body health and diet. This is the first such study to be conducted in the UK. The researchers monitored the people&#39;s health for 10 years, analyzing their risk of developing any cancer and 34 types of cancer, as well as the participants&#39; risk of dying from cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers conducted the most comprehensive assessment to date of the link between overly processed foods and people’s risk of developing cancer, including soda, industrially produced bread, and more. Ready-to-eat meals and most breakfast cereals. These foods often contain high levels of salt, sugar, fat, and artificial additives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that people who eat a lot of overly processed foods are at a greater risk of developing cancer. Overly processed foods are particularly related to ovarian cancer and brain cancer. They also increase an individual&#39;s risk of death from cancer, most obviously. of ovarian and breast cancer. For every 10% increase in a person&#39;s intake of overly processed foods in a person&#39;s diet, the overall risk of cancer increases by 2%, and the risk of ovarian cancer in particular increases by 19%. It is associated with a 6% increase in overall cancer mortality, a 16% increase in the risk of death from breast cancer, and a 30% increase in the risk of death from ovarian cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The association between excessively processed food intake and cancer remained after adjusting for social, economic, behavioral and dietary factors such as smoking, physical activity and body mass index (BMI). Furthermore, previous research has shown that British adults and children consume the highest amounts of ultra-processed food in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the study by British researchers cannot explain the causal relationship and mechanism between over-processed foods and cancer, they believe that existing research evidence shows that reducing the intake of over-processed foods in the daily diet may avoid Higher cancer rates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overly processed food has become widespread around the world and is addictive.美国、巴西和西班牙的研究人员2023年10月9日在《英国医学杂志》上发表的一份研究报告指出，对36个不同国家的281项研究的分析发现，全球有14%的成年人和12%的儿童对过度加工食物上瘾，还有1/7的成年人和1/8的儿童可能会对过度加工食品上瘾，这些食物包括冰淇淋、碳酸饮料和方便食品等，会导致癌症、肥胖和心脏病风险的增加。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the consumption of ultra-processed foods is soaring around the world, and now more than half of the daily energy intake in the UK comes from ultra-processed foods. In the United States, ultra-processed foods account for 58% of Americans’ energy intake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fact that so many people eat over-processed foods suggests that they are addictive. Researchers explain the addiction to over-processed foods as higher levels of dopamine secretion may lead to over-processed foods. of addiction. Extracellular dopamine levels in the brain&#39;s striatum caused by refined carbohydrates or fats are similar to those of addictive substances such as nicotine and alcohol, thus creating a craving similar to alcoholism.因此，含有大量精制碳水化合物或添加脂肪的食物很可能是一种上瘾物质。 The speed at which these overly processed foods deliver carbohydrates and fats to the intestines may also play a role in their addictive nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Symptoms of addiction to over-processed foods include: strong desire to eat, withdrawal symptoms, difficulty controlling food intake, and obesity, overeating, poor physical and mental health, and reduced quality of life. Despite this, he continued to eat without restraint. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All of this suggests that the relationship between overly processed foods and health, as well as the addictive nature of such foods, should be further studied, and appropriate measures should be taken to protect people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京香山论坛：大国小国，平等对话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 10:06:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;&#39;Ten&#39; means maturity, perfection, harvest, and also indicates a new starting point and renewal. Let’s go.” On the morning of October 30, 2023, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, told officials from the defense departments of many countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held from October 29th to 31st, reaching the highest level and largest scale in history - more than 90 official delegations from countries and international organizations participated, including 19 defense ministers , 14 military commander-level representatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the podium at the opening ceremony, the &quot;ten&quot; in &quot;The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum&quot; was painted in red. In the audience, foreign defense ministers, representatives of international institutions and experts are looking forward to an &quot;international security event&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. (Photo by Lu Huiqian/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/01/7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01 /7f3de5d43e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256571&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text -align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered a keynote speech. （吕慧乾/摄）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“大国扮演着更重要的角色”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;10月30日上午九点，北京国际会议中心二层主会场座无虚席。 Dozens of defense ministers and senior representatives from various countries in military uniforms sat in the front row of the auditorium; the back row was divided into two floors and filled with nearly a thousand experts, observers or media members. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Common Security, Lasting Peace&quot; is marked with white letters on a blue background inside and outside the venue - this is the theme of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum and the core idea of ​​the Global Security Initiative in February 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Youxia pointed out that without mutual respect, it will be difficult to coexist peacefully, and common security will be out of the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 19 defense ministers participating in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu was the first speaker. Before the opening ceremony, Shaoyigu and Zhang Youxia walked into the main venue side by side and sat in the center of the first row. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Russia-China relations are exemplary and are increasingly attractive to other countries.” Shoigu mentioned, “The circle of friends between Russia and China who do not want to be involved in the Western confrontation agenda is constantly expanding.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a country involved in the Russia-Ukraine conflict, Shoigu’s attendance attracted much attention. He mentioned that after Russia countered NATO&#39;s eastward expansion, the United States was using Ukraine to attack Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Russia will only use nuclear weapons when it is attacked by a nuclear attack or when its national survival is threatened.&quot; Shoigu said in his speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the second time that Shaoyigu has attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and delivered a keynote speech. The last time was in 2019. After the meeting, Zhang Youxia held talks with Shaoyigu at the Bayi Building in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/c2f75269a6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/c2f75269a6.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;256572&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu attended the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The speeches of the guests at the first plenary session all closely followed the theme of &quot;Responsibility of Major Powers and Global Security Cooperation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It is important to strive for peace. In promoting global peace and security, major powers play a more important role.&quot; ASEAN Secretary-General Gao Jinhong said in the second half of the first half that major powers promote peace and make war a Obsolete things. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“From Asia-Pacific to the Global”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A few days before the opening ceremony, defense ministers and representatives from various countries arrived in Beijing one after another.作为主办方，北京香山论坛秘书处副主任赵小卓忙得不可开交。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 21:00 on the evening of October 29, when Southern Weekend reporters met Zhao Xiaozhuo, he had just finished the welcome dinner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recalling the first forum, Zhao Xiaozhuo still has fresh memories. &quot;At that time, most of the participants were scholars, and the total number of participants was only a few dozen, so it was very small.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Beijing Xiangshan Forum was founded in 2006 and is hosted by two think tanks from the Chinese military, the China Society of Military Science and the China Society for International Strategic Studies. In 2014, the forum was upgraded from track two (private) to track one and a half (semi-official, semi-private). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Since then, military and political leaders and national leaders will appear every year, and the conference has been adjusted from once every two years to once a year.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Farewell to online meetings during the epidemic, the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum attracted official delegations from more than 90 countries and international organizations including Russia, the United States, Saudi Arabia, and Iran, with more than 1,800 participants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 9 forums, there have been as many as 6 forums with the theme of &quot;Asia-Pacific&quot;. With the major changes in the nature of the forum, the scope of topics has also expanded from Asia-Pacific affairs to global issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xinbo, Dean of the Institute of International Studies at Fudan University, is a frequent visitor to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. Since the first forum in 2006, he has attended the forum almost every year. He said, &quot;The theme of the forum is increasingly consistent with China&#39;s core concepts and basic principles of international security, and the topics of the sub-forums are also increasingly consistent with the current actual international security situation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; On October 30, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/e1fca366e3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 256573&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 30 On the same day, the first plenary session of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum was held. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 30, ten small closed-door seminars were held simultaneously, covering topics such as global security governance, artificial intelligence security, and Sino-US crisis management and control. &quot;It has never happened before that ten meetings can be held at the same time.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said, &quot;It is up to the participating representatives to choose which forum they want to go to, who they want to talk to, and how much they want to talk.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shi Chande, a researcher at the Institute for Defense Analyses and former deputy assistant secretary of defense, is an &quot;old friend&quot; of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum and a well-known &quot;China expert.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I pay attention to China every day, and my understanding here may be deeper than that of the United States.” He told Southern Weekend reporters with a smile before the “Northeast Asian Order” sub-forum. The United States first sent official representatives to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum in 2015. Four years later, in 2019, then-U.S. Assistant Secretary of Defense Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense Shi Chande led a team to attend the meeting. It was the first time that a current senior U.S. military official appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the early days, the U.S. delegation’s participation in the Beijing Xiangshan Forum was relatively low, and basically only the military attache from the embassy in China was sent to participate.” Wu Xinbo recalled that as the importance and influence of the forum increased, the United States began to start from domestic Send some mid-level delegations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Similar to the Shangri-La Summit and the Munich Security Conference, an official&#39;s rank determines his stage. This is a common international practice.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo said, &quot;After lower-level officials arrive, they are often only responsible for collecting information. Various opinions and information.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the U.S. military delegation was led by Owen Lewis, dean of the Joint Forces Staff College of the U.S. National Defense University; previously, the president of the U.S. National Defense University also led a delegation to Beijing Xiangshan Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, Carles, senior director for China affairs in the Office of the Deputy Secretary of Defense of the United States, took over the &quot;baton&quot; from the head of the delegation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The levels of Carles and Shi Chande are almost the same, but in terms of specific ranking, Shi Chande is higher.&quot; During the welcome dinner, Zhao Xiaozhuo specially analyzed the level setting of U.S. officials to the U.S. Navy Feng Dewei, vice president of the center, asked for advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Calles, the official leader of the US delegation at this forum, kept a low profile and rarely appeared in public. On the evening of October 30, she appeared at a small seminar on &quot;China-U.S. Crisis Management&quot;, but did not speak. She only briefly communicated with the participants after the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, &quot;the level of the participants in the forum is not the most important matter. The communication between the two parties focuses on the substantive content.&quot; Wu Qian, spokesperson of the Ministry of National Defense, pointed out at a press conference held before the opening of the forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;International Issues &quot;Desktop Collision&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 15:00 on October 29, half an hour before the official start of the meeting, the conference room with less than 100 people was packed with people from all over the world. Representatives, experts and media, etc. This is a dialogue titled &quot;China&#39;s Role in Maintaining Asia-Pacific Security.&quot; Under the chairmanship of Wu Xinbo, experts from China, the United States, Russia and South Korea took their seats in turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why can the Asia-Pacific maintain stability for thirty years?&quot; The host first asked the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fu Ying, a former Chinese diplomat, shared &quot;the reasons for the Asia-Pacific economic miracle&quot;: peace and stability, focus on regional cooperation and dialogue, and economic globalization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She gave data from the Bank of Asia, &quot;In the past 42 years, Asia&#39;s GDP has grown seven times. Nearly half of it was created by China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And the United States&#39; GDP has grown seven times. Michael Swan, chief director of the East Asia Project at the Western Institute of National Affairs, believes that &quot;the change of power between China and the United States will bring huge uncertainty to Asia. In the next 10 to 15 years, the process of peace and stability in Asia may be disrupted.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen&#39;s view was refuted by Fu Ying: &quot;Today, China is the driving force of the development miracle in the Asia-Pacific region, and the United States has also benefited greatly from it, but now this has become a problem?&quot; Fu Ying said, The United States has launched a &quot;China-US trade war&quot; that has more gains than losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen during the celebrity dialogue on October 29. (Photo by Yao Yijiang/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /01/67dc03f7ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256574&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the celebrity dialogue on October 29, Fu Ying refuted American scholar Shi Wen. (Photo by Yao Yijiang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, Russian expert Karaganov mentioned that &quot;Russia wants to create a peaceful and stable Eurasia and Asia-Pacific.&quot; Karaganov is the dean of the School of World Economics and International Affairs at the Russian State Higher University of Economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This scene better reflects the current international security situation.” After listening to the whole process, Zhao Xiaozhuo told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the &quot;Northeast Asia Security Trends and Shaping&quot; parallel forum on the afternoon of the 30th, explosive scenes took place one after another. American scholar Shi Wen and Director of the Asian and African Studies Department of the Japanese Defense Research Institute Masuda Masayuki were criticized by Chinese scholars one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The Northeast Asian issue depends on the interaction of multinational relations between China, Japan, the United States, and South Korea.” Shi Wen said. He was the third speaker at this forum, and there were also scholars from China, Russia, South Korea and the UK. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Wen flicked the tablet on the armrest of his seat, trying to regard the North Korean nuclear issue and the Taiwan issue as the same type of regional conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the moderator of the sub-forum, Vice President of the China Institute of International Strategic Studies, and retired major general Du Nongyi made his point clear, &quot;The core of the Taiwan issue is China&#39;s sovereignty and territorial integrity. It has nothing to do with North Korea.&quot; Nuclear issues and other issues cannot be compared with each other.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half, Japanese scholar Masuda Masayuki became the target of public criticism because he blamed China for regional security problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xuguang, senior adviser to the China Institute for International Strategic Studies, took the microphone and changed his original speech. He said that Masuda Masayuki was trying to teach the Chinese people &quot;a lesson&quot;. &quot;It is true that I am a little speechless.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xuguang pointed out that the crux of the problem between China and Japan is rooted in Japan&#39;s psychological imbalance, trying to regard the Sino-US game as a &quot;rare opportunity&quot; to take action, and constantly pointing fingers at the Taiwan issue. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the rebuttal, Masuda Masayuki sat on the stage and smiled awkwardly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let developing countries have a voice&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the international public opinion field dominated by European and American countries, the voices of developing countries are rarely heard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although it is a global village, every country has its own goals.&quot; At the &quot;Chinese and Foreign Young Officers and Scholars Seminar&quot; on October 29, Chief Executive Officer of the Pakistan Balochistan Research and Development Think Tank Official Jawariya Tareen said frankly. The young American scholar next to her had a serious expression. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For more than seventy years, the India-Pakistan border issue has remained unresolved, and Kashmir has always been like a thorn in the relationship between the two countries. Jawariya mentioned that every time Pakistan wanted to have dialogue, India did not respond positively, and the relationship between the two sides only stopped at the think tank level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Developing countries face two major problems, one is development and the other is security.&quot; Lieutenant General He Lei of the Chinese Academy of Military Sciences told Southern Weekend reporters that in a sense, developing countries are the most important problems in today&#39;s world. The security demands of the &quot;vulnerable groups&quot; should receive more attention and reasonable concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum, internationally renowned security forums include the Shangri-La Dialogue, the Halifax International Security Forum, the Munich Security Conference and the Seoul Defense Dialogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“These forums have obvious ‘circle’ attributes, and developing countries do not have much room to speak out.” Zhao Xiaozhuo mentioned that only the Beijing Xiangshan Forum clearly provides a stage for developing countries to fully express themselves. safety concerns and demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Representatives from various countries at the main venue (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;645&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/70713a9895.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;256575&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Main venue representatives of various countries. (Photo by Lu Huiqian)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters observed that among the parallel group meetings and seminars, 5 of them were themed on developing countries and the &quot;Global South&quot;, and more than half of the speakers were from the development community. Chinese home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Global South&quot; is not a new concept. The term was first used by American political activist Carl Oglesby as early as 1969. &quot;European and American countries are using the Global South to exclude China from developing countries and isolate China to the maximum extent.&quot; Zhao Xiaozhuo believes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;China occupies a very critical or even core position in the global South. China&#39;s success has become the most important driving force for the global South at the international level...China has been promoting peaceful development through the &#39;One Belt, One Road&#39; initiative, which can What is the United States doing?&quot; Zheng Yongnian, President&#39;s Chair Professor of the Chinese University of Hong Kong (Shenzhen), asked on the morning of October 29. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With concerns about the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, Selchuk Chorakkoglu, the founding director of the Asia-Pacific Research Center of Turkey, came to the Beijing Xiangshan Forum for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The Palestinian-Israeli conflict has caused nearly 10,000 deaths on both sides, and there are also hidden dangers of spillover.&quot; Selchuk told Southern Weekend reporters that he hopes to discuss how to discuss the &quot;new Middle East security architecture&quot; Providing new solutions to Palestine and Israel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Alessio Patalano has participated in the Shangri-La Dialogue in Singapore and the Xiangshan Forum in Beijing for many times. He believes that the Beijing Xiangshan Forum is more &quot;pragmatic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This professor at the Department of War Studies at King&#39;s College London is very talkative. As soon as the forum began, Alessio was interviewed for an hour by the media who came to ask for advice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He told Southern Weekend reporters that providing a platform for developing countries to speak out is one of the greatest advantages of the Beijing Xiangshan Forum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Defense ministers and representatives from various countries came to Beijing Xiangshan Forum with the vision of seeking peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Common security and lasting peace are the basis for the common development of all countries.” Itizal Khadim, director of the Afghanistan Development and Peace Research Center, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Afghanistan, Itizal is a former government official who is now a professor of modern political history. He joked to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;I came to the meeting wearing two &#39;hats.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;36 million people in Afghanistan are suffering from extreme poverty and hunger. &quot;Only by creating jobs for the people, they will not turn to war.&quot; Itizal hopes that China can participate in the reconstruction of Afghanistan. &quot;China can help developing countries promote economic and social development instead of distributing gunpowder.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend interns Liu Yaqi, Lin Xi, Jiang Lai, Xu Ziyi, Feng Jiayi, and Zhang Xinyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[地理学家段义孚的终生追问：我是谁？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-02 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4P4YXsf2grzoKpD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/FyAmY2a5xnUsNmhK7SrIbjSux4 P4YXsf2grzoKpD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (third from right) in his later years with friends. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu ended his autobiography &quot;Who Am I?&quot; with an encounter in middle age. 》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At night, he was driving on a narrow highway with only one car in front of him. He lacks confidence in his driving skills, so he uses the taillights of the car in front of him as a guide to gain a sense of safety and comfort. Suddenly the car flashed its right turn signal and turned into a country road. Visible to the naked eye, he was the only one driving on the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;So, only my own headlights are left to guide the way. This light can only illuminate a very small area. It is a short road, but this road, farther away, is swallowed up in darkness.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Tuan is a famous geographer and the founder of humanistic geography. One of the people. He intellectually understands the relationship between people and place and considers himself a cosmopolitan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《我是谁？ &quot; was written in 1999, when Duan Yifu was 69 years old, and mankind was about to enter the new millennium. He sees &quot;Who am I&quot; as the fashionable question at the dawn of the new millennium. This issue actually received increasing attention as early as the 1960s, &quot;In order to generate a solid sense of self, a person needs the past, not just the present and the future.&quot; It is worth mentioning that &quot;Silent Spring&quot; combined poetry and science in the 1960s to jointly examine the relationship between man and the environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu continued to think about it and wrote important works in the next twenty years. &quot;who I am? 》 is a good stage summary, showing sincere self-examination. He seems to be getting closer and closer to a location, but he is not sure when he will arrive, or even further away. The ideal position always changes with time, space and thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;657&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SVkiVqcpkw2hvdv2FgjXAyDfc1uGucKRsdL3ua19.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the early 1940s, Duan Yifu and his family were preparing to move from Chongqing to Australia. During the group photo, Yifu Duan (third from left) tried to squeeze away from his younger brother and stay close to his mother to gain more attention. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The world in his eyes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; is shrinking inward &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the beginning, Yifu Tuan quoted the words of Socrates: An unexamined life is not worth living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before middle age, Duan Yifu had never lived in any city for more than five years. After leaving China, he continued to move around until he moved to Minneapolis at the age of 38 and stopped to engage in academic work. Migration is inseparable from both my father&#39;s work and historical events. He believed he was rootless and &quot;born to examine himself.&quot; He never married and could not fully integrate into American society, and his identity issues were always there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He considers himself an optimist and &quot;often places the golden age in the future.&quot; He knows that he gained his confidence early, having been relatively unscathed by racism while living abroad, and that later in life he began to question its source. His various ways of dealing with the world are closely related to the events he has experienced and the environment in which he lives. The book reveals his own “sense of place”—emotions and judgments about specific places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his first interview at Indiana University in 1956, an Asian history professor was surprised by his family background. Duan Yifu recalled his childhood memories and was sure that the other party was not joking. According to what he heard, the Duan family was divided into two branches in modern times, both in Anhui. Duan Yifu&#39;s family belonged to the poor branch, and his father Duan Maolan relied on his uncle Duan Qirui from the Hefei branch to fully fund his studies at Nankai Middle School. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu was born in Tianjin. From the age of 7 to 10, he lived in a village on the outskirts of Chongqing due to the war. His family was financially distressed. The school is a single room belonging to a power station. The place smelled sour and rancid, and the fetid mud dragged at his shoes. He was disgusted and horrified. Occasionally he encountered a funeral procession, with the bodies of the guards wrapped in bamboo mats. There is a rooster tied to it, which will crow if the corpse is found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;765&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/a42uW12ui3saCtCc97TRtXR6MdCOCYDs53MZdFQq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256473&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1954, Yifu Duan conducted field research in Arizona, USA. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Small schools are different places, where students learn about the history, Culture and Technology. Wilde&#39;s work &quot;The Happy Prince&quot; left an indelible mark on him, and he knew: &quot;&#39;Good&#39; can no longer be limited to fulfilling social obligations.&quot; These realizations inspired Duan Yifu to think, and he was always exploring how to determine a person&#39;s position in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu mentioned some important historical figures in his narrative. Duan Maolan and his alumnus Zhou Enlai wrestled with each other&#39;s arms to test whether the other&#39;s injured arm was healed. Zhang Boling, the principal of Nankai Middle School, had a rare refrigerator and distributed trays of ice cubes to everyone. In order to save them for him, his father used the folk remedy of spreading salt to delay melting. The adults are still thinking about how to treat their distant relative Wang Jingwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu has conflicting emotions about his father. He longs for love, but is disappointed by his father&#39;s preference for his brothers; he remembers the tenderness of the difficult times, but is also traumatized by his father&#39;s severity or anger. The most profound memory of my father is even just a childhood nightmare, and the scene in the dream has remained for many years:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; &quot;I opened my arms and wanted to hug him... What happened? But a ghost stood in front of me. It could be seen that it was my father, but he was covered in mourning clothes. This ghost was in the ever-changing airflow It was moving in the middle, weightless. It was an evil ghost, a corpse, with yellow light in its empty eyes.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The impression his mother left on him was warm and tough. , it’s a pity that she passed away prematurely. At the same time, Duan Yifu became increasingly sensitive due to his physical condition, and he became very ill for a time. He confessed his cowardice and unwillingness to participate in social change activities. Even in the face of racism and rude boys who treat him as a &quot;little girl,&quot; he has no motivation to actively fight back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world in Duan Yifu&#39;s eyes is shrinking inward. When he was a child, he was exposed to all kinds of extraordinary events. When he grew up, the war ended and he had to face many personal problems. He summed up this growth experience as moving from the universe to the stove, and used beautiful writing to integrate life and academia. He quoted the words of the poet TS Eliot:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;All of us, in our lifetime, have heard and seen , why does everything you feel (a bird singing, a fish leaping, an old woman walking on a mountain road) be reproduced with emotion, but other things are not?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;935&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Tw2YMqSRtEFS7cvb8JlUSD8tgfDCDHTROGbmRzmD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256474&quot;>;Youth Yifu Tuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Are you willing to be a lonely captain&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Poetry can break through the barriers or boundaries of language logic.” Liu Su told Southern Weekly. He used this to describe the beautiful words written by Tuan Yifu. He translated &quot;Love Land Complex&quot; and &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;Two books by Yifu Tuan, and I am currently translating &quot;The Divided World and Self&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was a graduate student around 2010, Liu Su often suffered from having no books to read. Many times he was attracted by the ideas mentioned in the book, but could not find relevant Chinese or even English translations. He tried his best to find the original work, went to Douban to ask Douban friends who had read the book, and also went to the library, but he might only be able to make half a copy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I might as well translate it myself!&quot; Those experiences inspired Liu Su&#39;s enthusiasm. He thus embarked on the path of academic translation, and future college students will no longer face the dilemma of reading. At the same time, many scholars have also participated in the translation and introduction of geography classics. The Chinese translations of scholars such as Tuan Yifu and David Harvey are enough to be compiled into a collection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer of 2021, in the crowded Chongqing subway, Liu Su received a WeChat message from another translator Zhicheng, asking him if he was willing to translate &quot;Who Am I?&quot; 》。 Even though the air conditioning was sufficient, he still broke out in a hot sweat: &quot;This book will finally be translated into Chinese!&quot; He had seriously considered that he was not willing to live a lonely life as a &quot;foreigner&quot; in a foreign country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《我是谁？ ” resonated with Liu Su’s heart. He experienced a long single life. When he got married, the children of his classmates were almost in junior high school. He may have experienced Duan Yifu&#39;s loneliness and his self-statement: &quot;I spent a lot of time in poems and essays about the sadness of spring and autumn, and spent them in places like libraries and coffee shops.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su finished class, said goodbye to the students, and went to the library for a while after walking out of the teaching building. Even if I don’t write anything, I would still like to sit in the corner and experience what Yifu Duan said: “Living on campus almost all my life, surrounded by young people, makes me feel happy physically and mentally.” He sometimes goes to a nearby coffee shop and sits by the window, looking at the pedestrians, vehicles and street lights, feeling that loneliness is far away. The sensibility of exquisite language gathers together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1998, Yi-Fu Tuan wrote &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;The previous year&#39;s work &quot;Escapism&quot; asked: What is the greatest escape? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When you lower your head and manage the environment around you with a heart that loves your neighbor, you can also look up at the vast starry sky.&quot; Liu Su talked about his understanding of this sentence and added a more realistic side, &quot;As a scholar, like him, I often look up at the starry sky of metaphysical thoughts and theories. However, whenever I look down at my single life, I often feel like I&#39;m in a mess.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot; 1536&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yuiWuAjVdL0ED9wFpbkVeQPFe5CYTThcg7YkL6fW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Duan Yifu (1930-2022), an internationally renowned Chinese geographer, was born in Tianjin and graduated from Oxford University. He returned to China in his later years. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su is looking for descriptions of single life in books. Yifu Tuan made his apartment simple and warm, dressed modestly and appropriately, maintained good health and longevity, had good interpersonal relationships, and gained precious friendships. However, &quot;he once dreamed that he died alone at home, and no one found his rotting body.&quot; Duan Yifu always writes about his loneliness, a complicated feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Perhaps the reason is that loneliness is the most authentic way of human existence. The state of not being lonely is actually the product of escape.&quot; Liu Su quoted the saying of &quot;Escapism&quot;. There are three questions surrounding Yifu Duan&#39;s life: &quot;I am mortal&quot; that has lingered since childhood; &quot;Who am I&quot; related to individual consciousness; and &quot;What is a good life&quot;. Yifu Tuan wrote &quot;Geography saved me&quot;. Geography was like a road that led him to understand himself and the problems of human life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Translation of &quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot; also allowed Liu Su to gain &quot;a friendship worth cherishing.&quot; After the book launch, he, Zhi Cheng, editors and readers friends braved the heavy rain and went into a noodle shop to chat. Five people each signed five books and kept them. He also wanted to write his feelings into a longer email and share it with Duan Yifu. Before the email was finished, Duan Yifu passed away in August 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tuan Yifu published a new book that year, and finally wrote: &quot;I would like to advise you again, young traveler! You must be full of courage to operate your own ship like a captain, even though it is only Life&#39;s puzzling clues and stars serve as your guide.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Su was devastated by his mistake, but would continue to translate classics of humanistic geography. He also asked himself if he was willing to be a lonely captain and walk on a narrow road. No matter what the answer is, Tuan Yifu&#39;s book &quot;will always be projected into the heart of every reader.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Where is the real home&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Duan Yifu recalled in the preface of &quot;Going Home&quot; that people often asked him where he thought the real hometown was. . He answered lightly: &quot;In general, it&#39;s the earth.&quot; &quot;Where on earth is it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Then, the meaning of the question is probably: there must be a place where he is most comfortable, The most yearning, can form the deepest sense of belonging. &quot;Some specific landscapes do have great appeal to me, such as a landscape that transcends aesthetics - the desert. I feel that I am very close to the desert psychologically, and I can even regard it as my home.&quot; Yifu Duan again and again Once I wrote about my love for the desert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in the winter of 1954, Yifu Tuan was conducting field research for his doctoral thesis in southeastern Arizona. The research object was the desert terrain called the foothill erosion surface. When optimistic British student David Harris joins the group, the physical and spiritual hardships of the wilderness thin out and are gradually replaced by friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This relationship brings me satisfaction, but it also causes insecurity—almost all relationships of any depth involve both. Why? Is there something wrong with me? ?&quot; Duan Yifu asked in the book. In 1962, they collaborated again. He remained single and became a teacher; David married and had two daughters. &quot;The David today is a broader, more elusive personality than I knew before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following description is sensitive and stinging, and such feelings appear repeatedly in the book . They each drove to Chaco Canyon to investigate, with Yifu Duan leading the way and David&#39;s family following behind. At dusk, maybe David knew the route, maybe the children needed care, David&#39;s car honked, kicked up dust and drove ahead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;The distance between us became wider and wider, and soon, all that was left in front of my eyes was the raised The dust was gone, and in the end, even the dust was gone. I fell into a lonely shadow... When I tried to catch up with the Harris family, I felt lonely and painful for the first time. What&#39;s worse, I I even feel ridiculous. What on earth was I doing on a dirt road in New Mexico? Chasing a young family in a car?&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yifu Tuan&#39;s eyes, friendship must meet two basic requirements: The conditions—like-mindedness and sympathy—should be balanced in an ideal friendship. &quot;If overly oriented toward shared interests and interests, these two people may become more like colleagues than friends; conversely, they may be more like lovers, staring into each other&#39;s eyes rather than into the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Shy people, unsociable people, or people like me who have their social needs suppressed by eccentric pursuits, perhaps should devote themselves to Nature...maybe only by staying in an inorganic environment, such as deserts and icebergs, can people feel relaxed and happy, and forget the good and the bad.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi-fu Duan also wrote about the German Alexander von Humboldt. Humboldt was the founder of modern physical geography. He “made outstanding contributions to the development of geodesy and was the first to use painting and poetry to develop human geographical experience-feelings, emotions and concepts, which are the core of humanities. The starting point of socialist geography”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humboldt lived to be 90 years old and was full of energy throughout his life. In his sixties, he could still travel through Siberia and Central Asia. He enjoys socializing, but has never been married, and has been trapped in emotional entanglements with men three times. He wrote in a letter to the married soldier Reinhard von Haften: &quot;Even if you reject me and look at me coldly, like a stain, I still want to be with you. ...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If I leave the universe, or to be precise, leave the harmony of nature and the joy brought by human beings&#39; ultimate achievements, my life will become miserable and I will not be able to survive.&quot; Yifu Duan listed He felt all kinds of human misery, &quot;But, I don&#39;t want to stay in those shadows for a long time...&quot; He believed in the light, the beauty of the universe, and the beauty and kindness of events. The next chapter is &quot;Geography Saved Me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, taking the opportunity of attending an architectural conference, Yi-Fu Tuan returned to China after 60 years of absence and deliberately stayed for a while. He wrote a book called &quot;Going Home&quot;, which was translated into Chinese by Zhicheng. During the trip to Chongqing, he once again mentioned the nightmare that had plagued him throughout his life. When his father passed away in Taipei in 1980, he did not go back to see him for the last time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The end of the autobiography is the contrast between the dim light of the car lights and the vast darkness. That is not despair. Duan Yifu is still looking at himself. He asked the translator to attach his speech notes in 2012 as an updated understanding of &quot;who I am.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are no so-called ordinary people in the world. The people you talk to every day are actually people with immortal souls... They joke with us, work together, and get married, but they are also ignored and exploited by us. All people are actually people with immortal souls. Among these people, some are immortal and terrifying, and some are immortal and brilliant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Maybe it has been too long, he I really forgot&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Who am I?&quot; &quot;Yu Shiyi, the editor of &quot;WeChat,&quot; appeared somewhat silent - just like when communicating with text on WeChat - but soon opened up the situation, became talkative and humorous. His daily schedule was very regular and he even added a short period of time that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later he added that he should not talk too much about his own story, and autobiographers should be given more space. So, this part is an extra chapter of this article. People are always faced with questions such as &quot;Who am I?&quot; The questions and answers constantly change with the situation, each covered with attractive colors. For example, the great director Bergman claimed that he knew less about himself than he did ten years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi has unique feelings about discrete events. In early 1949, the Taiping shipwreck occurred in the waters west of Daishan Island where he was born. When he was a child, he had no idea about this tragedy. He only learned about it through documentaries when he left his hometown to attend college. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1950, approximately 125,000 young men, soldiers, and 25,000 civilian personnel and civilians moved to Taiwan from Zhoushan, later forming the first generation of Zhoushan people of 20,000 to 30,000 people. The initiators of Taiwan’s Veterans Return Movement in 1987 were Zhoushan people. Before the “Three Direct Links”, it was very difficult for them to contact their homeland. The local historical materials exhibition hall uses an entire wall to display letters forwarded by the Red Cross at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Islands shape cognition. Yu Shiyi left Zhoushan for Ningbo ten years ago, and then went to Shanghai to study. When I was growing up, there was no cross-sea bridge in Zhoushan. When a typhoon came, the island became an isolated island, physically and psychologically isolated from the rest of the world. Compared to county towns, provincial towns, and cities, visitors from small islands seem to be “small” and marginal. At first he longed to merge from the margins into the mainstream, but now he wants to have subjectivity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“As an immigrant, your regional identity is the first thing that is mentioned when you arrive in a new environment.” Yu Shiyi has a friend who was born in Hubei and grew up in Shenzhen, and later moved to Shanghai. He asked: What is the local accent of “other”? In 1973, 43-year-old Yifu Duan officially became a U.S. citizen. He has been living in the United States for nearly two decades, debugging himself as a &quot;cosmopolitan and a thinker writing about discrete subjects.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also the little grandpa - my grandfather&#39;s younger brother - talking about the past during the Chinese New Year. He claimed that he once drove a simple diesel-powered boat from Qushan Island to Dongjiadu, Shanghai, in one night. Alone, without a GPS, all I have is experience and a compass. Yu Shiyi could not imagine the plight of the fishermen. Wouldn&#39;t they be scared if they were wandering around without land? He wrote down his boundless imagination in his notes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The lanky man drove a small sampan from the island Set off and drive northwest, through night and day, to Dongjiadu. The lighting system at that time was not perfect, and there was no positioning system. Some waterways were almost dark at night, but he arrived at his destination safely without saying a word about the wind and waves he encountered. I think maybe too much time has passed and he has long forgotten the ups and downs along the way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I remember that there is a famous lighthouse on Flower and Bird Island. I wonder if he passed by it. Under certain conditions, There will also be the wonder of the fluorescent sea. I always feel that the waterway from my hometown to Shanghai is full of mysterious powers. I once took a ferry from the island to Shanghai. I landed ashore at dusk and landed at dawn. It was the first time I saw the waves gurgling like spring water and seagulls soaring in the sky. Looking out from the small round glass of the third-class cabin, there are faint lights. Maybe I have seen the lighthouse of Flower and Bird Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I asked the tribesmen, have you gone ashore? He said he had unloaded the goods but did not go up. I was so sorry. I wanted to get the secrets of Shanghai in the 1980s from him, but he said, it’s nothing. The Bund is just across the Dongjia Ferry Road. I can’t understand those Western things. At that time, everything could be bought by ticket, and the people were people on the water. , naturally cannot be obtained. He drove the sampan up the Huangpu River and finally reached Jiangyin. This was undoubtedly an adventure. As for what to do there and how to get back to the island, he stopped talking without saying a few words. Maybe it&#39;s been too long and he really forgot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Memories and narratives form fragments one after another, embedded in life. More than thirty years after my grandfather left Shanghai, Yu Shiyi also arrived in Shanghai. During the National Day holiday in 2022, he took a boat to the island with his father. The father was hesitant at first, after all, the house was no longer theirs. Many places are different. Old houses and new ones are popping up one after another. Fortunately, the road remains where it is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Shiyi returned to the lane where he was born. The commercial house he bought more than 20 years ago was still there, but it was older. The back door was open, he went in and saw the washboard from many years ago. After all these years, it&#39;s still there, like a miracle. There was someone living nearby, and he was too embarrassed to disturb him, so he just wanted to go to the front door to take a look. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the resident saw the stranger, he became alert and asked: &quot;Who are you?&quot; Yu Shiyi was stunned, silent for a few seconds, and instinctively replied: &quot;This is my home.&quot; He walked to the front door and took a photo Teru then left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You have become the &#39;other&#39;.&quot; He recalled, &quot;There are physical things, and it used to be my home.&quot; He didn&#39;t know how many hands the house had changed. I felt relieved that I could finally say goodbye. For almost twenty years, he always thought of this home, worried about it, and was afraid it would be demolished. Now all the playmates and neighbors have left, leaving only photos and washboards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The recognition and memory of your hometown, in turn, become the means for others to identify you. Not long after being asked &quot;Who are you?&quot;, in December 2022, Yu Shiyi took over &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;, the book will be launched at the Shanghai Book Fair in August 2023. The above is always a bit of an unexpected fate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>