<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[欧洲公厕为什么很少且收费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258137]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Toilet may seem like a small thing, but it is also a necessity of society. In many cases, it can reflect the history and present of a society. , China and foreign countries are no exception. Everyone who has traveled to Europe will have experienced the toilet dilemma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are generally very few public toilets in European countries, and it is often only possible to find one within a few kilometers, so there are apps for finding toilets in Europe. In contrast, in China, the function of finding toilets is covered by map apps. It is not a popular feature and cannot support an APP alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being cheap, toilets in Europe also charge a fee. In many European countries, such as the United Kingdom, the Netherlands, Germany and other places, you have to pay to use public toilets. For example, most of the toilets in high-speed service areas or shopping malls in Germany have to pay. Even the toilets in fast food restaurants, shopping malls, train stations, McDonald&#39;s, and KFC are charged. For example, in Cologne, Germany, there is a fee for using the toilets inside McDonald&#39;s. For another example, a KFC in Poland posted a notice: The restrooms in the store are only available to customers. People without consumption receipts need to pay 30 zloty (approximately 53 yuan) if they want to use the restroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also various forms of charging. There is a person sitting at the door to collect the fee, there is a gate that rotates after a coin is inserted, and some are trustworthy and put a tip tray. In some stores, the toilet door has a password, and the password is printed on the shopping receipt. Not every floor of German department stores has restrooms. They are usually located near the restaurant floor on the top floor. Using the restrooms is generally free, but if there are cleaners there, a tip of about 0.3 euros is usually required. If you are in a tourist area, we will also thoughtfully provide exchange rate conversion, and prices are clearly marked in each country&#39;s currency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The charges for European toilets are not cheap. The last trip to the toilet costs as little as 0.3 Euros and as much as 2 Euros. 1 euro is equivalent to 7.7 yuan, which is equivalent to between 2 yuan and 15 yuan. Even if the income is higher, going to the toilet in Europe is really not cheap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the richest regions in the world, Europe is also a region with the most complete &quot;social welfare&quot;. Why are there so few free public toilets? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it’s because of history. In many European cities, such as London, England, Stockholm, Sweden, and Paris, France, there are semi-open open-air toilets on the streets. It wraps the lower body but can only be used by men. These open-air urinals are used very frequently in the local area. This strange street urinal has been around in Europe for nearly 200 years. This also reflects the historical origin of the lack of public toilets in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result of this historical path, people may not regard public toilets as a government obligation. In fact, public toilets in many places in Europe are basically privatized. In this case, solve the problem according to market thinking. Toilets require regular maintenance and repairs, and you also need to hire someone to clean them. Most European countries are developed countries, and labor costs are high. This has resulted in high maintenance costs for toilets. Businesses are unwilling to include it in a package of services, but charge separately. supply. Private toilets in European cafes, small bars and other commercial places assume some functions of public toilets. Of course, you must consume food first and then use the toilet. Europeans are also accustomed to paying to use public toilets, or go to a coffee shop to buy a cup of coffee to solve their internal problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation in European countries is not exactly the same. In Denmark, which has high taxes and high welfare, the government believes that the freedom to use public toilets is a public service that the government must meet. Therefore, in the urban area of ​​Copenhagen, the capital city with a small population, there are sufficient public toilets, good environment, and they are free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Chinese toilets also used to charge fees. From the late 1970s to the late 1980s, as the economy developed, cities in China began to build higher-grade public toilets one after another, implementing water flushing and mechanical pumping. As the level of public toilets has improved, the cost has also increased. Some cities have begun to charge for public toilets to alleviate the shortage of funds for public toilet construction and management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the 20th century, with the further development of the economy, Chinese people began to have higher requirements for toilets. New residential areas were built, and toilets were increased from one to two bathrooms. However, public toilets are not free so early. In mid-tier cities like Qingdao, public toilets were not open for free until May 1, 2008, which is only 15 years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Free public toilets, after all, the government has money. After years of accumulation of reform and opening up, especially after joining the WTO, the economy has developed rapidly, real estate has taken off, and local governments have obtained sufficient funds from land finance, so they are able to bear the entire cost of public toilets. Therefore, free public toilets in China are mainly the result of economic development. Whether to charge or not is closely related to the economic situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Toilet charges are essentially a matter of government revenue and the scope of government public services. If the situation of public toilets in Europe is very bad, it is because of historical, cultural and customary reasons. Society has also developed various alternative forms and people have adapted to them. In some countries, the benefit of free public toilets has never appeared, and naturally it is not felt much. But if you return from free to paid again, you will have a different perception. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[粉黛花海迷人眼丨指尖华夏⑧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257591]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is the golden autumn, and Naluhua is in Wanfenglin Street, Xingyi City, Qianxinan Guizhou Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province Domestic pink grass has entered its best viewing period, and the sea of ​​flowers is like a &quot;pink ocean&quot;, attracting tourists to come to watch, play and take photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DEiE0219q1U3AkwUsCgItxHTBfduJWFzvK0ruMxK.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/DEiE0219q1U3AkwUsCgItxHTBfduJWFzvK0ruMxK.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists play among the Nalu flowers and flowers in Wanfenglin Street, Xingyi City, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/xf3YOtuf3TUEUzNQWh295QekijZcfkOndJ8KQlRF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;772&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/xf3YOtuf3TUEUzNQWh295QekijZcfkOndJ8KQlRF.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/fhT2Gp9moi1hgnhqU006KeqZ2UXgYspsjY6TyCcc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;713&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/fhT2Gp9moi1hgnhqU006KeqZ2UXgYspsjY6TyCcc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Guizhou Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/h92oyYkyXDZ2Cfz0qFPWsahzUBDu7KGp5zwBkUDu.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1266&quot; height=&quot;752&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/h92oyYkyXDZ2Cfz0qFPWsahzUBDu7KGp5zwBkUDu.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/25/5jB7nm7vSqneKfW1krlUrnG0zfcitKNrxyupmk3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/25/5jB7nm7vSqneKfW1krlUrnG0zfcitKNrxyupmk3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tourists in Xingyi, Qianxinan Buyi and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, Guizhou Province In Wanfenglin Street of the city, there are flowers, sea flowers, pink flowers and flowers playing in the grass. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Ye Shunqiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 15:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[济南城投公司一次性售1341套现房，房从哪来？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258138]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国女篮夺冠，带妆打球的李梦砍下全场最高分]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258154]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/9Ybm20M4OciGBen6wKO9BuY6uLwbmNJORLc4inaX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/9Ybm20M4OciGBen6wKO9BuY6uLwbmNJORL c4inaX. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253083&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, in the women&#39;s final of the basketball event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, China The team defeated the Japanese team 74-72 and won the championship. Chinese team player Li Meng won the gold medal at the award ceremony &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 5, 2023, Hangzhou Asian Games In the women&#39;s basketball final of the Asian Games, Wang Siyu scored a layup in the last 10 seconds. The Chinese women&#39;s basketball team defeated the Japanese women&#39;s basketball team with a score of 74-72 and successfully defended the Asian Games women&#39;s basketball championship. This is also the seventh time that the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team has won the Asian Games gold medal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this fierce duel, Wang Siyu scored 14 points, Li Meng 17 points, Li Yueru 13 points and 9 rebounds, and Han Xu scored 10 points and 8 rebounds. After the game, Li Meng, who was once called the &quot;main scorer&quot; by Yao Ming, became a hot topic because of his makeup and brave play style. She wrote on her personal social media, &quot;This year is a year of harvest. I keep challenging and making breakthroughs. Basketball will always be my love and pursuit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the 28-year-old Li Meng, this is off the court. A year of constant turmoil is also a year of full harvest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days before the women&#39;s basketball finals, the Women&#39;s National Basketball League (WNBA) officially announced the league&#39;s best rookie lineup. Li Meng, who played for the Washington Mystics last season, was selected. In this regard, she said in an interview, &quot;Thank you everyone for your recognition of me. It is not easy for everyone to recognize your ability in a foreign country. This is also a preliminary goal achieved. As I said, I am satisfied and adjusted. Have a good attitude and leave the rest to time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/nVE3Hvb9Zav9UdVjRfon5E64p8ZlBJl1RgUhmvN5.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/nVE3Hvb9Zav9UdVjRfon5E64p8ZlBJl1RgUhmvN5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253081&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 11, 2023, in Seattle, USA, during the 2023 WNBA regular season, the Washington Mystics defeated the Seattle Storm 71-65. Washington Mystics player Li Meng (left) broke through in the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2023, Li Meng officially Joined the WNBA team Washington Mystics and became the ninth women&#39;s basketball national player in history to land in the WNBA. Among the current Chinese women’s basketball players, four players including Han Xu, Li Yueru, Yang Liwei, and Li Meng have realized their WNBA dreams. As early as 2019, the Minnesota Lynx offered an olive branch to Li Meng, but because the national team still had a series of games at that time, she ultimately gave up the opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Washington Mystics official website recorded Li Meng’s outstanding performance in 34 games in his first season in the WNBA: averaging 5.6 points, 1.1 rebounds and 1.0 assists per game. As a player from China, Li Meng leads all rookies in three-point shooting percentage, hitting a total of 44 three-pointers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Washington Mystics general manager Mike Thibault said of Li Meng: &quot;She is the leading scorer of the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team and an excellent outside player who has the ability to help the ball with her excellent three-pointers. The team opens up the space.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Same words were said by Yao Ming, chairman of the Chinese Basketball Association and former NBA superstar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/P1tI2RAa6wA6jgwdOPgOOw0Wp8gUNSGI97O58L3H.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/P1tI2RAa6wA6jgwdOPgOOw0Wp8gUNSGI97O58L3H.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253084&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, in the women’s final of the basketball event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese team player Li Meng (front right) shot a shot during the game&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2022 Women&#39;s Basketball World Cup, Li Meng averaged 16 points per game and was the highest scorer on the team, although she ended up missing due to illness. Able to participate in the semi-finals and finals, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team still won the silver medal. Yao Ming said in an interview after the game, &quot;The results achieved this time can be said to exceed expectations, but the growth of a team certainly does not happen overnight. In fact, many people on the team began to emerge 10 years ago, such as the main scorer. Li Meng already achieved good results when he participated in the World Youth Championship in the National Youth Team.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Meng started playing basketball at the age of 5. At first, he was rejected by the coach because he was too young and was difficult to coach. At her mother&#39;s insistence, she started practicing dribbling on the sidelines. There is a competitive side to her character. She could not grab the ball from the coach&#39;s hand. After being pointed out, she dared to &quot;fall to the ground and grab it&quot; and she actually hit the ball. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/ST1n4DyBXt93N6XobeOyOo1g3u4AHmZt4G1mcNti.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/ST1n4DyBXt93N6XobeOyOo1g3u4AHmZt4G1mcNti.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253082&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, in the women&#39;s final of the basketball event at the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese team player Li Meng (left) communicated with teammate Han Xu&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 5, she didn’t know what basketball could bring to herself, she just thought it was fun. &quot;But when you get in touch with it slowly, you like it and it turns into love, and it continues to this day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2010, young Li Meng became a blockbuster at the U17 Youth World Cup Basketball Tournament. At that time, the Chinese team finished third, and at the age of 15, she won the tournament&#39;s Most Valuable Player (MVP) title by averaging 15.4 points and 6.2 rebounds per game, becoming the first player in Chinese history to win this honor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no smooth road. Li Meng, who has just emerged, has been plagued by injuries from ruptured anterior cruciate ligaments in both legs. Injuries have always been a problem that every athlete has to overcome, but for the teenage Li Meng, it was indeed a solid blow. &quot;Actually, it was okay after the first injury, but after the second injury, I started to think about whether this path would not be suitable for me.&quot; She told her mother that she wanted to go to school, but the coach felt it was a pity and rushed Come to persuade. After months of arduous recovery, she was able to return to competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2012 to 2013, Li Meng landed in the WCBA. In his rookie season, he averaged 14.7 points, 3.9 rebounds and 1.5 assists per game, and was awarded the Rookie of the Year. In the following years, she was always the top scorer in the WCBA. However, due to her personal characteristics of strong offense and weak defense, she missed the 12-man national team roster led by Maher and missed the 2016 Rio Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/B2KEJKf7PkXLw1WLrhShsBHJDFvy3Wu6Vv61me5s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;632&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/B2KEJKf7PkXLw1WLrhShsBHJDFvy3Wu6Vv61me5s.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253079&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 1, 2022, in the 2022 Women&#39;s Basketball World Cup finals in Sydney, Australia, the Chinese team lost to the United States and won the runner-up. Chinese team player Li Meng took photos with fans after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the reason why Li Meng was eliminated, he was still a football player at the time Xu Limin, the team&#39;s assistant coach, explained, &quot;Because of Li Meng&#39;s defense (weakness), she was eliminated at the last minute of the Rio Olympic selection, which was a huge blow to her.&quot; Xu Limin was later promoted to the head coach of the women&#39;s basketball team. He specifically approached Li Meng to emphasize the defensive issue, &quot;If you want to be the world&#39;s top athlete, you must be both offensive and defensive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Meng took this advice to heart. By the time of the Tokyo Olympics, she had become an indispensable main player of the women&#39;s basketball team. She said, &quot;In the past, my physical strength may have been 50% on offense and defense, but now my physical strength on defense can reach 80%.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because With her outstanding physical fitness and all-round performance on the court, Li Meng is called the &quot;LeBron Dream&quot; by fans, and LeBron James has been her idol for many years. &quot;His professionalism, technology, leadership, and psychological quality, He is a role model among players and I have been learning from him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/z3MVMri8BnHbR8sfbwcAdzgTJyMnaK6oKafkG00P. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/z3MVMri8BnHbR8sfbwcAdzgTJyMnaK6oKafkG00P.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;253080&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 2, 2023, in the 2023 Women&#39;s Basketball Asian Cup finals held in Sydney, Australia, the Chinese team won Defeated Japan 73-71 and won the championship. Chinese team player Li Meng (right) makes a layup during the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months ago, the Asian Cup final , it was still the Chinese team against the Japanese team, and the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team also won the championship with a two-point advantage, returning to the top of Asia. This is also the first time that the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team has won the Asian Cup after 12 years. Li Meng also contributed important goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At several important moments in Li Meng&#39;s 2023, she mentioned &quot;Always be the best version of yourself and never give up.&quot; We have reason to believe that she will uphold this belief and lead the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team to face the Paris Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(Reference materials: The Paper, Xinhua News Agency, China News Service, Beijing News, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国女篮最后时刻两分反超日本夺得亚运会冠军]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258156]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Li Yuan dribbled the ball through during the game .&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/b0f6860047.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/b0f6860047.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253085&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align : center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Li Yuan made a breakthrough with the ball during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 5, 2023, in the Asian Games women’s basketball final held at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center, the Chinese team played against the Japanese team. With only 13 seconds left in the game, the Japanese team tied the score with a three-pointer; then, the Chinese team successfully seized the last opportunity to attack, used a fast break to take the lead again, and won the last-minute defensive rebound. With a score of 74:72, they successfully defended the Asian Games women&#39;s basketball championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball players stood on the podium.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/06/f77a36a586.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06 /f77a36a586.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253086&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, the Chinese woman stood on the podium Basketball players. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, after the game, the head coach of the Chinese team Zheng Wei was surrounded by the women&#39;s basketball players and thrown together.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/847bc45a7d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/06/847bc45a7d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253087&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 On the 5th, after the game, the head coach of the Chinese team Zheng Wei was surrounded by the women&#39;s basketball players and was thrown into the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, the crowd in the auditorium waved the five-star red flag and cheered for the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/06/671eb5024f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/06/671eb5024f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253088&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 5, 2023, the crowd in the auditorium Waving the five-star red flag, cheering for the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this game, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team entered the state quickly at the beginning. Han Xu, Huang Sijing and Li Meng teamed up inside and outside to give the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team a 10-point lead in the first quarter. In the second quarter of the game, the Japanese women&#39;s basketball team began to exert its strength, constantly using its speed advantage to break through to the inside and succeed. At the end of the half, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team led 45:40. Entering the second half, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team continued to exert force, and the scores of both sides increased alternately. The Chinese women&#39;s basketball team led by 6 points 57:51 entering the final quarter. Entering the decisive moment, the Japanese team continued to use passes and cuts to score inside, and the point difference was once reduced to 1 point. After a short adjustment, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team scored 5 points in a row in the last three minutes to solidify the lead, with 13 seconds left before the end of the game. , the Japanese women&#39;s basketball team tied the score with a three-pointer. In the end, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team stabilized its position and Wang Siyu made a layup to end the game. The Chinese women&#39;s basketball team defeated the Japanese women&#39;s basketball team to win the championship and successfully crowned the seventh Asian Games champion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Li Meng dribbled the ball through during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/06/3928a7579b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06 /3928a7579b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253089&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Li Meng was in the game Breakthrough with the ball. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, Han Xu intercepted a Japanese player&#39;s pass during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/06/7af5584199.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06 /7af5584199.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253090&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, Han Xu stole a Japanese player during the game pass. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Siyu made a layup during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/06/3e5012b463.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/ 3e5012b463.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253091&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Siyu broke through in the game basket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Li Meng made a layup during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/06/fdba0e4cb6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06 /fdba0e4cb6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253092&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Li Meng was in the game Breakthrough layup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Li Yueru fought in the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/e92f1e553a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/e92f1e553a. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253093&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 5, 2023, Chinese team player Li Yueru fought in the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at this Hangzhou Asian Games, the promotion process of the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team was very smooth. In the previous games, they defeated their opponents by big scores. Chinese women&#39;s basketball coach Zheng Wei once said that the players have been maintaining high-intensity training and have prepared for problems they may encounter in the game. Before the final, the team was well prepared to face difficulties, so it arranged a tactic that the opponent didn&#39;t know much about and achieved a quasi-win. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, after the game, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball players waved to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/26c1790113.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/06/26c1790113.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253094&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 2023 On the 5th, after the game, the Chinese women’s basketball players waved to the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, in the auditorium, a well-dressed spectator waved the five-star red flag to cheer for the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/0f33397bc1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/06/0f33397bc1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253095&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 5, 2023 In the auditorium, a well-dressed spectator waved the five-star red flag to cheer for the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, fans of the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team excitedly waved posters and jerseys of the players.&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/f2a9dc1441.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/f2a9dc1441.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253096&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot; >;On October 5, 2023, fans of the Chinese women’s basketball team excitedly waved posters and jerseys of the players. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;Next, the Chinese women’s basketball players will return to their respective clubs to participate in the WCBA league in the new season. Subsequently, the Paris Olympic Qualifying Tournament in February 2024 will be a key task for the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 5, 2023, after the awards ceremony, the Chinese and Japanese women&#39;s basketball players took selfies and group photos on the court.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/82c44cbc57.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/06/82c44cbc57.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253097&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 5, 2023 After the award ceremony, the Chinese and Japanese women&#39;s basketball players took selfies and group photos on the court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2023年诺贝尔文学奖：约恩·福瑟并非冷门，残雪还有机会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258152]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 11:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/06/6SLqu56bYMVGFKaptupGjpsMsb4T0JCGTjxPcXep.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/06/6SLqu56bYMVGFKaptupGjpsMsb4T0JCGTjxPcX ep. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253078&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The 2023 Nobel Prize winner in Literature, Norwegian writer Jorn Fosse. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who is Jon Fosse? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the eve of the announcement of the 2023 Nobel Prize in Literature, because Chinese writer Can Xue ranked first in relevant odds on the Nicer Odds website, many readers expected her to win the prize. At 19:00 on October 5, Beijing time, the winner was announced, Can Xue lost. But this does not mean that the odds have no reference value. In fact, Norwegian writer Jon Fother ranks second after Can Xue on this odds list. Unlike Gurner, the 2021 winner, Fauser is not an unpopular choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the more than 100-year history of the Nobel Prize for Literature, only 17 female writers have won the prize, and 8 of them won the prize in the 21st century, including the American female poet Glück in 2020 and French female writer Ernault in 2022. Undoubtedly, the Swedish Academy, which has been questioned by public opinion, is turning its attention more and more to outstanding female authors. Therefore, Can Xue still has a good chance of winning this award in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The citation for the award was &quot;for his innovative plays and essays that give voice to the ineffable&quot;. Fosse&#39;s award &quot;quite reasonably follows the tradition of the Nobel Prize in Literature not forgetting outstanding playwrights, from Maeterlinck, Shaw, and Beckett to Dario Foe, Pinter, and Handke. It is quite brilliant. Even more convincing than the list of novelists,&quot; poet and critic Liao Weitang told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eon Fosse is one of the most famous figures in contemporary theater and a popular candidate for the Nobel Prize in recent years. His works also cover poetry, novels, essays, children&#39;s literature and translations. Fother&#39;s plays have been staged thousands of times around the world, including &quot;The Girl on the Sofa&quot; in China in 2004 and &quot;One Summer&quot; produced by the Shanghai Dramatic Art Center. Fosse once watched his own play &quot;Somebody&#39;s Coming&quot; in Shanghai and felt that it was one of the best stage presentations of his work in the world, and he developed a respect for Chinese drama and Chinese culture. Fother&#39;s honors include the Scandinavian National Theater Award (2002), the Norwegian Arts Council Honor Award (2003), the Swedish Academy&#39;s Nordic Prize (2007), and the International Ibsen Prize (2010). ). The work &quot;New Title: Heptata 6-7&quot; was shortlisted for the 2022 International Booker Prize. Anders Olsen, chairman of the Nobel Prize Committee for Literature, said his works &quot;touch upon your deepest feelings, anxieties, insecurities, questions of life and death.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fosse was born in Haugesund on the west coast of Norway on September 29, 1959. He began his creative career at the age of twelve, which he calls &quot;ashamingly early&quot;. Fosse loved to play guitar and at one time was in a rock band. Translator Zou Lulu believes that &quot;his early musical experience brought a unique Fother-like color and style to his later writing - a strong sense of rhythm and musicality in his dramatic language.&quot; Since the late 1970s, Fosse has lived in Bergen, Norway&#39;s second largest city and the country&#39;s cultural capital. In recent years, he has also gone to southern France and Austrian towns on the outskirts of Vienna to write. Fosse is very energetic and often starts writing at four or five o&#39;clock in the afternoon and works until nine o&#39;clock the next morning. When asked if he had any advice for writing, he said: &quot;Write, don&#39;t think! Think before you write, think after you finish, but don&#39;t think about anything while writing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About En Fauser&#39;s earliest reading memory is a small book. In the book, a major felt that his town needed a fire truck, and then he and some citizens built it. It looked more like what children built out of wood. Car. “I used wood to build cars when I was a kid,” Fosse said. He admired Trakl, Kafka and Beckett, and at the same time, Beckett was an important object of &quot;resistance&quot; when he wrote dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fosse uses a rare language, &quot;New Norwegian&quot;. Even in Norway, which has a population of only more than five million, its speakers only account for one-tenth of the total population. Fortunately, New Norwegian can be easily understood by Norwegian, Swedish, and Danish speakers. But it is with the help of translation that Fosse&#39;s works are known to more readers. Currently, his books have been translated into more than forty languages. At first, he only wanted to write poems and novels. In 1993, he was invited to write his first script because he was short of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, there are John Fother&#39;s drama selections &quot;Somebody&#39;s Coming&quot; and &quot;Autumn Dreams&quot; published by Shanghai Translation Publishing House. Wenjing is about to publish &quot;Trilogy&quot;, one of Fosse&#39;s masterpiece novels. This work won the Nordic Council Literary Award in 2015 and demonstrates his cold, solemn and concise epic style. The novel contains three closely connected parts: &quot;Awakening&quot;, &quot;Olav&#39;s Dream&quot; and &quot;Tiredness&quot;. The story begins with the young lovers Asle and Alida leaving their hometown for Björgven (the city of Bergen). Alida is about to give birth, but the couple has difficulty finding a place to live. They later found a place to live and gave birth to a son, Sigvald, who began to adopt different names, Olav and Åsta. But someone recognized Asler, and it was very clear that Asler and Alida seemed to be carrying murder cases, although Asler might have acted out of helplessness. Asler was eventually hanged. In the last part, the story time advances to the life of Asler and Alida&#39;s daughter Ales. By this time Ales is already an old woman. She recalls her sister who died young and herself. His brother Sigvald left him when he was young...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Wan, the editor-in-chief of &quot;Trilogy&quot; is a young writer and translator. In her opinion, John Fother&#39;s After the work was introduced to China, it has not attracted widespread attention from readers, and even senior readers rarely know about him. &quot;Fosse is not an issue-oriented writer. He has very consistently inherited the Nordic expressionist drama tradition. His language is concise and full of tension. His profound depiction of the character&#39;s spirit and his analysis of the relationship between people have reached a very high level. He will not write about trivial daily life, but pay attention to people&#39;s mental state.&quot; Li Wan told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The protagonist of Fosse&#39;s work is somewhat similar to himself. He is an alcoholic. He has some mental problems and has many extreme fringe experiences. He faces his own heart very directly and exposes himself. He is a writer who can share with others the most helpless side of a person.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;With this,同时，约恩·福瑟形成了独特的文体，很少用句号，一个句子经常写得非常非常长，他用很多逗号去连接，给人一种内心独白不断向前滚动的感觉。这可能出于一个剧作家的敏感，把戏剧因素带进了小说。另外，他会在小说不同的部分使用一些重复性的语句，但是这种重复并非一模一样，而是随着语境的不断改变、语词的细微变化，产生变体和变奏，带来一种循环往复又不断推进的节奏。”李琬说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被上司“甩锅”怎么办？当首先秉直做好自己的分内事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258030]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;职场里吐槽上司是一个经久不息、乐此不疲的“节目”。关于“你听过管理者最无耻的一句话是什么”的问题，有网友的回答引人共鸣：下属提出方案，领导说不行，必须按他的意思修改，下属坚持，领导怒，“听我的就行”。执行领导修改后的方案出了问题，领导找到下属说：“当初你为什么不坚持，你认为对的就应该去坚持，你要想办法说服我。一点主见都没有。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“为何不好好劝我”骨子里，这句话代表了一种责任推卸术。不是有那么一句话嘛，“功为己，过为人”，说的就是这样的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种领导确实是易惹众怒的那种，明明下属有主见但是意见被“拍死”，还说人家没主见，简直是耍流氓。但还不算太奇葩，因为他至少暗示了下属的原方案是正确的，而让一个领导承认这一点极其不容易。这样做事的领导，如今真的是凤毛麟角，推卸责任的领导不会做得这么明显而且没有技巧，因为这么简单粗暴的智商，是不可能坐上这个位置的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比这“无耻度”高一点的情况，是一位网友提到的：正常情况下，领导会跟你说，我这么好的方案都被你搞砸了，怎么执行的？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这句话让我大赏，对，某些领导就是这个口吻，就是这个味道。他们在下属面前就是“常有理”。但这还不是“推卸型领导”中的极品，真正的极品是从来不说他的方案是啥，让你执行就完事，继而一直改下去。这样的领导不是水平高深莫测，看不上平庸方案，就是水平极差，喜欢在“藏拙”的同时，拿下属做方案“小白鼠”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后一情形在现实中并不鲜见，说白了，一些人不知道怎么就登上了重要管理岗位，然后开启外行指导内行的喜感人生。老实说，我顶怕这个，若是外行领导比较看重你的才华和能力，因此选择尊重你的方案，那还不坏，最坏的是不懂装懂、固执己见，用一堆笑料百出的“管理智慧”来逼迫下属“听话”。我年轻时就遇见过张口就爱说“你们只需要听话”的上司，这类鼓吹“听话学”的，九成九是志大才疏、特别爱装的上司。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相对而言，那种“霸道”但能扛事、能担责的领导，要好得多。那些既想显现领导权威又没有格局的领导，不过是“矮子型”领导，他们之所以不敢扛事、不敢担责，还是私心和面子作祟，没有勇气承认自己不如下属、嫉贤妒能罢了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;都说管理是门艺术，这话没毛病，可是应该补充一点：管理首先得讲人味。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随之而来的思索是，面对前述那些爱推卸责任的领导，下属究竟应该怎么办？换言之，职场中，上级和下级的责任边界在哪里？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在任何一个单位，上级和下级都是“目标共同体”，如果考虑到大多数单位采取的都是项目负责制，上级和下级本应同心同德、有力出力、有智出智，总之以才论短长。但现实当中，这种局面并不多见，很多情况下，上级和下级的博弈、内耗，充斥着一个单位的时空，令人窒息、喟叹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，“推卸型领导”固然责任最大，但下属就无可反思了吗？并非如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个单位里，“老实人”总是最多。他们往往只想老老实实把事干好，按时领到报酬。但凡事若是这么顺溜，那就没有“职场风云”这回事了。而一个本本分分的员工，遇见的最大困惑，就是被上司甩锅甚至找茬刁难。在这种环境中，你怎么干都不合意，每天光看领导脸色就够够的。对此，很多人的坏情绪难免淤积于心，除了时不时地找可靠的人吐个槽，似乎别无他法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但背后吐槽没什么用，领导听不见的话最后不还是飘散在风中？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，作为下属，遇见奇葩领导后，并不是只能束手无策，任人家“虐”，而是大可根据实际情形予以应对。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一件事或一个方案，如果下属没有被赋予职责，并承担最终后果，那自不待言，正常情况下听领导的就行了。如果领有职责，把它干好属于分内之事，干不好要承担最终后果。即便领导提出意见，那也只能参考。不对的地方，坚决不盲从。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果这事的“终极负责人”是上司，而你只是一个执行者，那么，在遇见领导祭出明显的昏招时，可以分两种情况做。其一是该劝则劝，陈明利害，让领导听到正确观点，至于领导采纳不采纳，决定权在领导；其二是如果领导刚愎自用，不仅听不进不同意见，就连提意见这种行为也不容，那么这样的部门呆着也没劲，与其长期受气、背锅，不如考虑换部门——等于把领导给换了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;劝说领导，确实有风险。职场有那种喜欢给提意见者穿小鞋的领导，但如果你是一个正派的下属，有什么不敢提意见的？仅仅担心领导对自己有看法？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年前，我在担任一家公司中层干部时，就经常给上级提意见，甚至不惜争执。有时，我的意见得到了采纳，例如，保护了所在部门的员工，使之不被滥罚；有时，我的意见被无视，例如在末位淘汰事务中领导处事不公，导致不该走的人被“淘汰”，却拒不纠错。这类窝心事多了，我便觉得难以难受，在经过慎重考虑后，我选择了拂袖离去。尽管我因此失去了一些看得见的“好处”，但我赢得了知我者的尊重和理解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说到底，一个下属要想和上级在工作和生活中处好关系，协调好各种事务，不卑不亢、守住底线是基本原则。失掉这个原则，双方关系必然扭曲。一个是非观念很强的人，确实无法改变因为坚持正确立场而产生的不利影响，也无法像某些人那样“八面玲珑”，但依然应该坚持做一个正直的人、敢言的人。否则，我们就算做到了“利益最大化”，可是也因此失去了底线和品性，我们还能问心无愧吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[尹学芸：故乡是一枚爱人丨月是故乡明⑥]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257348]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/73f60a5ff76ba4f9050678f79d1cf516.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/73f60a5ff76ba4f9050678f79d1cf516.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;159101&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;初读尹学芸的《寻隐者不遇》，读者可能会感到些许茫然，她的小说总是“上来就说，不拉架势”，像地里长出来的青苗，朴实、俏拔，带着清新的土腥味，一个写惯了乡村、县城、官场、酒局的作家，怎么会想到写一部雾里看花的都市情爱小说？2021年同名小说集收录了《寻隐者不遇》《望湖楼》《喂鬼》《苹果树》《比风还快》等几部中篇，继续往后读，这部“蹊跷”的小说才渐露来历，一个让老读者熟悉的尹学芸也慢慢浮现。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;尹学芸文字的源头在天津市最北部的蓟州&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（2016年以前为蓟县）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。小城里有一片人工湖，曾是天津重要的水源地。过去，人们常在湖里钓鱼、坐船、游泳，但为了保护水源，这些项目都取消了，湖边的许多建筑也一一拆迁，她闲来无事就沿湖走走。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《寻隐者不遇》讲述了薛小梨、苏梅这两个女人和一个年轻男人寒武几次“两两组合”，去一座废弃庄园寻找隐居高人的故事。小说缘起于尹学芸本人的一次偶遇。一次闲逛中，她走进了一座废弃的庄园，在里面看到不同的花花草草，还有秋千、体育场、养鱼池、望湖亭，旧日的奢华清晰可见，她甚至还看到了自己熟悉的人的题字。小城从前有很多家装潢讲究的疗养院，都是各个部门在依山傍水的地方建造的，普通人平时难以进来，后来纷纷拆除。这样一个庄园竟然能藏身在小小的蓟州，连本地人都很难发现，她猜想，这个园子也是那些疗养院之一。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ec25f82eb0ee551da14bf69a97e2a8f0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ec25f82eb0ee551da14bf69a97e2a8f0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;159102&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;小城只有几处场景，一个场景可以被来回打量、猜测、使用，这个隐秘的庄园先后被尹学芸写进了《望湖楼》和《寻隐者不遇》。繁华的时候，园子是县城的退休工人掏空腰包也要请客吃一次的望湖楼；萧瑟的时候，园子又成了背着手、迈着官步的老干部神出鬼没的地方。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;反复打捞、淘洗、咀嚼自己的生活，不肯浪费一粒灵感，似乎是她写作的本能。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8ded87050634cf1d3cb1a36b522a0991.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8ded87050634cf1d3cb1a36b522a0991.png&quot; data-key=&quot;159097&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;从罕村到埙城&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;蓟州是天津唯一一个半山区，北高南低，高山、平原、大洼、库区在这里汇聚。最早的历史可以追溯到春秋时期，明代有诗云：“西来山尽处，始见蓟州城。”山区里的生活少变动，人也不善变通，尹学芸笔下的人物都有执着的底色：《岁月风尘》中在战乱年代坚守爱情、追寻光明的李勋李荃姐妹，《菜根谣》中不顾反对坚持寻找失踪小伙伴的冯诺，《苹果树》中对苹果树的神力坚信不疑的刘苹……有历史学者告诉尹学芸，清军入关时蓟县人至死不降，以致被三次屠城，这里人的性格就是横、楞、拧。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;蓟州是产生执念的地方，尹学芸的文学也是执着结下的果实。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;有人读完尹学芸的作品去寻访她的村庄，却失望地发现河水没有那样清、街巷没有那么长，进村也不是总有牛叫和炒蚂蚱香。尹学芸真实见过这些美丽，但她笔下的罕村既不是一个桃花源，也不是诞生诡奇传说的化外之地，而是一个生活的地方，其间穿梭着形形色色的乡里乡亲，为一日三餐奔波、算计，人和人之间的关系盘根错节、千丝万缕。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;准确说来，尹学芸出生成长的村子在蓟州南部最低的洼处，三面环水，只有南边有一条公路。让她获鲁迅文学奖的“李海叔叔”，每年就是沿着这条路，两手空空来到“我”家，给一家人带来只存在于想象中的荣光，然后满载着东拼西凑的粮食、物资回去。有去无回的友情坚持了二十多年终于透支，家里人对李海叔叔讳莫如深，“我”才知道叔叔屈辱的生存史，他不是住在有花园、高楼的城市小区里，而是偏僻贫瘠的苦梨峪，家中一贫如洗，好几口人每年都等着李海叔叔从“我”家带回面粉才能包饺子过年。两家人相互仰望又暗自攀比着，度过艰难的时期。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;尹学芸小时候，村子里的日子以几近凝固的速度流动着，唯一的变化是谁死了、谁出嫁了。有些人家冬天和夏天穿一套衣服，只不过，夏天把棉絮掏出来，冬天再塞进去。村子的外号叫“唠叨村”，有的是不务正业、好吃好喝的人，在别的村子里卖不出去的肉，在这里准卖完。她的父母都是农民，身边没有一个跟文字工作打交道的人。她寻找自己文学基因的源头，那是会看话本、会唱戏文、会喊夯号的爷爷。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;很多作家都记得自己的阅读史，她也在小本子上记：《野火春风斗古城》《战斗的青春》《金光大道》……从小学一年级到初中毕业读的书名，记了147个，这个数字让她自己也怀疑，是不是记错了？但这些书用她的话概括，都是讲打仗的，对文学来说可能没有太多营养。十多岁时，她还不知道世界上有杂志这回事，更别提接触外国文学。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;即便这样也要读书，一本一本地读，一点一点地走出来。由于稀缺，对书的记忆反而牢固。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;乡下孩子接触书籍并不容易，有时候还需要跟哥哥姐姐“斗智斗勇”。小时候，比她大七岁的姐姐爱看书，经常往家里拿书，却不给她看。有一次姐姐藏了一本说是“少儿不宜”的书，她把家里翻了个底朝天，最后在一只旧棉鞋里找到了，把书掏出来，只闻到一股脚丫子味，姐姐不在家时她掏出来看，看完再塞回去，偷偷摸摸地看完了那本“搞对象”的书&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（后来知道是《青春之歌》）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/7f8bae790b16dddbf271186d99de917a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/7f8bae790b16dddbf271186d99de917a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;159107&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;不上学的时候，她一边放羊一边看书，身旁一只小羊，膝上放一本没有书皮的《红楼梦》，书是繁体字写的，她基本看不懂，但还是能记得“尤二姐吞生金自逝”这样的情节，书里的故事在她脑子里扎下根。去镇子里上学的路上，她和村里的孩子走在麦子地里，孩子们都争先恐后挤到她身边，她手上拿着纺锤，把棉花田里随手扯来的棉花纺成线，嘴里则把书籍、记忆混上想象编成故事，又讲给小伙伴们听。她开始幻想有朝一日自己写的字能变成铅字。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;高中毕业后，尹学芸去村办服装厂当了一名缝纫女工。只要有一天假，她就跑到县城买上十本杂志，彻夜翻完，工作之余也开始给刊物投稿。最开始的时候她没留心不同刊物之间的区别，记不得自己读过的作家的名字，什么也不懂，屡被退稿。有时，编辑在退稿信里批评她不该一味模仿某个作家，她很困惑，不知道自己“模仿”的这位作家是谁。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;她骨子里仍然是个靠天吃饭的农民，雨下得多，秧苗就疯长，大旱则颗粒无收，写作也是这样，不存拿奖、出名的野心，只是按部就班地耕耘，想到哪就写到哪。这一时期她靠着与生俱来的灵性和情分，写乡里的生活、村野的生态，表现周围那些“想着法儿活着的人”，发表的刊物从《蓟县文艺》到《天津文学》《天津日报》，付出慢慢地有了回报。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1980年代末，尹学芸的小说《一个叫素月的女人》被改编成电视剧在央视播出，这部电视剧的背景音乐由一种叫“埙”的乐器演奏，尹学芸被埙的声音深深感动，决定用“埙”给今后作品中的城市命名，从此“埙城”成了她的另一个文学地标。当时她正在帮县里写县志，由于央视的影响力，县委特地给了她一个名额，从临时工直接转成了国家干部。谈到这里，尹学芸不住感叹：“文学改变命运，真的是文学改变命运。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/48d2bb4bfb153e940de848008ae8bbf9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/48d2bb4bfb153e940de848008ae8bbf9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;159106&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8f8e08f82497d537eb26d7520546f685.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/8f8e08f82497d537eb26d7520546f685.png&quot; data-key=&quot;159099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;浮出深水&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;从农民转变成了干部，尹学芸辗转文化馆、旅游局、住建委等多个不同的部门，工作让她接触了形形色色的人，她拉开一段距离，观察人在工作中怎么思考、行动，有什么样的关系需要协调，写出了一个个入木三分的基层干部形象。早些年，还有单位的人警告她，别把自己写成小说，她暗自反问：“哪个单独的人物能构成一篇小说？”她喜欢将人物放到时间的长河里冲刷，洗掉他们一时的意气风发和灰头土脸，留下平时幽微却又真实的人性，再为他们编织一个故事的框。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;和乡村不一样的是，机关把人分出了很多层面，领导和非领导、年龄大的和年龄小的，甚至身后的背景都会有人刻意衡量和揣测，在单位里，人总要面对很多不同的人，处理很多不同的关系，在这样复杂又温吞的日常生活里，她拓展着人灵魂自省的深度。《士别十年》&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（2015年发表）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;是一个典型的人性在机关工作里蜕变的故事，这本小说很早就开始写，中间被搁置在电脑里长达十年，十年的时间，让“看事物总是一厢情愿，见不得任何形式主义，眼里容不得一粒沙子”的文艺女青年郭缨子，学会了察言观色、收敛锋芒，成了办公室里八面玲珑、酒局上左右逢源的主任，与当初的缨子处境极像的陈丹果不堪领导骚扰和同事孤立，跳楼自杀，陈丹果的死让缨子意识到自己已沉沦为帮凶，也向读者提出一个发人深省的追问：世俗的成功是否以丧失常识和常态生活为代价？这部小说引起了很多人的共鸣，并获得百花文学奖的认可。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;小说问世之前，尹学芸在文学上也经历了一段“温水煮青蛙”的时间。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;她对名利一直不敏感。用她的话来说，偏远山区的作者远离了都市，也就远离了名利场，所以人一直是潜在深水里的状态，想漂浮都难。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;90年代之后，尹学芸给人的印象是写作停顿了几年。那时她年纪尚轻，时不时发表点小说、散文，办着一份小刊物，和相识的作者到处赏花、打牌、野餐，每天乐乐呵呵的。但很快她感到疲乏。虽然一直有作品发出来，但常联系的刊物只有几家，小说在一个小圈子里撞来撞去，没有向上的动力。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;走出了山洼，年岁渐长之后，她想到了以前没想过的事情。“你生活在一个山高皇帝远的地方，好处是自己比较自由，坏处也是自己比较自由，没人督促你。后来认识河北那些作家，特别羡慕人家有这样一个三五个人的小团体，写东西知道好在哪、不好在哪。但那时候我在有的地方发了也没人看见，也没人告诉你应该怎么走。”尹学芸说。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;好在，基层作家之间的善意“接住”了她。在她小说写得不温不火时，有经验的作家给她指路——去更生活化、读者更多的晚报发表。于是她开始为晚报写小说，也写散文、随笔，内容更加丰富了，侃足球、忆乡村、拉家常，什么都写。那段时间，她天天傍晚去登山，一边登山一边琢磨写作，“有的时候一串题材在后面排队，总有很多可写的东西，就是这样一种感觉，让你觉得生活就是很有意思的。”尹学芸形容。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;报纸的专栏发稿量大，一次要发好几篇，她想到了写自己生活的乡村中慢慢消失的词语。眼看着城镇化不断加速，农村一些具有历史意义和地方色彩的场景变得面目模糊。乡民走入城市，存于50到70年代之间的许多方言词汇退出人们的交流，有相当一部分在80年代初即已成历史。为了不让这些词语悄无声息地消失，她走遍了县境里大大小小的村庄，从本地人口中挖来那些字词。有些词传播的地域广阔，有些词在南方和北方、古代和现代的用法不一样，有的口音难以用文字模拟，遇到难以把握的部分，她也跟天南海北的网友讨论。这段在田垄上的寻访经历，留下了诸如“开圈”&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（队里把地里的白薯、花生或小麦都收完了，允许社员们去刨遗留下的白薯、花生或拣拾残留在地上的麦穗）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;、“新宿”&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（偶尔借宿在别人家里）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;、“看青”&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（在庄稼即将成熟、由绿转黄的时候看守庄稼，防止别人偷粮食）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;等百个乡村词语的记录，后来成书为《慢慢消失的乡村词语》&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（2009年出版）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;写了几年散文、专栏，她逐渐找到了自己写作的感觉，整个城市的百姓也知道了她。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/c460ca9c53226d3823b9f98c2f0cb4c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/c460ca9c53226d3823b9f98c2f0cb4c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;159100&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2014年对尹学芸来说是个特殊的年份，她发了五部中篇小说，写出了《李海叔叔》和《士别十年》，进入了作品的井喷期。直到现在，她和这几部作品的命运仍然让她唏嘘。当时一部中篇小说《玲珑塔》被退稿，她怎么也想不明白退稿的原因，就把稿子给了《收获》杂志，编辑不到一周就打电话来提出了修改意见。等待终审的那几个月她什么也没干，不知道自己是怎么过来的。她对自己说，终审过了再开始写，终审不过以后就不写了。那年她50岁，到了女干部离岗的年龄，如果稿子没有给《收获》、没有过审，她也许会换一个活法。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;终审还是过了，《收获》发表《玲珑塔》后，陆续有编辑找尹学芸约稿。她第一个写的就是《李海叔叔》，但因为版面的问题一直搁置。她又把另一篇稿子拿给编辑提意见，被对方要走发表，这篇就是《士别十年》。“我老跟那些作家朋友说，不用着急，自己慢慢写，你自己有机会，作品有机会，来了就来了。有的时候反正你找也找不到，这又不是一部作品就怎么样的时代。”尹学芸说。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;第二年尹学芸继续发力，发了10部中篇，到2016年发了14部。她至今都觉得那段时间的生产力是不可思议的。“虽然说那个时候都已经不是创作力最好的时候了，但是你会觉得文学突然给你打开了一扇窗，你可以抓住这样一个机会，其实那个时候没有任何人告诉你应该怎么样，但是自己真是有这种感觉。”她说。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ef2d03ef4a1659a5a7086bcd87ce3563.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;171&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/09/04/ef2d03ef4a1659a5a7086bcd87ce3563.png&quot; data-key=&quot;159104&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;士别三十年&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;近年来，尹学芸的视野从乡村跨越到城市，投向城乡之间的牵扯、纠结和疼痛。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;离开故乡30年后，她写了一篇名字骇人的《喂鬼》，小说的主人公云丫为躲避故乡的干娘临终前指派她在葬礼上为其“喂鬼”的仪式，急匆匆与网友阿祥相约远赴云南旅行。一路上却不断接到来自干娘的大儿子的催促和央告，令她心神不安。结果旅行结束返回埙城，她还是按照干娘的遗愿去喂鬼，才知道喂鬼只是一个很简单的佛教法事&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（“喂鬼”也叫“放焰口”，其实就是赈济鬼魂，给予法食令其饱满。）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;。三个多月后，云丫接到电话，她的朋友阿祥已在三个月前死于一场车祸。这是一场徒劳的出走。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;尹学芸谈起这篇小说的创作时说：“很多时候故乡就是一枚爱人，有时候让你想着法地逃离，可更多的时候，又让你想着法地回归。有对比才有反差，有反差才有不同情感方式的表达。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;尽管作为基层工作者，尹学芸还是需要经常跟乡村打交道，但已经不是小时候那种生活在其中的状态，而是客居。年龄大了，和乡村的距离也在拉大，她和家乡的那些人、事之间有了一层越来越碍眼的隔膜。过去她喜欢把熟悉的人反复用在多部作品里，刻画人物不同的侧面，把故事写得满满当当，但现在她的生活里已经很难找到这样的人。在《寻隐者不遇》中，现代人的神龙见首不见尾，人与人之间感情的淡薄、疏远，通过大量留白表现出来。再也找不到《李海叔叔》里那种长达二十多年的精神连接。“再然后你就发现，其实你跟所有的故乡、所有的乡村都是隔膜的，其实变化的不是它们，是你自己，很多时候都是你的眼睛变了，或者你的心也变了，我回去得越来越少了，跟他们的交往越来越少了。”尹学芸说。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;作为以乡村题材见长的作家，她不得不对这种隔膜警惕起来：“作品中的那种温度其实都在退，那种底色都在褪。我觉得是作家的通病，可能隔一段就得反思，怎么在生活中找到切口，这是很重要的。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;（参考资料：《尹学芸印象》《尹学芸：没有哪段生活是白费的》《尹学芸：我曾被这盏灯照亮也期待它照亮更多人》《专访」尹学芸：最基层的作者离文坛很遥远，发再多小说也不是著名作家》《尹学芸：乡村的秩序》，感谢译林出版社和邓郁为采访提供的帮助）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这个假期，打工人流行去围观山姆盒马“小学生打架”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257410]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;国庆长假期间，一些没有出游、宅在家的年轻人，会选择去往仓储会员店，一次性采购长假期间所需要的食物，山姆会员店和盒马X会员店成为很多人的优先选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如今，这两家仓储会员店不仅可以满足消费者的购物需求，也可以满足他们凑热闹、看八卦的需求，因为8月以来，山姆与盒马的“小学生打架”就没有停止过。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高端的商战，往往采用最朴素的方式，那就是我的商品比你低1元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;此前，山姆与盒马为一块榴莲千层蛋糕“打”得不可开交——榴莲千层最先由山姆热卖，一块128元，盒马直接标价一块99元。山姆不服输，把榴莲千层的价格打到88元，盒马降到86元，山姆就调到85元，几个回合下来，蛋糕价格一度降至79元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;随后，从月饼西瓜到鸡蛋小零食都卷入这场商战，很多人疑惑，山姆与盒马为何要“小学生打架”？价格战能让他们顺利地圈到中产消费者吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;巨头们各有烦恼&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;正当传统商超经营普遍陷入困境时，带有批发性质的仓储会员商店发展得如火如荼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;仓储会员店走的量贩售卖模式，大包装、品类多、价格优惠，消费者每隔一段时间才去大采购一次。艾媒咨询数据显示，2021年仓储会员超市行业市场规模达304.3亿元，2022年市场规模达335亿元，预计到2025年有望接近400亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;作为中国仓储会员商店的头部品牌，山姆会员店和盒马X店各有风光，也各有烦恼，不得不铆足劲头竞争。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆会员店已成为沃尔玛业绩中重要的增长点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据沃尔玛第二季度的数据，第二季度总营收为1616亿美元，同比增长5.7%或5.4%（受汇率影响），营业利润同比增长5亿美元，增长率为6.7%。其中，沃尔玛中国净销售额为41亿美元，同比增长21.7%，仓储会员业务与电商业务增长亮眼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆会员店坐稳国内仓储会员店的头把交椅。一方面，1996年，山姆就在深圳开了中国第一家仓储会员店，将仓储会员的模式与理念传输到国内。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;另一方面，作为世界500强常年的第一名，沃尔玛在全球范围内建立了庞大、稳固的供应链体系，沃尔玛旗下的山姆会员店能够以更低的价格拿到更高品质的商品，并让利给消费者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆会员店1983年就在美国开了第一家店，至今已经有40年历史，它的积淀与经验是其他仓储会员店一时半会还难以比拟的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;然而，山姆也有烦恼，那就是模仿者、竞争者甚至是“碰瓷者”太多了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;同样诞生于美国的Costco，主打仓储会员模式，是山姆的老对手，麦德龙、家乐福等国外品牌也穷追不舍，至于国内，诚如永辉、盒马等来势汹汹，尤其是后起之秀的盒马X店，已经渐渐对山姆形成严峻挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对于成立于2015年的盒马来说，历史尽管不长，走过的弯路也不少，除了招牌的盒马鲜生以外，盒马此前推出的盒马小站、盒马MINI、盒马集市和盒马邻里等，大都已经铩羽而归。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前盒马形成三个比较稳定的业务，一个是盒马鲜生，一个是盒马奥莱店（折扣店），另外一个就是仓储会员模式的盒马X店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;今年，阿里巴巴启动“1+6+N”组织变革，盒马只是“N”中的一部分，在集团中的地位有所下滑，盒马还是阿里最有希望上市的业务之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如果只是盒马鲜生盈利肯定是不够的，所以，X店成为盒马的重中之重，被寄予厚望。除了赶紧多开店外，更是要抢占市场份额，提升盈利能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;瞄准中产，抢占中产&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;仓储会员店的目标客户，是中国新兴的中产阶层。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆会员店早在1996年就在中国大陆开了第一家，不过，截至2016年，整整20年时间也仅只有16家店。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;伴随着中国中产阶层的迅速崛起，山姆会员店才迎来爆发式增长，从2017年至今6年不到的时间，山姆会员店已经新增了29家店，目前大陆已经有45家山姆会员店，预计到今年底将达到48家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;仓储会员店的中产属性，另一个标志是它并不便宜的年费。比如山姆普通会员费为260元，盒马X黄金会员年费为258元。值得注意的是，会员费的期限只有一年，并且不能抵现。换句话说，得先花260元才能进入山姆消费，哪怕你一年在山姆什么也没买，260元也是不能返还的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;会员费门槛自然阻隔了很大一部分消费者，无疑也会提高付费消费者的购物黏性，办了这里的会员卡，当然会来这里高频购物，才不会浪费了会员费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;凭借强大的供应链和议价能力，仓储会员店也会努力以“物美又全、价格合理”的商品，让消费者的260元的会员费花得不亏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆与盒马对准的都是具有较好的经济基础、对生活品质有高追求的中产尤其是中产家庭，二者的用户高度重合。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据月狐iAPP所示，山姆与盒马的用户重合率达到43.1%。而今年2月，沃尔玛中国区CEO朱晓静在一场内部讲话中表示，山姆唯一竞争对手可能就是盒马。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这一次也是盒马率先发起针对山姆的“价格战”，盒马的畅销活动叫“移山价”，一语双关，既是愚公移山，也是要移走山姆。这名称，“小学生打架”的意味蛮浓。搞笑的是，美团也一度加入战局，推出的价格叫“拔河价”，这“河”，不正是“盒马”吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;谁能“打赢”这群架&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在这场仓储会员领域的群架中，谁能“打赢”？&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;单靠价格战，并不是最优解。既因为不可持续，也因为价格战只针对少数的商品品类，并非全线都比对方低价。更关键的是，中产在意的并不是那一两块钱的差距，很多人愿意花贵一点的价格购买更优品质的商品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以，仓储会员商店还是得回到根本上来：“物美又全，价格合理”——这考验的仍然是供应链的强度与韧性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;能否在全球范围内，以更低的价格采买优质的产品？从采购到上架，需要多长时间？如何确保货柜上的热门商品能够源源不断提供？消费者网上采购，能够以多快的速度送货上门？能否不断提供爆款的自营产品？&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;它们都与供应链有关。在这一点上，山姆与Costco布局多年、树大根深，确实需要盒马不断追赶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;作为本土品牌，盒马的优势是带有更加鲜明的“本土化”特色，更加契合国人的一些消费需求。比如中国正步入单身社会，单身的中产越来越多，山姆会员店那种超大量的贩卖模式不适合这些单身中产，盒马的X会员店，就很注重经营小包装商品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中国的电商经济高度发达，盒马背靠阿里健全成熟的物流体系，送货上门的速度极快，反之，Costco不久前才推出到家配送服务，真的是姗姗来迟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;再比如，下沉市场仍是仓储会员商店未充分开发的领地，盒马主打折扣商品和临期商品的奥莱店，可以在一线城市扎根，在下沉市场也有很大的想象空间……&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;山姆、盒马等仓储会员店该如何扬长避短，好戏还在后头。无论如何，它们充分竞争是好事一件，帮消费者把价格打下来，消费者还能顺便看看八卦，何乐不为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 10:26:35 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女子诬告强奸在新加坡被判入狱：世界性难题如何破解？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258118]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一起发生在国外的案件引发关注。综合新加坡《联合早报》《海峡时报》报道，中国籍女子张露恬（22岁）10月2日在法庭上认罪，承认自己向公务员提供虚假资料。法官最终判其入狱五周。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;案件并不复杂：当事女子2021年4月通过社交软件与男子刘栋扬结识，一个月后见面并在当年8月确立恋爱关系，之后又在刘栋扬处同居。2022年3月9日，两人在刘栋扬住处发生激烈争吵，当事女子在午夜00：38报警。面对到场调查的十名警员、五名调查人员和四名法证人员，当事女子称自己遭遇刘栋扬虐待，也曾三次遭遇后者强奸，并向医务人员重复了指控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘栋扬一共被问话44分钟，两部手机与护照也遭警方扣留。然而在报案一个月后，当事女子就改口承认自己撒谎，并且撤回了虚假指控。“为的就是要让男方惹上麻烦。”当事女子还透露自己早在事发约一周后就尝试销案，但是并未成功。检察官Kevin Liew表示，被告提供假信息浪费了公共资源，也冤枉一名无辜的受害者，因此提议法官判被告坐牢至少六周。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;面对检方的指控，当事女子哽咽发表辩词称，事发时自己刚满21岁，认知能力尚不成熟，一时冲动才犯下错误。除了对受害者外，自己行为并未对公众利益造成巨大伤害。当时因遭前男友粗暴对待，急着寻求帮助才会谎称遭到对方强奸。她已追悔莫及也得到了前男友原谅，希望法官从轻发落。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这起案件已经尘埃落定，法官确实也如当事女子所愿对其“从轻发落”，将刑期从六到十个星期变成了五个星期。不过，这起案件仍有一些未发之覆，值得深入辨析与评论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，案件本身显示当事女子的说辞存在矛盾之处，其辩词并不能服人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当事女子所谓“认知偏差”的辩称透露着一股黑色幽默，特别是那句“对法律条款的认知能力不足，对于自身犯罪的严重性认知也非常不成熟”。那么，既然她“认知能力尚不成熟”，为何却以强奸罪指控男友？要知道，强奸罪在新加坡可是最高刑期20年同时最多鞭刑12下的重罪。因此，当事女子的言行似乎只能解读为她对强奸罪罪名的后果有所认知，却不足以认知诬告他人的法律后果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，“认知偏差”的话术也常见于国内强奸或性侵诬告者在露馅之后的自辩。在喧腾一时的“罗冠军案”中，梁颖就声称“她本人对强奸罪法律定义的认知出现偏差，才会在网上冤枉罗冠军”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诬告者自辩“认知偏差”，其实是无法自圆其说的。从梁颖发动的“小作文”舆论攻势与本案中当事女子的司法攻势来看，诬告者对于公开指控“强奸罪”的后果其实有着清晰的认知，目的就是“把对方弄到社会性死亡”“给对方惹麻烦”。而在其它案例里，诬告者还有“把你送进监狱”这样直白的威胁。难道诬告者不知道“强奸罪”的严重性？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不难想见诬告者的心路历程：公开指控对方性侵或强奸，最好的结果是逼迫对方让出利益或者让自己吃到流量红利，乃至真的将对方送进监狱，至少毁掉对方的人生；最坏的结果也不过是“自己记错了”，以类似“认知偏差”的理由为诬告行为开脱，“可攻可守”的状态，足以让自己立于不败之地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也正是如此，当事女子才在耗费大量公共资源、诬告已经实锤之后，以“认知偏差”辩称诬告之举，借助“心智不成熟”企图脱逃报假案之罪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，本案也显示“性侵或强奸诬告”是个全球性难题，诬告者需要承担的举证责任、所需承担的民事与刑事责任，均与诬告成功的可能获利严重不成比例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本案中，当事女子最终的罪名只是“向公务员提供虚假信息罪”，检察官在指控中也只是强调了其“浪费大量公共资源”的行径。根据新加坡《刑事法典》第177条，向公务员提供虚假信息者将被处以最高六个月的刑期，或者并处罚金5000新元。然而，对比当事女子的诬告之举，以及一旦罪名成立之后男方所面临的的严厉刑责，这是严重不符比例原则的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果类似诬告行为总能实现“零成本高回报”，而且即便报了假案作了伪证也只是坐牢六个星期的话，那么其所带来的“制度激励”仍将制造更多的诬告案件，从长远来看同样会伤害公共利益。难道，社会只能在“默许乃至宽纵诬告”与“保障真正受害者敢于报案”之间或此或彼？这又是一个“虚假两难推理”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其三，被诬告者也未能站出来伸张自己的权益，控告对方的犯罪行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新加坡法律没有诬告陷害罪，但有诽谤罪。根据新加坡《刑事法典》第499条，如果发现足够的证据，警察可以采取行动逮捕诽谤的罪犯。受害者也可以选择根据《诽谤法》提起民事诉讼，或向警方报案进行刑事起诉，如能证明诽谤者有意图、知道或有理由相信他的话会损害受害者的名誉，即可发起控告，挽回自己被侵权的损失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在本案中，当事女子诽谤的事证确凿，而且不无作伪证的嫌疑。其对当事男子的直接伤害是数十分钟的问话、护照手机被扣以及人格名誉的损害，潜在可能的伤害更是“有期徒刑加鞭刑套餐”的重刑。然而当事男子并没有反诉女方，而是“就此原谅”。实际上，这增加了公共利益受损的风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以新加坡麻醉科医生杨绍南为例，他在遭遇一名女子的性侵诬告之后四年（2017-2021）才得以洗脱冤屈，但冗长的法律程序让他丢了公立医院的职位，付出了巨额经济损失，承受了名誉的毁灭性打击，最终打赢官司也是于事无补，控方至今也未对女子提供虚假证据作出任何行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上早在2021年9月13日，新加坡国会就有议员联合提案说，在制定新的法律增加对性侵罪刑罚的同时，也要寻求对那些遭遇错误指控者的保护。加强对诬告受害者的保护，首先就需要加大对诬告犯罪者的打击，鼓励受害者站出来反诉，不能再让性侵诬告变成一种“低成本高收益”的游戏，让“认知偏差”成为诬告者脱罪减罪的捷径。诚如杨绍南医生在真相大白之后表示：法律制度应当能对滥用法律的人施加足够的威慑力，同时不会阻止真正遭受性犯罪的受害者勇敢地站出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[礼盒混装、糕点伪装……月饼何时“包装有度”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258144]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-06 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/RS8BqslrScjLpqvROABv5zXcTRD8Yj8tDTuhfG52.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/RS8BqslrScjLpqvROABv5zXcTRD8Yj8tDTuhfG52.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;新国标的实施可以推动厂商专注于月饼本身的创新、取缔过于精美繁复的包装，但目前仍然存在部分商家“钻空子”的行为，需要相关部门加强监管。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个中秋国庆长假有多少人的早餐被月饼承包？又有多少人注意到家中堆积如山的月饼礼盒正在发生哪些变化？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果你手边正好有月饼礼盒，不妨做个小测验：打开礼盒，除了月饼是否还配备刀叉、盘子或其他产品？从月饼所在的包装袋向外数，能不能数出四层？如果得到肯定的答案，那么眼前的月饼极有可能因“过度包装”违反国家相关标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该标准为国家市场监管总局（国家标准委）修订发布的《限制商品过度包装要求食品和化妆品》（GB 23350—2021），于2023年9月1日正式实施。该标准第1号修改单从包装空隙率、包装层数、包装成本、混装要求四个方面进一步提出限制月饼过度包装的规定，已于2022年8月15日实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据第1号修改单，月饼不应与其他产品混装，包装不应超过三层。销售价格在100元以上的月饼，包装成本占销售价格的比例不得超过15%。同时包装材料不得使用贵金属、红木等贵重材料。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一年过渡期后，月饼是否依旧存在过度包装现象？南方周末记者随机抽样调查了电商平台的月饼礼盒商品，发现混装现象最为突出，也有一部分商家在商品描述上玩花样，规避相对严格的月饼管理标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市海淀区计量检测所工程师张梦娇向南方周末记者表示，月饼作为中秋传统食物，引人联想的画面是家人团聚而不是精美包装，尽管月饼具有一定的社交属性，但收礼者也希望月饼能够物有所值，新国标的实施可以推动厂商专注于月饼本身的创新、取缔过于精美繁复的包装，但目前仍然存在部分商家“钻空子”的行为，需要相关部门加强监管。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;月饼混装的重灾区：文创和联名礼盒&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;月饼礼盒包含塑料刀叉，曾是广式月饼的“常规操作”，禁止混装的新规出台后，除去用于保护月饼的食品用脱氧剂、冰袋，包括刀叉在内的所有产品都不被允许出现在月饼礼盒中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者调查发现，2023年的月饼市场上仍然存在不少混装产品，文创和联名礼盒的混装现象最为突出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，知名食品品牌稻香村推出小兔顺耳IP联名款月饼礼盒，礼盒中包含稻香村月饼馅料包和DIY模具，并提供了制作月饼的教程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/E1WdzWFPUkXj7ZwQcnixLf2EV21LWNEuScV5Wsyn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;774&quot; height=&quot;1313&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/E1WdzWFPUkXj7ZwQcnixLf2EV21LWNEuScV5Wsyn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253061&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月5日，稻香村联合陈小桃推出月饼礼盒，混装DIY模具。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（天猫稻香村旗舰店/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;部分餐饮品牌也推出混装礼盒，并屡探500元上限。2022年6月，国家发改委、市场监管总局等四部门联合发布《关于遏制“天价”月饼、促进行业健康发展的公告》，提出对单价超过500元的盒装月饼实行重点监管。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高端连锁品牌大董和宋代院体细笔绘画研究学者刘庆杨联名推出“董之月·礼享集”月饼礼盒，礼盒包含七款月饼和一幅挂画，标价468元（优惠后398元）。产品种类下设两种选项，虽然名为“月饼馅种类”，但大董电商客服告诉南方周末记者，两款礼盒的月饼种类一致，区别在于收到的画作是《百种牡丹谱》还是《梧桐双月兔》。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了食品品牌，部分文创定制商家也在试探着月饼过度包装的底线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，淘宝平台上一家主营节日定制伴手礼的店铺推出的中秋礼盒分为不同组合的套餐，套餐内标配2粒百草味月饼，消费者还可以自主选择香薰片、乌龙茶、香水、贺卡等内容物进行多元化混装。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Jv26GpQJVUDfv0enJJsYaviqmYY7zHPae3MGK6Dl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;1385&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/Jv26GpQJVUDfv0enJJsYaviqmYY7zHPae3MGK6Dl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;某文创定制店铺，售卖“月饼+文创”组合的中秋伴手礼。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（淘宝店铺/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“按照月饼标准管理的文创产品，只要装入了月饼之外的产品就属于混装。如果一款礼盒采用创意包装，包装本身可以用作其他用途（如带镜子的收纳盒、带玩具的桌游板），也需要先确认该礼盒是否按照月饼标准管理。”张梦娇说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;混淆糕点和月饼&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;逃避处罚的新招&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《限制商品过度包装要求食品和化妆品》（GB 23350—2021）国家标准第1号修改单对月饼包装提出要求，但并非所有月饼礼盒装的都是“真月饼”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者发现，本土巧克力品牌诺梵推出的“月光之城”巧克力月饼礼盒混装了刀叉和盘子，电商平台月销量超过4000件。但该品牌客服向南方周末记者提供的商品外包装显示，该产品的食品名称为“月饼型巧克力制品”，参照巧克力及巧克力制品标准管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dKn03YIl3wwOw3Z9tOjJ2g49c0eOPcJlwozGfN3U.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;787&quot; height=&quot;1622&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/dKn03YIl3wwOw3Z9tOjJ2g49c0eOPcJlwozGfN3U.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253063&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月2日，诺梵电商客服告诉南方周末记者，除两个款式外，其他巧克力月饼礼盒都混装刀叉和盘子。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（天猫诺梵旗舰店咨询页/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者在电商平台随机抽取了10个不同品牌存在混装问题的月饼礼盒，其中有3款礼盒虽然在营销时标有“月饼”字样、食品外形为传统月饼形状，实际上产品却是按照糕点执行标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市海淀区市场监督管理局标准化科魏彦丹向南方周末记者表示，在我国境内生产、销售和进口的所有食品（含散装食品）和化妆品的销售包装均适用于《限制商品过度包装要求食品和化妆品》（GB 23350—2021）。南方周末记者查询发现，根据第1号修改单，月饼、粽子的包装要求更为严格，除月饼、粽子外，对其他食品和化妆品并未做出混装限制。这意味着，糕点、巧克力等食品虽然适用新国标的限制过度包装要求，但仍然可以与其他产品混装。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照现行的月饼推荐性国家标准（GB/T 19855-2015），月饼的定义为使用小麦粉等谷物粉或植物粉、油、糖（或不加糖）等为主要原料制成饼皮，包裹各种馅料，经加工而成，在中秋节食用为主的传统节日食品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这种情况下，如果实际判断为其它糕点，但按月饼售卖，那么可能存在实物与描述不符的情况，需要进一步确认其售卖食品与其标签是否标注一致。”张梦娇表示，通常，预包装食品标签上的品名、执行标准、食品生产许可证编号等，均可作为判断依据，或由主管部门综合判断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者发现，还有一类商家在商品描述中故意模糊月饼和糕点的概念，将“真月饼”伪装成糕点，试图规避新国标对月饼混装的要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市海淀区市场监督管理局标准化科魏彦丹告诉南方周末记者，根据《中华人民共和国标准化法》第二十七条的规定，“企业应当按照标准组织生产经营活动，其生产的产品、提供的服务应当符合企业公开标准的技术要求。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;如何判断月饼是否过度包装？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“以《蟾宫玉兔图》为灵感，礼盒采用前后镂空图案，放入灯饰装饰，如揽明月入怀”，这段介绍来自一款以新中式包装为亮点、包含“高档”“送礼”等关键词的月饼礼盒，该产品标价358元，在电商平台吸引了上百人购买，评论区里不乏“外包装好看”的买家推荐语。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为普通消费者，又该如何判断购买的月饼过度包装呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据《限制商品过度包装要求食品和化妆品》（GB 23350—2021）国家标准第1号修改单，判断月饼是否存在过度包装可以从四个指标着手：包装层数、包装成本、混装以及包装空隙率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/BRKT4wkwzvaCnYeTBKnzwGGG0TXpskpIyXjuWqgw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1039&quot; height=&quot;1503&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/05/BRKT4wkwzvaCnYeTBKnzwGGG0TXpskpIyXjuWqgw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253062&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（梁淑怡/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;包装层数是指完全包裹内装物的可物理拆分的包装的层数，其中完全包裹指的是使包装物不致散出的包装方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果是敞口的手提袋、固定内装物或包装物的半托、包装盒外的腰封，不符合完全包裹的定义，都不能算作一层。而抽屉式包装，哪怕有两层抽屉，也只计入一层包装。对于包装精美复杂但层数符合要求的创意月饼包装，可以进一步判断包装成本是否违规。”张梦娇说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;包装空隙率根据月饼的净含量计算得出，月饼单件净含量越大，标准规定的空隙率越小，单件净含量大于50g的月饼，空隙率必须≤30%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张梦娇表示，由于计算方法较为复杂，包装空隙率一般由技术机构在实验室对抽检样品进行检测。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海市市场监督管理局向南方周末记者表示，自2023年8月以来，上海市市场监督管理局对本市市场销售的月饼开展了过度包装监督抽查，涉及超市、连锁面包房、酒店等52家生产经营单位，共抽查月饼80批次，月饼包装违规的主因是包装空隙率不合格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IPG中国首席经济学家柏文喜告诉南方周末记者，打击过度包装有助于降低消费者购买成本，提高购物体验，也能减少消费者购买高价月饼的行为，从而降低社会浪费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者从上海市市场监管局获悉，消费者可以使用上海市市场监管局开发的微信小程序“包装有度”，通过输入商品包装简单信息，只需1分钟时间即能初步判定商品是否涉嫌过度包装。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>