<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[日本作家铃木凉美：我不认为夜生活出身的人写书有什么稀奇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260978]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/J1df1hgCGaZhUHvm6xw2wqPEDmdfcHZDhjKBS9ZA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/J1df1hgCGaZhUHvm6xw2wqPED mdfcHZDhjKBS9ZA. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258877&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Suzuki Ryomi’s mother is Haijima Kari, a researcher of Japanese children’s literature. , she wrote a collection of essays &quot;A Bouquet for Love and the Womb&quot; before and after taking care of her sick mother, unfolding this complex mother-daughter relationship that is both alienated and full of love. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suzuki Ryomi is a &quot;hot girl who grew up in Tokyo&quot;, who is in love with Cinderella-style misfortune. Will consider themselves a victim. Her speeches and works reveal lightness, some humor, and inherent heaviness and pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the collection of essays &quot;A Bouquet for Love and the Womb&quot;, she devoted a lot of space to writing about her rebellion against her original family. Her family must be the envy of most people. Her mother is the translator Kari Haijima, and her father is Suzuki Akira, an honorary professor at Hosei University. Happiness is hard-won, and the pieces of life gradually accumulate tension between mother and daughter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are not free. Although we are not expecting a big reversal of fortune, we are still shackles. We can always feel the mother’s curse hidden between our spine and skin, and we can’t help but feel chills in our bones. .&quot; The book writes about the mother&#39;s overly ardent hopes for her daughter. She wanted to get rid of the regrets she had in her original family and married life, but she changed her mind and injected specific trivialities into her daughter&#39;s life, always in the name of love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If she follows the established path, Suzuki Ryomi can easily become the stereotype of a &quot;decent person&quot;. That was not the case. She knew a part of the world that many people knew and experienced, but few could express. After entering the night world by mistake, she discovered many familiar stories among the women around her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;As long as you walk into the night, you will temporarily forget everything else. The longer you sink into the dazzling and crazy world, and the longer you stay in a world that worships emptiness as nobility, the less you can touch it. That thing.&quot; Suzuki Ryomi sold underwear to middle-aged men in high school. After graduation, she &quot;couldn&#39;t wait to go to nightclubs and work many odd jobs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nightlife compared to the daytime is indeed paradoxical, &quot;there are as many girls as Cinderella-like as you want.&quot; Women pay for the cowherd, who is often more domineering; female escorts need to endure the domineering male guests. A large number of details more or less reflect the essence of gender issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The men and women there occasionally share the cruel joys and sorrows. As time goes by, the fragile &quot;equality&quot; will inevitably disappear, and the people in the night world have overdrawn their youth early. Many female practitioners in custom shops have decent family backgrounds and education, and college students often work part-time jobs at night; while the cowherds are often in a difficult situation, with average education levels and lack of ability to make a living. All these people will age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suzuki Ryomi went to graduate school and wrote a master&#39;s thesis on pornographic film actresses. She worked as a journalist and later resigned. In 2014, &quot;Weekly Bunshun&quot; reported on her past as an actress in pornographic films. She is now a well-known author and considered a sociologist, although she denies the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she started writing &quot;Flowers for Love and the Womb,&quot; her mother had her first cancer surgery. Some time later, my mother&#39;s cancer recurred, and she died half a year before finishing the book. Her mother repeatedly said: &quot;I&#39;m sorry, I still have many things to tell you, but I don&#39;t have time.&quot; Through writing and recalling, Suzuki Ryomi discovered the similarities between herself and her mother, and also understood more about her mother&#39;s various ways of doing things. . She once said: &quot;It is very lonely to lose such an enemy and a friend.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later than &quot;Flowers for Love and the Womb&quot;, Suzuki Ryomi&#39;s correspondence with the scholar Chizuru Ueno The collection &quot;Starting from the Limit&quot; was published. She was born in 1983, more than thirty years younger than Chizuru Ueno. The age gap between the two is about the same as that of mother and daughter. It is no surprise that there is a huge difference in the perspective of understanding the world. In the correspondence, she mentioned that a man who had had sexual relations several times said to his friend in a serious manner in front of her: &quot;Which man is willing to date a woman who has acted in AV.&quot; Those men who bought underwear had already The impression that it was impossible for me to understand this creature seemed to be happening again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suzuki Ryomi&#39;s mother always said: &quot;If you are caught for fraud or terrorist activities, I will do my best to stand with you. If you become an AV actress, forget it.&quot; &quot;Such words are like the swan song that Ms. Haijima Kari sang for part of her life. At the same time, she also said: &quot;I am very happy. I have raised a good daughter.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/kdZnRltNFpZnTR2Q8EwLTLu9FNTwg2EEangNog4Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1044&quot; height=&quot;1568&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/kdZnRltNFpZnTR2Q8EwLTLu9FNTwg2EEangNog4Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258878&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center ;&quot;>;UTF-8&#39;&#39; Japanese writer Suzuki Ryomi was born in an intellectual family in Tokyo in 1983. She once worked as a bartender and a pornographic film actress. After retiring, she was admitted to the University of Tokyo for a master&#39;s degree and became a journalist. He was shortlisted for the Akutagawa Prize, Japan&#39;s highest literary award, for two years. He is well-known to Chinese readers for his collection of dialogues with Chizuru Ueno, &quot;Starting at the Limit.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the publisher)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;At least my mother is not the kind of person who doesn&#39;t care about the world&quot;&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is an impressive description of mother in the book: &quot;They are performing another kind of mysterious and unspeakable magic, never stopping, spreading the powder called love to us.&quot; You then recorded some suffocating past events. So, can you go back to that statement? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The relationship with the mother has an immeasurable impact on the child&#39;s future life. This is not a simple dichotomy of love and dislike, likes and dislikes, respect and contempt, but a complex interaction between the mother&#39;s expectations, preferences, personality and habits and the child&#39;s personality and life. Although there are exceptions, it is generally believed that mothers love their children, and I can indeed feel that my mother loves me. However, I feel that the so-called &quot;love&quot; is not always warm and soft, there is also a lot of mud and roughness in it. Many young people will more or less rebel against their parents&#39; overbearing and overly strong love and achieve independence by having a world unknown to their mothers. But even so, the relationship and influence with the mother is more or less undeniable. I use the word &quot;magic&quot; to describe this feeling: I had been a part of my mother&#39;s life, and once I became independent, I would be separated from her, but never completely separated, as if by magic. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After several years, your feelings for your mother have changed. What changes? Has the “magic” faded? Will you understand her better because of some memories? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Basically, I think as we grow older, we will slowly have our own world that our parents don’t know about. The &quot;magic&quot; with our mother fades because we will have faces that we can share with others but have never shown our parents, and things we have never told them. During my bad teenage years, I managed to develop a relationship with my parents: I was connected to them but didn&#39;t necessarily share everything with them. It is not so much that a certain memory has deepened my understanding of my mother, but that now that my mother has passed away and time has passed, when I am the same age as the mother who once raised me, I recall every bit of our childhood. I sometimes imagine that maybe that was the mood. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are in &quot;A Bouquet for Love and the Womb&quot; &quot;&quot; writes about the subtle emotions between mother and daughter. They both think that the other is in a better position, which seems to be a kind of competition between mother and daughter. Is this phenomenon common between mothers and daughters? Or is it unique to your family? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mother and daughter are the two closest and most similar people in the world. Dependent on mother&#39;s relationship. When they grow up, they are in an environment where they can conform to the same gender, and naturally a very complex and primitive competitive relationship will arise. I think many people have had this experience. During adolescence, they are unwilling to accept the female side of their mother, but sometimes mothers are also unwilling to accept the female side of their daughters. I think there is a subtle psychology in it. Both of them obviously love each other very much, but they don&#39;t want her to be like themselves. I think the meaning of parents in life is different for everyone, and for me, they are the ones who keep asking me questions. Even now that they have passed away, I feel like I am still being questioned by my mother. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In China, parents often want their children to have a partner. , or urging marriage due to family reproduction issues. Is this phenomenon common in Japan? If so, does it have anything to do with the gender of the child? Is the reason due to child care issues, or is it just a stubborn point of view? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In recent years, it is said that more and more parents value their children&#39;s wishes or feel lonely when their children finally get married. But I often heard in the past that if you are still single at the age of thirty, your parents will nag you to get married. This situation still exists in some areas of Japan and elsewhere. Marriage in Japan used to be a family affair. Marriage is a necessary means to maintain the survival of the family, so the pressure on the eldest son is particularly great. Women, for their part, want to marry themselves off, even though it has nothing to do with the survival of their own families. But Japan is a country with a lot of peer pressure. Everyone else gets married at about this age. Only my family doesn’t get married. People will talk about it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, I have recently begun to think that in real life, there may be a more real desire, and that is the happiness of children. Of course, there are forms of single happiness. But I think parents still hope that their daughters can experience the happiness of starting a family, and do not want their daughters to live alone in this world one day after they die. At least my mother is not the kind of person who doesn&#39;t care about the world, so when she said she hoped I could have a companion one day, I felt she was doing it for my own good and hoped I could experience the happiness she experienced. Of course, some people may feel stressed or nosy about this. And in Japan, some sexual orientations are not recognized and can be married, so I can&#39;t say that this is completely well-intentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, I think it&#39;s best not to take your parents&#39; words too seriously, just listen to their opinions from time to time, but don&#39;t take them too seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Now that I am really 40 years old, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;but &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;not much has changed&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As expressed in the Chinese word &quot;forty without confusion&quot;, it seems that people of this age will understand There are many principles, such as how to treat others and how to fight for rights and interests. You mentioned in &quot;Flowers for Love and the Womb&quot; that when you were about thirty years old, you discovered that the few people who stayed in Tokyo were not only friends, but also survivors. When you were forty, did you have a similar realization? A certain idea that seems natural actually changes quietly with age. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was a teenager or 20 years old, I imagined that I would know clearly when I was 40 years old. No matter what you want to do or what you don’t want to do, your relationship with others will be stable. But now that I&#39;m actually forty, I feel like I haven&#39;t changed much. I still wanted a lot of things, still lacked confidence in myself, and still worried about what others thought of me. I didn’t grow much. At least work-wise, though, I have more experience than I had in my twenties, so I have more concrete ideas about what I want to do in the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;So, when communicating with younger girls , do you feel the generational difference obviously? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Sometimes I feel there is no difference, and sometimes I feel it is completely different. Overall, young girls today are much more docile, kind, classy and mature than they were when we were young. But at the same time, they don’t have that much energy to do stupid things when they are young. Perhaps it is because Japan&#39;s economy has been in recession for a long time and people are full of uncertainty about the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said in &quot;Starting from the Limit&quot;, &quot;Standing at the limit, I look at things from where I am.&quot; Are there any recent changes or shifts in the “limits” of how you view the world? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I may be a pessimist, a realist at best, a cynic at worst, so I had a habit from the beginning of limiting my expectations, assuming that things were never going to change no matter what. Society won&#39;t change anyway, so let&#39;s enjoy freedom as much as possible in this society, etc. However, for example, the issue of sexual assault has recently begun to be widely reported in Japan, which was unimaginable twenty years ago. In this sense, I think I should be more idealistic. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you because of communicating with Ms. Chiheko No? , and lead to some new thinking? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think I have changed drastically since we ended the correspondence. It&#39;s just that when I think about something, I ask myself, &quot;Is this really the case?&quot; &quot;Isn&#39;t there anyone else who has such an idea?&quot; I think the main thing is that now I have another channel to think about problems. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;When a woman has several categories of attributes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;it often scares men&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What literature and social science books have had a great influence on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ryomi Suzuki:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For example, Mieko Kanai&#39;s &quot;Yeye Shengge&quot; and Inoue Yasu&#39;s &quot;Japanese Grammar&quot;. When I was young, I didn&#39;t really realize that thinking about problems was an exciting thing. I thought it was more exciting to give up thinking, such as nightlife and consumption. But after encountering a good book, I realized that the opposite was actually true. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What does the night world currently occupy in your life? What proportion? Would you talk about your identity as a writer and sociologist with your friends in the night world? Do they understand this part of your life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the current life, the participation rate in the night world is now almost 0%, up to 10%, but my brain I still spend 50% of my time thinking about the people living in the night world. I don’t consider myself a sociologist, but not many of my former Night World friends know that I’m a writer. Whether it is current acquaintances or new friends, everyone knows that I also write books. In fact, I don’t think it’s unusual for someone with a nightlife background to write a book. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will the temporary equality of the sexes in the night world be possible? Will it become more and more unstable as we age? For example, if an elderly cowherd no longer engages in this job, he may become a grumpy uncle. Will the equality brought about by sharing the joys and sorrows with the women around him easily disappear? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ryomi Suzuki:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;York World is basically divided into male and female characters, and I feel like gender equality is not well recognized there. Because many people sell their looks, youth has great commercial value, and this trend is more obvious among women. Rather, this &quot;world&quot; in the sense that young women here have more power than middle-aged men can create a different gender balance than the normal daylight world. Yet it is also a sad world, as young capital is dwindling every year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Read &quot;A Bouquet for Love and the Womb&quot; When reading, I feel through words that men and women in the night world are somewhat insecure. What kind of protection should they get? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Even those who once had no problem surviving in the night world will later encounter problems in life due to the loss of youth. difficulty. I think there should be social security for people who have problems after leaving the night world. Indeed, some people enter the night world at an early age and have no choice. The best social security is to give them the opportunity to receive a proper education, regardless of the circumstances of their birth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can you imagine an ideal relationship between the sexes? Way? What is your understanding of the “male gaze”? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I still don’t know what an ideal relationship should be like, where we use each other’s fantasies without hurting each other. Change slowly and flexibly? When you want to use one word to describe the male gaze, you can actually imagine a lot of things. For example, when dividing the roles that women play for men into different categories, I think it is masculine: mother, wife, coworker, mistress , prostitutes, students, etc. When a woman has several attributes at the same time, many people will be very angry. For example, when a colleague is a mistress or his wife is a prostitute, it often scares men. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Finally, could you introduce your current work progress? ? For example, your novel &quot;Backstroke&quot; tells the story of a forty-year-old woman looking back on her life. Is this a summary for you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suzuki Ryomi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Backstroke&quot;, I only reviewed what happened in a certain month when I was nineteen, so I can&#39;t say It is completely autobiographical, but it reflects strongly on my experiences. When I turned thirty-nine, I realized that twenty years had passed. When writing a novel, I often draw from past experiences or memories and weave them into a text. This is nothing special. But I have a soft spot for it because it is closer to my own experience than anything else I have ever written. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[武大靖：期待新生活]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260998]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/21/FDFQyeVtbLaS66HB2YDLtYGRHf5iLyLDfFzH827s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;572&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/FDFQyeVtbLaS66HB2YDLtYGRHf5iLyLDfF zH827s. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258961&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 22, 2018, men&#39;s short track speed skating at the Pyeongchang Winter Olympics in South Korea In the 500-meter final, Wu Dajing won the championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The &quot;new journey&quot; of the speed skating veteran&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On a windy winter day in Beijing, Wu Dajing appeared in the studio to record an exclusive interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shooting plane required a change of thin clothes. In order to relax him and quickly complete the shooting, the photographer joked: &quot;It is summer at 30℃!&quot; Wu Dajing showed a big boy&#39;s smile and cooperated patiently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This day is November 12, 2023. What a coincidence is that on November 12, 2018, five years ago, Wu Dajing won the Men’s Short Track Speed ​​Skating World Cup Salt Lake City Station in the 2018-2019 season. In the 500-meter final, he won the championship with a time of 39.505 seconds, breaking his own world record set at the PyeongChang Winter Olympics in February 2018. As of now, Wu Dajing is still the holder of both the Olympic record and the world record in this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past five years, Wu Dajing has experienced the glory brought by his fame-at his peak in 2018, he broke the world record three times in a year and set a new Olympic record; he has also experienced the trough-injury. Under heavy pressure, he finally stood on the highest podium at the Beijing Winter Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Beijing Winter Olympics, for 28-year-old Wu Dajing, it was the best time to retire after success. Age and injuries will only bring greater uncertainty to the future. Retiring at this time can be regarded as a perfect ending. But Wu Dajing chose to continue standing on the ice rink. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Recently, I have been carrying out rehabilitation and restorative training step by step.&quot; Wu Dajing said. In 2023, he participated in some domestic competitions and will continue to participate in other competitions next year and beyond. What he is most worried about is the recurrence of old injuries, like an elusive bomb. He doesn’t know when it will explode next. “So now I try to extend my cycle as much as possible and make a sufficient long-term plan. It must be very scientific. Be careful and you may not make it to the end if you are not careful at all.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ S9aj6ar7tSsUFdbTKqDeVvt1OQirCsFfBxBOri95.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;664&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/S9aj6ar7tSsUFdbTKqDeVvt1OQirCsFfBxBOri9 5.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;258960&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Dajing feels relaxed&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has been preparing for the Beijing Winter Olympics for 4 years. Before the game, he injured his right knee, and then the waist injury recurred. &quot;It was a particularly hard blow at that time, because you didn&#39;t know if you could play. All the athletes had gone to train, and I was the only one lying there. It was quite uncomfortable. One thing, I was very helpless. At that time, I felt like a child, knowing nothing and unable to do anything.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, he withstood the pressure, worked with the team, and won the short track speed He won a gold medal in the men&#39;s and women&#39;s 2000-meter mixed skating relay, which was also China&#39;s first gold medal at the Beijing Winter Olympics. After the game, he and Fan Kexin hugged each other tightly. As the oldest athletes in the men&#39;s and women&#39;s teams, they have both experienced three Olympic Games. &quot;At that moment, we really understood each other with just one look. It was like watching a movie in my mind, and all the details of the preparations for the war in the past few years emerged.&quot; Wu Dajing recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people once said to him, &quot;Otherwise you will quit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There will also be entanglements. At some point, I feel that otherwise I will quit. Because no matter from the perspective of Neither my physical condition nor my age condition is in the best state, so I weighed and compared myself, but in the end I still felt that I couldn’t let it go. Skating has always been my passion. As an athlete, I have been engaged in my favorite industry for so many years. It doesn&#39;t mean that you can just let it go. For me now, it&#39;s easy to persist, but it&#39;s not easy to let go.&quot; Wu Dajing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Dajing has created many histories of short track speed skating in China and is called the &quot;King of Sprints&quot; by the International Skating Union. He is the first Chinese men&#39;s Olympic gold medal in ice racing and the first Chinese men&#39;s Olympic gold medal in short track speed skating. At the PyeongChang Winter Olympics, he won the championship with a time of 39.584 seconds, breaking the world record and Olympic record, and won the first and only gold medal for the Chinese team at the Winter Olympics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From being a sparring partner for the women&#39;s team to becoming a world champion, he described it as &quot;every time he is breaking through and challenging himself.&quot; Now, facing this new journey, what he needs to challenge is his mentality, which is different from the past. &quot;Enjoy the process of preparing for the war, the process of training and sweating every day, and the process of tiring myself to exhaustion every day. The rest is Yes, results are no longer the only important thing to me. The moment athletes are on the court, they actually have to prove that they have achieved good results, but now I am more passionate about it, so I use a better mentality to do it. Prepare, maybe it will be better. I can still be an athlete, I can still stand on the ice rink, I think this is enough.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/6MjG4run4Y6Vsj6fnq8MCbiQaR6oKgma3UK60fpH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;664&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/21/6MjG4run4Y6Vsj6fnq8MCbiQaR6oKgma3UK60fpH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258963&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Dajing&#39;s sense of relaxation&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Childhood&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Training Ground and New Identity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, Wu Dajing became A coach in the short track speed skating project of Jilin Provincial Sports Bureau Ice Sports Management Center. As both an athlete and a coach, this is a new beginning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, before Wu Dajing became a coach, he began to play the role of a link in the team very early. In September 2018, Wu Dajing was elected as the new captain of the Chinese short track speed skating team. In addition to improving his own skills, he also began to cultivate the team&#39;s ability to collaborate with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This reminded him of his childhood, when young athletes were afraid of their coaches. When Wu Dajing first joined the national team, because the coach&#39;s energy was limited, he would give more time to the main athletes. &quot;So when I was in my first and second year with the national team, I felt very happy if the coach could say a word to me one day and help me with a move. The coach talked to me, and I was happy all day long. &quot;When he didn&#39;t talk to me or give me guidance, it was a very uncomfortable day.&quot; Wu Dajing recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“At this time, we need someone in the team who is both a senior and a teammate to stand up and tell us the most real physical condition or problems we encounter, and then we will help. He changes or helps him avoid some detours. We have been doing this in recent years.&quot; Wu Dajing pointed out that the coach&#39;s attention may affect the mentality of the players, and he hopes that he can play such a role - - Help coaches share attention, help juniors, and become a bond between them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/dfB1Y8mru3d3ckt0RXHCdlFcFA4jvDkLBuHchq2g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;664&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/dfB1Y8mru3d3ckt0RXHCdlFcFA4jvDkLBuHchq2g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258965&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Dajing feels relaxed&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From personal responsibility to collective glory, Wu Dajing fully feels the strength and value brought by a team. &quot;Skating left me with beautiful and scary experiences in my childhood. From the collective life I experienced as a child, to the relationship I had with my teammates when I grew up, to the time I was able to represent my motherland in competitions and perform on the world stage. Himself. This experience is wonderful and worth remembering.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his childhood, he usually had to get up at more than 4 o&#39;clock in the morning. The winter in the Northeast is extremely cold. There are no street lights in small cities. His mother rides a bicycle to take him to the ice rink, and the road is covered with snow. Before dawn, they put up a light on the ice rink. &quot;We were training there, and parents used big brooms to sweep the ice on the ice rink. There was a clear division of labor - there were those who swept the ice and those who poured the ice. Then these parents I spontaneously built a simple shed and lit a fire inside to keep warm.&quot; There is no board wall outside such a training place, and parents use snow to build a protective wall to prevent the children from falling out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was a child, because the price of skates was relatively expensive, I usually bought larger ones. My feet hurt, and they often bleed and scab over and over again. &quot;But when I was a child, I didn&#39;t feel bitter. (I even) felt that it was very comfortable on the ice rink, and I could even put on skates. I didn&#39;t feel cold at that time, but now I think about it, it is really cold. I am particularly afraid of the cold now. Maybe when I was a child It’s too cold.” Wu Dajing smiled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Dajing once said that he has a pair of &quot;very ugly feet&quot;. He has accumulated &quot;pimples&quot; due to ill-fitting skates and accumulated training over the years, and even has deformed bones in some places. &quot;I said that I must wear good shoes and buy good shoes in the future. The thing I am most sorry for in my life is my feet. They have been witnessing my journey of more than ten years. From the beginning of skating to now, I still feel He is still accompanying me through hardships. He often jokes that I will take better care of my feet in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Wu Dajing built a charity ice rink in his hometown of Jiamusi, Heilongjiang to support his hometown. The short track career is located at the &quot;wild ice rink&quot; where he trained when he was a child. He hopes to give his children more training venues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, this public ice rink has a lot of people in winter, including children and ice skating enthusiasts, and they organize themselves to maintain the ice rink. &quot;I don&#39;t think I built it in vain. Many people use it. Children, the elderly, and young people can all skate here. I think it is a very meaningful thing and can help more people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Dajing also feels happy to devote himself to public welfare undertakings. After he won his first gold medal at the Beijing Winter Olympics, he got a golden dungeon and would sleep with it in his arms. But on the closing day, he decided to auction off the Golden Dundun and donate the proceeds to the &quot;Project Hope·Dajing Ice and Snow Charity Project&quot; to create conditions for ice and snow sports for rural teenagers. He feels, &quot;We can help others with visible results, which maximizes its meaning.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/21/MWJ2d93PXuCo5qs2C5bFLHyQCGSu4rKoDSURFtea.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;657&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/21/MWJ2d93PXuCo5qs2C5bFLHyQCGSu4rKoDSURFtea.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258964&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;February 5, 2022, in Beijing in the winter of 2022 In the mixed team relay final of the Olympic short track speed skating event, the Chinese team won the championship. Wu Dajing celebrates after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;As long as you feel worthy It is enough for you to be worthy of the&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;project you are engaged in&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly ：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As a veteran of short track speed skating, what kind of new stage of life do you think you have entered? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Dajing:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Now there is an additional coach to help the team improve together. This is a new beginning, and it is enough to continue to shine in this project. Although I am in a confused period now and I feel like I still want to prove myself, my mentality will have changed a bit compared to before, but I can still stand on the training ground and exert all my strength, which is enough. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Competitive sports not only test results, but also test mentality. In the past, you just had to practice well by yourself, but now it is different. You need to think about the entire team and the young athletes, and the responsibilities on your shoulders are heavier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We can no longer joke with our teammates as unscrupulously as before. This team needs to move forward. I am also slowly exploring this process, not only integrating into the feelings between our athletes and teammates, but also improving my identity as a coach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you use three keywords to describe yourself, what would you do? Which three to choose? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Dajing:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Luck, happiness, and expectation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was lucky because I had a wonderful childhood, did things that other children did not challenge, and achieved ideal results. When we are athletes, we have a strong motherland to support us. We are lucky to have such a glorious moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Happiness is that I can still do what I like to do now, and maybe in a few years, I can still engage in this career. This is the happiness of the moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The expectation is that I will face the choice of transformation in the future. Whether I am an athlete, a coach, or engaged in other things in the industry, it will be a new test for me. I am looking forward to the arrival of a new life, especially yearning for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have just recalled many moments. Is there any moment that stands out? Zhang photos impressed you particularly? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wu Dajing: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; In fact, there are very few photos in our family, and almost five or six can be added in total. In the summer of 2022, the three people came to Beijing together and brought the medals. Then, then I wore a lot of clothes and took a group photo in the middle. For many years, I haven&#39;t accompanied their parents to spend the Spring Festival and have not accompanied them to live a good time for a while. Next, they will bear the responsibility of their families more. I washed this photo and placed at home. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How will you overcome anxiety, bold pursuit The life of &quot;full score&quot;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wu Dajing: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I will be anxious when my results are not improved. I am an old athlete in this industry. Facing the transformation of new identity. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; As the age is older, this anxiety will be obvious every day in my body. I think it is normal to have anxiety at different times. A good mentality is not to say that you ca n’t be anxious, but how to solve it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For myself, I find my own direction -I really want to do what I want to do, and whether to prepare in that direction. After doing this well, I feel that anxiety will be less. There will be more sense of responsibility towards the goal, and the rest is just to fight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Character Weekly: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; Is there a veteran you admire very much, he has insisted on the field on the field Idol? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Wu Dajing: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Athletes are actually admired by each other, because only enough concentration can become the best in a certain field, such as Malone, such as Malone, Gong Lizhen, Su Bingtian, etc., and those who silently paid for the Chinese sports industry are all people I admire from the heart. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; They are examples of the entire sports industry worth learning. They have chosen to continue to persist and impact their dreams. Although the results will decline and face doubts, as long as you feel that you are worthy of yourself, you can afford the project you are engaged in. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[最高人民检察院依法对李再勇决定逮捕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261016]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 14:34:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reporter learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate on November 21 that the former member and vice chairman of the Guizhou Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference Li Zaiyong&#39;s suspected bribery and abuse of power case was investigated by the National Supervisory Commission and transferred to the procuratorate for review and prosecution. A few days ago, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate made a decision to arrest Li Zaiyong on suspicion of bribery and abuse of power in accordance with the law. The case is under further processing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[虎扑“高校评分”爆火：哪些才是一流大学的硬指标？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260986]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, &quot;Hupu College Rating&quot; has attracted widespread attention and heated discussions, especially among college students. Many &quot;witty comments&quot; have become new &quot;internet memes&quot;. For example, the People&#39;s Public Security University of China commented that &quot;gathering is like a fire, scattering is like a police station&quot;, Tianjin Normal University commented that &quot;dormitory conditions are suspected of violating the Geneva Convention&quot;, and Northeast Petroleum University commented that it has &quot;excellent traditions and has served two presidents.&quot; &quot;, Changsha University of Science and Technology&#39;s &quot;E-Sports 985, Rap 211&quot;, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public opinion field responded to this &quot;college rating&quot; with mostly voices of goodwill and tolerance. There is no other reason. This &quot;college rating&quot; is an evaluation from the perspective of students. &quot;Satisfaction&quot; and &quot;trust&quot; are the standards based on which students rate and write comments. It is more interesting and participatory than those conducted by other institutions. &quot;University Rankings&quot;. On the occasion of public opinion and carnival, there are also some problems worthy of analysis: What kind of &quot;college evaluation&quot; is credible? What kind of “college assessment” do we need? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The outside world has never lacked criticism of major universities, and the evaluation forms are also diverse: from various university rankings by independent institutions, to industry association breakdowns to professional lists, to formal or formal or professional rankings in the corporate world. There are many private comments. However, almost no assessment can satisfy everyone, and no set of &quot;rankings&quot; or &quot;lists&quot; can eliminate controversy. The reason is naturally the wide variety of evaluation subjects and evaluation standards, as well as the merits of the selection process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to cater to various &quot;university rankings&quot;, Chinese and foreign universities have also tried their best. For example, in order to improve their ratings, some domestic universities recruit international students regardless of the quality of their students; many European and American universities have also engaged in a lot of marketing operations in order to attract international students. The result is that the evaluation criteria for these rankings are not only one-sided, but some of them are even untenable, which in turn damages the credibility of the institution itself. As far as colleges and universities are concerned, it is not trivial to make a bloated face and look fat, nor is it advisable to cut off one&#39;s feet to fit the shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even &quot;seemingly fair&quot; statistics such as faculty strength and scientific research quality are not always fair and reasonable in reality. There has long been a saying in the market that &quot;a higher level of knowledge will lead to a higher level of magic.&quot; One foot&quot; coping strategy. For example, in the 2021 mathematics subject rankings announced by USNews, Qufu Normal University surpassed Peking University to rank first, which surprised the industry. However, the process of its publication is &quot;reasonable and well-founded&quot;, relying on techniques such as &quot;paper filling&quot; and &quot;self-citation within the school&quot; that are fully in line with the evaluation procedures. However, it is self-evident how authoritative this evaluation standard will be in the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, Chinese and foreign universities have expressed dissatisfaction with such evaluations, and actions to &quot;withdraw from rankings&quot; have occurred one after another. In 2022, the National People&#39;s Congress, Nanjing University, and Lanzhou University will withdraw from the world university rankings, announcing that they will no longer provide data for them and will not be led by &quot;foreign indicators.&quot; In November 2022, Yale Law School publicly announced its withdrawal from the &quot;US News American University Rankings&quot; on the grounds that its rankings are &quot;seriously flawed&quot; and the institution itself is &quot;for-profit&quot; in nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back to &quot;College Ratings&quot;. On the surface, &quot;university ratings&quot;, like &quot;Dianping&quot;, &quot;Taobao ratings&quot; and &quot;Douban ratings&quot;, are consumers&#39; &quot;quality evaluation&quot; of businesses, but college students&#39; evaluations of universities are a bit more subjective and arbitrary. In essence, this &quot;college rating&quot; activity can be called an extension of Internet subcultures such as &quot;taunting each other,&quot; &quot;cross-hatting,&quot; &quot;advanced trolling,&quot; and &quot;self-hatred.&quot; It can be regarded as an alternative kind of &quot;college evaluation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of this, the evaluation of colleges and universities by students living in this mountain will be affected by the &quot;observer effect&quot; after all, and it is impossible to be completely objective and fair. This time in the &quot;Hupu College Ratings&quot;, comments such as &quot;No matter how bad your alma mater is, it still has to be given full marks&quot;. There are also many comments and ratings that are truly &quot;just for fun&quot;. For example, Tsinghua University&#39;s rating is only 5 There are many points, and the hot comments are also entertainment words that &quot;it feels like a school&quot;. Such &quot;complaints&quot; obviously should not be taken too seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the &quot;Hupu College Rating&quot; that triggered a carnival of public opinion is destined to be just one of many &quot;college evaluations&quot;. It is not very scientific and authoritative, but it is enough to remind the outside world. : Diverse assessment subjects, changing assessment standards, and different assessment procedures mean that any form of college assessment can only have a reference value within a certain range, rather than a golden rule that everyone must follow, and colleges and universities are not worthy of it. Go to great lengths to match certain &quot;rankings&quot; and &quot;lists.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what exactly is a good college assessment? Furthermore, what qualifies as a good school? There are already thousands of reviews on colleges and universities in the public, and a good school does not rely on one or two good rankings to become a good school. In addition to those indicators that are often used in evaluations and are easily spoiled, the quality of students, alumni achievements, peer certification, and job market recognition are the hard indicators that are difficult to shake, and it is not possible to make rapid progress in a short period of time by relying on opportunism. true indicator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes, &quot;a teacher chooses a disciple, and a disciple chooses a teacher,&quot; the same is true for the relationship between universities and students. There is a two-way selection between schools and students. School rankings are essentially rankings of students. Most of the evaluations of colleges and universities by the corporate world are also based on the evaluation of graduates, which leads to hierarchical differences among colleges and universities. After all, major universities are not products placed on the shelves for anyone to choose from, nor are they music/movies/games that everyone can buy and experience. The group of students who are qualified to evaluate colleges and universities have often been screened by college evaluations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the writer Fang Long, a scholar says he has discovered a great truth and must impart his knowledge to others. As a result, a group of young people gathered around him, and the university was born. It was initially a union of professors and students. &quot;Studying together in the right way&quot; is the foundation of the university and the starting point for all evaluations. This &quot;college rating&quot; is a small tribute to the ancient tradition. At least, rather than focusing on university rankings, universities should first listen to the voices of current students and alumni. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[上海实业集团总裁周军被查，曾三度任600亿医药龙头董事长]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261012]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 14:14:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 20, the Shanghai Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection’s official WeChat public account &quot;Integrity Shanghai&quot; announced that Shanghai Industrial (Group) Co., Ltd. President Zhou Jun is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Shanghai Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/e12e73a810ea7726fd064b3561b927b9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1552&quot; height=&quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/e12e73a810ea7726fd064b3561b927b9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258989&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Shanghai Pharmaceuticals (601607.SH) also issued an announcement. On November 18, the company’s board of directors received a written resignation report from Zhou Jun. Zhou Jun was unable to devote sufficient time to performing his duties in the company due to personal matters. He resigned from all positions including chairman of the company, non-executive director, convener and member of the strategy committee of the board of directors, etc. The resignation report will take effect from the date it is delivered to the company&#39;s board of directors. In addition, Shanghai Industrial Holdings (00363.HK) and Shanghai Industrial Environment (00807.HK) also announced that Zhou Jun applied to resign from all positions in the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned company stated in the announcement that Zhou Jun has confirmed that he has no differences of opinion with the board of directors, and there are no matters related to his resignation that need to be brought to the attention of the company&#39;s shareholders; the company has a complete governance and management structure. As well as the internal control mechanism, the above matters have no significant impact on the company&#39;s daily operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Zhou Jun holds a bachelor’s degree in literature from Nanjing University, a master’s degree in economics from Fudan University in international finance, and a doctorate in business administration from Shanghai Advanced Institute of Finance, Shanghai Jiao Tong University and Arizona State University in the United States. Zhou Jun has nearly 30 years of professional work experience in securities, mergers and acquisitions, financial investment, real estate, project planning and corporate management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 1996, Zhou Jun joined Shanghai Industrial Group and served as executive director of Shanghai Industrial Urban Development Group Co., Ltd. (00563.HK) and Zhejiang Shanghai-Hangzhou-Ningbo Expressway Co., Ltd. (00576.HK) Independent non-executive director, vice president and general manager of the investment planning department of Shanghai Industrial (Group) Co., Ltd., deputy general manager of Shanghai Real Estate Group (Shanghai) Co., Ltd. and Shanghai United Industrial Co., Ltd., deputy chief executive of Shanghai Industrial Holdings Co., Ltd. Managing director of Shanghai Galaxy Digital Investment Co., Ltd. and other positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From October 20, 2016, Zhou Jun began to serve as the chairman of Shanghai Pharmaceuticals. According to Shanghai Pharmaceuticals’ announcement, on June 29 this year, at the first meeting of the company’s eighth board of directors, Zhou Jun was re-elected as chairman of the company for the third time and his term should end in 2026. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A reporter from Nandu Bay Financial News noted that Shanghai Pharmaceuticals is a member company of Shanghai Industrial Group. In terms of performance, in the first three quarters of this year, Shanghai Pharmaceuticals’ revenue was 197.508 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 13.11%; net profit attributable to the parent company was 3.797 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 21.13%. Among them, operating income in the third quarter was 64.916 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 3.2%; net profit attributable to the parent company was 1.187 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 6.14%. As of the close of trading on November 20, Shanghai Pharmaceuticals&#39; stock price closed at 17.92 yuan per share, with a total market value of 66.36 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Zhou Jun also served as a representative of the 16th Shanghai People’s Congress, president of the Shanghai Pharmaceutical Industry Association, president of the Shanghai Environmental Protection Industry Association, and president of the Shanghai Young Entrepreneurs Association. and director of Shanghai Immunotherapy Innovation Research Institute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the beginning of this year, the Shanghai pharmaceutical industry has launched an anti-corruption storm, and many senior executives of many companies have been investigated. On September 2, the Shanghai Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision announced that four cadres of Shanghai Pharmaceuticals and its affiliated companies were subject to disciplinary review and supervisory investigation, including Pan Deqing, the former vice president of Shanghai Pharmaceuticals Group Co., Ltd. and the former chairman of Shanghai Shangke Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Li Ping, general manager of Shanghai Shangke Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Chen Binhua, former general manager of Shanghai Shanghai First Biochemical Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Huang Zhenhui, former deputy general manager of Shanghai Shanghai First Biochemical Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regarding the recent deepening of anti-corruption in the pharmaceutical field, at the 2023 Jinan Biomedicine and Big Health Industry Seminar held on August 10, Zhou Jun said that Shanghai Pharmaceuticals will fully cooperate and resolutely implement it. &quot;It is inappropriate for this industry to make huge profits. Its public welfare, importance, and particularity determine that &#39;serving the people and serving the country&#39; has always been the industry&#39;s most important value.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[水庆霞下课：中国女足没落，不仅是教练不行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261006]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 12:45:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/21/7m9LighL8qVbKNRtWZHKLier5cSBeoCSk0oDM9Gk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;741&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/7m9LighL8qVbKNRtWZHKLier5cSBeoCSk0oDM9Gk . jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258986&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 1, 2023, Shui Qingxia, the head coach of the Chinese team, was in the Australian Adelaide Ryder raises his hands to greet fans after the 2023 FIFA Women&#39;s World Cup Group D match against England. The Chinese team lost to England 1-6 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 20, 2023, the Chinese Football Association officially It was announced that Shui Qingxia will no longer serve as the head coach of the Chinese women’s football team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shui Qingxia, born in 1966, is a famous Chinese football star and the main player of the Chinese women&#39;s football team in its most glorious period. After retiring in 2001, Shui Qingxia took up the coaching position. In the women&#39;s football match at the Olympic Games in July 2021, the Chinese women&#39;s football team suffered a 2-8 defeat to the Dutch team. Shui Qingxia was appointed at a critical moment and officially served as the head coach of the Chinese women&#39;s football team in November 2021. In two years, she has brought victory and hope, as well as defeat and even despair. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2022, Shui Qingxia led the Chinese women&#39;s football team to defeat Japan and South Korea in succession, winning the Asian Cup again after 16 years. But by 2023, the women&#39;s football team has failed to meet people&#39;s expectations in the three major events of the World Cup, Asian Games and Olympic preliminaries. In the World Cup, the Chinese women&#39;s football team failed to qualify in the group stage and was defeated by England 1-6. They lost to Japan in the Asian Games and missed the finals. The same group failed to qualify in the Olympic preliminaries and bid farewell to the 2024 Paris Olympics in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After winning the 2022 Asian Cup, Shui Qingxia received overwhelming praise. It is generally believed that she is the best coach candidate because she comes from the women&#39;s football team, has a brilliant resume, is well versed in the laws of women&#39;s football and athlete psychology, and has been the coach of the local team for a long time. But after consecutive losses this year, what awaits Shui Qingxia is a flood of criticism. Some good people dug up netizen comments and media comments from different periods and found that the overlap rate between those who praised Shui Qingxia at the beginning and those who are now endlessly belittling her is quite high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This itself is a reflection of the impetuous side of Chinese football, which is true for managers, practitioners and fans. After Shui Qingxia&#39;s dismissal, many people believe that some players who have not been reused before will get more opportunities. But if you know a little bit about football, you will know that the plight of the Chinese women&#39;s football team is by no means a problem that can be solved by changing the coach or a few players. Its backwardness is all-round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/mUZslvouVksauZg35GdBF6w1FVEv56vmyt2C6ZQk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/mUZslvouVksauZg35GdBF6w1FVEv56vmyt2C6ZQk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 22, 2023, after the Group A match of the women&#39;s football group match of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese team players bowed to head coach Shui Qingxia (first from right). The Chinese team defeated the Mongolian team 16-0 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Shui Qingxia’s departure is A metaphor for the decline of the &quot;old women&#39;s football model&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;To be fair, although Shui Qingxia has many problems in selecting, employing and on-the-spot command, she can be said to be conscientious in her role as the head coach of the Chinese women&#39;s football team Responsible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back then, Shui Qingxia was an all-rounder on the court. She first practiced track and field. She started to receive professional football training at the age of 17, but she was summoned into the national team more than a year later with her hard practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shui Qingxia once recalled that the training conditions in the 1980s were very bad. The training ground only had dirt with stones on it. When she was thirsty, she could only drink tap water. This is not an isolated case. Most of the Sonorous Roses of that year stood out under such difficult conditions and competed in various world competitions under difficult conditions. However, the development of women&#39;s football in the world has long passed the era when &quot;only relying on fighting spirit can lead to victory.&quot; Shui Qingxia&#39;s dismissal is itself a metaphor for the complete decline of the &quot;old women&#39;s football model&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the defeat to England in the 2023 World Cup, player Wang Shuang choked up and asked: &quot;I dare say that we have to train harder and pay more than those players in Europe. Why can&#39;t we always get what we want?&quot; Results?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the face of absolute strength and the laws of competition, it is useless to rely solely on hard work. Moreover, compared with the hard-working Chinese women&#39;s football model, &quot;enjoying the joy of football&quot; is the basis of competitive rules. As England player Lauren James said after that game: &quot;The game is like playing football in the street when I was a kid. We are enjoying football to the fullest.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, around the world, In an era when no one pays much attention to women&#39;s football, the Chinese women&#39;s football team can earn its own glory through hard training and fighting spirit. However, as the professionalization of women&#39;s football is advancing rapidly, major football powers are injecting men&#39;s football and market-oriented models into women&#39;s football, and operating women&#39;s football leagues based on the mature operating experience of men&#39;s football professional leagues and professional clubs, causing the Chinese women&#39;s football team to completely lose its past advantages. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/UaIoO4PJESvwEdtA8hA0cqoQzvJIM2eDQxVWYFbt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/UaIoO4PJESvwEdtA8hA0cqoQzvJIM2eDQxVWYFbt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258983&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 11, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s football team members trained in Adelaide, Australia, to prepare for the Women&#39;s World Cup&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Concepts also need to be adjusted. Many people&#39;s judgment of women&#39;s football is still stuck in the Rose Rose era. This concept not only refers to performance, but also to the environment. For example, when talking about the plight of the women&#39;s football team, many people immediately said that the women&#39;s football team is too poor. It would be great if the unsatisfactory men&#39;s football team could allocate part of the money to the women&#39;s football team to solve their worries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This statement shows that you don’t understand football. In recent years, the rapid development of women&#39;s football teams, beneficiaries often have a highly professional and market -oriented football league as the foundation. What the men&#39;s football team provides to the women&#39;s football team is not only the club&#39;s operating model and advanced management, but also a steady stream of financial support. &quot;Raising women&#39;s football teams with men&#39;s football teams&quot; has long been the norm in the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese men’s football team is indeed unsatisfactory, and the Jinyuan Football Team in previous years has also been criticized. But anyone familiar with the history of women’s football knows that after the retirement of the Sonorous Rose generation, the Chinese women’s football team fell into a long-term trough. The “Little Indian Spring” in recent years also benefited to some extent from the abundant funds of the Jinyuan Football Era. Although the level of the Chinese men&#39;s football professional league is not high, it is still more professional than the women&#39;s football league and can provide a relatively complete structure and system, as well as financial support. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also with this support that the income of Chinese female football players is not low, and the training conditions have also been greatly improved. The &quot;Global Women&#39;s Football League Research Report&quot; released by FIFA in 2021 shows that the average annual operating costs of Chinese Women&#39;s Super League clubs rank first in the world, close to US$2 million. At present, the income of players in the Chinese Women&#39;s Super League is not lower than that of their foreign counterparts, and overseas players even face the problem that the salary for playing abroad is not as good as at home. Therefore, it is no longer appropriate to use the word &quot;hardship&quot; to describe their living conditions. The real gap in women&#39;s football is not in economic conditions, but in the backward understanding of the laws of football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/yTpRowYElStPUo5e8VN1DB5ZEoD3qWqc10RP8nSo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;663&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/yTpRowYElStPUo5e8VN1DB5ZEoD3qWqc10RP8nSo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258984&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 6, 2022, the Chinese women&#39;s football team defeated the South Korean team in the 2022 Women&#39;s Asian Cup final, winning the Asian Cup for the ninth time and standing in Asia again after 16 years. Top &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;China&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Women&#39;s Football&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; There are many difficulties in achieving nirvana&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Judging from the situation of the 2023 World Series, the Chinese women&#39;s football team is lagging behind in all aspects. Shui Qingxia once concluded that European players generally run and sprint at a high intensity of more than 700 meters in a game, and some good players can reach more than 1,000 meters, while the average Chinese women&#39;s football team member only reaches 300 meters. When faced with the opponent&#39;s pressing, it is difficult for the Chinese women&#39;s football team members to even look up and watch the ball being passed, and their past technical advantages have long since disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The development of Chinese women&#39;s football has always had many inherent problems, including limited popularity of grassroots football, an imperfect youth training system, and a low level of professional leagues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current Women&#39;s Super League is still very irregular, the schedule changes frequently, and it is impossible to cultivate a fan base. Data shows that the average number of spectators per game in the first 16 rounds of the Women&#39;s Super League this season is basically around 1,500, and many spectators are family members and friends of players, or employees of sponsors, and there are very few real fans. In comparison, the women&#39;s Premier League averaged 5,099 attendances per game last season, and the &quot;North London Derby&quot; between Arsenal and Tottenham attracted 47,367 people. The &quot;National Derby&quot; of Barcelona and Real Madrid women&#39;s football team in the 1/4 final of the Women&#39;s Football Champions League last season attracted 91,553 audiences to watch the ball. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to achieve results, the national team often adopts the outdated long-term training model, which in turn affects the league schedule and quality, making it even more difficult for players to receive the influence of high-level competitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/mKvr4Rzijkzh9uGFSE5nNW7whRPzZ1V0EtF8j8cN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/mKvr4Rzijkzh9uGFSE5nNW7whRPzZ1V0EtF8j8cN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258985&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 1, 2023, during the final round of the Asian second stage (Group B) of the Paris Olympic Women&#39;s Football Qualifiers held in Xiamen, the head coach of the Chinese team Shui Qingxia (Left) Coaching player Wang Linlin. The Chinese team drew 1-1 with the South Korean team and missed the chance to qualify for the Paris Olympics &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The league soil is not sufficient, so If there are not enough &quot;jobs&quot; provided, there will only be fewer and fewer girls willing to embark on the path of professional football. The situation of campus football is well known to everyone. Some time ago, there was a hot topic of &quot;giving ten minutes between classes to the children.&quot; If they can&#39;t even have ten minutes between classes, how many children can get the right to play football? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The past model of women’s football was a light league and a heavy emphasis on the world series. This is a kind of inertia of thinking. Its backwardness is not only because it has lost the soil of the league, but also because even if it is limited to the World Series, it is vulnerable because it despises the laws of modern football and sports science. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Women&#39;s World Cup, Chen Wanting, the coach of the technical research team, once lamented that it was difficult for her to see the video materials she needed in the Chinese Women&#39;s Super League. Because the video materials provided to her were only shots from the perspective of the television broadcast, not the entire scene. As we all know, fans watch the game from different perspectives than coaches watch the game. What the coach needs is full-field analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coaches cannot keep up with the development trend of women&#39;s football in the world, and it is difficult for players to improve their technical and tactical abilities. The old training model can no longer adapt to the needs of modern football. It involves running circles and practicing without thinking. On the field, facing the opponent&#39;s rapid transition of offense and defense, you will be at a loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, the Chinese women&#39;s football team has always faced a situation of alternation between hot and cold. Every time there is a World Series, people call for concern and development of women&#39;s football. After the competition, there is silence again. Many people use women&#39;s football as a tool to crowd out and ridicule men&#39;s football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is praising and beating Shui Qingxia, or using the Chinese women&#39;s football team to compete with the men&#39;s football team, it is actually meaningless. What the Chinese women&#39;s football team urgently needs to do is to calm down and truly understand and learn the development laws of world football. There is no other way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安部：缅北共向我方移交电信网络诈骗犯罪嫌疑人3.1万名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260984]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 11:23:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/21/7da4b29319035f4df2cd598d3cac1f3c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;7008&quot; height=&quot;4672&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/21/7da4b29319035f4df2cd598d3cac1f3c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258936&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the current severe situation of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, the Ministry of Public Security has deployed public security agencies in Yunnan and other places to continue to promote border police We have cooperated with law enforcement and carried out multiple rounds of crackdowns. So far, relevant local law enforcement departments in northern Myanmar have handed over to us a total of 31,000 suspects of telecommunications network fraud, including 63 behind-the-scenes &quot;financiers&quot;, organizational leaders and backbones. There are 1,531 fugitives, and the crackdown has achieved remarkable results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since September this year, under the command and deployment of the Ministry of Public Security and the Yunnan Provincial Public Security Department, public security agencies in Xishuangbanna, Pu&#39;er, Lincang and other places have carried out border police law enforcement cooperation with relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar, and carried out a series of During the crackdown, a large number of telecommunications network fraud suspects were handed over to us one after another, achieving remarkable results. Since November, in order to advance the crackdown in depth, our public security organs have further deepened police law enforcement cooperation between China and Myanmar and launched a fierce offensive against telecom network fraud crimes in northern Myanmar. The results have been remarkable and good news has been reported frequently. Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen, the important leaders of the Kokang telecom network fraud criminal group in northern Myanmar who were publicly wanted by our public security organs, were successfully arrested and brought to justice. The first criminal Ming Xuechang committed suicide in fear of crime. A large number of overseas fraud dens were successfully eradicated, which dealt a severe blow. The arrogance of overseas fraud groups. On November 18, the Dehong Public Security Bureau made an important breakthrough in border police law enforcement cooperation. The law enforcement department in the Muse region in northern Myanmar handed over 571 telecommunications network fraud suspects to us one after another, forming a strong deterrent to fraudsters. So far, with the strong cooperation of all parties in Myanmar, a total of 31,000 telecommunications network fraud suspects have been handed over to us and have been successively taken back by the public security organs of the places involved. The public security organs will thoroughly investigate all illegal and criminal facts and resolutely punish them severely in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ee443362355a261326cc529713496e08.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ee443362355a261326cc529713496e08.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258935&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the public security agency stated that they will always maintain a high-pressure and severe crackdown on telecommunications network fraud criminal groups in northern Myanmar, continue to deepen police law enforcement cooperation on the China-Myanmar border, continue to organize special crackdowns, make every effort to clear out fraud dens, and arrest people in accordance with the law. Those involved in fraud must resolutely safeguard the safety of life, property and legitimate rights and interests of the people, and effectively maintain border security and stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[奥本海默：电影与传记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260939]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/nb3RZ0KzIfdWagl85AZGBXSuXlgM0RAhLVDd5Haw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1298&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/nb3RZ0KzIfdWagl85AZGBXSuXlgM0RAhLV Dd5Haw. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258848&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Reading &quot;The Biography of Oppenheimer&quot; can help us understand many scenes in the movie. On the left is the poster of the movie &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; and on the right is the movie &quot;The Biography of Oppenheimer&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The movie &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; which has been released globally (except Japan) since the summer of 2023 It is adapted from &quot;Oppenheimer: The Triumph and Tragedy of the Father of the American Atomic Bomb&quot; (CITIC Press, 2023) written by two Pulitzer Prize winners, Kay Byrd and Martin Sherwin. The movie can be said to be very faithful to the original work. There is almost no key dialogue between the characters that is not based on the original work. Of course, due to the time limit of the film, many conversations from different occasions were grafted into one scene. For example, President Truman said that Oppenheimer was a &quot;crying scientist&quot; in a text message to his acting Secretary of State Acheson, not in person in the movie, but Oppenheimer did say this to Truman in person. &quot;I feel like my hands are stained with blood,&quot; and Truman replied, &quot;The blood is on my hands, let me worry about it&quot; (p. 393). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, reading &quot;The Biography of Oppenheimer&quot; can help us understand many scenes in the movie. When Oppenheimer first met his devoted girlfriend Joan Tatlock (a child psychiatrist who committed suicide at the age of 29), Joan discovered that he was very familiar with the different schools of psychoanalysis. If we don’t read the biography, we may generally understand that Oppenheimer is amazingly knowledgeable in both arts and sciences, which is indeed true; but the biography tells us that Oppenheimer understood the different schools of psychoanalysis and his own treatment. It is related to his experience, which also explains the incident in which he gave his Cambridge tutor Blackett (the 1948 Nobel Prize winner in physics and a famous British socialist) a &quot;poison apple&quot; when he had a mental breakdown (p. 61). When the movie deals with this incident, Bohr, a Danish physicist and one of the founders of quantum mechanics, picks up an apple, only to have it snatched away by Oppenheimer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/7y9GAec50FgO29ZkMoUxJCO3Hqq0Uc4lSttAE4xP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;1125&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/7y9GAec50FgO29ZkMoUxJCO3Hqq0Uc4lSttAE4xP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258847&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Oppenheimer (1904-1967). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oppenheimer had many mental crises in his youth. It was with his upper-middle-class Jewish family that related to family background. His father immigrated to New York from Frankfurt, Germany in 1888 and gradually became a successful clothing businessman. However, discrimination against Jews was widespread in Western society at that time. In June 1925, when Oppenheimer was preparing to study at the University of Cambridge in England, his Harvard undergraduate tutor wrote this recommendation letter to him: &quot;You can tell from his name that he is a Jew, but there is nothing common about him that is Jewish. Features. He has a long body, and the instrument is quite a gentleman. When considering his application, I don&#39;t think you need to have any concerns because of his Jewish background. &quot;(P. 52) Isidor Rabi (who won the 1944 Nobel Prize in Physics for the discovery of nuclear magnetic resonance, which is now widely used in hospitals) later recalled: &quot;I don&#39;t know if he considered himself Jewish, I think he fancied that he was not Jewish. I I remember he once said to me, &#39;I find Christianity very confusing, its mixture of blood and grace.&#39; He said that was what attracted him&quot; (p. 98). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oppenheimer&#39;s Jewish family background was obviously one of the important factors in his transition from an apolitical physicist to an active participant in political activities after 1936, because he had to rescue several Relatives who were persecuted by the Nazis helped them immigrate from Germany to the United States. But the more important factor that prompted him to care about politics was that California, where he taught at the University of California and the California Institute of Technology, was the home base of radical political movements in Roosevelt&#39;s New Deal. In 1934, the famous author Upton Sinclair almost became governor with his &quot;Plan to End Poverty in California.&quot; In 1938, left-wing Democrat Cabot Olson was elected governor of California with the open support of the state&#39;s Communist Party. His campaign slogan was &quot;Building a United Front Against Fascism&quot; (p. 142). Oppenheimer&#39;s girlfriend, wife, brother and sister-in-law were all dues-paying members of the Communist Party of the United States. The ex-husband of Oppenheimer&#39;s wife joined the Lincoln Detachment funded by the Communist Party of the United States in 1936 and died on the battlefield defending the Spanish republican system. Kenneth May, a doctoral student in the Department of Mathematics at the University of California, Berkeley, was the head of the Communist Party of the United States in Berkeley (page 172). He went to Oppenheimer&#39;s house several times to discuss political issues. Years later, he proved that in democracy The &quot;May&#39;s Theorem&quot; about simple majorities is very important in mathematical theory. Haakon Chevalier, a French literature teacher at the University of California, Berkeley, became a good friend of Oppenheimer. In 1934, he translated into English the novel &quot;The Human Condition&quot; by French writer André Malraux (who later served as President de Gaulle&#39;s Minister of Culture), which was set during the Chinese Revolution in 1927. In the spring of 1937, Chivalier accompanied Malraux on a visit to California. (Page 147) In the subsequent hearings on Oppenheimer in 1954, the &quot;Chivalier incident&quot; became the focus of questioning Oppenheimer&#39;s &quot;national loyalty.&quot; This incident has been prominently shown in the movie and will not be discussed further here. Biography can be helpful in understanding the &quot;Chivalier Incident&quot; in the movie: Chvalier and many of Oppenheimer&#39;s Communist friends believed that the United States should be informed of the plan of the United States to try to build an atomic bomb before Hitler&#39;s Germany. The Soviet Union was the ally that made the greatest sacrifice in the fascist war. Oppenheimer agreed with this view in principle, but he firmly opposed personal leaks through the back door and believed that the US government should inform the Soviet Union (page 282). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/CmZwCvdycnQzIrLl2wwBY1fhuGbElNuCFWucs4Oy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;708&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/CmZwCvdycnQzIrLl2wwBY1fhuGbElNuCFWucs4Oy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258845&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lewis Strauss, Chairman of the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission (first from left) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course , we can criticize Oppenheimer for being too naive. However, most scientists who participated in the &quot;Manhattan Project&quot; were deeply disturbed that the achievements of 300 years of modern science were mainly reflected in the creation of atomic bombs that could destroy mankind. On October 5, 1943, Oppenheimer&#39;s spiritual idol, the Danish physicist Bohr, escaped from Nazi-occupied Copenhagen by hiding in the bomb bay of a British bomber. After he came to Los Alamos, the site of the Manhattan Project, he persuaded Oppenheimer to turn his attention to the postwar consequences of the atomic bomb. Bohr believed that the Soviets must be informed of the existence of the nuclear bomb project and ensure that it would not pose a threat to them, in order to avoid a postwar nuclear arms race (p. 319). In the spring of 1944, Bohr held private meetings with Roosevelt and Churchill, but failed to persuade the leaders of the United States and Britain to share plans for atomic bomb production with the Soviet Union. Despite this, most scientists who participated in the &quot;Manhattan Project&quot; still regarded Bohr as God and Oppenheimer as a prophet of God (p. 326). Interestingly, Oppenheimer called the first atomic bomb test the &quot;Trinity Experiment,&quot; implying that man was becoming &quot;God&quot; (p. 679). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Oppenheimer participated in the &quot;Manhattan Project&quot; and became its scientific director in order to build the atomic bomb before the Nazis, then he was already very reluctant to the decision to drop the atomic bomb in Japan (this The reason why he told President Truman that he had blood on his hands). By the summer of 1952, Oppenheimer was clearly and firmly opposed to the United States experimenting with a hydrogen bomb that was thousands of times more powerful than the atomic bomb. &quot;Opposing the development of the hydrogen bomb&quot; was one of the two accusations against Oppenheimer (the other one was the aforementioned &quot;Khiva&quot;) in the 1954 hearings held by U.S. Atomic Energy Commission Chairman Lewis Strauss (the main scene of the movie). Lié incident&quot;). But in fact, opposition to the development of hydrogen bombs is the unanimous opinion of the Advisory Committee of the Atomic Energy Commission, chaired by Oppenheimer, whose members include Nobel Prize winners in physics Fermi, Lawrence, and Harvard University President Conant (page 495) . The hydrogen bomb (fusion reaction), which is more terrifying than the atomic bomb (fission reaction), will definitely escalate the nuclear arms race. As Vannevar Bush, who had a great influence on the formulation of U.S. science and technology policy after World War II, said when testifying in support of Oppenheimer at a hearing in 1954: &quot;I maintain that that experiment (referring to the 1952 U.S. hydrogen bomb experiment ) made it impossible for us to reach the only feasible agreement with the Soviet Union, which was that neither side would conduct experiments again.&quot; (Page 626) George Kennan, the proposer of the &quot;containment&quot; strategy not shown in the movie, also opposed the development of the hydrogen bomb. When he attended a hearing in 1954 to defend Oppenheimer&#39;s participation in the left-wing movement when he was young, he said, &quot;If the church only focused on his youth when judging St. Francis, he would not have become what he later became.&quot; In fact, as early as January 1950, after an in-depth discussion with Oppenheimer, Kennan wrote a report in the form of a &quot;personal note&quot; to Secretary of State Acheson opposing the development of the hydrogen bomb, and Acheson told Kennan He said that after writing this report, it would be best to consider resigning. After leaving the government, Kennan spent the rest of his life at the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton (p. 503). This also shows that the strategy actually implemented by the United States in the Cold War was not Kennan&#39;s &quot;containment&quot; but the National Security Council (NSC) drafted in April 1950 by Paul Nitze, who took over as director of the Office of Policy Planning of the State Department after Kennan resigned. - Document No. 68, which clearly rejected Kennan&#39;s &quot;no first use of nuclear weapons&quot; policy proposition. (Page 507)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The villain in the movie is undoubtedly Strauss. He not only fought against Oppenheimer as chairman of the Atomic Energy Commission, but also continued to fight against Oppenheimer as chairman of the board of directors of the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton. An interesting example is: Strauss opposed Oppenheimer&#39;s proposal to hire Kantolovitch, the author of The King&#39;s Two Bodies, because he refused to require the University of California to require teachers to swear an oath not to join the Communist Party, despite a later U.S. Supreme Court decision UC’s oath requirement is unconstitutional. Strauss was a self-made millionaire. In 1917, when he was 21 years old, he worked as an unpaid assistant to future U.S. President Herbert Hoover. He used this as a springboard to get the opportunity to enter a Wall Street investment bank ( page 427). He was extremely ideologically opposed to the domestic and foreign policies of Roosevelt&#39;s New Deal. At the same time, he is extremely sensitive and has a pathological ego. A scene in the movie is that at his 54th birthday party, he wanted to introduce his son and daughter-in-law to the &quot;celebrity&quot; Oppenheimer, but because that day President Truman denied the objections of Oppenheimer and other scientist advisors. Oppenheimer was in a very bad mood over the hydrogen bomb suggestion and was very rude to Strauss&#39;s son and daughter-in-law. This was one of the reasons why Strauss held a grudge against Oppenheimer. But Strauss was cunning and knew that Oppenheimer, as the &quot;Father of the Atomic Bomb&quot; on the cover of Time magazine, would not be easily brought down completely. Therefore, he only held a meeting within the Atomic Energy Commission to discuss whether to revoke Oppenheimer&#39;s safety. Internal hearings on the permit, without letting Senator McCarthy intervene, because he believed that the extremely hysterical McCarthy might mess things up. Strauss finally got his wish, and the hearing revoked Oppenheimer&#39;s security clearance, but still said he had no doubts about Oppenheimer&#39;s loyalty to the country. Oppenheimer was able to retain his position as director of the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, but he was completely eliminated from U.S. technology and defense policymaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Einstein appears at the beginning and end of the movie. Einstein is quoted in the biography: &quot;Oppenheimer&#39;s problem was that he fell in love with a woman who didn&#39;t love him - the U.S. government... The problem was actually very simple. Oppenheimer only had to go to Washington and tell Officials, they&#39;re all fools, then go home” (p. 596). Einstein also suggested that Oppenheimer leave the United States to conduct research in Europe, but Oppenheimer&#39;s response was: &quot;Hell, I love this country deeply.&quot; This is Oppenheimer&#39;s tragedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[池田大作 “真正的成功的人生是什么呢？”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/LzbyXRcNYzMvh1Rfw8pMR2QZejt5jYRjMxY1i7mh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/LzbyXRcNYzMvh1Rfw8pMR2QZejt 5jYRjMxY1i7mh. jpg &quot;data-key =&quot; 258930 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Local time April 24, 1979, Tokyo, Japan, Ikeda held a press conference. , announced his resignation as president of the Soka Gakkai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1996, a &quot;nuclear weapon threat exhibition&quot; was held in San Jose, the capital of the Republic of Costa Rica in South America. hold. At the opening ceremony, just as the participants solemnly sang the national anthem in unison, suddenly, a series of children&#39;s voices came from the &quot;Children&#39;s Museum&quot; across the wall. That was the laughter of primary school students who were impatiently waiting for the opening of the exhibition. The bursts of laughter disrupted the guests&#39; speeches many times. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The lively and energetic laughter of children is a symbol and embodiment of peace. These laughters are filled with the power of hope to fight against the &#39;nuclear threat&#39;.&quot; Daisaku Ikeda at the opening ceremony Listening to the children&#39;s voices, I smiled and said, &quot;This is the indicator of a sound society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Daisaku Ikeda is the third president of the Soka Gakkai of Japan. He expanded the scope of the Soka Gakkai. scale and developed it into the largest religious organization in Japan. He also actively participated in politics and founded the Komeito Party in 1964. To this day, Soka Gakkai remains the main supporter of Komeito. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Daisaku Ikeda’s greatest contribution was to promote the secularization of Nichiren Buddhism. For Ikeda, Nichiren Buddhism is a philosophy of life that actively integrates into the modern world and society and actively faces all challenges in it. Ikeda devoted his life to promoting culture, education, and peace, and won the United Nations Peace Prize in 1983. Regarding Sino-Japanese relations, he proposed the initiative to normalize diplomatic relations between China and Japan in the 1960s. He was received by Zhou Enlai and Deng Xiaoping, and was awarded the title of &quot;Peace Envoy&quot; for Sino-Japanese friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aversion to war, the desire for peace, and the exploration of the dignity of life ran through Ikeda’s life until the end of his life. The Soka Gakkai of Japan announced on November 18, 2023 that Daisaku Ikeda, honorary president of the Soka Gakkai and founder of the Komeito Party, passed away on November 15, 2023, at the age of 95. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Dialogue is the foundation of peace&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On January 26, 1975, a special rally was held in Guam. This was one of the bloodiest battlefields of World War II. Soka Gakkai members from 50 countries and regions around the world gathered here and established the International Soka Gakkai International, headed by President Daisei Ikeda. The place was chosen as the venue for the meeting as a symbol of the new peace movement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I was born in 1928, which was a war-torn era. In my young mind, I had already deeply realized that nothing is more tragic and nothing is more cruel than war, so I I made up my mind to never let such inhumane tragedies continue to happen in the future.&quot; In 2020, in an interview with Global magazine, Daisaku Ikeda recalled the origins of his desire for peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1928, Daisaku Ikeda was born in Tokyo. His family made a living from seaweed farming. There are eight children in the family, and Ikeda ranks fifth. The era when Ikeda grew up was a period when Japan was moving towards war under the leadership of the military government. Japan was plunged into the abyss of world war, and all walks of life in the country - from families, factories, schools to religious groups, were forced to serve in the war effort. All opposition voices were brutally suppressed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1937, Japan launched a full-scale war of aggression against China. Ikeda&#39;s eldest brother Kiichi was drafted into the army, followed by his three brothers. Ikeda often mentioned Hiichi in conversation and writing. He said that when Kiichi returned home on a vacation, he described to him the brutal behavior of the Japanese army in China, his tone full of disgust. He also mentioned that after the war, the whole family was looking forward to Kiichi&#39;s return, but in the end they waited for the news that he had died on the battlefield. The scene of his mother silently accepting Xiyi&#39;s white urn was something he would never forget in his life. &quot;Aside from anger... I deeply understand how cruel, ignorant and meaningless war is.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a boy, Ikeda&#39;s home was destroyed twice in air raids. He also personally experienced the Tokyo bombing on March 9-10, 1945, in which more than 100,000 people were killed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of World War II, Ikeda was 17 years old. He described: &quot;The young people at that time were left with an indelible spiritual void. It was not just the country that was burned. The hypocrisy of the fanatical militaristic values ​​that had been instilled since before the war was exposed after the war. There was nothing left, so it immediately fell apart.&amp;nbsp;Many young people fell into the despair of &quot;not believing in anything&quot; because of this. This seems to be an inevitable conclusion.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such despair also occurs in Regarding Ikeda, he wrote, &quot;For those who once glorified war and sacrificed many young people on the battlefield, but after the war they transformed into intellectuals pursuing peace and democracy. No matter how they dressed themselves, I absolutely cannot believe the rhetoric of these powerful people.&amp;nbsp;”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the turbulent international situation of the last century, Ikeda has always played the role of a messenger of peace. He firmly advocated: dialogue is peace fundamental. Since 1970, he has been engaged in dialogue activities with representatives from all over the world in the humanities, politics, traditional beliefs, culture, education and academia. He seeks consensus from dialogue and finds solutions to the complex problems facing humanity. More than 70 of these conversations have been published in books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During his lifetime, Ikeda co-authored &quot;Looking into the Twenty-first Century&quot; with the British historian Toynbee, co-authored &quot;Spiritual Lessons of the Twentieth Century&quot; with the last leader of the Soviet Union, Mikhail Gorbachev, and co-authored with Jin Yong Author of &quot;In Search of a Glorious Century&quot;. Since November 16, 1995, Ikeda and Jin Yong have met many times in Hong Kong, China and Japan, during which they even exchanged letters and never stopped communicating. Jin Yong once said: &quot;The conversations are impromptu, sometimes at the dinner table, sometimes during tea talks, sometimes while admiring the beauty of the landscape and the garden.&quot; They focused on many issues such as the return of Hong Kong, Buddhist philosophy, literature, etc. There was a serious discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1993, shortly after the end of the Cold War, a research institution was established on the east coast of the United States adjacent to Harvard University. Originally named &quot;Boston 21st Century Research Center&quot;, it was renamed &quot;Ikeda Center for Peace, Education, and Dialogue&quot; in 2009. The center expands the peace and humanitarian network by inviting experts and scholars from various fields around the world to hold various seminars to conduct in-depth discussions on peace, human rights, environment, education, culture and other issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Advocating Sino-Japanese friendship as a common man&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 8, 1968, at a rally attended by more than 10,000 Soka Gakkai students At the meeting, Daisaku Ikeda made a speech that was considered &quot;bold&quot;. He called for the normalization of diplomatic relations between Japan and China and proposed specific steps to achieve this goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, many Japanese regarded China as an enemy country, and China was relatively isolated in the international community. Ikeda&#39;s suggestion drew criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, this suggestion also attracted the attention of some people in China and Japan who were concerned about the restoration of diplomatic relations between the two countries, including Zhou Enlai. In addition, Kenzo Matsumura, a member of the Japanese House of Representatives who supported the restoration of normal relations between the two countries at the time, also contacted Ikeda after his speech and urged him to visit China. However, Ikeda believes that politicians should start this matter, so he suggested that a delegation of Komeito members should visit China. Sino-Japanese relations began to improve, and the two countries finally restored diplomatic relations in 1972. In May 1974, Ikeda led a delegation to visit China, and he led delegations to visit China many times in the following decades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 1974, during their second visit to China, Ikeda and his delegation were received by Deng Xiaoping, then Vice Premier of the State Council. Zhou Enlai, who was hospitalized due to illness, met with Ikeda and all members of the Soka Gakkai&#39;s second visit to China in Beijing despite the objections of the medical team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years later, Daisaku Ikeda still remembered this interview vividly, &quot;Premier Zhou once said to me when looking forward to the 21st century that the last 25 years of the 20th century will be the most important period for the world. The whole world must respect each other on an equal footing and encourage each other for mutual benefit. Premier Zhou also said clearly in a bold voice, &#39;I hope that the China-Japan Treaty of Peace and Friendship can be concluded at an early date.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The year after the meeting with Premier Zhou, that is, 1975, since there were no universities in Japan open to Chinese students to study abroad at that time, Ikeda personally acted as a guarantor, so that the first batch of six publicly funded overseas students in New China could smoothly study at Soka University he founded. Soka University was the first school in Japan to accept publicly funded international students from China, and has since continued to accept publicly funded and self-funded international students from China to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the world was in a tense period of confrontation between superpowers, and nuclear weapons seriously threatened the survival of mankind. Ikeda expressed his hope that as a common man, he could do his best to ease the tense situation at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda visited China, the Soviet Union and the United States in 1974 and 1975, and was received by Chinese Premier Zhou Enlai, Soviet Prime Minister Kosygin, and U.S. Secretary of State Kissinger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He described the situation at that time:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“From 1974 to 1975, I visited China, the Soviet Union and the United States one after another, directly having dialogues with the heads of state, and exploring the situation from the perspective of a private person. A way to ease tensions. At that time, in addition to the confrontation between the United States and the Soviet Union, there was also tension between China and the Soviet Union, which made the world face a crisis of tripolarization.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&quot;When I visited China for the first time in May 1974 , visited the large-scale air-raid shelter built by Beijing citizens and was known as the &quot;Underground Great Wall&quot;, and felt firsthand the threat posed by the Soviet Union to the Chinese people. In September of the same year, I visited the Soviet Union for the first time. When meeting with Prime Minister Kosygin, I frankly Asked him if the Soviet Union had any intention to attack China. Prime Minister Kosygin asserted that the Soviet Union had no intention of attacking or isolating China.&quot;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&quot;In December of the same year, I visited China again with this information. During this visit to China During this period, I had the honor to meet with Premier Zhou Enlai. During the meeting, we jointly confirmed the importance of Japan and China working together for world peace and prosperity.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&quot;Here, I heard Premier Zhou Enlai say that China We will definitely not become a superpower. Based on the content of my previous dialogue with Prime Minister Kosygin, I am convinced that the day of Sino-Soviet reconciliation will not be too far away. In fact, history has proven that my prediction was right.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br >;&lt;br>;&quot;In January 1975, I visited the United States and met with Secretary of State Kissinger in a lightly snowing Washington. During the meeting, I told him that Premier Zhou earnestly hoped to conclude a treaty of friendship between Japan and China at an early date. Dr. Kissinger expressed his great Agree.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&quot;On the same day, I met Prime Minister Ohira Masayoshi (then Minister of Finance) in Washington. I conveyed Dr. Kissinger&#39;s words to him and emphasized the importance of concluding a treaty. Prime Minister Ohira I fully agree and will work hard to realize it. Three years later, in August 1978, the &quot;Sino-Japanese Treaty of Peace and Friendship&quot; was finally formally concluded.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A society eager for change&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In mid-August 1947, defeated Japan was under the control of the Allies. At night people can only see dim lights flickering in temporary shacks or bomb shelters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Daisaku Ikeda’s later recollection, at a time when everything was in dire straits, the entire Japanese society was eager for change. Calls for democracy could be heard on every street corner, and the faith of a generation collapsed. At this time, young people are eager to read classics to enrich their spiritual world and build confidence. People started exchanging books and forming reading groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, 19-year-old Daisaku Ikeda met his life mentor and the second president of the Soka Gakkai, Toda Josei. It was a Buddhist exchange meeting. Toda Castle left a deep impression on Ikeda: his hoarse and warm voice, steady demeanor, and the content of his speech was not like other religious leaders, and it did not contain empty terms and theories at all. It is very down-to-earth, as if the highest truth exists in daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Toda was rebuilding the Soka Gakkai, the organization he had founded in 1930 with fellow educator Tsunesaburo Makiguchi. During World War II, Toda was imprisoned along with Makiguchi. The Japanese military government forced its people to accept state Shinto ideology as a means of sanctifying its war of aggression. The two men still adhered to their religious beliefs under oppression, and Makiguchi died in prison. The Soka Gakkai collapsed when Toda and Makiguchi were arrested by the military government during the war. Toda was convinced that Nichiren Buddhism, which focused on the infinite potential within each person, was the key to transforming Japanese society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda and Toda met each other late in life, and have been friends since then. Ikeda was deeply interested in literature since childhood and began writing poetry as a teenager. When he was unable to continue his studies due to various reasons, Toda, a knowledgeable educator, personally taught him. Ikeda quickly accepted the teachings of the Soka Gakkai and joined 10 days later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Toda, Ikeda has unwavering confidence in Nichiren Buddhism and believes that its emphasis on the Buddha nature and unlimited potential of every human being can revitalize the decadent post-war Japanese society. . The key is a process of &quot;human nature transformation&quot; that unfolds in people&#39;s hearts. In that process, when a person decides to take action for his or her life and happiness, the surrounding environment and community will change for the better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the company run by Toda was on the verge of bankruptcy, Ikeda devoted himself to helping him manage the business. Unable to receive their salaries, employees left Toda&#39;s company one after another. Ikeda insisted on not leaving and was running around to negotiate with the company&#39;s creditors on debt repayment. &quot;I haven&#39;t received a salary for half a year, my leather shoes are tattered, I don&#39;t have formal clothes, and my body is extremely weak. Even so, I thought that as long as I can protect Mr. Toda, it doesn&#39;t matter even if I suffer the torture of the hungry ghost world and the hell world, Determined to never regret.&quot; Ikeda recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a difficult period, Toda revealed his idea of ​​running a school to Ikeda - to establish a series of education from elementary school to university based on the Soka pedagogy concept of his teacher Makiguchi Tsunezaburo. School. Such an idea seemed unrealistic at the time, but Ikeda, who was only in his twenties, took Toda&#39;s words to heart. Twenty years later, Ikeda turned Toda&#39;s ideal into reality and founded a Soka education institution from kindergarten to university. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1960, two years after Toda&#39;s death, 32-year-old Daisaku Ikeda was appointed as the third president of the Soka Gakkai. Fifteen years later, Daisaku Ikeda founded the Soka Gakkai International. Today, Soka Gakkai International is an international organization composed of 12 million members in more than 190 countries and regions. Ikeda wrote: &quot;Everything depends on people. Therefore, we must resolutely and thoroughly expand the alliance of good people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some media commented that Ikeda has led a &quot;Buddhist secular movement&quot; on a global scale. Movement”, established a complete education system based on religion and its values ​​to inspire individual potential and teach the importance of peace and contribution to society. The system runs from kindergarten to graduate school, with institutions including universities in Tokyo and California, USA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda has stated many times that the mentor-disciple relationship with Toda has affected his life. Unlike other religions that highlight the importance of suffering in life, Ikeda emphasizes the positive and optimistic side. He often said that by helping others gain happiness, he would also gain happiness. For Ikeda, happiness means &quot;being true to oneself&quot;, and he believes that only in this way can happiness be increased in an infinite way. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Fundamental Dignity of Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“One person’s great human transformation can change the fate of a country or even all mankind.” Ikeda put this sentence Written in the preface to the novel &quot;Human Revolution,&quot; Ikeda&#39;s masterpiece, this novel describes the history and ideals of the Soka Gakkai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the decades of developing the Soka Gakkai, Ikeda’s job was not easy. His wife, Kamineko, recalled that whenever Ikeda came home after a day at work, he was often so exhausted that he could barely take off his shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda was invited to give a lecture at the University of California, Los Angeles in 1974. The following year, he gave a lecture on &quot;New Paths for East-West Cultural Exchange&quot; at Moscow State University and received an honorary doctorate from the university. When the world was in the grip of the Cold War, Ikeda did not choose to take sides in the political confrontation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda valued the fundamental dignity of life as the key to lasting peace and human happiness. He believes that to achieve world peace, it ultimately depends on the inner change of each person, rather than solely on the reform of social and organizational structures. He firmly believes that this seemingly long road is the only way to build a lasting culture of peace. The philosophy held by the Soka Gakkai can be summed up in the term &quot;human revolution.&quot; According to the meaning contained in this concept, a spontaneous inner change will have a positive impact on the external environment and promote the growth of human society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the number of honorary doctorates and honorary professorships awarded to Ikeda by academic institutions around the world has exceeded 300. His peace writings are now selected as university textbooks in Argentina and the United States, and more than twenty research institutes are dedicated to studying his philosophy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda founded a series of &lt;span>;&lt;span>;Soka education institutions from kindergarten to university&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;. These schools are non-religious schools. Their educational purpose is to treat each student as a unique being, strive to explore their potential to create value, and instill in them concepts such as peace, social contribution and global citizenship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Ikeda’s view, children’s lives are a mirror of society: If adults promote a chaotic and decadent outlook on life to teenagers, it is equivalent to the buds of hope that will be full of longing for the future. Trampled ruthlessly. &quot;Isn&#39;t it true that the hearts of children who are unsatisfied and desolate can easily be misled unconsciously into the kind of cold values ​​​​that only determine their success or failure based on the abundance of money?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&quot;What is a truly successful life?&amp;nbsp;What is a truly wealthy society?&quot;&amp;nbsp;Ikeda feels about the era he has experienced, which was a society with long-term hollowing out of values, and this is what he always recalls. They all described it as a &quot;painful&quot; experience, but regarding happiness and the dignity of life, he chose to spend his life &quot;sincerely searching for the correct answers (to these questions).&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Source: Soka Gakkai Global Network, &quot;Sowing the Seeds of Hope&quot; by Daisaku Ikeda, &quot;The Wisdom of the Lotus Sutra&quot; (Volume Six)&quot;.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[心脑血管发病年轻化，看看这份防治“地图”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260972]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/20/ae893efa1f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 20/ae893efa1f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258929&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The National Center for Cardiovascular Diseases is investigating the incidence of acute myocardial infarction and stroke. In the patient survey, it was found that the age of first onset of disease has a downward trend. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;By 2030, the awareness rate of hypertension among residents over 30 years old will be no less than 65%, and the rate of standardized management of hypertension patients will not be low. More than 70%, the mortality rate from cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases has dropped to less than 190.7 per 100,000, and the overall 5-year cancer survival rate in the field of cancer has reached more than 46.6%.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;The above new goals come from the &quot;Healthy China Action - Cancer Prevention and Control Action Implementation Plan (2023-2030)&quot; and the &quot;Healthy China Action - Cardiovascular and Cerebrovascular Disease Prevention and Control Action Implementation Plan (2023-2030)&quot;. On November 15, 2023, two sets of plans were jointly issued by 13 departments including the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters compared the plan released in 2019 and found that the new version of the plan has further improved the main goals. In the cancer prevention and treatment plan, the overall 5-year cancer survival rate is nearly 3 percentage points higher than the 2019 plan; the mortality rate from cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases was previously required to drop to 209.7/100,000 in 2022. In terms of prevention and control, it also emphasizes the movement forward and the integration of medical and defense, focusing on the whole process of health, and realizing people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We all know that prevention is the most economical and effective health strategy. Both plans insist on prevention as the main focus, strengthen the control of risk factors of chronic diseases, and improve the Full-process management from prevention of chronic diseases, screening of high-risk groups to early diagnosis, standardized treatment and integrated rehabilitation services.&quot; said Guo Yanhong, director of the Medical Emergency Department of the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Expand the coverage of cancer screening and improve the accessibility of HPV vaccine&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Promoting cancer prevention and treatment to move forward&quot; is the new cancer prevention and treatment plan A major feature. As of 2022, the early diagnosis rate of key cancer types in high-incidence areas in China has reached more than 55%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The main method used in cancer screening is &quot;risk stratification&quot;, which is to conduct organized screening for areas with high cancer incidence and key groups with higher risk, and at the same time, through Opportunistic screening and standardized cancer prevention physical examinations will expand screening coverage. Zhang Yong, secretary of the National Cancer Center, suggested that residents with higher risk of cancer, such as family history with cancer, long -term smoking and drinking, patients with occupational exposure or patients with hepatitis B and pre -cancer diseases should be screened regularly for cancer. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with the previous version of the plan, the new version of the cancer prevention and treatment plan also mentions that qualified areas will be promoted to incorporate HPV vaccination into local policies to benefit the people. For those who meet the requirements The review and approval of the domestically produced HPV vaccine will be accelerated, the accessibility of the HPV vaccine will be improved, and various channels will be used to ensure vaccination for people of appropriate age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Regional Exploration and Improvement Strategies for HPV Vaccine Benefit Policies&quot; released by the Vaccine Delivery Research and Innovation Laboratory of Duke Kunshan University mentioned that if vaccination can Further optimization of the strategy can further enhance the policy influence on public health. For example, many local policies apply to girls with school registration or household registration, but provide insufficient protection for migrants or girls who have dropped out of middle school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Shenglan, founding director of the Global Health Research Center at Duke Kunshan University and head of the Vaccine Delivery Research Innovation Laboratory, told Southern Weekend reporters that it is necessary to protect poor areas or poor people The only feasible and effective way to improve the vaccination coverage of HPV vaccine among people of appropriate age is to include HPV vaccine in the national immunization plan, that is, it will become a first-class vaccine for free vaccination. The source of funds can be through national financial support or subsidies from medical insurance funds. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Provinces such as Guangdong, Hainan, Jiangxi, Fujian, Tibet, and Chongqing have successively launched or announced that they will launch free HPV vaccination programs across the region. Most regions have established a collaborative mechanism of &quot;government leadership, department coordination, and social participation&quot; to not only reduce the economic cost of HPV vaccination for school-age girls in a free or subsidized manner, but also through multiple departments and institutions such as the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, hospitals, and schools. Participation and the cooperation of media publicity have improved public awareness of the HPV vaccine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;These policies also bring about a wind vane effect, which also plays a leading role in the HPV vaccination of local people not covered by the policy.&quot; National Cancer Center, said Zhao Fanghui, director of the Epidemiology Research Office of the Cancer Hospital of the Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Improve the first aid system and strengthen the provision of AEDs in public places&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;National Cardiovascular Disease Center’s investigation of patients with acute myocardial infarction and stroke , a downward trend in the age of first onset of disease was found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hu Shengshou, director of the National Center for Cardiovascular Disease and academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering, believes that the main reason is the urbanization process of my country&#39;s economic development over the past 40 years of reform and opening up. The impact of lifestyle changes. For example, in terms of diet, the proportion of fresh fruits, vegetables and milk in the diet of Chinese residents has indeed increased significantly, but the proportion of whole grains and beans continues to decline, while the proportion of fat intake and energy supply continues to increase. &quot;In short, we eat less and less whole grains and more and more fats.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new version of the cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease prevention and treatment plan mentions, It is necessary to vigorously promote healthy lifestyles and promote scientific sports; promote the construction of food nutrition standard systems and strengthen the guiding role of food nutrition labels. And we must actively promote the construction of a smoke-free environment and continue to promote tobacco control measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In medicine, it is often said that time is the heart and time is the brain. This is because cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases are chronic diseases with acute attacks. In the early stages of the attack, life-saving treatment is crucial. closely related to time. Therefore, strengthening the frontier movement and improving the first aid system are also one of the focuses of the new cardiovascular and cerebrovascular prevention and treatment plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2022, the National Health and Health Commission issued a document requiring county-level hospitals to speed up the construction of &quot;five major emergency centers&quot;, including chest pain centers and stroke centers. The new version of the cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease prevention and treatment plan mentions that by 2030, all stroke centers in secondary hospitals and above will carry out intravenous thrombolysis technology. Where conditions permit, &quot;first aid maps&quot; for chest pain and stroke can be established to effectively improve treatment efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the public level, strengthen the provision of first aid facilities and equipment such as automated external defibrillators (AEDs) in public places, and strengthen inspections of the equipped first aid equipment to ensure emergency response Available. &quot;We are promoting the international &#39;BEFAST&#39;, which means difficulty in balancing, unclear vision, incorrect face, difficulty in arm leveling, and difficulty in speech. If one of the five symptoms occurs, it means that you have cerebrovascular disease. At this time, you must treat it as soon as possible. For emergency calls, call 120 and go to the hospital.&quot; Wang Yongjun, director of Beijing Tiantan Hospital affiliated to Capital Medical University, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new version of the cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease prevention and treatment plan also requires expanding the scope of community cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease prevention and treatment services, and exploring the secondary prevention and treatment of patients with coronary heart disease and stroke. Rehabilitation treatment is included in the scope of services contracted by family doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The causative basis of cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases is atherosclerosis. It is very important to prevent and treat them at the same time, and to diagnose and treat them early. Wang Yongjun also called for the establishment of vascular health management centers at the grassroots level to jointly manage the high-risk groups of cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, and to establish diagnosis and treatment centers for cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases in large medical institutions. If you have cardiovascular disease, cerebrovascular disease or comorbidities If the patient is ill, he can see different experts after registering once to jointly solve the problem of common cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江苏无锡一纺织厂起火致7人死亡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260982]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 07:55:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to the official WeChat account of Wuxi Huishan District Emergency Management Bureau, on November 20, 2023 at 18:00 pm At about 1:30 a.m., a fire broke out at Tiantianrun Textile Technology Co., Ltd. in Qianzhou Street. Rescue operations at the accident site have ended, resulting in a total of 7 deaths. Accident investigation and aftermath are underway. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>