<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[贫困大学生哭诉助学金被挤占：福利如何才能落到需要的人手里？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259963]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a video of poor college students crying about being squeezed out of their scholarship qualifications has been widely circulated on social networks. attracted great attention. Tianjin Sino-German University of Applied Sciences, which was involved in the incident, said on November 2 that it had set up a special work team to conduct investigation and verification as soon as possible. The subsequent investigation results will be handled in accordance with regulations and announced in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the video posted online, a boy said that his father died and his mother married when he was young. His grandfather also died when he was 18 years old. Now he only has his grandma as a relative. Their family is registered locally. poor households. After entering college, he received national scholarships in previous years, but this year, the class held a scholarship qualification selection, and he was not selected. The students who were selected were wearing real AJ sneakers (a sneaker brand owned by Nike, the price Not cheap), using Apple 14 Pro Max mobile phone and iPad Pro tablet, often having dinner parties and traveling. He reported the situation to the counselor, but was forced to move out of the dormitory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If this is true, it is really outrageous, and this video has attracted a lot of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, fraud in scholarship applications is nothing new in some colleges and universities. National scholarships for colleges and universities are financial aid provided by the state finance to college students with financial difficulties. They are mainly used to meet the living expenses of students. The average aid standard is 3,000 yuan per person per year (not equal, can be divided into 2-3 levels), about 20% students may receive financial aid. Bursaries are a benefit provided by the state to some poor college students. Since it is welfare, how to distribute it and how to let people who really need it get this money is a very important issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to this student, the scholarship qualifications for his class were selected by the whole class because he was not satisfied with the results of the first selection and went to the teacher to report it. As a result, he came last in the second selection. , became the person least qualified to receive scholarships in the class. The whole class selection seems very &quot;reasonable&quot;, but when used here, it is undoubtedly very absurd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who is in financial difficulty and who is not is not a matter decided by one person and one vote. If the selection is held, it will become a &quot;connection&quot; competition, and it is inevitable that some students will form gangs and even bribe the vote. As for truly poor students, they may not be able to mingle with better-off classmates due to financial constraints, and as a result, they may not be eligible for financial aid. On social networks, it is not uncommon for a group of people to &quot;unite together&quot; to promote one person to receive a scholarship and treat them to dinner, and then another person will take turns to receive it next time. Such posts are not uncommon. As a result, some colleges and universities have issued notices that award-winning students are not allowed to use their scholarships to treat guests, otherwise their qualifications for future assessments will be cancelled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some schools and classes even ask students applying for financial aid to tell their situations in front of the whole class and &quot;campaign&quot; for financial aid. This is letting people show their scars for others to see, which may cause a huge blow to the students&#39; self-esteem. Although some students are poor, they do not want others to know, especially in public. After all, poverty is not something worth showing off, and not everyone is compassionate. It is common for students to laugh at poor students in school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also not a good idea to let counselors, class teachers, etc. have the decision-making power about scholarship eligibility. First of all, it is difficult to ensure that these people are completely public-minded in the quota allocation process. Maybe most counselors are fair, but it is inevitable that there will be a few who are partial. Sometimes, financial aid eligibility may even become a tool to blackmail students into &quot;obedience.&quot; Secondly, counselors and others may not be able to fully understand the students&#39; financial situation, and lack sufficient and correct information to make correct judgments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There should be some objective criteria for determining scholarship qualifications, rather than just subjective determination, whether it is the subjectivity of an individual person (identification by the counselor or class teacher) or the subjectivity of the entire class (selection by the whole class) . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the objective standard? Theoretically, it can be whether the student&#39;s family income is below a certain standard. However, schools cannot directly obtain the income and assets of students&#39; families, so many schools ask poor students to provide poverty certificates from village committees or neighborhood committees. But these proofs are not entirely credible. For one, these proofs of poverty are not necessarily true. Especially for many rural areas, when village students are admitted to college, even if their families are not particularly poor, it is not difficult to go to the village committee to issue a poverty certificate. After all, they are all fellow villagers, and a certificate can alleviate the family&#39;s financial burden. Many village cadres will cover the burden unless the family&#39;s income is significantly higher than the village average. Secondly, the poverty standards in different regions are also different. Poverty in economically developed regions and poverty in western regions are completely different concepts. In recent years, there have been frequent cases of government officials visiting &quot;poor&quot; people and being criticized. Although some of them are falsely poor, there are also some misunderstandings caused by differences in regional economic levels. Therefore, the family poverty certificate issued by the place of origin can only be a reference and should not be used as a deciding factor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How should the scholarship qualifications be determined? This is of course a very complex issue and difficult to achieve completely ideally. But there are still some standards that can be referenced. For example, applying for a student loan can be a necessary condition. In the national student aid policy system, student loans are mainly used to solve the tuition and accommodation fees problems of students with financial difficulties. Nowadays, the tuition and accommodation fees of most schools are much higher than the scholarship standards. If you can pay for tuition and accommodation by yourself, it means you are not too poor. Otherwise, you can apply for a student loan to pay tuition and keep your own money for living expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can also observe students’ consumption on campus. The approach of Nanjing University of Science and Technology is a good reference. In 2016, Nanjing University of Science and Technology analyzed student consumption data in the cafeteria and listed those students who ate more than 60 meals in the cafeteria per month with a total consumption of no more than 420 yuan as aid recipients, and paid money directly to their meal cards. This is a very smart approach. As we all know, food in school cafeterias is much cheaper than outside. If a student eats almost every meal in the school cafeteria and the average consumption per meal is not high, there is a high probability that he is a poor student. Rich students either eat less in the on-campus cafeteria and often eat out and order takeout, or they spend more in the cafeteria and eat well. Eating is a basic necessity for people, whether rich or poor, everyone needs to eat, so using food consumption level as a measurement standard can cover all students. And the level of food consumption is difficult to fake. It is difficult for a person who is accustomed to a high standard of diet to continue to lower his dietary standards for a few months if the economic conditions do not change. Of course, this approach may also be used opportunistically, eating a little in the cafeteria for each meal, and then going out to eat and drink, but I am afraid that there are not many rich people who can persist in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, as a welfare provided by the national finance to poor students, the national scholarship should be used wisely to truly reduce the burden of life for poor students, and should not become Tang Monk meat that everyone wants to eat. Tianjin Sino-German University of Applied Sciences officially stated that it has launched an investigation and hopes that the investigation and handling results will be fair and just. More importantly, the problem of unfair distribution of scholarships occurs in many colleges and universities, and should arouse the vigilance of all colleges and universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当一个盲人想要登上珠峰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259956]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/olqpWxQWEpUrbnUzTSjDFES4jSoUR9IEeffnviOT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;641&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/olqpWxQWEpUrbnUzTSjDFES4jSoUR9IEeffnviOT. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256991&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the climb, there were crisscrossing and completely irregular ice cracks underfoot. Zhang Hong You need to use trekking poles to test the location and terrain first, then use your feet to measure the approximate width of the crevasse, and finally dare to step out. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing on the top of the world&#39;s highest peak, blind man Zhang Hong&#39;s first thought was &quot; Get down quickly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Most of the mountaineering accidents occur on the way down the mountain.” Zhang Hong said that when climbing, a person’s center of gravity is first. Even if he falls, the mountain will block him. When going down the mountain, “it all depends on the subconscious mind.” . He felt at ease until he returned to Everest Base Camp and took off his crampons - which meant that danger was truly far away. Sherpa (note: local people living on both sides of the Himalayas, usually serving as guides) gave him a cup of milk tea and a few biscuits to satisfy his hunger. The climb to the summit and back nearly exhausted his strength, and he nearly fell into coma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years later, the cognitive system composed of sound, hearing and touch makes his memories of the world’s highest peak still vivid. He clearly felt the difference in wind at different altitudes: the wind from the glaciers at low altitudes was mixed with freezing cold air, the storms at high altitudes made loud noises, and the strong winds picked up snow particles, ice slag and small rocks, giving people a sticky feel. , like a high wall that is insurmountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hiking across the glacier, the ice on the soles of your feet has a hard texture, and there is a &quot;click&quot; sound like biting potato chips when you step on it. Even with crampons, the risk of slipping is unavoidable. The snow is thick, and the sound of footsteps is muffled in it, giving people a more solid feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 24, 2021, at the 8848.86-meter summit of Mount Everest, Zhang Hong followed the example of his predecessors and left several photos and a 15-second short video. The former became his WeChat avatar, and the latter was the certificate of his record as &quot;the first blind man in Asia to climb Mount Everest&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the news of the successful summit reached Fan Lixin’s base camp, the documentary director had mixed emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He was happy that Zhang Hong’s years of hard work had paid off. In 2019, he heard about Zhang Hong&#39;s ambition from a mountaineering friend: a blind masseur eager to climb Mount Everest. Everyone around him thought it was unreliable, but Fan Lixin became curious about this character. Like a gambler, he wanted to film this story that was very likely to fail. In May 2020, the documentary was launched, and the fate of the two &quot;paranoid&quot; people intersected since then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is worrying is that due to an oxygen problem, the two accompanying photographers were not able to go up together. The video footage of Zhang Hong’s summit was blank. Fan Lixin cried out that she collapsed, “It’s hard for a clever woman to make a meal without rice.” On October 27, 2023, the documentary &quot;The Invisible Peak&quot; was released nationwide. Fan Lixin filled the gap in the material with a &quot;black&quot; segment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We shot more than 360 hours of material, and it took a year to edit. When editing, I was thinking, if there is no material for this section, why not use a black field and an immersive (Sound experience), immersing the audience into the world of a blind person.&quot; Fan Lixin told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Use this black field to take the audience to the top of the world, following Zhang Hong&#39;s footsteps.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/WivtRGd596cs3s9SoNMddIhhBxMGdd3QSXOa6bhS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/WivtRGd596cs3s9SoNMddIhhBxMGdd3QSXOa6bhS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256989&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text -align: center;&quot;>;Zhang Hong and his wife Xia Qiong. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Hong has an almost paranoid desire to climb Mount Everest. At that time, he was working as the deputy director of the Traditional Chinese Medicine Department of a hospital in Tibet. He was in his forties, had a stable job, worked with his wife, and had a son. Everyone was puzzled by his &quot;crazy&quot; desire to climb Mount Everest: &quot;This thing is completely unreliable. I have such a good job in my hand, and I have stabilized, and I still want to do this. This is full.&quot; I can hold on.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Hong admitted that obsession comes from a certain desire to prove something. &quot;I used to label myself as an unfortunate person in society. But the process of climbing Mount Everest taught me one thing: In fact, I am the same as everyone else, and society and nature have no regard for me. I don’t look at it differently.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Mount Everest will not give me more sympathy just because I am blind”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Official filming of the summit Fan Lixin followed Zhang Hong for more than a year. At that time, Zhang Hong&#39;s biggest anxiety during his trip to Mount Everest was money. When the documentary was launched, Zhang Hong received support of US$5,000 from a foundation, but there was still a big gap between the &quot;small one million&quot; RMB. In front of the camera, Zhang Hong took advantage of the wine and asked his brother in embarrassment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I didn&#39;t know much about it at the time. To be honest, I was quite anxious. If he couldn&#39;t raise the money, he wouldn&#39;t be able to go even if he wanted to,&quot; Fan Lixin told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &quot;It&#39;s possible that he would become a The story of &#39;Don Quixote.&#39;&quot; Later, through crowdfunding, brand intervention, and hospital support, Zhang Hong was able to scrape together the money one week before departure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Hong took the traditional route to climb Mount Everest. Take a helicopter or small fixed-wing plane from Kathmandu, the capital of Nepal, to the small town of Lukla, and then hike for 7 days to the Everest base camp, which is &quot;equivalent to initial adaptive training.&quot; After a short rest at the base camp, the team conducted two training sessions. The destination of the first training session is Lobuche, which is more than 6,100 meters high; the second training session involves climbing to the C3 camp at an altitude of 8,300 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fan Lixin has never climbed a mountain before, and Luo Buche, who was training for the first time, was the first mountain he had climbed. When he was a child, he had an operation on his leg and one-third of his knee was cut off, making it difficult for him to climb Mount Everest with Zhang Hong. He invited two mountain photographers, including the producer who also served as a sound engineer, and the team was streamlined to only four people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climbing from the base camp to the C1 camp, the altitude does not increase much, but you have to pass through the Khumbu Glacier, which is known as the &quot;terrible glacier&quot;. There are trenches in the glacier. In the wide ice ravine, two ladders were stacked together to form a bridge, and people and cameras trembled across it. Even Sherpas who have competed with Mount Everest all year round cannot take it lightly. During the filming of the documentary, a Sherpa fell into an ice ravine and hung on by a thread. After the people in the same team worked hard to rescue him, his body was curled up and his ears were purple from the cold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climbers with normal vision can take one step and look at ten steps, but Zhang Hong can only stare at the current step. Every step is difficult. With every step he took, he silently recited in his heart: &quot;This snowfield accepted me again, and the footprints under my feet carried me again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/03/WPjpaab7QJy6eKt9fLqo3FPrpOBP9neXcuFCWk76.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/03/WPjpaab7QJy6eKt9fLqo3FPrpOBP9neXcuFCWk76.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256990&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;When shooting on Mount Everest, the biggest difficulty was the electricity , because the diesel generator needs to come up little by little and can only be charged by solar energy. However, the sun is often not seen for three to five days when climbing, and the documentary team often feels anxious. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Everest will not give me more sympathy just because I am blind. There is an ice cave under the glacier, and there is a cliff next to it. The ladder is also shaky, and the difficulty will not be reduced just because I can&#39;t see it.&quot; Zhang Hong was hit by a similar feeling when he climbed the mountain for the first time, &quot;I can feel that I and Everyone is the same, doing one thing in an equal and fair environment, there is no barrier between me and everyone, instead of before I thought that I was an unfortunate and alternative existence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, due to the inability to see, ice climbing poses many obstacles to Zhang Hong. Fan Lixin said that the weather in the Himalayas was bad that year and the road conditions were complicated. When climbing an ice wall, sighted climbers can step on the ice pits that have been stepped on by the person in front of them. But Zhang Hong couldn&#39;t see it. The steel crampons under his feet were difficult to accurately kick into the old pit, and it took more effort than ordinary people to kick out the new pit. When hanging on the ice wall, the climber relies on three points of support, pulling the rope with one hand and smashing the ice with an ice ax with the other hand to pull his body upwards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We can see it, so we probably know where to hit it, and it will get more force. But he can&#39;t see it, so he just chisels randomly. If he chisels once, the ice will fly away and the chisel will be in vain, so he has to chisel again. Climbing an ice wall of more than ten meters is very tiring.&quot; Fan Lixin observed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the first training session, Zhang Hong suddenly lost his temper and said he no longer wanted to climb, and asked for a helicopter to be sent to pick him up. Some people in the team felt that his pace could not keep up with the progress and slowed down the progress. Zhang Hong looked displeased. &quot;He needs to get in touch with the team. He will feel that the risk is too high. He is not afraid that something will happen to him. What he is most afraid of is that he has not really climbed yet, and he is injured just in training, or his physical strength Exhausted.&quot; Fan Lixin told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Above five or six thousand meters above sea level, people’s emotions and thinking are completely different from those in the plains.” Zhang Hong analyzed his mentality at the time, “If you haven’t climbed (officially) yet, it’s better to practice. It’s not worth it if you get injured during the training.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the second training session, Zhang Hong suffered from an attack of cholecystitis, which caused his facial features to twist tightly together in pain. Back at base camp, the camp doctor examined him. Zhang Hong learned from others that the doctor recommended sending him back to Kathmandu for treatment, &quot;even requiring surgery.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Once I went to treatment, the climb almost came to a standstill.” Zhang Hong wrapped himself in a sleeping bag and broke down crying. &quot;Time waits for no one, the weather is bad, and the window period is limited, only a few days. You can&#39;t give up climbing just because of this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He blamed himself for not having a plan for this, but he was also optimistic about it. There is nothing that can be done about the pain, except rubbing the abdomen and massaging the liver and gallbladder meridian. One of the reasons why he climbed Mount Everest was to break the outside world&#39;s stereotype of blind people. Blind people can not only do massage. But as fate would have it, after two or three days of massage, the symptoms were really relieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Everything is God&#39;s will.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/pxIY9yIS7ks79vnYsbBCixImw9AWvHoKHvS1nygy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/pxIY9yIS7ks79vnYsbBCixImw9AWvHoKHvS1nygy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256987&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 24, 2021, Zhang Hong, who has been blind for 25 years, successfully climbed the world&#39;s highest peak, Mount Everest, from the Nepalese side, becoming the first blind person in Asia to climb Mount Everest. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;To the summit&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The moment of reaching the summit Come on May 23, 2021 at 7pm. Zhang Hong, the Chinese guide, photographer and Sherpa set off from the C4 camp to the top of Mount Everest. When we were only 100 meters away from the peak, something unexpected happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The bad weather froze everyone&#39;s oxygen regulator valves, causing oxygen leaks. Taken together, the current amount of oxygen cannot support everyone reaching the summit. Qiangzi is Zhang Hong&#39;s Chinese guide. He has 15 years of experience as a mountain guide, but has never climbed Mount Everest. For mountaineers, the 100 meters that can be climbed in 2 hours is a &quot;huge temptation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hadron finally decided to give up his oxygen, and the two photographers made the same decision. The three of them descended, and Sherpa accompanied Zhang Hong to the summit alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fan Lixin later asked about the reason for giving up. Qiangzi said that in the three or four years he had known Zhang Hong, he had witnessed his difficulties and grievances along the way. &quot;I really don&#39;t want him to leave again. Maybe he will never have a second chance to leave again in this life. Training, raising money, withstanding the public opinion of the surrounding society, and the doubts of relatives and friends - you see No, why are you taking such a big risk? No one would think that a blind person also has the right to realize his own ideals, pursue his own value in life, and at the same time give his family a voice.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three Summers Erba and Zhang Hong were connected on a rope, and Zhang Hong pushed the ascender forward. A Sherpa led the way about 1.5 meters in front. The two of them did not understand the language and only relied on simple English words &quot;go&quot;, &quot;up&quot; and &quot;down&quot; to communicate. There were two Sherpas carrying oxygen behind him, and one of them occasionally patted his legs to &quot;express comfort and encouragement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before climbing to the top, the most difficult section is the &quot;Hillary Steps&quot;, which is a blade-shaped ridge with almost vertical rock walls that &quot;cannot even catch snow&quot;. Zhang Hong estimated that the narrow spot is only about 30 centimeters, which can only accommodate half a foot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hands became his eyes at this time. He supported it with one hand, and used the other hand to explore the way forward along the tip of his toes. After finding the foothold for the next step, he used the other hand to find the support point. Every time he took a step, he &quot;had to stop and rest for a long time.&quot; Zhang Hong said that climbing the Hillary Step was like walking through the artificial rockery he had seen when his eyesight was still intact. The stone gaps were completely irregular and &quot;I didn&#39;t know what to do next.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Hillary Steps&quot; are only 12 meters from the peak, but it took Zhang Hong more than two hours. When climbing, he lost the concept of time for a while. He would swing the rope left and right at intervals and ask the Sherpa who was leading the way: &quot;How long? How long?&quot; Sherpa&#39;s answer was half an hour every time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The results haven&#39;t arrived after several and a half hours. Maybe I asked how long it would be after 5 minutes, and then asked again after 10 minutes.&quot; Zhang Hong was a little anxious and said several times. No,” “I’m going to die,” “I’m going down.” At first Sherpa ignored his complaints, but the last time Sherpa was also angry. He emotionally agreed to Zhang Hong&#39;s request to give up, and turned around to help him remove the ascender and replace it with the descender. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/FZaEOpaZ1qtetpzFuojXRkKa8TGvXX6nZFA75asj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;586&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/FZaEOpaZ1qtetpzFuojXRkKa8TGvXX6nZFA75asj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256988&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fan Lixin recalled that there were two or three major cyclones in the Indian Ocean that year, which caused heavy snow and strong winds on Mount Everest. On the day Zhang Hong reached the summit, the wind speed reached 60 kilometers per hour, and people were almost killed. If it blows down, if the clothes are scratched and the down flies off, the consequence will be &quot;instant hypothermia and death.&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unwillingness gripped Zhang Hong, and he said to Sherpa: &quot;Go ! Go! Go! &quot;&quot;Keep walking.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While crawling, Zhang Hong suddenly felt his crampons stepping on a soft snow. The further he walked, the thicker the snow became. Until the snow is deep enough to cover the entire sole of the foot. He suddenly bumped into the backpack of the person in front of him. &quot;You summit.&quot; He heard the leading Sherpa turn his head and say to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I didn’t think I had really reached the top.” Zhang Hong recalled, “I didn’t know where I was going, but I just walked like this. Maybe I was too tired and couldn’t take a step from He can react with his concentration.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His senses captured the changes in the surrounding environment before his consciousness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While going up the mountain, Zhang Hong invisibly felt that the mountain he was climbing was like a huge obstacle blocking his face. But in that moment, the barrier disappeared. He could hear the surroundings becoming empty, the kind of emptiness that was unobstructed. He turned his head to the left, then to the right, and listened carefully to the sounds around him. The sound of wind swirling violently on his head made his hair stand on end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They didn’t stay on the top of Mount Everest for a long time. Zhang Hong heard Sherpa say, “Photo, photo,” and quickly took a few photos. It wasn’t until they got down the mountain that they found out, and even took photos for certification. video. He later told Fan Lixin that he only heard various incomprehensible languages ​​blaring on the intercom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When he thought about that moment, it was even a little ridiculous. He had prepared for so many years, prepared many postures and rhetoric to say on Mount Everest, but nothing, just 2 seconds, he He woke up and said, hurry down, this place is too scary, like hell, the howling of the wind.&quot; Fan Lixin recalled, &quot;When he was blind before, he really felt that the world was collapsing, just like in hell. He said that I I have been climbing for 20 years, climbing from hell to flat ground, and then from flat ground to the top of Mount Everest. (When I reached the summit) I felt as if I was in hell again, so I hurried down the mountain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;End of the climb Later, they were trapped in Nepal by a new wave of COVID-19. At that time, it was the most noisy time outside. Fan Lixin counted that more than 70 international mainstream media, including the BBC and AFP, were reporting on him. Zhang Hong said that he was not immersed in the feeling of being under the spotlight at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After he climbed Mount Everest, he discovered that climbing Mount Everest was not the highlight moment he needed at all, but made him understand that the current step is the most important. Because this step has not been stepped on Well, you may just fall and you will be dead. There is no so-called highlight moment at all. The real highlight moment may just begin when you are in the most dangerous moment. The guide in the movie also said: Climbing to the top is not the end. Returning to the top is not the end. Home is the end.&quot; When he was in Nepal, Fan Lixin chatted with him, &quot;He said, now you tell me that where I am standing is the top of Mount Everest, and I believe it because I can&#39;t see it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;He wanted others to think that blind people can not only be masseurs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When he first started filming Zhang Hong, Fan Lixin felt that he was a somewhat impatient person, debugging equipment or Zhang Hong would look a little anxious when it was time to replace the battery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The impatience comes from his sudden blindness. At the age of 21, he suffered a glaucoma attack and permanently lost his vision. It took three or four years for Zhang Hong to try to accept being unable to see, and his personality changed as a result. He became &quot;emotionally broken&quot; and &quot;bad-tempered&quot;. He failed to get what he wanted, or accidentally knocked over a cup. They will show their impatient side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My wife Xia Qiong captured these moments softly. She once tried to put herself in her husband&#39;s shoes, shut herself in the room, turned off all the lights, and closed the windows tightly. &quot;It felt like the four walls were squeezing in on you.&quot; She realized her husband&#39;s nervousness about danger in an unknown environment. &quot;It was originally a very docile sheep, a free species, but suddenly it was trapped in an invisible black cage.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The environment in which Zhang Hong grew up as a child was closely linked to &quot;blindness&quot;. His father and uncle are both blind. He, who has good vision, sometimes acts as a &quot;blind stick&quot;. The three of them pull a bamboo pole, and Zhang Hong leads the way. On a rainy day, the road was slippery and Zhang Hong fell, taking his father and uncle with him. In rural society, he had long been aware of the plight of blind people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have known their lives since I was a child, and I cannot accept the thought that I will have to live in such an environment in the future.” Zhang Hong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xia Qiong noticed that family background and childhood memories created a self-defense mechanism in Zhang Hong&#39;s heart. Before getting married, Zhang Hong had never taken the initiative to talk to her about his father and uncle. They got acquainted with Zhang Hong when he could still see the world. Later, Zhang Hong lost his sight. She joked that she was &quot;harmed&quot; by Jin Yong&#39;s martial arts novels. She bravely felt that &quot;he should not be left alone with no one.&quot; Tube&quot;. In 1999, the two people, who had been in love for three years, decided to testify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The family elders unanimously opposed it, and his father cried in front of Xia Qiong. Zhang Hong promised her: &quot;I will definitely make your family look at you with admiration.&quot; She thought that maybe it was from that time that he laid the groundwork for her husband&#39;s &quot;constant tossing&quot; in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the two decades before Tibet settled down, Xia Qiong described their life as &quot;precarious.&quot; Zhang Hong studied massage in school, but he was not obsessed with it. After he lost his sight, professionalism actually saved him from being unable to eat. Xia Qiong also learned massage. The couple first worked as masseurs in Chengdu and lived a &quot;suffering&quot; life. Later, I went to work in a massage shop in Shanghai, and the two of them were ranked among the &quot;top one or two in the shop.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, when Xia Qiong went home to give birth, she received health care products from Zhang Hong from Shanghai. She knew that her husband was &quot;troublesome&quot; again. Zhang Hong quit his job behind her back and went to work in sales. &quot;He sometimes told people that he couldn&#39;t find a way out in the subway in Shanghai. He was trapped in the subway and at an intersection on the road in Shanghai.&quot; Xia Qiong said, &quot;He wanted to let others I feel that blind people can not only be masseurs, but also do other things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, after climbing the 7,500-meter Muztagh Peak, Zhang Hong decided to prepare for climbing Mount Everest. In order to save money, he adopted the most cost-effective training method - climbing stairs. While climbing, I put on mountain boots and an oxygen-blocking mask, and carried more than 20 kilograms of weight at the same time. I climbed for three to four hours every day. He lived in the hospital&#39;s apartment building and climbed from the first floor to the twelfth floor and then took the elevator down every day. When he met his colleagues in the hospital, he felt the pressure. &quot;Countless people around him questioned him, thinking that this guy was not only blind, but also crazy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Enduring the strange looks from people around him and the difficulty of not being able to raise funds, Countless times, after he got on the elevator, his fingers hesitated and hesitated between the first floor and the floor where his home was located. &quot;I have been struggling like this for two years.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Some people may think that it is enough for their wives to have enough food and clothing, and for their children to have enough money to study; some people think that they should set an example for their children, so that the people they love can have a bright face in front of and behind others.&quot; Xia Qiong said that her husband Zhang Hong &quot;may be the latter.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Zhang Hong successfully climbed Mount Everest, some subtle changes occurred. People in the hospital used to refer to Zhang Hong as &quot;Dr. Xia&#39;s husband.&quot; Now, they call her &quot;Zhang Hong&#39;s wife.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When her son was two years old, Xia Qiong and a relative turned off the lights and asked her son in the darkness: Who do you want to protect when it gets dark? The two-year-old son said sweetly: Protect daddy. Xia Qiong and her female relatives were puzzled: We are all women, why should we protect our father? The son said without thinking: Because dad can’t see. Today, the son feels that his father is &quot;very capable&quot; and &quot;relatively strong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both Fan Lixin and Xia Qiong observed that after successfully climbing Mount Everest, Zhang Hong became much more relaxed in life. After losing his sight, he had difficulty accepting the feeling of being inferior to others. Like every ordinary person, he has his own shortcomings, but he would rather hear criticism from a straight level than praise from a downward view. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Before climbing Mount Everest, I had been outside for so many years and never told anyone about my family’s affairs. Only my wife knew about it, and no other person knew about it. But after I came down from Mount Everest, , I can share anything that happens in my family with anyone, including my father and uncle who can’t see me. I couldn’t face it before, but now I can face these things calmly,” Zhang Hong said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“制造业当家关键在于人”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259951]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In 2008, Hu Xiaoyan was elected as the first batch of migrant workers to the National People&#39;s Congress. (Interviewee/ Picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8f932639d9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1051&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8f932639d9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;In 2008, Hu Xiaoyan was elected as the first batch of migrant workers to the National People&#39;s Congress. (Interviewee/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;It took me three days and three nights to get to Foshan, changing trains and buses all the way. So, I My first impression of Guangdong was probably the feeling of motion sickness.&quot; It was the late autumn of 1998. Hu Xiaoyan was 24 years old. In order to pay off the foreign debt of more than 20,000 yuan owed by her family, she decided to leave her hometown of Guang&#39;an, Sichuan and embark on the furthest journey in her life. A trip - to work in Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;35 years later, Hu Xiaoyan is already the full-time vice chairman of Foshan Sanshui District Federation of Industry and Commerce. On October 25, 2023, at the third &quot;Storytelling Meeting on the 45th Anniversary of Reform and Opening Up&quot;, she recalled the years when she first arrived in Guangdong to work hard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In ten years, Hu Xiaoyan rose from a female assembly line worker in an electronics factory to the management of a ceramic production workshop, and was selected as one of the &quot;Top Ten Migrant Workers in Foshan&quot;. In 2008, for the first time, three representatives of the migrant workers group participated in the National Two Sessions, including Hu Xiaoyan from Guangdong, a major labor import province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since the reform and opening up, the &quot;tide of migrant workers&quot; has promoted China&#39;s industrialization and urbanization process. Guangdong is a major labor importer. In 1988 alone, the number of laborers from other provinces who came to work reached about 3 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The event was hosted by the Information Office of the Guangdong Provincial Government. In addition to Hu Xiaoyan, Shang Xiaodong, a second-level researcher at the South China Sea Institute of Oceanography, Chinese Academy of Sciences, and a mechanical technician from Guangdong Province were also invited College teacher Yang Denghui tells his story. The three people are from different generations and backgrounds, but what they have in common is that they are all foreign talents from Guangdong. Shang Xiaodong was admitted to Taiyuan Institute of Technology (now Taiyuan University of Technology) after the resumption of the college entrance examination. He entered graduate school at the age of 32. In 2005, he came to Guangdong to research physical ocean research. Yang Denghui, who was born in 1997, is the champion of the CNC milling project of the World Skills Competition. He studied at the Guangdong Mechanical Technician College and was elected as a representative of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 26, 2023, workers at an agricultural science and technology enterprise in Yunfu City were cultivating flower seedlings. With the help of the local rural revitalization talent station, the company solved the problem of industrial talents, Technology shortage problem. (Chen Yulong/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c400f44f2d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c400f44f2d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256983&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 26, 2023, workers at an agricultural technology enterprise in Yunfu City were cultivating flower seedlings. With the help of the local rural revitalization talent station, the company solved the problem of shortage of industrial talents and technology. (Chen Yulong/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The first batch of migrant workers&#39; representatives&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;As the spokesperson of more than 200 million migrant workers, I participated in the 5 During the National Two Sessions, a total of 20 suggestions were put forward, and each suggestion was ultimately implemented for migrant workers.&quot; Hu Xiaoyan mentioned that since the reform and opening up, the system for protecting the rights and interests of migrant workers has been changing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Migrant workers are a group born with the reform and opening up. &quot;Household production quota&quot; liberated rural surplus labor from the land, and a large number of rural people poured into cities in search of opportunities. This trend continues today. According to the National Bureau of Statistics, the number of migrant workers was 78.49 million at the beginning of the century, and the total number in 2022 exceeded 295 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Guangdong occupies three of the four major special economic zones identified in 1979, which has created a huge demand for labor. Hu Xiaoyan thus joined the ranks heading south. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The emergence of migrant workers has also highlighted the problem of migrant workers. In 2006, relevant documents from the State Council mentioned that there were problems such as low wages and arrears for migrant workers, and many occupational diseases and work-related injuries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In January 2008, Yang Chengyong, deputy director of the Election Committee of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress, revealed to the media that Guangdong, as the province with the largest influx of migrant population, planned to elect After six migrant workers were elected as representatives to the Provincial People&#39;s Congress, one migrant worker was elected as a deputy to the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before that, Guangdong had been at the forefront in protecting the political rights of migrant workers. In 2000, four outsiders were elected during the general election of the Shenzhen Municipal People’s Congress. Representatives of migrant workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the end, Hu Xiaoyan became the first batch of migrant workers to be a deputy to the National People&#39;s Congress, but before that, she had never served as a deputy to any people&#39;s congress at the township, county, city, or province level. Hu Xiaoyan recalled to Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;I don&#39;t find it difficult because I already live among them (migrant workers).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hu Xiaoyan mentioned To: &quot;The first batch of migrant workers to represent the National People&#39;s Congress became the most eye-catching label on me. From then on, I began to learn how to conduct research, write suggestions, speak, and learn how to perform my duties.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After becoming a deputy to the National People&#39;s Congress, she used her vacation time to visit workers and put forward suggestions including criminalizing unpaid wages, connecting with medical insurance, off-site college entrance examinations, and housing benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At almost the same time, national policies also shifted to consider the new needs generated by migrant workers entering cities. Hu Xiaoyan once suggested “allowing the children of migrant workers to take the college entrance examination in the workplace.” At the end of 2013, Guangdong Province officially announced the implementation measures for the college entrance examination for migrant children in other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today, more &quot;Hu Xiaoyans&quot; have become deputies to the National People&#39;s Congress. Among the deputies to the 14th National People&#39;s Congress, there are 56 migrant workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 26, 2023, students are practicing industrial robot operation at the Technician College in Zhaoqing, Guangdong. (Chen Yulong/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/a56de893e0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/03/a56de893e0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256984&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;October 2023 On the 26th, students were practicing the operation of industrial robots at the Technician College in Zhaoqing, Guangdong. (Chen Yulong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Scientists and Craftsmen&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Shang Xiaodong, a 32-year-old graduate student, said that he and Hu Xiaoyan &quot; “Have the same starting point” as shop workers. It&#39;s just that it&#39;s much older. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The turning point occurred in 1978. Shang Xiaodong heard that his high school classmates were admitted to college, and he began to prepare for the exam. In the second year, he relied on self-study and was admitted to the physics teaching class of the Department of Physics Basics of Taiyuan Institute of Technology. After graduation, he was assigned to serve as a teacher at the Command College of the Chinese People&#39;s Armed Police Force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More than ten years later, he keenly discovered that there were more masters around him, and he felt that &quot;if you don&#39;t study, you will fall behind.&quot; After completing his postgraduate studies in the Department of Mechanics of Tianjin University, he went to Hong Kong, China and the United States for further study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2005, Shang Xiaodong came to Guangdong and entered the South China Sea Institute of Oceanography, Chinese Academy of Sciences. Previously, Guangdong had just issued the “Decision on Accelerating the Construction of a Strong Science and Technology Province.” &quot;There is a good scientific research atmosphere here, and there is a passion for pioneering and bold attempts. This is why our family chose to take root in Guangdong.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Just returned to China At that time, ocean observation instruments had long been monopolized by foreign countries, so Shang Xiaodong decided to lead his team to independently develop ocean observation instruments. In the end, the team developed the &quot;fast temperature sensor for ocean detection&quot; with the fastest response in the world, with a response time of 7 milliseconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under the policy of &quot;strengthening the province through science and technology&quot;, Guangdong also hopes to solve the problem of &quot;two skins&quot; between technology and economy. Empowering new manufacturing industries with new technologies focuses on the integration of technological innovation and industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Denghui said that after enrolling in a technician college in 2014, he &quot;competed with things thinner than a hair every day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yang Denghui, who was born as a technician, saw the new demand for talents behind the &quot;manufacturing industry&quot;. “The key to success in the manufacturing industry lies in people.” He believes that in addition to scientific research talents like Shang Xiaodong, it also needs a large number of highly skilled talents to support it. This is an important reason why he chose to stay in Guangdong Mechanical Technician College to teach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After entering the school, Yang Denghui was selected into the training team preparing for the 43rd World Skills Competition. The training project was CNC milling, which is an automatic processing technology that uses computers. Drawing and programming realize part machining. At that time, China had not won a gold medal in this event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If you want to achieve success in CNC milling projects, you must practice &quot;knife skills&quot;: choose appropriate tools according to different materials and production requirements of the parts, and strictly control them The accuracy of parts and components is controlled within 0.02 mm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2017, Yang Denghui, who started his career again, won the CNC milling championship at the 44th World Skills Competition. He was only 20 years old that year. After graduation, he joined the technical education team, and the students he guided won the world championship gold medal in this project again in 2019 and 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Data from the Guangdong Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security show that currently, the total number of skilled talents in Guangdong is 18.5 million, including 6.31 million highly skilled talents. Talents account for 34.1%. In 2023, Yang Denghui will also become a representative of the National People&#39;s Congress, and naturally he will focus on the cultivation of skilled talents in performing his duties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;(Hope) to help skilled employees break through the &#39;ceiling&#39; for promotion, so that more talents can make a difference in Guangdong.&quot; Yang Denghui expressed at the event His vision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[违法转运火化遗体，蓄意瞒报4死4伤事故，36人被问责]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259959]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 10:36:34&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 13:29 on April 2, 2023, Jikun, Jiangyuan District, Baishan City, Jilin Province Mining Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Jikun Coal Mine&lt;/span>;) +290m east of Shimen South Wing, a large gas explosion accident occurred on the second floor of the fourth uphill coal mining face, causing 4 deaths and 4 injuries (another 4 people Physical discomfort, recovered after receiving oxygen), direct economic loss of 10.16 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the accident, Jikun Coal Mine failed to report the accident as required, illegally transshipping and cremating the remains of the victims, and sealing off the accident site to conceal the accident. After receiving reports from the masses, when the Baishan City Emergency Management Bureau and the Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau went to the coal mine to verify the reported cases from April 3 to 12, 2023, the mine still did not report truthfully. On April 13th and 14th, four people including the mine investor and mine manager surrendered under pressure. The accident was verified to be true by the Baishan Municipal People&#39;s Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Jilin Bureau of the National Mine Safety Supervision Bureau released the accident investigation report. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;How the accident occurred&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the day shift on April 2, 2023, mine manager Li Yonghai organized a pre-shift work meeting. Li Yanping, deputy director of production, Lu Wanping, chief engineer, and Li Shichen, technical consultant, assigned production tasks to each team. After the meeting, Yang Licheng, captain of the third mining team, assigned production tasks for the shift to Wang Hongchang, the squad leader of the accident squad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Hongchang’s team has 13 people on duty and 1 tile inspector. Wang Hongchang arranged for Leng Jun, Ji Yaomin, Zhang Chengxue and Zhang Qinglong to set off cannons and produce coal at Sanshang Mountain. He, Wang Junfu and Sun Cheng set off cannons and produce coal at Sishang Mountain, Li Junsheng and Guo Wensheng built wood stacks for reinforcement at Wushang Mountain, and Yang Lianpeng and Gao Cai installed equipment in the main alley. Cars, Huang Fujun and Zhang Yongsheng are responsible for pulling coal. Lu Xiang is responsible for checking the gas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The workers entered the well from the abandoned heating tunnel at about 8:00, and picked up their own miner&#39;s lamps from the &quot;Miner&#39;s Lamp Supermarket&quot; there. They did not carry personnel identification cards and self-rescuers, and arrived at their respective operations at about 8:15. Place. At around 10 o&#39;clock, in order to solve the ventilation problem at the Wushangshan working face, the ventilation team leader Guan Yanlin led three workers to move the local ventilator between Sishangshan and Wushangshan at +290m East Shimen back 20 meters and move it away from the wind The bifurcation of the cylinder connects the air duct to Wushangshan. This local ventilator supplies air to the three working surfaces of Sanshangshan, Sishangshan and Wushangshan at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 13:30, Ji Yaomin and others who were working on Sanshang Mountain suddenly saw a puff of black smoke and the wind stopped. They felt difficulty breathing and could not see anything. Zhang Qinglong and Zhang Chengxue took the lead to escape. Ji Yaomin and Leng Jun took the tools and then ran outside. When they ran to Sanshang Pass, they found that there was wind in the alleyway. At this time, Zhang Qinglong and Zhang Chengxue were lying on the ground and lost consciousness. They immediately performed cardiopulmonary resuscitation and rescued them. About 5 minutes later, The two woke up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, Liu Tiezhu, the project manager who was walking to the entrance of the central water pump room at +290m, felt a large fluctuation in the wind flow, and saw a lot of dust in the wind flow in the direction of Dongyi Shimen, so he went After checking, they saw the injured Lu Xiang, Gao Cai and Guo Wensheng respectively (Gao Cai and Guo Wensheng were seriously burned), and heard Leng Jun&#39;s voice at Mikami Pass, and then returned and took Lu Xiang to the +290m water pump room, and Call the dispatch office to report the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Accident rescue process&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After receiving the accident report, dispatcher Meng Fanjun reported the accident to mine director Li Yonghai. Yonghai immediately reported the situation to mine investor Wang Haoming and legal representative Cong Peifu, and arranged for Li Tao and Huo Jianguo to organize personnel to go down the mine to carry out rescue. Rescuers met survivors such as Lu Xiang, Zhang Chengxue, Ji Yaomin, Guo Wensheng, Huang Fujun and Zhang Yong, and sent people to escort them to the well. At the same time, a person (Yang Lianpeng) was found buried in coal at the fan switch, with only one leg exposed. He was confirmed dead at the scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rescuers found a fall at the Sishang Pass. They checked that the carbon monoxide concentration on the inside of the Sishang Pass was 999ppm (portable multi-function detector range 0~999ppm), the gas concentration was 0.1%, and the oxygen concentration was 5%. All people on the mountain were believed to have died, and the search for rescuers continued. When we reached the Sanshang Pass, coal fell and blocked the roadway. We found 4 people calling for help in Sanshang Mountain. We immediately cleared the coal and entered Sanshang Mountain to rescue the seriously injured Gao Cai and Li Junsheng. Then we lifted out Zhang Qinglong, who could not stand on his right leg, and finally Rescue Leng Jun and escort him to the surface. At 18:10, all survivors had reached the ground and were sent to hospitals for treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 18:40, rescue workers began to clear the pile of coal where Yang Lianpeng died, and pulled out the body and transported it to the ground. Then the carbon monoxide was discharged section by section up the mountain. When the discharge reached 13 meters from the mountain pass, the deceased Wang Hongchang was found. The gas continued to be discharged, and the victims Wang Junfu and Sun Cheng were found about 1 meter below the shelter. So far, all the bodies of the victims have been found and transported to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Direct reasons&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;+290m East Shimensi Mountain is connected to the +355m goaf area, and gas surges in the goaf area out; a local ventilator was used to supply air to three working locations at the same time. The air volume was insufficient, causing gas accumulation, and the workers fired cannons in violation of regulations, leading to accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;The accident concealment process&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the accident, Wang Haoming, the investor and actual controller of Jikun Coal Mine, arranged for the mine manager Li Yonghai organized the rescue on his own without reporting to the emergency department; arranged for Wang Zhenshan and Wang Weidong to treat the injured and the aftermath of the deceased; arranged for Cong Peifu to assist the mine manager in handling the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Weidong sent four seriously injured people to the Hunjiang District Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital, and then transferred them to the First Affiliated Hospital of Jilin University in Changchun City. Four workers who felt unwell were sent to Tonghua City Hospital for inhalation. Oxygen therapy. Wang Zhenshan sent the four victims to the Jiangyuan District Cemetery Funeral Home, Jiangyuan District Ni Tai Hospital, Sanchazi Forestry Bureau Hospital Morgue, and Textile Factory Funeral Home, and reached a compensation agreement with the families of the victims. Subsequently, he purchased two &quot;Resident Death Medical Certificates (Inference)&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Death Certificates&quot;) from Wang Yonghai, director of the textile factory funeral home, for 50,000 yuan each, resulting in the illegal disposal of the remains of the two deceased persons. At the same time, Wang Zhenshan arranged for personnel to delete video surveillance data related to the accident on the afternoon of April 5, deliberately concealing the accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At around 2:00 on April 3, after the on-site rescue work was completed, Li Yonghai arranged for Guan Yanlin to lead the ventilation team members into the well, and at the original sealed position of +290m East Shimen and +355m return air alley. Construct a &quot;quick seal&quot; to seal the accident scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Concealing the verification process&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 23:00 on April 2, Baishan City Emergency Management Bureau, Jilin Provincial Emergency Management Department, and Provincial Party Committee Inspection Team have successively received reports about the Jikun Coal Mine accident. report. On April 3, the Baishan City Emergency Management Bureau took the lead in setting up a joint verification team with the Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau to verify the reported cases, inspected the safety monitoring system, personnel location monitoring system and video surveillance system, and conducted a review of the April 2 incident. During the day shift, 52 people working in the well were questioned and collected evidence. As of April 13, the inspection team found no signs of a gas accident in Jikun Coal Mine, and evidence collection from those who entered the mine on duty showed that no accident occurred in Jikun Coal Mine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of April 13, in accordance with the spirit of the Baishan Municipal Party Committee meeting on April 12, the relevant leaders of the Baishan City and Jiangyuan District governments took the lead and organized the Public Security Bureau, Emergency Management Bureau and other departments to establish a joint verification team. , conduct in-depth verification of reported matters. At 18:00 on April 13, Jikun Coal Mine Director Li Yonghai, legal representative Cong Peifu, and Deputy Mine Safety Manager Li Tao surrendered to the Jiangyuan District Public Security Bureau with the consent of investor Wang Haoming under pressure from the investigation, admitting that gas occurred underground in Jikun Coal Mine. The accident resulted in 4 deaths and 4 injuries. On April 14, investor Wang Haoming surrendered to the Jiangyuan District Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation and verification, the Baishan Municipal People&#39;s Government Office&#39;s &quot;Explanation on the &quot;4·2&quot; Gas Accident of Jikun Mining Co., Ltd., Jiangyuan District, Baishan City&quot; confirmed: at about 14:00 on April 2, 2023 , a gas accident occurred in Jikun Coal Mine, resulting in 4 deaths and 4 injuries. After on-site inspection by the mine rescue team of Tonghua Mining Group Company, the hidden area was sealed and comprehensively searched, and no other casualties were found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;36 people were held accountable: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The accident investigation report put forward accountability and handling suggestions for 36 relevant responsible personnel. . Among them, 12 people were recommended to be transferred to judicial authorities for processing:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10 people including the manager of Jikun Coal Mine, legal representative, investor (actual controller), chief engineer, and the outpatient department of Jiangyuan District Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital A total of 12 suspected criminals, including the director and the director of the Jiangyuan District Textile Factory Funeral Home, were transferred to the judicial authorities for investigation and investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Eight people were recommended to be given administrative penalties: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jikun Coal Mine Project Department Manager, Deputy Manager, and Deputy Safety General Manager Eight people including the engineer, deputy chief engineer of mechanical and electrical engineering and director of the dispatching office were respectively imposed administrative penalties and had their professional qualifications revoked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;15 people were recommended to be held accountable for party and government discipline: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The employment contracts of three mine safety supervisors were terminated and Ordered not to engage in coal mine safety production work within the administrative area of ​​Jilin Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The director of the Wangou Town Safety Supervision Branch of the Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau was given a one-year party probation and was removed from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the second office of the Coal Supervision Section of the Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau was given a serious demerit penalty and removed from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Criticize and educate the executive deputy director of Jiangyuan District People’s Government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To the deputy director in charge and captain of the law enforcement detachment of Baishan City Emergency Management Bureau, the former party secretary and director and deputy director in charge of Jiangyuan District Emergency Management Bureau, the party committee secretary, town mayor and deputy town mayor of Wangou Town and Nine public officials, including the president and vice president of Jiangyuan District Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine, were given party disciplinary and government sanctions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Jikun Coal Mine was fined and closed&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A total of 5 million was fined for concealing the occurrence of a major accident in Jikun Coal Mine and concealing the report. A fine of RMB 10,000 was included in the joint punishment targets;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jikun Coal Mine did not obtain a safety production license and illegally produced coal outside the scope of technical transformation design. It was an illegal coal mine and its illegal gains and mined coal and mining were confiscated. equipment, and be fined and requested to the Baishan Municipal People&#39;s Government to close it down in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 10:55:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在上海，他们进行了一场现实主义“万梗节”狂欢]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259893]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;October 31, 2023, on Julu Road, Shanghai, cosplaying with White Snake and Fa Hai young people. Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49f8464d89.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 703&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49f8464d89.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256936&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 31, 2023, on Julu Road in Shanghai, a young man cosplayed White Snake and Fa Hai. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Halloween has passed, but the &quot;Ten Thousand Stem Festival&quot; has not. This large-scale carnival still has lingering warmth in the metropolis of Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 1st every year is the traditional Western festival of Halloween. The most lively moment is on Halloween, when children dress up as various cute ghosts, knock on doors and do trick-or-treating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Halloween in Shanghai in 2023 comes earlier. Starting from October 28, the city switches to the magical side. Major theme parks and some Internet celebrity bars will hold Halloween activities, as well as spontaneous street parties. Monsters and monsters of different shapes appeared on the street. What is unexpected is that Internet memes with a strong Chinese style have suddenly emerged and become popular all over the Internet. They are dubbed as a new trend of &quot;Renaissance&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the lanterns come on, an ordinary old street can turn into a movable feast. It will be a fairy tale world where you can cosplay various characters and experience another identity; it can be a channel to release stress and express yourself; it can also be a traffic pool full of temptations. The cosplayers in the pool are eye-catching enough, and there are precedents for Xiti’s hot search lists on major platforms, which means that traffic and money will have the opportunity to be included in the bag. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters interviewed more than a dozen &quot;crazy citizens&quot;. According to them, Shanghai has not been this lively for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 30, the Julu Road area was crowded with people. Visual China&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /03/66c8c013f9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/66c8c013f9.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;256937&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 30, the Julu Road area was crowded with people. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Pure happiness&quot; on Julu Road&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After leaving the subway station, the flow of people under the bright yellow lights was surging in one direction. Even without navigation, you can determine the general direction of Julu Road. The closer you get there, the denser the crowds will be. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The location with the strongest Halloween atmosphere is Julu Road in Huangpu District, Shanghai. This is a commercial street named after the giant cruise ship &quot;Julu&quot; of the French Post Line. There are many exotic and Western-style shops. Historical buildings spread across this prosperous area. The most iconic one is the Sunken Plaza at No. 158 Julu Road, which has always been the most popular place to visit on Halloween. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 31st, the night in Shanghai was getting darker and the carnival began. There is Tathagata Buddha riding a shared bicycle inadvertently passing by, exuding golden light; there is a zombie bride and the fire ghost king who are all dressed in red; there is also Lu Xun in a long robe, lamenting that studying medicine cannot save the Chinese people ; Pretending to be a potted plant, acting out a famous painting, or even raising a middle finger in a headband can create a bizarre landscape... The journey from Julu Road to Fuxing Park, less than 1 kilometer away, is packed with people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The level of crowding made police nervous. The entrance to Julu Road has been blocked by police with iron railings, and blue and red police lights are flashing everywhere. While maintaining order, the traffic police repeatedly emphasized: &quot;I am not a cosplayer.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the fence could not stop the enthusiastic flow of people. They took a shortcut from the nearby green slope about ten meters and sneaked into Julu road. Southern Weekend reporters followed the flow of people up the slope. Looking from above, Julu Road looked like a colorful light strip. The crowds of people almost filled the entire space on the road and flowed slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The adjacent Chengdu South Road disperses some of the flow of people overflowing from Julu Road. Relatively speaking, this place is a lot ordinary. There are two or three-story private houses on both sides of the road, full of clothing stores, leather bag stalls, taverns and fly restaurants. A restaurant owner sitting on the street is surrounded by a crowd of people. &quot;Normally there are not many people.&quot; Here, from last Saturday until now, there are many people in the store.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you take a few steps, you will see large and small black and white impermanences. They hold long red tongues. On their black and white high hats are written &quot;Peace in the world&quot; and &quot;Wealth at first sight&quot;. , including many children wearing thick black eye shadow and looking cute. At the corner, I met the White Snake and Fahai living in harmony. The masked men from the popular Korean drama &quot;Squid Game&quot; stood in a row against the wall and obediently cooperated with tourists to take photos. It had nothing to do with horror. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most eye-catching people at the scene were the boys cosplaying Batman. They were tall and tall, with black masks covering their eyes, clear mandibles and indifferent expressions. From time to time, girls around him would scream, &quot;So handsome.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Batmans have been touring twice, always causing commotion at the scene. Their trump card is to take off their tight tops and expose their porcelain chest muscles if they disagree. Circle after circle of people gathered around to cheer. The tourists on the outside couldn&#39;t see it. They just stood on tiptoe and pointed their raised mobile phones towards the center to take pictures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within only three seconds, the Batmans were pushed out of the crowd by the police, and there was a burst of laughter from the crowd. This is a routine operation to maintain order on Halloween. People and &quot;ghosts&quot; causing congestion will be taken away by the police and moved to another place to ease the flow of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Batman Strong Man. Photographed by Li Zixuan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0aafd3e5ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/0aafd3e5ef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256938 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Batman hunk. Photo by Li Zixuan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A God of Wealth holding a gold ingot was undoubtedly respected. There was a long queue of tourists taking photos. Some people clasped their hands and bowed their heads in worship to the God of Wealth, begging her to bless them with good fortune. For about half an hour, the God of Wealth was blocked and did not move a step. The gold ingot was touched here and there. Every time he wanted to leave, he was pulled back by the person who took the photo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The faces of the elderly also appeared in the crowd, and they were also very busy. Maybe it’s because “I can’t understand it, but I’m very shocked.” An elderly man sighed, “We also get to know the things of young people. It’s lively, fun, and fresh.”&lt;/p>; &lt; p>; &quot;Don&#39;t you think this is a release? A release of stress.&quot; Another Shanghai uncle talked to a Southern Weekend reporter. He had been standing on the roadside for two hours, observing and feeling the carnival atmosphere. My uncle is from Shanghai, but he has never seen such an atmosphere. &quot;I am very happy to see such an atmosphere. I think everyone is also happy from the bottom of their hearts. This is not a festival. Everyone is just using the festival as an excuse to be happy.&quot; , pure joy.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Go crazy together and release stress”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A novel scene appeared at the subway entrance near Julu Road. Many people gathered together to exchange professional opinions. So much so that the subway entrance was blocked again. Some said they were studying law, some were studying civil engineering, and some were studying architecture. Everyone complained that it was difficult to get along in the corresponding industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What resonated strongly was the boy surrounded by Xiao Xie. He looked haggard and had pale lips. The card hanging on his chest had four big words written on it: Studying Architecture. He was also carrying two wads of toilet paper. take-out box, looking impoverished. &quot;It is true that this industry is not very prosperous, and my work is not going well, so I take this opportunity to go crazy together.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Everyone is going crazy, and I want to go crazy too. It feels so good, and I put all my inner thoughts into it.&quot; Release the pressure.&quot; Xiao Xie just did a bold thing and resigned naked in October 2023. It was a period of work where &quot;I couldn&#39;t move even if I wanted to curl up, but I didn&#39;t dare to lie down&quot;. Everyone didn&#39;t dare to leave their seats after get off work, and they were chased by their leaders to make work demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The migrant worker who is even more out of the circle is Li Qiubai, the actor of Party B who wanders the same street. His makeup was rough and exaggerated. The dark eyeshadow and highlighter applied on his face made it look like his cheekbones were protruding and his cheeks were sunken. He had an A4 paper with &quot;Party B&quot; written on it in the collar of his checkered shirt, clearly showing a person who had been squeezed by Party A for a long time. haggard beat worker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Party B coser. Photo provided by interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/ea2ca50d1b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1194&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/ea2ca50d1b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256939 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Party B cosplayer. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I cosplayed a character who had just finished his shift, and I didn’t expect the effect to be so good.” Li Qiubai had indeed just finished his shift, and it was already late at night when he arrived at Julu Road, so he decided to perform a Party B, who was tired, was constantly surrounded by people taking photos. The number of views on his social account has &quot;exploded&quot;, and many netizens have left messages expressing sympathy. &quot;Some people read the jokes, and some people look in the mirror. There are many comments like this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Maybe it&#39;s because after the epidemic, there is no such activity that everyone can enjoy. Although the previous festivals were holidays, various tickets were not available.&quot; Li Qiubai said that now it has reached a In a festival where everyone can go crazy, I have an outlet to vent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, Li Qiubai also encountered many poor people who did not need to dress up, as well as the resentful Party A. Some people held up signs: &quot;People who usually have a hard time pretending to be themselves don&#39;t need to dress up for Halloween.&quot; It&#39;s OK.&quot; Li Qiubai summed up this type of cosplay as: using realistic expression techniques to present the things that workers fear most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 31st, many cosplayers said they came over right after get off work. A King Zhou finished putting on a solemn dramatic face in his company, and walked around the streets to find two strangers, Daji, to form a CP; a 28-year-old young man drove here from Jiaxing City, Zhejiang Province, and she cosplayed Hayao Miyazaki&#39;s classic animated character, the Faceless Man, stood hunched silently on the roadside, with more than a hundred people gathered around to take a group photo. Because she had to go to work the next day, she returned to Jiaxing overnight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Gongzi chose to release herself in another way. She played the role of SpongeBob SquarePants, who is also 37 years old. On weekdays, she is engaged in the company&#39;s business work, talking about cost-effectiveness and the company&#39;s maximum benefits. But before Halloween comes, the homemade yellow felt board square shell makes her purely the embodiment of happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Mr. Wang cosplayed Spongebob Squarepants into Happy Valley, he immediately became the center of attention and was even mistaken by tourists for being a professional staff member of the park. A crowd of chirping children followed her, stuffing her with candies and throwing out a hundred thousand whys: Did Mr. Krabs give you a day off? Why don&#39;t you bring Xiaowei to play with you? What’s the secret ingredient to the Krusty Krab? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night, Mr. Wang said, the whole group went crazy. Di Dixi, a colleague cosplaying as a Haidilao waiter, was originally a typical i person (referring to an introvert). In this atmosphere, she was directly reshaped into an e person (referring to an extrovert). She would take the initiative to get in front of some tourists. There is no real thing to do in the crazy performance, just twisting the hands in the air, but it is self-intoxicating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night, Di Dixi also interviewed &quot;Li Jiaqi&quot;, a cosplayer who sells eyebrow pencils for 79 yuan. The other person responded in a long voice, &quot;Why is it so expensive? It&#39;s always the same price. It&#39;s really annoying.&quot; Dixi burst into laughter on the spot. Later, this video unexpectedly went viral. Prince Wang and his friends were all shocked. Is the Sheniu girl in front of them the same Didixi who dared not speak in front of others and pretended to be immersed in looking at her mobile phone? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She became more aggressive after she woke up the next day. Looking back, she felt so embarrassed and a little bit ashamed.&quot; Didisi&#39;s friend recalled to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Within a few days, Didixi led her two friends who were smarter than herself and headed towards Julu Road. She put on heavy makeup and went back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;There are people on the street who cosplay and learn computers. Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/23771ba873. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;631&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/23771ba873.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;256940&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;There are people on the street who are cosplaying and learning computers. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Take advantage of the popularity to become a fan”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Chen Yanzhi is on the hot search again. In 2022, he was dressed like An Lingrong and danced on roller skates, which made him a hot search. After all, &quot;The Legend of Zhen Huan&quot; is the &quot;electronic mustard&quot; for all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this sea of ​​folk joy, Halloween has also become a traffic carnival, with many video teams wandering around. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“She is so hot.” ​​A Ying, who cosplayed An Lingrong’s Maid, was a little proud. She told Southern Weekend reporters that after deciding to perform the scene of “An Lingrong singing on the bow”, several commercials A team of people made careful planning and posted a &quot;thaw&quot; trailer on the short video platform, implying An Lingrong&#39;s return. They also made a video invitation with a route plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“What we are looking for is Lalamove to drag the prop boat over. As soon as it got off the cargo puller, many people called An Lingrong.” On the evening of October 28, An Lingrong was sitting on the boat. As soon as he came out, he was surrounded by a crowd of people, which directly diverted the traffic of other nearby cosplayers. They put on cheap wigs and the same costumes as in the play. An Lingrong on the bow of the boat was holding a lotus. The music &quot;Lotus Can Be Picked in Jiangnan&quot; was played on the Bluetooth speaker, and everyone sang along. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of likes for the short video shot by the team at that time soared to tens of thousands. When it came to Fuxing Park for the second time, thousands of people watched the live broadcast. &quot;It&#39;s quite fun. Everyone came up with a lot of creative ideas. I finally saw how relaxed the people in Shanghai are.&quot; A Ying said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An Lingrong’s previous appearance in the industry also inspired the Hangzhou boy Xingxing. In this Halloween, he became popular with his cosplay of Xiang Tai. In one of his most widely circulated videos, Xingxing is wearing a pink coat that the team temporarily bought for 400 yuan, looking rich and wealthy. Someone asked him what he thought of Xiangtai&#39;s daughter-in-law Guo Biting. He smiled slightly and imitated: &quot;It&#39;s easy to control.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response, Xiangtai himself responded from a distance: &quot;The clothes are too low, he should imitate Make it more beautiful.&quot; This shocked the Xingxing team. Originally, everyone joked that the Halloween cosplay star lineup would be enough to receive letters from lawyers from all the celebrities on the Internet, but it was so popular that people were still caught off guard. &quot;We were actually a little scared, afraid that if the Xiangzuo team came to us and asked us if we had any problems, but in the end they only said to interact, then we went to interact.&quot; Ami, a staff member of the Xingxing team, told a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ami introduced that Xingxing is a self-media beauty blogger. After causing trouble with Taizhuang, many cooperative merchants approached us, &quot;Many people sent us private messages to discuss cooperation. We should wake up We woke up and pretended to interact with each other, but we refused because we were afraid of being scolded.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people were worried and some were happy. After seeing Xiang Tai and An Lingrong become popular on the Internet, Na Ying, the actor who plays Na Ying, was also moved. &quot;Then I have to go.&quot; On November 1, she imitated Na Ying&#39;s tone on the other end of the phone when being interviewed by a Southern Weekend reporter.此前，她买来《妻子的秘密》剧中黎明朗的衣服，最低配版的墨镜、发夹和话筒，连去巨鹿路三晚，模仿那英不断输出“那言那语”，“我一张嘴，他们就嗷嗷叫唤”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;效果立竿见影。这英版的那英，走到哪里都自带流量，即使是戴上口罩，摘掉眼镜，换上朋友的衣服，还是会被人认出来，狠狠体验了一把明星被追的待遇。 “他们以为我是真的那英，所有人尖叫，说太像了，喊&#39;那姐，别跑&#39;，&#39;那姐，给我拍照&#39;。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我去之前我就知道会出圈，只是不确定会出圈到什么程度。”三天下来，这英的抖音粉丝涨了近十万，她紧紧抓住流量密码，“万圣节当晚回到家后，我还开了一场直播，希望可以趁着热度涨点粉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在10月31日现场狂欢中，一声嘶吼突然让噪杂的人群顿了一下。 “还让不让人过了？”一个陷在人流里的外卖小哥发了火，他的车轮此刻寸步难行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但很快气氛就恢复了，这样的场景并不陌生，时不时就有外卖员在沸腾的人群里嚷嚷：“让一让，超时了，超时了。”在这场分不清楚真真假假的狂欢活动中，很难不让人怀疑，他们是在cos外卖小哥。在采访期间，也有人向南方周末记者投来疑惑的眼神，问“你是在cos记者吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直到临近午夜时分，巨鹿路的人流逐渐淡了下来。跨过这个夜晚，上海又将回归大都市节奏紧张的一面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（文中受访者姓名均为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[划着轮椅，出门去]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259854]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Xm69IGLIOY0RdqFGd0x7xHAkdl2sxvVquGUPdTNq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Xm69IGLIOY0RdqFGd0x7xHAkdl2sxvVquGUPdTNq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;田野在他的串串店图/网商银行公益小店联盟提供&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海是蓝蓝的，一眼望不到边。向外是沙滩，长满了度假的人。再向外是主路，平坦宽阔，一台轮椅从远方驶来，正从沥青路向海边移动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里是海南三亚，松软细腻的沙粒尽显优质，然而却是对轮椅的挑战。轮椅的轮子容易下陷，田野坐在上面，得有人倒着向前拉，他才能缓缓移动，一点点，再一点点，沙滩和大海以更缓慢的速度，来到这个小伙身前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出门最艰难的处境在于，经常要等，“等一个帮助你的人出现”。田野几次跟我回忆旅途，比如从主路到沙滩，半米高的铁栏杆挡在眼前，别人能一下跨过去，他却不能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;溜冰、散打、开车，17岁之前的西安小伙田野好动，眼中的未来“无所不能”。 2004年，一场意外车祸导致他高位截瘫，此后只能坐在轮椅上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在被动等待之外，他和其他坐在轮椅上的“伤友”们互相鼓励着，走出门去，绘制出西安主城区三环内各处无障碍设施的地图，标记出存在的问题，打通出门的路。 3个月、4辆轮椅，每天15小时，成就一张597平方公里的无障碍地图，三种颜色分类做出了上千个标记，布满西安三环内所有主干道，相关部门据此清理障碍，更多出门的路出现在身障人士眼中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一路走来，他们遭受过不少非议，“绕一下不就得了吗，为什么非走这条路？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“没有想抄近路，我只是想走本来的那条路。”田野坐在轮椅上，重复这个回答。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/H8IgQNi0WPgEHVQguJObawbf6qFhz4KA5xiCCPJJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;541&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/H8IgQNi0WPgEHVQguJObawbf6qFhz4KA5xiCCPJJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256495&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“伤友”们一起推着轮椅行走在无障碍通道图/微电影《嘿，出来》 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;被精确的身体需求&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;一辆轮椅遇见另一辆轮椅，越来越多，五六个开轮椅的人聚在空旷的场地上，“嘿，出来！”简单的招呼过后，他们开始了比赛——轮椅竞速。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赛道很长，需要穿过一些无障碍通道，道路细微的不规范可能导致轮椅的减速甚至暂停，这是坐在轮椅上的他们驶过无数次的路，曾经的不规范被一一标注、反馈、打通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竞速结束，他们会相约去吃上一顿，聚餐地点在田野的串串店。在那里，身障人士就餐打五折，是“伤友”们的固定聚餐点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但一连数日，我始终没等到这样的画面。 9月中旬，正逢西安雨季，持续十几天的阴雨，分隔开此前的夏与之后的冬。 “西安没秋，”当地人这么说。一转眼，天气由热转冷，不给人准备的时间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即便在西安生活了数十年，即便是天气的细微变化，“伤友”们也感觉不适，雨来了，他们更加出不去了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;凑在一起，不容易。他们正在慢慢习惯，就像生活中很多的细节，都需要重新适应，在时间中寻找新的秩序。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们需要精确控制自己的身体需求。比如最简单的喝水，要定时、定量，做好精确管理，否则无法控制大小便的时间规律，给出门增加困难；不喝水是不行的，有人试过，膀胱系统感染、尿路感染的问题会随之而来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/UlsQrXIjBHgH2o9TqtQrZZpjwhsb6zBL2GZwJCRj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/UlsQrXIjBHgH2o9TqtQrZZpjwhsb6zBL2GZwJCRj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;微电影拍摄杀青后，田野和剧组人员合照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（网商银行公益小店联盟提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;喝水的速度也要控制，喝得太快、太猛，水过快从喉咙到了膀胱，误差随之出现，五分钟的时间差，对于出门的轮椅来说，就可能意味着超过两小时的意外。这两小时的行程是紧凑的：找到合适的地点、清理自己的身体，再推开门走上街，假装一切不曾发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与身体培养默契，需要应对季节的变化。比如夏天和冬天，人的出汗量不同，对应的喝水规律自然不同。探索每一细小规律的方寸之差，源自“伤友们”心底深处难以抗拒出门的诱惑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野开的打五折的串串店也是“伤友”们出门的诱惑之一。 17岁那年他遭遇意外车祸，高位截瘫，依靠轮椅出行，成为“伤友”圈的一员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一次见到田野，是在他的家中。尿路感染是伤友们的常见病之一，田野刚从医院输液回来，坐在轮椅上，身体歪向一侧，讲话的尾音垂在地上，带着强撑精神的疲惫。脚上是运动鞋，不时需要人帮他搬动一下，确保踩在轮椅的踏板上，聊天时间一长，就需要移动一下。重力的作用会让他的脚越来越不舒服，直到向身边的人开口求助。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大多数时候，这个人是他的爸爸。 “爸，喝水。”“爸，可乐。”不需要道谢，不需要解释，或者其他任何理由，漫长的时间会把这样的对话简化为最直接的表达。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野住在西安市曲江新区，这里平均每隔几百米建有一个公共卫生间，配备有无障碍卫生间。田野坐在电动轮椅上，熟练地开往家附近的一个公共卫生间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;打开无障碍卫生间的门，里面设施完备，有能把婴童放在横板上躺着换尿布的设施，有能把婴童固定坐在一侧方便家长如厕的设施，也有带着扶手方便残障人士如厕的设施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而完备的另一面，只有真正使用的人才能感受到其中细微的差异。田野推着轮椅，走到镜子前，在平整洁净的半身镜中，他看不到自己。田野解释，镜子需要有一定的倾斜度，才能在低处看到自己的面貌。我试着弯腰低头，让自己的视线与坐在轮椅上的他的头部高度持平，不再敢说这是“细微”之差。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从主路通往卫生间的无障碍通道的两边并不平整，而站在一旁却看不出异常。 “两边不平，”田野的爸爸用手比量了一下。相关道路规范是误差不能超过2厘米，“1厘米以内（误差）对于轮椅上下来说不影响，但这条路至少有5厘米的误差。”直到田野的轮椅缓缓上行，几次用力都推不上去，猛然加速可能侧翻，我才意识到视线内的毫厘之差对于轮椅意味着什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野接着解释刚刚走过的盲道分类：盲道砖是分两类，条形状的是引导砖，引导盲人安全放心前行的，这种称为行进盲道砖；另外一种就是圆点状的提示砖，用于提示盲人前面有障碍，应该进行转弯了，这种称为提示盲道砖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我以前什么都不懂，”田野笑了笑，开始回忆“懂”的节点，那是一场意外车祸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wQfffxl6KOaODmI8pg8ZKFKJx3CfUGGQw8fThb3J.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wQfffxl6KOaODmI8pg8ZKFKJx3CfUGGQw8fThb3J.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256502&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;田野的串串店成了“伤友”的相聚之地&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（网商银行公益小店联盟提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;给所有人看的戏&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;灰白色的桑塔纳穿过，车牌号留在田野心底，直到多年后他依然能脱口而出。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;车子尚未驶过之前，田野的人生是“动”的。他出生于1987年，祖祖辈辈在西安大雁塔附近生活。田野从小调皮好动，喜欢看武侠片。李连杰主演的《黄飞鸿》里“狮王争霸”的名场面给他留下深刻印象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，他去了武校，从13岁到15岁，整整两年，练习武术。年少时喜欢滑旱冰，他总是滑得最好最快的那一个。当时流行一种叫“开火车”的游戏，一群人前后拽着向前滑，时而直，时而斜，变换着队形，开在第一个的人被称作“火车头”，“火车快不快，全靠头来带”，田野总是扮演火车头的角色。有武校的底子在身，他的速度与平衡感、力量感都很出挑，“像秋天的叶子在空中飘落”，侧空翻、劈叉不在话下，拉火车能拉一百多人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再后来，不念书、不学武了，田野开过推土机，修过车。在工地，除了塔吊，别的能见到的“车”，他都开过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样的速度停在17岁那年。 2004年，田野遭遇车祸。捡回一条命后，他住了21天ICU（重症监护治疗病房），不知道花了多少钱，接着又在床上躺了8个月，瘦成皮包骨，那是人生中最痛苦的一段时间。田野回忆，当时他1米7多的身高，体重只有七八十斤，身上肋骨根根分明，看得真切。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来的10年里，父母带着他四处求医问药，去过专科医院，也找过江湖郎中。偏方、秘方不知试了多少，钱花了，苦吃了，人却没能站起来。 “凯子（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当地方言，意为&#39;傻子&#39;&lt;/span>;）上当，当当不一样，”田野感慨当时一家人的状态，不愿意接受事实，总觉得还能站起来，应该能站起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现实中寻不到出口，田野把一个梦记在心里。梦里他进了一座庙，很多和尚正在打坐敲木鱼，他跪在佛像面前。大雄宝殿突然门开了，伴随一道金光，一个老和尚进来，他对着田野说，“你本应该下地狱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野不解，哭着问，“我这么善良，没做过什么天大的坏事，为什么我要下地狱，为什么我要坐轮椅？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和尚回，“坐轮椅已经很不错了，你本来要下地狱的。”和尚在空中画了一个圈，像是个电视，田野在里面看到自己是一个王子，在战乱厮杀中跑进一座寺庙，拿木棍把一尊菩萨像的头打了下来。看完后，田野在梦里嚎啕大哭，醒来继续哭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哭过之后，尽管梦境虚幻，田野却好像从现实之外找到了某种安慰的理由。他不再困惑，不再觉得被命运针对。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;聊到转变的节点，田野沉吟了一会，说到“使命”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你的使命是什么？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我在演一场戏，观众是所有人。过去我是个特别调皮的孩子，意外出了车祸，周围的一些人说那就是报应，或者说是因果，因为我以前太调皮了，别人会用我来教育自家孩子。一开始我觉得反感，后来我是开心的，我的遭遇成了家长教育孩子的反面教材——&#39;不要学田野&#39;。就从这里，我慢慢找到了自己人生的方向，便不再寂寞。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野决定开一家串串店。最早开在小区里，2013年5月，从8个蜂窝煤炉、一把伞、几条板凳，到六七十个炉子、搭了棚子，再到活动板房，“变得有模有样”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HhSWrv4fr2rlVImIZRyMe3AFC0sx4JLiDOIl0a8O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HhSWrv4fr2rlVImIZRyMe3AFC0sx4JLiDOIl0a8O.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256499&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2021年夏，田野和“伤友”们在西安曲江南湖体验无障碍设施&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年6月，小店搬到离家1公里左右的铺面，“那是生意最好的时候”。 120平方米的店面，每天能开百来桌，人多到坐不下。半年后，店面再次扩大，田野换租到隔壁300平米的店铺。刚搬完的当月中旬，西安出现新冠肺炎病例，2021年11月，田野的串串店刚开张就迎来闭店。 2022年整一年，小店关门180天，亏损几十万。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了2023年，田野以为疫情没了、政策放开了，一切会变好，但生意却变淡了。我们见面的9月中旬，店面正在装修，田野想用新的面貌来迎回曾经的红火。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“新店要不要装无障碍卫生间？”在田野的另一家米线店，我看着他问。这家米线店可能开不下去了，田野想缓解一点财务压力，以后有余力再做。米线店的房租支出一年在9万元左右，生意并不好，他分析是因为地段不好。我们在店门口聊天的时候，小雨时不时落下，这家店夹在写字楼的背面，附近还有几家快餐店，生意都不算好，雨天的街上行人稀少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，考虑过装无障碍卫生间，但还是不现实。好在方便的是，串串店附近一百米左右就有公共卫生间，那里有无障碍设施，方便“伤友”解决如厕问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开店以来，身障人士来田野的串串店消费，一律打八五折。 2021年5月，网商银行公益小店联盟成立，田野的串串店加入，在网商银行的支持下，推出残障人士半价吃串的套餐活动。王烨是这个公益小店项目的发起人，她介绍平台的主要用户是小店主。在做这个公益项目的时候，她想知道“店主们”都是什么人。当时正处在疫情期间，王烨最先接触到一家西安饺子馆的店主，一些人来西安找工作没找到、钱花完了，老板在门口贴了张纸，大意是“有困难没什么大不了，进来吃碗饺子，不要钱”。公益小店项目给了饺子店主1万元扶持金。 “怎么会有这么真诚的人，他明明就很难。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来王烨发现了田野的串串店，同样给了1万元扶持金，“伤友五折吃串”的活动上线。王烨的工作任务是在全国找到1000家这样的店，“1000是我们的上限。我们不找一开始就下决心做公益的，那样很难坚持下去的，我们就找那种本来就在正常经营的。”接触过很多家这样的公益小店后，王烨感慨公益不是靠感性的冲动，需要有目标感，需要有价值观在心里，不能是一时的热血，一定是一直的信念，“我知道我在干嘛。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HRxm6HYZRBJQrPvguHMPfH6yDPutZ5LttZbHWl4j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/HRxm6HYZRBJQrPvguHMPfH6yDPutZ5LttZbHWl4j.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256497&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;微电影拍摄期间，导演王烨（左一）和伤友一起体验轮椅出行&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（网商银行公益小店联盟提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;交给时间去呈现&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;除串串店外，田野和伤友们的公益“版图”还在于绘制一张无障碍地图。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年8月，田野与结识的6名残障人士自筹资金共同成立“SCI无翼飞翔”公益中心。 “没有翅膀，也想飞行”是他们成立“无翼飞翔”的初衷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无翼飞翔”成立后，田野与伤友们用3个月的时间开展西安市三环内的道路无障碍环境调查，想法最初是“伤友”黄远提出来的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄远，今年52岁，2011年7月遭遇车祸，胸部第9根到第12根肋骨受伤，此后需要借助轮椅出行。在轮椅上，他跑过半程马拉松。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈到和“伤友”一起出门，他觉得更加没有压力。最困难的可能是临时上厕所的问题，比如大小便没控制好，尤其是大便，要回到家中或者在无障碍厕所一点点清理自己，动辄一两个小时。 “伤友”之间一个眼神、一句话就完全懂，不需要解释，也能给予全部的理解，因为他们有“平等的身体”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;身体最严重的问题在于没有知觉，他的大腿在一次出门后肿成了原先的3倍，直到那时才发现受伤。右腿伤疤，是2022年5月份留下的，至今还没好。他挽起裤管，凹凸不平的小腿上有深深浅浅的疤痕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;讲到出门，黄远总是笑意满满。 “伤友们”开着轮椅在路上观察，发现哪里的无障碍设施有问题就拍照传给黄远，汇集了上万张照片。黄远最终选择可用的5000张照片，制作成电子地图。这需要大量的幕后工作，比如GPS反向读出坐标，然后把照片对应到相应位置，用不同颜色的记号标注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份电子地图有不同图层加以区别：一是按照行政区域划分，二是按照原因分类，包括设计不规范、建设不到位和后期破坏与损耗三类。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以黄远的经验来看，设计方案大部分是到位的，因为有标准图，但在施工建设和监督验收的环节，有时会出问题，出现“样子货”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过3个月的调研，黄远编写了《西安市无障碍设施状况调查报告》，制作出一份特殊的西安无障碍问题分布的电子地图，清晰标注了每一个存在无障碍问题的地点、图片展示、原因类别等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调查结果以电子邮件方式递送到相关路政部门，其中一些问题得到了整改。这份地图和报告依然在黄远的电脑中保留着，尽管“公益中心”目前已经因为资金不足无力维系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;完整的调查并不是一开始就有的，最初是零星的“爱心贴”。刘思芳顺手从茶几下拿出一沓，粉红色的便利贴上印有“我是残障人士，您的车辆挡住了无障碍通道”的话语，他的轮椅背包里也有一摞，出门随身带。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘思芳今年60岁，50岁那年血管发病，颈动脉漏了，医生告诉他，患这种罕见病的人，世界范围内的记录不超过50例。 2014年，他在西安医学院做了手术，此后的生活离不开拐杖和轮椅。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘思芳家里养了几只鹦鹉，在房间里飞来飞去，一会儿落在肩上、一会儿落在头上，平添几分生气。他给这些鸟都起了名字，在家也算多个了乐趣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈到制作爱心贴和做无障碍通道地图，刘思芳提到，“是给出门找一个理由。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原先是零零星星的爱心贴，后来伤友们想，“算了，自己跑吧，做个整体的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“验收的人也不是残疾人，”谈到使用无障碍设施遇到的问题，刘思芳更多选择了理解：会碰到不合规的“斜坡问题”，还有一些把无障碍通道做成石子路的，也许是为了美观，但小轮轮椅走不成，得是大轮轮椅，限制了一部分轮椅的出行……这样的细节只有坐在轮椅上才能有真正的认知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加速度会上瘾，为了让更多“伤友”出门，也为了鼓舞自我，3个月、4辆轮椅、每天15小时，小店“伤友”们在西安走出了一张597平方公里的无障碍地图，3种颜色、上千个标记，布满西安三环内所有主干道。 “伤友”们被称为“轮椅竞速小王子”，他们经常约在西安城郊，坐在轮椅上开展竞速赛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出门是困境，也是诱惑。田野去过最远的地方是三亚，那是在五六年前。面对大海，头上是阳光，脚下是沙滩，喝着冰镇西瓜汁，戴着墨镜，他仿佛置身于一个新世界。那是春节时分，远在千里之外的家乡西安正是隆冬，风照刮、雪照下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他并不擅长表达，海浪的声音怎么形容呢？谈到那种遥远，田野的目光拉长，变得越来越远，穿过面前的墙壁，淡淡的笑容浮现在脸上，他好像又听见了，那“像西安的春天”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“等一个帮助你的人出现”是出门可能需要的好运气。就在我们访谈的前几天，西安下了一场大雨。店里有事必须去对接一下，田野开着电动轮椅出门，一不小心栽倒在路边水坑，因为雨太大把坑盖住了没留意到。妈妈看他半天没过去，沿路回来找，才发现儿子人跪在地上，半个身子泡在水里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雨天行人不多，有位女士想帮忙扶，但力气不够，后来又来了一位男士，几人合力才把田野救出。等待足足花了半小时，“也有经过但没帮忙的人”，田野在最后淡淡补了一句。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出门会听到反对的声音，“残疾人啥都干不了，就在家里别出来了。出门干嘛，尽给社会添乱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;田野对这样的话感到愤怒，“一个正常的社会应该是一个包容的社会，不但包容人，连马路上的小动物、花花草草也应该包容。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接触中，王烨感受到田野的乐观是带有悲凉底色的，“他不是没心没肺的、没有痛苦的，他会有很多沉思的时候，他遇到的困难都是经营上的，身体上的他已经习惯了。”在王烨眼中，田野是用心经营的一个店主，“我更愿意介绍他是一个用心努力的人，是一个店主，而不是先用残障人士去介绍他。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10年前，有了想写一本书的念头，田野坐在轮椅上，断断续续述说过往，他想写自己这一生。窗户在他背面，屋外是淅淅沥沥的雨声，屋内有些凉意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我没有想过开头和结尾，”田野回答我对于“一辈子”这本书的疑问，“也许人生毫无意义，但并不代表应该随便度过。我知道自己的剧本是什么样子，但还是会把它演完。”这本书，他想一步一步讲，用时间去呈现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黄仕忠：怀念郭在贻老师]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259816]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/VtJosBtrjhfwd8TDOJidGESphrBDcbzN0ZrDVbVt.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;464&quot; height=&quot;704&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/VtJosBtrjhfwd8TDOJidGESphrBDcbzN0ZrDVbVt.png&quot; data-key=&quot;256610&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;郭在贻（1939-1989）。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（郭宪玉供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭在贻老师从根底里是一个十分骄傲的人。在他去世三十多年后，我读到他在1977年11月21日写给哥哥郭连贻的长信，畅谈书法流派及当时知名书家，挥斥方遒，非胸中藏有百万兵，不得如此。而手迹所见书道造诣之深，令我骇然。因知其论，乃从胸臆中自然流出，在他，不过是与其兄长的平常谈论，因系私信，无须拘束，遂直言不讳，说得酣畅淋漓，而非欲故作惊人之语也。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/FfXSAW9J2JSE9FokIQ036gM9yZDexKcABY9Nb7wV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/FfXSAW9J2JSE9FokIQ036gM9yZDexKcABY9Nb7wV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256609&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;郭在贻致其兄郭连贻书。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1988年，郭老师与学生合作完成《敦煌变文集校议》初稿，他在给友人的信中写道：“此稿专谈我们自己的看法，自信不无发明，其中俗字和俗语词的考释方面，尤多独得之秘。”也是充满自信而非自夸。这样的语气，在他的书信和与友朋的话语中，都可以看到或听到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我与郭老师只曾偶接謦欬，他个子不高，眼睛不大，但炯炯有神，当他微眯着眼扫视而过时，有居高临下之势，令我不禁心生退缩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时他刚过不惑之年，身上仿佛凝聚着无限的能量，光芒四射，不能直视。尤其是汉语史领域，他是在姜亮夫、蒋礼鸿先生之后扛大旗的人。 1986年7月，经国务院学科评议组的批准，杭大中文系在姜亮夫先生之后，迎来了一批新的博导，他们是：沈文倬、蒋礼鸿、徐朔方、郭在贻。前三位都已年过六旬，郭老师才47岁，是当时人文社会科学领域最年轻的博导。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我读本科时（1978-1982），他给78、79级开过选修课，当时我没选，但我对他则是仰望已久。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时，77级的几位同学，受郭老师古代汉语课的影响，自发组成了一个兴趣小组，展开语词训诂研究。其中有一位叫边新灿，是我的同乡，且我俩同龄，所以交接略多。他说：“郭老师学识渊博，上课幽默，其中一句话对我触动很大：&#39;发现一个新的义项就像发现一颗行星。&#39;可谓照亮了我的心灵。”于是他一头扎进古书堆里，做卡片，抄语词，到四年级时（1981），就在《杭大学报》和《中国语文》发表了论文。那年他才21岁。他的毕业论文也是郭老师指导的。我读过他登在《杭大学报》上的论文，所释语词，证据确凿，令人信服，与蒋礼鸿先生《敦煌变文字义通释》的做法简直一模一样。他说，文章写成后，战战兢兢地呈递给蒋礼鸿先生，居然得到热心指导，并向《杭大学报》作了推荐；《中国语文》的文章则是他自行投稿而录用的。那时很多老师都苦于写不出论文而不能升等，所以这事给我印象极深。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兴趣小组中的王依民、张涌泉、计伟强诸位，也都于大学时或毕业初就在颇有影响力的专业刊物上发表了论文。依民说，他在《中国语文》的目录上看到自己的名字与杭大老师倪宝元先生排列在一起，让他小有激动。而涌泉在毕业两年后重新考回杭大，跟随郭老师读研究生，在敦煌俗语词研究领域开辟了新天地。这背后，都能看到郭在贻老师的身影。他们只是本科生，经郭老师的点拨，就有这么出色的成绩，让当时还是学生的我十分崇拜，并无限想象于他本人的厉害。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我本科毕业应届考上了本校古代文学研究生，这是1982年秋天的事。郭在贻、祝鸿熹等老师则招了六名古代汉语研究生，其中有方一新、陈白夜、金小春、郭小武、王云路和叶青。男生寝室相邻，一新、白夜和我是本科同学，所以我经常去串门，听他们在议论，郭老师要求先标点通读《说文》段注。那时段注有影印本，紫色封皮，大开本，他们每人桌上都翻开着，十分庄重，也颇有炫耀的意思，因为“我们郭老师”认为这是入门的正道，郭老师自己就点读过三四回。这令我很是羡慕，也专门买回了一本，但在是否要跟着通读的问题上犹豫再三，最终放弃了，因为那时我在徐朔方师的指导下，正在做《史记》《汉书》的比勘，时间不够用。而第二学年我从《史》《汉》回到戏曲，系统地通读元明戏曲基础文献，其实也是受到了郭老师间接的影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭老师给他的研究生开了“楚辞解诂”课，我也选了课。这是我第一次走进他的课堂，大开眼界，也大呼过瘾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/nOgen87qOxr0PuPE2YstF401S5uyak71yRpmVexM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/nOgen87qOxr0PuPE2YstF401S5uyak71yRpmVexM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256607&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;年轻时的郭老师，充满着阳光。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（郭宪玉供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭老师是山东邹平人，口音很重，对我这个浙江人来说，有些字音颇难辨别。即便如此，他讲课却十分引人入胜。他先提出例词，列出异说，再摆出他的证据，一二三四，仿佛做小学生的竖式算术题那般，层次清晰，一目了然。其实训诂的例证选择极难，若不是对字词语义及其源流十分精熟，便无法找到精准的例词。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可惜我当时只觉得了解一些训诂学的“方法”就可以了，对郭老师的论文只是浅尝辄止，理解其实不够深入。郭老师是以自己多年的研究为基础，结合前人的成果，在课堂上作补充延伸和示范。核心的内容已经刊出，一篇是《楚辞解诂》，发表在《文史》（第6、14辑，1979、1982）上；另一篇是《唐代白话诗释词》，发表在《中国语文》1983年第6期上。 1984年，他凭借这两篇论文，获得了中国社会科学院首届青年语言学家奖二等奖（共有三人获奖，另外两位是北大中文系李家浩和蒋绍愚）。这个奖项是“文革”结束后，吕叔湘先生为表彰青年学者（限45周岁以下）捐资设立的，“首届”时未有一等奖，所以这就是最高奖了。两年后，他被批准为博导，据说徐复先生对他的研究极为赞赏，竭力推荐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭老师很多精辟的讲解，如今我大多遗忘，但他教导的一些“方法”，对我后来的学术研究起到了实在的效用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;例如郭老师介绍了连绵词的概念，多为双声叠韵，须重其音，有音声相近的不同写法，而不能拆成单个字来作解释。他又说有些是姜亮夫先生的发现。姜先生的成名作《屈原赋校注》，完成时才二十九岁（1929年初撰，1931年成书）。我翻看《楚辞》，有数十条词语都属连绵词,但当代学者的选注本，仍多是依旧注拆字作解。也就是说，仅凭“连绵词”作追索，就让年轻的姜亮夫有了诸多新见。他在清华国学院的毕业论文《诗骚联绵字考》是王国维指导的。王国维敏锐地把清儒的讨论列为专题，他自己只在一篇文章中点到了问题，就将这个题目交给了学生，学生顺此延展，就开拓出自己的领域。这让我看到掌握“学理”和“准则”的必要性，同时也知道了“家法”和“师承”的重要性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭老师在课堂上对楚辞中的难解之词，以及往日学者以为“无解”之词，作了精彩的解释。从王逸、朱熹、洪兴祖，到郭沫若等当代诸楚辞学名家，都在他精妙的“解诂”面前，露出某些弱点。他则站在这个领域的高台之上，指点江山。解诂之余，也会给我们讲一些花絮，语含得意。他说，凡是新出的楚辞注本，他都会买一本来，翻检一遍，大多是翻过就扔了，因为没有新见。同时，他会给某些注家写信示贺，表明你的书我已看过了，也是给个暗示：“你用郭沫若、文怀沙的，就特别注明；我的解说，却用而不讲，其实我是知道的！”说完这话，他紧闭嘴唇，微微侧头，翘起下巴，在我的脑海中留下了一个定格。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——我于是知道，一个学者被认可，需要一个资历的积累过程。这让我在日后能够平静面对同样的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭在贻老师，是当时青年学者中最璀璨夺目的一位。这也让我们十分好奇，他究竟是如何脱颖而出的呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据说，在“文革”中他是“逍遥派”，抱来资料室的《楚辞》有关书籍，一本一本地读。他的《楚辞解诂》，就是读了数百种有关资料之后写成的。其间之痴与迷，有一则自述的故事可以为证：有一次去买肉，排着长队，他捧着书本看得入了迷，待到清醒过来，发现天色已暗，市场早已散尽，只他一个人，站着那里看了半天书。但那个时候是“知识越多越反动”，读这些东西只有负面作用，所以人多笑话于他。而他的一位老同学，论才华或不在他之下，论“精明”则远过之，在“文革”中积极投入，一度叱咤风云，“文革”后则成“三种人”受检查，当他回到教学岗位时，郭在贻已在学界大放光芒。他才痛觉前非，重头开始。大家由此形成一个共识，学者应当远离“运动”。同时也隐约有传言，郭老师由于读书太用功，身体不很好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1985年夏天，我研究生毕业后留校任教，分配教工宿舍，与同学金小春共居一室。小春的毕业论文是郭老师指导的。在此后一年中，我从他这里，听到“我们郭老师”的不少故事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;先得说我有一件与郭老师有关的故事。这年秋冬时节，我和何春晖老师赴上海送本系教师晋升的评审材料，涉及吴熊和、蔡义江、郭在贻、倪宝元等老师。我负责送达文学方面的专家，春晖负责送达语言文字学的专家。她说见到华东师大的史存直先生，很热情，对杭大这几位老师，特别是郭老师评价甚高。这几位我尊敬的师长晋升职称，我曾获参与，颇觉“与有荣焉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小春在过年前结了婚，妻子是杭州人，家境甚好，他就搬去住新房，平时很少回来。但回来时, 总会与我分享“我们郭老师”的故事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1986年的春夏，因为职称晋升，郭老师改善了待遇，添置了一些新家具。他心情十分愉快，对小春摆弄他新购置的物件。小春与老师乃处于亦师亦友之间，有时故意与老师斗嘴。记得郭老师得意于他新买的双人沙发，小春便逗着说：我家的是三人沙发！郭老师一时语塞，说：“嘿，我不和你比。”就左看右看，自作欣赏，按捺不住内心的喜悦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;听着小春道说这类小故事，我们心中共同的感受，是一种说不出的辛酸。不过，幸好，这一切都将成为过去，老师的愿景，已经洒满了阳光！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这年秋天，我考入中山大学读博士；不久后小春也赴美做学术交流，我就很少听到郭老师的消息了。两年多后，1989年元月中旬，突然传来郭在贻老师去世的消息，我简直惊呆了！时也命乎？无以言之，只能默默祈祷，愿他在天国安好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年以后，我从张涌泉的文章中，得知郭老师最后的状况。就在B超检查显示为肝癌的那天下午，郭老师忍受着精神上的巨大痛苦，给学生写了一封遗书：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;涌泉、黄征：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;匆匆地告别了，万分惆怅。你们要努力完成我们的科研规划，争取把三本书出齐，以慰我在天之灵。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有件事拜托你们：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;请把我未收入《训诂丛稿》的文章搜集起来，编一个续集，过几年后争取出版（现在当然不可能），为的是赚点儿稿费，以贴补我的家属，我个人则无所求也。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;在贻&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;一九八八年十一月五日&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个多么骄傲的人啊，在那一刻，也不忘记他的“科研规划”；而为了家人，又只能卑微地说，希望能“赚点儿稿费，以贴补我的家属”，仍要声明：“我个人则无所求也。”读这“遗嘱”，怎不令人潸然泪下！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭老师强忍着病痛，跨入了一九八九年，但最终无力回天，于一月十日抛却人世。离他五十岁的生日，还差一天！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我后来又读到傅杰写的回忆：“在生命最后的日子里，在贻师的话越来越少——既是没有精神，也是因为忧郁。不止一次，他默然甚至是木然地躺着，失神的眼睛不看身边的我们，只看着天花板，突然就出声抽泣起来，让当时还年轻的我们张皇失措。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也是在确认病症那天，他对涌泉说：“情况不妙，我已作好了思想准备，只可怜他们孤儿寡母的……”但即使在去世前两天，他也还对涌泉说：“方以智的《通雅》是本好书，如果到了，给我也买上一本。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他是多么留恋这人世啊！因为他有太多的事情想做，近期就有“敦煌三书”的计划，正与弟子们一起实施，还有一双稚子尚在读中学，然而，羸弱的病躯已经无力支撑，他纵有万分的不甘，却也无可奈何，且无人可与诉说，才会“失神的眼睛只看着天花板”,“不止一次”“突然就出声抽泣起来”……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Tq1A69PfkBbm4SZNlJcFh0ld3eWP1r0BjZzfoS3i.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;652&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/02/Tq1A69PfkBbm4SZNlJcFh0ld3eWP1r0BjZzfoS3i.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256608&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;这张照片，或是最后的夏日所拍，眉头微皱，不无忧郁。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（郭宪玉供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭在贻老师离开人世，转眼已是三十多个年头，若是天假其年，今年也不过八十四岁，但那将为汉语史研究开拓出怎样的一片天地啊！他的同学后来厚积薄发，在学术上也做出了的成绩，如今身体健康。人生若能再度选择，人们将会如何择取？夏承焘对好友王季思说：“季思啊，学问靠长命不靠拼命。”可是，人生在世，无关受制于时代与社会，哪能真的由得自己选择呢？况且“文章憎命达”，纵是再骄傲的人，也敌不过命运的捉弄啊！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“无级别”5年后，国家消防救援指挥机构明确为副部级丨时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259954]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 23:06:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/VdVT8tlsJa7WV8VicSdrrscSPhiA2sNvy6pxV3HQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1126&quot; height=&quot;674&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/VdVT8tlsJa7WV8VicSdrrscSPhiA2sNvy6pxV3HQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256986&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年8月29日上午，国家消防救援局浙江机动队伍增编组建进驻仪式在桐庐举行。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;挂牌10个月后，国家消防救援局的“三定方案”终于公布。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月31日，中国机构编制网发布的编制规定明确，国家消防救援局是应急管理部管理的国家局，为副部级；领导格局为“一正四副”，设一名政治委员；共有275名行政编制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了应急管理部，2023年10月以来，中央编办密集公布了多个其它部委的职责机构编制调整信息，涉及工业和信息化部、生态环境部、国家卫健委、中国人民银行、中国社会科学院等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家消防救援局的“三定方案”受到关注的一个重要原因在于，整合之前的应急管理部消防救援局和应急管理部森林消防局，自2018年10月组建之后，就一直没有明确行政级别。这两个机构在2023年1月合并组建国家消防救援局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如此计算，中国的消防救援队伍的领导指挥机关在过去5年是处于“无级别”状态，直到此次被明确为副部级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;消防队伍管理体制和机构设置已几经变化。2018年10月，公安消防部队、武警森林部队退出现役，成建制划归应急管理部，组建国家综合性消防救援队伍。其中，公安消防部队管理机构改为应急管理部消防救援局，武警森林部队管理机构改为应急管理部森林消防局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一年后，2019年11月，中央编办印发通知，明确应急管理部消防救援局、森林消防局分别为消防救援队伍、森林消防队伍的领导指挥机关，但“暂不明确队伍行政级别”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通知还显示，自2018年8月22日起，有3年的“试行磨合期”；磨合期内，根据磨合情况及时规范领导职数配备等问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;磨合期满之后，2022年2月印发的《“十四五”国家应急体系规划》则进一步明确，要“将消防救援队伍和森林消防队伍整合为一支正规化、专业化、职业化的国家综合性消防救援队伍”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后又过了一年，2023年1月6日，由应急管理部消防救援局和森林消防局整合而成的国家消防救援局正式挂牌。而从国家消防救援局挂牌到明确行政级别，又过去了10个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家消防救援局“三定方案”明确，国家消防救援局设第一政治委员并由应急管理部主要负责同志兼任，国家消防救援局局长由应急管理部副部长兼任，国家消防救援局政治委员由应急管理部政治部主任兼任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前，人社部网站消息显示，应急管理部党委书记、部长王祥喜已兼任国家消防救援局第一政治委员，应急管理部党委委员琼色出任国家消防救援局局长，应急管理部党委委员徐平出任国家消防救援局政治委员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按照“三定方案”，还会在应急管理部应急指挥中心加挂国家消防救援局指挥中心的牌子，国家消防救援局指挥中心主任由应急管理部应急指挥中心副主任兼任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国家消防救援局“三定方案”公布的同时，&amp;nbsp;应急管理部的职能也作了相应调整。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;应急管理部消防救援局和森林消防局的职责、教育训练司承担的国家综合性消防救援队伍教育训练相关职责划转给国家消防救援局；应急管理部管理国家消防救援局，并增加拟订消防员退出安置计划并组织实施、指导地方建立健全应急联合指挥平台职责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，应急管理部按照下管一级原则，继续履行国家综合性消防救援队伍职务任免、调配、表彰、奖励、处分、烈士评定等有关工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;人事动向&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【民政部换帅，陆治原任民政部党组书记，唐登杰转任山西省委书记】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据新华社2023年10月28日报道，日前，中共中央决定：唐登杰任山西省委书记。此番履新前，唐登杰担任民政部党组书记、部长。山西省委书记一职此前由蓝佛安担任，他已接替刘昆出任财政部部长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唐登杰履新后，陆治原已任民政部党组书记。陆治原曾在陕西省内工作多年，担任过榆林市委副书记、市长，渭南市委书记等职，2018年1月升任陕西省副省长，2018年9月跨省改任辽宁省委常委、组织部部长。2021年9月，陆治原调任山东省委常委、青岛市委书记，后任山东省委副书记、青岛市委书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【国家发改委主任郑栅洁添新职】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月1日求是网消息显示，2023年第21期《求是》发表郑栅洁署名文章——《深耕细作久久为功扎实推进共建“一带一路”高质量发展》，文章结尾作者介绍显示，国家发展改革委主任郑栅洁，已任推进“一带一路”建设工作领导小组办公室主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【奥运冠军陈若琳拟调配体总游泳运动管理中心工作】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，国家体育总局人事司发布公示称，根据工作需要，拟从京外调配陈若琳到游泳运动管理中心工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈若琳，女，1992年12月出生，大学本科学历，现任南京体育学院游泳学院教练员。陈若琳2000年进入江苏省跳水队，2005年入选国家跳水队，曾获2008年北京奥运会女子单人、双人10米台冠军，2012年伦敦奥运会女子单人、双人10米台冠军，2016年里约奥运会女子双人10米台冠军。她也是全红婵的教练。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【最高法：刘少云为中华人民共和国一级大法官】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月28日，最高法发布公告显示，根据《中华人民共和国法官法》等有关规定，刘少云为中华人民共和国一级大法官。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;反腐纪事&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【2023年1至9月全国共处分40.5万人】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据中央纪委国家监委网站10月29日消息，2023年1至9月，全国纪检监察机关共接收信访举报261.7万件次，其中检举控告类信访举报81.9万件次。处置问题线索128.3万件，其中谈话函询26.6万件。立案47万件，其中立案中管干部54人、厅局级干部2480人、县处级干部2万人、乡科级干部6.5万人；立案现任或原任村党支部书记、村委会主任4.6万人。处分40.5万人，其中党纪处分33.1万人、政务处分10.8万人；处分省部级干部34人，厅局级干部2244人，县处级干部1.6万人，乡科级干部5.4万人，一般干部5.6万人，农村、企业等其他人员27.7万人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【退休后仍不收手，国家烟草专卖局原副局长何泽华被提起公诉】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据“检察日报正义网”微信公众号消息，国家烟草专卖局原副局长何泽华涉嫌受贿、利用影响力受贿案，由国家监察委员会调查终结，经最高人民检察院指定，由辽宁省大连市人民检察院审查起诉。近日，大连市人民检察院已向大连市中级人民法院提起公诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何泽华曾是凌成兴的副手。2013年5月，凌成兴任国家烟草专卖局党组书记、局长时，何泽华已任国家烟草专卖局党组成员、副局长近10年。2023年10月23日，中央纪委国家监委网站发布通报，国家烟草专卖局原党组书记、局长凌成兴涉嫌严重违纪违法，正接受中央纪委国家监委纪律审查和监察调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【湖南整治领导干部子女相互请托办事】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，湖南省纪委监委召开全省领导干部利用职权或影响力为亲友牟利专项整治工作推进会。会议强调，要在监督重点上再拓展，既要聚焦原来已经确定的违规经商办企业、“打牌子”“提篮子”等3类21项重点内容，又要紧盯领导干部子女相互请托办事6种典型表现，强化教育管理监督，坚决刹住歪风邪气。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;湖南方面资料显示，湖南省政协原副主席易鹏飞等案件暴露出了领导干部子女相互请托办事等问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【受贿近五千万元，临沂市委政法委原书记王行华获刑13年】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月31日，日照市中级人民法院一审公开宣判临沂市委原常委、政法委原书记王行华受贿一案，对被告人王行华以受贿罪判处有期徒刑十三年，并处罚金人民币四百万元；对王行华受贿所得财物依法没收，上缴国库。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;部委信息&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【国家卫健委：推动在中职、高职专科等增设婴幼儿托育服务专业】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月1日，国家卫生健康委办公厅主任王斌在新闻发布会上介绍，将推动在中职、高职专科、高职本科增设婴幼儿托育服务专业，促进医疗机构支持托育服务发展，逐步完善托育服务的政策法规、标准规范和服务供给，进一步推进人口政策不断优化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【文旅部：暂停、解除部分国家级非遗代表性项目保护单位资格】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据央视新闻报道，近日，经保护单位自查、各地检查评估并征求项目传承人群意见、文化和旅游部审核等程序，有2981家保护单位评估合格；1家保护单位评估不合格，暂停国家非物质文化遗产保护资金申报资格，限期进行整改；3家保护单位履职尽责不力，解除其保护单位资格，重新认定保护单位；619家保护单位存在单位性质、机构等方面重大变化，不具备保护单位基本条件等情况，重新认定保护单位；认定3家此前空缺的保护单位；12个申报地区或单位不予认定保护单位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;法治播报&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【2017年以来共办理文物违法案件4200余起】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月30日，最高检、国家文物局在联合举行的新闻发布会上表示，2017年以来，全国共办理文物违法案件4200余起，行政追责650余人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【“外嫁女”征地补偿安置标准不统一，检察机关制发检察建议】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对“外嫁女”征地补偿过程中存在安置标准不统一等问题，检察机关制发检察建议，推动行政机关制定统一补偿标准。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最高检表示，“外嫁女”应否予以补偿安置，以及补偿安置标准是否一致，事关妇女群众切身利益。在土地征收补偿安置中，农村集体组织单独登记立户的“外嫁女”，应当平等享有安置补偿权利，以单独一户按照统一标准进行补偿安置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【羁押902天被判无罪，湖北前首富兰世立获国家赔偿59万元】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月24日，兰世立收到广州市检察院作出的《刑事赔偿决定书》。&amp;nbsp;2021年12月17日，广州中院经审理认为指控兰世立的罪名不能成立，判决兰世立无罪。三天后，兰世立被释放。《刑事赔偿决定书》认定，兰世立被羁押限制人身自由共902天，应获得国家赔偿59万余元。&lt;br>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;公开报道显示，兰世立，1960年出生，湖北武汉人，曾于2005年凭超过20亿元身家登上福布斯富豪榜，成为“湖北首富”，他也是东星集团及东星航空创始人。2008年，全球金融危机爆发，东星航空亦受波及并最终走向破产，兰世立陷入诉讼。2010年，兰世立因逃避追缴所欠税款被判处有期徒刑4年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;科教动态&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【杭州市教育局：将开展校内文体活动自甘风险研讨】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据杭州市委、杭州市政府网站11月1日消息，杭州市教育局近期答复杭州市十二届政协二次会议第146号建议关于“从法院判决上保证学校敢于落实体育教育”“多重保障防止家长过度追责”等内容称，将开展关于校内文体活动中自甘风险的研讨，同时坚持自愿原则，倡导家长购买学生（幼儿）综合保险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【广东省教育厅：严禁“萝卜刀”等有害玩具进校园】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近期，一款名为“萝卜刀”的新型玩具在中小学生（幼儿）群体中走红。近日，广东省教育厅发出《关于加强有害玩具教育管理的通知》（简称《通知》），要求各中小学校、幼儿园要严禁此类危险性有害玩具进入校园。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【网传韦东奕被解雇，北大辟谣】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，有关北京大学助理教授韦东奕被解雇的信息在网上流传。11月1日，中新网就上述信息向韦东奕所在的北京大学数学科学学院求证，该学院综合处工作人员表示，目前韦东奕仍在职。该学院宣传处工作人员说，“没有收到有什么变化的消息。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，北京大学数学科学学院数学系官网上，“全体教员”一栏中仍挂有韦东奕的简历信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;地方政情&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【新疆自贸试验区挂牌成立】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月1日，中国第二十二个自贸试验区——新疆自贸试验区挂牌成立，成为中国在西北沿边地区设立的首个自贸试验区。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【昆明：取消商品房限售限购】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;“昆明发布”消息显示，11月2日，昆明市政府官网发布《昆明市人民政府办公室关于废止一批房地产政策文件的通知》，决定废止2017年、2018年出台的相关房地产政策，意味着昔日发布的商品房限售限购政策全部取消。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【长春三孩育儿补贴方案落地：要求本地户籍，一次性补贴1万元】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据长春市政府网站近日公布的消息，夫妻合法生育三孩及以上家庭每孩将一次性补贴1万元。条件是：夫妻双方均为长春市户籍（含夫妻一方为长春市户籍，另一方为现役军人，或夫妻双方均为现役军人），在本方案印发之日（即10月25日）起，合法生育三孩及以上子女并落户本市的家庭，且已办理生育登记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;声音&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【&amp;nbsp;楼阳生：今日之河南，比以往任何时候都重视创新，比以往任何时候都渴求人才】&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月27日，在第六届中国·河南招才引智创新发展大会和第三届中国·河南开放创新暨跨国技术转移大会开幕式上，河南省委书记楼阳生致辞表示：“河南是中华民族和华夏文明的重要发祥地，自古以来人杰地灵、人才辈出，发明创造熠熠生辉，尊才爱才蔚然成风。” “今日之河南，比以往任何时候都重视创新，比以往任何时候都渴求人才。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（综合自新华社、央视新闻、上观新闻、中央纪委国家监委网站、“昆明发布”微信公众号、央广网、中新网、广州日报客户端、澎湃新闻等）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃货文人”梁实秋丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259949]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 22:31:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“男性没有情绪价值需要”是偏见：互相取暖才能行稳致远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259842]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在一个人能向另一个人提供的诸多价值中，情绪价值是最能体现“互动性”的一种。如果两人交往，失去了关于情绪价值的“礼尚往来”，而使得情绪价值只成为一方的供应物，那一定说明这两个人之间的权力与地位不对等，居下位者才需要向居上位者不断提供情绪价值，所谓“伏低做小”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而两性关系总体上应该是一个对等的关系，互相尊重对方、取悦对方才是正常的关系。在这个意义上，男人对于情绪价值的需要常常被忽视，这是一个不能回避的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位博主说，男人其实也是非常需要情绪价值的，他提到一个典型的例子：一个互联网老男人在微博诉苦，讲自己的中年危机，自己情绪崩溃的一瞬间。这个互联网老男人平时是以“妇女之友”形象出现的，所以积累了一定量的女性粉丝。结果当他开始诉苦的时候，并没有获得自己女性粉丝的同情和安慰，哪怕平时他一直给他的女性粉丝提供情绪价值。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;博主感慨道：某些女性好像是真心认为，男人一定非常幸福，不应该吐槽和抱怨。而她们自己则无时无刻不在抱怨，哪怕很多时候她们在外人看来非常幸福，但总能找到点抱怨。这些女性似乎有一种集体意识，“千万不能让男人感受到快乐，千万不能让男人获得情绪价值。至于为什么，我也理解不了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这话于我心有戚戚焉。当然，夫妻相敬如宾或互相取悦的例子，总能举上不少。不过根据我观察，男性总是更容易在向女性获取情绪价值的过程中遭到挫折。《围城》里方鸿渐在自己的妻子那里所遇见的，就是这种挫败感。没结婚时，两个人关系还行，孙柔嘉给了逆境中的他一种特别的心理满足。但婚后孙柔嘉便似变了一个人，让读者都感觉有点不可思议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;博主认为，男人跟女人搞对象，并不全是为了性。若有女性天天把情绪价值挂在嘴边玩极限压榨，但凡有点自尊的男人最终都会离开——譬如方鸿渐便有过此意。当然，离开的方式是各异的，很多男人发现，“女人给不了的情绪价值，兄弟们能给，游戏能给，甚至钓鱼都能给”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这话很“直男”，不仅很好地解释了我家门前河边成天成夜总有许多“钓鱼佬”聚集的原因，也很好地说明了一些中年男人在下班回家前总要打一番游戏或者在楼下静静待一会才入家门的道理：他们知道，家门内，有无休止的抱怨、无休止的精神损耗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之所以如此，正如博主所言：过去很多年，男人对情绪价值的需求被压抑住了。以至于很多女人以为男人只需要付出就可以了。而之所以这种畸形关系还能勉强维持，是因为一种叫“责任感”的思想钢印束缚住了男人——不管是对社会还是对家庭的。传统思想和价值观告诉男人，你必须结这个婚生这个娃。并且应该为此而忍受被吸取任何价值包括快乐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这话想必击中了很多在婚姻中感受不到快乐的男人的心。很多女士动不动说结婚得找一个“情绪稳定”的，为什么呢？这么选择的主要原因恐怕不仅仅是为了淘汰掉那些情绪不稳定喜欢发怒的男人，而是在更深层也更实用的情景中让“情绪稳定”的男人为家庭任劳任怨、将忍受作为最高追求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;问题是，生而为人，谁比谁更应该情绪稳定？这摆明了是一个伪命题。情绪稳定与否总是相对的，没有人生下来就是一个“情绪稳定”者，绝无不稳定之时——这样的人如果存在，那一定是塑料和钢铁做的。值得注意的是，当这种要求成为一种当然的时候，也就必然导致不公平情境的出现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;结婚为了什么？恐怕各人有各人的想法，但总体上，不外乎这几点：继续书写爱情、得到稳定的性、养育后代。提及婚后的责任承担，绝大多数情况下，男人往往成为家庭主要甚至唯一的收入来源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;傅首尔和老刘的婚姻波折，充分说明情绪价值是受到家庭经济关系影响的。一个男人一旦在家带孩子，结果往往不乐观。因为社会对于全职太太和全职丈夫的宽容度是不一样的，男人要想保持尊严，不受歧视，也不受窝囊气，就只能尽力多挣钱——最好挣得比妻子多。毕竟一个打流混世的男人比一个只在家带娃的女人，更容易被舆论轻看，甚至被视为“吃软饭的废物”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;按理说，在男主外模式下，男人在家庭获得情绪价值的希望很大。但有意思的是，理论上的内涵在现实中经常被打破。一些男人在外累死累活，回到家还得被说：就知道打游戏、就不知道干家务。有时还被贴上“丧偶式育儿”标签。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓的情绪价值说到底就是“哄劝”，女人心酸了，男的给哄哄，反过来也应该一样。如果男人总是被强行赋予“坚强”“刚硬”的人设，被打造为与情绪价值绝缘的角色，而在更广阔的范围内一味付出；或者说，男的必须照顾女的情绪，反过来就不行，甚至男的有了心事只能靠自己解决，那么这种关系就变味了，也失去了患难与共的情感基础。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;男人难道就没有情感需求，或者说就不应该寻求情感帮助吗？当然不是这样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在情绪价值问题上，男人和女人应该是对等的。承认男人和女人一样都有情绪价值需求，给予尊重和呵护，这才是正常的相处方式。基于此，互相关心，互相排解，这才是平衡之道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个家庭，绝不能成为一方享有绝对权力、另一方只能委曲求全的泥潭。没人会愿意嫁一个或娶一个“奴隶主”给供着，因而无论男女都希望自己的权利和精神得到另一方的尊重，而拒绝跪舔和无休止的单方付出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当下结婚率暴跌、离婚率上升、不婚族增多，在一定程度上说明年轻人对“家”的内涵予以更为理性、更为严格的审视，从而主动让自己的身心逃离一份无形的枷锁。这个冷峻的事实告诉我们，婚姻和家庭是两个人用爱意、诚意共同经营的“非物质”主体。要想让婚姻和家庭长久，要想大家对婚姻和家庭多一份信心，就必须公平看待双方的情感需求，营造一个有爱的对等关系，尤其是摒弃“男人没有情绪价值需求”的偏见，从而让彼此在最大程度上保持体谅和包容对方的自觉，互相取暖才能行稳致远。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[戛纳金棕榈获奖影片，一场对亲密关系的审判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259887]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcOZC4eqXITmA884bPF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;519&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/OCo1c2xv8Ztbs2c46cQ4nEcO ZC4eqXITmA884bPF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256876&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the movie, after the husband fell to his death from a building, the court began a trial to determine whether it was murder or suicide. , while also unveiling an analysis of family relationships. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(File picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a cabin under the French Alps, an interview is taking place. The female writer seems to be good at avoiding questions, and once turned into the guest and became the questioner. The young reporter sitting opposite her seemed a little overwhelmed and had no choice but to follow her wishes and start chatting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suddenly, the music played by the writer&#39;s husband came from upstairs, which was deafening, and his dissatisfaction was obvious. The interview was terminated and the female reporter left. Shortly after she left, the writer&#39;s husband was found dead in the snow outside the cabin by their son. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, who is the murderer? According to previous suspense narrative strategies, the plot always has to go through multiple reversals before the truth comes to light. The film &quot;Anatomy of a Death from a Fall&quot;, which just won the Palme d&#39;Or at the Cannes Film Festival in 2023, provides another solution. Director Justine Trier does not seem to care whether the plot is reversed, and it does not even matter who the murderer is. unimportant. Putting aside the cloak of suspense, Trier is more interested in how people use their own narratives to complete the analysis of a death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film cleverly sets up the court trial, so that the intimate relationships that should be in the private realm are laid bare and presented to the public. One party wants to prove murder, and the other wants to prove her innocence by proving that her husband committed suicide. Both parties are trying to use their own narratives to get closer to the truth, and all clues may become evidence in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a novelist, Sandler Voight&#39;s writing has become the object of scrutiny by the prosecution. &quot;Her life is in the book, especially her relationships.&quot; In the novel, the wife&#39;s disgust for her husband, the possibility of her husband&#39;s death, and the imagination of how to kill are all understood as reflections of the real motivations for killing. Under this kind of scrutiny, the narratives in the book are no longer complete. They are cut into fragments or even sentences, and then the narrative is reconstructed using human will to connect it with reality in the mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the key pieces of evidence in the film is the recording of her husband Samuel before his death. Samuel is a former teacher who also enjoys writing. Out of guilt for being partially responsible for his son Daniel&#39;s permanent vision impairment, Samuel spent a great deal of his time on various family matters and on Daniel&#39;s company. He seemed unapologetic and willing, but the recording revealed another side of the family&#39;s close relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the recording, Samuel asked his wife to reconsider the division of labor in the family, believing that he had sacrificed too much personal time on family affairs and that he wanted more time to write. After listening, Sandler mocked him coldly, saying that a writer would not stop writing just because he had children and housework. No one forced him, and he did not owe him anything. The director seemed to have intentionally reversed the genders. What Samuel experienced was actually the helpless and struggling situation of many women in married relationships in reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, the dispute between the two in the recording became more intense. Sandler&#39;s bisexual identity, cheating and other private information were revealed one by one from Samuel&#39;s mouth, and fell into the ears of everyone in the trial. In the view of the prosecution, these are the motives and reasons for the unbalanced relationship between husband and wife and the wife to murder her husband. Here, the recording, which originally only recorded a certain dimension of the relationship between people, is also used to refer to the whole picture, helping the prosecution complete the deduction and reconstruction of the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sandler attempted to deny this ever-reconstructed narrative, telling Samuel&#39;s psychiatrist, who was one of the witnesses, &quot;You&#39;re only telling a small part of the whole situation. A pair of Husband and wife are like a mess...&quot; She believed that this did not prove that she was the murderer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The paradox is that Sandler himself is also consciously or unconsciously self-narrating the truth, including her husband&#39;s unusual behavior in taking medicine six months before his death, seeing a psychiatrist, and being depressed in writing, etc. , all became her reconstruction of the reasons for his suicide during the defense process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if the evidence fragments presented by both the prosecution and the defense are real, perhaps no one dares to confirm that the suicide or homicide story reconstructed based on these fragments is the truth itself. As director Justine Trier said, &quot;This is very modern, this is how we live today. In the trial, various things change and are given extra weight, resulting in new fictions.&quot; &quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The evidence was not only presented in front of the prosecution and defense, but also slowly unfolded in front of his son Daniel, who also began to look at his parents again. At first, he had no doubts about his mother, but as the two sides narrated at the trial, his attitude gradually became swaying, and he even had an image in his mind of his mother hitting his father hard and pushing him downstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, he also tried to give medicine to the dog to verify the fact that his mother said that his father had vomited after taking medicine. He also recalled the conversation his father had with him when he sent the dog to the doctor. He thought This revealed his father&#39;s suicidal tendencies. From various swings to his own selection of factual fragments after review, Daniel finally constructed his own narrative version of the truth in his mind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/HSp4I05LqVgIERt0uszA4B1zVAGtWR6wapo1Ubgq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256875&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A still from &quot;Anatomy of Death from a Fall&quot; (also translated as &quot;Judgment of a Fall&quot;). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Justine Trier once mentioned in an interview, &quot;These trials have a profound impact on people.&quot; It&#39;s a nightmare to say because your own life is being taken away from you. Everyone is creating a fiction and not really trying to get to the truth. I&#39;m very fascinated by truth and trying to find it through stories and I find that very interesting .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, the director also wants to draw the audience into the search for the truth and the construction of the narrative. Under the shell of suspense, we as the audience have naturally been thinking about who the murderer is since Samuel fell from the building. In the battle between the prosecution and the defense, every time they list new evidence, make new statements and excuses, we, like Daniel, can&#39;t help but turn our eyes to Samuel and Sandler, trying to learn from the evidence provided by both sides. Find your own narrative from factual evidence and their narratives to deduce the truth of death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But outside the film, we are more passive. All narratives are always based on the characters&#39; interpretation of the truth in the film, which also means that our perception of the truth is more uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film ends with Sandler being found not guilty. Since there are elements of fiction on both sides, why does one narrative prevail over the other? Perhaps it was the emotional power of it - Daniel&#39;s monologue about his father moved the judge and helped his mother win. After Sandler came home, Daniel hugged and kissed her. In the silence of the room, a rare warmth lingered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is this the truth? Not really. In the previous narratives from all parties, the director has successfully planted the seeds of doubt in the hearts of the audience. Even if Sandler was found not guilty, people&#39;s hesitation and uncertainty about the truth have not disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sandra Wheeler, who plays the heroine, once asked the director about the script, whether her character was guilty or innocent. Trier told her, &quot;I don&#39;t know, but I hope You act as if she is innocent&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She could be responsible but not guilty, or she could be guilty but not responsible. She could be responsible for driving him to suicide but not guilty of killing him, or she could be guilty of killing him without wanting to. to kill him - either in an impulsive way or in a way that we can try to imagine. The truth is there, but it is too complex to grasp here.&quot; Director Justine Trier said in Said this in an interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But looking back, the truth may no longer be important. Fiction is a human talent. As long as you are willing, you can construct your own narrative with the help of a few keywords. However, if the relationships between people are like this death, being scrutinized and reconstructed, then in fact, no relationship can withstand such rigorous and detailed analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>