<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[我和物业博弈的这一年：解决问题有多难？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261740]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The fate that every new owner cannot escape is to deal with and confront the property. This is his homework and his of practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since I took over the house and became an owner in October last year, I have started to form a front with my neighbors and compete with the property management. Today, the team has collapsed, losing ground, and the rights protection has ended in failure. It&#39;s the same as the mental process of decorating, from being full of emotions to being discouraged, and finally giving up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the house was handed over for inspection, the quality of the house was worrying and many areas needed repairs. However, the developer did not do anything and delayed to solve most of the problems. Until now, the paint surface of the corner of my second bedroom is cracked. The seam is still there intact. This is indeed the developer&#39;s problem. The property management company can only help me communicate my needs, but they belong to the same company, and the property management company has collected property fees early. I have to discuss an explanation with the property management company. It is not unfair at all to take the blame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process of fighting with the property owners, each other&#39;s tactics also changed according to the other&#39;s actions, and they continued to see each other&#39;s progress and retreat. If the housekeeper responds politely and politely, I will also communicate politely. If I am tougher, she will get angry at me. More often than not, the housekeeper will use low-grade deception, but I can&#39;t expose her directly. I have to leave a little kindness so that we can meet each other in the future and everything can be discussed. She told lies and fully accepted my needs, saying that she would urge and reflect them, but my problems would not be advanced or solved. She treats me as a fool. If she can evade something, she will do it first. Later problems will be dealt with later. The rhetoric will always be dealt with in a unified manner later. In the end, he couldn&#39;t do anything perfunctorily and ran out of patience. The housekeeper simply stopped making excuses and played the emotional card. She admitted that the developers were rogue and the property management companies were rogue. She only received a salary of a few dollars a month, so how could she have the final say? Without pretending, I was moved by her words that were completely embarrassing, and I began to accept in my heart that this was the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before I paid the property fee, I had to ask the housekeeper to get the key when I opened the door of my house. The owner of the owner group once privately suggested that I replace the lock cylinder and argue with the property management company about when to solve the problem and when to pay. . I didn&#39;t want to take an extreme approach, and I was eager to get a property certificate to install charging piles, so I had no choice but to surrender. Once the money is handed over, it becomes even more difficult to ask them to do something. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on this year’s negotiations and observations, I found that one of the main job responsibilities of the property management company is to collect fees. As early as September, before the previous year&#39;s property fees were due, the housekeeper started a show of fancy reminders to pay the next year&#39;s property fees. Taking advantage of the fact that the owners were at home at night, the housekeepers divided their forces and went door to door to collect property fees. Everyone among the owners condemned this behavior of only enjoying rights without assuming obligations. A few days later, the property management company sent out a notice with bait, offering free rice and cooking oil if the property management fee was paid during this period. So, I often see the housekeeper walking in the community carrying grain and oil, and watching her retreating back, I wonder, if the execution of solving problems is so touching, why are we here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a year of fighting, my interest in fighting for the rights of my neighbors has slowly cooled down. Recently, there have been voices in the group that want to replace the property, but I no longer have such high expectations for the final result. Confrontation between property owners and property owners has become the norm. I am afraid that my property and I, as well as the domestic property management industry, still have a long, long way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is an employee of a state-owned enterprise in Hangzhou, Zhejiang)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to you Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[香港仔：太平山B面]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261712]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Take the green-painted Star Ferry from Tsim Sha Tsui. Rows of high-rise buildings slowly approach and zoom in. Behind them The Taiping Mountains are spread out like a belt, rising and falling gently in the porthole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original name of Taiping Mountain is Hard Head Mountain, also known as Xianglu Peak. It was renamed because after the surrender of the great thief Zhang Baozai during the Jiaqing period of the Qing Dynasty, the residents of Hong Kong Island thought that there would be peace from now on. In a broad sense, Taipingshan is composed of Mount Chechi, Lufeng Gorge, Gough Hill, Kwun Lung Kok and Mount Keli; in a narrow sense, it refers to Mount Chechi, the highest peak on Hong Kong Island with an altitude of 554 meters. There are two theories about what flag-pulling is: one is that Cheung Po-tsai raised the flag as a signal when he was a thief and commanded the people at the bottom of the mountain to rob merchant ships; the other is that in 1841, the British army occupied Hong Kong Island and raised the Union Jack here. Austin, who served as Colonial Secretary of Hong Kong from 1868 to 1878, named the mountain Mount Austin, and later renamed it Victoria Peak after the Queen of England (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;Victoria Peak&lt;/span>;) and is still used today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After living in Shenzhen for more than 20 years, I have traveled to Hong Kong many times and visited Victoria Peak. To be precise, it is the crowded places on the north bank of Victoria Peak such as Central, Admiralty, Causeway Bay, and The Peak. Among Hong Kong people, the Peak refers specifically to Victoria Peak, and there is no ambiguity. However, most tourists today mistake the cable car terminal and Lingxiao Pavilion area for the top of the mountain. In fact, it is called Lufeng Gorge. Even for me, it was a few months ago that I walked through the slightly deserted Austin Mountain Road and climbed to the top of the real mountain for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing on the observation deck on the top of the mountain, leaning on the railing and overlooking the sky, the north bank is surrounded by red dust and glitz; on the south bank, countless low hills seem to be eager to embrace the South China Sea... If the noise and commotion were the Taiping Mountains The A side of Taiping Mountain, then, silence and tranquility are the B side of Taiping Mountain. A green mountain magically captures a completely different contrast. Unfortunately, due to other arrangements, I had no time to get close to Nan&#39;an Fangze that day. This time, Aberdeen, Hong Kong, where I made a special trip, is located in the center of Side B of Victoria Peak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photography of Pang Mian looking at Aberdeen Deep Bay, Hong Kong&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c1ca8b8bac.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c1ca8b8bac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 260440&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Overlooking Aberdeen Deep Bay, Hong Kong&amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Looking for Hong Kong Village&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4 >; &lt;p>;At Admiralty, transfer to the MTR South Island Line. One stop will bring you to the famous Ocean Park in Hong Kong, and then take a short shuttle bus to the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel you booked. Speaking of which, I am no stranger to Fullerton. Many years ago, I stayed at the Fullerton Hotel in Singapore on a business trip. It was a neoclassical building completed in 1928. It is as legendary as the Peace Hotel in Shanghai. I still remember that the passage on the ground floor leads directly to the Merlion, the landmark of the Lion City. The Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel where I stayed this time is located in the geometric center of the south bank of Victoria Peak. When the bus turned around and got rid of the noisy city, the transparent windows were suddenly filled with green mountains and blue and white sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Aberdeen location map courtesy Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cd1f944deb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;734&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/cd1f944deb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260441 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Aberdeen location map&amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hotel faces the sea, on the left hand side, dozens of steps away, is 2021 The Ocean Park Water Park, Asia&#39;s first all-weather seaside water park, opened in 2016, has layers of recreational facilities that spread over the entire hillside like terraces. On the right, two breakwaters piled with rocks are as gray as scratches, collecting the treasures of the rich. &quot;Toys&quot; - yachts and sailing boats; and directly ahead, Ap Lei Chau, which looks like a duck swimming in water, has half its head and body buried in the sea, vividly dividing the sea area connecting Victoria Harbor and the South China Sea into There are two waterways, wide and narrow: within Ap Lei Chau, the narrower one is called Aberdeen Strait, which is used by small boats; outside, the wider one is called East Lamma Strait, which is used by large ships. Stop for a moment, and before your eyes, you can see the endless busyness of various ocean-going ships and the slow and leisurely pace of various yachts and sailing boats. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;View of Ap Lei Chau from The Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel. Photography by Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/dc6241d429.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/dc6241d429.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;260442&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Overlooking Ap Lei Chau from the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel. &amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The entrance to Aberdeen Country Park is on Nam Fung Road near Ocean Park. Like Hong Kong citizens, hiking in Aberdeen Country Park is one of my bucket list for this trip. Unexpectedly, after walking a few steps along Nanfeng Road, I encountered a small black and white road sign with an arrow pointing north to &quot;Wong Chuk Hang Stone Carvings 250m Meters&quot;. Soon, on the north side of the Jockey Club Science Building, behind a stack of easily overlooked cement steps and next to a rushing stream, I saw the Wong Chuk Hang rock carvings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a relic dating back about 3,500 years. A yellow mountain cliff stands on the right bank of the creek. Although it has been weathered and eroded, three groups of slightly blurred swirling patterns on the six or seven square meters of rock surface still look like the eyes of an animal staring at me as I &quot;break in&quot;. This reminds me of the similar Shang and Zhou bronzes &lt;span>;Taotie pattern&lt;/span>;. Taotie is a vicious and greedy monster in ancient Chinese mythology. &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; believes: &quot;Greed for money is gluttony, gluttony is gluttony.&quot; In modern times, with the rise of peace, its meaning has become a description of a foodie who is fond of delicious food. As for the Taotie pattern, it first appeared on the pottery and jade of the Liangzhu Culture in the lower reaches of the Yangtze River. Because the patterns often have heads but no bodies, they are also called &quot;animal face patterns.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perusing the on-site cultural relics plaque, I learned that there are nine ancient stone carvings in Hong Kong. Only two existing ones on the south coast of Hong Kong Island are Tai Long Bay and Wong Chuk Hang. Among them, the Tai Long Wan Stone Carvings were the first to be listed as a statutory monument (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1978&lt;/span>;), while the Wong Chuk Hang Stone Carvings are the only ones located inland. , stone carvings far away from the coast. So, why is the stone at this moment? According to my judgment, if the stream under my feet has flowed forever, this is probably the place where ancestors worshiped water sources and drew fresh water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where there is fresh water, there must be villages. When I turned back along the original road, I noticed that the stream took advantage of the grass and rocks to penetrate into the underground culvert of Nanfeng Road and disappeared without a trace. Fortunately, there is a blue sign reading &quot;Old Walled Village&quot; erected at the opposite intersection, eye-catchingly pointing to the Nanfeng Trail branching off from Nanfeng Road. &quot;Wei&quot; is a common name for villages in Lingnan in the past. It not only means &quot;gathering people here&quot;, but also has an &quot;image summary&quot; of the walls and houses built in the village. Jiuwei and Laowei are equivalent to the old villages and old villages in the north, and refer to the villages with the longest history in the area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The full name of Jiu Wai Village is Wong Chuk Hang Jiu Wai, because of the ravine with flowing water in the former village (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; span>;) is named after the broom-shaped yellow bamboos that grow all over the place. However, according to Ye Lingfeng&#39;s book &quot;Hong Kong Stories&quot;, Jiuwei Village was first called Hong Kong Village or Hong Kong Wai. It is recorded in ancient books such as &quot;Yue Da Ji·Guangdong Coastal Map&quot; by Wanli in the Ming Dynasty and &quot;Xin&#39;an County Chronicle&quot; by Kangxi in the Qing Dynasty. At that time, the production and sales of Wanxiang (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;referring to the agarwood produced in Dongguan, Shenzhen, Hong Kong and other areas today) were booming, and this area became prosperous. As the initial distribution center. As late as 1866, the &quot;Comprehensive Map of Xin&#39;an County&quot; printed in Leipzig, Germany still marked the name of the village &quot;Hong Kong Wai&quot;. The name of Hong Kong today &quot;was gradually popularized based on the name of this small village.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The south wind path is not long, and the old walled village is huddled on the steep slope at the end. The lower slope is filled with vehicles; the upper slope is incredibly covered with squatter houses made of iron sheets. Entering the village and walking around, except for a small Buddhist hall and a small mountain shrine that were dimly lit by incense, I didn&#39;t find any ancient meaning. I asked the grandmother who tended the vegetable garden and learned that many years ago, the Aberdeen Tunnel Toll Station and Wong Chuk Hang Hospital were built, and the old houses were demolished. While I was talking, suddenly, four or five big yellow dogs came close to me and barked at me. When I was young, my experience in fighting dogs in the countryside came in handy. I forced myself to stay calm and made steady progress. At this time, I saw a bamboo pavilion and a nest of slender bamboos at the entrance of the village, which perfectly echoed the name of the village in Wong Chuk Hang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The swimming pool of the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel faces the East Lamma Strait. Photo courtesy of Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/12/02/d712e53ef0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/ d712e53ef0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260443&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;The swimming pool of the Fullerton Ocean Park Hotel faces the East Lamma Strait. &amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Hiking in Aberdeen&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Returning to Nanfeng Road, after hiking for several miles, I plunged into the Aberdeen Country Park embrace. As you walk higher and farther, your body and mind rise and fall with the mountains, as if you are immersed in the fragrance of the forest and the occasional singing of birds. Aberdeen Country Park is one of the first country parks in Hong Kong. It was established in 1977 and covers an area of ​​about 423 hectares. It encompasses the Nip Ko Sun, Cameron Highlands, Ban Na and Tin Wan mountains from east to west. The hiking trails in between are connected with those elsewhere, and can reach the entire Hong Kong Island. At the end of the 19th century, the old houses in Jiuwei Village were still there, and the surrounding fields and grassy fields attracted visitors from Victoria City (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;today’s Central and Sheung Wan, Hong Kong High-ranking officials, wealthy businessmen, gentlemen and ladies from the area (&lt;/span>;) came in droves to spend time. The more people walking, the more roads there are in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climbing to the mountainside, a water diversion channel (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Aqueduct&lt;/span>;), which is more than 1 meter wide and deep, is clearly visible. Eyes, U-shaped bottom trickling gurgling. As we all know, fresh water in Hong Kong is poor, especially on Hong Kong Island. In order to alleviate the tension, in the 1960s, Guangdong Province successively built the Shenzhen Reservoir and the Dongjiang-Shenzhen Water Supply Project to provide support. The Hong Kong government excavated diversion channels and other facilities in the mountains to collect spring water and rainwater, and then directed them into reservoirs (&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That is, the reservoir&lt;/span>;). Today, aqueducts and reservoirs have become &quot;standard features&quot; in almost all country parks in Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/3ead0c739e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/3ead0c739e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260444&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Lady King&#39;s Horse Racing Trail offers a bird&#39;s eye view of the center of Aberdeen. &amp;nbsp; Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the water diversion channel turned around and rushed down the pit, at the feet, the road surface of Mrs. Jin’s Horse Racing Trail changed from gravel to loess. Mrs. King&#39;s Horse Racing Trail, also known as Mrs. Gold&#39;s Trail, is named after the wife of the 17th Hong Kong Governor Clementi Clementi. It is about 5 kilometers in length, and some sections overlap with the famous Hong Kong Island Trail. Mrs. King&#39;s name was Mary Ayers. She was born in 1889 and later moved to Hong Kong with her father, Admiral C.J. Ayers. In 1912, she married Clementi, who was 14 years older than her. The two were deeply in love as a couple and loved traveling and Chinese culture. Clementi was even promoted to Governor of Hong Kong in 1925 because of this. During his tenure, Clementi worked hard to eliminate the negative impact of the general strike in the province and Hong Kong on Hong Kong, improve relations with the mainland, and promote Chinese education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under his initiative, the University of Hong Kong established a Chinese Department in 1927 and invited a group of former Qing Dynasty officials to teach old classics. Unexpectedly, this move aroused verbal and written criticism from figures in the New Culture Movement such as Lu Xun and Hu Shi. What is right and what is wrong has changed with time. However, it is also an indisputable fact that the Department of Chinese Language and Literature of the University of Hong Kong set off a trend of attaching importance to Chinese education, and later emerged famous literary figures such as Zhang Ailing, Huang Zhan, and Lin Xi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to official duties, Clementi often accompanied his wife on horseback riding outings here to appreciate the mountains and seas of Aberdeen. Writer Liu Kexiang pointed out in &quot;Three Quarters of Hong Kong&quot; that in winter, there are six to seven hundred &quot;mountain eagles&quot; in the Aberdeen Country Park area. &lt;/span>;) favored urban green fields&quot;. Maybe I came a little early in the season and only saw a few flying birds. But the Clementi couple should have seen the scene of the eagle circling and covering the sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hiking in Nanlang Mountain, photo provided by Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/27c1665f22.jpg &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/27c1665f22.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot; 260445&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Hiking in Nanlang Mountain&amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Dan Family and Seafood Fang&lt;/strong>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;At this moment, at 4 o&#39;clock in the afternoon, I arrived at the Buchang Bay Pier and was immediately surrounded by ships on the sea and shipyards on the shore. At this time, the sun jumped down from Yuguishan, the main peak of Ap Lei Island on the opposite side, catching red, blue, green and white reflections to fight. In a daze, I was placed in the background of a certain Hong Kong movie, which was a bit outdated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bu Ching Bay is adjacent to Tai Shue Wan, where the Fullerton Hotel is located, to the south and Sham Wan to the north. Many online posts explain that Buchang Bay got its name from the many garment factories that used to be there. In fact, this is not the case. According to my on-site observation, &quot;cloth factory&quot; should be a homophonic corruption of &quot;bunchang&quot;. Yangjiang Pichang, the hometown of Guan Shanyue, the master of traditional Chinese painting, is a wharf close to the sea and wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photography of Pang Mian on a sampan swimming from Shenwan&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/ 474c20fddd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/474c20fddd.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;260446&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Sampans swimming from the other side of Shenwan&amp;nbsp;Photography by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shaoqing, the other side of Shenwan A small boat with a red hood swam up, with yellow flags on all sides, fluttering in the wind. After getting on the boat and sitting down, we found that the tent was full of decorations: red lanterns, artificial flowers and plants, and small &quot;ten thousand flags&quot; with the names of Hong Kong places. As soon as the boat started to sail, it swayed slightly. Grandma Zhu, who was driving the boat, said proudly: &quot;This sampan is the most beautiful one on the water in Aberdeen, Hong Kong.&quot; The most handsome among the people on the water in Aberdeen.&quot; The boat made a beautiful arc, the motor hummed, and headed in the direction it came from. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The people on the water are called &lt;span>;對&lt;/span>; in the mainland and are mainly distributed along the southeast coast. Historically, the Dan family had various names, such as Yaiyazi, Baishuilang, Danmin, 蜑, Zhi, Yaohu, etc. Until the Tang and Song Dynasties, they were collectively called &quot;獍&quot;. Liu Zongyuan&#39;s &quot;Lingnan Jiedushijuntang Ji&quot; of the Tang Dynasty is the earliest document in which &quot;獍&quot; appears. Regarding the views on the origin of the Dan family, scholar Chen Xujing has made statistics, and there are as many as thirty kinds. Among them, the most romantic ones: first, they are derived from the mermaids, or mermaids; second, they are the descendants of Fan Li and Xi Shi of the Yue Kingdom in the Spring and Autumn Period. The generally accepted view is that the Dan family are descendants of the Baiyue people who fled the country during the Qin Emperor and Han Dynasty&#39;s expedition to the southeast. The &quot;Lingwai Daida&quot; written by Zhou Qufei of the Southern Song Dynasty said: &quot;Those who use boats as houses, regard water as land, and float on rivers and seas are Dan&quot;; Yang Wanli&#39;s &quot;Poems of Dan Households&quot; says: &quot;God divides his life by water. , taught him to step on the waves since he was a child. When cooking crabs as food, you can recognize rice, and when you gather bananas for cloth, you don’t need gauze.&quot; Since the 1950s, Dan families from the mainland have come ashore to settle one after another, but there are still survivors in Hong Kong and Macao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Grandma Zhu did not agree with the views in the book. She told me that in the past, people and boats on the water were too small to raise pigs and cows, so we had to raise chickens, ducks and geese. People on the shore come to the beach to buy eggs. After a long time, they call the people on the water &quot;Dan (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Tongdan&lt;/span>;) home. &quot;If my mother were still alive and heard about the Dan family, she would curse people. It&#39;s so taboo.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo by Pang Mian, Granny Zhu, who has been driving a sampan all her life&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/d9bf2e440b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1439&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/12/02/d9bf2e440b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260447&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Grandma Zhu who has been driving sampans all her life&amp;nbsp; Photography Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1841, when the British army first came, Chen Qun, a Dan family member, was asked to lead the way. When passing through Hong Kong Village, when asked about the name of the place, Chen Qun, who had a Dan family accent, answered &quot;Kang Kong&quot;, so the British army recorded it as &quot;Hong Kong&quot;. Of course, this is just a legend. As far as I know, in 1793, when the British Macartney mission left China, relevant reports already mentioned &quot;HongKong&quot;: &quot;Lingding (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;Now Shenzhen&lt;/span>;) and Hong Kong are suitable for colonization.&quot; But no matter what, this legend also reflects the relationship between Hong Kong and the Dan family. As for the origin of Aberdeen, it is also related to this legend: after Hong Kong became the name of the entire island, in order to avoid confusion, the people changed the name to &quot;Aberdeen&quot;, that is, &quot;Little Hong Kong&quot;. Later, the British Hong Kong government changed the English name of Aberdeen from &quot;LittleHongKong&quot; to Aberdeen (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Aberdeen&lt;/span>;) to commemorate the George Hamilton-Gordon, the fourth Earl of Aberdeen and British Foreign Secretary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The boat entered the deep bay, revealing an empty water surface, with a huge neon sign reading &quot;Welcome&quot; coldly. A little far away, there is a dim painted boat - Taibai Seafood Boat - moored, like an aging lady reminiscing about her youth. &quot;The original location of Jumbo Seafood Restaurant,&quot; Grandma Zhu said, and the guests turned their heads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 1930, the Dan family from Guangzhou brought the &quot;Getang Chu&quot; to Aberdeen. This kind of floating restaurant that combines singing, dancing, entertainment and sightseeing, coupled with the famous local fresh seafood, quickly became popular. Even a number of cultural celebrities who visited Hong Kong from the south, such as Hu Shi and Cai Yuanpei, came here to enjoy the aroma, follow the smell, invite friends and company, and enjoy the food here. After entering the 1950s, there were more than ten upgraded versions of the &quot;Getang Chu&quot; seafood boats. In 1971, a fire broke out during the decoration of Jumbo Seafood Restaurant and was seriously damaged. When Macau gambling king Stanley Ho heard the news, the Dan family gene in his bones awakened (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;his great-grandmother was a Dan family&lt;/span>;), he formed a partnership with others and made huge investments It was bought and renovated for more than 30 million Hong Kong dollars. In 1976, the Zhenbao Seafood Restaurant, designed in the style of the Ming Dynasty palace and able to accommodate more than 2,300 people, opened. A few years later, Stanley Ho acquired his biggest competitors, Taibai Seafood Restaurant and Haijiao Palace. The world&#39;s largest restaurant at sea - Treasure Kingdom was born, becoming a feasting landmark in Hong Kong. At that time, when politicians and celebrities visited Hong Kong, they all came here to &quot;check in.&quot; Grandma Zhu, a young and vigorous woman, earns over 10,000 yuan a month by ferrying guests to and from people on a ferry boat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interestingly, the glorious era of the &quot;Treasure Kingdom&quot; was also the period when Hong Kong films were at their peak and most prosperous. From Bruce Lee to Jackie Chan, from &quot;Enter the Dragon&quot; to &quot;Infernal Affairs 2&quot;, this place has become a popular filming location for Hong Kong films. Especially in &quot;The God of Cookery&quot;, the scene where Stephen Chow flutters in white clothes, steps on the clear waves, and flies through a broken window has left a deep memory for star fans. By the way, the real shooting location of &quot;God of Cookery&quot; was at Taibai Seafood Restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1998, the Asian financial crisis severely damaged the &quot;Jewel Kingdom&quot;. Haijiao Palace first closed down and then moved to Qingdao. From then on, the &quot;Treasure Kingdom&quot; went from bad to worse. In 2022, the Jumbo Seafood Boat towed away from Hong Kong was swallowed up by wind and waves near the Paracel Islands in the South China Sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Photo courtesy of Pang Mian, Taibai Seafood Restaurant, the filming location of &quot;The God of Cookery&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02 /fc2b691b61.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/fc2b691b61.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;260448&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Taibai Seafood Restaurant, the filming location of &quot;The God of Cookery&quot;&amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Typhoon Shelter View Sunset&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Crossing the Ap Lei Chau Bridge, more and more water birds appeared, flapping their wings up and down to welcome us. Guests constantly stood on the bow of the boat to take selfies, capturing the moment of being in the same frame with the water birds. The girl next to me also excitedly held up her mobile phone and looked around, but she didn&#39;t know which one to take a good picture of. &quot;Look, there is a big fake bird beside the boat.&quot; We looked along the girl&#39;s fingertips. Perhaps the sea breeze carried her words, and the &quot;fake bird&quot; instantly &quot;resurrected&quot;, twisted its long neck, and &quot;glared&quot; at us. Amid roars of laughter, the Aberdeen Typhoon Shelter arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original meaning of a typhoon shelter is a water surface where small and medium-sized boats can temporarily take shelter from typhoons. When Aberdeen was still called Seac Pai Wan, the Dan family was already engaged in fishing and short-distance water transport here, and participated in the bulk transshipment of stones, incense, etc. But what I saw before me was unexpected. It was clearly a floating city on the water. Vegetable selling boat, shop boat, house boat, repair boat, trafficking boat, ferry boat, marine police boat, fish collecting boat, sightseeing boat, catering boat, cleaner&#39;s boat, selling seafood Ships, luxurious ships, simple ships, dilapidated ships, brand new ships, hurried ships, slow and leisurely ships... I can&#39;t help but think of American William C. Hunter&#39;s comments on the Pearl River Estuary 198 years ago. Description: “The river was crowded with local boats... In addition, there were sampans and ferries plying to and from Henan (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;South Bank of the Pearl River&lt;/span>;) , there are also some barber boats and boats selling various food, clothes, toys and daily necessities sold in shops on the shore.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Grandma Zhu slowed down and moved closer to a sampan with pots and stoves on it. Over there, they waved their hands early; here, Grandma Zhu praised &quot;Business is good&quot; and resumed the boat&#39;s speed. It turned out that it was a &quot;fenzai boat&quot; that specialized in selling fish egg noodles and roasted pork noodles. In the 1960s and 1970s, Aberdeen&#39;s fishery production reached its peak, and &quot;pink boats&quot; became very popular and could be seen everywhere in typhoon shelters. In addition to frequent visits by fishermen and sailors, citizens and tourists also come here and wave for boats on the shore. Now, there are still three or two boats doing it from time to time. &quot;It depends on your luck whether you can eat or not.&quot; Grandma Zhu continued, &quot;This boat is the most popular on the Char Siu River (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Powder&lt;/span>;). Right.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What also needs to be &quot;checked for luck&quot; is the Zhu Daxian Jiao Festival in the typhoon shelter. According to Grandma Zhu, the Zhu Daxian worshiped at the Zhu Daxian Jiao Festival is Zhu Bajie. Because he served as the Grand Marshal of Tianpeng and was in charge of the Tianhe River, he was regarded as the god of the sea by the people on the water in Aberdeen and recognized as &quot;Master Qi&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Godfather&lt;/span>;)&quot;, whose status is second only to Queen Mazu. Among all the Jiao festivals in Hong Kong and Macao, only the Zhu Daxian Jiao Festival is held entirely at sea every year, so it is also called the Jiao Festival on the water. Since the meeting period is not fixed, when to hold the meeting has to be determined in advance. Whether you can enjoy the prosperity depends entirely on luck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the countless boats, we found one, no, two Zhu Daxian Temples. It looks like it was transformed from a double-decker cruise ship, with a towering flagpole on the cabin and a fluttering yellow triangular red flag against the setting sun. The reason why there are two, Granny Zhu explained, is because &quot;Old Zhu Daxian&quot; needs to lead &quot;New Zhu Daxian&quot; to get familiar with the personnel of the typhoon shelter. After a few days, the shift will be completely handed over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Watching the sunset on a sampan is one of the &quot;compulsory courses&quot; for traveling in Aberdeen. Photo provided by Pang Mian&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/fae0742e11.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/fae0742e11.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Sitting on a sampan to watch the sunset is one of the &quot;compulsory courses&quot; for traveling in Aberdeen. &amp;nbsp;Photo provided by Pang Mian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to the boat with great excitement, we passed by the &quot;ruins&quot; of Zhenbao Seafood Boat again. The night rose, submerging the neon sign in a mass of black shadow. And ahead, the lights are bright and brilliant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雄心勃勃的印度海军扩张计划丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261746]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-03 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/8VKWWkFNgROpwdXswGako2MkS5jhghhKp18mAPPx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/8VKWWkFNgROpwdXswGako2MkS5jhgh hKp18mAPPx. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259964&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On August 17, 2023, Kolkata, the Indian Navy&#39;s new warship INS Vindhyagiri sailed in Hooghly River&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Indian Navy has made a request to purchase the French Scalp long-range cruise missile, hoping to use this missile It serves as the standard anti-ship and ground attack weapon for the 26 Rafale-M carrier-based aircraft equipped with the aircraft carrier INS Vikrant. A month ago, Ukraine used a Scalp cruise missile to destroy a Russian Black Sea Fleet submarine that was being repaired in a Crimean shipyard. This is the only submarine sunk by a cruise missile so far. In addition, the Scalp missile also accurately hit the headquarters building of the Black Sea Fleet, and its performance in actual combat was quite outstanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this is not the only naval equipment that India has recently purchased from France. On October 28, 2023, the Indian Navy just submitted a purchase request for 26 Rafale carrier-based aircraft to the French government. It can be seen that India is preparing to The carrier-based aircraft will be completely replaced with French Rafales instead of upgrading the Russian-made MiG fighters that have been used for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The procurement plan is by no means simple. It is part of India&#39;s ambitious naval reorganization plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Indian Navy Vice Admiral Ajendra Bahadur Singh told the media: “Some naval ships will be decommissioned in the next few years, and at the same time By adding some more ships, we hope that the number of naval ships will reach more than 200 within 15 years (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;to 2037&lt;/span>;).&quot;&lt;/span>; p>; &lt;p>;Since India’s independence in 1948, the Indian Navy has always hoped to become a blue water navy with 142 ships and operating two aircraft carriers at the same time. However, so far, the Indian Navy has only about 132 ships and 200 ships. The ship&#39;s target seemed a bit difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difficulty of India&#39;s naval expansion is far from a matter of quantity being far from 200 ships. It is that India not only needs to add 68 ships within 15 years, but also needs to acquire most of the navy&#39;s main battle equipment within these 15 years. NATOization. This also means that India must eliminate at least one-third of its active main warships, that is, more than 40 ships, in order to achieve the initial goal of NATOization. In this case, India must equip more than 100 ships within 15 years, and India currently equips about 4 new ships every year. At this rate, the Indian Navy may only maintain its current scale, not to mention India&#39;s huge equipment expansion The plan also includes building a new aircraft carrier, which is undoubtedly more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a realistic perspective, India&#39;s naval reorganization plan may not be as ambitious as it claims. The Indian Navy has long relied on Russia to supply equipment, and Russia suffered huge losses in the war. Most of the supporting supply chains for large surface ships in the Soviet era were in Ukraine. Since the Crimean crisis in 2014, Russia has been unable to obtain supporting products from Ukraine. As a result, its large surface ships have difficulty even in overhaul and maintenance, and may no longer be able to continue to supply India in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When India and Russia previously cooperated on the &quot;Chaori King&quot; aircraft carrier renovation project, the progress was delayed and the cost was seriously overrun. At that time, India realized that relying on Russia was unsustainable, so it had begun to build large surface ships on its own. Industry Planning. Unfortunately, India was sanctioned by the United States because of nuclear weapons issues, and could only make do with continuing military cooperation with Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As relations with the United States have heated up rapidly in recent years, India&#39;s plan to manufacture its own naval equipment is accelerating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first indigenous aircraft carrier &quot;Vikrant&quot; manufactured by India&#39;s Cochin Shipyard Limited (CSL) will be officially commissioned in 2022, marking that India has the ability to build its own aircraft carrier - although this The construction of the difficult-to-deliver aircraft carrier has been delayed from the start of construction to the official commissioning. The Indian Navy has been waiting for this for 17 years. However, compared with aircraft carriers, the construction process of India&#39;s domestic destroyers can be said to be quite smooth. It only took ten years from the project establishment in 2011 to the commissioning of the first ship in 2021, and it is being launched at a rate of one per year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, India has built three 7,000-ton Visakhapatnam-class destroyers on its own. The ships have a stealth appearance and an Aegis air defense system. India claims that its localization rate has reached 75%. It is a model of Indian warships made in China. It can be seen that the Indian shipbuilding industry has no big problems with technology and construction capabilities, at least in building large battleships of the destroyer level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thing that is good for the Indian shipbuilding industry is the signing of an agreement between India and the United States in 2021, announcing that India will become the future large-scale equipment maintenance center of the U.S. Navy in the Indo-Pacific region. The 2022 US-India 2+2 ministerial dialogue announced that the United States intends to inspect Indian shipyards. Immediately afterwards, the USS Charles Drew (T-AKE-10) docked at Kattupalli Shipyard for maintenance and repairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This agreement means that the United States will help India improve its maintenance and construction capabilities of large warships, and even directly provide technical cooperation, allowing India to master the construction and maintenance technology of large U.S. warships, as well as related technical standards and management. process. Judging from the experience of Japan and South Korea, the cooperative weapons and equipment maintenance bases established by the United States after the Korean War played a key role in improving the technology of the local shipbuilding industry and optimizing management processes. In particular, a country like South Korea, which became independent after World War II, has a weak industrial base and a lack of talent. The technical support provided by the United States is crucial to the establishment of its industrial system. Thanks to this, South Korea has also established its own military industry, and even Now it has begun to become a new type of weapons and equipment exporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although India&#39;s independent manufacturing capabilities for main battle equipment have long been poor, it has to admit that it has at least independent manufacturing capabilities for naval equipment. The remaining problem is how to connect with American standards and become a Part of the U.S. global military equipment logistics maintenance system. Considering that India&#39;s economic development momentum is booming, and the technical restrictions on it by the United States and Europe have been almost completely lifted, it is possible to replace the original Soviet-Russian system and Westernize its naval equipment in 15 years, at least while maintaining the existing Given the scale, it is a completely achievable goal to replace the old and adopt the new. As for whether it can be expanded to a scale of 200 ships, it depends on the execution capabilities of the Indian shipbuilding industry and economic development. However, it is foreseeable that with the help of Western technology, the combat effectiveness of Indian naval ships will definitely be greatly improved. This is also the goal that the United States and India hope to achieve in military cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北极光：极夜中的极致绚烂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261722]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我匆匆地走入森林中丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261724]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/NQsVYC8CantGXtnTIuGm3J0qDiNMceoDGzXZeGIW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/NQsVYC8CantGXtnTIuGm3J0qDiNMceoDGzX ZeGIW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259217&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Junjie/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/260804 &quot; title=&quot;The dispute between the 94-year-old man and his nanny for 2 million pension funds&quot;>;The dispute between the 94-year-old man and his nanny for 2 million pension funds&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the summer, a dazzling news: 94 Lu Delin, a 20-year-old Shanghainese man, told on social media that he was abused by his nanny and defrauded of his pension. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shanghai is the super-large city with the highest aging population in the country. According to Shanghai&#39;s 2022 elderly population and aging undertaking monitoring statistics, the registered elderly population aged 60 and above in Shanghai in 2022 will be 5.5366 million, accounting for nearly 40% of the total registered population. Among them, the number of elderly people living alone is 300,600. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The connection between individual circumstances and the lifeline of the times is about to emerge. It is a topic of public value. After encountering countless stories, I still can’t help but feel the initial excitement and impulse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, standing in winter and thinking back to that summer, the first thing that comes to mind is the part about mosquitoes. The scene we first arrived at was the community where the incident occurred. The community is located in Huangpu District, Shanghai, in the city center. It was built in the early 1990s and has 4 high-rise buildings interspersed with lush tall trees and low grass. It was a summer evening in Shanghai, and there were two or three old people sitting on the benches downstairs enjoying the shade. I wanted to know some surrounding information, and I became the target of &quot;mosquitoes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The culprit is probably the &quot;flower mosquito&quot; as the local elderly call it. In just three or two hours, it left more than a dozen red and swollen bumps on my legs that were already wearing trousers. It was obviously not appropriate to scratch and chat at the same time, so I had to scratch twice quickly in the gap from one bench to another. The physical feeling was real, and this unspeakable and unseemly detail became the first fragment that hit me in my memory. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This feeling is like a coincidence, and it has been fulfilled in several recent questions, which are about the body. In the topic of Lu Delin, the accused nanny is no longer in the local area. Even during the exchange of evidence before the court session, she still did not appear. The subjects on the other side, the two elderly people, were taken to Hangzhou by their son and daughter-in-law, and their mental condition was not very good for a time. Well, considering that I was afraid that the visit of strangers would bring excitement to the two old people, I did not go to see them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the message left for me? It&#39;s an empty house, and there are surrounding clues that need to be found. Room number 2401, pushing open the closed door, the first thing that came out was a sour smell. This is supposed to be well-ventilated, with a square shape, looking into the other side of the living room, with a wide balcony and large windows. There are several orchids on the balcony. The flower pots are quite old, and the branches and leaves are wilting. For a moment, people don&#39;t know whether they should be described as being well-groomed or not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moldy cutting boards, dirty yellow clothes, expired food, all indicating the disorder of life, suddenly broke into my eyes in an instant. In the eyes of young people, in the undisordered time, what I discussed with my friends around me was more about the spiritual part, and the instinct of the body was automatically ignored in the surface respectability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The last topic was in Xi&#39;an. The interview subjects were some disabled people. In the continuous rain, we could not wait for the scene of their &quot;reunion&quot; and had to go door to door to chat. During the process, everyone The disorder of the body was mentioned invariably; and after Lu Delin chose the topic, I continued my business trip in Shanghai. The new topic was about Alzheimer&#39;s disease. The wife who became a caregiver told the story of taking care of her sick husband for nine years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From these stories, we can see what everyone is trying their best to maintain, and this effort seems to be an inevitable disorder of life. As a bystander, I hurriedly walked into this forest and felt the &quot;disorder&quot; that I had never experienced in real life. Some disorders are accidental, such as a car accident or sudden illness. They are also unprepared and rush into the forest and never get out; some disorders are slow, such as aging. They are already on the road to aging. It has been too long, so long that I have to admit that aging has come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Returning to the perspective of journalism, when we encounter these stories, how should we report this disorder? After the initial excitement and impulse, it’s time to write. I think that we should not visit this forest with a pair of curious eyes and notice something unsightly. It should not be regarded as the author&#39;s delicate observation and be presented freely. It’s better to enter this forest with a level gaze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although this time we entered this forest because of work, such a forest may break into our real life at any time, and in addition to the accident that breaks in at any time, its final arrival is a kind of inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“巴基斯坦可以从中国学到很多”:专访巴参议院国防委员会主席]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261738]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73936&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70727&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/4eecfa1ded.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Exclusive interview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At noon on December 1, Mshahi De accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporter. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Wang Hang)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/12/02/4eecfa1ded.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260507&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December At noon on the 1st, Mushahid accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Wang Hang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of December 1, Guangzhou Yuexiu International Conference Center. After the one-hour press conference, Pakistani guest Mushahid Hussain Saeed walked out of the venue quickly. Entering December, the weather in Guangzhou turns cooler. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I like Guangzhou. It has a pleasant climate and is a very dynamic place in China.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mushahid is the chairman of the Defense Committee of the Senate of Pakistan and the chairman of the Pakistan-China Society. From December 1st to 3rd, he was invited to participate in the 2023 &quot;Understanding China&quot; international conference to discuss and communicate with domestic and foreign guests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past fifty years, Mushahid came to China many times. In his words, he witnessed the poverty-stricken China in the 1970s and the reform and opening-up China in the 1980s. &quot;What we see today is a prosperous and powerful China that is leading the development of globalization.&quot; Mushahid said, &quot;I am very happy to witness the rise of China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Mushahid Shahid spent four years in Washington, the United States, and obtained a master&#39;s degree in international relations from Georgetown University&#39;s School of Foreign Service, &quot;with an understanding of the U.S. political system and how it operates.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He proposed that there are two different &quot;roads&quot; in the world today. One proposed by the United States and Western countries is security-centered, military-led, and focused on conflicts and confrontations. On the contrary, China insists on connectivity and cooperation, respecting diversity and being more inclusive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past 10 years, the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor, an important pilot project of the “Belt and Road Initiative”, has brought development opportunities to Pakistan. &quot;26 billion U.S. dollars of investment, 250,000 job opportunities, and 28,000 Pakistanis came to China to study. Electricity, roads, hospitals, education, etc. are constantly improving.&quot; Mushahid said, &quot;These have benefited Pakistan.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Global and regional security are also the focus of the conference. Regarding peace on the India-Pakistan border, Mushahid has optimistic expectations. &quot;Border conflicts can be resolved as long as there is will. We reject global hegemony and we reject regional hegemony.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon on December 1, Mushahid accepted a face-to-face interview with Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“If you want to learn from China, it is crucial to understand China”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/h4>; strong>;&lt;span>;Is this your first time to participate in the &quot;Understanding China&quot; forum? How do you feel? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is my first time to participate in the &quot;Understanding China&quot; forum. This forum is very valuable. First of all, we use this platform to understand China, the region and the world, and how they change and develop. Secondly, it is important for Pakistan to understand China. Because China is our closest strategic partner and our neighbor. Third, personally, I have been dealing with China for nearly fifty years. When I first came to China, I was still a young man of 17 or 18 years old. As a friend of China and a student of Chairman Mao, I saw China at that time. It can be said that I have witnessed China&#39;s transformation. If you want to learn from China, it is crucial to understand China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Compared with the first time you came to China, now what is the difference? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first time I came to China was in the 1970s. At that time, China was very poor and isolated from the world. Today, China has become rich and powerful, a global leader, and a leader in globalization. China has proposed the “One Belt, One Road” initiative to lead green development and technological innovation. So, this is a huge change. In addition to China, the world has also changed. Because the global center of gravity is shifting from the West to the East. This change in China also reflects global changes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;What are your impressions of Guangdong? For example, for the two big cities of Guangzhou and Shenzhen&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first time I came to Guangdong Province was in 1972, when Guangzhou A trade fair is being held. During that time, I went shopping at Guangzhou Friendship Store. I only had 200 yuan with me at that time, but I felt like a &quot;millionaire&quot;. Because no matter how I bought it, I never spent all the money. At that time, the price of Chinese goods was too cheap. There were no computers at that time, so people used calculators to calculate accounts or calculate money by hand. Then, I took a train from Guangzhou to Hong Kong, which was indeed a wonderful experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I went to Shenzhen was in 1982, and then in 1984. At that time, Shenzhen was a remote fishing village. After seeing it in person, I also felt that it was too backward and underdeveloped. When I first came to China, the city of Shenzhen did not exist. But in the subsequent 1980s, I saw the rapid rise of Shenzhen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many Pakistani businessmen do business in Guangzhou. Can they find business opportunities here? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mushahid: Of course. Pakistani businessmen in Guangzhou have been working here for years, even decades. In fact, many trades began not just now, but decades or even centuries ago. Guangzhou has always been a hub of connectivity and a warm and welcoming city. Foreigners are welcome to come here to do business and stay here. It has a pleasant climate, is close to the sea, and is a beautiful city. So Pakistanis enjoy life here, we support them and they can make a lot of money. So I think it&#39;s very good and they play a very good role in promoting relations between the people of Pakistan and China. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Pakistan can learn a lot from China”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span >;Over the past 40 years, China has undergone tremendous changes. What lessons do you think this has for Pakistan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think Pakistan can learn a lot from this. First, have a clear vision. Second, there must be the will to turn this vision into reality. Deng Xiaoping, the architect of China&#39;s reform and opening up, once said, &quot;Seek truth from facts&quot; and &quot;development is the last word.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Insist on development and openness, simplify bureaucracy and cumbersome processes, give talents the attention they deserve, and put them first. Good leadership qualities, policy continuity, learning from mistakes, openness and inclusiveness, focus on people-centered development, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I said, we can learn a lot from Guangdong, China, and China&#39;s reform and opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Are you confident about Pakistan’s future development? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am very optimistic about the future of Pakistan. I studied in the United States for four years, but I didn’t want to live there. I said I would go back and serve my country. This is thanks to our relationship with China, which is our neighbor and our best friend. China invests extensively in Pakistan. We must unleash the energy and creativity of the people of Pakistan, move forward, reduce bureaucracy and allow them to develop. We need to build industries, innovate, get education, and let them focus on what they should do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73937&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70728&quot; src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c3787969cf.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Interview.png&quot; alt=&quot;At the media meeting on December 1 , Mushahid said that the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Mao Shujie)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/c3787969cf.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260508&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At a media conference on December 1, Mushahid said that the “One Belt, One Road” initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan. (Photo/Southern Weekend reporter Mao Shujie)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Under the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative, development opportunities have come&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot; >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Is the “One Belt, One Road” initiative a development opportunity for Pakistan? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative is a historic opportunity for Pakistan, and we must seize this opportunity. In the past ten years, China has invested US$26 billion in Pakistan, created 250,000 jobs and produced 8,000 megawatts of electricity. These results have given Pakistan and its people confidence in the future. For example, Gwadar Port has developed and become a hub between Pakistan and Central Asian countries. So this is a big opportunity. Because of the “One Belt, One Road” initiative, a whole new world is unfolding. This is a historical opportunity for Pakistan to develop rapidly, and it is also a historical opportunity to learn from China&#39;s poverty alleviation and green development model. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people have misunderstandings about the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, but most Pakistanis fully support the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and the Maritime Silk Road. Many Pakistanis care about China. They believe that China is Pakistan&#39;s good friend and close ally. Therefore, the negative voices come from foreign propaganda. They come from misinformation, false stories and fake news. We have to fight back against this. This is the biggest challenge facing the Belt and Road Initiative in the next decade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Terrorist attacks occur frequently in Pakistan. How should the government solve the problem of terrorism? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Unfortunately, terrorist incidents do happen from time to time. Some of the terrorists come from neighboring areas, which are very unstable. Some are forces that do not want cooperation and development between Pakistan and China. In addition, we feel that there are foreign forces controlling terrorist activities in Pakistan, and they specifically target Chinese companies, individuals and projects. Therefore, we must develop an effective counter-terrorism strategy in Pakistan, carry out effective Pakistan-China security cooperation, and develop effective plans to protect Chinese projects and Chinese people living in Pakistan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“We reject global hegemony and regional hegemony”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2023, Pakistan’s Foreign Minister will visit India for the first time in 12 years. Do you think India and Pakistan have the will and motivation to deal with border conflicts? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Border conflicts can be resolved as long as there is a will. India should be broader-minded and not become narrow-minded in dealing with small countries. We reject global hegemony and we reject regional hegemony. Whether it is Pakistan, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, etc., they all reject hegemony. Look at Afghanistan, they reject American hegemony even though they are a small country. Therefore, the size of a country does not equal its strength. India should learn from the mistakes of other major powers and understand how they went in the wrong (direction). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The internal and external obstacles to solving the India-Pakistan issue are What? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think the internal obstacles mainly come from the negative attitude of the Indian government, and their mentality must change. The external problem is the &quot;new cold war&quot; launched by the United States against China in Asia. They are using India to counter China. This is where the problem lies. Therefore, India should be part of the Asian countries and should be part of the Belt and Road Initiative. We want India to be united with us. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;India is a nation-state with a great civilization. Why say no to this? Why should India work and behave like Washington or London? India should cooperate with Beijing, Kathmandu, Dhaka and Colombo. This is a regional issue. The future belongs to this region, not Europe or the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong style=&quot;color: rgb(154, 0, 0);&quot;>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If India continues to respond negatively to relations between the two countries, will there be a risk of escalation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mushahid:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think escalation can be avoided because India also knows that if they try to escalate, the other country will respond . Every country hopes to safeguard its territorial integrity, safeguard sovereignty, and maintain unity and dignity. They tried to launch an attack on Pakistan in February 2019, and they sent several aircraft over Pakistan. But we fought back and shot down two helicopters. So the country will respond, and this response will come quickly and strongly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[金融合规榜：万余条罚单中，哪家银保机构在坚守底线？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261734]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:24:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For the financial industry with strict supervision and strong supervision, compliance Rules are the bottom line that must be adhered to. As the world&#39;s largest banking market and the second largest insurance market, China&#39;s banking and insurance industries have always been the focus of supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Today, financial institutions’ compliance will be elevated to a new level. The Central Financial Work Conference pointed out that &quot;financial chaos and corruption problems continue to occur, and financial supervision and governance capabilities are weak&quot; and emphasized that &quot;financial supervision must be comprehensively strengthened to effectively prevent and resolve financial risks.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Compliance has thus become a core consideration for the soundness of financial institutions’ operations. Which financial institution often commits crimes? Which financial institution frequently charges sky-high fines? Which financial institution has the most business lines involved? This is not only the key regulatory orientation of regulatory agencies, but also a concern of every financial consumer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to monitor the compliance of various financial institutions in real time, the relevant departments of Southern Weekend worked together for nearly a year to build the &quot;Shepherd-China Financial Industry Compliance Cloud&quot; Platform” (hereinafter referred to as the “Sheepdog Platform”). After continuous iterative upgrades and improvements, the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; now collects in real time the administrative penalty information publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration, the State Administration of Foreign Exchange and their national offices, and simultaneously performs manual correction. test. In order to ensure the accuracy of the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; data, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center compared the recorded data with the information released by the three institutions one by one. The comparison results show that the accuracy of the penalty information data collected by the Shepherd Platform is as high as 100%, with no omissions or errors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In order to objectively present the compliance of 20 systemically important banks and nine major life insurance companies in 2023, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center focused on the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; &quot;More than 10,000 pieces of data collected were mined and analyzed to construct the 2023 China New Financial Compliance List. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Penalty information from three regulatory agencies, two dimensions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot; in real time Includes administrative penalty information publicly released by the People&#39;s Bank of China, the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau, the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, and their national offices. Therefore, this data information basically covers all regulatory penalties for the banking and insurance industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center also conducts statistical analysis on the number of fines and the amount of fines received by financial institutions, because the number of fines and the amount of fines respectively reflect the extent of violations. How many and whether the violation is serious or not. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to statistics, from January to October 2023, 20 Chinese systemically important banks and their branches received a total of 802 fines, with an average of 802 fines per bank. and its branches received 40 fines; the above-mentioned fines totaled nearly 1.127 billion yuan in fines, and each bank and its branches were fined nearly 56.3548 million yuan on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Nine major life insurance companies and their branches received 287 fines, with an average of 31 fines per life insurance company and its branches; the total of the above fines The fine was nearly 52 million yuan, and each life insurance company and its branches were fined nearly 5.73 million yuan on average. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From a mean perspective, banks have higher values ​​than life insurance companies in terms of both the number of fines and the amount of fines. Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that this is related to the bank&#39;s large scale and business volume. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center collected 10,467 pieces of penalty information (including institutions) issued by the three major regulatory agencies from January to October 2023 on the Shepherd Platform Penalty information and personal penalty information) conduct data mining analysis and construct a new financial compliance list for 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Which bank was fined the largest amount? Which company has been punished the most? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The bank compliance list shows that China Construction Bank, Minsheng Bank and Shanghai Bank took the top three spots. Among them, China Construction Bank and China Minsheng Bank were fined more than 200 million yuan each, far exceeding the 98.544 million yuan imposed by Bank of Shanghai. The list of the number of penalties imposed on the bank compliance list shows that the five major state-owned banks of Industry, Agriculture, Postal Service, Construction, and China are among the top five in the list, and the number of institutional penalty information is more than 70, far exceeding the sixth place Minsheng Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Financial Competitiveness Ranking - Bank Compliance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/4bfa379375.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2389&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/4bfa379375.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Banks in the new financial competitiveness list Compliance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Observed by bank type, from January to October 2023, the number of institutional fines received by each bank is basically the same. They are arranged in order of state-owned banks, joint-stock banks and city commercial banks. There is no obvious pattern in the amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;For state-owned banks, during the time period included in this list, compared with the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, China Construction Bank, and Postal Service Bank, Bank of Communications The degree of compliance is relatively good. In terms of the amount of fines, Bank of Communications ranked twelfth, while the other five state-owned banks were all ranked in the top ten. At the same time, the number of fines received by Bank of Communications is also relatively small, and it is the only bank that is not in the echelon of state-owned banks in terms of the number of fines. The bank received 41 pieces of penalty information during the time period of this statistics. The number of penalty messages is only higher than that of China Minsheng Bank, a joint-stock bank in the echelon, with 42 messages. China Construction Bank became the bank with the largest amount of fines at this stage due to a fine of nearly 200 million yuan issued by the former China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission (now the State Administration of Financial Supervision) on February 16, 2023. In addition, the amount of each fine of ICBC, which ranked first in the number of fines, did not exceed 6 million yuan. Therefore, its total amount of fines ranks low among state-owned banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The compliance status of joint-stock banks and city commercial banks is relatively similar. During the statistical time period of this list, one bank in each of the above two categories ranked in the top three in the list of fines imposed, and the reason was that they received large fines of more than 60 million yuan. Bank of Nanjing and Bank of Jiangsu are the two banks with the best compliance during the statistical period of this list. The fines imposed on the above two banks did not exceed 10 million yuan, which were 600,000 yuan and 8.601 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that because the four major banks have large business scale and many branches, a high number of penalties does not necessarily mean that their compliance is lower than that of other banks. bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Loans are still the hardest hit area for violations&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Analyzing the types of violations, the statistical time of this list During this period, the violations of the 20 systemically important banks were concentrated in three areas: loans, external guarantees and customer identification. Among them, the loan business is the hardest hit area for bank violations. The above-mentioned fine of nearly 200 million yuan from China Construction Bank involves a total of 38 violations of laws and regulations, 15 of which are related to violations of loan business. Among the top ten in terms of the amount of fines received, except for Shanghai Bank, which only had one fine for &quot;violating the handling of domestic guarantees and overseas loans&quot; and seven other fines involving illegal handling of foreign exchange business, the fines received by the remaining nine banks all related to loans. Business violations. In fact, according to penalty information over the years, loan business violations have always been an &quot;old disease&quot; in the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Illegal handling of domestic guarantees for overseas loans and illegal external guarantees are the largest fines imposed on banks by the State Administration of Foreign Exchange during this statistical period. Bank of Shanghai and China CITIC Bank were fined 98.544 million yuan and 11.7544 million yuan respectively for the above-mentioned issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, customer identification issues were the third highest fine imposed on banks by regulatory agencies during this statistical period. Among them, the highest fines received by Ping An Bank and Postal Savings Bank during this statistical period both involved &quot;failure to perform customer identification obligations as required&quot;, and the fines for these two tickets were 53.4117 million yuan and 31.86 million yuan respectively. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the above analysis, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center suggested that banks need to focus on the compliance of loan business, guarantee business and payment and settlement business. How to eradicate old diseases and ensure the compliance of loan business is an issue that major commercial banks need to think about urgently. Today, some banks have applied artificial intelligence technology to assist manual loan review and other processes. Therefore, improving the accuracy of artificial intelligence technology in assisting in reviewing loan information may be one of the feasible solutions to rectify the &quot;old disease&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance companies urgently need to strengthen the implementation of internal control systems&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The life insurance compliance list shows that regardless of Ping An Life ranks first in terms of both the amount of fines and the number of fines it has received. Taikang Life ranked third and second respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The second place in the list of the amount of fines and the third place in the list of the number of fines are Taiping Life and China Life respectively. It is worth noting that AIA Life Insurance Co., Ltd. performed better in this compliance list. During this statistical period, AIA Life was the only financial institution among all participants in the list that did not receive any fines from the three major financial regulatory agencies and their dispatched agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;New Financial Competitiveness List - Life Insurance Compliance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/717a9f37af.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1313&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/12/02/717a9f37af.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;Life insurance in the new financial competitiveness list Compliance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From the perspective of the types of violations, life insurance companies’ violations are mainly fraud, deception and inducement of policyholders and system management issues . According to the &quot;Sheepdog Platform&quot;, from January to October 2023, there were 453 pieces of information about penalties for life insurance companies. Among them, 187 involve fraud, 105 involve deceiving or inducing policyholders, and 130 involve internal control systems and management issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In fact, most of the fines involving &quot;inadequate implementation of internal control systems&quot; involve &quot;preparing false information&quot; and &quot;inciting and inducing insurance agents to engage in acts that violate integrity&quot; voluntary activities”. &quot;Instigating and inducing insurance agents to engage in activities that violate their fiduciary obligations&quot; is the root cause of &quot;deceiving or inducing policyholders&quot;. This may be related to the business value concept of the company and its branches. If the design of the company&#39;s assessment indicators is unreasonable or the implementation is deformed, or the managers of relevant departments behave inappropriately, it will be difficult for their subordinates, especially grassroots personnel, to ensure business compliance when conducting business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Therefore, the compliance issues of life insurance companies this year can basically be attributed to the unscientific design of the indicator system and the inability to implement the internal control system. The Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center recommends that leaders of life insurance companies should adhere to the strategic focus of high-quality development and should not ignore compliance for temporary performance impulses, let alone engage in fraud that affects the image of the company or even the life insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[寿险效能提升榜：谁现在领先？谁拥有未来？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:31:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In 2023, China’s life insurance industry will continue to undergo difficult transformation. In a complex and ever-changing market: Life insurance was a hot seller in the first half of the year due to high interest rates, but the twists and turns in the equity market made life insurance investments suffer. &quot;Integrating newspaper and bank into one&quot; (see Southern Weekend App for details) Perennially deformed? &quot;>;&quot;Big accounts are high and small accounts are constantly rising. Why is the bancassurance business deformed all year round?&quot;&lt;/a>;) The new regulations have made the bancassurance channel under pressure even more uncertain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, life insurance companies are still determined to continue transformation, pursuing efficiency improvements, and are more committed to the blue ocean market of pension insurance and insurance +, and are competing for more considerate customer service upgrades . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Who is leading the race to transformation? Who sticks more to the &quot;customer-centric&quot; strategy? Which company is more transparent and open to the media and the public? Which company pays more attention to compliance? Which company pays more attention to innovation? Based on the principles of objectivity, fairness and science, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center constructed an evaluation index system for life insurance performance improvement rankings and evaluated the performance of each life insurance company. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Eight major dimensions&amp;nbsp;Fourteen sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Life Insurance Performance Improvement List&quot; Quantitative The qualitative evaluation index system consists of six first-level indicators and fourteen second-level indicators. Among them, the first-level indicators include three quantitative dimensional indicators of &quot;operational capabilities, customer service, and regulatory compliance&quot; and three qualitative dimensional indicators of &quot;business cross-penetration, comprehensive health ecology, and product innovation.&quot; The secondary indicators are refined into fourteen sub-indicators. The total weight of the quantitative and qualitative indicators is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center team assigned media factor weights based on the special research on the above-mentioned life insurance companies, and invited an external expert jury to evaluate the participating life insurance companies. The company conducts independent real-name scoring. Both scores have a weight of 15%. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the life insurance company under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/48d509878a. png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2087&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/48d509878a.png&quot; data-key= &quot;260503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Now The specific description of quantitative and qualitative indicators is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(1) Business capability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;How to judge the management ability of a life insurance company? From the perspective of business model, the business logic of life insurance companies is to collect premiums to form insurance liabilities, use insurance liabilities to invest to form investment assets, and the investment assets generate investment income. Therefore, to evaluate the operating capabilities of a life insurance company, one is to look at its ability to obtain premiums; the other is to look at its investment asset management capabilities. Original premium income is commonly used in the industry to measure the liability capacity of life insurance companies, but the premium income of nine life insurance companies accounts for about 3/4 of the life insurance industry. The life insurance performance list aims to select the best among the best, so the new indicator insurance service income is included in the statistics&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;What is insurance service income? According to the explanation in China Ping An’s semi-annual report, insurance service income refers to recognition during the insurance period based on the provision of services, and excludes investment components. Insurance service income reflects the income obtained from engaging in insurance business. In accordance with the provisions of the &quot;Accounting Standards for Business Enterprises No. 25 - Insurance Contracts&quot; (Finance [2020] No. 20) revised and issued on December 24, 2020, listed insurance companies will implement it from January 1, 2023. This regulation is also called the &quot;Chinese version of IFRS 17&quot;. Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found in its survey that, except for China Life and Taikang Life, seven other life insurance companies have applied the new insurance contract standard IFRS17. Under the new accounting standards, insurance business income is replaced by insurance service income, which also leads to a significant reduction in the recognition of premium income of life insurance companies. Life insurance companies with a large proportion of investment savings products and a high proportion of single premiums will be more obviously affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In addition, new business value and embedded value measure the insurance company&#39;s value, profitability and sustainable development, and the total investment return rate measures investment performance. These three indicators are commonly used indicators in the industry. In summary, the total weight of the four secondary indicators in this dimension is 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(2) Customer service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The insurance industry is a typical service-intensive industry. How to implement the &quot;customer-centered&quot; development concept, meet the diverse needs of customers, and improve the service quality of the insurance industry are key issues for my country&#39;s insurance industry to achieve high-quality development. From the demand side, the age composition and demand of insurance customer groups have changed significantly, and young customers have increasingly higher requirements for insurance services. From the supply side, my country&#39;s insurance products are highly homogeneous, with little difference in product pricing and basically similar scopes of liability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the life insurance industry cannot sell insurance as a &quot;fast-moving consumer goods&quot;. Otherwise, large-scale surrenders may occur, and the service attributes of &quot;slow experience&quot; and &quot;slow decision-making&quot; of insurance should be returned. Risk protection is the core function of the insurance industry. To implement &quot;customer-centric&quot;, on the one hand, insurance must be renamed insurance and return to the protection function; on the other hand, insurance must be made &quot;value for money&quot; insurance. In other words, we need to make it affordable, worthwhile, convenient and reassuring for consumers. Based on this, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center has set up three secondary indicators to measure claims settlement amount, average claim settlement timeliness and surrender rate in the customer service dimension. The total weight of the three indicators in this dimension is 15%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(3) Compliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;During the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, &quot;standardization&quot; has become the key word for the development of the insurance industry. At present, institutional supervision, behavioral supervision, functional supervision, penetrating supervision and continuous supervision have gradually formed. In 2021, the focus of supervision will be on the top-level design of the reform. In the fields of corporate governance, solvency, and insurance capital utilization, the &quot;Corporate Governance Guidelines for Banking and Insurance Institutions&quot;, &quot;Insurance Company Solvency Supervision Rules (II)&quot; and &quot;On Modifying the Parts in the Areas of Insurance Capital Utilization&quot; were released Notice of Normative Documents&quot;. In 2022, regulatory agencies will deepen supervision of consumer rights and interests and issue the &quot;Management Measures for the Protection of Consumer Rights and Interests of Banking and Insurance Institutions.&quot; This is a basic and programmatic document in the field of consumer rights protection in the banking and insurance industries. In 2023, supervision will shift to the regulation of bancassurance and individual insurance channels, and the &quot;Notice on Regulating Insurance Products in Bank Agency Channels&quot; and &quot;Measures for the Management of Insurance Sales Behavior&quot; will be issued. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center sets four sub-indicators in the compliance dimension, among which core solvency adequacy ratio and comprehensive solvency adequacy ratio are key regulatory indicators; insurance The service quality index refers to the 2022 insurance service quality index released by China Banking and Insurance Information Technology Management Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;China Banking and Insurance&quot;); the data on the number of administrative penalties comes from &quot;Sheepdog&quot; - China Financial Industry Compliance Cloud Platform Regulatory data collected by the system from January to September. The total weight of the four sub-indicators of this dimension is 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(4) Business cross-penetration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This dimension reflects the synergy and cross-selling capabilities of life insurance companies between different business lines. The Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the growth logic of life insurance institutions has shifted from &quot;scale&quot; to &quot;quality.&quot; The “insurance + service” development strategy has become an industry consensus. The weight of this dimension indicator is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(5) Healthy ecological construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The development of pension finance is inseparable from the construction of a comprehensive health ecosystem, because &quot;the elderly are provided for and the sick are treated&quot; are inseparable. Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluates the development of life insurance companies in the field of big health business based on the annual reports or other public information of each life insurance company. The weight of this dimension indicator is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;(6) Product innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;This dimension mainly reflects the product development and innovation capabilities of life insurance companies. The weight of this dimension indicator is 5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life leads the way&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on the above dimensions and indicator system, and integrating the 2023 results of various life insurance companies Mid-year reports and announcements, as well as data from third-party rating agencies, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center evaluated 9 insurance companies and obtained a total score of quantitative and qualitative indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Based on media factor weights and external expert review weights, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center constructed a life insurance performance list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The results of the list show that China Life, Ping An Life and AIA Life ranked the top three. Among them, China Life and Ping An Life have a clear lead and are the only two life insurance companies on the list with a total score of more than 60 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /02/1da3a7600f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1188&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/02/1da3a7600f.png &quot; data-key=&quot;260504&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify ;&quot;>;Sub-indicator system observation shows that in the quantitative and qualitative indicator scores, China Life, Ping An Life and AIA Life ranked in the top three, and there was a wide gap between the scores of the other six life insurance institutions. There is a nearly ten-point difference in scores between AIA Life in third place and Taiping Life Insurance in fourth place. This shows that the first-tier life insurance companies have a larger lead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the scores of the expert jury, the expert judges favored Ping An Life Insurance. The company was the only life insurance company to receive a score of 9. In the media factor, AIA Life, PICC Life and China Pacific Insurance failed to respond within the limited time for some reason and did not score, which in turn affected the overall score to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Observed from different dimensions, China Life, Ping An Life and PICC Life ranked the top three. China Life&#39;s 2023 interim report did not apply the new insurance contract standards, but replaced insurance service income with insurance business income, so there is an overestimation to a certain extent. However, China Life’s third quarter report for 2023 shows that its insurance service revenue reached 136.439 billion yuan, only slightly lower than Ping An Life’s 168.945 billion yuan. Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center calculated and found that the adjustment did not affect China Life&#39;s ranking in the life insurance performance list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Why does China Life top the list? China Life has obvious advantages on the liability side. China Life&#39;s third quarterly report shows that in the first three quarters of 2023, the scale and growth rate of premium income, new policy premiums, and first-year regular premiums all hit new highs for the same period in the past three years. First-year regular premiums with ten years or more were RMB 44.639 billion, a year-on-year increase of 15.4%, accounting for 42.12% of first-year regular premiums; new business value continued to grow in the first three quarters of 2023, with a year-on-year increase of 14.0%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;From an asset perspective, declining investment returns are a common problem in the industry. Against the backdrop of downward shifts in interest rates and fluctuations in the equity market, investment returns in the insurance industry have generally declined. Data from China Chengxin International shows that in 2022, the life insurance industry&#39;s investment return rate will drop to 3.8%, a decrease of 0.6 percentage points from 2021, which is significantly lower than the industry&#39;s average investment return rate of 5.3% in the past ten years. Therefore, the overall score for this indicator is low, with PICC Life scoring the highest because it uses group data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;China Life performs well in the customer service dimension. In terms of sub-indicators, China Life’s three indicators are all at the leading level in the industry. Data from the company&#39;s 2023 interim report show that the average claim settlement timeframe is 0.39 days, a year-on-year increase of 17%; &quot;claims prepayment&quot; exceeded 74 million yuan; &quot;claims direct payment&quot; exceeded 3.41 million; &quot;one-day critical illness compensation&quot; compensation amount exceeded 5.4 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 50%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, China Life does not fall behind in terms of regulatory compliance. In terms of sub-indicators, the company&#39;s core solvency adequacy ratio reached 140%, and its comprehensive solvency adequacy ratio reached 204%, both well above regulatory requirements and at the average level among the nine life insurance companies. In the 2022 Insurance Service Quality Index released by China Banking and Information Technology, China Life received a high score of 94.61, which is higher than the average level of 85.28 in the personal insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;However, according to data from &quot;Sheepdog&quot;, a compliance cloud platform for China&#39;s financial industry, China Life was fined 47 times (including branches) in the first three quarters, a high On average 29 times. Because China Life has a large business volume and many branches, this indicator does not mean that the company&#39;s compliance is lower than that of other peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Develop pension finance and cultivate new growth poles&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In the midst of high-quality transformation of life insurance companies Nowadays, as the core component of the third pension pillar, pension insurance is becoming a strategic insurance type. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believes that pension finance has huge potential. The three-dimensional indicators of business cross-penetration, comprehensive health ecological construction and product innovation reflect the development of pension finance of life insurance companies to a certain extent. However, the disclosure standards of various life insurance companies are not uniform because they are in the exploratory period. Therefore, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center conducts evaluations based on the annual reports of each life insurance company and with reference to various information such as announcements and publicity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The results of the list show that although Ping An Life ranks second in the total score of the list, it scores first in the three qualitative indicators. China Life Second, AIA Life, Taiping Life and Sunshine Life tied for third. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center also found in its survey that nine life insurance companies are actively participating in the construction of pension finance. Among them, China People&#39;s Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., China Life Pension Insurance Co., Ltd., and Taiping Pension Insurance Co., Ltd. are the first batch of pension insurance companies designated by the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau to participate in the commercial pension pilot. The pilot is about to be completed for one year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Other life insurance companies are also actively exploring pension finance business. For example, Ping An Life relies on the resources of Ping An Group of China to continue to make efforts in the direction of &quot;insurance + services&quot;. In terms of &quot;insurance + health&quot;, Ping An Life launched the &quot;Ping An Zhenxiang RUN&quot; health service plan. In the first three quarters of 2023, Ping An Life has served more than 19 million customers, a year-on-year increase of more than 10%; in the &quot;insurance + high-quality health care community&quot; In terms of &quot;Ping An Life Insurance&quot;, Ping An Life has teamed up with other professional companies within the group to build a high-quality health care brand &quot;Zhen Yi Nian&quot;. In October 2023, Ping An Zhenyi Nian officially released Wellness Care 3.0, launching two new benefits: residence and CCaH (Continuing Care at Home). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In terms of &quot;insurance + home care&quot;, Ping An Life continues to explore home care services. As of the end of September 2023, Ping An&#39;s home care services have covered 54 cities across the country, with a total of more than 70,000 people qualified for home care services, and more than 50% of policyholders in 54 cities have activated their home service rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Taikang Life has formed a collaboration with 20 &quot;Taikang Homes&quot; across the country and has become an industry benchmark. Sunshine Life will start with the Sunshine Family (Guangzhou) health care community and gradually deploy a chain of CCRC senior care communities across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that the integration of medical and nursing care is a general trend, and &quot;insurance + services&quot; is becoming a new blue ocean. All life insurance companies should continue to innovate in products and services. On the one hand, they should enrich product connotations and expand the coverage of insurance products; on the other hand, they should extend the value chain of insurance services and provide comprehensive services such as health management, medical services, and long-term care. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[欠发达县1个在编身后1.8个临聘：转移支付保“吃饭财政”难以为继]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to &quot;Half Moon Talk&quot;, the reporter was in a county in Wumeng Mountain District During the investigation, it was found that the county’s total wage guarantee budget expenditure for the year was 2.63 billion, including 2 billion for in-service personnel, 170 million for retired personnel, and 460 million for temporary personnel. The number of temporary employees is 1.8 times that of in-service employees, but the total salary budget of the former is less than a quarter of the latter. In addition, the county&#39;s total salary expenditures for temporary employees have exceeded the county&#39;s total tax revenue. In several neighboring districts and counties of the county, the average number of temporary employees is 1.7 times that of in-service employees. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Specifically, the per capita annual income of temporary employees in the county is about 16,100 yuan, and the total number of employees is 28,806; the per capita annual income of current employees is about 12.83 million, and the total number of personnel is 15,580. The per capita annual income of current employees is eight times that of temporary employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How do you view this phenomenon? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First of all, the county has been completely reduced to &quot;food finance&quot;. The total annual salary budget for temporary staff is 460 million, which has exceeded the county&#39;s total tax revenue, which means that the county&#39;s economic strength and endogenous fiscal capacity are very weak. Against the background that the sluggish housing market has stalled land finance, especially in small localities, the total annual budget expenditure of 2.63 billion on guaranteed wages will most likely come from transfer payments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for the economically developed areas that currently provide sources of transfer payments, their finances are not sufficient or even very difficult. It is impossible to maintain the &quot;food finance&quot; for a long time by relying on transfer payments. , the county may have to slim down: reductions in personnel, staff, budgets, and expenditures are inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, the so-called on-the-job personnel are formal workers with a formal establishment; the so-called temporary personnel are temporary workers and contract workers without a permanent establishment. If we have to reduce headcount, which category of people will be eliminated first? From the perspective of effectiveness and efficiency, how should redundant staff be eliminated? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The answer to the first question is obvious. In the case of financial difficulties, unemployed personnel will be laid off first. This is also a common practice everywhere. It’s called “clearing out temporary workers.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason is very simple: the principle of minimum action. In theory, there is no iron rice bowl anymore. The current &quot;Civil Service Assessment Regulations (Trial)&quot; has annual assessments, and the results are divided into four grades: excellent, competent, basically competent and incompetent. &quot;The annual assessment for two consecutive years is determined to be Those who are found to be incompetent will be dismissed.&quot; But in fact, unless a major principled error is made, it is very difficult to lay off an employee with a civil servant or a public institution, and few leaders are willing to be evil and &quot;smash people&#39;s jobs&quot; and are worried about being sacked. The job holder or his family may cause trouble, be unsightly, and have a &quot;bad influence.&quot; But it&#39;s different for temporary workers without official establishment. They are mentally prepared to be laid off due to the company running out of money or the superior&#39;s request. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, should temporary workers be eliminated (first)? Before answering this question, you must understand why the company recruits temporary workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Temporary workers are different from temporary workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​is that there is a relationship, but the relationship is not strong enough and it is not enough to get the establishment in one step. First, recruit people to make a temporary transition and wait for the internal opportunity to become a regular employee. Banyuetan reporter&#39;s investigation found that the recruitment and management of most temporary personnel are not handled by a unified department and are basically carried out according to the principle of &quot;who employs people, who recruits them&quot; without approval or approval from the establishment department, finance department, organization department, human resources and social security department. The registration and recruitment procedures are relatively haphazard, with the phenomenon of disorderly growth in quantity and unguaranteed quality, and it is difficult to eliminate recruitment based on personal relationships and relationships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The other type is irrelevant or almost irrelevant. They are recruited to do the dirty and tiring work that regular workers are unwilling to do. , hard work and troublesome work, you may be pushed out to take the blame if something goes wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also many internal contradictions in such units: on the one hand, formal workers get more money, good benefits, but work less, and there are various ways to obtain honors and Opportunities for promotion; on the other hand, temporary workers who work receive less money, poor benefits, and more work. If something goes wrong, they will be pushed out to take the blame. With such a close contrast, the latter&#39;s psychology will be very unbalanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, if we look at the logic of the market, temporary workers are paid market prices; for the same position, regular workers are paid more than temporary workers. Part of it is the premium brought by the preparation. When multiple people compete for an organization, they compete for the premium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Public people think that when &quot;retiring temporary workers&quot;, the first type of eviction is to let those who do not work leave to improve efficiency, but in fact The second type is often eliminated, which is to let the temporary workers leave. It doesn&#39;t matter and they are hard-working, so there is the least resistance to the elimination. However, after they are dismissed, the regular workers often complain because someone has to do the work. After laying off these many people, work can still be done. In this sense, efficiency has been improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Finally, government functions should be viewed from the perspectives of government and market/society. Government management should also live within its means: a county&#39;s tax revenue is less than 500 million a year, and the total budgeted expenditure on guaranteed wages is 2.63 billion. The county has been financially exhausted. Do we really need so many people, spend so much money, and take care of so many things? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;We should sort out: which management and service functions are absolutely necessary and can only be performed by the government, and what budget and staff size are appropriate; which ones can be abolished to allow Society manages itself; what is considered excessive regulation or improper regulation stifles economic vitality? Even if a county has too many net outflows of people and its population and economic scale continue to shrink, then merging counties is also a good choice, and merging villages It has been practiced in many places such as , , towns and villages, reducing the scale of government and releasing market vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, it is because civil servants have become the de facto iron rice bowl and the premium brought by the establishment is very high, that’s why everyone has such a big interest in the public examination preparation. enthusiasm. If we can implement the annual assessment of civil servants and public institutions, and dare to fire veterans who only get paid but do not work like market-oriented enterprises, and reduce the premium brought by the establishment to zero, everyone will be more rational about the public examination preparation. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There is another way to compress or even eliminate the premium brought by staffing: marketize job salaries and see how much the temporary workers recruited from the market are paid. Then the salary of regular workers is as close as possible to that of temporary workers, so as to squeeze out the premium of establishment. Cleaners in a certain place have a staff. Cleaners with staff hire people to do their work and then enjoy the price difference. This difference is the premium brought by the staff. The government or taxpayers were taken advantage of and spent more money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 18:25:19 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家卫健委：目前流行的急性呼吸道疾病均由已知病原体引起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261726]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 15:16:28&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The National Health Commission held a press conference today to introduce the prevention and control of respiratory diseases in winter. Mi Feng, spokesperson of the National Health Commission, said that at present, the National Health Commission, together with the State Administration of Traditional Chinese Medicine and the State Administration of Disease Control and Prevention, continue to carry out winter respiratory disease monitoring and research and judgment, and are doing a good job in allocating medical resources, optimizing the medical treatment process, and playing a central role. Medical functions and other work are deployed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to monitoring, the currently prevalent acute respiratory diseases are all caused by known pathogens and have corresponding mature treatments. No new infectious diseases caused by new viruses or bacteria have been found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is necessary to further increase the supply of medical services, promote the &quot;opening of pediatric outpatient clinics at all levels and types of medical institutions such as traditional Chinese medicine hospitals, maternal and child health hospitals, etc.&quot;, increase the number of noon, night and weekend outpatient clinics according to the number of patients, and extend the number of outpatient clinics. service hours, expand inpatient beds, and continuously optimize registration, examination, payment and other medical procedures to facilitate people&#39;s medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is necessary to carry out hierarchical diagnosis and treatment, smooth referral channels, transfer personnel across departments and hospitals, ensure the supply of medical supplies, promote Internet medical care, and maximize the capacity to receive medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is necessary to give full play to the role of traditional Chinese medicine and integrate traditional Chinese and Western medicine to target common respiratory diseases in winter, popularize knowledge of disease prevention and treatment with traditional Chinese medicine, and improve the effectiveness of prevention and treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is necessary to ensure the supply and vaccination services of influenza and other vaccines, and ensure that key groups such as the elderly and children are vaccinated as early as possible to reduce the risk of illness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wearing masks, washing hands frequently, and ventilating frequently are very effective in preventing the spread of respiratory diseases. It is necessary to take good personal protection, go to work without illness, go to school without illness, and adhere to good personal hygiene habits and a healthy lifestyle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雪后长城，巨龙伏纱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261720]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-02 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 15:25:08 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>