<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[施工方举报大桥偷工减料：事件逐渐“失焦”，情况属实还是造谣生事必须搞清楚丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256667]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, an accusation of &quot;cutting corners on a highway bridge&quot; has attracted attention. On August 30, 2023, a netizen surnamed Liu with the online name &quot;Liu Shao&quot; reported in real name on the social media platform that there were construction quality problems in the Qinghai Tongsai Expressway Taohe Bridge built by China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau No. 5 Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu claimed to be the actual construction party and began to undertake the substructure project of the Taohe Bridge on April 6, 2022, which lasted more than eight months. He reported that the project leader of China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company &quot;did not use steel bars from the shortlisted manufacturers according to the design, privately used non-standard steel bars from non-shortlisted manufacturers, cut corners during construction, and used unqualified sand and gravel materials during winter construction, resulting in poor concrete quality.&quot; qualified&quot;. Among them, statements such as &quot;the pile inspection process changed the second-category piles to the first-category piles&quot;, &quot;80% of the pile foundation steel bars are unqualified&quot; and &quot;there are hidden safety and quality risks&quot; attracted the attention of the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 6, the Fifth Company of China Railway No. 5 Bureau issued a public statement stating that it had previously entrusted Qinghai Provincial Traffic Inspection Co., Ltd. as a third-party testing agency to conduct quality inspections on the bridge. The inspection report shows that &quot;the physical quality of the Taohe Bridge meets the design requirements and the quality is qualified.&quot; The steel bars and concrete used in the construction are all qualified, and the pile foundation tests are all Class I piles. Liu&#39;s reports have been refuted one by one. At present, the competent authority has entrusted a testing agency to &quot;conduct physical quality inspection and raw material sampling inspection&quot;, and the re-inspection results will be announced to the public in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu didn’t buy it. He showed evidence to &quot;Running News&quot; and said, &quot;The test report I got contains Class II piles.&quot; The pouring time was May 26, 2022. The test date is June 29, 2022. Liu admitted that he made the report because the Fifth Company of China Railway No. 5 Bureau not only refused to pay him for his labor services, but instead cleared him from the site, causing heavy losses to him. “Now I have to report the project quality issues even if I don’t need any money.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to media reports, Liu was sued by China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company to the People&#39;s Court of Ledu District, Haidong City, Qinghai Province for infringing the company&#39;s reputation rights because he reported that his labor fees had not been settled. The case will be heard in court on September 18. Liu also presented evidence, saying that he had received a message from the other party &quot;Look at the hardness of our China Railway No. 5 Bureau&quot; after reporting with his real name; the other party also proposed a &quot;compensation plan&quot;, but he did not agree if he was not satisfied. The Fifth Company of China Railway No. 5 Bureau responded that Liu’s main purpose was blackmail and “I will report it as soon as I don’t get the blackmail.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident has evolved to this point and has gradually become &quot;out of focus&quot;: the dispute between Liu and China Railway has become a new hot spot. A closer look at this incident reveals that there are actually two important aspects that deserve further analysis and questioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the relationship between the civil dispute between Liu and the Fifth Company of China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau and his reporting behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is Liu&#39;s self-report or the &quot;extortion of money&quot; accusation from China Railway No. 5 Bureau, it is shown that the report was due to Liu&#39;s financial demands and that the two parties had a civil dispute. But what is curious is why the case was initiated by China Railway No. 5 Engineering Co., Ltd. against Liu for &quot;infringement of reputation rights&quot; instead of Liu launching a civil lawsuit against China Railway No. 5 Engineering Co., Ltd. due to a labor contract dispute? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cause of this incident was an economic dispute over &quot;unpaid labor fees&quot;. Following this line of thought, Liu first reported the problem when he could not get the labor fee, but was sued for &quot;infringement of reputation rights&quot;. Then, instead of filing a civil lawsuit on the grounds of a labor contract dispute and demanding payment of the labor fee, he filed an online lawsuit He reported that the project was cutting corners and materials, saying &quot;I have to report project quality problems even if I don&#39;t get labor fees,&quot; and rejected China Railway&#39;s compensation plan. This shows that Liu escalated the incident at all costs, giving the outside world the impression that &quot;the fish is dead and the net is broken.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the evolution of the incident, there are still some questions hidden in the game between the two parties during this period: Has Liu&#39;s labor fee been settled? If it was indeed not settled, Liu initially went to China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau and the relevant departments in Qinghai to report this problem. I am afraid it was just a normal rights protection. Why was he sued by the Fifth Company of China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau for &quot;infringement of the company&#39;s reputation rights&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the chat records provided by Liu, the words of a person from the China Railway No. 5 Bureau after the real-name report, &quot;The more you cause trouble, the less afraid I am. Look at the hardness of our China Railway No. 5 Bureau&quot; to the outside world. It leaves more room for interpretation. This sentence can make people reasonably speculate that Liu chose to &quot;turn the table&quot; by exposing the quality problems of the project precisely because his demands for labor fees were repeatedly ignored by the other party. So, will the labor fees be settled on time, or will the compensation plan of China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company satisfy Liu after the report, and the matter will be settled smoothly? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Liu came out to expose the project quality problems just because the labor fees were not paid, and the project quality problems were true, then the whole incident would have the flavor of &quot;unevenly sharing the spoils, and turning the table over in anger&quot;. The problem behind it is undoubtedly more worrying; or, if the truth is as claimed by China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company, Liu intends to &quot;extort money&quot;, then whether the test results and the evidence he presented are forged, and how much his labor fees are? A clear answer should also be given as to why it was not settled and why it was not settled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, whether the truth of the incident is that Liu extorted money or that the Fifth Company of the China Railway Fifth Bureau was in arrears of labor fees, it cannot conceal the most important focus of this incident: whether the construction of the Taohe Bridge on the Tongsai Expressway was completed. Through safety inspection, whether there are any project quality problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that the Tongsai Expressway has a total length of 204 kilometers, and the total estimated investment of the project is 18.562 billion yuan. The main project will start on June 15, 2022, and is planned to be completed in October 2025. This expressway connects Qinghai Huangnan Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture and the Qinghai-Gansu border area. It is a section of the &quot;G0611 Zhangwen Expressway&quot;. The Taohe Bridge is located in Saierlong Township, with a total length of 824.5 meters and a total of 20 spans. On July 17, 2023, the first box girder of the bridge was successfully erected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Mou chose to report after the substructure project of the Taohe Bridge was completed and the first box girder was successfully erected. Judging from the current situation, it was because of the intensification of economic disputes. Which one is more convincing is the previous test results announced by the fifth company of China Railway Fifth Engineering Bureau, the test results of the supervision company commissioned by Liu himself, and the evidence presented. This is something that the competent authorities should conduct an in-depth and serious investigation in the follow-up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, inconsistencies between actual construction and prior surveys are relatively common in the engineering community. If Liu&#39;s accusation is true and China Railway No. 5 Bureau No. 5 Company chooses &quot;non-standard steel bars, unqualified sand and gravel materials and Class II piles&quot; in construction, its impact on the quality of the project will also need to be determined through professional evaluation. The key to the problem is whether changing construction materials will affect the quality of the project and thus endanger the safety of the Taohe Bridge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the focus of this matter should not be on the dispute between Liu and China Railway No. 5 Bureau. Relevant departments should adhere to the principle of safety first in the follow-up investigation, focus on the inspection of project quality, investigate whether the fifth company of China Railway No. 5 Bureau made normal changes in construction materials or cut corners, and fully demonstrate the impact of changes in construction materials on the traffic of the Taohe Bridge. impact on safety and fully disclose the findings to the public. If there is indeed a case of cutting corners and affecting the quality of the bridge, the relevant responsible persons should be severely dealt with and even held criminally responsible; if the whistleblower spreads rumors and causes trouble, he cannot go unpunished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 11:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“数字”间谍来自何处？有何招式？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256665]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The current development of network technology is rapid, and new things such as 5G, Metaverse, ChatGPT and so on are emerging. It makes people exclaim &quot;the future is already here&quot;. Along with it, there are also a large number of hidden network security risks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a specialized agency for safeguarding national security and a department in charge of counter-espionage work, national security agencies continue to strengthen the tracking, monitoring and prevention of relevant activities, effectively safeguard our network security, and make &quot; &quot;Digital&quot; spies reveal their true colors and have nowhere to hide! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Where did the attack come from? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Spy shadows thousands of miles away&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Currently, cyberspace has become a target for overseas espionage and intelligence agencies. An important position for my country to carry out cyber espionage work, our country has become the main victim of high-level persistent threat (APT) attacks. In recent years, national security agencies have discovered that dozens of espionage and intelligence agencies from different countries and regions have carried out cyber attacks in our territory. They either set up specialized agencies, set up &quot;cover companies&quot;, and developed professional means to directly carry out cyberattacks and penetrations against me, or through &quot;behind-the-scenes control&quot; and &quot;service outsourcing&quot; methods, they instruct professional companies and hacker organizations to carry out the operations, or through &quot;purchasing&quot; &quot;Data, loopholes, tools and other methods are used to lure domestic institutions and personnel to implement it. Some countries also use the guise of &quot;hunting&quot; to lure other countries to implement it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Who are the potential targets? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;The flash of swords and shadows within easy reach&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From the perspective of attack targets, in addition to the continued attacks on our national institutions and related In addition to carrying out cyber attacks on &quot;traditional targets&quot; such as confidential units, overseas espionage and intelligence agencies have also continued to strengthen attacks and penetrations on China&#39;s critical information infrastructure and major infrastructure network systems, and have further extended their black hands to China&#39;s universities, scientific research institutions, and large-scale infrastructure. Enterprises, high-tech companies and other institutions and business executives, experts and scholars and other groups. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Judging from the attacks, various software systems such as email, office automation, user management, and security protection are involved, as well as various hardware devices such as servers, computers, switches, and routers. , as well as mobile phones, WIFI, cameras and other civilian household equipment, it can be said to be &quot;pervasive&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;What are the tricks? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;A highly threatening &quot;professional team&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Different from ordinary social hackers, overseas espionage and intelligence agencies It has many resources to mobilize, strong technical capabilities, rich experience in cyber attack activities, and more covert methods. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Some of them collect and steal personal information, use social engineering, and accurately forge “phishing” emails and websites to conduct deception attacks on target objects; some use mining and purchasing key &quot;Zero-day vulnerabilities&quot; in software systems and hardware equipment directly attack and penetrate the company; some first intrude into the network of companies that control our supply chain or operation and maintenance service organizations, and then use this as a &quot;springboard&quot; to attack downstream user units; some on a large scale Penetrate and control China&#39;s civilian network and home network equipment, and establish &quot;positions&quot; to carry out cyber attacks against China and other countries. Behind extremely professional and covert attack methods, there are often more dangerous intentions! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/0005c4c4635be7fb8fdab302f8671fc4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;488&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/0005c4c4635be7fb8fdab302f8671fc4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250757 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Overseas cyber attacks against us&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Common&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Common techniques&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;How much harm is caused? &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;Security issues that cannot be underestimated&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Cyberattacks by overseas espionage and intelligence agencies are large-scale and deep-seated , strong sustainability. Once the network systems of our country&#39;s state agencies, secret-related units and other important corporate institutions are attacked or invaded, the state secrets, important data, documents, etc. stored and processed may be &quot;caught in one sweep.&quot; Once our critical information infrastructure and major infrastructure network systems are invaded and controlled, they will face the risk of being disrupted and destroyed at any time. Overseas spy agencies conduct cyber attacks to steal trade secrets and intellectual property rights of our companies and institutions, and monitor the content of our citizens’ network communications for a long time. They also seriously infringe upon the legitimate rights and interests of our citizens and organizations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4e45429180f71bb35c1ff1b37ee0e262.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4e45429180f71bb35c1ff1b37ee0e262.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250756 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Environment&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Reduction of cyber attack and secret theft scenarios of foreign spy and intelligence agencies&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt; /a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[吼书、盲书、射书、乱书，哪种是真正的书法？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256848]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Wang Dongling has a notebook with &quot;dirty material&quot;. The notebook is filled with comments from netizens who &quot;spite&quot; him, such as &quot;Wang Dongling is a braggart&quot; and &quot;Wang Dongling has gone crazy...&quot; Wang Dongling opened the notebook, which contained both serious critical articles and vulgar abuse. &quot;When a compilation of information about me is printed in the future, all of this can be printed.&quot; Wang Dongling said with a smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/iEHpMrxz8zLzg2FWn0ChNAsStIgboEFTZZuRnxUS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;671&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/iEHpMrxz8zLzg2FWn0ChNAsStIgboEFTZZuRnxUS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250939&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In November 2016, Wang Dongling&#39;s calligraphy art solo exhibition opened at the Taimiao Art Museum in Beijing, and he was swiping at the scene. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Dongling is a calligrapher, but he is also happy to be called a calligrapher. modern artist. Rather than being praised by his peers, the &quot;chaotic books&quot; he created gained more from the incomprehension of ordinary audiences. Wang Dongling&#39;s &quot;chaotic calligraphy&quot; is not the first to be criticized for modern calligraphy, and it will certainly not be the last. In recent years, netizens have criticized Zeng Xiang&#39;s &quot;Roaring Book&quot;, Zhang Qiang&#39;s &quot;Blind Book&quot; and Shao Yan&#39;s &quot;Shooting Book&quot;... As the name suggests, when creating &quot;Roaring Book&quot;, Zeng Xiang was drunk. He seemed to be mad, roaring and yelling; when Zhang Qiang wrote, he didn&#39;t look at the brush and the writing object, and applied it by hand; Shao Yan filled the ink with a needle and sprayed the words on the rice paper, which can be said to follow the shape of the object... Popular opinion Not understanding these various new &quot;calligraphy&quot;, some people simply call them &quot;ugly calligraphy&quot;. In the newly released movie &quot;The Story of Yong&#39;an Town&quot;, the director who is good at ridicule pokes fun at the film industry, but also satirizes the &quot;Master of Shouting Books&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with them, Wang Dongling still looks like traditional calligraphy at least in the &quot;movements&quot; of his creation - but people still can&#39;t see clearly what he wrote in his &quot;random calligraphy&quot;. When I open a piece of Wang Dongling&#39;s &quot;chaos calligraphy&quot; work, I can see intersecting lines, like dead branches on the ground, and like swords fighting in chaos, but not a single clear and independent Chinese character can be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/x5vR2CmqqVYEed2yUX4uTTTlYb5NIYaqNd2Ilqkg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/x5vR2CmqqVYEed2yUX4uTTTlYb5NIYaqNd2Ilqkg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250938&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Dongling&#39;s &quot;Li Bai Poetic&quot; calligraphy installation was exhibited at the China Academy of Art Museum&#39;s &quot;Calligraphy·Not Calligraphy - 2019 International Modern Calligraphy Art Festival&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a social inscription scene, Wang Dongling asked the organizer with a sly smile, &quot;Do you want me to Should you write more messily or be more disciplined?&quot; The words to be inscribed were &quot;Art for a better life&quot;. The organizer nodded Weiwei and said, &quot;Be more disciplined, be more disciplined.&quot; Wang Dongling picked up the brush and thought for a moment. Several big words had already fallen on it. on paper. If you look carefully, you will see that the strokes of these characters are indeed much more &quot;regular&quot;, with some adhesion but little overlap. &quot;My characters are not very intertwined, but there is still some expressiveness in them.&quot; Wang Dongling told Southern Weekend the reporter said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Wang Dongling, Zeng Xiang, Shao Yan and Zhang Qiang can also write very &quot;proper&quot; characters. When the public laughs at them, few people ask why they give up &quot;proper&quot; writing. Calligraphy, doing these things that look like performance art? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/RwoyLDwCx3eScTYdhSSixPRJawmBEqWliHGpfpxU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;655&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/RwoyLDwCx3eScTYdhSSixPRJawmBEqWliHGpfpxU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250935&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Not all of Wang Dongling&#39;s works are in the form of &quot;chaotic calligraphy&quot;. The picture shows his works on display at the Zhejiang Art Museum in 2021. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Everyone has the desire to criticize and explain. I am now a target to let people have this desire. It looks good to me,&quot; Wang Dongling said. Nearly eighty years old, he seems to be in a good mood. He said that when he was young, he could not hear scolding, which would make him feel uncomfortable, but now he has become &quot;early&quot;, and he would sometimes laugh out loud when looking through the notebook with &quot;dirty information&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Breaking the &quot;Word Barrier&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wang Dongling has a thin figure, with dry white hair and messy hair. Sometimes she speaks in a breathless voice, and you have to get closer to hear it clearly. It was startling. If his voice is compared to a calligraphy work, then his layout is what Deng Shiru said: &quot;It can be sparse but airtight.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/XMW6phxDtMlF5HkI3kvGnoKS5L39KNQEgz0DBVNJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;673&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/XMW6phxDtMlF5HkI3kvGnoKS5L39KNQEgz0DBVNJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250937&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Dongling once presented Chinese cultural classics in the form of &quot;chaotic scripts&quot; and &quot;wall scripts&quot;. The picture shows the large-scale mirror wall book &quot;I Ching&quot; he exhibited in 2016. It is written on a stainless steel plate with white paint and is 32 meters long and 3.5 meters high. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first impression given by &quot;Chaoshu&quot; is its white cloth and unique composition. &quot;Zhangfa&quot; and &quot;Bubai&quot; are calligraphy terms, which refer to the arrangement, layout and mutual response between words and lines during the entire writing process. In traditional calligraphy works, the line spacing is roughly clear, and the strokes cannot cross between words. Even the continuous grass of the late Ming Dynasty will still generally abide by such rules. &quot;Look at Xu Wei&#39;s &quot;Ying Zhi Ying Sword&quot;, there are a few places where the strokes touch and cross, but it is not obvious.&quot; Wang Dongling zoomed in on Xu Wei&#39;s work on her mobile phone and kept zooming in until the complete picture could no longer be seen. Glyphs and dancing lines fill the entire phone screen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was a child, Wang Dongling observed an old tree in front of his teacher’s house, and the zigzag lines were imprinted in his memory. Later, he also looked at the trees in the American wilderness and found that the lines created by the vitality of the trees were different, but intersected harmoniously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every winter, he goes to see the dead lotuses on the West Lake. He has more than 20,000 photos of dead lotuses on his computer. Look at the dead lotus stems, scattered in all directions, seemingly chaotic, but there is an underlying order in the chaos. When the ideographic nature of Chinese characters is completely covered up - like the enlarged Xu Wei that makes it difficult to see what character it is, then only the lines of the Chinese characters are left in front of the viewer&#39;s eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the history of calligraphy, the &quot;overlapping&quot; of characters can be traced back to Yan Zhenqing&#39;s &quot;Seat Struggle&quot;, but that may be unconscious. When it came to Xu Wei, &quot;I think his calligraphy was intended to break the line spacing,&quot; Wang Dongling said. Later, Zheng Banqiao&#39;s calligraphy was called &quot;paving the streets with random stones.&quot; &quot;In fact, they all wanted to break the calligraphy and line spacing.&quot; &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Chaoshu&quot; is to push this &quot;break&quot; to the extreme. If you look at Wang Dongling&#39;s random writing process, every word he writes is actually in accordance with cursive writing (cursive, a calligraphy term, refers to the cursive writing rules of Chinese characters. The cursive writing of each character is roughly fixed and conventional). &quot;It&#39;s nothing more than an overlap.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When words overlap and strokes intertwine, the viewer cannot clearly see what is written. Therefore, the &quot;word barrier&quot; for Chinese people to read calligraphy is broken, and they can concentrate on feeling the lines. flow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/A8S5wOWaeRQwSuOfYRqzliYcZV6WtpKzCLP7BfPV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;663&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/A8S5wOWaeRQwSuOfYRqzliYcZV6WtpKzCLP7BfPV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250936&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2021, the 60-year exhibition of Wang Dongling&#39;s calligraphy art was held at Zhejiang Art Museum. The picture shows an audience staying in front of Wang Dongling&#39;s works. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Chinese people, when they look at a piece of calligraphy, they first of course want to understand what it says. , in Wang Dongling&#39;s opinion, is a &quot;writing barrier&quot;, which keeps many ordinary people away from the deeper beauty of calligraphy. Just like someone listens to his mother tongue and understands the meaning, but unconsciously ignores the beauty of the pronunciation. Only people who do not understand the language at all will notice the high and low pitch values ​​and the gentleness of the timbre when listening. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Calligraphy has developed over thousands of years. Traditional calligraphy has been very perfect and mature. It is difficult for you to break through at all.&quot; Wang Dongling said that calligraphy has two attributes, one is cultural attribute, and the other is cultural attribute. It is Chinese characters written by Chinese people, so we naturally want to understand it, &quot;There is nothing wrong with this&quot;, but another attribute of calligraphy is its artistic attribute. If you admit that it is an art, then it must Have personality and express the creator.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Chaotic script is the extension of ancient cursive script.” This is Wang Dongling’s own understanding of chaotic script. He puts his creation into the track of the ancients, “Of course my heart is not as wild as Xu Wei’s. , but you must have passion to write cursive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Can people who understand music learn calligraphy faster? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Walking into Wang Dongling’s studio, the floor is covered with all kinds of manuscript papers, rice paper, and albums. It can be said to be a “street full of paper.” This studio has received many foreigners who admired Chinese calligraphy. &quot;Professor Wang Dongling gave me my first calligraphy lesson.&quot; In 2015, Apple CEO Tim Cook said on Weibo. At that time, Cook visited Wang Dongling&#39;s studio, and Wang Dongling taught him to use Apple pencil to write the word &quot;goodbye&quot; with calligraphy strokes on the iPad. Prior to this, he was invited to Apple headquarters in California to provide professional calligraphy advice on the iPad’s writing capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Apple, this Weibo undoubtedly has a strong marketing temperament, but Wang Dongling does not reject invitations from other cultures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 1989, Wang Dongling went to give lectures at the University of Minnesota in the United States. What he brought with him was a large pen and the &quot;Longzang Temple Stele&quot; which he copied repeatedly. Wang Dongling still remembers the winter in Minnesota, when there was heavy snow outside the window, and his car was stuck deep in the snow, like an ink mark in the snow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Dongling’s English is very poor. In his own words, when he first arrived in the United States, he didn’t know all 26 letters. So far, I may only recognize 200 words. But he is very willing to exchange calligraphy with foreigners. In 1981, Wang Dongling received a master&#39;s degree in calligraphy from Zhejiang Academy of Fine Arts (now China Academy of Art) and stayed at the school to teach. At that time, Zhejiang Academy of Fine Arts was the only school in the country that majored in calligraphy, so the Ministry of Culture sent all international students studying calligraphy to Zhejiang Academy of Fine Arts. From then on, Wang Dongling took on the task of teaching calligraphy to international students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even now, many people still feel that it is impossible to teach Westerners to learn calligraphy. They do not understand ancient Chinese, and learning Chinese characters does not happen overnight. But Wang Dongling&#39;s teaching practice told him that this does not seem to be the case. &quot;They often make mistakes in stroke order and structure, and even write wrong words. But this is not a problem.&quot; In Wang Dongling&#39;s view, foreigners have overcome the &quot;writing barrier&quot; from the beginning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;British art historian Gombrich once concluded that the role of calligraphy in Chinese culture corresponds well with music in European culture. Wang Dongling&#39;s experience tells him that students who have previous musical accomplishments will learn faster. &quot;The form of cursive calligraphy art is a division of space by overflowing tension and irregular lines. This kind of space displayed after black and white processing is full of virtual reality and rhythmic changes, and it is a musical space.&quot; Wang Dongling said . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Internet celebrity &quot;Teacher Andy&quot; of Bilibili, who is now over seventy years old, has been working tirelessly to popularize Western classical music to the public on the Chinese Internet in recent years. His full name is Andreas Stier. German, he is a piano professor at the Hamburg State University of Music. He was once a student of Wang Dongling. Wang Dongling still remembers that in the 1980s, he took Andy Shi and several other international students to the home of Mr. Lu Yanshao. Mr. Lu Yanshao read the works of several foreign students in turn and saw the &quot;Silence&quot; in the &quot;Taishan Diamond Sutra&quot; written by Andy Shi. &quot;Chinese people have not been able to write at this level for a long time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1990, Wang Dongling was in the United States, watching various contemporary art and contemporary dances. Once, he watched an artistic performance by American middle school students. There were solo dances and group dances of three people. The children were twisting their bodies unscrupulously. &quot;Their body language made me feel that no matter how innovative Chinese calligraphy is, it should be allowed,&quot; he said. &quot;Wang Dongling said that graffiti, like dancing, is one of human instincts. &quot;The writing of Chinese characters has a strong graffiti nature. Calligraphy is a spiritual artistic product that combines human instincts with Chinese characters.&quot; And in Kuangcao. In &quot;Kang Cao&quot;, human instincts are released as much as possible. &quot;Kang Cao is greatly weakened from the constraints of ranks, providing a free world for the author to express space. In Kuang Cao, the writing, rhythm and rhythm of calligraphy are brought into full play.&quot; ”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Traditional calligraphy, Jianghu style, modern calligraphy&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although Wang Dongling looks thin, in the face of the physically demanding calligraphy, he can write the large-scale &quot;Thousand-Character Essay&quot; 》. It took four hours to write a random piece of &quot;The Thousand Character Essay&quot;. In Wang Dongling&#39;s own words, it was indeed improvised writing, but it was not a &quot;disordered accident, but a kind of muscle memory after years of training.&quot; And when writing, you should always pay attention to the connection between words and the overall layout. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qi Gong once said, &quot;Layout is very difficult.&quot; Layout has also become one of the criteria that distinguishes professional calligraphers from calligraphy enthusiasts generally known as &quot;Jianghu style&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Dongling&#39;s opinion, the current people who study calligraphy can be roughly divided into three types of people. One type is those who follow the traditional path, conscientiously write posts and monuments, and write &quot;good-looking&quot; characters according to traditional standards. This type of people is the cornerstone of calligraphy. The second category is the &quot;jianghu style&quot;. &quot;With the participation of all people now, there must be some people who are not good at basic skills but are eager for quick success and quick success. They attract people&#39;s attention but have no level. These people can be called &#39;jianghu style&#39;.&quot; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;There are also some people who want calligraphy to become a breakthrough modern art. Not only are there people like Wang Dongling who are making breakthroughs within calligraphy, but there are also people who are combining calligraphy with contemporary art such as installation, performance, and video. Some of the &quot;ugly books&quot; considered by the public come from the Jianghu style, and a large number of them come from this group. Wang Dongling also makes no secret that he belongs to the third category. Although his daily training is the same as that of traditional calligraphers, he also has to write calligraphy every day. &quot;In the final analysis, modern calligraphy is to express people&#39;s emotions. I am a firm supporter of modern calligraphy and Promoter&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Few people know that the establishment of the first calligraphy major in China actually came from the influence of modern calligraphy. After World War II, Japan regarded calligraphy as an art, engaged in modern calligraphy and avant-garde calligraphy, and attached great importance to the popularization of calligraphy education. In the early 1960s, Pan Tianshou went to Japan to study calligraphy and was deeply moved. He returned to Hangzhou and founded China&#39;s first calligraphy and seal cutting major at the Zhejiang Academy of Fine Arts with Sha Menghai, Lu Weizhao and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1979, Zhejiang Academy of Fine Arts was commissioned by the Ministry of Culture to recruit the first master&#39;s degree students in calligraphy in the country. Wang Dongling became a student of Sha Menghai, Lu Weizhao and other gentlemen, and was one of the first five masters of calligraphy in New China. In the autumn of 1980, Wang Dongling accompanied Mr. Sha Menghai to Beijing to see the original stone drum exhibition at the Palace Museum. I have read Han Yu&#39;s &quot;Song of the Stone Drum&quot;, seen the original rubbings of &quot;The Inscriptions on the Stone Drum&quot;, and read Wu Changshuo&#39;s &quot;The Inscription on the Stone Drum&quot;, but when I saw the original copy of the Stone Drum, &quot;Even if I don&#39;t look at the specific words, the kind of text that the Stone Drum carries The atmosphere of ancient times makes people deeply moved. This experience is the same as looking at the statue in front of Huo Qubing&#39;s tomb, which is very wonderful.&quot; In Wang Dongling&#39;s own memories, this trip to Beijing greatly shocked his artistic concepts. &quot;I feel that the highest state of calligraphy is far from the stability and exquisiteness of pointillism. What is more important is that lines can carry abundant vitality and inexhaustible vitality.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, Wang Dongling After returning to the United States, he began to devote himself to promoting and practicing modern calligraphy. Since then, he has been subjected to pressure and ridicule from all walks of life. At first, there were doubts from the professional calligraphy community. In recent years, the situation has reversed. The professional calligraphy community has turned to a positive evaluation of him, but the public in the Internet age has made an even harsher voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Dongling has some intuitive self-explanations to explain the creation process of chaos books to the public, such as Huai Su watching the peaks of summer with many strange clouds, Zhang Xu watching Gongsun Auntie dancing with a sword, Huang Tingjian watching the boatmen rowing, all enlightened He developed new calligraphy skills, and connected his random calligraphy with the residual lotus. When asked if this was an afterthought, he smiled and said, &quot;the two grew out of each other.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Zeng Xiang, the &quot;master of shouting&quot;, he likes to write big characters. When he writes, there are many onlookers - but Wang Dongling basically doesn&#39;t shout. When writing calligraphy, people are watching and cheering. This is also a tradition. When Zhang Xu writes cursive script, people often watch him. Jin Shengtan listed thirty-three joyful things in life, one of which is &quot;How wonderful it is to watch people write big books in a nest!&quot; He also hopes that people can enjoy calligraphy with the mood of &quot;It is wonderful&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Dongling supports the innovation of calligraphy as a modern art, but he seems quite hesitant about one question. A reporter from Southern Weekend asked him: &quot;Will the innovations of some young people with weak basic skills be successful?&quot; Will it be superficial? But if young people follow the tradition and practice to the state of &quot;old people and books&quot; as the ancients said, and then make innovations and breakthroughs, have they missed the best time in their lives? Is there any hidden meaning in this? Contradiction?&quot; For a person who is still enthusiastic about creation when he is nearly eighty years old, this may not be a problem. Wang Dongling paused for a long time and replied: &quot;Creation must have good basic skills. People with good basic skills should promote them. Create more.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“滑板女孩”“全盲男孩”，今年又有一批“特殊”的新生丨大学你好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256706]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-16 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[科学家揭开白牦牛身世之谜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256560]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/YDftAEy1DozqWbBA5Ic9L9oxcFRw1J1ejVXro2pU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/YDftAEy1DozqWbBA5Ic9L9oxcFRw1J1ejVX ro2pU. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250481&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Book of Mountains and Seas·Beishan Jing&quot; describes: &quot;On Panhou&#39;s Mountain... there is a beast, which looks like an ox and has hair on all four joints. It is called an ox.&quot; In ancient times, In Tibetan mythology, wild yaks are called &quot;stars&quot; in the sky, and white yaks are especially revered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Putting aside the veil of mystery, where did the white yak come from in reality? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both the black yak and the white yak are domesticated by humans from wild yaks. The wild yak is a first-level protected animal in China. Archaeologists have discovered bison and other ungulate fossils in the middle and late Pleistocene strata of the Quaternary about 3 million years ago. Wild yaks were once widely distributed in China. They can be seen everywhere in the Himalayas, Kunlun Mountains and Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. Nowadays, with human development, the distribution area of ​​wild yaks has rapidly shrunk and fragmented. They can only be found in the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, mainly living in the Qiangtang National Nature Reserve in Tibet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Domestic yaks were domesticated from wild yaks. From the past to the present, people have used molecular genetics knowledge, sequencing technology and other biological information methods to extract information from many species by combining morphological similarities with archaeological discoveries. This aspect reveals evidence of wild yak domestication. Professor Liu Jianquan from the School of Ecology of Lanzhou University constructed a complete yak genome structure variation map by studying the genome structure of 23 individuals of domestic yaks and wild yaks. He found that domestic yaks living in the alpine pastoral areas of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau at an altitude of 2,000-5,000 meters are descended from humans. It was domesticated 7,300 years ago from the wild yak that currently lives in the uninhabited area of ​​the northern plateau. At the same time, there are highly differentiated structural variations between domestic yaks and wild yaks, that is, structural variations that are subject to artificial selection during domestication. Domestication traits such as genes and nervous system development and behavior, as well as reproductive ability and immunity, are affected by selected structural variations. It is related to functions related to economic traits, providing a new perspective for understanding the genetic mechanism of yak domestication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The latest survey results of the National Livestock and Poultry Resources Committee in 2019 show that domestic yaks include 17 local breeds and 2 cultivated breeds, distributed in Gansu, Qinghai, Xinjiang, Yunnan, Tibet and Sichuan, and are affected by various Affected by regional geographical conditions, these yak breeds have also formed distinctive local characteristics in the long-term evolution. The most scientifically troubling mystery about these different domestic yaks is the mystery of coat color, especially when and where the white yak was produced. Is the spotted yak the result of a cross between a white yak and a black yak, or a cross with other cattle? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subsequently, Liu Jianquan’s team cooperated with researcher Yan Ping of the Lanzhou Institute of Animal Husbandry and Pharmacy of the Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and other research groups. Through nearly 30 years of field sampling, they completed the sampling of all varieties of domestic yaks and more than 20 wild yaks. The yak was sampled and complete DNA was successfully extracted for genome analysis, thereby constructing a genome map of the Bovine species. Research has found that after domestication, domestic yaks were crossed with another type of cattle. Nearly 90% of domestic yaks have genomic structural variations from cattle, accounting for about 1%-5% of all genomic structural variations. Cattle were domesticated from bison in the Near East and the Indus River Basin, and were brought to the Tibetan Plateau by humans no more than 4,000 years ago. The relevant research results &quot;Evolutionary origin of genomic structural variations in domestic yaks&quot; were recently published in the international academic journal &quot;Nature Communications&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is the genetic introgression from cattle that leads to the key genetic basis for phenotypic variation in different breeds of domestic yak. In layman&#39;s terms, within about two thousand years, the domestic yak and the flowered yak produced the flowered yak due to active or passive interspecific hybridization during the grazing process, and the flowered yak then produced the white yak through genetic mutation. This solved the mystery of the &quot;white yak&quot; that has troubled the scientific community. In addition to unraveling scientific mysteries, this study provides a new perspective on the improvement of yak breeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the closed breeding environment of yaks and the lack of communication between livestock species, as well as the impact of global climate change and the destruction of natural pastures by overgrazing, the living environment of yaks has deteriorated, and various yak breeds have developed different characteristics. degree of degradation. Therefore, hybrid improvement and breed selection of domestic yaks have become an important task. Although domestic yaks and wild yaks have varying degrees of differences in appearance, breeding methods, production performance and disease resistance, they are generally similar. The biggest difference is that wild yaks have significantly better disease resistance than domestic yaks. Respiratory diseases, parasitic diseases, pasteurellosis and other infectious diseases are common diseases in domestic yaks. Wild yaks are strong and resistant to stress. The weight and other indicators of the first generation of hybrid yaks bred using wild yaks are in line with the local conditions. Compared with domestic yaks of the same age, they were significantly enhanced. Existing research has found that the physique and meat production of domestic yaks in areas with wild yaks are significantly better than those in areas without wild yaks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yaks are an indispensable breed of cattle on the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau. In the future development of the yak industry, we should devote ourselves to the improvement and cultivation of domestic yaks, and use scientific research as technical support to deeply explore the genetic resource advantages of wild yaks. , vigorously improve the production performance of domestic yaks to bring greater economic benefits. As Professor Liu Jianquan said: &quot;In the era of gene editing and transgenics, interspecific hybridization should still be an important means of cultivating new varieties or even new species that adapt to climate change and human needs, but ideas and technologies must be innovative.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[触目惊心，这国洪灾已致1.1万多人丧生]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256772]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Hurricane &quot;Daniel&quot; made landfall on the Mediterranean coast of eastern Libya on September 10 and caused floods in Derna, Bey Caused a large number of casualties in Da, Shehat and other places. The Libyan Red Crescent said on the 14th that the hurricane and the floods it caused had killed more than 11,000 people in the city of Derna, and more than 10,000 people were missing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Libyan Red Crescent said that as of the 14th, the number of victims of the disaster in the severely affected city of Derna had reached 11,300, and another 10,100 people were missing. The mayor of Derna estimated that based on the damage, the final number of victims may be much higher than the announced number, &quot;reaching 18,000 to 20,000 people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/39ceec0cde570eb0b753d30b97ea7459.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1018&quot; height= &quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/39ceec0cde570eb0b753d30b97ea7459.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250927&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;This is the scene after the floods in the eastern Libyan city of Derna on September 11. Xinhua News Agency (Photo provided by the government appointed by the Libyan National Congress)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The road to Derna remains severely blocked due to destroyed roads and bridges, and power and communications interruptions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Within seconds, the water level suddenly rose.&quot; Agence France-Presse quoted an injured survivor as saying that he and his mother were swept away by the flood, and the two later managed to climb into an uninhabited building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The disaster was brutal,” said the International Committee of the Red Cross representative in Libya. “Seven-meter-high waves destroyed buildings and swept infrastructure into the sea.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/d18833f7814670ea893399ccf6c186ef.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1018&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/d18833f7814670ea893399ccf6c186ef.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250925&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;This is the scene after the floods in the eastern Libyan city of Derna on September 11. Xinhua News Agency (Photo provided by the government appointed by the National Congress of Libya)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Martin Griffiths, the United Nations Under-Secretary-General for Humanitarian Affairs, said that the scale of the disaster is shocking. &quot;Thousands of people have died, tens of thousands are homeless, and more people are missing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, rescue teams from Egypt, Tunisia, the United Arab Emirates, Turkey, Qatar and other countries Has arrived in Libya to assist the local government in disaster relief. Other countries have gradually joined the assistance operation or pledged to provide assistance. Global aid operations for Libyan floods are accelerating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/d95c21f75a21c28d26b6e2553d3ffbae.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1019&quot; height= &quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/d95c21f75a21c28d26b6e2553d3ffbae.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250926&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, staff moved aid supplies sent to Libya at a military airport in Amman, Jordan. Xinhua News Agency (photo by Mohammed Abu Gush)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Climate scientists believe that this disaster is related to global warming and Libya’s outdated infrastructure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, the United States and other Western countries intervened armedly in Libya to support the opposition to overthrow the regime of Muammar Gaddafi. Libya has been in political turmoil ever since. Due to years of war, Derna City has no unified central government management, old infrastructure, and weak flood control capabilities. At the time of the incident, there was neither a flood warning system nor an emergency evacuation plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中纪委一个月内通报20名 “内鬼” | 时政周报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256827]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/15/rblI2dlGiNsyfzAC9gfvyLrYbOOH7fqi8jQ0mPHh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;978&quot; height=&quot;572&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/rblI2dlGiNsyfzAC9gfvyLrYbOOH7fqi8 jQ0mPHh. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250928&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The issue of &quot;darkness under the lights&quot; has become the focus of disciplinary inspection and supervision agencies at all levels. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Interface News/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, 2023, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection once again reported information about the investigation of an &quot;insider&quot; , this is the sixth list of disciplinary inspection and supervision cadres suspected of serious violations of discipline and law notified by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection within a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The latest &quot;insider&quot; reported is Liu Lixian, former Party Committee member and Secretary of the Discipline Inspection Commission of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, who voluntarily surrendered. Public information shows that Liu Lixian was born in 1954. He served as deputy director of the Corruption and Bribery Prosecution Department of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, deputy director of the General Administration of Anti-Corruption and Bribery, director of the Procuratorial Technology Bureau, and director of the Procuratorial Theory Research Institute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, Liu Lixian officially joined the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and served as Secretary of the Discipline Inspection Commission of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China in October of that year. After that, Liu Lixian was appointed as the deputy leader of the 11th Central Inspection Team in June 2013, and worked successively in the State Sports General Administration, China Guodian Group Corporation, China First Heavy Machinery Group Corporation, Harbin Electric Group Corporation and other units. Inspections were conducted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This week, in addition to Liu Lixian, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection also reported information on four &quot;insiders&quot; on September 11. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiang Yuewen, member of the Standing Committee of the Bengbu Municipal Party Committee and Secretary of the Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection in Anhui Province, is one of them. His resume shows that Xiang Yuewen, who was born in 1973, has worked in Anhui for a long time and has served as Secretary of the Shucheng County Committee of the Communist Youth League, Secretary of the Lu&#39;an Municipal Committee of the Communist Youth League, and Magistrate of Huoshan County. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the release of this notice, on July 19, Xiang Yuewen’s name also appeared in an article on the WeChat public account of Anhui Discipline Inspection and Supervision. The article mentioned that he attended the Second Inspection Team of the Anhui Provincial Party Committee A work mobilization meeting was held to inspect Yuhui District and Huaishang District of Bengbu City, and specific requirements were put forward for cooperation in the inspection work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Ming, former deputy director of the Office of the Inspection Leading Group of the Shaanxi Provincial Committee and first-level inspector, Li Ren, leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Sichuan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection at Chengdu Institute of Technology, and former Standing Committee Member of the Jiangning District Committee of Nanjing City Yang Bin, the former secretary of the District Commission for Discipline Inspection, was also announced as a &quot;ghost&quot; together with Xiang Yuewen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Ming has worked for the Shaanxi Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection for a long time. In 2012, he attended the anti-corruption work conference in universities as the director of the Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Bin, who was born in Zhenjiang, Jiangsu, has worked in the disciplinary inspection and supervision system for a long time. His resume shows that since his employment, Yang Bin has served as deputy division-level discipline inspection and supervisor of the Discipline Inspection Commission of Nanjing Yanjiang Industrial Development Zone, deputy division-level discipline inspection and supervisor of the Second Office of Discipline Inspection and Supervision of the Nanjing Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection, director of the third office, secretary of the Discipline Inspection Commission of Nanjing Jiangning District, and district supervisor. Director of the Supervisory Committee, leader of the Nanjing Municipal Party Committee Inspection Team, etc. In January 2022, Yang Bin was transferred to deputy secretary of the Party Leadership Group and deputy prosecutor general of the Nanjing Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Ren, who holds a doctorate in law, is a cadre who came out of school and has only served in the disciplinary inspection system for a short time. After graduating from the Mathematics Department of Aba Teachers College in 1986, Li Ren stayed at the school and worked as deputy secretary of the Aba Teachers College Committee of the Communist Youth League. He later served as secretary of the Aba Teachers College Committee of the Communist Youth League, director of the Organization Department of the Party School of the Sichuan Provincial Committee, and assistant researcher. After 2005, Li Ren successively served as the director of the Audit Bureau of Suining City, secretary of the Shehong County Party Committee, and deputy mayor of Suining City. Until December 2019, he was transferred to the leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Sichuan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection in Chengdu Institute of Technology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back, in the past month, on August 23, August 25, August 29, and August 31, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection reported 15 people under investigation four times. News about the &quot;ghost&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 23, the largest number of people were notified, reaching 6 people. They were Jia Muquan, leader of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team of the Shanxi Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection in the Provincial Department of Civil Affairs, member of the Party Leadership Group of the Provincial Department of Civil Affairs, and the Second Inspection Inspector of the Guangdong Provincial Committee. Team leader Su Quangui, former deputy team leader of the Hainan Provincial Party Committee inspection team Wu Jie, former member of the Standing Committee of the Changzhou Municipal Party Committee and former secretary of the Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection Shen Bin, former secretary of the Xuchang Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and former director of the Municipal Supervision Commission Luo Jun, Hebei Province Geology and Mineral Exploration and Development Congratulations to the former first-level inspector of the bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Weiping, the former leader of the Discipline Inspection Team of the Henan Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection in the Provincial Public Security Department, was notified separately on August 25. In addition to the above-mentioned personnel, Han Taiguang, the former leader of the Hainan Provincial Party Committee’s inspection team, Yue Dechuan, the former leader of the 13th Inspection Team of the Shandong Provincial Party Committee, a former member of the party group of the Guizhou Provincial Department of Culture and Tourism, and the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team assigned by the Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection to the Provincial Department of Culture and Tourism Former team leader Jiang Zhilun, leader of Inspection Group Three of the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Party Committee Wang Liangshan, former deputy department-level discipline inspection inspector of Hubei Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection Ai Shaobin, Secretary of the Discipline Inspection Commission and Supervision Commissioner of Jilin Provincial Water Investment Group Co., Ltd. Liu Xiangyu, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of Harbin Red Cross Society , Executive Vice Chairman Liu Zhi, and Chen Gang, former member of the Party Committee of the Guizhou Provincial Public Security Department and former leader (department level) of the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Team assigned by the Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection to the Provincial Public Security Department, are also among the &quot;ghosts&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2023, the issue of &quot;darkness under the lights&quot; has become the focus of disciplinary inspection and supervision agencies at all levels. On September 9, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission issued a document stating that inspection and rectification should pay more attention to facing the problems head-on and being strict to the end. We should use hard work to identify problems, self-examination and self-correction, and clean up the door, resolutely eliminate the bad apples, and prevent &quot;lightning&quot;. &quot;Under the black&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 24, the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection published the &quot;Supervision, Inspection and Investigation of Discipline Inspection and Supervision Cadres in the First Half of 2023&quot;. The data shows that in the first six months of 2023, the national discipline inspection and supervision system received a total of More than 20,200 cases of clues and reports on issues involving disciplinary inspection and supervision cadres were handled, and more than 18,700 cases of clues on issues involving disciplinary inspection and supervision cadres were handled. 6,647 disciplinary inspection and supervision cadres were interviewed by letters of communication, 2,482 cases were filed, 1,647 people were punished, and 73 people were transferred to judicial organs. Among them, there are 54 cadres at the department and bureau level, and 123 people have been put on record for serious violations of disciplines and laws. Southern Weekend reporters noticed that the above data have almost doubled compared with the same period in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Personnel Trends&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【 Ministry of Justice, Ministry of Science and Technology , Ministry of Public Security leadership adjustment]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, 2023, the State Council released information on the appointment and dismissal of national staff, appointing Chen Jiachang as Deputy Minister of Science and Technology, and Hu Weili as Deputy Minister of Justice . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Jiachang was previously the director of the High-tech Department of the Ministry of Science and Technology, and Hu Weilie was previously a member of the Supreme Procuratorate Committee and director of the Eighth Procuratorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, the State Council released information on the appointment and removal of state workers, removing Liu Zhao from the post of deputy minister of the Ministry of Public Security. Liu Zhao was born in Fufeng, Shaanxi Province in December 1963. He once served as the director of the Traffic Management Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security, a member of the Party Committee and Director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security. In July 2020, he was appointed as the Deputy Minister of the Ministry of Public Security. &lt;p>; On the 13th, the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council held a press conference, and the new spokesperson Chen Binhua officially appeared to the media. At the beginning of the meeting, he greeted the reporters present in Mandarin and Hokkien. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public resume shows that Chen Binhua was born in 1971 and is from Zhao&#39;an, Fujian. Before becoming the spokesperson of the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council, he had more than 20 years of experience in media work. From 1993 to 2016, Chen Binhua worked at the Xinhua News Agency Headquarters and was one of the first mainland journalists to station in Taiwan. In April 2016, he was transferred to the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council and served successively as deputy director of the Maritime Research Center, deputy director of the Research Bureau, deputy director of the Economic Bureau, and first-level inspector. He currently serves as deputy director and first-level inspector of the Information Bureau of the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The former host of CCTV Wang Zhiren is the vice president of Minzu University of China]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently According to updated information in the &quot;School Leadership&quot; column on the official website of the University for Nationalities of China, Wang Zhi, a former CCTV host, has now become a member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee and Vice President of the University for Nationalities of China. According to public information, Wang Zhisheng was born in 1965. After graduating from university, he was assigned to Hunan Television and later entered CCTV. He served successively as reporter and host of the &quot;Son of the East&quot; column, reporter and host of &quot;Investigative News&quot;, and producer and host of &quot;Face to Face&quot; People, journalists. In October 2008, Wang Zhi took up a temporary position as the deputy mayor of Lijiang City, Yunnan and deputy director of the Information Office of the Yunnan Provincial Government. He was later transferred to the China Red Cross Foundation and served successively as secretary of the party branch of the foundation. In July 2012, Wang Zhi served as assistant to the president of Communication University of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Anti-Corruption Chronicle&lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ For accepting bribes of more than 325 million yuan, Wang Bin, the former chairman of China Life Insurance Company, was sentenced to suspended death in the first instance]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023, the Jinan Intermediate People’s Court ruled against the former chairman of China Life Insurance (Group) Company. The case of Party Secretary and Chairman Wang Bin for accepting bribes and concealing overseas deposits was publicly pronounced. Wang Bin was sentenced to death with a two-year suspended sentence, deprived of political rights for life, and confiscated all personal property. Wang Bin was sentenced to death with a two-year suspended sentence. After being commuted to life imprisonment in accordance with the law, he will be sentenced to life imprisonment without the possibility of commutation or parole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court found after trial that from 1997 to 2021, Wang Binli served as deputy secretary of the party group and deputy president of the Jiangxi Branch of the Agricultural Development Bank of China, president of the Beijing Branch of the Bank of Communications, and deputy banker of the Bank of Communications. Chairman, Chairman of BoCom International Trust Co., Ltd., Chairman of China Taiping Insurance, Chairman of China Life and Chairman of China Guangfa Bank, etc., directly or indirectly illegally received property equivalent to more than 325 million yuan in total. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Five managers of central enterprises accepted review and investigation]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 14 On the morning of the same day, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission issued a notice on the website stating that five managers of central enterprises were under review and investigation. The five people are Sun Honghong, deputy secretary of the Party Committee and general manager of China Energy Construction Group, Zhao Kun, former party secretary and deputy director of Huazhong Optoelectronic Technology Research Institute of China State Shipbuilding Corporation, Xiao Mingde, chairman of the supervisory board of China Grain Reserves Group Finance Co., Ltd., and former deputy director of Sinopec Natural Gas Branch. General Manager Wu Canqi, and Li Zhanping, former secondary business director of Jilin Electric Power Co., Ltd. of the National Energy Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[The director of a judicial office in Shanxi was suspended after his wife reported cheating]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;On September 13, the Judicial Bureau of Wenxi County, Yuncheng City, Shanxi Province issued a notice stating that after receiving relevant reports, Zhang, the director of the Judicial Office of Yangyu Town within the county&#39;s jurisdiction, had been suspended. According to Jiupai News, the whistleblower is Zhang’s wife. On September 11, Zhang’s wife posted a real-name video online reporting that her husband had cheated on her during their marriage and had committed domestic violence many times. The incident attracted widespread attention online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ministry and commission information&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development: Guarantee this year More than 70% of the task of raising and constructing affordable rental housing has been completed]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, 2023, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development stated that this year, 2.04 million units of affordable rental housing will be raised and constructed nationwide. )’s mission is currently 72% complete. The progress of financing and construction in Fuzhou, Ningbo, Shanghai and other cities is close to or has exceeded 80%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in the past two years, a total of 5.08 million units (rooms) of affordable rental housing have been raised and constructed in various places, with an investment of more than 520 billion yuan completed, which can be used to solve the housing difficulties of nearly 15 million new citizens and young people. question. The Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development also mentioned that it will continue to take multiple measures to expand the supply of affordable rental housing in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/W4wUsJhRJ2pAPCp4KwecE8rAx4s07AkmttufMLNq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;649&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/15/W4wUsJhRJ2pAPCp4KwecE8rAx4s07AkmttufMLNq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250930&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A construction site for prefabricated steel structure affordable housing in Ganzhou, Jiangxi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【二Joint notice from departments requires strengthening the standardized management of large-scale performances]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, the Ministry of Culture and Tourism and the Ministry of Public Security jointly issued a notice stating that they will further strengthen the regulation of large-scale commercial performances with more than 5,000 people. Standardized management of activities. The notice pointed out that large-scale performance events implement a real-name ticket purchase and admission system. Only one ticket can be purchased with a single ID card for each performance. The ticket purchaser must keep the identity information of the person attending the event; the organizer should establish a refund mechanism. Set reasonable tiered refund fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs: Organize three provinces and one city in Donghai District to severely crack down on illegal fishing]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In order to implement the requirements of the Central Committee’s No. 1 document and strictly implement the fishing moratorium system and implement the national marine summer fishing moratorium system, from September 10 to 11, the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs mobilized fisheries from three provinces and one city, Zhejiang, Fujian, Jiangsu, and Shanghai. The Chinese government and law enforcement forces dispatched 6 law enforcement boats and 132 law enforcement personnel of the China Fishery Administration to launch a surprise joint law enforcement operation to collect nets in a unified manner. It is reported that the law enforcement operation captured a total of 20 suspected illegal fishing vessels (including 3 fishing vessels), 216 people involved, and seized more than 10,000 boxes of catches (about 200 tons). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Rule of Law Report&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Supreme Procuratorate, Ministry of Public Security Initiate the joint listing and supervision of the third batch of five extremely serious cross-border telecommunications network fraud cases]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate and the Ministry of Public Security announced that they will jointly supervise the handling of the third batch of five extremely large cross-border telecommunications fraud cases. Internet fraud criminal cases. These five cases are the &quot;9·6&quot; telecom network fraud case in Putian, Fujian, the &quot;5·11&quot; telecom network fraud case in Shapingba, Chongqing, the &quot;6·16&quot; telecom network fraud case in Jiangyin, Jiangsu, and the &quot;8·26&quot; telecom network fraud case in Wenzhou, Zhejiang. Telecom network fraud case, Sichuan Leshan “1·12” telecom network fraud case. &lt;p>; p>; According to the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate on September 13, in May 2020, the mandatory reporting system for cases of violations of minors was officially launched, playing an important role in promptly discovering crimes, stopping crimes, rescuing minors, and protecting the legitimate rights and interests of minors. . Data show that in the past year, the number of mandatory reports of violations of minors has increased significantly. The average number of monthly reports has increased from 140 in the same period in 2022 to 280 in 2023, a significant increase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme People’s Procuratorate introduced that in the next step, the procuratorial organs will strengthen the accountability for failure to fulfill mandatory reporting obligations through “case-by-case back-investigation” and further consolidate the reporting responsibilities of relevant units and personnel. &lt;p>; >;The Eighth Ministerial Meeting on Cooperation in Combating Crime between the Ministries of Public Security of China and Vietnam was held in Beijing on September 13. The meeting was co-chaired by Wang Xiaohong, Secretary of the Secretariat of the CPC Central Committee and Minister of Public Security, and Su Lin, Member of the Political Bureau of the CPV Central Committee and Minister of Public Security of Vietnam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the meeting, Wang Xiaohong and Su Lin jointly signed a memorandum of understanding on cooperation between China and Vietnam in combating cross-border gambling. Wang Xiaohong mentioned that since the seventh China-Vietnam Ministerial Conference on Cooperation in Combating Crime in 2021, the Ministry of Public Security of China and Vietnam have cooperated successfully in many fields such as chasing fugitives, recovering stolen goods, and combating human trafficking. China is willing to work with Vietnam to deepen the implementation of political security, network security, etc. cooperation. Su Lin said that Vietnam is willing to strengthen high-level law enforcement exchanges between the two countries, deepen law enforcement cooperation in various fields, and create a safe and stable social environment for the development of their respective countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Science and Education News&lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【 There are more than 15,000 technology business incubator institutions in China]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 10, 2023, the High-Quality Incubator Development Forum was held in Baoshan, Shanghai. At the meeting, He Defang, deputy secretary-general of the Ministry of Science and Technology, introduced that by the end of 2022, China had more than 15,000 technology business incubator institutions of various types, forming a chain-type technology entrepreneurship service system of nurseries, incubators, accelerators, and technology parks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Defang mentioned that in 2022, various incubation institutions across the country will serve nearly 680,000 start-ups and teams, creating more than 5 million jobs. It is reported that technology companies that have emerged from incubators in recent years have accounted for 40% of the total number of hard technology companies on the Science and Technology Innovation Board. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Sichuan released 3255 postdoctoral positions, with scientific research funding up to 7 million per year]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Sichuan Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security released information on postdoctoral recruitment requirements for postdoctoral establishments in Sichuan in 2024. A total of 192 establishments participated, and 3,255 postdoctoral positions were announced. The number of positions increased by 4.7% compared with 2022. %. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the recruiting units, key industrial fields account for a large proportion, such as biomedicine, new materials, integrated circuits, artificial intelligence, clinical medicine, biology, materials science and engineering, etc. There is a large demand for talents. The quantity accounts for more than 60%. At the same time, each station unit has launched corresponding policies to attract advantages. The average salary is 250,000-300,000 yuan per year, with a maximum of 800,000 yuan per year, and the maximum scientific research project funding is 7 million yuan per year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Local political situation&lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[ Temporary residence registration for Taiwan compatriots in Fujian has been cancelled]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency on September 12, 2023, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;About Supporting Fujian to Explore New Paths for Cross-Strait Integrated Development and Build Cross-Strait Integration&quot; Opinions on the development of demonstration areas. The opinion pointed out that Fujian, as the first home for Taiwanese compatriots and Taiwanese enterprises, will take the lead in canceling the temporary residence registration of Taiwanese compatriots in Fujian, encourage Taiwanese compatriots to apply for Taiwan resident residence certificates, expand the scope of application of Taiwan resident residence certificates for identity verification, and strive to realize the realization of Taiwan residents’ residence permit. The ID card is as convenient for social use as the mainland resident ID card. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[108 Zhejiang companies were shortlisted for the top 500 private enterprises in China, ranking first in number for 25 consecutive years]&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;On September 12, the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce released the &quot;Top 500 Chinese Private Enterprises in 2023&quot; list. A total of 108 Zhejiang companies were shortlisted, ranking first this year. The second, third and fourth places were Jiangsu , Shandong, Guangdong. This is the 25th consecutive year that Zhejiang Province ranks first among all provinces in the country in terms of the number of shortlisted companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Zhejiang Provincial Industry and Commerce, the total revenue of these 108 Zhejiang shortlisted companies is 8.7 trillion yuan, total assets are 7.94 trillion yuan, and after-tax net profit is 322.3 billion yuan. Among them, 42 are in Hangzhou. There are 20 companies in Ningbo, 12 companies in Shaoxing, and 10 companies in Wenzhou, and 83.3% of the companies have increased operating income compared with 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;[Shandong releases new policy for unannounced inspections of production safety]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Emergency Management Department 9 According to news on March 13, the Shandong Provincial Work Safety Commission recently issued the &quot;Shandong Provincial Production Safety Undercover Inspection System&quot; to clarify the principles, leading units, methods, contents, procedures, requirements, etc. of production safety undercover inspections (hereinafter referred to as unannounced inspections). , making the unannounced inspection system a normalized work measure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;System&quot;, unannounced inspections refer to going straight to the grassroots level and going directly to the scene without giving prior notice, saying hello, listening to reports, accompanying or receiving reception, and conducting surprise inspections, random inspections, and &quot;turning back&quot; See how review works. Undercover inspections are carried out on a regular and irregular basis. In accordance with the principle of combining daily inspections with unannounced inspections, the frequency of unannounced inspections is increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;Voice&lt;/strong>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;【国Taiwan Affairs Office spokesperson Chen Binhua: Taiwan is not eligible to join the United Nations]&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council held a regular press conference. At the meeting, the new spokesperson Chen Binhua answered reporters’ questions regarding the Taiwan authorities’ recent proposal to urge the United Nations to amend UN General Assembly Resolution 2758. Chen Binhua said that the United Nations is an intergovernmental international organization composed of sovereign states. Taiwan is part of China, not a country, and is not eligible to join the United Nations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resolution 2758 was adopted by the 26th United Nations General Assembly in 1971. The resolution decided to restore all legal rights of the People&#39;s Republic of China in the United Nations and made it clear that representatives of the government of the People&#39;s Republic of China are China&#39;s only legal representatives in the United Nations, so that there will be no problems of &quot;two Chinas&quot; and &quot;one China, one Taiwan.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Comprehensive from Jiupai News, Xinhua News Agency, the Supreme People’s Procuratorate WeChat official account, the official website of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, the official website of the Ministry of Public Security, Agriculture and Rural Affairs Ministry official website, CCTV News, Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development official website, Sichuan News Network, The Paper, Beijing News, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国新金融竞争力榜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256721]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Benchmarking is the best state and core consideration for business competition. Finance is the blood of the economy, affecting the whole body. What should be special about its benchmark? In order to highlight the commonality of financial benchmarks, the research team of Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center spent more than four months to build a scientific and rigorous evaluation index system, and used the 2022 financial report as the benchmark value, following the principle of openness and fairness, to select &quot; China’s New Financial Competitiveness Ranking”. This list is divided into six sub-lists: &quot;Wealth Management List&quot;, &quot;Green Finance List&quot;, &quot;Digital Finance List&quot;, &quot;Data Security List&quot;, &quot;Life Insurance Efficiency Improvement List&quot; and &quot;Credit Card Quality and Efficiency List&quot;.</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[教师的主业是教书育人，而不是攒论文]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256673]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, I had a dinner with several fellow villagers. A physical education teacher who works in a primary school in Guangzhou expressed his difficulties to me. He works diligently and conscientiously. More than 20 years have passed, but he still cannot be awarded a senior professional title because he has no grasp of thesis writing and has never published a scientific research paper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experience of fellow students is not unique. Many primary and secondary school teachers, especially older teachers, were turned away during the professional title review process because they did not complete the basic requirements for writing scientific research papers, regardless of their teaching years. How long it has been, how rich the teaching experience is, and how many outstanding students it has trained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A journal editor friend of mine told me that her professional title evaluation was based on the editing sequence, but the evaluation indicators were basically the same as those of scientific researchers. In other words, the relevant parties&#39; performance evaluation is based on the same as that of a full-time scientific researcher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to the experiences of teachers, there are doctors and people in other fields. For example, doctors also have basic requirements for scientific research papers or scientific research projects during the professional title evaluation process. They are busy treating diseases and saving people, and have no time to write papers, or are unable to complete papers. When the time comes for professional title evaluation, they are often at a loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An agricultural expert may have rich practical experience in agriculture. After years of exploration and practice, he and his team have cultivated improved seeds, greatly increased grain output, and significantly increased grain productivity. He has trained many outstanding talents, but perhaps he still has an intermediate professional title simply because he is old and does not have or is not good at writing and publishing papers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, writing papers and applying for projects have become prerequisites for the evaluation of professional titles for most professional and technical personnel. Without a paper of a certain weight and a project of a certain level, you cannot be promoted to a professional title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are several basic problems here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, papers and projects have become the most important factors in the assessment and evaluation mechanism of practitioners in many industries. Is this reasonable? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Common sense tells us that a teacher’s primary duty is to teach and educate people so that students can grow and thrive healthily; a doctor’s primary duty is to treat illnesses and save people, and relieve patients from their illnesses. Compared with publishing papers or applying for projects, teaching or saving people are the most important things for teachers or doctors. It is really difficult and unnecessary to ask every teacher to be good at doing scientific research and writing papers, to ask every doctor to be good at doing scientific research and writing papers, and to ask every agricultural expert to write papers and submit projects. In other words, if you put the importance of writing papers and applying for projects above teaching, saving people, and taking root in the field, you are literally putting the cart before the horse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, since papers and topics should not be the most important indicators, why are they most frequently adopted in various personnel assessment and evaluation mechanisms? This is mainly due to the advantages of quantification. Generally speaking, for the assessment of a person, quantitative indicators are generally better than qualitative indicators. The former can eliminate subjective factors such as favors or relationships to a certain extent, that is, by counting the number of published papers and the level of journals, the level of applied topics and Funding is used to determine a person&#39;s professional level. As the main basis for professional title evaluation, it is relatively fair and fair, and it is relatively simple to operate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, are published papers or successfully applied topics necessarily very good? Can it truly reflect the scientific research ability or professional level of the person concerned? Not really. Many teachers are busy with daily teaching, or are not familiar with the routine of writing papers due to their old age. Many doctors are busy with heavy work and have no time to write papers. What should I do? Some people can only temporarily hire gunmen to write their papers and buy space to publish them. There are even “paper processing factories” and “paper gunmen” emerging one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The result is that fake and shoddy papers are flying all over the place. Even if many papers are published, the authors themselves are too lazy to pay attention to them, and either shelve them or abandon them. Many papers are completed behind closed doors in the office, that is, mainly by purchasing data, constructing models, copying and pasting, and revising and revising. As for the relationship between the theoretical contribution of the paper and its practical value, and the relationship between the paper and one&#39;s own field of expertise, it is not important. What is important is that the article has been put into print. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same way, the funds applied for for many projects are not small, ranging from several million to tens of millions, but they are of little help in solving major issues in China&#39;s comprehensive modernization process, and they are not very helpful in promoting this discipline. There are very few major theoretical innovation contributions in the field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fourth, what is a good paper or a good topic? Yu believes that a good topic or paper must originate from real production and life practices, must be combined with real production and life practices, and must undergo careful and rigorous exploration, investigation and research, or fill a certain research field. The blanks will either play a positive role in promoting human understanding and revealing the truth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course qualified teachers are encouraged to write papers, but the direct or main purpose of writing papers is to improve the quality of teaching, not to complete requirements, let alone write empty and irrelevant articles that have nothing to do with their own teaching. Boring garbage article. As a teacher, the topic or focus of the paper or topic should mainly focus on teaching, such as the discussion of teaching methods, the improvement of teaching forms, the summary of teaching experience, the design of teaching models, etc. As a doctor, the topic or focus of his paper or project should mainly originate from or be inspired by his own medical treatment process. The paper or project should be conducive to the fundamental alleviation or solution of a difficult and complicated disease and contribute to the practical improvement of medical treatment. It plays a practical role in improving patient treatment efficiency and fundamentally improving human health conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant parties need to re-examine and seriously reflect on the concrete meaning of the four words &quot;people-oriented&quot;: schools are places to cultivate talents, &quot;people-oriented&quot; should be student-oriented, and teachers&#39; primary responsibility is to make students healthy Growth and vigorous development; the hospital is a place where diseases are treated and patients are saved. &quot;Humanism&quot; is based on the patient, and the doctor&#39;s primary responsibility is to relieve the patient&#39;s pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the assessment and evaluation of relevant practitioners, the overall principle is to allow most people to return to their main business or first business, give full play to their strengths, and fundamentally change or optimize the current KPI assessment system in all walks of life. inappropriate or unreasonable elements, moderately or significantly reduce the proportion of papers or topics; implement different assessment methods and details for different types of practitioners, including paper or topic assessments and practical ability assessments, rather than the current relative The prevailing one-way street of only essays or only topics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 19:25:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《横琴方案》发布两周年，数读成绩单丨一图读懂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256710]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;72646&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69538&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/b21efb4423.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;Second Anniversary of the Hengqin Plan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height=&quot;8301&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/b21efb4423.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250814&quot; style=&quot; &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在“被强奸”漩涡中挣扎八天后，一位44岁农妇选择自杀]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256716]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The old house hidden under the trees, Yi Yonghong&#39;s self-report of being &quot;raped&quot; The place where the incident occurred. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/821c2f3b8c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height =&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/821c2f3b8c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250822&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house hidden under the trees is where the &quot;rape&quot; incident described by Yoshinaga Hong took place. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 23, 2023, Yi Yonghong decided to commit suicide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She placed the suicide note on the plastic stool at the head of the bed, and her purse and mobile phone, which she never left, were neatly placed beside the bed. The purse contained more than 3,000 yuan in cash. She locked the door and ignored the clothes in the washing machine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I&#39;m leaving. I don&#39;t know what I can do to make you less hurt... I don&#39;t ask you to forgive me. I just hope that you can live a happy life and forget that I am a bad wife and mother.&quot; .&quot; She said in her suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To commit suicide, she chose a mile away. She had to pass through a large guava field. The unripe fruits wrapped in white plastic bags were hung all over the orchard. They were the fruits of her summer. The guava tree is not high, so you have to bend down when walking through it, and you have to cross a drainage ditch in three to five steps. The last section of the road is a slope about two meters high. Climb up and you will reach the embankment. A wide pond with a wide water surface slowly unfolds in front of you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The embankment is covered with mimosa, lush and green. The pair of pink slippers were neatly placed on the steps by Yi Yonghong, with the toes facing the pond. A few hours later, her husband Cheng Shanzhi discovered her. She was wearing a red top and floating in a prone position in the middle of the pond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight days before committing suicide, at the age of 44, she reported that she was raped by fruit vendor Huang Mouguan. The police decided not to file the case because the existing evidence could not prove that a crime had occurred. After committing suicide, the police decided to open a case for investigation on September 7 because &quot;new evidence was discovered.&quot; In order to prove that she was raped, she was preserved in an ice coffin and underwent a craniotomy and a thoracotomy for an autopsy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Misfortune in the banana fields&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Typhoon Taili is approaching. Before the violent storm arrived, Yi Yonghong had to cut down more than 20 acres of plantains at home. Nine years ago, this couple from Yongzhou, Hunan, planted fruits on a contracted land in Wenchang, Hainan. Now the contracted land covers nearly 50 acres, half of which is planted with bananas and the other half with guava. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong’s WeChat chat records show that on the evening of July 14, she and Huang Mouguan finalized the time to harvest bananas the next day. Huang Mouguan opened a fruit wholesale stall near the busiest park in Wenchang, and would go to fruit farmers&#39; homes to buy fruit. In the Wenchang area, most of the fruit growers are outsiders who have crossed the Qiongzhou Strait to make a living, and most of the fruit vendors are Hainan locals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong rarely goes out in public to sell bananas, and spends most of his time working in the banana fields. In early 2023, Yi Yonghong&#39;s husband Cheng Shanzhi started doing business with Huang Mouguan after being introduced by a fellow villager. By the time the incident occurred, he had sold bananas to him five times in total, with a transaction volume of 1,480 yuan. The first two times, Cheng Shanzhi cut down plantains and traded them with Huang Mouguan. Because her husband&#39;s left ankle was severely cut due to an accident, Yi Yonghong took over the job of cutting plantains for the next three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was these three experiences of selling bananas alone that pushed Yi Yonghong&#39;s life to a point of no return. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The banana land contracted by Yi Yonghong and his wife is not close to the village where she rents, and it takes half an hour by electric bicycle. In 2014, they built a shelter house using hollow bricks next to the plantain field. There was no other house within a radius of 200 meters. When we moved out in 2022, there was only a guard dog and a few free-range chickens left there. The unused old house began to fall into dust and became desolate. There was no longer a fire in the kitchen, and no one could sleep on the bed. Except for resting when working, Yi Yonghong rarely came here. The airtight trees almost swallowed up the small house. house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The old house at the crime scene. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ c5d8bd5bd3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/c5d8bd5bd3.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;250823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old house at the crime scene. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time Yi Yonghong took over for her husband who injured his foot and cut bananas alone with Huang Mouguan was on July 2. To cut bananas, vendors usually go to the fields to select the bananas, and the farmers carry them to the field, where they are finally weighed and loaded onto trucks. Yi Yonghong seems to particularly like pink. She has a short-sleeved shirt of this color, which she wears specially when working. Her right shoulder is covered with dark green glue marks from banana. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong later told her husband that that time, Huang Mouguan took the opportunity to help her carry the banana on his shoulders and touched her breasts. He also said to her: &quot;Don&#39;t do such hard work, I will give you money.&quot; Yi Yonghong refused him: &quot;Don&#39;t say this, we are doing hard work to earn hard money, I am not that Plant people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No more evidence can be obtained for what happened in the banana field. Other merchants next to Huang Mouguan&#39;s fruit shop said they had not seen him for more than a month after the incident. On the afternoon of September 2, Huang&#39;s wife was selling fruit at a stall next to the shop. She was emotional and refused to be interviewed: &quot;You don&#39;t know how much impact they have on our lives. I am under great pressure.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A week later, the bananas had to be picked again. Yi Yonghong and Huang Mouguan met again in the deserted banana field with wild vegetation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of meeting seems inevitable: Yoshinaga chooses to endure it, and there are only three &quot;basho bosses&quot; working with them at the same time. One is a very old man who walks a little shaky, and the other boss does not The last one who came to purchase was Huang Mouguan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his wife’s account to Cheng Shanzhi, Huang Mouguan once again committed inappropriate behavior. After the attempt, Huang Mouguan gave Yi Yonghong an additional 100 yuan in addition to the 470 yuan in banana money, “My wife just Throw it back to him without asking for it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third time was two days before the typhoon arrived. Cheng Shanzhi said that on July 15, Yi Yonghong arrived at the banana field at the agreed time and selected, cut off the backs, weighed and loaded the bananas. After paying the money, a heavy rainstorm suddenly fell from the sky in the afternoon. Yi Yonghong told Huang Mouguan, who had a canopy installed on the car, that he did not have a raincoat and would wait until the rain stopped before leaving, so he asked him to go first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Yi Yonghong entered the house and sat on the bed that she had not slept on for nearly a year to take shelter from the rain. In the subsequent report, Yi Yonghong said that she was raped at that time. Afterwards, Huang Mouguan left 150 yuan and ran away. Two days later, she told her husband that she felt a little uncomfortable after drinking the honey chrysanthemum tea handed to her by Huang Guan that day. She didn&#39;t know whether it was because of the heat stroke or the chrysanthemum tea, but she felt dizzy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Husband and daughter’s questioning&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If her husband hadn’t found out, Yi Yonghong originally planned to let these things rot in her stomach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decision to &quot;hide it&quot; is not difficult to make. In the subsequent live recording of the two parties’ contact, Yoshinaga stated that she was worried that if she told her husband what had happened, he would definitely retaliate against him and eventually harm his two children. “I just want to protect this family.” Cheng Shanzhi added that his wife had other considerations, such as the fact that the other party was rich and powerful and she was a wandering migrant; another example was that she was &quot;raped&quot; at the age of 44, which was &quot;disgraceful.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong has been covering up the traces of being &quot;raped&quot;. Huang Mouguan forced her to go to bed for the first time. When Yi Yonghong broke away and ran away, her inner thighs were red. When her husband asked, she lied that it was scratched on her back. After the incident, Yi Yonghong fell three times while riding her bike home. After returning home, Cheng Shanzhi saw that she was unhappy, but she didn&#39;t suffer any injuries, so he didn&#39;t take it to heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But on the night of the incident, Yi Yonghong asked her husband to sleep in her daughter&#39;s spare room, which made Cheng Shanzhi feel something was wrong. After 23 years of marriage, they rarely sleep in separate beds. Later, Yi Yonghong explained to her husband that the reason for dividing the room was that she didn&#39;t know whether Huang Guan was sick and was afraid of infecting him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how much his wife wanted to hide it, Cheng Shanzhi, who was full of doubts, discovered the clues the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As usual, Cheng Shanzhi rides to the banana patch every morning to feed the guard dog. When he opened the door, he found that the pillows on the bed had been touched, and only a small roll of paper towels was left in a large roll that had not been used for a long time. Cheng Shanzhi &quot;immediately suspected that this might happen.&quot; He didn&#39;t buy any groceries, so he hurried to his home in Sanpaipo Village and asked his wife what happened yesterday, but the answer he got was &quot;nothing happened.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi felt that the roll of paper towels was strangely lacking. He thought that he and his wife would use paper towels to wipe after sex, so he continued to press. Until late at night, after questioning still yielded no results, he called his daughter who was working in Haikou during the summer vacation, hoping that her daughter could ask him something. At first, her 22-year-old daughter Cheng Haiyan didn&#39;t believe what her father said, but she felt that he was very angry on the phone. She still called her mother and asked, &quot;Have you been bullied by others?&quot; and &quot;Have you done anything like that with others?&quot; Yi Yonghong was silent and crying on the phone for a long time. After asking the two questions several times in turn, Yi Yonghong finally relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Yi Yonghong&#39;s daughter returns to her banana field. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/4e271c4134.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4e271c4134. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250824&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yi Yonghong’s daughter returned to her family’s banana field. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After listening to his wife’s story, Cheng Shanzhi was very angry. He was angry about why his wife didn’t tell him. If he had told him the first or second time, there would have been no such thing. What happened next. He also couldn&#39;t understand why this kind of thing could happen to him. &quot;If you tell me, your body will not be obtained by others. This is the place that hurts my heart the most. I feel that my wife will be mine for life and cannot be shared with others.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;His wife kept it secret for many times, which made Cheng Shanzhi wonder whether she had been &quot;raped&quot; or cheated on her. That night, Cheng Shanzhi, who had never touched his wife before, slapped Yi Yonghong on the forearm. &quot;Am I still sorry to you in this life? I depend on you for everything, and you are in charge of the money. How do you want me to treat you?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I know that no one would believe that something like this happened. If you don’t understand, I can’t even defend myself,” Yi Yonghong said in her suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reconciliation and alarm&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On July 17, Typhoon Taili was getting closer and stronger, and a storm was imminent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That morning, Cheng Shanzhi called Huang Mouguan and asked him to come to his home. He wanted to confront the other party face to face and also wanted to take revenge on the other party. At almost noon, Huang Mouguan came to the door carrying a box of Wong Lo Kat. Cheng Shanzhi opened a switchblade more than ten centimeters long and hid it in his pants pocket. When Yi Yonghong found out, he hugged him and told him not to do stupid things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first time that the three of them are present at the same time, and it is also the last time. Southern Weekend reporters heard from the live recording at the time that it was not so much a confrontation between two parties, but rather that the three people had their own concerns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi did not forgive his wife, and said to her angrily: &quot;As long as you get along with him, it&#39;s your own business.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong sometimes shouted hoarsely, He scolded Huang Mouguan: &quot;I can&#39;t protect myself now. I thought you were a very serious person. I&#39;m asking you, why do you want to mess with me? Why don&#39;t you mess with others.&quot; Sometimes he is powerless and self-pitying: &quot;Anyway It’s all my fault, and it doesn’t matter if I die. I have nothing now, and I don’t know where to go.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Originally, Huang Mouguan was supposed to be the target of the crime, but he was like “ &quot;Peacemaker&quot;, while urging the two to live a good life, he agreed to the settlement plan and said to Cheng Shanzhi: &quot;I will give you 10,000 yuan, and we will be settled, and nothing will happen. We are all good brothers.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi said that Huang Mouguan wrote a note on the spot: &quot;I had sexual relations with Yi Yonghong, and now I will compensate Yi Yonghong&#39;s husband for mental loss of 10,000 yuan.&quot; He signed Huang Mouguan&#39;s name. He took out 6,000 yuan in cash and transferred 4,000 yuan via WeChat. But Cheng Shanzhi did not accept the money. He followed his daughter&#39;s advice, called the police and handed the note to the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan listened to the reconciliation via phone. She did not agree with this settlement plan. In addition to the risk of the other party suing for extortion, she also wanted Huang to apologize to his mother and even wanted him to go to jail. &lt;p>; .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/68115a27c2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/14/68115a27c2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 17, Huang The Wang Laoji that Guan brought with him during the reconciliation is still in Yi Yonghong&#39;s home. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in retrospect, Cheng Haiyan always felt that asking her father to call the police was a bit excessive. &quot;(The family) did not communicate well, so they called the police right away.&quot; In fact, the night before Huang Mouguan came to reconcile, Cheng Haiyan filed a complaint to the police, but Yi Yonghong kept crying and said that there was no evidence and the other party would not admit it. Cheng Haiyan believes that even if she fails to win in the end, she still wants Huang Mouguan to apologize to restore her mother&#39;s reputation. &quot;The other party has always wanted to use money to settle the matter. I think no matter how poor we are, we can&#39;t let you bully us like this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan tried to call Huang Mouguan to &quot;collect evidence&quot;, but every time he said When it comes to key issues, the other party will say, &quot;Don&#39;t talk about this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult to tell whether the public reporting to the police was more difficult for Yi Yonghong to accept than being &quot;raped&quot;. On the evening of July 17, Typhoon Taili landed in Wenchang, bringing heavy rain and strong winds to Bajiao. At this time, Yi Yonghong, Cheng Shanzhi, and Huang Mouguan were being questioned at the police station. Cheng Shanzhi heard that Yi Yonghong had been crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To the surprise of the couple, on the afternoon of July 18, the day after the alarm was called, Huang&#39;s wife, son, daughter, sister, and brother-in-law came to their home with the intention of reconciling. The &quot;lawyer&quot; daughter in Huang&#39;s mouth told Yi Yonghong that words of discord would be unpleasant to hear in the future, and would also have a bad impact on her daughter who is currently in school. Cheng Haiyan didn&#39;t know what else she said to her mother, which made Yi Yonghong feel that her daughter didn&#39;t understand the law. She called her daughter and asked, &quot;Do you understand the law or not?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi refused to reconcile. Later, the other party&#39;s attitude began to change. Cheng Shanzhi said that Huang&#39;s wife threatened them and humiliated Yi Yonghong, &quot;wanting to give her husband to her.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The crying collapse&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the incident to the two failed reconciliations, to calling the police and being questioned, Yi Yonghong is being pushed to the edge of the cliff little by little. Cheng Haiyan said frankly that her family did not take much care of her emotions at that time, and also ignored the understanding and companionship she needed more. But to Cheng Haiyan at that time, her mother&#39;s behavior was &quot;everything was normal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yoshiyong Hong’s collapse may have started with a hysterical cry. At around 5 a.m. on July 19, Cheng Haiyan was woken up by her mother&#39;s cry. My mother had cried before, always while lying on the bed covered with quilts and crying silently. This was the first time Cheng Haiyan had seen her crying heartbrokenly like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi stood at the door, he didn&#39;t know what to do. Cheng Haiyan stood beside her mother&#39;s bed, equally at a loss. She was scared and didn&#39;t know how to express concern or comfort her. Even, she couldn&#39;t understand her mother&#39;s pain at this moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She considers herself to be an emotionally rough daughter, because in this family, they are taught that daughters can only rely on themselves, and sons rely on their parents. &quot;My grandmother&#39;s generation would regard their daughters as It&#39;s relatively light and I won&#39;t give too much emotion to my daughter.&quot; Yi Yonghong was taught that it was useless for girls to study, so she dropped out of school before finishing the second grade of junior high school. At that time, Yi Yonghong had good grades, ranked among the top three in her class, and was selected by a dance school, but her grandfather was unwilling to spend money to support her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A group photo of Yi Yonghong&#39;s family. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ 825d62be57.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1175&quot; height=&quot;1383&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/825d62be57.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;250826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A photo of Yi Yonghong’s family. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Haiyan&#39;s generation, she is still treated in this way. When she was a child, Yi Yonghong often told her that her sister must give way to her younger brother, and her younger brother&#39;s clothes must be washed by her sister. The couple&#39;s preference for their son reached its peak in 2015 after his son was diagnosed with acute leukemia. In order not to burden her parents, Cheng Haiyan earned living expenses by herself. She worked as a waiter, dishwasher, and cashier at the front desk. &quot;It was so hard that I felt numb.&quot; In recent years, Cheng Haiyan rarely spends the Chinese New Year with her parents and works outside to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong&#39;s crying did not subside. She repeatedly said &quot;Is this sentence correct?&quot; Cheng Haiyan didn&#39;t know what &quot;this sentence&quot; was. She called her uncle, who was the most suitable person she could think of to comfort her mother. Grandma is old and can&#39;t stand the excitement; her sick brother is doing an internship in another place and is the key target of the family&#39;s concealment; and her aunt and uncle have a bad relationship with their mother and often quarrel. There are few people who can support Yoshiyong Hong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Yi Yonghong has a strong self-esteem and is unwilling to let her family know about her. &quot;We rarely ask relatives for help or call them to complain. My mother feels that people will make fun of you and not want to help you,&quot; Cheng Haiyan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My uncle who was far away in Dongguan answered Cheng Haiyan&#39;s call. &quot;He called my mother&#39;s name twice, &#39;Honghong, Honghong&#39;, and she immediately calmed down.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan didn’t know why the backbone of the family suddenly collapsed. She survived even when her brother was sick and undergoing chemotherapy. Cheng Shanzhi also couldn&#39;t understand why his wife couldn&#39;t get over this hurdle: &quot;I didn&#39;t mention divorce, and I didn&#39;t drive you away. As a husband, I still love you, so why can&#39;t I just think about it?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi is very satisfied with himself. His wife is beautiful, has fair skin, never puts on makeup, and speaks softly. When she took her home for the first time, people in the village praised him, &quot;Your ancestral grave is so nice.&quot; &quot;What else can I say about this kind of wife? There is nothing to dislike at all.&quot; Cheng Shanzhi often teaches his daughter that she should learn from her mother and be nice to her husband in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong is a traditional and conservative rural woman. Even when they fell in love, they only found out Cheng Shanzhi’s zodiac sign and birthday before they got together. After marriage, in addition to doing farm work, Yi Yonghong naturally took over the housework of washing and cooking. She massaged her husband&#39;s feet every day and trimmed his nails every other time. Jiu went to help him serve the rice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the memory of her family, Yi Yonghong rarely interacted with the opposite sex or joked. She always hid when buying sanitary napkins and must put them in black plastic bags. Washed underwear is always hung among other clothes to dry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong doesn’t have many friends. Her pastimes are drinking tea, playing mahjong and scrolling through Douyin. Occasionally, she would take TikTok videos by herself, putting on a fancy template with the filter turned to the maximum, and staring at the camera with a serious expression. Sometimes she laments the hard life, and sometimes she sings the song &quot;Married girl, throw away the water, don&#39;t talk too much when you return to your parents&#39; home&quot; and &quot;Why is it so difficult in this life?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2000, I followed my husband to Hainan to work hard. They planted lemongrass and raised snakes, and finally saved money to build a house in their hometown. However, their son was diagnosed with acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Due to long-term labor, the joints of Yi Yonghong&#39;s hands were deformed and unable to be straightened. She often told her daughter that after following your father, there was no house in her hometown, no house in Hainan, and no home anywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After her mother died, Cheng Haiyan always dreamed of her, but she could never see her face. Cheng Haiyan guessed that maybe her mother &quot;didn&#39;t want to see us, and we let her down.&quot; Cheng Haiyan did not dare to read the suicide note left by Yi Yonghong a second time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Questioned resistance&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Another important reason why Yi Yonghong is under tremendous pressure is that she always believes that the evidence is not enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the incident, in order to hide the incident, Yi Yonghong took a shower and washed the clothes she wore that day. She also threw the used tissues under the tree outside the house and had them removed. Heavy rain washed it away. &quot;I hate myself for not knowing how to use the law to protect myself... There is no evidence of guilt, and I&#39;m afraid I won&#39;t win against him,&quot; she stated in her suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another thing that made Yi Yonghong feel even more desperate was that during the incident, she was not sure whether her behavior was considered resistance. In her suicide note, she said: &quot;If resistance involves scratching as you said, tearing clothes to pieces, there is no such thing. Because I am afraid that he will beat me and harm my family. In my confession, I only said to push him and not to do it. , is this considered resistance?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi seemed to be comforting his dead wife. He said that Huang Guan was a head taller than him, his arms were as thick as his own, and he was tall and tall. &quot;If he holds you with both hands, do you have the strength to resist? No matter whether my wife resists or not, it is you, the man, who takes the initiative to violate my wife, not my wife who violates you.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan doesn&#39;t know what resistance is. In her opinion, pushing the other person away is also resistance. She rarely pays attention to news about women&#39;s rights protection. After her mother committed suicide, a friend recommended Cheng Haiyan to watch the TV series &quot;Imperfect Victim&quot;: &quot;The heroine did not know how to resist under mental oppression. I felt that I My mother is mentally rebellious. If she had not resisted, she would not have cried.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Hangyuan, the 66-year-old village team leader, has his own views on resistance. He believes that to leave a mark on the other person&#39;s body, even if a knife is placed on the woman&#39;s neck, she must resist. After Yi Yonghong committed suicide, another version of the story circulated in the teahouse where Yi Yonghong used to frequent in this small village with only 13 households: The two had an affair and committed suicide after being discovered by her husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another factor that complicates the case is the 150 yuan Huang Mouguan left behind when he left. In a confrontation between the two parties after Yi Yonghong committed suicide, Huang&#39;s wife believed that by giving 150 yuan, the nature of the matter changed and became a &quot;business.&quot; After Yi Yonghong committed suicide, the two dirty, black banknotes were crumpled and stacked in Yi Yonghong&#39;s pocket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Shanzhi felt that his wife was insulted by their money, &quot;He (Huang Mouguan) lost the money and ran away. My wife will definitely pick it up.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 21, the sixth day after the incident, Cheng Shanzhi and Yi Yonghong were called again to take statements. This was also the second time they took statements after the incident. It was after recording this confession that Yoshinaga wrote the suicide note. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Haiyan remembered that after her mother came home after taking the confession, she called her mother and asked: &quot;Are you willing to file a lawsuit? If you are willing to file a lawsuit, I can only try my best to help you. If If she doesn&#39;t want to sue, she won&#39;t sue.&quot; Cheng Haiyan realized later, &quot;(Before) we wanted her to sue, not that she wanted to sue herself. Taking the initiative and being pushed are not the same thing.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Yi Yonghong chose to sue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Yi Yonghong’s experience was reported by the media, on August 26, the Wenchang Municipal Public Security Bureau stated that it had deployed elite police forces to set up a joint investigation team to conduct a comprehensive review. According to Cheng Haiyan’s statistics, after Yi Yonghong’s suicide, the police re-collected the following evidence: 20 bottles of honey chrysanthemum tea (2 bottles unopened, 18 empty boxes), Yi Yonghong’s mobile phone, 150 yuan banknotes, Yi Yonghong’s gynecology department Check the medical records, the underwear worn by Yi Yonghong the next day after the incident, sheets, quilt covers, mats, pillows, bras, trousers, coats, tissues washed away by the rain, as well as the blood, liver and spleen obtained by Yi Yonghong&#39;s autopsy . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As to whether Huang Mouguan has been detained and what new evidence is available for filing the case, a staff member of the Political Affairs Office of the Wenchang Municipal Public Security Bureau told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;The case is under investigation and it is not convenient to disclose it.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The bedroom of the house where Yi Yonghong lived before his death, the suicide note was placed on the red stool. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/14/3e56ff08d4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4032&quot; height=&quot;3024&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/14/3e56ff08d4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The bedroom of the house where Yi Yonghong lived before his death , the suicide note was placed on the red stool. (Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Chen Jiahui)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cheng Shanzhi’s view, even on the day Yi Yonghong secretly wrote the suicide note, he did not notice anything unusual about his wife. On July 22, after working for a day, the couple decided to have dinner in a restaurant. Cheng Shanzhi bought four cans of Red Bull for his wife. Yi Yonghong loved to drink Red Bull and drank one can almost every day before the incident. Cheng Shanzhi lay on the recliner waiting for her. After taking a shower, Yi Yonghong hugged her husband and kissed him. For dinner, they ordered a piece of white-chopped chicken and a plate of sweet potato leaves. Yi Yonghong still had no appetite. She didn&#39;t even drink her favorite Red Bull and only ate some sweet potato leaves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;July 23 was the day when Cheng Haiyan returned to Wenchang from Haikou to record her confession. Early in the morning, Cheng Shanzhi called her: &quot;Hong, let&#39;s go with our daughter to record a statement. The two of us have a companion.&quot; After calling her three times in a row, Yi Yonghong refused. &quot;She said, go ahead, I&#39;ll wait for you to come back at home. I&#39;m very tired and want to take a rest at home.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a normal day, Cheng Shanzhi would go pick her up and the couple would always be inseparable when traveling. But that day, &quot;I forgot to give her a hand.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>