<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[被检出兽药残存，明治召回4.4万瓶牛奶！客服回应了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260470]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Remnants of veterinary drugs were detected in Meiji milk, a well-known Japanese dairy brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 11, according to the Japan Broadcasting Association (NHK), the famous Japanese dairy brand Meiji Milk announced the recall of 44,000 bottles of bottled milk that have been on the market due to the detection of veterinary drug residues in the products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/9c973624a99c1a9fc552d3637d344bcc.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;602&quot; height=&quot;339&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/9c973624a99c1a9fc552d3637d344bcc.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258011&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that this veterinary drug residue is called sulfamethoxazole, which is commonly used to prevent or treat infectious diseases in cattle or pigs. Since this substance will remain in the milk and have adverse effects on the human body, in accordance with production safety regulations, this drug must not be used on animals within 72 hours before milking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Japan Broadcasting Association (NHK), the milk with residual residue was produced by Meiji Dairy&#39;s Kansai factory in Kaizuka City, Osaka Prefecture, and is mainly 180 ml bottles for home delivery. On the 6th, the local government discovered veterinary drug residues during an inspection of the factory and ordered Meiji to recall the problematic products in accordance with relevant food safety regulations. So far, about 44,000 bottles of the product have been recalled. However, since the shelf life of this batch of problematic products ends on November 13, the products have been sold in many regions such as western and central Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, Meiji Dairy Group issued a product recall announcement and stated that it would conduct a thorough investigation of the raw milk and production process to prevent similar incidents from happening again. The company argued in the announcement that there is currently no evidence to prove that residual sulfamethoxazole is obviously harmful to the human body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding this matter, a reporter from Nandu Wancaishe asked the customer service of the Meiji flagship store on major e-commerce platforms. The Meiji customer service on the JD.com platform stated that the milk and other products sold by the store in China, except for the use of Except for the raw milk raw materials produced in China, all dairy products are made from dairy products other than Japan. Moreover, the acceptance of raw milk is strictly in accordance with the regulations of the Chinese government, so please feel free to eat it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/66b60fd49e7eb2d4cee80761f61c7d0d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;681&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/66b60fd49e7eb2d4cee80761f61c7d0d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258010&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Meiji customer service on the Taobao platform stated that the chocolates and biscuits sold in the store are produced in China, and there are no milk products sold in the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/94007c36a82c2c134b41e0abe37bd10d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;528&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/94007c36a82c2c134b41e0abe37bd10d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258009&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女子在昆明海埂大坝“捡垃圾”谋生？真相与事实不符]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260456]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman posted a video&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Screen It was she who picked up plastic bottles at Haigeng Dam in Kunming&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reverse happened the next second&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/f9ed9baba59b0d5c749ab9c6c7a6a464.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;661&quot; height=&quot;946&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/12/f9ed9baba59b0d5c749ab9c6c7a6a464.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257982&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/12/b6df50b17db342cf66be00451efa2d82.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1073&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 12/b6df50b17db342cf66be00451efa2d82.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257983&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, when the woman took the video, the witness Mr. Lin happened to be playing at Haigeng Dam and witnessed the woman leading her child to take the video. Video of the entire process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“What I saw was that she was carrying two plastic bags, and then she took out a lot of bottles and put them on the ground, and then asked her children to help her take a video of picking up garbage.” Mr. Lin said, &quot;The entire dam was clean that day, but the woman deliberately made such a fake video to slander tourists and elevate herself, which made people very angry.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/72aec6aea0a2d201bb1685df9c6d1cbf.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;552&quot; height=&quot;310&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/72aec6aea0a2d201bb1685df9c6d1cbf.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257998&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Lin put This video&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Posted on social platforms&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon a netizen left a message and it was exposed&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The woman’s account&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because The content of the video is seriously inconsistent with the facts&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Arousing strong condemnation from everyone&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /12/eabb38ad07f95378be3d2714517c66d9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;258&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/eabb38ad07f95378be3d2714517c66d9.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;257984&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/d62d5d619fad9914a67b32ae60b01f72.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;253&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/d62d5d619fad9914a67b32ae60b01f72.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257988&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;The reporter then found the woman’s social account and found that the woman claimed that she was a divorced single mother, homeless, and lost the ability to work because of a hand injury. She has been unable to work for 6 years. With no income and hundreds of thousands in debt, I can only earn living expenses by collecting bottles and selling them...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/12/666272ad083b2d2d2b53e67a7f286fec.png &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 834 &quot;height =&quot; 836 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/ 1/12/666272ad083B2D2B53E67A7F286FEC. png&quot; data-key=&quot;257989&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the comments below the video she posted&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many netizens&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;have criticized her for her fraud. Reveal&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/ef4069076bc9cfca341f3f3f692eeb6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;233&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/ef4069076bc9cfca341f3f3f692eeb6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257987&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/d5424030efc3d12d288310f35d15d26e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;241&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/d5424030efc3d12d288310f35d15d26e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257986&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many netizens&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Complain on behalf of sanitation workers and tourists&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/09497efc90cc912562837a9838e50b64.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;439&quot; height=&quot;102&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/09497efc90cc912562837a9838e50b64.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257990&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/0c4f84c13bb5c0696b3bfeb429f6e83f.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;433&quot; height=&quot;83&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/0c4f84c13bb5c0696b3bfeb429f6e83f.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257995&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/0eca3ef94ddc6f363d2faecb3a36dda0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;430&quot; height=&quot;79&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/0eca3ef94ddc6f363d2faecb3a36dda0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257992&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/12/cb4f4b8cbb630c23e32d213f635d0b7d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;436&quot; height=&quot;107&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/12/cb4f4b8cbb630c23e32d213f635d0b7d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257993&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12 /b62e6dc7cc75dc99986214058166cc34.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;446&quot; height=&quot;114&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/b62e6dc7cc75dc99986214058166cc34.png&quot; data -key=&quot;257991&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The woman&#39;s account has been temporarily banned from publishing works by the platform due to violation of relevant regulations&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/067130ccdb61ed06a382b433dc1b22b3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;823&quot; height=&quot;442&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/067130ccdb61ed06a382b433dc1b22b3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257994&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新梗“公主请”爆红：应遵循自愿原则，不可情绪勒索丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260466]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Internet meme &quot;Princess Please&quot; has become popular. It is said that if you have never used or even heard a term starting with &quot;Princess please&quot;, then you are already behind the Internet trend. This new &quot;meme&quot; on the Internet is not only used as a joke between parents, children and spouses, but also used by some businesses for &quot;Double Eleven&quot; promotions and live broadcasts to bring goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prototype of the line &quot;Princess please&quot; comes from the classic old movie &quot;Roman Holiday&quot;. The reporter played by Gregory Peck said &quot;Princess please&quot; to the princess played by Audrey Hepburn. &quot;Get in the car&quot;; and &quot;Princess please&quot; became an Internet meme, which originated from a funny video on Douyin: a father picked up his daughter on a bicycle, but the daughter said &quot;You said &#39;Princess please get in the car&#39;&quot;. Unexpectedly, the father did not continue riding away, leaving his daughter behind to chase him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After this funny video became popular on the short video platform, it immediately brought about a wave of imitation and secondary creation. The main promoters were short video bloggers and e-commerce platform merchants, which gave rise to &quot; More hot memes like &quot;Princess please drink tea&quot;, &quot;Princess please dine&quot;, &quot;Princess please sign for receipt&quot; and &quot;Princess please place order&quot; can be described as a victory of &quot;emotional marketing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the carnival of &quot;Princess Please&quot; has gradually emerged with some new &quot;games&quot;, and its negative externalities are worthy of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One is the &quot;identity&quot; issue of the &quot;Princess Please&quot; short video on the Internet platform. A careful review of these &quot;Princess Please&quot; videos on the short video platform can be roughly divided into three types: one is completely staged and belongs to situational skits; the other is a real shot on the spot, with immediate reactions to the real shot; the third is difficult to distinguish between true and false. It’s not marked and can’t be seen, which is problematic in itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These short videos are common on social media platforms: bloggers find the takeaway guy and ask him to say &quot;Princess, please dine&quot;; ask the boss at the restaurant to cooperate in filming &quot;Princess, please dine&quot;; ask the bus and An online ride-hailing driver said &quot;Princess, please get out of the car&quot;; he asked security guards at the school gate to say &quot;Princess, please go back to school&quot;; recently in Nanjing, Jiangsu, a woman who fell asked an ambulance doctor to say &quot;Princess, please get in the car&quot;; and even in Yunnan Province In a certain hospital, a surgeon appeared in the process of operating on a patient and said &quot;Please princess, please remove the electric knife&quot; and &quot;Please say thank you princess&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is obvious at a glance that most of these &quot;Princess Please&quot; short videos are fictitious and staged, but the result is that they appear to be &quot;real-looking&quot;. Such an unlabeled operation is inevitable Non-compliant. Disguising it as news to mislead the public is not without the suspicion of guiding public opinion. I would like to ask, will the proliferation of &quot;Princess Please&quot; videos create the illusion that &quot;all walks of life say &quot;Princess Please&quot; is a reality, and in turn &quot;force&quot; all walks of life to &quot;must say Princess please&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the Cyberspace Administration of China issued the &quot;Notice on Strengthening the Management of &quot;We-Media&quot;&quot;, which is commonly known as the &quot;Thirteen Articles&quot;, including &quot;annotation of fictitious content or controversial information&quot; Requirements for &quot;label&quot; (Article 5): When &quot;self-media&quot; publishes content that contains fictional plots and plot interpretations, the website platform should require it to mark the fiction or interpretation label in a conspicuous manner. If the staged &quot;Princess Please&quot; is not marked and deliberately makes it difficult to distinguish the authenticity, it will inevitably be suspected of violating this law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, whether staged or real, the proliferation of &quot;Princess Please&quot; videos has brought about problems of blurred boundaries and emotional blackmail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When parents, children and spouses say &quot;Princess please&quot;, it is an emotional interaction between close relatives; when e-commerce platform customer service personnel say &quot;Princess please&quot;, it is to use emotional marketing to promote actual transactions. Follow It is also the market principle of voluntary transactions; and if strangers who are neither relatives nor friends must be forced to say &quot;Princess please&quot; in front of the camera, and even public authorities follow the &quot;playful joke&quot;, this will cause a problem. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to those &quot;princess please&quot; short videos that are obviously staged, there is also a type of &quot;princess please&quot; that is real and even more worrying: the head teacher takes advantage of his position to ask a whole room of primary school students to shout &quot; Princess, please leave the get out of class.&quot; &quot;Beautiful princess, please leave the class.&quot; Children don&#39;t quite understand what posing is, so teaching them to cooperate in a performance only requires &quot;coercion and inducement.&quot; This approach is tantamount to using one&#39;s position to coerce children to satisfy their own emotional values ​​and help them harvest traffic. It is not compliant with the procedures and unfair in the results. It is not the way to teach and educate people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Official accounts of government departments also use &quot;Princess Please&quot; to promote laws and regulations. It seems to be a closer relationship and facilitates dissemination, but it can easily give people the impression of not being serious in the long run. It is also detrimental to popularize legal knowledge and promote citizens to abide by the law: what public authorities need is to perform their statutory duties, strictly abide by the law and strictly enforce the law. How can they show such a humble attitude of &quot;asking people to abide by the law&quot; and &quot;asking people to abide by the law&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thirdly, the popular &quot;Princess Please&quot; is just another &quot;Internet meme&quot; destined to have a short life cycle, but it has characteristics that are different from previous &quot;Internet memes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Princess Please&quot; is not the first-generation Internet meme of &quot;emotional marketing&quot;. Memes such as &quot;kiss&quot; and &quot;little fairy&quot; have been circulated for several times. Online language ebbs and flows, coming and going quickly. This is what is commonly known as &quot;language inflation&quot; (referred to as &quot;call inflation&quot;): just like currency, the &quot;face value&quot; of language is getting larger and larger, and the value it expresses is getting bigger and bigger. However, its &quot;value&quot; is getting smaller and smaller, and the thoughts and feelings it can carry are becoming increasingly poor. All kinds of &quot;internet memes&quot; are overused but internally poor, and have become quickly decaying words instead of meaningful idioms, which is the natural ending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter how you play &quot;Princess Please&quot;, it should still follow the principle of voluntariness, there must be boundaries, public power should not be involved, and teachers should not emotionally blackmail students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[涉嫌贩卖出生医学证明，广西南宁相关医院责任人已被采取刑事强制措施]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260468]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 15:14:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The reporter learned from the Nanning Municipal Health Commission in Guangxi that people reported that a hospital in Nanning was suspected of selling medical birth certificates , the obstetrics and gynecology department of the hospital involved has been suspended for rectification, and criminal coercive measures have been taken against the relevant responsible persons of the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a joint investigation by the health, public security and other departments, it was found that the hospital involved was Nanning Chenghe Hospital, and relevant work such as investigation and evidence collection is being further carried out. The Nanning Municipal Health Commission stated that medical institutions that violate laws and regulations will be dealt with resolutely in accordance with the law, and those who violate laws and regulations will be dealt with in accordance with the law and will never be tolerated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从画屏到绿幕：屏风进化论]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260369]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 14:06:18&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/cpBimUbCjN6iXjIaj4QiNr9DMEiZzVR0HhBPOnL2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/cpBimUbCjN6iXjIaj4QiNr9DMEiZz VR0HhBPOnL2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257471&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Paraventi: Screen&quot; exhibition, Prada Rongzhai, Shanghai, 2023.11.03– 2024.01.21&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Alessandro Wang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The screen was originally used to block the view, but later, this refusal to view gradually evolved It became an invitation to watch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China is the hometown of the screen. The earliest screen known today appeared in the late Zhou Dynasty. Initially, they were used to help the owner abandon distracting thoughts and focus on contemplation and meditation. Later, they gradually became one of the living furnishings of nobles and literati, used to isolate space, block sight, and increase the sense of privacy. As the Tang Dynasty spread eastward, screens were introduced to Japan. The Japanese often placed them at the door of their homes to block the sneaky atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/PAzTf0V0D61jhUAk8q0ZEIGxbcxPmV5dD99omqKG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/PAzTf0V0D61jhUAk8q0ZEIGxbcxPmV5dD99omqKG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hide Both architecture and storage are oriental. Whether it is architecture, gardens or homes, Eastern aesthetics avoids &quot;straight to the point&quot;. Direct access is always vulgar. &quot;Shadow walls&quot; and &quot;stone screens&quot; must be built to block the line of sight. This is also in another sense. Screen - In &quot;Dream of Red Mansions&quot;, in order to welcome Concubine Yuan to the royal family, a lot of effort was put into building a luxurious Grand View Garden. As soon as he entered the garden, he first built a rockery with green peaks to cover all the scenery. Jia Zheng explained, &quot;If it weren&#39;t for this mountain, what&#39;s the point of seeing all the scenery in the garden when you enter?&quot; In one sentence, the screen was broken. The psychological motivation of existence: to welcome but also to reject, the winding path leads to the secluded place, &quot;the more you explore the scenery, the better you will get&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When screens were introduced to the West, their shapes and techniques had become diverse. People in the Baroque period even used them as props in dramas and operas, whether to beautify the stage, indicate scenery, or isolate narrative space. The performance capabilities of the screens are all top-notch. By the 19th century, many artists, architects and designers had widely adopted this form, giving screens more artistic expression. The screen therefore also has multiple identities: is it a painting or a sculpture? Is it art or furniture? Is it a practical object or a decorative item? Is it a prop or a device? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Zv6COcmOL4pHzHQDlEu5BM8Rw5PaeU8ZZx5zVuCu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/Zv6COcmOL4pHzHQDlEu5BM8Rw5PaeU8ZZx5zVuCu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257468&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None The standard answer is that the screen answers this unsolvable proposition with its complex and diverse attitude. In modern society, &quot;screen&quot; has also been given more and more meanings. We are surrounded by various &quot;screens&quot;, isolating and attracting us. This was the inspiration for the exhibition Paraventi: Screen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a comprehensive exhibition that shuttles between many cultures. This one located in PRADA Rongzhai in Shanghai is a branch of its global exhibitions, and therefore has more Chinese colors. . A royal rosewood screen from the 18th century conveys the most classic and elegant appearance of the Chinese screen. This is a screen commonly used by ancient literati. The 12 surrounding screens are hinged to each other and can be arranged in an alternating pattern or in a single line. Or arranged in an arc, there is a place for posting paintings above each fan board. Generally, the owner will entrust the artist to customize a group of 12 paintings, which are painted on rice paper or silk and then pasted on the screen. Sometimes the owner himself is also proficient in it. Painting skills, painting screens have become elegant props for displaying works and offering appreciation. Ancient screens were often moved and the paintings were easily damaged. Therefore, the owners often removed their favorite works from the screen and framed them in scrolls for preservation. Therefore, the paintings on the screen could be replaced frequently. It is for this reason that most of the surviving ancient screens do not have paintings posted on them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another common Chinese-style screen is the single-leaf vertical screen that has a history of more than 2,000 years in China. This type of screen is usually made of stone or brick. One of the screens on display in Rongzhai This kind of small stone screen is often placed on the desk. The stone wall inlaid on it has patterns that resemble mountains and rivers, and also represents the ravines in the minds of scribes. This small desk screen is not just for viewing. It has a very practical functionality. When the owner is writing and painting, the desk screen can prevent the draft from drying the ink quickly. It is one of the important study rooms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the many contemporary screen works in the exhibition hall, the one that amazed me the most was the work of the video artist Cao Fei, who completely transformed Rotunda No. 1 of Rongzhai into a green screen. The blue and green curtains outline oval screens, echoing the blue and green stained glass in the windows of the old bungalows. There are many images displayed in the exhibition hall, all related to &quot;green screen&quot;. As we all know, green screen and blue screen are important props in the imaging industry and are often used to create virtual scenes. Cao Fei photographed many scenes in modern life: strong men pedaling bicycles with green screens on their backs, men and women spinning green screens wildly on public fitness equipment, beauties staring at a green screen on the beach, in blue, blue, and green screens. The blue screen and green screen in the green trash can, and the fierce woman using the green screen as a target to practice fighting in the elevator room seems to be Cao Fei himself... Among all these images, images will appear intermittently on those green screens. , but will return to the green screen after a while, repeating the cycle, like a fable that is both true and false, constantly reminding us: In an era flooded with videos, everything we see and the images we see may be virtual. , untrue, and untrustworthy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nKn2fq2DqnXA4To94A6o5CmsM5655OqlEN17GRnm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/nKn2fq2DqnXA4To94A6o5CmsM5655OqlEN17GRnm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cao Fei, Screen Autobiography (Shanghai), 2023, &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (artist, Vitamin Art Space and Schbutt Mag Gallery provided/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the images that appear on the green screen are precisely images from the pre-Internet era, most of which are from the nostalgic 1980s: Spring Festival Gala, News Network, and nostalgic golden songs , female workers on the assembly line, etc. This huge difference creates a ridiculous visual tension. The environment in which the green screen exists is extremely absurd, but when pictures appear on the green screen, there is an era where we still trust images. In that era, images are true to their word and keep their word. Today, these images are like ghosts, flashing intermittently on the green screen. The green screen is filled with the most incredible places and is overwhelming in the exhibition hall. There are even many live broadcast stations carefully arranged in the green screen, which is beautiful. Sitting under the lantern, the visitors have transformed into amateur anchors! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cao Fei said that when she was a child, she saw prohibitive luxurious screens in the Forbidden City. In southern China where she grew up, various old-style screens with carved dragons and painted phoenixes were not uncommon. There were always Only large households with sufficient space can use screens. But what made her feel warm were the simple, warm screens that could be used by ordinary people. The light green cotton curtains were stretched on the shelves to provide the simplest shielding. People who need injections hide behind this screen and expose half of their buttocks for nurses to insert injections... But from the perspective of the image, the &quot;screen&quot; in her eyes means another kind of isolation and obstruction. &quot;With the prevalence of live broadcast culture, green screen technology has given the screen new fluidity, uncertainty and fiction, reshaping the world we see... It is like the reality behind the live video: except for a bare Outside the &#39;green screen&#39;, there is nothing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;As a video artist, I have long distrusted images.&quot; Cao Fei said that this is exactly what she wants to express in this group of works &quot;We are truly living in an era where images are not trustworthy, reality cannot be determined, and every frame is different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[湖北襄阳“健桥医院贩卖出生证”最新通报 叶某芝等6名犯罪嫌疑人被批捕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260463]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 13:26:22&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 12, the Hubei Xiangyang Municipal People&#39;s Government issued a notice. On November 6, netizens reported Xiangyang Jianqiao After the hospital (No. 169 Chenhou Lane, Xiangcheng District, privately owned, legal representative Ye Mouzhi, female, 55 years old) sold birth medical certificates and other issues, Xiangyang City immediately established a team with the main leaders of the municipal party committee and municipal government as team leaders and relevant city leaders As the heads of each working group, a special work team composed of municipal public security, health, discipline inspection and supervision departments will carry out problem investigation, case investigation and accountability in a strict and expeditious manner and in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Up to now, 6 suspects including Ye Mouzhi have been arrested by the procuratorate. The public security organs have criminally detained 4 suspects in accordance with the law. Relevant investigation and investigation work is being stepped up. The health department has revoked Ye Mouzhi&#39;s &quot;Physician Practice Certificate&quot; and Liu Moujing&#39;s &quot;Nurse Practice Certificate&quot; in accordance with the law. The investigation and handling of other medical personnel involved in the case are in progress; Jianqiao Hospital has been canceled in accordance with the law. Infant health care technical service qualification. The disciplinary inspection and supervision agencies quickly launched investigations into the dereliction of duty, disciplinary and law violations of relevant leading cadres and public officials, and have opened cases for review against 13 relevant responsible persons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, Xiangyang City will continue to investigate cases, conduct in-depth investigations, and severely punish illegal and criminal acts in accordance with the law; organize special rectification of the health care industry, and effectively strengthen standardized management; thoroughly investigate dereliction of duty and those behind the scenes. Corruption will never be tolerated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 13:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在乌镇嘉年华寻找子期]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260366]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/0cxJUdC68WBgK7oOAfRd0by0CqthkUjVFnjmv1ey.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/0cxJUdC68WBgK7oOAfRd0by0CqthkU jVFnjmv1ey. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257474&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Serial Strategy·Small Banquet&quot; was performed on the ancient stage of Zhaoming Academy when it was dark &lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 19, 2023, the 10th Wuzhen Theater Festival opened. I can’t remember how many carnival performances I happened upon at the Wuzhen Theater Festival last year and this year. Chance encounters here are very common. Carnival performance venues are mostly on Xizha Street, the main street of Xizha, as well as under bridges, in pavilions, and in awning boats. There are hundreds of performances including improvisational drama, physical drama, opera, and dance in ten days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just like last year, more than one performance team stood on stilts and wore costumes, slowly setting off from the hall of Zhaoming Academy for a parade. But this year, six rows of spectators were packed into the narrow Xizha Street (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;a stone road that usually only allows three people to walk abreast&lt;/span>;) . The actor on stilts headed west, followed by a group of people, and a group of people took advantage of the traffic jam to ease and walked in the opposite direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/KErtoyLZGqm2nn09wInla1PNLXgX2A4inb3N8rs0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;762&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/KErtoyLZGqm2nn09wInla1PNLXgX2A4inb3N8rs0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Young heroes competing near Yudu Bridge&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was on the road several times because of the traffic jam caused by too many passers-by watching the carnival performances. I was almost late, but this time The excitement makes people lose their temper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Farewell to the first team of stilt walkers, I met the second team of stilt walkers at the bridge end of Lingshui Street. A man and a woman both wore armor and wielded spears. They seemed to be young heroes. A dwarf (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the world of stilts, real people are considered dwarves&lt;/span>;), drew his sword to fight against two guns. The audience applauded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people like to wear ancient costumes and take pictures this year, including Wuzhen. I am even more confused as to whether this was also the case for people visiting temple fairs in ancient times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/S1c7XN0lLP0OauLPRUnpMnZp1BN4gXOWsF1qikSc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;786&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/S1c7XN0lLP0OauLPRUnpMnZp1BN4gXOWsF1qikSc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257470&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The actor who plays the scheming clown&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ding Naizhu, the chief planner of the Wuzhen Theater Festival, promoted the ancient town carnival, he said, &quot;There are all kinds of life and drama, and you can be the audience. , you can also blend into it.&quot; Last year, the Wuzhen Theater Festival was held at the end of November, when the new coronavirus epidemic prevention policy was the most stringent. This year, at least four times as many tourists as last year entered Xizha, and the audience was more closely connected with the carnival performances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Including this pair of heroes, there are three acting spots in a row under the Yudu Bridge. The audience formed a circle outside each point, and the three circles were crowded together, almost intersecting. I stood on the bridge and watched. Not far away, the heroes of the contest were performing a physical drama. There were two or three chairs, a piece of white cloth, and several Rose petals constitute the entire performance field. The actors and actresses cover the chairs with white cloth, scatter rose petals, spin in circles, look at each other, push down the chairs, and do not speak. They use these actions to express their emotional changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/LeiTvAm2ANJ6J6jZbHNhS0X3FbRmTtHMDj3UsYoE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;701&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/LeiTvAm2ANJ6J6jZbHNhS0X3FbRmTtHMDj3UsYoE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Carnival actors running on Xizha Street&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another person with a lot of interaction was the Wooden Box Theater Company. The second time I passed by, I stopped to watch their improvisation. comedy. The rules are as follows: one actor acts as the guesser and goes to the other side to hide far away. The other actors listen to the audience&#39;s instructions. The audience assigns roles and quirks, and the actors improvise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Killer!&quot; Someone said the loudest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Okay, play the killer. Next comes fetishes. &quot;Dance the girl group dance!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, the guessing actor was called back, and his companion performed a killer who danced the girl group dance, and he had to guess. If you don&#39;t guess correctly, the audience can boo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sE2zbaL4adSbK90lNB3fPWBzo03qQKVh0kzXK6Ng.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/sE2zbaL4adSbK90lNB3fPWBzo03qQKVh0kzXK6Ng.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The environmental experimental drama &quot;Centaur 2023&quot; by the bridge was a little quiet in the second half&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many such interactive carnival performances this year. For example, two clowns handed out red and white balloon sticks, dividing the audience into red and white teams. The children were very enthusiastic. The white team&#39;s clown exaggeratedly replaced the red team&#39;s clown&#39;s balloon. The little boys and girls (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;their parents dressed them up as young masters and ladies in ancient times&lt;/span>;) did not have stage fright, and followed the white clown to tease the red clown. Play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day I rushed to the Sun and Moon Square to interview the theater director who was preparing for the rehearsal. The square was occupied by three tall Russian performers and several rows of spectators. It seemed very exciting. During the interview, I could still hear the sound of the organ and the clapping and cheering of the tourists. I passed here again at the same time the next day, and sure enough I caught three Eastern Europeans, dressed in steampunk costumes. One played the organ, one played the clarinet, and one played the drums. Each of them had a flexible rotating lamp above his head that could be turned on ( &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I don’t understand the meaning of this design&lt;/span>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The performance lasted for about twenty minutes. At several points in the middle, the three people introduced themselves or communicated with the audience. There was no translation, and no one present probably understood it, but everyone had a tacit understanding, and the Eastern Europeans spoke in the same way. After a while, everyone cheered and applauded without hesitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some are also very classical. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7zigEVt8BqTYVKmW1vdEhjI9kAsVpA5VcC6lWNQh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/7zigEVt8BqTYVKmW1vdEhjI9kAsVpA5VcC6lWNQh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257473&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Beside the river outside Lingshuiju, there is a carnival installation that lights up at night&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two times at the ancient stage of Zhaoming Academy, I stopped and listened to the sea &quot;Lianlian Ji·Small Banquet&quot; by Fengxian Xiqin Opera Art Inheritance Center. When the sky was getting dark, on the stage on one side of Zhaoming Academy, under the introduction of Situ Wang Yun, Lu Bu met the eighteen-year-old Diao Chan. Lu Bu asked Diao Chan why she wasn&#39;t married yet? Diao Chan waved her water sleeve, and Lu Bu gently held a corner of the water sleeve, pretending to be a wine glass with his hand, swiping back and forth on the water sleeve, and drank the contents of the cup in one gulp. In order to take the bait, the hands, eyes, body and steps are all interesting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhaoming Academy was built to commemorate Xiao Tong, the prince of Liang Dynasty in the Southern Dynasties. The inner courtyard was expanded and became the venue for many performances at the Wuzhen Carnival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By coincidence, I watched &quot;Bosom Friend&quot; twice in Zhaoming Academy one day, and both times I only saw the second half, Boya&#39;s one-man show: it was an adaptation of Boya Ziqi&#39;s story, Academy In the open space, there is a guqin and a singing bowl. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GO7Nowll01yN3UFYlGRCbFTdZXL2HpbHv6He1ygC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/GO7Nowll01yN3UFYlGRCbFTdZXL2HpbHv6He1ygC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257475&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;During the Wuzhen Theater Festival, posters of specially invited plays were posted on the exterior walls of houses, and tourists took photos with their children&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bo Ya was wearing a red robe and a white silk ribbon , sometimes facing the sky, sometimes holding arms, shouting, Ziqi, Ziqi! A tourist holding a child answered and said, Ziqi is here, here! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the actors took their final call, Ziqi appeared. I realized that Ziqi was the person who sat across from me at lunch an hour ago. He was wearing a white robe and a red ribbon, and he matched Bo Ya perfectly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wanted to take a break in the afternoon, so I sat down at a riverside cafe. When I looked up, I saw Ziqi again on the bridge. The white robe and red silk were very eye-catching. The editor and I were discussing work. After more than ten minutes, I looked up and saw that Ziqi was still on the bridge and someone was taking pictures of him. At this time, two tourists sat down next to me. One said, &quot;I&#39;m looking at the scenery under the bridge, and the people watching the scenery are looking at you on the bridge, right?&quot; &quot;What?&quot; replied the other. The previous speaker pointed to Zi Qi, &quot;I remember this saying, right?&quot; At this time, Zi Qi got off the bridge, as if he was going to watch a performance on the other side of the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刘润“翻车”后左支右绌：“商业战略大师”到底是门什么生意？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260450]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The famous business consultant Liu Run &quot;overturned&quot; and broke the circle due to what happened on October 28, 2023 A statement from an annual speech given. Liu Run said in his speech that it took three years for brand discount MAMA stores to open 2,500 stores across the country, with total revenue exceeding 1.7 billion. This set of data has been questioned by many parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Xintong, the founder of Discount Niu, posted a video on Douyin, saying that according to the public statement of the founder of Discount MAMA, the brand should have 20 to 30 stores in September this year, and the annual turnover should be It&#39;s less than 100 million. Some netizens questioned in the comments, &quot;1.7 billion, 2,500 stores, each store sells about 680,000 yuan a year on average? And where are these 2,500 stores mainly opened?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Run repeatedly explained, saying that &quot;there are explanations in the speech and in the full text&quot; &quot;these 2,500 stores include self-operated stores, co-branded stores and stores supported by the supply chain&quot; &quot;this number has been confirmed by Xing Yunfei himself&quot; &quot;. MAMA founder Xing Yunfei also responded that discount MAMA has 4,000+ stores nationwide supported by direct operations, joint operations, and supply chain hosting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Run even published a report titled &quot;Liu Run: 2,700 stores, 1.7 billion, discount MAMA&#39;s data. Is it fiction?&quot; &quot;The article, &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter if you use my traffic, but you have misled many sincere entrepreneurs&quot; caused more dissatisfaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After much hesitation, Liu Run finally issued an apology letter on Weibo on November 2, admitting several mistakes. The storm is over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Liu Run&#39;s mistake in his annual speech was very obvious. As he finally admitted, the so-called &quot;2,500 stores&quot; were not opened by MAMA, but most of them were MAMA &quot;services&quot; business partners. If business partners such as upstream and downstream supply chains and co-branding are included in the stores opened by brands, how many more &quot;unicorn&quot; companies will China need to add? What&#39;s even more ironic is that according to the water injection standard for cooperation, the data given by Xing Yunfei is more than 4,000, indicating that the &quot;2,500&quot; mentioned in Liu Run&#39;s speech is also very inaccurate. Could it be a compromise of &quot;fuzzy processing&quot;? There should not be such low-level data errors in the annual speeches of business consulting professionals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You shouldn’t make simple mistakes, and you shouldn’t admit it in time when you are wrong. People can not escape from doing wrong. If you can change your past, there is no greater good. Admit it openly when you are wrong and then give a reasonable explanation. This is the most basic principle of crisis public relations. Liu Run did not do this. It may not be because he does not understand, but because the &quot;Internet celebrity&quot; business model of establishing a personality and generating traffic caused deformation of his actions. Business consulting business cannot do this, but &quot;Internet celebrity&quot; traffic business must do this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the rise of the Internet, a group of Internet celebrity &quot;business consultants&quot; or so-called &quot;business strategy gurus&quot; have emerged. Their resumes are as bright as a crucian carp crossing a river. Liu Run is one of the representative figures. However, the business model of these &quot;business consultants&quot; is very different from the traditional business consulting industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;business consultants&quot; who are active online are IP-based and media-based, and are keen on the &quot;to C&quot; business of mass communication, rather than the &quot;to B&quot; business of traditional business consulting agencies serving enterprises. For example, Liu Run&#39;s title includes strategic consultants for many large companies, but it is difficult for the public to understand how much he has contributed to the strategic optimization of these companies, and how much he and his business team have gained from these corporate consulting services. revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Run’s most eye-catching business achievement is the huge income that expensive online courses and even more expensive offline courses have brought him. The prospectus of Thinking Creation, the parent company of &quot;Get&quot;, Liu Run&#39;s main sales platform, shows that Liu Run has appeared in &quot;Get&quot;&#39;s major procurement contracts for four consecutive years starting in 2017. From 2017 to 2020, Liu Run received a total of 58 million in online and offline course revenue. Liu Run’s IP has become a high-quality “obtained” asset. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult to evaluate Liu Run&#39;s career using traditional business consulting standards. What is certain is that Liu Run is a very successful Internet content producer and an &quot;Internet celebrity&quot; with high IP value. The &quot;business consultants&quot; who are active on the Internet today are basically in this situation. It is difficult to see how successful their consulting business is. The content dissemination channel of paid knowledge is the main source of revenue. Of course, traditional business consulting also earns training fees, but this is not how the courses are sold, and the audience is not so &quot;taught but not differentiated&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The service targets of traditional business consulting organizations are very limited. Small and medium-sized organizations are usually only responsible for a few long-term customers, and large organizations only have dozens or hundreds of long-term customers. Their services require constant performance appraisal from customers, and every &quot;golden idea&quot;, every special report, and every training class must be of practical help to business operations. The traffic of &quot;business consultants&quot; in the hundreds of thousands or millions means that the audience is huge and the actual performance is difficult to measure. No one can count how many &quot;students&quot; who bought courses have gained business benefits from the wise words of the &quot;business consultant&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If this kind of content creation and dissemination must be classified as a business consulting industry, it can only be said that the training branch of the business consulting industry is moving toward a &quot;sinking market.&quot; The audience is huge, the good and the bad are mixed, and the specific scenarios vary widely. It is impossible to provide customized services like the traditional business consulting industry. The communication effect is the goal of this sinking market. This &quot;sinking market&quot; competes for traffic, not service performance. Therefore, the primary means of competition is presentation skills rather than actual performance in furthering the commercial interests of the audience. The macro narrative is gorgeous, the micro is chicken soup for the soul, new concepts and golden sentences fly together, and the words are not surprising, all in order to attract more fans and gain more traffic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The behavior patterns of &quot;business consultants&quot; and &quot;business strategy masters&quot; are closer to other &quot;Internet celebrities&quot; who do traffic business than to traditional business consulting agencies. Like all internet celebrities, they must always give top priority to maintaining their personality and traffic base. Traditional business consulting agencies have neither such &quot;traffic pressure&quot; nor room for prevarication and confusion - customers are all experts and are not easy to fool. Even if you fool around for a while, it will be in vain if there is a performance problem in the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the &quot;business consultants&quot; who are active on the Internet are not the networking of the business consulting industry, but the Internet celebrityization of business culture communication. “Internet celebrity” itself is not a derogatory connotation. Used correctly, it can improve the efficiency of information dissemination and help popularize knowledge and ideas. However, if used incorrectly, it will become the starting point for a decline in industry standards and a decline in professional ethics. Liu Run made low-level mistakes first and refused to admit his mistakes later. He can be classified as the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an emerging industry in the Internet era, &quot;business consultants&quot; must be tolerant and willing to see results, but they also need to be vigilant and learn from each experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident is a warning to the &quot;business consultant&quot; industry. There is nothing wrong with spreading business culture, but don’t overly elevate your industry positioning. Most of them are content producers who disseminate business knowledge to the public. Why bother with the &quot;sheep head&quot; of &quot;business consulting&quot;? Micro business scenarios vary widely, and market segments are diverse. Even if you have the power to penetrate the universe, how many users can you provide consulting services to? The bluff of forcibly creating IP and selling characters goes against the spirit of business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For consumers who pay for knowledge, this incident is also a reminder. If two to three hundred yuan of course money can buy you the secrets of getting rich that can change your destiny, how can there be any poor people in the world? Consume rationally and choose carefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also those large companies that have so many &quot;strategic consultants&quot; that they can&#39;t even remember them. They should cherish their famous products. If you don’t want to be fooled, don’t let others use it to fool others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“双11”当天全国快递业务量达6.39亿件，是平日的1.87倍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260454]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 10:58:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Monitoring data from the State Post Bureau show that from November 1 to 11, 2023, postal express delivery companies across the country collected a total of There were 5.264 billion express parcels, a year-on-year increase of 23.22%, and the average daily business volume was 1.4 times the usual business volume. On November 11, a total of 639 million express parcels were received, which was 1.87 times the daily business volume and a year-on-year increase of 15.76%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bian Zuodong, deputy director of the Market Supervision Department of the State Post Bureau, said that this year’s peak season for express delivery business mainly presents two peaks, which are more stable, supporting consumption recovery, economic improvement, and user experience is more convenient. Big features. This year&#39;s express business peak season will continue to form two peaks on November 1 and November 11, sharing the pressure of the industry at a single peak and making the operation more stable. Postal express delivery is deeply integrated with e-commerce, modern agriculture, modern manufacturing, etc. During the &quot;Double 11&quot; period, the entire network&#39;s collection volume hit a record high, reflecting the vitality of my country&#39;s consumer market and a vivid portrayal of the economic recovery. Postal express delivery is deeply integrated into the e-commerce industry chain. A large number of pre-sale goods are pre-stored in the express cloud warehouse, making delivery services faster and more accurate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that this year’s express delivery business peak season will start on November 1 and end on the eve of the Spring Festival in 2024. In order to do a good job in ensuring service during peak seasons, the State Post Bureau has formulated a guarantee plan based on full situation analysis and service capability assessment with major e-commerce platforms and delivery companies, and comprehensively deployed and implemented it, coordinating e-commerce platforms and delivery companies to continue to play &quot; The core mechanism of &quot;staggered shipment and balanced promotion&quot;. At the same time, we will carry out in-depth investigation and rectification of potential safety hazards to ensure production safety, delivery safety, and information security in an all-round way, and prevent casualties in the industry; adhere to the standardization, recycling, reduction, and harmlessness of express packaging, and encourage e-commerce express shipments to be sent directly with original packaging , Reduce excessive front-end packaging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During peak business seasons and under low-temperature, rainy and snowy weather conditions, front-line couriers work for long hours, with heavy loads and high pressure. To this end, the postal management department continues to strengthen the care and care work of grassroots employees, safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of the courier group, and issues consumer tips, calling on users to give more tolerance and understanding to the courier group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[圣药丨本草物色]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260208]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/2fb4OeDpmkRFUzm2iHSIuYWuvkT2mgksjEEbRgMo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/2fb4OeDpmkRFUzm2iHSIuYWuvkT2mgksjEE bRgMo. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257540&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Boiled donkey hide gelatin. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Donkey-hide gelatin, known as the &quot;Three Treasures&quot; along with ginseng and deer antlers, has unquestionable unparalleled popularity. It is widely rumored that the famous doctor Ye Tianshi, who once used Wutong leaves as a medicine introduction, said that donkey-hide gelatin is a product of flesh and blood and is the most nourishing. The so-called products of flesh and blood, that is, animal medicine, were highly regarded by Ye. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Donkey-hide gelatin is the glue produced in Adi, and the named region is a classic label for authentic medicinal materials. Tao Hongjing broke the topic: It came out of Dong&#39;e, so it was named donkey-hide gelatin. Li Shizhen refined and extended: Ajing is located sixty miles northeast of today&#39;s Yanggu County, Yanzhou Prefecture, Shandong Province, which is the ancient Dong&#39;a County. There are official residences that prohibit it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The talented scholar Cao Zhi moved to fiefdoms many times during his lifetime, and Dong&#39;a was his last stop before King Chen. After his death, he was buried in the local Yushan in accordance with his last wishes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called official residence prohibits it, which reveals the qualification of donkey-hide gelatin as an official tribute tribute. There is a &quot;Shui Jing Zhu&quot; that can be endorsed: (Dong&#39;e) On the west side of the north gate of the big city, there is a big well on Gao Shang. It is as big as a wheel and six or seven feet deep. It is used to cook glue every year and pay tribute to the heaven. &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; calls donkey hide gelatin. Therefore, it has the name of Ajing in the secular world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Li Shizhen&#39;s description, the Ajing water used for cooking glue was injected with Jishui. Use it to boil glue, and use it to stir the turbid water to make it clear. Therefore, Geji water is clear and heavy, and its nature tends to be downward. The so-called heavyness lies in the richness of minerals it contains. It is said that each pound of Ajing water is about 3 pounds heavier than ordinary well water and river water. It seems that boiling glue is like making wine, and living water with natural texture plays a considerable role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; mentioned by Li Daoyuan is the &quot;Shen Nong&#39;s Materia Medica&quot;. The origin of &quot;Compendium of Materia Medica&quot; is recorded in it, which shows the antiquity of donkey-hide gelatin production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the raw material of boiled glue, &quot;Famous Doctors&quot; says that it is made from boiled cowhide. In other words, donkey-hide gelatin in this era was originally cowhide. Li Shizhen pointed out that those using cow, buffalo and donkey skins were the top ones, followed by those using pig, horse, mule and ostrich skins, and those using various old skins, shoes and other items were the bottom. Most of the ancient recipes used cowhide, but later generations used donkey skin. As for the reason for this change, Chen Zangqi explained that all kinds of glues are mainly responsible for wind, antidiarrheal, and tonifying deficiency, and donkey skin is the most important for wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the replacement of cattle and donkeys should also be related to the fact that cattle are the main livestock power in farming and even military resources, so they are strictly controlled by the government. Qin law had strict laws that stipulated that those who killed cows and horses would die. Although later dynasties no longer required beheading, they still had to bear criminal responsibility. For example, Tang law stipulated that even if you kill your own cattle, you will be sentenced to one year in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The donkey, with its trimmed tail and drooping back, and its giant ears and two gongs, is regarded by the Central Plains people as a rare animal of the Xiongnu. According to Gu Yanwu&#39;s &quot;Rizhilu&quot;, since the Qin Dynasty and above, donkeys have not been seen in written records, even if they exist. Be an unusual animal. &quot;The donkey is an object. It was named after the Han Dynasty. It was filial to the martial arts and found its way into the forest. It was filial and spiritual and was honored. However, its species mostly came from outside the fortress.&quot; Probably during the Han Dynasty, donkeys &quot;entered the fortress with their tails attached.&quot; &quot;They are all our animals.&quot; From the appreciation of Shanglin&#39;s strange beasts, they can be used as livestock for transportation. They are resistant to extensive diseases and easy to drive. They are strong in disease resistance and have early maturity and longevity. They also win in the cost-effectiveness trade-off and win the favor of both the government and the private sector. The poet&#39;s descriptions of &quot;riding a donkey into the sword gate in the drizzle&quot; and &quot;the poetry of the sky and the sea are carried on the back of a donkey&quot; vaguely reveal the relationship between donkeys and literati. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to the use of donkey skin as medicine, it should be after its mass breeding. In addition to the use of donkeys for servitude, eating meat and sleeping on their hides is an appropriate meaning in the title, and tanning and making rubber are also included in the title. As for the uses of glue, Tao Hongjing pointed out that there are three types of glue: clear and thin glue used by painters; clear and thick glue called potting glue and used for medicinal purposes; turbid and black glue not used for medicine, but can be used to glue things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called donkey skin is the most popular, which is the conclusion of the Tang Dynasty. As late as the Northern Song Dynasty, the donkey hide gelatin made from black donkey skin and boiled in well water was recognized as the best. In the view of strict medical practitioners, outside Dong&#39;a, there is only donkey gelatin but no donkey-hide gelatin. However, due to the exclusivity of tributes and the official ban on Ajing, ceiling-level real glue is extremely rare. Most of the goods sold among the people are forged horsehide, old leather, saddle boots, etc., which smell foul and cannot be used as medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although counterfeit medicines have been condemned, they have never disappeared. As a doctor with a benevolent heart, Li Shizhen is considerate and considerate. The yellow color is as transparent as amber, or the light and black color is as black as lacquer. The true one does not have stinky skin, and the summer moon is not wet and soft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The prototype of Mr. Bai Qiye, played by Mr. Chen Baoguo in the drama &quot;The Mansion Gate&quot;, is Le Jingyu, the young master of Tongrentang. Mr. Lelao came to Jinan that year and founded Hongjitang. The donkey-hide gelatin he produced was known as the Nine Tips and Nine Roasts: peeling off the hair at the winter solstice, starting from the awakening of the stings, using copper pots and silver shovels, burning mulberry firewood, nine tips and nine moxibustions, and taking the ointment at nine days. There are ninety-nine processes, complicated but not many. The vernal equinox is exposed to the sun and the beginning of summer becomes glue. This is the path of Gongjiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shizhen’s explanation is more concise: When making all kinds of glue, from October to February or March... all raw skins are taken, soaked in water for four or five days, washed and scraped extremely clean. Boil, stir it from time to time, and add water constantly. When it is rotten, filter the juice and boil it into glue, pour it into a pot and wait for it to solidify. The glue that is close to the pelvic floor is called jiaojiao, and the glue that is salty and bitter is better when fried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the time line of glue making, &quot;Qi Min Yao Shu&quot; also said that it takes February, March, September and October to cook glue, and the remaining months are not enough. The reason why it is not successful is that if it is hot, it will not coagulate, and it will not make cakes; if it is cold, it will freeze and become sticky, and the glue will not stick. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is the preparation complicated, but also the preparation of the medicine is quite difficult. Tao Hongjing said: Whatever is used, it must be burned with fire. Lei Jiao, known as Thunder God, said: For any use, first soak it in pig fat overnight, take it out, dry it with willow wood and grind it before use. Li Shizhen divided and conquered it: the current method is to stir-fry pearls, stir-fry with flour, stir-fry, stir-fry with clam powder, stir-fry with grass ash, turn into ointment with wine, or hydrate the ointment, each should be based on its own prescription. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most famous effect of donkey-hide gelatin is to harmonize blood, nourish yin, remove wind and moisturize dryness. As Li Shizhen said, donkey-hide gelatin basically only replenishes blood and fluids, so it can clear the lungs, nourish yin and cure various syndromes. In addition, he pointedly mentioned that dysentery is often caused by excessive heat, and donkey-hide gelatin is an important medicine for the large intestine. Those with heat and toxin retention can be relieved; those without heat and toxin retention can be safe. From this, he regarded donkey-hide gelatin as a holy medicine and made it a god. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This classic classifies donkey-hide gelatin as a top-grade medicine, that is, it is a royal medicine that &quot;maintains life and responds to the sky, is non-toxic, and does not hurt people if taken for a long time.&quot; Although not all top-quality products are the best, donkey-hide gelatin is indeed comparable to ginseng and licorice, and is worthy of its god-like existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公安机关公开通缉缅北果敢自治区电信网络诈骗犯罪集团重要头目明学昌、明国平、明菊兰、明珍珍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260458]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12 11:12:56&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Currently, the situation of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar is severe, the social harm is serious, and the people have reacted strongly. Investigation by the Wenzhou City Public Security Bureau in Zhejiang Province revealed that Ming Xuechang, Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen are important leaders of a criminal group involved in telecommunications network fraud in the Kokang Autonomous Region in northern Myanmar. The criminal group headed by Ming Xuechang has organized and opened fraud for a long time. The den is open to armed fraud and carries out telecommunications and network fraud criminal activities targeting Chinese citizens. The amount of fraud is huge. Under the severe and high-pressure situation of the public security organs, it still does not restrain or stop, and continues to organize and carry out illegal and criminal activities. At the same time, it is suspected of intentional homicide. , intentional injury, illegal detention and other serious violent crimes, the circumstances are extremely bad and the consequences are extremely serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has been found that the criminal facts of Ming Xuechang, Ming Guoping, Ming Julan and Ming Zhenzhen are clear and the evidence is conclusive. The Wenzhou Municipal Public Security Bureau of Zhejiang Province has decided to issue a public reward for their arrest. The public security organs urged the four criminal suspects Ming Xuechang, Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen to recognize the situation clearly, step back from the brink, voluntarily surrender themselves, and strive for leniency. At the same time, we hope that all walks of life and the general public will actively report the crime and assist in the arrest of criminal suspects. For those who provide effective clues and assist in arrests, the public security organs will reward RMB 100,000 to RMB 500,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/UqJ0oPL9FmeNfZXTGzKDetP4S9YwiER5nzweN11E.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height= &quot;792&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/UqJ0oPL9FmeNfZXTGzKDetP4S9YwiER5nzweN11E.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258001&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/0UqEd83ptsiPSLyHQF2FwQgTl0WWin9CYMduHlQK.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;792&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/0UqEd83ptsiPSLyHQF2FwQgTl0WWin9CYMduHlQK.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258002&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/ctLXwsz1T06nEjNSwQzzRA7OzcOlWR1HqUU45BMM.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;792&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/12/ctLXwsz1T06nEjNSwQzzRA7OzcOlWR1HqUU45BMM.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258000&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/12/i056fcAa0u8aVFd1wraLjlR5IVKJxPD9uk9lUrN0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;792&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/i056fcAa0u8aVFd1wraLjlR5IVKJx PD9uk9lUrN0. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257999&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>