<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[网络炒热的韩国防猝死套餐，是真的要命]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257412]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/30/JDT8Ejb6qBaGrTcyi4GdEVs1TtAJGoO77KOirq5R.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/JDT8Ejb6qBaGrTcyi4GdEVs1TtAJGoO7 7KOirq5R. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252839&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图） &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, a sudden death prevention package that is said to have become popular in South Korea has been on the hot search. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This package is composed of coenzyme Q10, fish oil, lutein, vitamin D3 and other health products. Some netizens shared that they feel very energetic after taking it. Questioning that such a &quot;sudden death prevention package&quot; does not really have the effect of preventing sudden death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this regard, some experts believe that sudden death is a type of disease, and health food itself does not have a clinical role in treatment or prevention. It can be eaten but can only be used as a Health aid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the final analysis, the &quot;sudden death prevention package&quot; has triggered heated discussions, mainly due to the mentality of contemporary young people who love to stay up late and are afraid of sudden death. The truly effective &quot;sudden death prevention method&quot; &quot;what exactly is it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/d065c741f2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;548&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/22/d065c741f2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251683&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Why do people die suddenly? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First of all, let’s look at why people die suddenly from a medical perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;No other disease can compare with the suddenness, urgency, severity, malignancy and consequences of sudden death. The occurrence of sudden death is unexpected and cannot be predicted in most cases. This is why sudden death is the most terrible disease in the world. Clinically, sudden death can be divided into two categories, namely sudden cardiac death and non-cardiac sudden death. Among all patients who die suddenly, 75% are caused by heart disease, the most common cause of which is coronary heart disease; about 25% are caused by non-cardiac diseases (i.e., the patient has causes other than the heart). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to facilitate understanding, I divide it into internal causes and external causes. The internal cause is the premature aging of the body&#39;s own functions, weakening the ability to decompose and eliminate metabolic waste and toxins entering the body and produced by the body itself, resulting in abnormal body metabolism, increased blood lipids, blood sugar, and uric acid, and excessive accumulation of fat in the internal organs, blood, and subcutaneous tissue. Formation of atherosclerotic plaques (fatty plaques that line the walls of arteries). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Once these plaques rupture, they will immediately stimulate coagulation function in the corresponding blood vessels, forming thrombus almost instantly. If a certain branch of the heart blood vessel is blocked, Sudden death will occur if the heart is suddenly ischemic. Therefore, maintaining a youthful state of the body and improving the normal functions of various organ systems in the body are fundamental to prevention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;External factors refer to various factors outside the body and attached to the body, which lead to the deterioration of physical conditions. This is all too common in the workplace: the glamorous appearance cannot hide the tiredness caused by working overtime and staying up late, the pressure from bosses, superiors and project progress, the open and secret fights between peers and colleagues, commuting to and from work, squeezing into elevators, subways, heavy traffic jams, and lack of sleep. , irregular diet, having to socialize with each other, lack of exercise, supporting a family, and all kinds of consumption for the sake of face...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;All of these are overdrafting your body , making the already disordered hormone secretion and metabolic system in your body even more overwhelmed, exacerbating the possibility of tragedy. That is to say, insufficient rest, insufficient and extremely unbalanced nutrients, and long-term mental stress, resulting in the body being unable to repair and improve itself normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, the most fundamental thing is that your heart function is already in a bad state, but you don&#39;t know it at all. Coupled with the above-mentioned workplace pressures, the chance of sudden death greatly increases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/Hl2cmWoPON0F3tUJkXGtlvba93yX5nhFYxqhQTdi.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/Hl2cmWoPON0F3tUJkXGtlvba93yX5nhFYxqhQTdi.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252840&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（IC photo/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;You can’t just resign and quit, right? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some people say that my working status is like this, I can’t resign, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, for some people, resigning may be a good idea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, if you have to stick to this job in order to support your family, try to make the following adjustments, which will not only prevent sudden death, but more importantly It can make up for your overdrafted health and live a healthy life for yourself and your family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1. First go to a regular hospital and ask a responsible doctor to do a comprehensive physical examination (especially to check for hidden cardiovascular diseases). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2. Scientific diet and balanced nutrition: A reasonable dietary structure means that the nutrients contained in the diet are complete in variety, sufficient in quantity, and in appropriate proportions to satisfy both needs and requirements. It can meet the physiological needs of the body and avoid imbalances in the proportion of nutrients in the diet (or even nutritional disorders caused by lack or excess of certain nutrients). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is best to have three meals a day: a. Vegetables and fruits: more varieties are better, mainly supplementing vitamins, minerals and antioxidants, etc., every day The number of meals should be at least equivalent to the size of one&#39;s own fist; b. Protein foods: mainly supplement various amino acids, trace elements, vitamins, etc. necessary for the human body, including meat proteins (such as seafood, chicken, duck, and fish meat), each meal The quantity is equivalent to the size of your palm minus your fingers) and non-meat proteins (eggs, milk, soy products, etc., the quantity of each meal is equivalent to the size of your fist); c. Grain and starch foods: various rice and flour products, potatoes Categories, corn, etc., mainly supplement starch (sugar), vitamins, dietary fiber, etc. The amount of each meal is equivalent to the size of your own fist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, according to a random survey of more than 10,000 people by relevant research institutions in the United States, the vast majority of people are unable to achieve truly balanced nutrition through diet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;3. Adhere to scientific and reasonable exercise: According to the results of the physical examination, combined with physical condition and time, carry out step-by-step exercise (you can practice by yourself, or you can go to the gym to do it) Personal training depends on your own hobbies and level of wealth). However, no matter where you exercise, the so-called aerobic exercise (such as running, swimming, cycling, etc.) and anaerobic exercise (mainly strength exercise) must be closely integrated and indispensable, and must reach a certain intensity. Only then will your exercise have a real effect on improving physical function. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;4. Develop good living habits: Try not to stay up late. You may not feel the harm once or twice occasionally. Staying up late for a long time is overdrafting your health. . Adequate and high-quality sleep is a necessary means for the body to repair itself and regulate its functions. Overdraft without actively replenishing it is like a mobile phone battery that has been depleted but not recharged in time. The final result can be imagined. As for the harm that heavy drinking (whether short-term or long-term habitual) does to the body, even if I don’t say it, most people will understand it! &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;5. Emotional management: Although it is difficult to control emotions in a busy working environment, remember not to let yourself be overjoyed or sad. This is meaningful to ensure that you can live a healthy and safe life and maintain a harmonious family and society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;6. Supplement safe and effective health products: If you accept the basic common sense that the human body is composed of substances, you should understand that without an adequate material basis, the functions will not be sufficient. How much better would it be. Theoretically, all injuries in the human body can be cured through its own repair. The basic raw materials for repair are nutrients such as protein, lipids, sugars, vitamins, minerals, dietary fiber and water. However, the reality is that today’s food can no longer provide adequate and balanced nutrition to the body. Therefore, it is not a question of whether to take health supplements or not, but that you have to take health supplements for your health. Everyone&#39;s nutritional deficiencies exist objectively, but the degree of deficiency is different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;7. Appropriate drug intervention for discovered diseases: However, drugs only target symptoms, they are not the fundamental factor in solving the problem. The contribution of medical intervention to human health only accounts for about 10%, and the rest is the result of the above comprehensive factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;I found someone suspected of sudden death, what should I do? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What should you do if you find someone suspected of sudden death? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First, identify cardiac arrest and call 120 emergency services. Second, take cardiopulmonary resuscitation measures quickly. I won’t go into details about the specific steps. The principle is to check breathing and heartbeat, and clear the airway, and then perform cardiopulmonary resuscitation mainly with chest compressions (if it is a sudden cardiac arrest). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The compression position is in the middle left of the sternum (most people&#39;s heart is in the left chest), 100 to 120 times per minute, and the depth is 5 to 6 centimeters. The key is to continue compressions until professional rescuers arrive. Third, implement defibrillation as soon as possible. For sudden cardiac arrest, the most effective first aid method is electric defibrillation. If it is done one minute earlier, the patient&#39;s hope of survival will increase by 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国男篮亚运两连胜，球员坦言球队仍需成长适应大赛强度]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257936]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Zhenlin broke through Chinese Taipei under the basket The player defends and shoots the basket.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/48085416cd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/48085416cd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Zhenlin broke through the defense of Chinese Taipei team players under the basket and shot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 28, 2023, in the Asian Games Basketball Men’s Preliminary Group B match at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Gymnasium, the Chinese team ushered in the first place in the group stage. The two opponents were the Chinese Taipei team. In the end, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team defeated the opponent 89-69 and won two consecutive victories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team player Zhao Jiwei broke through with the ball during the game. He scored 19 points and sent 7 assists.&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/1a5da9a952.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;746&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/1a5da9a952.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 28, Chinese team player Zhao Jiwei made a breakthrough with the ball during the game. He scored 19 points in this game and also sent 7 assists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this game, the Chinese team players put a lot of pressure on the opposing players on the defensive end. The Chinese Taipei team, which is good at shooting, only shot 31 from three-point range. %. On the offensive end, the Chinese team flourished under the coordination of Zhao Jiwei. Du Runwang hit 5 long-range shots and Zhang Zhenlin performed many wonderful dunks. Zhao Jiwei scored a team-high 19 points, all of his shots were outside the three-point line. He made 6 of 8 three-pointers, with a hit rate of 75%, and provided 7 assists. The other team members&#39; scoring data were Du Runwang with 17 points, Hu Jinqiu with 15 points, Zhang Zhenlin with 10 points and 10 rebounds, Wang Zhelin with 9 points and 8 rebounds, Cui Yongxi with 9 points, Zhu Junlong with 5 points and 4 rebounds, Zhao Rui with 2 points and 2 rebounds, and Hu Mingxuan with 3 points. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Zhenlin dunked during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/30/3066d40e81.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1448&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/3066d40e81. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Zhenlin dunked during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Zhelin made a layup during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/30/45aed7805b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1465&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/45aed7805b .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252835&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Zhelin made a layup during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Jiwei said in an interview after the game that there are many players in the current team participating in the World Series and Asian Games for the first time, including himself, who is also participating in the Asian Games for the first time. Yes, the team must adapt to the intensity of international competitions. The Chinese men&#39;s basketball team had a total of 17 free throw opportunities in this game, but only 8 were made, with a free throw shooting rate of only 47%. Zhao Jiwei said that in addition to basic skills, it is more about mentality. In the future, more needs to be done Keep looking for the feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team player Wang Zhelin made a layup under the defense of Chinese Taipei team player Atino.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/30/a420f9f83b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1342&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/30/a420f9f83b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252836&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 28, 2023, Chinese team Player Wang Zhelin made a layup under the defense of Chinese Taipei player Atino. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the next game, the Chinese men&#39;s basketball team will face its third opponent, the Hong Kong team of China, at 8 pm on September 30. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team players high-fived after scoring.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/30/602fd470cd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1453&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/30/602fd470cd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252837&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 28, 2023, Chinese team players high-fived after scoring. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多劳多得：45年前，五元钱的“清远经验”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257912]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;The five-yuan reward may not seem like much now, but by chance, the nitrogen fertilizer in 1978 The factory has a new look!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 20, 2023, the &quot;Storytelling Meeting for the 45th Anniversary of Reform and Opening Up&quot; hosted by the Information Office of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Government was held in Qingyuan. Liang Gewen, the former Secretary of the Qingyuan Municipal Party Committee, mentioned it again. The &quot;Qingyuan Experience&quot; evolved from the 5 yuan reward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Qingyuan Experience&quot; was an attempt by Qingyuan to expand enterprise autonomy and mobilize workers&#39; enthusiasm at the beginning of reform and opening up, and pioneered the reform of state-owned enterprises in Guangdong. Over the past 45 years, the &quot;Qingyuan Experience&quot; advocating &quot;dare to be the first&quot; has continued to play different roles in various historical periods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Liang Gewen, the event also invited Deng Sai from the Party Building Office of the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of Guangdong Province and Lu Guowei, member of the Party Branch of Lianzhang Village, Lianjiangkou Town, Yingde City. The three of them witnessed different stages of reform and opening up. . Deng Sai was one of the first batch of civil servants recruited openly when the Provincial State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission was established in 2004. He has deep feelings about the reform of state-owned enterprises in the past two decades. Lu Guowei shared the great changes in Lianzhang Village in the past five years from the perspective of a grassroots poverty alleviation cadre. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the event, the 80-year-old Liang Gewen always emphasized that today we still need to emancipate our minds and boldly innovate. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;More work, more rewards, turn losses into profits&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1978, on the eve of reform and opening up, Qingyuan began to implement the &quot;exceeding plan profit commission bonus&quot; reform . Liang Gewen, then the press secretary of the Qingyuan County Party Committee, was 35 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liang Gewen has a deep understanding of Qingyuan’s traffic. Qingyuan is located in the mountainous area of ​​northern Guangdong and has inconvenient transportation. At that time, there was no road from Qingyuan to Guangzhou, so one had to cross the river by boat and then take a bumpy car. Liang Gewen went to Guangzhou to deliver articles to newspapers. Riding a motorcycle was faster than a car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The geographical location led to Qingyuan&#39;s economic backwardness to a certain extent. Its economic aggregate and fiscal revenue basically ranked at the bottom of the province at that time. In 1977, Qingyuan failed to complete the profit plan issued by the state and suffered a loss of more than 300,000 yuan. Some companies even needed to borrow money from the local government to pay workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because workers eat from a big pot, it doesn’t make much difference whether they work more or less. Qingyuan’s largest state-owned nitrogen fertilizer factory at the time faced the problem of workers being passive and slow in working. The nitrogen fertilizer plant, which was put into operation in 1970, was the largest factory with the most workers in Qingyuan at that time. However, the annual output of a medium-sized fertilizer factory with more than 400 people was only more than 5,000 tons at its peak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Output cannot increase, and the factory has been losing money year after year. According to factory employees, when farmers queued up to buy fertilizer, some people started fighting over it. &quot;If fertilizers cannot keep up, food production will be reduced, and farmers will have to look for fertilizers everywhere.&quot; Liang Gewen said. During the busy farming season of July and August every year, the county party committee secretary would come to the factory to supervise production. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The turning point occurred in October 1978. A policy called &quot;Super Planned Profit Commission Award&quot; was first piloted at Qingyuan Nitrogen Fertilizer Plant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this reform, there was an accident in the factory. A worker accidentally closed the wrong valve of a gas tank, causing the gas tank to become severely deformed. According to past experience, it takes three months to repair. In order to meet the construction deadline, the factory leaders summoned technical personnel from all over Qingyuan and promised that whoever could repair the equipment and resume production in advance would be rewarded 5 yuan. In the end, it only took 10 days to complete the task. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the concept of 5 yuan? At that time, workers&#39; monthly salary was 33 yuan. In order to support their families, many workers go to the mountains to cut firewood, go down to the rivers to catch fish, and fish for snails in the fields after get off work to increase their income. &quot;Five yuan can buy eight pounds of pork. At that time, the target was half a pound of pork per person per month.&quot; Liang Gewen said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident made the factory leaders realize that incentives can be used to mobilize motivation. In the atmosphere of great discussion on the issue of truth standards, the nitrogen fertilizer plant also held a discussion meeting. An agreement was reached at the meeting to improve everyone&#39;s enthusiasm through reforming the reward system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since October 1978, the county party committee began to pilot the &quot;exceeding plan profit commission award&quot; in four plants including the nitrogen fertilizer plant. &quot;For example, if we plan to hand over 1 million yuan in profits, if the annual profit is 1.5 million yuan, we will take part of the 500,000 yuan and distribute it to the workers.&quot; Liang Gewen explained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the mechanism of more reward for more work, the efficiency of the factory has been significantly improved. After 18 days of trial operation, a profit of 35,000 yuan was achieved in the month. This was also the first month to achieve profit in nine years of production. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Opposition&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Reform is not without opposition. Some departments in the county consider this to be a &quot;private division of state property.&quot; Fortunately, with the support of county leaders, it was implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reform of the nitrogen fertilizer plant has even attracted the attention of the Guangdong Provincial Government. But the opinions in the province are not unified. In May 1979, the finance and labor departments of Guangdong Province jointly issued a document requiring Qingyuan County to stop implementing the &quot;exceeding plan profit commission award.&quot; The reason is that there is a lack of documentary evidence and the commission ratio is too large. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months later, at the group discussion of the Guangdong Provincial Industrial Transportation Production Increase and Conservation Conference, the debate on the &quot;Qingyuan Experience&quot; was settled. The meeting decided to promote Qingyuan’s “Exceeding Plan Profit Commission Award” to county-owned industrial enterprises across Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that since turning losses into profits in 1979, the nitrogen fertilizer plant has achieved profits every year. By 1989, it had achieved a total profit of nearly 10 million yuan for 11 consecutive years. In the years that followed, Liang Gewen was often asked about the impact of the &quot;Qingyuan Experience&quot; on Guangdong. His answer was simple - the most important thing was that the cadres and masses of the nitrogen fertilizer plant dared to be the first and boldly innovated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The courage to be the first and bold innovation in the &quot;Qingyuan Experience&quot; have also taken root in the reform of state-owned enterprises in Guangdong Province. According to Deng Sai, since the three-year action of state-owned enterprise reform was launched in 2020, &quot;Guangdong&#39;s state-owned economic layout structure has also undergone major changes, and state-owned capital has become more concentrated in important industries and key areas related to the national economy and people&#39;s livelihood.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that as of the end of 2022, the total assets of local state-owned assets supervision enterprises in Guangdong Province reached 16.27 trillion yuan, ranking third among local supervision enterprises in the country. In 2022, the operating income and profits of local state-owned assets supervision enterprises in the province The total amount ranked third and second in the country respectively. Among the province&#39;s local state-owned assets supervision enterprises, 6 have entered the Fortune Global 500. &quot;This means that Guangdong&#39;s state-owned economy continues to grow in scale and strength, and is promoting the sustained and healthy development of the national economy.&quot; Deng Sai said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lianzhang Village, located in the northeast of Qingyuan City, is experiencing the &quot;Qingyuan Experience&quot; in the new era. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Born in 1993, Lu Guowei is a native of Lianzhang Village. He often hears people mention the story of the reform of the nitrogen fertilizer plant. In 2017, Lu Guowei returned to his hometown and became a grassroots poverty alleviation cadre. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Guowei remembers that when he was a child, Lianzhang Village was one of the poorest villages in Lianjiangkou Town. The village was surrounded by mountains and only connected to the outside world by a rugged road. The village&#39;s pillar industry was Sugar orange. &quot;Except for a small amount of rice, peanuts, and corn, every household grows sugar oranges,&quot; Lu Guowei said. In 2011, affected by Huanglongbing, almost all the sugar orange trees in the village were wiped out. In the end, except for a small number of people planting bamboo shoots, most young adults chose to go out to work, while the elderly and children stayed behind in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, Lianzhang Village has gradually explored new paths for rural development. On the basis of vigorously developing specialty industries such as bamboo shoots and black tea, it also simultaneously promotes the intensive processing of specialty agricultural products. Lu Guowei said that currently there are more than 20 small and large enterprises stationed in the village, realizing everyone&#39;s wish to work at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Whether it is for Lianzhang Village or Qingyuan, we still have to dare to think and act.&quot; Liang Gewen said with emotion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在诺奖得主古尔纳的故乡，大海不再只有伤痛 | 月是故乡明②]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257356]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/ 11/07/b840996666c29ba0936ba0ac8e934fd8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;578&quot; height=&quot;386&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/ b840996666c29ba0936ba0ac8e934fd8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169416&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Zanzibar, a woman picks up seaweed at low tide. /ICphoto&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the occasion of the New Year in 2016, I came to Zanzibar for the first time - &quot;Unguja Island&quot; from the southern big island&lt;/span>;&lt;span style =&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(also known as &quot;Zanzibar Island&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, the northern island &quot;Pemba Island&quot; and other small islands, hereinafter referred to as &quot;Zanzibar Island&quot;—— The capital of Stone Town&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(&quot;StoneTown&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, on a hazy morning at sunrise, I walked to the edge of the Indian Ocean with jagged reefs. Fishermen returning from the sea came ashore. They were shirtless, laughing and yelling in Swahili with tired faces. They pulled the not-full nets ashore, picked out lobsters, large octopus and tuna, and threw aside the remaining inferior goods. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A few hours later, these high-quality and fresh seafood will be delivered to a number of high-end Western, Indian, Arabic or Swahili restaurants. Then it is placed on the plates of tourists from all over the world. Those of poor quality will be transported to the local fish market and sold to countless people wearing bamboo baskets on their heads and wearing colorful kanga at a price of less than one-twentieth.&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #888888;&quot;>;(Traditional costumes of Swahili women)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, local women chattering enthusiastically. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I think that if I read the novels of Abdul Razak Gourna, at that moment, I might not be able to help but think of those in his different stories. A long paragraph about Mulberry Island, and empathize with it, such as: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url=&quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8 -length=&quot;113&quot; data-source-title=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;...the water plants were washed endlessly by the waves, lying on the beach It’s like a sunburned dream. There’s also the smell of sea salt, floating in every corner, in the nostrils and in the cochlea, just like the monsoon wind blowing from the sea and the port.&quot; (&quot;Farewell&quot; &quot;Memory of Departure&quot;, 1987)&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Unfortunately, although I have lived in Tanzania for six years and visited San Island three times, on October 7, 2021 Before the Nobel Prize for Literature was awarded to Gurna, I knew nothing about this author who grew up on Sand Island until he was 18 years old. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;1955, Stone Town&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the East African Islands, the dominant position has always been the sea, and the ocean further offshore. Every November, the southwest monsoon and ocean currents blow through southern India, southern Arabia and the coast of Somalia, to San Island, and then further south to the Comoros Islands and Madagascar. Before tourism became the main industry of Sand Island, the vast majority of people in Stone Town relied on the sea for their livelihood, including fishermen, sailors and merchants who came and went with the wind. At one time, there were dangerous merchants who sold ivory, spices and slaves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In today&#39;s Stone City, various houses of different sizes are dotted along the entire coastline. Many are Islamic-style buildings, and a few are decorated with complicated European patterns. It has been converted into post offices, office buildings, cafes, restaurants and private residences, among which there are many simple shabby iron shacks owned by local fishermen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At the beginning of 2019, I came to Stone City for the third time. Taking advantage of the New Year holiday, I wandered around for nearly a week, looking at the remains of the ancient shell city wall seven or eight centuries ago. See the dungeons and chains at the former site of the slave trading market, and the monument to the 1964 Zan Island Uprising&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(Zanzibar uprising to overthrow the Sudanese rule, 4 years later, Gurna left Sang to go to England)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;See how the lovely blue water licks the rocks of history little by little. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/0f29c1a85781d77f84cf6340ecd8f7ba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/0f29c1a85781d77f84cf6340ecd8f7ba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169419&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;Writer Abdul-Razzak Gurnatou/Visual China&lt;/span >;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;One evening, I was walking in the old city and came to a square old house. It was hidden, but it was empty inside. It is not clear whether the house is for private or public use. Walking around the alley next to the house to the backyard, you can see a group of little boys wearing robes and square hats. They are squatting and playing with marbles and soda bottle caps. On the other side of the yard, there were several men leaning against the wall. They crossed their arms and talked about the rainy season, the wind direction and the lowest price for buying lilacs. Behind them were several women who set up small stalls selling fruits and vegetables. They seemed to be selling scattered dried fish, cherry tomatoes and onions. In fact, they were more interested in chatting. It didn&#39;t matter whether the things could be sold or not. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The sun was setting at that time, and the light shone just right in the yard and on the roof, and finally briefly settled on the sweaty brows and cheeks of men, women, old and young. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After walking out of the yard, I went to a cafe across the street, ordered a cup of Americano with clove flavor, and pulled out an old book from the bookshelf. The book is called &quot;Eye of Cloves&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(&quot;Eye of Cloves&quot;, F.D. Omani)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, published in 1955. When I opened it, I didn&#39;t have any expectations, it was just to kill time. Sand Island is called the &quot;Lilac Island&quot;, so judging from this title, it is not much different from most travel books about Sand Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I flipped through the pages of the book until I saw an old black and white photo. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Isn’t that square house and yard in the photo the same place I just passed by? More than fifty years have passed, and nothing seems to have changed. It seems that even people&#39;s status and clothing have been frozen at that moment. The adults sit or stand bored, and the children run or jump carefree. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The caption of the photo reads: Arab residential area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This description can be used to summarize almost any neighborhood I passed through today, but to put it more accurately, most of the neighborhoods can be called &quot;Indian Arab Swahili&quot; Xili Mixed Residential Area&quot;. Because in today&#39;s Stone City, the vast majority of locals are accustomed to interracial trade, mixing, and intermarriage. It is difficult to accurately identify whether a person is of Arab, Indian, Southeast Asian, or Sri Lankan descent just by looking at his skin color and dress. With Vasili ancestry or a mixture of two or even three of them, almost everyone became a &quot;Zanzibar&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/b916a255dac148c595805f20cc1d0b79.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/b916a255dac148c595805f20cc1d0b79.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169420&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;Overlooking Stone City/Visual China&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span >;In 2015, Gurner mentioned this residential area in a lecture at the University of Kent where he teaches. He was born and grew up in Stone Town, an area generally known as the &quot;Arab residential area.&quot; He projected a related black-and-white photo in class. The photo showed a small square house with a simple two-story building standing on the left. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url=&quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8-length=&quot;98&quot; data-source-title=&quot;&quot; >; &lt;p>;&quot;I was born in the small building on the left. When I was a child, we always stood on the terrace on the second floor and watched the sailing ships leaving the port or returning from the sea, one after another, loaded with various goods. If you go downstairs and pass through the courtyard downstairs, you will see a workplace, a warehouse, and a vegetable market behind it.&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url= &quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8-length=&quot;244&quot; data-source-title=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;p>;But what you can’t see from the photo is what kind of person he is. Live in this place. If you could see them, you might feel helpless like me. Why? Because when the outside world talks about us and this place, they will always savagely describe it as The complexity and richness are summed up in these seven colorless words (referring to the &quot;Arab residential area&quot;)... But in fact, in the house at the back, there lived an Indian family; next to them, lived The president of the Lilac Planting Association is an Englishman; the house on the far side is the local police station, and the chief is a San Island native of Somali descent; behind the police station is a cafe run by a Yemeni businessman... But According to convention, this is only an Arab residential area.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Gulna described all this calmly to the thoughtful college students in the audience, except for the slightly wrinkled Meifeng, no emotion can be seen. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I think of that photo taken in 1955. Gurna was only about 7 years old that year. Maybe he was among the group of children playing in the background of the photo. From that time until he left home at the age of 18, it was a decade of great change in the history of Sang Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/5da0c2c9b6ad5aaebca8654dfef6c27c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/5da0c2c9b6ad5aaebca8654dfef6c27c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A man draws characteristic tingatinga paintings and sells them to tourists/ICphoto&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;1964, Mulberry Island Revolution&lt;/h3>; &lt; p>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Lilac Eyes&quot;, I also turned to another dated black and white photo. Its caption read: European residential area - although the large Arab-style flat-roofed building in the photo looks There is nothing &quot;European&quot; about it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The next day, I found out the specific location of the building. After arriving, I discovered that the building complex was built one after another by Arab merchants two to three centuries ago. In the 19th century, the British became more and more active on Sand Island. Until the end of the 19th century, Sand Island became a British protectorate and this area was officially occupied by the British. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1872, Richard Belden published two issues of his travel diary about Zan Island, &quot;Zanzibar: City, Island and Seaside&quot;, and many subsequent comments They all thought that he might want to use this to hint that European readers had begun to explore the source of the Nile in 1856, much earlier than Livingston. But surprisingly, the influence of this diary is more evident in his inadvertent description of the slave trading system on Sand Island, which reminds people that the slave trade in East Africa is no less rampant than in West Africa. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a meeting place for Arabs, Indians, Europeans and Africans, San Island is like a corridor connecting various rooms and halls, and at the same time provides sweet dates from the Arab region. Plantations, the tea fields of India, and the sugar industry of Southeast Asia&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(even the Americas)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; provided labor. The most miserable ones were the male slaves who were selected as eunuchs by the Ottoman Empire. Because of the unhygienic conditions of castration, usually only one in ten could survive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Belden mentioned: Investigations show that before 1897, when the British used both carrot and stick to ask the Sultan who was in power at that time to abolish slavery, two-thirds of the people on Sand Island were of the population belonged to the slave class. Still, Belden wrote, it was difficult for him to differentiate between black and brown people and what their ancestry was. &quot;Swahili, Persian&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(later developed into the &quot;Shiraz ethnic group&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, Arabia and India...all mixed together , I feel that the people here&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(referring to Sang Island)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; are simply like a brand new race.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 1890, the British officially took over Sand Island, but did not provide any effective and constructive mechanism for sustainable development. Land, wealth and power are still highly concentrated in Asia&lt;/span>;&lt;span style =&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(Including Arabia)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In the hands of the merchant class. At the same time, as was the practice in many other colonial powers, the rulers adopted a rigid management method in Sand Island by classifying all civilians according to their ethnicity and forcing them into a certain ethnic identity group. This made the tension inherent in the complex and subtle multi-racial mixture of Mulberry Island suddenly become tense. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Until the 1950s, a political storm against colonial rule swept across Africa. In 1963, Sand Island declared independence from the United Kingdom, the new Sudan succeeded to the throne, and British forces hurriedly withdrew from Sand Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Two days after leaving the &quot;European residential area&quot;, I came to the outskirts of Stone City and stayed at a B&amp;B recommended by a friend. &quot;Chat with the boss, you I&#39;ll be interested.&quot; My friend told me with a wink. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wilson, the owner of the B&amp;B, is a Tanzanian, British-Indian, 70-year-old man. He was born and raised on Sand Island until he was 6 years old, and then moved to Sang Island with his parents. Dar es Salaam&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(Tanzania&#39;s largest city)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;until the age of 20, then went to Edinburgh to attend university for four years. anthropology. After graduation, he changed three or four teaching jobs. &quot;I felt like I couldn&#39;t find a sense of belonging no matter how much I stayed in Europe,&quot; so he returned to East Africa. At first he wanted to take root on San Island again, but before he could settle down, he encountered the 1964 revolution. He had to take his Indian wife and three children and flee to Nairobi and Mombasa on the coast of Kenya, where he lived for more than ten years. Then we moved to the evergreen town of Mosh at the foot of Mount Kilimanjaro in Tanzania. It was not until 2005 that he returned to Sang Island and has settled there ever since. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;I found Wilson and sat with him among the coconut trees in the evening breeze, drinking ice-cold ginger ale. His eyes were as low as his voice, and like most people on Mulberry Island, it was difficult to tell where he came from just by looking at his appearance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“Although I am not a real Sandao person, when I talked about the revolution with many Sandao people, I found that their memories of it and their The definition of it - whether it is good or bad, good or bad, depends largely on who they consider their best friend, who they often share a pot of coffee with, or who they often invite into their home. Relatives and friends for dinner, in general, are extremely personal. For example, if your best friend is an Indian or a Shiraz, your evaluation of the revolution may be completely different. , because the Indians may be robbed and killed, but Shiraz can escape unscathed...&quot; Wilson said slowly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“But in fact, the revolution had already begun to take shape before 1964,” Wilson continued, “because it had only been more than half a century since slavery was abolished. , the old skeleton of society was basically shattered, and a reasonable new skeleton had not yet taken shape. It was full of loopholes. In addition, the British implemented many policies and regulations on clear class divisions. The Arabs still occupied a large number of people in San Island at that time. Absolutely outstanding status. So when the British withdrew, the undercurrent of conflict between the majority of landless African laborers and the minority of Arab landowners immediately transformed into a revolution.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;Wilson still remembers that in 1963, in Stone Town after independence, the iron gates of the police station were opened one after another, and all the imprisoned and beaten Africans poured into the streets and alleys, with eyes full of resentment and rage, as if they were gathering strength. , volcanic lava ready to erupt at any time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 3 a.m. on January 12, 1964, the &quot;African-Shirazi Party&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>; (ASP, Afro-Shirazi Party&quot; member and Ugandan John Okello led 600-800 &quot;revolutionaries&quot; with extremely simple equipment to launch a surprise attack on the police headquarters and radio station. They had no guns and ammunition, only spears, machetes, iron rods and daggers. However, because of their surprise and desperate determination, they won comprehensively in just a few hours. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this regard, the leader of the revolution, Oklo, always insisted that the actions of himself and other insurrectionists were &quot;pilgrimage acts&quot; in order to do justice for heaven and liberate the people who were persecuted. The people of San Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/a73eb2ebf13993d40816f628301beeb7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/a73eb2ebf13993d40816f628301beeb7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Citizens chatting on the street/ICphoto&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;2005, at the seaside&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In &quot;Pilgrimage&quot; &quot;Pilgrims Way&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(PilgrimsWay, 1988)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;In &quot;PilgrimsWay, 1988&quot;, Gulner set the protagonist Dauda as a man who lived on the island of Mulberry in 1964. After the revolution, he fled to Canterbury&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #888888;&quot;>;(British city)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and became a nurse in a hospital. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After living in England for many years, Dauda returned to Stone City. At the seaside, I remembered that I and my friend Bosie once sat on the pier like this, &quot;watching the sea foaming with hands and feet and gnashing teeth.&quot; I remembered that on the same day, they paddled out to sea in a small boat and enjoyed that moment &quot;like &quot;Freedom without borders&quot;, watch how the Stone City gradually becomes smaller and smaller behind you, until &quot;it seems to have turned into a beautiful mirage&quot;. At that moment, they fantasized about escaping from the narrow and twisted streets of this small town and going to the distance to find opportunities as colorful as soap bubbles. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/3f125a9a5679eec53025d346922a999f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/21/11/07/3f125a9a5679eec53025d346922a999f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;169425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Picture of a boy diving near Stone City Pier/ICphoto&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Suddenly, the wind direction and ocean current seemed to be disturbed, and the boat started to stumble. Dauda became wary, but Bossi told him with a smile that this was just a sign that the northeast monsoon &quot;musim&quot; was blowing from the coast of India and Arabia to East Africa, while rowing the boat steadily steadily. When the sea seemed to have calmed down, Bosie explained why he could not leave his mother and daughter and go to England with Dauda, ​​and then come back to take care of them after he had established a foothold:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style &quot;One day, these people who we have regarded and used as slaves for centuries will unite and cut the throats of those who enslaved them. To At that time, the Indians will go back to India and the Arabs will flee back to their Arabia. What about you and me? What will we do... We will be slaughtered like animals... Who will care about us? They just They will tell us that this is Africa, their Africa, even though we have lived on this land for more years than they have.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Bosi then handed the boat over to Dao As a challenge, he was asked to row the boat back to the shore and jump into the sea to swim back by himself. But the sea suddenly changed its face, and fierce hurricanes filled the entire ocean. &quot;I was struggling and beating the wooden paddle randomly,&quot; Daoda recalled, &quot;but when the storm finally calmed down, I looked around, but No more Bosie.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url=&quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8-length=&quot;132&quot; data-source-title=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;&quot;I can&#39;t find him... Bo Xi, I miss you. Even at this moment, I am still crying for you. What else can I say? The wind and tide pushed me to the north headland and pulled me ashore. I didn’t even know who I was. How did I finally get back to the shore after I tried everything possible... But Bosie, you missed the worst part. The moment I landed, I was beaten with sticks and stones.&quot;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Gurner set the two endpoints of the timeline in &quot;a certain November when the northeast monsoon is about to begin as usual and merchants are about to visit East Africa again, and the slave trade is about to begin. It will be between November, when the trade of Sang Island once again reached a climax, and January 12, when the revolution of Sang Island broke out in 1964. Drag the scale back and forth between these two points, discrete and aggregate, and start over and over again. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Later, Wilson took me to a beach 40 kilometers away from the B&amp;B, where he and his family had sat and waited for hundreds of hours under the scorching sun. Beaches expecting British rescue signals and ships from Kenya. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At 10 a.m., this unnamed beach not close to Stone City and unknown to tourists is empty and quiet, with no one and no wind, and only the bright sunshine shines warmly Staring at the milky white sand made me feel dizzy after just looking at it for a little while. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;About the beach, in &quot;Farewell Memories&quot;, Gurner wrote: In the past, those slaves who refused to be slaves would come to the beach next to Stone City. , and died there. Their corpses will float on the sea together with dead branches, leaves, debris and garbage, showing the fatigue after the struggle, just like their wrinkled black skin and the broken hearts under the skin. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In addition, I wonder if the beach where Daoda frantically searched for Bosi and was beaten crazily was similar to this one? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In 2005, Gurna published &quot;Escape&quot;. Like almost all his novels, it is also about &quot;wanting to escape from a foreign land that cannot be escaped, and wanting to return to a foreign land that cannot be escaped.&quot; The story of immigrants who cannot return to their hometown. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In the same year, after years of struggling with his inner alter ego, Wilson finally plucked up the courage to return to Mulberry Island alone. Not long after he settled down, he met his current wife, Khadija, a girl who was almost 30 years younger than him and born and raised in Sang Island. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The afternoon after returning from the beach with Wilson, Khadija and I sat on a wicker chair by the sea, picking fresh wild spinach and preparing dinner together. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Hadija was born in the 1970s and grew up in a fisherman&#39;s home. She only had general concepts about the slave trade, colonization and revolution, and did not have many specific feelings. Wilson almost never mentioned to her those bitter memories that had been sealed for a long time and seemed to have happened yesterday. &quot;I fell in love with her simplicity, carefreeness, and no need to be entangled in the past... In short, I fell in love with her.&quot; , experiencing too much is not a good thing. Fortunately, the current generation of Sang Island has revived because of tourism. After many years, the sea is no longer just a symbol for most people. With the pain and shadow, it once again became their hope.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Wilson&#39;s emotion is still in my mind yesterday, reminding me of a passage in Gurner&#39;s book Words: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote data-type=&quot;2&quot; data-url=&quot;&quot; data-author-name=&quot;&quot; data-content-utf8-length=&quot;129&quot; data-source-title= &quot;&quot;>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;&quot;Going back to the beach feels like returning home. How can I put it? It&#39;s like I can realize that this place once belonged to me... No matter where you go here, you will be treated like one of your own family... I can still feel the generosity in her bones from this place. Nobility and palpable passion.&quot; (&quot;By the Sea&quot;, 2001) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more Multiple RSS: &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href= &quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[呼伦贝尔：一抹秋颜，油画里的童话 | 眼睛在旅游①]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257596]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[篁岭“晒秋”丨指尖华夏①]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257580]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province, during the harvest season of fruits and vegetables, Huangling Village Villagers used bamboo plaques to hold harvested red peppers, corns, pumpkins, beans and other crops, and placed them on wooden racks in Hui-style houses for drying, outlining pictures of &quot;autumn sun-bathing&quot; in mountain villages with a bumper harvest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/JJ8Fw9wkQc612fkckK0w8E2Vj5dxVfj8qgbwibKJ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height= &quot;801&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/25/JJ8Fw9wkQc612fkckK0w8E2Vj5dxVfj8qgbwibKJ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251994&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Huangling Village, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province, villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/djIu7O6bSFec6lMrEFlsBfFS6faaIXyzgP0HqZem.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;756&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/djIu7O6bSFec6lMrEFlsBfFS6faaIXyzgP0HqZem.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251993&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/hy2QJB2VLUg8vjvzoIfahKqRVAAeNRGiuKPNR5wp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/hy2QJB2VLUg8vjvzoIfahKqRVAAeNRGiuKPNR5wp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251991&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/y5pMPP9HGJVGpBAWK55N1xtlg65nzgsqbxnmJnAd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;739&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/y5pMPP9HGJVGpBAWK55N1xtlg65nzgsqbxnmJnAd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251990&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/gwwGmmz7mu1OZTfMcA7JZlAzUwOoWfPmFvcVa9pE.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/gwwGmmz7mu1OZTfMcA7JZlAzUwOoWfPmFvcVa9pE.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251989&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/25/ofIyLJjx6z174cq6PIVNTZpltMilcx1WeSbuAqNU.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/25/ofIyLJjx6z174cq6PIVNTZpltMilcx1WeSbuAqNU.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251988&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Huangling, Jiangwan Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City, Jiangxi Province Villagers dry red peppers, corn and other crops on wooden frames in their houses. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/CICPHOTO/Hu Dunhuang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一身都是月 | 中秋国庆“悦”读专题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257720]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 21:23:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;This is Southern Weekend’s “Joy” reading special topic, and I’ll see you again. At this moment, maybe you are already on the road. go home? Visiting friends? Or run all the way to poetry and the distance. The meaning of reading is to make time more valuable and make the journey no longer long and lonely. So, please keep these selected contents, take an 8-day long vacation, blow out the reading lamp, and be covered with moon.</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 21:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在故乡普洱茶山，醉茶]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257357]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h3>;The temptation of spring tea is greater than the virus&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;On the sixth day of the first lunar month of 2020, because Due to the novel coronavirus pneumonia, the county has been closed down. I sent a message to my older cousin in the countryside early in the morning to ask how my relatives in my hometown were doing. My cousin said everything was fine. He has asked his family not to wander around outside unless they have nothing to do; and for his uncle who likes to hunt wild animals in the mountains, he has been strictly forbidden to go hunting in the mountains again. &quot;My uncle is quite honest,&quot; my cousin said. This makes me a little bit unbelievable. My uncle has always been fiery, but now he is willing to listen to his cousin. It seems that his dignity as the head of the family has already been established. My cousin is very busy. He leaves early and comes home late every day. He is the barefoot doctor in the village. He has to go to the monitoring point at the entrance of the village to measure the body temperature of outsiders every day. He has a heavy responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a special period, there are still outsiders coming, for no other reason than that my hometown is one of the best producing areas of Pu&#39;er tea in Yunnan, and March and April are the time to start picking spring tea. In previous years, before the spring tea was picked, many foreign merchants would come to the village early to reserve tea trees and tea farmers, so that the first crop of spring tea could be purchased, packaged, and transported as soon as it was roasted. Although there are not so many people coming this year, for some people, the temptation of spring tea is still greater than the virus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/GKBNpqDRxP4vc2LgiCeJsYZbFjwjbkfejw1kFD3f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/GKBNpqDRxP4vc2LgiCeJsYZbFjwjbkfejw1kFD3f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Spring in Pu&#39;er Tea Mountain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Information/Pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pu&#39;erbanna area belongs to the middle and low mountains and hilly areas, with interspersed large and small mountain basins and The valley flats pushed out by the Lancang River and its tributary water systems in the area are the main human settlements. Because it is located inland, surrounded by mountains, and has a high quiet wind rate, the cold lake effect is prone to occur in winter. This is especially noticeable when driving on a winding mountain road. It will become hot and cold as the terrain changes, and you will also see the cold lake effect in the winter. There is thick fog at the bottom of the basin and white clouds lingering in the mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Xishuangbanna-Menghai-Huimin line is one of the main producing areas of Pu&#39;er tea. Mangzhi, Manzhuan, Mansa and Youle produce Pu&#39;er tea with excellent quality, and Yiwu tea is produced in Mansa. Menghai Huimin belongs to the six new tea mountains outside the Yangtze River (on the west bank of the Lancang River) - Nannuo, Hekai, Mengsong, Jingmai, Brown and Bada. The well-known Pu&#39;er tea brands &quot;Brown Mountain&quot; and &quot;Lao Banzhang&quot; are Produced in Brown Mountain, Menghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/xyqcOrWkZO0vTxXGzd88RbCkCplOnBnTIPhwKkFp.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;549&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/xyqcOrWkZO0vTxXGzd88RbCkCplOnBnTIPhwKkFp.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58413&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Schematic diagram of the distribution of ancient Pu&#39;er tea mountains. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend Information/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Pu&#39;er is known as the source of tea in the world and is a famous Pu&#39;er tea town. The good Pu&#39;er tea is in Lancang, and the Jingmai-Mangjing-Manghong area in Huimin Township is one of the important producing areas of Lancang good tea. The largest ancient tea garden of 10,000 acres among the twelve major tea mountains is here here. The ancient tea garden was planted in 696 AD and has a history of more than 1,300 years. There are also many semi-wild ancient tea trees in the area. The age of the trees is unknown, but according to locals, the oldest tea tree is 1,600 years old. These ancient tea trees still produce a certain amount of output every year and are a cash cow for local villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;My hometown is in a village of the Blang ethnic group&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;In the spring of about three years ago, I went back to my hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My hometown is in Manghong, a village inhabited by the Bulang people. According to the tea mountain classification, it belongs to Jingmai Mountain. The Bulang people living here are good at planting, picking and making tea. Since ancient times, Tea is not only their daily necessities, but also an important commodity in exchange for supplies. Bags of Pu&#39;er tea carried on horseback are transported from Jingmai Mountain to Pu&#39;er Prefecture, Myanmar, and Thailand. Ma Gudao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I rarely go back to my hometown. When I was a child, transportation was inconvenient—my hometown was hidden in the mountains, and the roads used to be difficult. To get from the village to the county seat, one had to walk over mountains and ridges for most of a day, catch a shuttle bus in the countryside, and then take a four- to five-hour ride. When I grew up, I had little time to go home because I studied and worked outside, let alone my hometown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Spring Festival holiday that year, when they heard that I was coming back, my brother-in-law and cousin sent me a message asking me to go back and have a look. The Blang people celebrate the Water Splashing Festival in the Dai calendar year and don’t pay much attention to the Spring Festival, so I didn’t go back during the Spring Festival. Instead, I went back to my hometown with my brother and sister-in-law after Powu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I entered Mangjing from Huimin Township, I found that the road conditions were much better than a few years ago. This was all because of the Pu&#39;er tea. Anyone who sells tea knows that Pu&#39;er tea in this area is good. During the tea-picking season, merchants from all over the country come to collect tea. In order to facilitate the transportation of trucks, the government funded the construction of a road, which greatly improved the efficiency of logistics and transportation. The Blang people who grew tea became rich as a result, and the place became a well-known wealthy town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a checkpoint at the bridge that must be passed when entering Tea Mountain. Cars going out are basically ignored, but cars entering are checked very strictly. It is said to be to prevent someone from smuggling in Pu&#39;er tea of ​​average quality from other places and passing it off as local Pu&#39;er tea before selling it. Although they are in a remote area, people here have already had brand awareness and cherish their tea and brand very much, and do not allow anyone to ruin the reputation of their tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/VMXuGJSIQJZcZ6Q0kYQ3VdEXyn7U0RzVk326YbW7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/VMXuGJSIQJZcZ6Q0kYQ3VdEXyn7U0RzVk326YbW7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58414&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pu&#39;er scenery. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the road conditions are completely different from those in the past, it still took four hours to reach Mang. It was already past 11 noon when we arrived at Hong Laozhai. The uncle came out from the stilted building and waved us into the house. The old house is a traditional Blang wooden house with a history of several decades. Last time I came back, my grandpa and grandma were still alive. They have passed away for a few years now, but the old house still maintains the layout and layout of the past: there is still a fire pit in the kitchen. Although the village has long started to use electricity and biogas, The fire pit still dances with flames day and night. The old people use the fire in this fire pit to bake their favorite cup of roasted tea. On winter nights, they sit around the fire pit to warm themselves up, drink tea, smoke hookahs and chat. The firepit is the soul of the home and cannot be thrown away at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is almost noon, only my uncle is at home. My cousin goes to school and has lunch at school and doesn&#39;t come back until the afternoon; my aunt goes to the mountains to pick tea and doesn&#39;t come home until the afternoon. Although the ancient tree tea has not yet reached the best time to pick, the first batch of platform tea has already begun to be picked. From this time until the end of April, it is the busiest time for the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Platform tea refers to Pu&#39;er tea cultivated in recent decades. Although the taste is not as mellow as accumulated through a long history, it is still a fine quality tea. No artificial fertilizer is applied, and the tea is made by the soil itself. It is nourished by the fallen leaves of ground forest trees, sunlight, rain and dew, and is also called ecological tea. A Taiwanese friend of mine once told me that Taiwan has very strict requirements for tea imports, and only completely ecological tea is allowed to be imported. The tea from my hometown is very popular among Taiwanese businessmen. A considerable part of the tea is bought by Taiwanese businessmen every year, which shows the superior quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Use Red Bull to relieve tea drunkenness&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;Although the layout of the old house has not changed, I still found two more things. One is a huge tea table - made by my uncle himself. Judging by its size, the tree must be quite old. With the entry of tea merchants from other places, a different way of life has been brought to the village, such as drinking tea. In the past, when drinking tea, you would take a copper kettle sitting on the fire pond to boil water, grab a handful of tea in a small earthenware pot, and roast it by the pond fire. When the water boiled, the tea would also be roasted and fragrant. When you pour some water into the jar, you will have a jar of fragrant tea, with a strong and wild fragrance. This cup of tea is very fragrant, but it is also very bitter. After the bitterness, it becomes sweet again. The power of tea is also very overbearing. First-time drinkers will become drunk if they are not careful, causing shortness of breath and palpitation, which is very similar to the symptoms of hypoglycemia. The local method is to grab handfuls of uncooked rice and chew it, which is said to be very effective. Canned roasted tea is easy to get drunk when you first drink it, but it can become addictive if you drink it for a long time. In the past, people in the village rarely went outside the mountains. Traffic was one reason, and they also thought the tea outside was weak. If you have to go out, you must bring your own pre-roasted tea leaves. After drinking the tea, no matter how things go, you must go back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, the old people also pay attention to the tea ceremony when drinking tea, including tea sea, tea wash, teapot, tea rules, aroma cup, host cup, tea tasting cup, etc., and there are many of them, paying attention to water temperature and water quality. , pay attention to making soup. One move after another, the ancient village is also absorbing new knowledge and changing with the changes of the times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another change in the old house is the addition of a disinfection cabinet one person high. The Blang people themselves are a nation that loves cleanliness. As for my old house, although it is old, it is kept very neat and clean. The open-air palm (the local name for the terrace of the stilted building) is spotless, which makes people feel simple and friendly. Nowadays, the villagers are paying more and more attention to hygiene when making raw Pu&#39;er tea. Not only the houses, but also the roads in the village are still very clean, although they are still dirt roads. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After welcoming us into the old house, my uncle was not busy with anything else. He first invited us to drink tea - during the tea-picking season, almost everyone was busy in the tea mountains all day long, and there was no concept of lunch at all. The tea is spring tea that has just been picked and roasted. Although it is not ancient tree tea, it is still top quality. The uncle poured boiling water into the teapot, closed the lid and let it simmer for five or six seconds, then poured the tea into the sea of ​​tea and distributed it to us. In order to see the color of tea, my uncle specially bought a small transparent glass cup. After pouring the tea, I saw that the tea soup is clear and fresh green in color. There is a fresh bitterness in the mouth. After two cups, the sweetness comes back, and the sweetness overflows in an instant. It fills the space between the lips and teeth, and expands in waves in the mouth, like a young girl who is shy and timid when she first met, but is enthusiastic and lively after getting to know her better - I think she must be a girl from the Brown ethnic group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that drinking Shenpu shaving oil is very powerful. I arrived home at noon, and the breakfast in my stomach was almost digested, and my uncle was giving me a cup of tea on the left and right. Soon I had symptoms of hypoglycemia, and I slumped on the sofa and shouted for food. The uncle then suddenly realized it and patted his head and said, &quot;You are drunk with tea!&quot; Then slowly arrange the cooking. He first cooked the rice in the rice cooker, then set up a large pot on the fire pit, poured water in, pulled off a strip of bacon, chopped it into several pieces and threw it into the pot. While waiting for the water to boil, he went out like a gust of wind. After a while, my uncle came back like a gust of wind, brought back a pile of Red Bull and put it in front of me and said, drink some first, and you will not be drunk after drinking tea. I opened a can and drank it, and I felt better - it seems that Zuicha no longer chews uncooked rice, but drinks Red Bull instead. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My uncle thrust Red Bull into my hand and ran out to get lunch. He grabbed a chicken from the chicken coop and killed it, then chopped it into pieces. When the water in the pot boiled, he poured them all into the pot, added seasoning salt, stirred a few times, covered the pot and continued to simmer. ; He also took out a large bowl of water pickled vegetables from the pickled vegetable jar, mixed some with soy sauce and chili for cold dressing, and chopped some into pieces and stir-fried with the turtle dove meat. At two o&#39;clock in the afternoon, we finally had a belated lunch - free-range chicken cooked with bacon, mixed with pickled vegetables, and stir-fried turtle doves with pickled vegetables. The food cooked over a firewood was particularly fragrant. I ate it with gusto and kept enough to eat. Two bowls of rice. &lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;Our ancient tree tea&lt;/h3>; &lt;p>;After dinner, my eldest cousin happened to come back from get off work at the village clinic. He said hello to his uncle and said to me, Sister, do you want to see our tea garden? I said yes. The cousin and his uncle went downstairs to start the motorcycle. Manghong Village is built in the mountains. The roads in the village are not wide and the slopes are very undulating. It is not possible to ride bicycles. The daily means of transportation is motorcycles. Every household has at least one or two motorcycles. My cousin drove me along a thin yellow winding dirt road toward the mountains, followed by my brother-in-law and my brother. When we reached a slightly flat spot halfway up the mountain, my cousin stopped the motorcycle and led me to the roadside. He pointed to me not far down the mountain and said, &quot;Sister, look, that&#39;s our village!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is early spring at 4:30 in the afternoon. The sun has turned slightly yellow, the sky is clear and the light is soft. Under the blue sky, stilted buildings with sloping roofs on all sides are scattered in an orderly manner, among the smoky bamboo canopies and banana trees. Under the cover, it undulates intermittently and extends to the mountains on the opposite side, showing a quiet rural style. My cousin said that this is his favorite place. He usually stops to take a look when he passes by the tea farm. When nothing happens, he will also come here to stand for a while. &quot;This is the village where I grew up. Our ancestors were all born and buried here. There is no better place than here,&quot; the cousin said. We looked at it for a while, then my cousin waved me into the car and continued driving up. After turning a few more turns, my cousin stopped the car again and said, &quot;We&#39;re here.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/ 02/04/H3lU50w9mcJSHm6oFrojMJPnRP6mf3ZfyfGJVc6B.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/02/04/H3lU50w9mcJSHm6oFrojMJPnRP6 mf3ZfyfGJVc6B. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;58415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mountain village. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a hillside that looks like an undisturbed mountain forest, with thick and thin trees growing intricately. Trees, shrubs and some vines of varying heights. Between the tall trees and low shrubs, there are tea trees about 2 meters high. Among the dark green adult leaves, new green pointed leaves are piercing out like swords. They will be picked in a few days; Qiu The curved branches are covered with mottled layers of moss, as if they are the sedimented remains of time; the moss grows and withers season after season, and a thin layer of moss soil accumulates on the tea branches, becoming a place for parasitic plants to settle down. Here, as long as the Pu&#39;er tea trees grow to a certain age, there will be a parasitic plant called &quot;crab legs&quot;. The scientific name of crab legs is liquidambar mistletoe, which is very effective in treating rheumatic joint pain, lumbar muscle strain and acute cystitis. When tea leaves sprout, it is also the flowering and fruiting stage of crab legs. They grow in clusters among the tea branches, often causing the tea buds to fail to grow. Yunnan ancient tree Pu&#39;er tea is a large-leaf tree tea with tall plants. It is not easy to remove crab legs. Therefore, in the past, it was an annoying parasitic plant for tea farmers. Nowadays, crab legs are widely sought after, and the price is more expensive than ordinary Pu&#39;er tea, which can easily cost one thousand yuan per catty. Tea farmers often regard crab legs as a by-product of tea, which is another considerable income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My cousin proudly pointed to these tea trees and said: &quot;Sister, these are our treasures, ancient tea trees! Look at these tea trees with particularly strong branches. This one is more than 300 years old. , that one is 500 years old, and that one over there is the &quot;Tea Soul Tree&quot; of this tea field. The old people in the village said it is at least 800 years old. They said they were planted when the tea field first opened... These tea trees I They are all numbered, picked separately every year, and fried separately, which can be sold at a very good price.&quot; The so-called &quot;tea soul tree&quot; is the first tea tree planted in each tea field. How old is the tea garden? No matter how old it is, the tea garden has disappeared, but maybe the tree is still there... The tea soul tree is the soul of the tea garden. It transforms into a god and protects the tea garden. Therefore, a tea festival, called &quot;Tea Soul&quot;, is held every April. , not only does each family have to sacrifice their own tea soul tree, but the village also invites the Big Buddha and respected old people to preside over a grand ceremony to sacrifice the tea soul and call the tea god. In addition to these ancient tea trees, which are hailed as &quot;treasures&quot; by my cousin, the &quot;main force&quot; of this tea land is composed of tea trees that are about 200 years old. The scattered small tea trees are made from cuttings of the branches of ancient trees. They inherit It has the characteristics of the mother tea tree and has a consistent flavor. All it lacks is the experience of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Sister, do you know the name of this mountain?&quot; I shook my head. &quot;This is Aileng Mountain, named after Pa Aileng!&quot; said my cousin proudly. Pa Aileng was an outstanding leader of the Blang tribe more than 1,800 years ago. Legend has it that in order to find an ideal place to live, he led the Blang tribe across mountains and rivers. After going through untold hardships, they finally found a place full of wild tea trees. , the soil here is fertile, the streams are gurgling, the vegetation is lush and lush, birds and animals roam here, and it is surrounded by mountains. It is an ideal place to build a village. So Pa Aileng led the tribe to settle here, and guided the tribe to domesticate tea trees and open tea gardens. This is the origin of Brown Village and tea gardens in Mangjing Manghong area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The water and soil in Lengshan are the best, and the tea in Lengshan is also the best tea!” My cousin said to me with an unquestionable and firm attitude. The Blang people believe that their leader Pa Aileng has found the best home and the most fertile land for them. They also believe in the principle of harmonious coexistence between man and nature. Therefore, except for necessary care, the Blang people never use artificial fertilization when growing tea. Needless to say the use of chemicals. The tea trees in the mountains suck the mist and dew, extract nutrients from the soil and dead leaves of weeds, and convert them into tea substances little by little, forming the characteristics of Jingmai Mountain tea, which is bitter and astringent, sweet and refreshing, and orange-yellow in color. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, my cousin suddenly turned around and faced me, and said seriously: &quot;Sister, I always think that my ancestors left me such a precious tea land, I must protect it, no matter what The quality of tea trees and tea leaves must not be destroyed in my hands.&quot; I understood what my cousin meant. His main job is as a rural doctor, but he spends almost all his spare time on tea. The Brown people are originally a very clean people. When my cousin came here, he also brought in the professional habits of doctors. When his family picks and roasts tea, he insists on &quot;three things not falling to the ground&quot;, that is, picking the tea does not fall to the ground, withering the tea does not fall to the ground, and frying the tea does not fall to the ground. As for the final pressing of the tea cakes, he does it himself without any help. &quot;I will definitely continue to make tea well, and Pa Aileng will bless us.&quot; The cousin cast his eyes to the sky in the distance. There, the sun that was about to set was covered by a cloud, and the light came out from behind the cloud, giving the clouds a bright golden edge, like some kind of hint and approval from nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[名字最有梗的小城，凭什么又翻红了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257896]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[墨西哥公布“外星人”遗骸，网友：长得太符合刻板印象]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257926]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 12, local time, the Mexican Congress held its first public hearing related to &quot;unknown anomalies.&quot; At the meeting, shortly after two scientists played several videos showing &quot;UFOs and unknown anomalies&quot;, they displayed the remains of two suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot;, and related topics quickly became a &quot;hot search&quot;. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/30ce9c40e8e1e64679e83b2f04cf4218.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/30ce9c40e8e1e64679e83b2f04cf4218.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252807&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023 local time, in Mexico City, the capital of Mexico, the remains of suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot; were displayed at a hearing. Source/Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to local media reports, Mexico plans to promote relevant legislation through hearings, and the country may become the first country in the world to recognize &quot;alien creatures.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Do you believe in the existence of aliens? Believe it or not, I can’t tell Submit&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Netizen: They look too human, so I don’t believe it&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to public information, the two remains were discovered in Peru in 2017. 1800 and 700. Judging from the footage released at the scene, the appearance of the remains is similar to that of humans, with a slender head and three fingers on each hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers said at the meeting that these specimens had been studied by scientists from the National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM). After comparing with other DNA samples, it was found that more than 30% of the specimen DNA was &quot;unknown&quot; of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/b5a0c6003422e9e8d534e44897417238.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/b5a0c6003422e9e8d534e44897417238.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252809&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023 local time, fingers of the remains of suspected &quot;alien creatures&quot; were found in Mexico City, the capital of Mexico. Source/Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;X-rays of the specimens were also shown at the hearing. One of them had &quot;eggs&quot; inside its body, and both had implants made of very rare metals. , such as Osmium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the news came out, it sparked heated discussions, and most netizens were skeptical:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It looks too human, so I don&#39;t believe it!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Very It fits the human stereotype of aliens!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How is this different from the ones seen in science fiction movies? It looks very &#39;expected&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The universe is so It&#39;s really not surprising that there are aliens. It&#39;s just that the appearance of this alien is too consistent with the previous fantasy...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/29/0aaadec694c7f26b6a3753bf0b6f547d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1052&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/29/0aaadec694c7f26b6a3753bf0b6f547d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252810&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yong, a researcher at the National Space Science Center of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and aerospace science ambassador, said in an interview with Southern+ reporters that aliens The existence of is a &quot;probabilistic event&quot;. &quot;There are about 300 billion stars in the Milky Way alone, not to mention more than 2 trillion galaxies like the Milky Way in the universe, so alien life will exist even if the probability is very small.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But for Mexico this time Liu Yong believed that the announcement of the remains was not credible and even &quot;nonsensical.&quot; In his opinion, on the one hand, there are many possible forms of aliens, but the possibility of them being like humans is very low; on the other hand, he believes that due to technical and other reasons, the possibility of humans finding aliens is very small at present. , only by developing from the &quot;Canoe Age&quot; to the &quot;Sailing Age&quot; can we discover further civilizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why are aliens and UFOs so popular? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Regardless of whether this is true or not, recently, news about aliens and UFOs at home and abroad have been flooding the screen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before Mexico released the remains, in early August, a Harvard professor also claimed that he &quot;may have discovered evidence of extraterrestrial life.&quot; It is said that the team is analyzing the remaining fragments from the unidentified object that crashed into the Earth in 2014. The professor believes that the fragments contain remnants of alien technology and may have been modified. He and his team are compiling their findings into a paper that they hope to release publicly in about a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, on the evening of September 7, the Jinan Seven Star Observatory released a video showing a &quot;luminous falling&quot; UFO in the monitoring screen on September 6. On September 1st and 5th, the Seven Stars Observatory also photographed traces of UFOs twice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Niu Guihua, vice chairman of the Shandong Astronomical Society and secretary-general of the Jinan Astronomical Society, believes that due to the existence of suspected power, we can only know that the UFO is not a falling object such as a meteor, but it is not clear what the actual object is. What. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/e46802e8b3061256fb33217f3b0175d4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;437&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/e46802e8b3061256fb33217f3b0175d4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252808&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Left picture: On September 13, 2023, local time, in Mexico City, the capital of Mexico, the remains of &quot;alien creatures&quot; were displayed at a hearing. Right picture: The movie &quot;ET&quot; &quot;The alien image in &quot;. Picture Source Visual China&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;About a week later, on the evening of September 13, “UFO” became a “hot search” on Weibo again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Weibo netizen &quot;Xiao Xiyu&quot; posted a video saying: &quot;Does anyone know what the two lights in the sky to the northwest of Caoxian County are? UFOs? When the video was recorded, the light pillars disappeared, and only this smoke remained. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many netizens said in the comment area that they had also seen the same UFO, with coordinates involving Beijing, Jiangsu, Shandong, Tianjin and other places, and posted photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are humans so fascinated by UFOs and aliens? Liu Yong believes that &quot;searching for extraterrestrial civilization&quot; has gone beyond a simple scientific issue and has become a philosophical issue. Exploring the mysteries of the universe and the origin of life may also be exploring people themselves and their meaning in the world and in the universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, human beings are constantly accelerating their exploration of the universe. From the two &quot;Voyager&quot; detectors launched in 1977 to the &quot;China Sky Eye&quot; built in Guizhou, various detection methods have become more complete. Taking the &quot;China Sky Eye&quot; as an example, its experimental goals include receiving signals from extraterrestrial civilizations, pulsars, rapid electrical storms and other signals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in Liu Yong’s view, humans are still a long way from finding extraterrestrial civilizations. “Perhaps it will only be possible on a time scale of thousands or ten thousand years.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[音乐家李海鹰：月光流淌在珠江上]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257914]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021849850177&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;People Weekly Li Haiying&#39;s manuscript video.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/G8hfqzJQv3VepINkT0VCcndx1kDzyd2fW3QrQgrz .jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/e6988e555576678021849850177/HVmbvbHXk6EA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/e6988e555576678021849850177/HVmbvbHXk6EA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August 2023, in the Pearl River On Shazhou Ersha Island, Li Haiying is rehearsing the symphony &quot;China 1921&quot; composed by him. This composer has turned to the creation of large-scale musical works in recent years. In addition to the symphony he is rehearsing, he is also working on the music for a major TV series. When we walked into the rehearsal hall of the Guangzhou Symphony Orchestra, it was like stepping into a flowing stream just as the orchestra was playing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When you walked in, you happened to reach the section about Guangzhou.&quot; Li Haiying said that a dozen meters away from the rehearsal hall is the Pearl River flowing eastward. The river flows further down, where he grew up when he was a child. place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As someone who grew up by the Pearl River, Li Haiying’s music has a strong sense of flow. Thirty years ago, he wrote &quot;Curved Moon&quot; and asked Liu Huan, who had a &quot;very floating voice&quot;, to sing it. He felt that the song had &quot;the feeling of being drenched by rain&quot;, even though the &quot;root-seeking craze&quot; was leading the culture at that time. world, &quot;Xintianyou&quot;, &quot;Nothing&quot;, etc. are blowing the northwest wind and sand throughout the mainland music scene. He also composed the music for &quot;Song of Seven Sons&quot;. In the song about Macau, he used the melody to simulate the crashing of the waves on the rocky shore. This song followed China&#39;s first lunar exploration satellite &quot;Chang&#39;e 1&quot; to space. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although I live in Beijing, many of my creative commissions are from Guangzhou.&quot; 69-year-old Li Haiying said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/eomOXOcVnf0VzkC2W51Rkyk8QpJWDriwbjOltSud.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/eomOXOcVnf0VzkC2W51Rkyk8QpJWDriwbjOltSud.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Haiying&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Li Lewei/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1970, 16-year-old Li Haiying Entered the Guangzhou Cantonese Opera Troupe and became a violinist and composer. Five years later, he became a violinist and creator of the Art Troupe of the Political Department of the Chinese Navy&#39;s South China Sea Fleet. From the end of 1982 to March 1997, he worked as a composer in the Guangdong Music and Art Troupe and wrote works such as &quot;The Crooked Moon&quot;, &quot;Song of the Seven Sons&quot; and &quot;I Don&#39;t Want to Say&quot;. He is good at integrating folk song elements into the melodies of popular music, so his works have a vivid sense of place, such as &quot;The Crooked Moon&quot; with Cantonese tune, &quot;Crossing the River&quot; with Northeastern duo style, and &quot;Crossing the River&quot; with Shandong music characteristics. Traveling everywhere”. He has also written a lot of pop music, such as Eason Chan&#39;s &quot;Where to Start&quot; and Sun Li&#39;s &quot;Love is Like Air&quot;, and has also scored for film and television works such as &quot;Bright Sword&quot; and &quot;The Devil Is Coming&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The symphony has always been his dream. At the age of 49, Li Haiying began to study conducting under conductor and music educator Professor Xu Xin. At the age of 54, he re-learned composition lessons in the classroom of the Central Conservatory of Music. In his fifties, he re-learned and practiced conducting and composing music, and he sat in the classroom with undergraduate students. &quot;Actually, they are all very basic courses, just undergraduate courses.&quot; He is happy to learn and to be a newcomer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, Li Haiying became a newcomer to the symphony orchestra. He wrote and conducted the large-scale symphony work &quot;Our Sun Yat-sen&quot;, plus later &quot;Ode to the Sixth Ancestor&quot;, &quot;Symphony No. 1 (Pearl River)&quot; and &quot; China 1921&quot;, he composed a total of four symphonic works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The grand historical themes are very concretely presented in Li Haiying&#39;s music. He uses different musical styles to correspond to different cities. He uses Peking Opera to depict Beijing, Dragon Boat Tune to depict Wuchang, and Changsha to use Flower Drum Opera. ...His music has always maintained a local feel, which may come from his familiarity with folk songs and his research into related content during creation. In the children&#39;s musical &quot;Cat God in the Forbidden City&quot;, Li Haiying did a lot of research in order to fully grasp the atmosphere of Beijing, hoping to use music to depict the history and modern vitality of a city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/yGLXcpFrWdn0r6AKhKQ47kltM4JIkXqYfqNHV6Va.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/yGLXcpFrWdn0r6AKhKQ47kltM4JIkXqYfqNHV6Va.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In May 2023, Li Haiying and the Guangzhou Symphony Orchestra performed &quot;China 1921&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Li Lewei/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is Li Haiying’s dictation:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Symphony and Pop: A Living Sense of Place&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;Before this show, I actually had a day or two of anxiety. &quot;China 1921&quot; is premiering in 2021. It has been performed for the seventh time this year alone. Is there anything else I can do? Can I make the orchestra perform better this time? If I want to do an operation that is not innovative, then I simply don’t do it, so during this rehearsal I was still changing the music and deleting bars. Of course, these were things I thought up at home, not a sudden inspiration on the spot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During the rehearsal, I had two roles, one was the composer and the other was the conductor. , equal to the player. When playing with an orchestra, I think about the music from another perspective and re-interpret the work. Moreover, you need to have an ability to make symphonies, and you need to have a strong memory. Just like playing blind chess, you have to remember the entire chessboard. This is also an ability that is constantly cultivated by making music. Basically, you have to memorize the music, and you also have to think about how to play it. Should it be more lively or soft? When I was a conductor, I had to modify some expression methods, and I also had to listen to the performance and make changes while performing, and I made a lot of adjustments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When the Guangzhou Symphony Orchestra commissioned this work from me in 2019, I didn’t expect that I would write such a long piece. For the work, Director Yu Long told me at the time that the first thing to do was to write a beautiful melody, and secondly to focus on the year 1921. I collected information based on this idea and found that from August 1920 to the spring of 1921, early organizations of the Communist Party of China were established in six cities: Shanghai, Beijing, Wuhan, Changsha, Guangzhou, and Jinan. At the same time, among the Chinese in Japan and France, early organizations of the Communist Party of China, composed of advanced elements among overseas students, were also established. Therefore, my earliest design was 9 movements, using 9 musical styles, describing the October Revolution and what happened in Beijing, Wuhan, Changsha, Jinan, Guangzhou, Shanghai, Japan, and France from 1920 to 1921 on the eve of the founding of the Communist Party of China. fragments of history. It was shortened to 5 parts according to the structure of the music, but it still consists of 9 paragraphs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first movement is a passionate Allegro, which describes the outbreak of the October Revolution and is called &quot;The Shock of the Earth&quot; . The second movement begins with a quiet Andante, including two sections: &quot;Beiping Flying Catkins&quot; and &quot;Wuchang Autumn Waters&quot;. The third movement is the waltz, &quot;Eastern Alley&quot; and &quot;Morning Light in Paris&quot;. The fourth movement is Chinese dance music, mainly about Changsha, Jinan and Guangzhou. The last movement came with the convening of the &quot;First Class&quot;. When I arrived in Beijing, I used Peking Opera. In Wuhan, I adapted Dragon Boat Opera. In Changsha, I used Huagu Opera. In the Jinan part, I created a Shandong tune. In the Guangzhou part, I can also hear many elements of Cantonese music. At the end, I used a method often used in symphonies - fugue, stacking different themes together, which symbolized the rolling torrents coming together to form a huge force rushing towards the end. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is my fourth large-scale musical work. I am currently cooperating with the China Children&#39;s Art Theater The musical is called &quot;The Cat God in the Forbidden City&quot;. The previous owner of the Forbidden City is no longer there, and now the cat in the Forbidden City, &quot;Dorgon (the cat&#39;s name)&quot; is very popular on the Internet. I am full of expectations for this subject and am working hard to create it. The Forbidden City is a gathering place for Chinese culture. We want to promote Chinese culture, so we created a &quot;cat god&quot; of the Forbidden City. I hope that the writing will be more trendy, with many modern elements, but also contain Beijing culture, such as Beijing nursery rhymes, Beijing Qinshu, Pingju opera, etc. I think this is very important. What kind of works can be recognized by the public? First of all, it must have roots and learn from the best cultures around the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Creation still requires continuous learning. I feel that I am in the sprint period now, but I am also inert. I told those students that everyone goes down the path of inertia. You know this is a weakness of human nature, so you might as well try going the other way. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Only through continuous creation can society accept me. At least for my musical collaborators, everyone’s expectation is that I will continue to improve. If one day I find that Li Haiying has stopped, the cooperation will basically be over. Only by constantly surprising others can I continue to make the music I want to do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/SHhPiGzjsaDFAYdtAiphLrdCCBKLJqGQKX9fX112.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/SHhPiGzjsaDFAYdtAiphLrdCCBKLJqGQKX9fX112.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252763&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Haiying&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Changing times中, the forever new musician&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In fact, my ideal since I was a child is to be a symphony performer. In the 1980s, I went into the pop music industry. After rolling a few times, I also made film and television soundtracks, such as &quot;Bright Sword&quot;, &quot;Foreign Girl&quot;, &quot;Happiness Like Flowers&quot;, etc., and I also participated in &quot;The Devil Is Coming&quot;. In the end, I felt that I had to go back to my childhood dream and realize it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I was a child, I once played Saint-Saëns&#39;s &quot;Introduction and Rondo Caprice&quot; at home. It was the first time I was moved by symphony. My father used to be the deputy director of Guangzhou Huangpu Shipyard. Many engineers in the factory studied in the Soviet Union, and many of them like music. So my family had a record player in the 1950s. It played &quot;The Blue Danube&quot; and also played a lot of Cantonese music and Cantonese opera. My musical initiation was this record player and another Baltic radio. When I was about 14 years old, I forced my mother to buy me a Qinqin. As soon as I got the Qinqin home, I immediately played all the Cantonese music I had ever heard. Later, the radio was playing the music of the Red Detachment of Women, and I picked up the violin and played along. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I was 16 years old, the Guangzhou Cantonese Opera Troupe came to our school to recruit students, and I was selected because I was the only student in the school who could play music notation and a little violin. Later, I entered the composition training class of Guangzhou Xinghai Conservatory of Music for a year and a half. By the 1980s, some record companies came to me to do composing, which was equivalent to an invitation to write music, and I started to become a freelance musician from then on. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first time I wrote lyrics was for &quot;The Curved Moon&quot;, and I had a few notes first , then I wrote the music and lyrics overlapping each other, and I finished it in half an hour. At that time, what was popular in the music world was the high-pitched and hard-hitting &quot;Northwest Wind&quot;. &quot;Curved Moon&quot; was a typical Cantonese tune. I said it had the &quot;feeling of being drenched by rain.&quot; It was many years later that I realized that this song recorded the life of the Dan family who lived on boats on the Pearl River. It was not only the description of the words themselves, but also the rhythm of the song was the rhythm of the Dan family&#39;s oars. This inspiration comes from the fact that I lived by the Pearl River when I was a child. I crossed the river in a boat rowed by the Dan family. The Dan family even carried a baby on their backs and rowed the boat. The boat could seat four people. I was sitting on the boat and heard them calling Gillian. Gillian is the most common name for girls from the Dan family. It’s just that the Dan family can no longer be seen on the Pearl River. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When I wrote this song, there was no commission from a music company, and I was not sure what I wanted to do. The singer comes to sing. The first person I found was Chen Rujia. After Chen Rujia came to record, I felt it was inappropriate as soon as I heard it, so I called Liu Huan and asked him if he was in Beijing and asked him to record the song tomorrow. Liu Huan didn&#39;t even listen to the song, so she agreed on the phone. I went to Beijing the next day, and he came to record in the afternoon. At that time, the commercial market based on stars had not yet formed, so the interaction with singers was that simple. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Guangdong in the 1980s and 1990s was also a golden age to some extent, because everything was It&#39;s new and changing with each passing day. Maybe everyone is nostalgic and feels that the past era was the golden age. In fact, the entire economic foundation was not at a very high level at that time, but the momentum and passion shown by people on the wave was quite rare. This wave played a great role in promoting Guangzhou. At that time, Guangzhou was not only in the music, but also in the media, such as TV stations, radio stations, newspapers, advertising, and film and television dramas. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/STJftJIqxtidMsGROGhEagOpstYMzv7sJHSJEd9e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/29/STJftJIqxtidMsGROGhEagOpstYMzv7sJHSJEd9e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252761&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Huan&#39;s &quot;The Curved Moon&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Curved Moon&quot; was composed in the late 1980s, when the northwest wind was blowing fiercely in the music industry, so when everyone heard it, they felt that this song Why is it so special, so southern, so soft. Of course, most people accepted it quickly. Only a few people in the industry felt it was inappropriate and that it was different from the trend of the entire era. At that time, it was all about &quot;My Hometown Is Not Beautiful&quot; and the like. Behind this trend all point to the &quot;root-seeking craze&quot; in the 1980s, such as the oil painting &quot;Father&quot; and the movie &quot;Red Sorghum&quot;. All of these belong to the root-seeking culture, and everyone is digging into the soil. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Because of Jiang Wen&#39;s movie &quot;The Devils Are Coming&quot;, I went from Guangzhou to Beijing to do the soundtrack. The filming has been completed and editing has begun. Cui Jian, Liu Xing, and I are responsible for the soundtrack. I didn&#39;t leave after arriving in Beijing that time, and began to devote more energy to film and television soundtracks. From &quot;Betrayal&quot;, &quot;Black Ice&quot; to &quot;Bright Sword&quot;, some people asked, why did you write the soundtracks for all the dramas? I didn&#39;t, it just happened to be those dramas that became popular. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After writing &quot;Song of the Seven Sons&quot;, I kept writing it for several years. Can&#39;t write well. A friend told me, Li Haiying, that you haven&#39;t released a song for a long time. His words made me realize that this is a problem. If you haven&#39;t had a popular song for a few years, people will think that your songs can&#39;t be released. Until the song &quot;Love is Like Air&quot;, I wrote the melody alone for a month and a half. It turned out well and became the theme song of the TV series &quot;Happiness is Like a Flower&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have always wanted to do symphony. Because of some work opportunities, I started to study with conductors in 2003 Teacher Xu Xin studies conducting. In 2007, I started to study composition systematically again. In 2008, a group of undergraduate students and I went to the Central Conservatory of Music to take classes. Once the head of the composition department of the Central Conservatory of Music stopped me and said, Li Haiying, what are you doing here? I said go to class. He said, who are you taking classes with? Don&#39;t be a bad learner. If you are a bad learner, it will be over. I still attend class honestly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From Cantonese opera, Cantonese music, pop music, to film and television soundtracks, to symphony, I am interested in music Always have something fresh, always be a newcomer. Times are turbulent, and I often do other things before the tide recedes. For example, I was doing film and television soundtracks, and later I was doing classical music. I didn’t wait until the wave ended and left me desperate, so I left long ago. I am a newbie in classical music calculation, and it was only in 2016 that I started writing large-scale works. As long as I maintain this state of learning, humility, and devotion, including now writing musicals and operas, I also hope to be innovative. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Music is written directly for people, it is a dialogue. Another point is that I do not advocate my own ideas. I will write your thoughts and feelings. Everyone feels that artists always emphasize themselves, but why do they separate &quot;I&quot; and &quot;you&quot;? I thought I was unimportant, I had long known that I was limited. This concept may make me seem very personalityless on the surface, but the more I go on, the more I feel that my music is not about me. What my music wants to express is this era, and it is about you and them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>