<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[去扬州看东坡：到心仪之地，施仁爱之方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260929]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;There are many thoughts and memories in Pingshan Hall&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Yangzhou once had a dense population of outstanding figures from all dynasties, and its winding flower paths are layer upon layer filled with cultural gold dust. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/iuFLzQrv52hE6WWvWJOAgg0YjIcLVwDAGdPa20BS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/iuFLzQrv52hE6WWvWJOAgg0YjIcLVwDAGdPa20BS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Overlooking the Slender West Lake from the Qiling Pagoda of Daming Temple&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Exiting the North Gate of Slender West Lake, across the road is the Daming Temple. Entering the slope of the scenic spot, the &quot;Qiling Ruins&quot; archway appears in front of you, with four pillars and three couplets, and double eaves and tile ridges. There is a stone plaque embedded in the wall on the east side of the courtyard. The big red characters &quot;The No. 1 View in Huaidong&quot; are very eye-catching. They come from Qin Guan&#39;s &quot;Pingshan Hall&quot; written by Ci Yunzi: &quot;If a tourist talks about the beauty of climbing, he must write &quot;The No. 1 View in Huaidong&quot;. Take a look.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After passing the Tianwang Hall of Daming Temple, there is an octagonal doorway on the west side, passing through it is Pingshan Hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In front of Pingshan Hall is a wooden flower gallery. The old wisteria planted on both sides are circling and twining. The dense branches and leaves and blooming wisteria flowers sprinkle the ground with coolness. I suddenly remembered the &quot;weeping willow in front of the hall&quot; and exited the flower gallery first. There are wintersweet, viburnum, boxwood, crape myrtle, etc. planted around. The leaves of magnolia are lush and moist. The tree is seven or eight meters high. It should be very gorgeous when in full bloom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a milky white stone on the grass on the south side of the vestibule, with the word &quot;European Willow&quot; written in big green characters on it. It is indeed there. Below is Ouyang Xiu&#39;s &quot;Chaozhongcuo&quot;: &quot;The sill of the flat mountain leans against the clear sky, and the mountain scenery is blurred. Weeping willows are planted in front of the hall, and there are few spring breezes...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first year of Renzong Jiayou&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(1056)&lt;/span>;, my friend Liu Chang was going to be appointed as the magistrate of Yangzhou. Ouyang Xiuwei gave this poem as a farewell farewell. It has been several years since he was transferred from Yangzhou, and he still misses the Pingshan Hall where he once visited. There is a hint of melancholy about the passage of time in the words, but the tone is broad-minded and clear, without any sense of decadence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I looked around, but there was no sign of the willow tree. It was a bit strange, so I continued searching. It turned out that it was right next to the stone, low, young, and leaning as if it was about to lie down. It was a tamarisk tree. The leaves are short and stubborn, not graceful at all. If you imagine the weeping willows planted by hand in Central Europe, they should be the delicate and slender ones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/5EZGfpAtygCizPHpjt6EyLPDL9oWXNb27K5sAAUz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;924&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/5EZGfpAtygCizPHpjt6EyLPDL9oWXNb27K5sAAUz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Pingshan Hall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pingshan Hall is very crowded. Tour groups are coming and going. The couplet below the plaque of &quot;Pingshan Hall&quot; incorporates the vastness of time and space, the boundless wind and moon, and there are knowledgeable and knowledgeable scholars in the scenery: &quot;When you lean on the railing at dawn, you can see the green mountains of six generations; when you come to drink wine at night, the bright moon is right above your head. On the east and west sides of the plaque, there are plaques &quot;Sitting on Flowers and Carrying the Moon&quot; and &quot;Feng Liu Wan Zai&quot; hanging high. The latter was inscribed by Liu Kunyi, the governor of Liangjiang in the late Qing Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the windows of the east and west wings of Pingshan Hall, Sikuquanshu&#39;s &quot;Six One Poetry&quot;, &quot;Ouyang Wencui&quot;, &quot;Wen Zhongji&quot;, etc. are placed; four wooden poetry plaques occupy half of the wall, recording He wrote poems by Su Zhe and others about Pingshan Hall. Mei Yaochen&#39;s &quot;Thousands of Mountains Flying Shadows Across the River&quot; and Su Che&#39;s &quot;Looking down at the river and the mountains from the hall&quot; both have a silhouette. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eighth year of Renzong Qingli&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(1048)&lt;/span>;, when Ouyang Xiu moved from Chuzhou to Yangzhou, he was still in the &quot; The political low period after the failure of the Qingli New Deal. He cared about people&#39;s livelihood, and maintained a lenient and simple administration without slacking off. People in Chuzhou and Yangzhou felt his virtue and government, and built shrines to Ou Gong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After official duties, Ou Gong spent time in poetry and wine. He built a Pingshan Hall in the southwest of Daming Temple, where he could not only meet friends and relatives, climb high and look far away, but also enjoy the tranquility alone. He was very happy in the letter he wrote to Han Qi, his former magistrate: &quot;Dupingshan Hall dominates Shugang, and the mountains south of the Yangtze River can be seen thousands of miles away.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at Ouyang Xiu&#39;s description, I thought Pingshan Hall was located. The Shugang is majestic and tall. Today, I was standing outside the hall. Under the stone railing directly south of the tamarisk tree, there was a piece of happy and beautiful red leaves. I tried to look into the distance again, but my sight was blocked by trees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, we took the elevator to the 70-meter-high Qiling Pagoda of Daming Temple, which was really good for the distant view. Pingchuan and vast fields stretch as far as the eye can see, with no peaks in sight. The gray buildings in the distance are as small as building blocks. The Slender West Lake at your feet is like a long scroll of scenery. The water bank is curved and lingering, as if randomly embedded in thick or light green trees, with a few pavilions scattered among it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f50omRqfzEpUrZGqTAUZNwAPhOL3tL38LXovRKZD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;834&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f50omRqfzEpUrZGqTAUZNwAPhOL3tL38LXovRKZD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Daming Temple Qiling Pagoda (right) and Hongfo Pavilion&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqiang/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Among the many stone carvings displayed in Pingshan Hall and Ouyang Temple, Dongpo&#39;s &quot;Moon on the Xijiang River&quot; and Ouyang Xiu&#39;s &quot;The Drunkard&#39;s Pavilion&quot; attract people&#39;s attention. The latter was written by Dongpo in Yingzhou. Shen Xiong&#39;s flexible regular script has always been favored by calligraphers. The lyrics of &quot;Xijiang Moon&quot; were written in Pingshan Hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Shi’s feelings for Mr. Ou are unusual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ouyang Xiu has always promoted virtuous people, and his grand reward for Su Shi was well known to the world. The prevailing Taixue style of writing at that time was tortuous, profound, difficult and eccentric, and Ouyang Xiu and others were determined to correct it. In the spring of the second year of Renzong Jiayou&#39;s reign (1057), Ou Gong, as the examiner of the provincial examination of the Ministry of Rites, wrote &quot;the words are very simple and have no meaning&quot;. Su Shi, who was decorated by &quot;Zhaozao&quot;, was promoted to the second place in the &quot;Lun&quot; examination. There are many famous people among this year&#39;s Jinshi, and the Jiayou Gongju Examination is regarded as &quot;the first in the millennium imperial examination&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After some well-known candidates who were determined to win the exam failed, they were angry and dissatisfied. Someone wrote a memorial letter as a prank and sent it to Ou Gong&#39;s house. There were also frivolous scholars who surrounded Ouyang Xiu and made noises in front of his horse. &quot;Thousands of people gathered to laugh and curse.&quot; It was difficult for the patrolling soldiers to stop him. But since then, the sick writing style has gradually been reversed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ouyang Xiu spoke highly of the three Sus, and Su Shi&#39;s rich and fluent writing impressed him even more. In his letter to Mei Yaochen, he happily said: &quot;Reading Shi&#39;s book makes me sweat, so good, so good! I should avoid the road and let him go out of his way. What a joy, a joy!&quot; This is the discovery of outstanding young people by senior writers. I can&#39;t help but feel happy, and it&#39;s the sympathy of genius for genius. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou Gong’s support and expectations made Dongpo grateful for his whole life. He said that he was &quot;the most deeply influenced by it&quot;. In the seventh year of Yuanfeng (1084), Dongpo traveled from Huangzhou to Ruzhou. When he passed through Yangzhou in October, he set foot on Pingshan again. Hall. He &quot;remembers the drunkard every time he goes to Pingshan&quot;, and this time is no exception. The ink on the wall is still there, but my mentor has passed away. It has been more than ten years since we last met. Dongpo deeply missed Ou Gong with a piece of &quot;Moon over the Xijiang River&quot;, and also lamented that time flies and things are illusory:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;em>; After passing the Pingshan Hall three times, I heard the sound of a snap of my fingers&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;. &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;I haven’t seen the old immortal in ten years, and dragons and snakes are flying on the wall. &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt; em>;If you want to express your gratitude to the governor, you still sing the spring breeze of the willows. Don&#39;t say that everything will be empty when you turn around. When you don&#39;t turn around, it&#39;s all a dream. &lt;/em>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ou and Su, two literary loyal dukes, leaders of the two generations of literary circles, both set an example for the world with their moral articles. Both of their terms were short, but they made Yangzhou people miss them and made Pingshan Hall full of magnetism. Descendants came to worship in an endless stream, leaving many poems and essays, continuing a romantic tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Shizhen&#39;s &quot;Flowers and Grasses&quot; said: Pingshan Hall is not high in terrain and has an ordinary environment. &quot;However, the European and Su poems make the place heavy.&quot; Once the pavilions and pavilions are stained with the luster of a wise man, or Blessed by Li Cihongpian, it will be more charming. Even if the eaves and corners of the corridor columns have been worn away by time, they are still immortal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pingshan Hall was abandoned and rebuilt several times. The existing buildings were rebuilt during the Tongzhi period and were subsequently overhauled many times. It made Yixingya feel beautiful and condensed a touching teacher-student friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What can be done in half a year&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;By the time Dongpo came to Yangzhou as a prefect, it was more than 40 years after Pingshan Hall was built. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhezong Yuanyou&#39;s seventh year&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(1092)&lt;/span>; In February, Dongpo received his appointment in Yingzhou , he was very happy to move to Yangzhou. He took office in March and stayed in Yangzhou for less than half a year. It is difficult to achieve anything in such a short time, but he impressed the people with his good governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dongpo loves flowers. He plants flowers, appreciates them, gives them hairpins, sighs at them, and interacts with them in various ways. The plum blossoms, orchids, chrysanthemums, peonies, crabapples, camellias, and rhododendrons in his paintings are either beautiful or quiet, some stand alone, or the trees are full of beauty. He was also able to appreciate the charm of peony. He wrote a poem &quot;Zhao Chang Peony&quot; and said: &quot;Yangzhou has been red with thousands of leaves recently, which is the beauty of the fashionable times.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Dongpo took office, he did A decision that ruined the scenery: the Wanhua Festival was cancelled. He wrote to his friend Wang Gong: The Wanhua Hui has become a big harm to Yangzhou, and the suspension of the Wanhua Hui &quot;will ruin the scenery, but it will not cause karma.&quot; His article &quot;Harming the People with Joy&quot; said: Yangzhou peony is the best in the world, and Wanhua Hui uses flowers. More than 100,000 branches not only destroyed the gardens of various houses, but also disturbed the people and harmed the people. Yangzhou people were very dissatisfied. , causing harm to the poor people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Mozhuang Manlu&quot; written by Zhang Bangji, a scholar of the Northern Song Dynasty, records: The Wanhua Hui began when Cai Jing learned about Yangzhou, and continued every year thereafter. The flower party was held, &quot;everyone was excited and happy.&quot; Zhang Bangji commented: Su Gong’s administration was basically like this, benefiting the people, so he was praised by them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On his way from Yingzhou to Yangzhou, Dongpo witnessed the tragic situation of the people struggling to survive and being displaced: there were many refugees in the cities along the way, unable to pay their accumulated debts&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italic style, italic style _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(owing taxes to the government)&lt;/span>; and dare not return home. When traveling to the countryside, Dongpo often screened officials and visited villages. The elders all cried with sorrow: Although the summer wheat is ripe this year, the demand for payment of accumulated debts in the good years will be more stringent. &quot;If the apprentice is at the door and the yoke is on the body, no one will be able to die.&quot; Dongpo couldn&#39;t help crying. He wrote two memorials: I once knew Hangzhou and Yingzhou, and now I went to Yangzhou. &quot;I personally saw that the people in Zhejiang, Jingxi, and Huainan were all burdened by accumulated debts.&quot; They were increasingly in distress, and more than half of them were exiled or died. Huai and Zhejiang had the most accumulated debts and suffered from disasters year after year. The officials, under the supervision of their superiors, pressed for collection and threatened and flogged the civilians every day. How do people live in peace and contentment? How is the benevolent government of the imperial court reflected? Dongpo &quot;said nothing&quot; and asked the court to suspend collection for one year, &quot;so that the people who have been trapped for a long time can know the joy of having a full meal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Su Shi&#39;s request, the imperial court issued an edict on June 1 that the debts accumulated on Huainan East and West Road and Liangzhe Road were suspended for one year. He couldn&#39;t help being happy: &quot;The edict is generous and the debts are owed, and the father is of good looks. Congratulate me again, I won&#39;t be greedy for this treasure. I smiled slumped at Ruan Ji, and drank a few books to thank me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After investigation, Dongpo found out about Taxation, warehouse law, water transportation, etc. also put forward suggestions for improvement to promote the advantages and eliminate the disadvantages. Disciple Li Zhuo&#39;s &quot;Teachers and Friends&quot; records: In the past, the government allowed Gangyun&#39;s boatmen to carry goods privately to supplement their income. They often regard official ships as their home, repair them at any time, and sail them quickly. In recent years, private transport has been strictly prohibited. As a result, the bad people on the boats have become poor, and the amount of water and rice has been lost several times more than before. Both public and private companies have suffered losses. Some boatmen have stolen goods due to hunger and cold, and have broken down and sold the cars and boats. In Yangzhou, Chuzhou, Sizhou and other prefectures, many boatmen were whipped and sent away, and some became beggars and thieves. The memorial on Dongpo suggested restoring the old practice, which was approved by the court. The disadvantages are eliminated, both public and private parties benefit, and no one is punished for it. Li Lao quoted the words of &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; and lamented: &quot;The words of a benevolent person are extremely beneficial.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Gulin Hall to the north of Pingshan Hall was built by Dongpo, and the existing buildings were rebuilt in the late Qing Dynasty. It is connected to Pingshan Hall by a corridor with red beams. Separated by a wall to the east of Gulin Hall is the Main Hall of Daming Temple. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three characters &quot;Gulintang&quot; on the forehead of the hall are derived from Dongpo&#39;s Dharma stickers. The couplet &quot;Under the deep valley is graceful; in the high forest there are tall trees and trees&quot; comes from his poem &quot;Gu Lin Tang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The overall feeling of Gulin Hall seems to be less solemn than that of Pingshan Hall. From the perspective of etiquette, it is in line with the order of seniority and youth. Of course, the decoration is also very rich. On the walls of the lobby and the east and west wings, there are portraits of Ouyang Xiu, Mei Yaochen, and the Su brothers, &quot;Jiayou Gongju Picture&quot; and &quot;Red Cliff Night Tour Picture&quot;, etc., and calligraphy of East and West. Poe Linyan Zhenqing&#39;s &quot;Tie for a Seat&quot; and his &quot;Tie for Seeing&quot;, &quot;Tie for One Night&quot;, etc. Displayed in the window are the yellow-covered &quot;Song Dynasty Dongpo Collection&quot; and the Siku Quanshu&#39;s &quot;Dongpo Shu Biography&quot;. The walls are neatly arranged with poem plaques written by the &quot;Four Scholars of Su Sect&quot;. Among them, Chao Buzhi&#39;s seven-line poem &quot;Zhao Jinyun Guards Guan Yanyuan, Professor Zeng Yan and Ji Pingshan Hall&quot; was written when he invited Zeng Yanhe and others to gather at Pingshan Hall: &quot; &quot;Shu Gang is connected to Shu Mountain, and dragons and tigers reach up to the purple sky... There are no traces of Shaoshi Yangliu.&quot; From the latter sentence, it seems that Ougong Liu no longer existed when Chao wrote the poem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/hvHZ8TiSIHMCy64YvGQVhxo5HpGDHZ66XctremeD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/hvHZ8TiSIHMCy64YvGQVhxo5HpGDHZ66XctremeD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Jiayou Gongju Picture&quot; on the wall of Gulin Hall&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqiang/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In the fifth year of Yuanyou of Chao Buzhi &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (1090)&lt;/span>; served as the general magistrate of Yangzhou. Dongpo knew about Yangzhou, and he served as his deputy, and the teacher and student got along well with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the seventh year of Yuanyou&#39;s reign&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (1092)&lt;/span>; In August, Dongpo received the imperial edict and served as Minister of War and concurrently In the southern suburbs, the envoy Lu Bo was enshrined. After repeated urging from the imperial court, Dongpo arrived in Beijing in September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chao Buzhi was the son-in-law of Du Chun, the minister of the Ministry of War. When Dongpo took over, he happened to be Du Chun&#39;s immediate boss. Considering that his father-in-law and his teacher had never been close together before, and he was worried that they would not get along so well, Chao Buzhi introduced to Dongpo Du Chunli&#39;s style of life and the advantages of being an official and benefiting all things. Later, his father-in-law wrote a letter saying that he had a good time working with Dongpo, but he felt that he was &quot;arrogant and argumentative.&quot; Chao Buzhi replied with a long letter, detailing Su Gong&#39;s high integrity in governing:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have nothing to praise for the fact that Su Gong is a corporal. However, he is upright, pure and has few desires. He has become extremely frugal, but he takes on official responsibilities. He is jealous of evil and loves things. He does everything he knows, especially if he does not neglect the details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chao Buzhi bluntly refuted his father-in-law - he did not think that Mr. Su had this problem: &quot;The letter came from him because he was so arrogant and argumentative. This is beyond Bu&#39;s knowledge.&quot; He also reminded his father-in-law: People Not sages, everyone has his shortcomings and strengths. He gave the example of Ji An and Zheng, the famous officials of the Western Han Dynasty: they had different temperaments and had different brilliance and flaws, but Sima Qian praised them as virtuous. Therefore, &quot;Gentlemen use the same to differentiate, if that is possible.&quot; Chao Buzhi believed that if all the sages were harmonious in the court, then the local good deeds would be consistent with the court, and then nothing would be impossible. This son-in-law is really serious about arguing with his father-in-law and defending his master. Chao Buzhi was the earliest known among the four scholars of Su family, and his admiration for Su Gong can be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Walking to the small garden on the north side of Gulin Hall, this corner is relatively quiet. A group of rockeries, several old osmanthus trees, the slanting branches of the osmanthus cover the ridge of the green tile roof, and the tall maple poplars and bamboos sway in the wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/nDQX5lQW91ibVFGxj7x2nuGqLXrSXsTQnNm6K4di.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/nDQX5lQW91ibVFGxj7x2nuGqLXrSXsTQnNm6K4di.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Small garden on the north side of Gulintang&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqiang/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dongpo After arriving in Yangzhou, he was in poor health and rarely received guests. After receiving the tea as a gift from Mao Zhengzhong, he organized a dinner party on the Dragon Boat Festival and entertained guests with sumptuous dishes and rice dumplings in accordance with the solar terms. He especially used the clear water from Shujing to cook tea. Dongpo confessed: &quot;Repaying the favor to the king is not in vain. You know that I am not sipping lightly.&quot; Mr. Mao&#39;s good tea was not given to the wrong person. Now you know how solemnly I drank it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Gulin Hall was built, Dongpo also drank tea in the woods beside the hall, right? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Writing poetry almost got into trouble again&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Very different from the hustle and bustle of Slender West Lake, Zhuxi Park is sparsely populated and quiet. It is located on the bank of the ancient canal and was built in 1989 near the ruins of Zhuxi Temple. The scenery inside is good, it seems like the back garden of a Yangzhou person&#39;s home. There are not many outsiders to disturb it, and it is quietly beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the rain, the air is cool and moist, and the patches of ginkgo, osmanthus, pine, bamboo, red maple, etc. become cleaner and fresher. The camellias are in full bloom, and the dense, finely chopped off-white flowers of pittosporum exude a light fragrance. There are shallow mountains, thatched pavilions, stone bridges, bonsai, and several old ruins of former sites, all of which are impressive. On the left side of Zhuxi Jingshe stands a portrait of Wu Daozi, a praise inscribed by Li Bai, and a copy of the Three Jue Stele written by Yan Zhenqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s8EobfkUrvx87kxWMu6kjkKEKLnaGzQ7AJfUxfeY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s8EobfkUrvx87kxWMu6kjkKEKLnaGzQ7AJfUxfeY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Three Jue Monuments&quot; in Zhuxi Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The water area in Zhuxi Park is not small, with streams and lakes, and the water is introduced from canals. The semicircular bridge hole of Yueming Bridge connects with the reflection in the water, just like a full moon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the pond deep in the park, there are two vertical corridors of inscriptions, displaying poems by Du Mu, Wang Anshi, Qin Guan, Jiang Kui and others in praise of Yangzhou. Dongpo&#39;s poem stele &quot;Ci rhymes with Su Bogu&#39;s visit to Shugang and sending Li Xiaobo as envoy to Lingbiao&quot;, which was once a treasure of Zhuxi Temple. Later, the poem stele disappeared. Wang Shizhen went to the temple to search carefully and found the ruins of the stele. He brushed away the cobwebs and dust, and &quot;sighed three times, as if he were talking to the public and singing in reciprocity that day.&quot; Then Ci Yun wrote &quot;The Stone Engraving Poems of Visiting Mr. Dongpo in Shangfang Temple&quot;, &quot;I remember the Emei people, their literary talent is truly immortal.&quot; The stele. On display in the gallery are copies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/YOFvVaMjeCCuq5k4a8sO9dhQhYxjiAmvK3CaYvJI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;790&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/YOFvVaMjeCCuq5k4a8sO9dhQhYxjiAmvK3CaYvJI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhuxi Park Stele Corridor&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Dongpo&#39;s &quot;Return&quot; In front of the stele of poems &quot;Yixing, &quot;Three Poems inscribed on Zhuxi Temple&quot;, there is a large rosy red rhododendron, full of flowers and brilliant colors, which perfectly matches his cheerful and joyful poems. The third one wrote:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I feel that nothing has happened in this life, and I am still having a great year this year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I am happy to hear the good words after returning from the mountain temple, and the wild flowers and birds are singing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spring of the eighth year of Yuanfeng (1085), Dongpo received Shenzong’s edict. Allowed to live in Changzhou. He happily returned south from Nandu &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (today&#39;s Shangqiu, Henan)&lt;/span>; and arrived in Yangzhou in late April. The pastoral dream has come true, and I feel good. On the first day of May, I visited Zhuxi Temple with my friends. I was entertained and enjoyed everything I saw and heard. I couldn&#39;t help but write poems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/n46RDz21F4KrmOO7hXbatDGdZ6DQnW2X928ovIio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/n46RDz21F4KrmOO7hXbatDGdZ6DQnW2X928ovIio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Su Dongpo&#39;s Poetry Monument in Zhuxi Temple&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangqian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A quilt in the park In a corner hidden by bamboo branches and holly, there is an old well. The wall of the small gray stone well is more than a foot above the ground, and there are several deep marks on the inside that have been made by the well ropes over the years. The word &quot;Shujing&quot; is engraved on the stone tablet about one meter high next to it, which was inscribed by Professor Qin Ziqing, a descendant of Qin Guan. Shujing, also known as the &quot;First Spring&quot;, is one of the eight scenic spots in Zhuxi Temple. Ancient people said that the water from the well tastes sweet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuxi Temple is located at the end of Sichuan Hill, where the hills tend to become gentle. It is said that the ground veins of Shugang are connected with Shu, and the spring veins are also connected with Shujiang River. Therefore, Dongpo called the water from Zhuxi Temple the flavor of his hometown, and he wanted to carry the well water with the flavor of his hometown to his new home in the south of the Yangtze River. It&#39;s so pleasant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unexpectedly, he almost got into trouble again with poetry. In the sixth year of Yuanyou&#39;s reign &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (1091)&lt;/span>; when Dongpo was appointed as a Hanlin scholar and knew how to make imperial edicts, his political enemies went so far as to check the records for Luo Zhi. It was said that Emperor Shenzong died in March of the eighth year of Yuanfeng. Su Shi regarded this as a &quot;good word&quot; when he wrote a poem, and he was overjoyed. Dongpo quickly wrote a letter to defend himself, saying that he returned to Changzhou after mourning the late emperor in Nandu in early March. When I went to Zhuxi Temple in early May, &quot;I saw a dozen people, elders of the common people, talking and laughing to each other. One of them put his hands on his forehead and said, &#39;See, what a young official!&#39;&quot; I was pleased to hear that the common people were praising the young emperor. Sincerely; in addition, his request to return to Changzhou to farm was approved; when passing through Huaihe and Zhejiang, he saw a good harvest in sight, so he wrote a poem and inscribed it on the wall of the temple. If I have any bad intentions, how dare I openly show them to others? Moreover, it had already been two months since the death of the late emperor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally no danger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2AJvSxYhhCzzu7cHQHHFiYe4YGT1ujJQenAXUU4h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2AJvSxYhhCzzu7cHQHHFiYe4YGT1ujJQenAXUU4h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhuxi Park is very quiet&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Lu Xiangxiang/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuxi Park Located on Zhuxi Road, there are also streets named after Zenzhi, Shangfang, etc. in the surrounding area. Go east out of the south gate of the park, go to the intersection, and turn north onto Jiangdu North Road. The small high-rise residential building on the right side of the road is called Zhonghai Shixi. I feel that the quality of the community is good. It must be a pleasant sight for residents to overlook the garden path of the park from their balconies. Three to four hundred meters ahead is Zenzhi Road, a slightly narrower branch road. On one side of the road is a construction site, surrounded by beige walls with slogans such as &quot;Yangzhou is my home, take good care of it.&quot; Continue north along Jiangdu North Road, and the next intersection is Shangfangsi Road. There is less traffic, the road is smooth, and occasionally three or two pedestrians walk leisurely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhuxi Temple, also known as Zenzhi Temple and Shangfang Temple, was originally the palace of Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty. Later it became a famous temple and hosted many emperors, famous ministers and literary figures. It was destroyed by war in 1853. From palaces and gardens where emperors enjoyed themselves, to famous temples where eminent monks resided, to historical sites where poets lingered, they transformed into parks, communities, and streets where citizens walked... This corner of the soil has lost so much prosperity and joy that it has melted away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the Tang Dynasty to the Qing Dynasty, countless poems were written about Zhuxi Temple, and many brilliant figures in the history of literature left their traces here. It&#39;s romantic and arouses people&#39;s imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If their figures were reproduced on film, it would look like this: Du Mu came with the sound of cicadas after the autumn rain, the surrounding moss covered the steps, and the sweet-scented osmanthus fluttered; Zhang Hu walked through the bustling ten-mile street , went to Zhuxi Temple, stood on the Yueming Bridge, watched the beauties parading around, and sighed that if he wanted to die, he would die in Yangzhou; Dongpo was particularly active. After entering the temple, he drank Jisu water first, then Yingsu soup, and borrowed vines. The bed was made of tile pillows, so I lay down and enjoyed the cool bamboo breeze. Before I left, I didn&#39;t forget to draw a jar of well water and dip it in ink to write a poem on the wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His &quot;image&quot; materials are the most abundant and vivid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[抢课大战后，年轻人在夜校找到了生活的盼头]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260905]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After the countdown reached zero, the system crashed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prepare for this battle to grab classes, Jim, a girl born in the 1990s, specially made a form and arranged the volunteers in order of priority, including African drum lessons, hand disc lessons, silver jewelry making classes and tie-dye craft classes. . The plan could not keep up with the changes, and on August 11, the system crashed as soon as it was started. She was lucky enough to get a spot in an African drum class. &quot;It&#39;s like grabbing tickets for a concert,&quot; she said. &quot;I have to have a sense of belief. I have to get it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;500 yuan, 12 lessons, Each class is one and a half hours long. In the fall of 2023, night school, a mass life with a sense of the times, suddenly became popular on social platforms. According to data from Meituan and Dianping, searches for “night school” on the platform increased by 980% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Yi, a &quot;senior student&quot; at the Shanghai Citizen Night School, experienced firsthand the enthusiasm that he had never experienced before. Around 2018, she accidentally learned about the existence of citizen night schools. Her mother originally wanted to learn mobile phone photography, but when she signed up for the night school, she found out that the age limit was between 18 and 55 years old. There is a special &quot;senior college&quot; for seniors over 55 years old. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Yi has since &quot;entered the pit&quot;. In the past five years, she has tried leather goods classes, crochet classes, and buttoning classes one by one. She said that at that time, citizen night schools were not as popular as they are today, and “you could basically get them by sticking to the spots (open places).” Most of the night school courses at that time were common subjects such as calligraphy and painting, yoga, and vocal music. Five years later, the registration page is confusing. There are many courses on the list that can arouse interest just by looking at the names, such as &quot;Pet-Friendly Social Courses&quot;, &quot;Shanghai-style Drinking Tea&quot;, &quot;December Flower Goddess Series Courses&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The purpose of young people joining night classes is very simple. A girl explained her intention to Southern Weekend reporter: &quot;Socialize, meet more like-minded people, or you just want to learn a new skill, or just go and see Look, if you can learn, just learn, if you don’t, forget it. It doesn’t matter.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the fierce situation, Ren Yi encountered the waterloo of rushing to class, but in the end he got good luck. In a dynamic system where people drop out of classes at any time, she missed one class. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Flock into night schools to “learn art”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ren Yi prefers handicraft courses and has previously taken leather goods and crochet classes at night schools. In the leather goods class, they use a complete piece of vegetable-tanned leather as a starting point. After cutting, punching, and stitching, they learn to sew card holders, key bags, or gold bags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the buckle class in the fall of 2023, the new object she fiddled with was the buckle, a button used to fix the placket of traditional clothing. The course starts at 7pm on a weekday and lasts for one and a half hours. She coiled long soft buckle strips into various kinds of buttons, such as gourd-shaped and swallow-shaped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Time flies by. &quot;Every time, we may not be able to finish the work at the end, but the cleaning lady is so anxious that she has to get off work, so she rushes us.&quot; Ren Yi considers herself to be a relatively clumsy student in the class, &quot;but I just never tire of it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s0wHEYsHW8aVjkdSRXynltS6wqLVnaKeTXMte0wY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s0wHEYsHW8aVjkdSRXynltS6wqLVnaKeTXMte0wY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the buttoning class, students learned to make the buttons that fasten the placket of traditional clothing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Eryu is a freelance illustrator. His daily routine is &quot;sleep early in the morning and get up at noon.&quot; &quot;The night class at seven o&#39;clock every night happened to be a relatively sober moment of her day. She signed up for tea art classes, flower art classes and Yue opera classes, which were held from 7 to 8:30 pm every Wednesday, Thursday and Friday respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Eryu said that the tea art class and the flower art class are &quot;leisure and leisurely&quot;. If you spend thousands of dollars to learn it outside, it is not worth it. It is better to use the money to learn a language, which will look better. Practical knowledge. The low price of night school lowered the threshold for her to get involved in such hobbies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/03eGV06UVYLt2pKNdY7VIfLPfX5r98BOaa2tR8VL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/03eGV06UVYLt2pKNdY7VIfLPfX5r98BOaa2tR8VL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258775&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lu Eryu’s tea class notes. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, if I wanted to learn this kind of course, I could only search it online. Being able to identify the level of a teacher “may lead to being deceived”. Before signing up, Lu Eryu paid attention to the background of the tea art teacher. He was a &quot;first-class tea art technician&quot; and &quot;an inheritor of tea ordering in the Song Dynasty&quot;, with reliable qualifications. The teachers at Citizen Night School have been screened, and the course introductions are clearly listed, which saves you a lot of trouble. “You may have something you want to learn, but when you think of complicated things to understand, keep asking these questions. That home, maybe the enthusiasm has worn off after the consultation.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She likes the atmosphere of the tea art class very much. There are more than ten people in groups of four or five. A group of people listened to the teacher talk about the origin of tea and the brewing method of black tea. The teacher taught the formula for memorizing the six types of tea, &quot;&#39;traffic light (black tea, green tea, yellow tea)&#39;, plus &#39;black, white, and green&#39;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/D62e0AYt7n8glJp50gV7sbZSWe51VFLHbahlhKQw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/D62e0AYt7n8glJp50gV7sbZSWe51VFLHbahlhKQw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tea art classes at night schools are cheaper than training courses on the market, and the teacher qualifications have been specially screened, making it convenient and reliable for young people. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the tea art class, the teacher brought different brands of mineral water or purified water and poured it on In a transparent cup, everyone can blindly taste the taste of tea made with different water. Tools that measure pH value can measure &quot;some water is 7.37, some is 8.08, and some is 6.26.&quot; Lu Eryu observed that the pH value of water usually has little impact on the taste, while the hardness and mineral content of water will bring about polarizing evaluations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the handicraft class that Ren Yi took, the last class was usually a results report, where everyone displayed the results of the semester. &quot;The long table in the entire classroom is filled with various works of everyone. If there is a night market today, our entire class can come out to practice stalls.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/tEhLHAOeGTtWR5hfmDhLLEzSBguexVra0BZxRBac.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/tEhLHAOeGTtWR5hfmDhLLEzSBguexVra0BZxRBac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258776&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Achievements of the handicraft class. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is not something that needs to be persisted&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >; &quot;I signed up for night school simply because of several considerations. First, it is very economical. Courses of the same quality and content may cost two or three times the price on the market. Second, it is very secure and the risk is relatively low. It is a project run by the Shanghai Mass Art Museum. It is not like many hobby training institutions outside, which have been affected by the economic downturn. I ran away before finishing the course, and my money was wasted. .&quot; Jim told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She has only been officially employed for a few years. She works in a government agency, and her profession requires her to maintain a &quot;serious and rigorous image.&quot; She has certain standards for both her professional image and her own behavior. But during African drum lessons, she doesn&#39;t have to be so tight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every day, Jim commutes by bicycle, carrying a backpack with an African drum behind him. From a distance, he looks like a backpacker. A solid wood African drum weighs five or six pounds. When her colleagues asked her if she was going out to play, she never explained, &quot;I said I was just going out to play.&quot; After get off work, she took off her professional clothes, changed into casual clothes, rode 20 minutes to the night school, and then rode home for half an hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The teacher who teaches African drum lessons knows a variety of instruments, such as ukulele, ruan, guitar, and keyboard. There are 12 lessons. The first half starts with basic quarter notes and eighth notes, and is interspersed with rhythmic teaching in the middle. Now that the course is halfway through, she is struggling with the latest assignment - the teacher requires everyone to compose a song of their own. She observed that African drum teachers pay great attention to cultivating their arrangement skills, so that after they learn it, they can convey their life insights through the instrument instead of just typing out a melody written by others according to the score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;(Djembe drumming) is not something that I need to insist on. I don&#39;t find it burdensome. It is something that I can relax after work.&quot; Jim said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After weighing the distance of the class location, the time cost and the urgency of learning, Sun Yiran finally chose the bridge class. This is a very plentiful chess and card game. As she listened to the teacher, she wrote a card type and rules on the notebook. The courses of the bridge card have only one subway from her house. &quot;It is equivalent to going to the night school to go to the subway in the morning to class. After taking the class, I will take the same class of subway and arrive at home.&quot; Students who are also night school classes, some people live in Pudong, and they rushed to the night school to go far away from home, just because they were interested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sun still feel that the night school once a week will not bring too much pressure on himself. &quot;There are other more important things, and there are other time to deal with it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; She usually engage in data analysis work. According to her, it is the fact that the information is sorting, analyzed, and output &quot;as follows.&quot; &quot;Work is not a purely rational state. The bridge has a complete rule. The obvious logic can actually be counted. You can fully make an AI robot, which can be counted as the probability. What can the other party may produce.&quot; Sun still said, &quot;I Although the work sounds like a collation and analysis, it is not pure. Many people participate in decisions for factors. I will feel a little restrained during the work, but the bridge card is not. &quot;She said that the pleasure that the bridge can bring her is here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A multi -person chess and card game, observing the different styles of players on the bridge table can also bring fun. Sun still observed that some people have their brains, and they have the cards to deal with various types of cards, but they are &quot;strong and strong&quot;; some people, like her, need to continue to look at notes when they are against It is very long; there is only one game of the game, tending to let the opponent directly tell the card, everyone thinks about what to do together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/7mrdyb4en1ffavylaqsx7b8lypiqgj9uoxbe.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;540&quot; height = &quot;960&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/7mrdyb4en1ffavylaqsx7b8lypiqgj9uoxbe.jpg =&quot; 258773 &quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Bridge card notes. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (interviewee confession/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sun still described the night school on the night of the night school, boring and disappearing time. &quot;Eating dinner, fitness, and watching variety shows have passed. Watching variety shows or movies is not available, you can always watch it when you have time. But if I have something else, I will not watch it because I have less. Two hours of variety shows are sad. &quot;Sun still said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Night school has a attendance rate assessment. More than three absences will lose the qualifications for the next season&#39;s night school. Many interviewees said that the night school courses are now more than half, and most of them have persisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Now the pressure of young people is greater than before, it needs more release and find some fun. The way everyone finds fun is different.&quot; Sun still said, &quot;Because the Internet is developed, everyone is more accustomed to everyone. To communicate online, there are less offline exchanges, and more time has become more, so everyone may want to go out to play, including the night school. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;h4>; After a week, I am very hopeful. &lt;/Strong>; &lt;/H4>; &lt;p>; After incorporating the night school into the schedule every day, these young people also feel the changes brought about to daily life that seem to be useless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the results of MBTI personality testing, Lu Eryu is a &quot;I&quot;. In the &quot;liberating nature&quot; Yue drama class, everyone has to stand up and sing, but also press the legs and run the circle. The classmates in the class are paired with two or two, one singing Huadan and the other singing a niche. There are girls in the Yue opera class, and they are informal. In the first few lessons, they studied &quot;Sister Lin in the Heaven&quot;, and Lu Eryu chose to play &quot;introverted&quot; Huadan. &quot;Jia Baoyu had some eye -catching plays. He said that Sister Lin fell off the sky, and he wanted to show &#39;wow, so beautiful&#39;, and seeing Huadan was surprised. Some students would show a particularly exaggerated expression, and the teacher would be laughing. You will be infected in this environment, &quot;she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the past, Lu Eryu, who recognized the &quot;otaku&quot;, could not go out for more than 20 days. She said, &quot;Night school is actually equivalent to forcing herself to go out for a time, do not completely disconnect with society. Because I do n’t go to work, and do not go offline (social activities), they are getting farther and farther with the crowd, so I also force myself this. I feel like going out for three days. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; shooting the African drum with the students, leaving Jim&#39;s unforgettable experience. When drumming, because you are not familiar with the score, you are worried that you ca n’t keep up with the rhythm, often the rhythm will become faster and faster. At this time, as long as one person realizes the problem, you can slow down, and more and more people will find that the rhythm is fast, and the heart is pulled back to normal. In the orbit, &quot;the overall rhythm will be pulled back.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jim said that this is the opposite of the &quot;inner roll&quot; that everyone is keen to talk about now. &quot;Inner roll&quot; has a classic similar metaphor: In the cinema, one person stands up in the front row to cover the sight of the back row, so more and more people stand up, and in the end, everyone can only stand and watch movies. The slowing pace of the African drums is just the opposite. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Back to the classroom again, Sun still felt that the atmosphere of the night school was much better than the university or middle school age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;It was basically forced before high school, you can only learn these, whether you like it or not. Although the university is a major you chose, basically each class has a large proportion of people In fact, I don&#39;t want to hear it at all. &quot;She observed that there were few crowbroken birds in the bridge class in the night school, and the teacher&#39;s problem could always get the enthusiastic response from the students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, with the deepening of bridge knowledge, Sun still felt the pressure of knowledge accumulation with the mentality of learning new things. &quot;Now I feel a critical point, the happiness I do to do this, and I am almost the same as that I have to pay for it to make it.&quot; She was worried that as the difficulty increased, the bridge brand would become a little pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;This place is more difficult to grab. You report your name, pay money and time, and you don&#39;t practice well, you might as well not go.&quot; Sun still said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wang Yiyi, who reported the leather tool, was also anxious occasionally. Once, because of a business trip, leather classes must fall. &quot;I think I will learn less than someone else?&quot; The teacher consoled her in turn, and came back to help her make up for this lesson. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; However, Wang Yiyi still feels that &quot;every week is very hopeful.&quot; &quot;Can let you get away from work and find a new sustenance. Every day, you have been tired of work during the day. If you have a new content at night, you can adjust your life. Give your mind, &quot;she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; (except Ren Yi, Luer Yu, the rest of the interviewees are pseudonym) &lt;/p>; &lt;/&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[近十年来最具话题度的日本动画完结，如何盖棺定论？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260933]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-20 08:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; On November 4, 2023, the &quot;Attack Giant Final Season End Chapter&quot; was broadcast. The name of this name reads the ten -year -old &quot;Attack on the Giant&quot; animation is complete. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; All dust is settled, we can fully evaluate &quot;Attack on the Giant&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Giant&quot;), the most popular Japanese animation work in the past ten years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/eataXG52WGHYONNB1zyhtwjuiza3pd9ltb.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;1920&quot; height = &quot;1080&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/eataxg52wghyon1rm5nnb1zyhtwjuuiz9ltb.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;258823&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The classic scene of giants staring at the giant in&quot; Attack on the Giant &quot;. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (data map/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; Why is the giant fire? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Evaluating the work of &quot;Giant&quot;, one of the first to answer is: why &quot;Giant&quot; has such a high heat and discussion globally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ypyryryryryryryryryryryejedeeeeeeeeeeeeeeez.jpg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; widt h = &quot;640&quot; height = &quot;342&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ypyjefyry4ciyeCGnojedeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeEyez.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;258821&quot;>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color : #999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The protagonist classic gesture of&quot; Attack Giant &quot;. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (data map/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; TV is still the most important broadcast channel for animation in Japan. Most of the Japanese animation under the context of Chinese language is returned to the late -night program. Their broadcast time is usually after midnight. Such a broadcast time arrangement shows that these animations have not considered producing as the public from the beginning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This is because Japanese cultural products have formed an industry with extremely mature market segmentation. Each work in such a market is almost specialized in its main audience, as is the Japanese animation as a late -night TV show. In the first season of &quot;The Giant&quot;, the hot works of the same period were broadcast in the first season. ! &quot;Master of the Devil&quot;, &quot;A scientific ultra -electromagnetic cannon S&quot;, etc. These animations are customized from the background setting, character characters, and the direction of the story. Okay, but it also limits these works at a wider level of popularization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Correspondingly, the conventional production concept of Japanese animation has also been low -cost and small output. In the Japanese animation industry with DVD and Blu -ray discs for a long time, a animation can sell 10,000 discs, even if it is a best -selling work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Giant&quot; is a &quot;alien&quot; in Japanese animation. The average sales of 9 volumes of 9 volumes in the first season of &quot;Giant&quot; were 52067. As of August 2016, the total sales volume was 46,8603. It is also the first TV animation in Japan in 2013. In mainland China, iQiyi, which introduced copyrights exclusively, received a total of 320 million network playback volume at the end of the first quarter. In North America, the sales of the work up to 200,000 copies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In a group of Japanese animation works, the production level of &quot;Giant&quot; is far higher than the industry average (whether the picture, action, or soundtrack), which is the production company in the previous seasons of &quot;Giant&quot;. Wit Studio won the nickname of &quot;hegemony&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The production cycle of the &quot;Giant&quot; animation is also different -such hot works, but they did not do it while the iron was hot. The second season of &quot;Giant&quot; was broadcast, up to four years before the first season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This long pause comes from the &quot;hegemony agency&quot; decision. The company believes that the success of &quot;Giant&quot; is mainly to make the level of production level and think about it. Earning some hard work money, it is better to use the production resources similar to &quot;Giant&quot; to make your own original animation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This animation is &quot;Kabbenrui of the Castle City&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Crimson City&quot;), Wit Studio has poured quite a lot of resources. Judging from the quality of animation other than the plot, &quot;Cross -Iron City&quot; is better than the &quot;Giant&quot; in the first season. However, &quot;A Tiecheng&quot; is far from the expectations of Wit Studio regardless of word of mouth and heat. The shortcomings are on the story of &quot;A Iron City&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Wit Studio&#39;s &quot;detour&quot;, it exactly provides a control group that allows us to clearly see the root cause of &quot;Giant&quot; by controlling the variable method — its own story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Unlike those stories with the &quot;charming house&quot; attributes that are generally aimed at the two -dimensional enthusiasts, &quot;Giant&quot; is a very rare work created by the model of popular popular works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0IMA5HCV5KLSY818ABDIAN5L1JDBT82RP.jpg&quot; 0 &quot;width = &quot;960&quot; height = &quot;540&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0IMA5KLSY818H8L1JDBT82RPJW9VP.jpg&quot; data-key = &quot;258822&quot;>; &lt;/p. >; &lt;p style = &quot;coloror : #999; text-align: center; &quot;>; Humans and giants in&quot; Attack Giant &quot;. &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (data diagram/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The popular popular cultural works have some basic commonality, that is to do a good job of worldview, On the basis of suspense creation, rhythm grasp, character portrayal, etc., tell a story with a good level of production. The original comic of &quot;Giant&quot; was in accordance with this law until the end of the end -good -looking stories were liked. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; How to evaluate &quot;Giant&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; Since the popularity of &quot;Giant&quot; is mainly derived from the original comic work, the evaluation of &quot;Giant&quot; should also be the original comic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the &quot;Giant&quot; comics, the reader had such a saying at the time: When the &quot;Giant&quot; comics were released, the most pleasant was the fans of &quot;The Gold Master of Steel&quot;, because the New Century Month was even more young. The status of the ceiling is kept. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It looks almost paragraph, but it is not fair. Before the end, the &quot;Giant&quot; comic is expected to impact the strongest young man in 2000, but in the end, it failed because of the ending problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;New Century&quot;, &quot;Monthly&quot;, &quot;Juvenile Man&quot;, are not like statistical data that are more and more segmented in sports competitions now. &quot;As long as there are enough limited words, everyone It is possible to become the first in history in some respect. &quot; It is because in a place like Japan that emphasizes market segmentation, there are great differences between different types of Japanese comics. Not only are young people, young man, and girls have their own completely different creative models and concepts. Even if it is also a teenager, because the frequency of issuance is different from each issue, there are almost two completely different ecology between the monthly comics and weekly comics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the other hand, trying to pull the works of different creative age simply and rough into &quot;Guan Gong Zhan Qin Qiong&quot;, and it is impossible to draw valuable conclusions. The highly commercialized Japanese comics are largely guided by readers&#39; preferences to a large extent. Therefore, the theme of the story trend and expression of a comic to a large extent reflects the acceptance of the mainstream audience during that period, not simply determined by the author. Moreover, the comics created later are more likely to complete the processing of bridges and plots than previous works. Aside from these talks and the level of narrative, it is inevitable that &quot;thick and thin ancient&quot; is inevitable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Even the most important indicator of the success of a commercial work -heat and sales -can not be used as a basis for the advantages and disadvantages of cross -era comparison works. The current Internet environment, coupled with the increasingly saturated marketing of the producer, and the continuous development of markets outside Japan, leading to higher popularity and sales than in the past. For example, when the Blade Edition of Ghost Destroyer&#39;s Blade Edition was released, it broke the box office record of &quot;Thousands of Thousands and Chihiro&quot; for more than 20 years. But I am afraid that many people will think that the quality of the work of &quot;Blade of Ghosts&quot; really exceeds &quot;Thousands of Thousands of Thousands&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; So how do you evaluate what kind of work is &quot;Giant&quot; in the history of Japanese comics? May wish to transform your mind and think about such a question: When will the next Japanese comic works such as &quot;Giant&quot; appear, and can it avoid the ending of &quot;Giant&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For the current and future Japanese comics, &quot;Giant&quot; has a complete world structure and social organization description, which is rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The world built in comic works actually comes from the author&#39;s own worldview and values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking back at the history of Japanese comics, you will find that the comicists of various periods have given them a rich enough life experience in each period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The earliest batch of cartoonists, such as Tezuka, and Fujiko F. Two, have personally experienced the reconstruction of World War II and post -war Japan. They can grasp the grand propositions such as war and human fate in their works. For example, the &quot;Firebird&quot; of Tezuka is a grand work that cannot surpass the theme of the universe and life in the history of Japanese comics. The &quot;Doraemon&quot; of Fujiko Fujio, even for children&#39;s funny comics, does not forget to let Doraemon and Nobita Nobita laugh and cheer in their works: &quot;Japan is defeated!&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The subsequent generation of Japanese cartoonists experienced the Japanese left -wing movement in the 1960s and 1970s, which affected the depth and value of social propositions in their works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Next, with the Japanese economy&#39;s steaming in the 1980s, cartoonists who grew up in this era have an international perspective beyond their predecessors. Their works have begun to really throw their eyes into the real world outside Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The current young comic authors are in Japan&#39;s &quot;lost thirty years&quot; after the economic bubble. Corresponding to the stagnation of the economy is the slow development of Japanese society and the islands of popular culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The comics authors who grow up in this environment not only difficult to understand the relationship between the real country, but even the logic of understanding the social operation. This leads to a large number of Japanese comics. When it is still within the campus in the early stage, the plot and characters look pretty good. Once the development of the plot is beyond the scope of the school, the character logic and world setting will have various slots, which will eventually lead to rotten. In recent years, the hot works, such as &quot;Miss Huiye wants me to confess ~ the love of the genius ~&quot;, &quot;The agreed Dream Island&quot;, &quot;Beastars&quot; and so on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; From this perspective, works like &quot;Giant&quot; are unavailable for the current Japanese comic industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The difficulty of building the world is just one aspect. &quot;Giant&quot; can have the current popularity, mainly because it controls the rhythm of the story before the end. Before 90, the &quot;Giant&quot; comics achieved the charm that &quot;information asymmetry&quot; should have. Various hidden clues are displayed little by little, gradually patching together the complete world. In the process, the foreshadowing and illumination before and after the comics can be called the grass snake ash line and the veins thousands of miles. This pleasure of searching is the most attractive place of &quot;Giant&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; So, if you do not seek the true and credible world view, but ask, &quot;Can Japanese comics appear a wonderful but not bad work at the same time?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It seems not easy. This is because for a comic work released in a serial form, the fascinating of the previous plot is actually highly positively correlated with the final end of the end. This form of serialization determines that Japanese comics are a matter of &quot;killing the monarch and horses&quot;. To grab the readers&#39; attention in the Japanese comic industry, which is highly rolled in the high level, it is necessary to make a variety of abnormal bridges in the early stage of the comics. The more these bridge sections violate the daily behavior logic, the easier it is to attract readers&#39; interest. However, for the normal progress of the story, in the next plot, the author must give a reasonable explanation to these abnormal bridge sections. This is a task that is almost impossible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Almost all Japanese comics have such problems. For example, one of the slot points of &quot;One Piece&quot;: the ceiling of the entire comic combat power, and the red hair of one of the four emperors, why is it in the comics, and was bitten off by a sea monster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; What worsen this situation is that the high -strength update frequency of Japanese comics. As a weekly comics, the comic author is generally required to update more than a dozen pages of content per week, and the monthly magazines are generally 30 to forty pages per issue. During this period, the author must complete the story and line ideas and mirror design, as well as comics drawing from drafts to final finished products. Although the vast majority of cartoonists will hire more than one assistant, the work intensity of the comic author is still far exceeding the imagination of ordinary people. In this state of high -intensity, it is difficult to look forward to the comic author&#39;s exquisite concept of maintaining the story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In contrast, the giant&#39;s clever treatment of various foreshadowing and clues in the early stage is so unusual in Japanese comics. It is also the increasing increase in the previous characters and the story line that raised the difficulty of the entire story, and it also raised the expectations of readers. All of this has become an unsolvable problem that is in front of the author&#39;s Yoshanchuang. In the end, he chose a way to make readers puzzled. This regret is unavoidable to think about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第十一届茅盾文学奖颁奖，专访茅奖新晋得主]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260851]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 23:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; On the evening of November 19, the 11th Mao Dun Literature Awards Evening Party was held in Tongxiang, Zhejiang, Mr. Mao Dun. Yang Zhijun&#39;s &quot;Snow Mountain and Earth&quot;, Qiao Ye&#39;s &quot;Bao Shui&quot;, Liu Liangcheng&#39;s &quot;Benba&quot;, Sun Ganlu&#39;s &quot;Thousands of Rivers and Mountains&quot;, and East and West &quot;Echo&quot; 5 Minister of Novels won awards.</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 23:25:06 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[支原体肺炎不只小孩得，大人也要当心]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260909]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-19 22:05:01 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Mycoplasma pneumonia is not only obtained by children, and adults must be careful. Recently, Ms. Zhu, 30 in Guangzhou, had a fever and cold, her limbs was weak, and her yellow sputum was cough. I thought it was a normal cold, but it was not good. After treatment, they improved. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &lt;strong>; The inexplicable high fever has not been refunded, and the general treatment failed to alleviate it. The highest body temperature is 39.8 ° C, accompanied by chills and cold battles, and weak limbs. After going to the hospital for treatment, the doctor gave the ibuprofen antipyretic and cephalosporin antipitrier infection. Her symptoms were not obviously relieved. Then she cough and cough yellow and white adhesive. It was not easy to cough, especially at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; So Ms. Zhu came to the second medical department of the provincial medical respiratory and critical condition for treatment for treatment. He Yao found that her doctor found that her right lung lobe infection lesions were found, so she was hospitalized and was hospitalized to further improve the examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The doctor found through the bronchial mirror inspection that Ms. Zhu&#39;s right lower lung bronchus had a large amount of yellow and white phlegm. Through rapid pathogenic testing, she found the &quot;chlamydia of pneumonia&quot;. In other words, Ms. Zhu got the recently popular &quot;pneumonia villain pneumonia.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In response to her situation, the doctor gave Ms. Zhu quickly improved to discharged by Ms. Zhu for targeted anti -infection and cough, phlegm and other symptoms. &lt;span>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/spsp; &lt;/sps>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0c6bbfe3c842916AD38F2062.jpeg&quot; &quot; border = &quot; 0 &quot;STYLE =&quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 550 &quot;Height =&quot; 366 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0C62916De7086C6AA d38F2062.jpeg &quot;data -Key = &quot;258779&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; Ct the chest CT: the lower lung leaf can see multiple small pieces of small pieces, spots-like density, shadow shadow , The density is uneven, the realm is blurred, and the sheet is real -like, and the air bronchial shadow can be seen inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2A7C361A2222986af6426d6189.jpeg&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;OPA City: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 550 &quot;height =&quot; 376 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/2A7C361A2222298AF6426D6189.JPEG &quot;Data-KE y = &quot;258778&quot;>; &lt;/ p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; After treatment light. &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; &lt;strong>; Pneumoniacurgrosis is also an important pathogenic original of adult pneumonia. Acute pulmonary infections, which are mainly caused by pneumoniac virus, are mainly pneumonia caused by common bacteria such as pneumococcus such as pneumococcus pneumococcus in clinical manifestations. The pneumonia caused by other atypical pathogens such as Keji body is called &quot;primary atypical pneumonia&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, a number of domestic adult communities have obtained sex pneumonia (CAP) epidemiological survey results show that: Pneumoniac and pneumoniac bacteria are important pathogenic primary primary primary primary primary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to reports, the latent period of mycoplasma pneumonia is 1 to 3 weeks, and the form of onset is diverse. Most patients are only low fever and fatigue. And nausea and other symptoms of poisoning. The symptoms of the respiratory tract are the most prominent with dry cough. They often last for more than 4 weeks. They are accompanied by obvious sore throats. Occasionally have chest pain and blood in sputum. A few severe cases can cause respiratory failure, which is manifested as respiratory distress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Among the symptoms outside the respiratory tract, ear pain, measles, or scarlet fever rashes are more common, and very few patients can accompany gastroenteritis, cardiology, myocarditis, meningitis, polio, hemolysis, hemolysis, hemolytic dissolving, hemolytic solubility Sexual anemia, diffuse intravascular coagulation, arthritis and hepatitis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Little lung positive and image performance is obviously an important feature of mycoplasma pneumonia. Most of the lesions are blurred and low -density, cloud -fog sample -shaped infiltration shadows, which radiate from the pulmonary field from the pulmonary to the outer pulmonary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 酮 Nonone and tetracycline drugs are the preferred drugs for adult mycoplasma pneumonia. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; According to reports, commonly used drugs used to treat pneumoniacoplasma pneumonia include large cycloids, fluorosinone, and Tetracycline, macalentine antibiotics (such as Azithromycin and craticin) are currently the first choice for treating child pneumoniacumum pneumonia. Lisid antibiotics are resistant, so clinical clinical should be used in conjunction with the individual conditions of patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Does McBlack pneumonia cause &quot;white lung&quot;? A small number of mycoplasma pneumonia violates a wide range of diseases, or the diversion of mucus is not smooth, which has accumulated the bronchial, alveolar, and lung quality, causing &quot;lungs to not open&quot;, and even &quot;white lungs&quot; in imaging. Back and bronchoscopy treatments are healed in a short period of time, and most patients have a good prognosis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Doctors remind that pneumoniacum infection can occur throughout the year, especially in the late summer and autumn and winter. The main source of infection is patients and bacteria, mainly through air droplets, such as cough and sneezing. Student and school -age children and adolescents over 5 years of age are high -incidence people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The prevention measures for mycoplasma pneumonia mainly include: ① Far away from the source of infection, open windows to ventilate regularly indoor, and it is recommended to wear masks when densely and closed. ② Do your hand hygienic, wash your hands with soap (hand -wash), or wipe your hands with alcohol -free washing handwashing solution. ③ Eat more fresh vegetables and fruits, drink sufficient amount of water, sleep sufficient sleep, and exercise appropriately to enhance immunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sun Ruilin, director and chief physician of the Division and Chief Physician of the Second Medicine of the Provincial Medicine, reminded that during the high incidence of respiratory infectious diseases, if there is symptoms of upper respiratory infection such as cough and fever, it is recommended to seek medical treatment as soon as possible to find out the cause. Treatment of treatment, do not take medicine by yourself to delay the condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[体验“人生的旷野”后，两位985大学生选择回归国企和考研]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 05/14/ZJx5I7atgzPCjqiRvBFQtetVpSN3VGDPyg6VvrzP.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2449&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/14/ZJx5I7atgzPCjqiRvBFQtetVpSN3VGDPyg 6VvrzP. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;234068&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Every year during the school recruitment season, we can hear different employment stories of college students. In many narratives of 2023, the word &quot;wilderness of life&quot; appears frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although more and more college students are joining the difficult job search path of civil servants, central enterprises, state-owned enterprises, large Internet companies, etc., there are still some people who choose to find the wilderness of life on the so-called non-mainstream path. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two guests on this podcast, one of whom is a graduate with a double 985 master&#39;s degree, chose to take 3 months out of the busy school recruitment season to study cooking at New Oriental School and graduate. It has been on the hot searches on Weibo and Xiaohongshu twice. Another guest is also from 985 University. After graduating from undergraduate degree in 2021, he has experienced 100 different lives through various unique part-time experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, after experiencing the wilderness of life, they eventually returned to the traditional path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly has higher education brought us? Do we have to return to the mainstream path eventually? Does the wilderness of life really exist? Let’s find the answer in this podcast conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;Guests for this issue: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qianyu&amp;nbsp;2022 Master&#39;s Degree from Renmin University of China Graduate, currently working in a state-owned enterprise in Shanghai&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;KAMA (pseudonym) 2021 undergraduate graduate of Nanjing University, currently preparing to take exams in the art field&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000 ;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Listening tips:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 03:25 Before and after graduation, I was on two hot searches&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 09:52 at In college, you will feel that everyone has the same goals&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 13:48 Life is a process of constantly collecting plastic bags&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 25:57 Leaving the step-by-step study life , I chose a stamp collecting part-time job&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 36:25 Young people always have to do a reverse weaning from their parents&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 38:43 When I was working part-time, I concealed my academic qualifications &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 50:11 Learning to cook at New Oriental made me feel that people can live no matter what&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 52:20 After leaving college, I realized my shameful sense of superiority&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;► 60:44 Does higher education constrain our choices? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: right;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #808080;&quot;>; Editing: Zheng Yuchun &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: right ;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Promotion and operation: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[双向出击拉拢英菲，日本意欲何为？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 15, 2023, the United Kingdom will send 150 soldiers to Japan to participate in the &quot;Alert Island 23&quot; military exercise . This bilateral exercise is the first joint exercise since the &quot;Reciprocal Access Agreement&quot; between the two countries officially came into effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A week ago, the fifth &quot;2+2&quot; meeting between Japan and the UK&#39;s foreign ministers and defense ministers was held face-to-face after a lapse of five years. In a joint statement issued after the talks, the two sides made it clear that they would increase the frequency of joint exercises. In addition, Japan will also provide cooperation with the United Kingdom in dispatching an aircraft carrier strike group to the Indo-Pacific in 2025. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Providing cooperation for the deployment of British aircraft carriers to the Indo-Pacific is just the latest step in deepening defense cooperation between Japan and countries outside the Asia-Pacific region. At present, Japan is promoting the joint development of next-generation fighter aircraft with the United Kingdom and Italy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan not only extended military cooperation invitations to European countries, but also played diplomatic cards in Southeast Asia. Previously, from November 3 to 5, Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida visited the Philippines and Malaysia for the first time. Since the beginning of this year, the Kishida government has frequently visited Southeast Asia, covering almost 10 ASEAN member states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan&#39;s efforts to win over countries in and outside the Asia-Pacific region such as the United Kingdom, France, Australia, and the Philippines are nothing more than wanting to revisit its old dream of the Russo-Japanese War and seek more interests for itself. While the United States continues to promote its Indo-Pacific strategy &#39;, and in the context of great power competition, relevant countries have also followed suit, trying to get a share of the regional game.&quot; Teng Jianqun, director of the Diplomatic Research Center of Hunan Normal University, told Southern Weekend reporters that in the context of multipolarization of international politics and global economicization, At the moment, Japan is trying to win over a large number of countries to stir up trouble in the Asia-Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 9, the spokesperson of the Chinese Embassy in the UK responded to the erroneous remarks about China in the UK-Japan “2+2” joint statement, saying, “China has indisputable territorial sovereignty and maritime rights in the East China Sea and South China Sea. rights and interests. China will unswervingly safeguard its sovereignty and rights and interests, and firmly oppose relevant countries to sow relations between regional countries and create confrontation and confrontation. If the UK and Japan really want to become responsible countries, they should stop fanning the flames and stirring up trouble everywhere. Do things that contribute to regional peace and stability.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/E8VmoXNPlqgtjxiaGlfabmI7LvYMgX0hrypTsScd.jpg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/E8VmoXNPlqgtjxiaGlfabmI7LvYMgX0hrypTsScd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258739&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 11, 2023, local time, London, England, British Prime Minister Sunak (right) and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida in London Towers sign defense agreement. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Winning over&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 7, Fumio Kishida met with the US Secretary of State at his official residence. Lincoln talks, exchanged views on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, and confirmed that the two sides will cooperate on related issues. The day before, Blinken had just concluded his &quot;whirlwind diplomacy&quot; in the Middle East and arrived in Japan to attend the Group of Seven (G7) foreign ministers&#39; meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The G7 Foreign Ministers’ Meeting, held in Tokyo from November 7th to 8th, was the last offline meeting hosted by Japan during its tenure as the G7 Presidency. During the meeting, Japanese Foreign Minister Yoko Kamikawa held talks with the foreign ministers of Canada, Germany and other member states, and took the opportunity to hold 95-minute consultations with the British Foreign Minister and Defense Minister. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In talks with defense ministers from various countries, the concept of a &quot;free and open Indo-Pacific&quot; was frequently mentioned by Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan&#39;s reaffirmation of the &#39;Indo-Pacific Concept&#39; through the G7 Foreign Ministers&#39; Meeting is just a rehash of old tunes with nothing new. What really deserves attention is Japan&#39;s gradual advancement in implementation.&quot; China Institute of International Studies Tang Qifang, associate researcher at the International Institute for Strategic Studies, analyzed this to a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, the Japanese government adopted three security documents: the revised &quot;National Security Strategy&quot;, &quot;National Defense Strategy&quot; and &quot;Defense Force Preparation Plan&quot;, which not only clearly stated that it must have counterattack capabilities, but also emphasized that While taking the Japan-U.S. alliance as the foundation, we will deepen cooperation with so-called &quot;friendly countries that share values&quot; and strive to realize the concept of a &quot;free and open Indo-Pacific.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Less than a month after the &quot;Three Security Documents&quot; were released, Japan and the United Kingdom signed a &quot;Reciprocal Access Agreement&quot;, allowing both sides to conduct larger-scale and more complex military exercises on each other&#39;s territory. At this point, the United Kingdom has become the only European country that can conduct bilateral military exercises on Japanese territory, and is also the second country to sign this agreement with Japan after Australia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After the promulgation of the new security strategy, Japan&#39;s defense policy has shifted from defensive to offensive, and the weapons and equipment, combat posture, and troop deployment of the Japanese Self-Defense Force have also changed from defensive to offensive.&quot; Teng Jianqun pointed out, &quot;The signing of the Reciprocal Access Agreement means that the relationship between Japan and relevant countries is entering a paramilitary alliance. The Japanese Self-Defense Forces can use this to go out and send troops to the United Kingdom and Australia to achieve the so-called &#39;national normalcy&#39; in a roundabout way.&quot; At the same time, Japan also wants to take the opportunity to release its military production capacity and accelerate the entry of weapons and equipment into the international market.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to linking up with countries outside the Asia-Pacific region, the Philippines has also become a key target for Japan to try to win over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 3, Fumio Kishida arrived in the Philippines and held talks with Philippine President Marcos. In Manila, Fumio Kishida delivered his first speech to the Philippine Congress. In his speech, Kishida Fumio praised that bilateral relations between Japan and the Philippines have entered a &quot;golden age.&quot; At the same time, Japan and the Philippines also reached a consensus on launching negotiations on the Reciprocal Access Agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The targets chosen by Japan are all core members of the US military alliance. Australia is known as the US&#39;s &#39;Southern Anchor&#39; in the Asia-Pacific region, and the UK is its core ally in Europe.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out, &quot;Although the Philippines is weak, the new President Marcos has tilted his foreign policy toward the United States after taking office. The United States is trying to turn it into a sharp thorn wedged in the South China Sea.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Linkage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Japan is not only &quot;casting a wide net&quot; on the road to expanding its &quot;paramilitary alliance&quot;, but also continues to promote joint military exercises with relevant countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japanese media reported that the goal of the &quot;2+2&quot; talks between Britain and Japan is to enhance military coordination and interoperability by holding &quot;more frequent and more complex military exercises.&quot; After the signing of the Reciprocal Access Agreement, the first joint military exercise between Japan and Britain is on the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, during the meeting of the G7 foreign ministers, the United States dispatched two aircraft carriers, the USS Ronald Reagan and USS Vinson, and the Japanese helicopter carrier USS Hyuga to conduct joint military exercises in the Philippine Sea. Rear Adm. Carlos Sadillo, commander of the U.S. Navy&#39;s First Aircraft Carrier Strike Group, pointed out that the exercise was designed to &quot;demonstrate how the United States and Japan can quickly respond to crises and interoperate and coordinate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Australia, the Japan Air Self-Defense Force is seeking to normalize military deployment. Japan plans to station F-35, F-15 and F-2 fighter jets at air bases in Australia as early as fiscal 2024, with each deployment lasting several months. Japanese media pointed out that there is no clear legal basis for dispatching permanent troops to Australia or providing security assistance when necessary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Reciprocal Access Agreement facilitates joint military operations between Japan and Britain and Australia, and the same equipment purchased from the United States provides a sufficient platform for mutual integration and interoperability.&quot; Military Expert Wang Qunhuai told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2020, the United States approved the sale of 105 F-35 fighter jets to Japan. Adding the 42 previously purchased, Japan will have a total of 147 F-35 fighter jets. Australia and the United Kingdom are also &quot;die-hard fans&quot; of F-35 fighters and have ordered a total of 210 F-35 fighters from the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, in 2023, the United States successively agreed to sell hundreds of &quot;Tomahawk&quot; cruise missiles to Australia and Japan to enhance its naval long-range strike capabilities. It is worth mentioning that the United States has always been very cautious about the export of &quot;Tomahawk&quot; missiles. Prior to this, Britain was the only country besides the United States to possess this type of missile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In fact, the sale of weapons and equipment is an important tool for the United States to strengthen alliance relationships. The more American equipment is used, the deeper the relevant countries will be tied to the United States, and the more military sovereignty concessions will inevitably be made.&quot; Analysis by Wang Qunhuai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan’s military assistance to the Philippines came more directly. &quot;The Kishida government not only wants to provide money and equipment, but also tries to send troops to the Philippines.&quot; Tang Qifang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his visit to Manila, Fumio Kishida sent a &quot;maritime gift package&quot; to the Philippines. According to a senior Japanese government official on November 3, Japan will provide five sets of fixed coast surveillance radars to the Philippines. This is the first time Japan has provided defense equipment to a foreign country under this mechanism since it established the &quot;Government Security Capability Strengthening Support&quot; (OSA) framework in April. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past, Japan focused on relying on &#39;government development assistance&#39; (ODA) and using economic diplomacy to expand its international influence, but now it has turned to improving the security capabilities of recipient countries.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out, &quot;Japan It is hollowing out the peaceful constitution step by step, trying to transform from an economic power to a military and political power.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Team formation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The interviewed experts and scholars told Southern Weekend reporters that Japan and the United Kingdom , the Philippines and other countries inside and outside the Asia-Pacific region &quot;form a circle&quot; and actively carry out defense cooperation, each getting what they need and utilizing each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, then Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe held talks with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and proposed the &quot;Free and Open Indo-Pacific Strategy&quot; for the first time in the joint communiqué. &quot;Since then, Japan has continued to promote this proposition in diplomatic settings, intending to cooperate with the United States in enhancing its intervention capabilities in the East China Sea, South China Sea and even the Asia-Pacific region, and to demonstrate its presence and enhance its international status and influence.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tang Qifang’s view, Japan’s continuous breach of red lines in defense policy is inseparable from the acquiescence and connivance of the United States. &quot;The United States expects Japan to act as a &#39;pawn&#39; in the Asia-Pacific and help it reduce its burden and pressure. Japan also hopes to vigorously develop its military power and pursue becoming a military and political power. Although the interests of the two sides are different, the strategic goals are basically the same.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The United Kingdom, Australia and other countries also have their own plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After Brexit, the UK has become an &#39;outcast&#39; in Europe. Based on geopolitical considerations, the UK hopes to use Japan as a &#39;bridgehead&#39; to strengthen its military deployment in the Asia-Pacific and highlight its status and From the perspective of business interests, the UK attaches great importance to the economic vitality of the Asia-Pacific region.&quot; Teng Jianqun analyzed that this is also the main reason why European and Asia-Pacific countries are willing to cooperate with Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as March 2021, the British government released &quot;Global Britain in the Era of Competition: A Comprehensive Assessment of Security, Defense, Development and Foreign Policy&quot;, which pointed out for the first time that the UK&#39;s global strategy must move towards the &quot;Indo-Pacific&quot; &quot;region&quot; tilt, and in May of that year dispatched the most advanced &quot;Queen Elizabeth&quot; aircraft carrier strike group to the Indo-Pacific region for the first time to conduct so-called &quot;freedom of navigation&quot; operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the British aircraft carrier&#39;s &quot;global journey&quot; did not go smoothly. Two destroyers accidentally separated from the formation. In September 2023, the British Navy&#39;s &quot;Queen Elizabeth&quot; aircraft carrier conducted joint patrols with allies along the coast of Norway and the North Atlantic. Due to the significant reduction in the number of British Air Force fighter jets, the British aircraft carrier, which can normally carry about 30 F-35B fighter jets, only carries 8 fighter jets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The wish of &#39;Global Britain&#39; is very good, but Britain is no longer the &#39;Empire on which the sun never sets&#39; in the past. Whether its strength can match its ambitions is still a question. And the Philippines is not only weak in strength. On the other hand, the determination to follow the United States is not as strong as that of Japan, Britain and Australia.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out, &quot;It remains to be seen how important the relevant countries can play in the so-called &#39;Indo-Pacific strategy&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facts As a die-hard ally of the United States, Japan is not willing to become a &quot;tool&quot; of the United States and still hopes to regain its autonomy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, the United Kingdom, Japan and Italy announced that they would jointly develop a common airframe for next-generation fighter aircraft. The three countries are determined to integrate their respective capabilities in cutting-edge air combat technologies such as stealth and high-tech sensors. By 2035 The latest fighter jet was launched years ago. It is worth noting that this is the first time since World War II that Japan has participated in a joint research and development program for advanced fighter aircraft that does not include the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Japan has specially set aside funds in its defense budget for fiscal year 2024 and plans to develop an air-to-air missile for use by the next-generation fighter aircraft jointly developed by the three countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan does not want to put all its eggs in the American basket, nor does it want to hand over its military industry dividends to the United States. However, historically speaking, no matter what kind of cooperation Japan adopts, it will It is difficult to break through the restrictions imposed by the United States in military production. This time is no exception. The United States will try its best to block it and strangle its research and development plans, including Japan&#39;s new generation fighter aircraft, in the cradle.&quot; Teng Jianqun concluded, &quot;Japan&#39;s It is difficult to get rid of the constraints of the Japanese and American League framework. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href =&quot; https: // feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[9.9元价格战背后：前三季近万家咖啡企业倒闭，有独立咖啡馆营业额不够发工资]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260913]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Lin Li runs an independent coffee shop on Beijing Road in Guangzhou. This shop has been open for more than three years and is currently experiencing difficulties. During the period, the monthly turnover cannot be covered by employee wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li told reporters from Nandu·Wancaishe that this year there has been a wave of store openings in the coffee industry. Some people who do not know how to open stores blindly open stores and occupy market space. Professional community coffee shops have attracted customers who know how to taste fine coffee. , and the spatial experience originally provided by independent coffee shops has become no longer rare, because chain coffee shops are also setting up large stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The chain coffee brands with larger store areas have taken away the in-store customers, and the community coffee shops along the street have taken away the in-store and take-out coffee cups. In short, now coffee shops The density is too high.&quot; Lin Li lamented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d33e2d4d182d5e6ae80bb77a5591e6b9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d33e2d4d182d5e6ae80bb77a5591e6b9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258785&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since this year, Coffee chains are making every effort to open stores. Recently, Cudi Coffee, which was founded just one year ago, announced that it has more than 6,000 stores, setting a new record for domestic coffee stores; Luckin announced that it has more than 13,000 stores and predicts that it will open 15,000 stores by the end of this year; Starbucks is also speeding up Expanding stores, it &quot;opens a new store every 9 hours in China&quot;; Manner, a specialty coffee brand founded in Shanghai, is also running wild. Yesterday (October 30), its number of stores officially exceeded 1,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, amidst the craze for coffee, a large number of coffee shops failed to survive this year. Statistics from the third-party platform Kamen show that in the first nine months of 2023, the number of newly registered coffee-related companies was approximately 45,000, an increase of 74.10% over the same period last year, and 9,825 coffee companies were deregistered, with the number of cancellations increasing by 58.95% year-on-year. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, reporters from Nandu Bay Financial News visited a number of independent cafes, trying to understand whether they can survive the &quot;9.9 yuan cup of coffee&quot; storm and the increasing density of coffee shops. , what do they rely on to survive? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Cafes are everywhere, and the 9.9 yuan price war continues&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Nearly 10,000 coffee companies closed down in the first nine months&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Lin Li works as a manager at an independent coffee shop on Beijing Road in Guangzhou Store manager, this store has three floors. The first floor of the store serves as the entrance. The second and third floors are bright and comfortable with simple decoration. There are large floor-to-ceiling windows on the side near the corner, allowing you to have a panoramic view of the outside scenery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The coffee products sold in the store include classic American coffee, milk coffee, special coffee and hand-brewed specialty coffee, with prices ranging from 20 to 100 yuan. There are also some baked simple meals for single consumption. The amount is about 50 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/4b6280e9848604abf3a19a02f5a9a56c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/4b6280e9848604abf3a19a02f5a9a56c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258786&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li told Nandu ·Wancaishe reporter, &quot;There used to be many customers on weekdays, and the daily turnover could reach tens of thousands of yuan.&quot; It is located in a tourist area, and it is &quot;extremely busy&quot; on weekends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, since the adjustment of epidemic prevention and control measures this year, the operation of the store has turned from profit to loss. In this regard, Lin Li said that he originally thought that there would be more customers this year, and he also vigorously promoted some creative and special products at the beginning of the year to attract traffic, but the effect was not good. &quot;Currently, the turnover is only two to three thousand yuan on weekdays and tens of thousands of yuan on weekends.&quot; However, after deducting the high cost of 65,000 yuan in shop rent, water, electricity and raw materials, there is still more than 10,000 yuan left, which is not even enough to pay employees&#39; wages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is located in a popular tourist destination, tourists do not help its business much. During the National Day this year, boss Lin Li visited nearby coffee shops. Although the streets were crowded, there were many empty seats in the coffee shops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li told reporters an observation: Foreign tourists are basically adults with children, and they do not have the habit of drinking coffee. On the contrary, Guangzhou locals did not travel abroad last year and came to coffee shops to kill time. There are more people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to changes in consumer customer groups, the increasing number of coffee shops on the streets has also impacted store business. Lin Li bluntly said that there has been a wave of store openings in the coffee industry this year. Some people who do not know how to open stores blindly opened stores, squeezing the market space. “The chain coffee brands with larger store areas have taken away the customers who come to the store, and the community coffee shops along the street have taken away the customers. The number of coffee cups sold in stores and for takeaways has increased. In short, the density of coffee shops is too high now.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The density of coffee shops in the Beijing Road business district is indeed increasing. Nanduwan Financial News reporter learned through Dianping that there are about 200 coffee shops within 2 kilometers of the Beijing Road business district. As of October 27, about 30 coffee shops have opened in the past three months, that is, every Within three days, a coffee shop opened in the Beijing Road business district. Among them, there are many well-known chain large space coffee shops such as Lavasa Coffee, store by.jpg, M Stand, and Starbucks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since this year, chain coffee brands have indeed been making great efforts to open stores. For example, Kudi’s stores have exceeded 6,000, and Luckin’s stores have exceeded 13,000. Statistics from Kamen show that in the first nine months of 2023, the number of newly registered coffee companies was approximately 45,000, an increase of 74.10% compared with the same period last year. At the same time, many coffee shops have fallen in the coffee wave. Kamen data shows that in the first nine months of 2023, 9,825 coffee companies have been canceled, and the number of cancellations has increased by 58.95% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to intensive store openings, leading coffee chain brand Luckin Kudi Tims has also successively launched promotions of 9.9 yuan/cup or 8.8 yuan/cup, lowering the selling price of coffee in order to seize the market share. customer. Although there is a big difference between the customer base of low-price coffee and the customer base of independent coffee shops, the impression that a cup of coffee only costs 9.9 yuan is still engraved in the hearts of many consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/b5d8d224b36f1aa66eb98e4984ecbc14.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/b5d8d224b36f1aa66eb98e4984ecbc14.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258781&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li revealed, A customer once was surprised when he saw the price list after entering the store, &quot;Americano coffee actually costs more than 20 yuan.&quot; However, Lin Li believes that &quot;six or seven years ago, the Americano and latte we drank were more than 20 yuan a cup.&quot; Yes, this is the normal price.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill, another independent cafe operator, also encountered customers who were confused about the price at his store. Bill thought, &quot;American and American cuisine cost more than 20 yuan. The nine-yuan American style uses different coffee beans, and the taste is different, so the price is naturally different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, due to the competitive pressure brought by the store opening wave and price wars, Bill&#39;s store coffee Some price adjustments have been made. For example, the price of iced Americano coffee has been reduced to 20 yuan, and many stores have launched a beverage promotion of &quot;42% off in the morning and 32% off in the afternoon on weekdays&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reduce the store area and shift towards high-end customers&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Independent cafes are also planning to change&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with the numerous stores that are still struggling with losses, Bill will The coffee shop moved from a shop along the street in Guangzhou to a community, and its store went from losing money to being able to continue operating. Although the operating area of ​​Bill&#39;s store has only been reduced by about 10 square meters, the rent burden has been cut in half, down to four digits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill is a coffee fan with more than 20 years of coffee experience. Out of interest, he opened his first coffee shop in 2019. However, the rent of this shop is high due to the location where it is located. , but the flow of people is not much, and it has been affected many times by the epidemic before, so it is not profitable. Last year, Bill accidentally saw a store in the community for rent, so he closed the old store and started over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The new coffee shop covers an area of ​​about 20 square meters, and most of the coffee drinks sold in the store are hand-brewed coffee. Bill manages it by himself because costs have dropped. According to his estimate, he can run the business with only 300 yuan a day. On the day when a reporter from Nandu Bay Financial News visited, he sold several hundred yuan of coffee beans and several hundred yuan of coffee drinks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ming Yue, who lives in Guangzhou, also wanted to open a coffee shop. Before opening the shop, she did some research. Mingyue found that although there were many coffee shops in Guangzhou, most of them had different decoration styles and menus. The drinks on the menu are all very similar. “As soon as I look at the menu, I can imagine what this cup of coffee will look like and taste like.” Moreover, what confuses Mingyue even more is that even though there are so many coffee shops, when she wants to When drinking a cup of hand-brewed coffee, she didn&#39;t know where to consume it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/90b868772cf40aeccd71515e58371d9d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;450&quot; ​​data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/90b868772cf40aeccd71515e58371d9d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258782&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, last year , Mingyue opened an independent cafe in the Yanyun West Community of Huifu East Road, Guangzhou. In order to distinguish it from most coffee shops in the market, she positioned the shop as a high-end cafe targeting high-end customers. The cafe is located in a quiet community. It has a two-story store with an area of ​​about 200 square meters, a monthly rent of 25,000 yuan, and three employees. The price of coffee products in the store ranges from 38 to 168 yuan, and competition-level premium hand-brewed coffee is also available. However, the supply of such products is small, and the pricing depends on the type of beans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One year after opening the store, Mingyue confessed to a reporter from Nandu Bay Financial News that the coffee shop business is not easy. Not many people know about the newly opened store. It is a process of slowly accumulating word-of-mouth and popularity. , until last month, the store was still losing money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the situation has been slowly improving. The differentiation of positioning and the ability to brew coffee have helped her a lot. Mingyue said, &quot;We suffered the most when we first opened, because at that time Severely affected by the epidemic... Only half of this month (October) has passed and we have recovered our capital. This month is a steady profit.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Independent cafes survive on high-quality beans&lt;/h4 >; &lt;h4>;But it may be difficult for novices to identify the route&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After visiting these independent cafes, reporters from Nandu Bay Financial News learned that the reason why there are so many coffee shops in operation is difficult, in addition to the location where they are located. In addition to the problem and the influence of coffee competition, one of the problems is that the target group positioning is not clear enough. His customer group includes white-collar workers, freelancers, and office workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why stores like Mingyue and Ah Bill can survive is that in addition to working hard to accumulate regular customers in terms of cost and positioning, it is also very important that they have good quality and cost-effectiveness in the supply chain. A channel for coffee beans that are high quality and in line with market tastes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d27afb385794723e0854e23204cf3d24.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; height= &quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d27afb385794723e0854e23204cf3d24.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258784&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Coffee beans sold at Mingyue store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ming Yue attaches great importance to the selection of coffee beans. The positioning of her coffee shop is to make competition-level specialty coffee, and she can often get some micro-batch specialty beans. Mingyue told a reporter from Nandu Bay Financial News that she drank more than a thousand beans from April this year to now before finally deciding to purchase a dozen beans. &quot;Finding beans can represent many things, and the struggle to make specialty coffee is actually to compete with your ability to select products.&quot; Her feeling is that being able to find good coffee beans will benefit the store&#39;s customer base - those who know the goods and are willing to spend money. For customers who have money to drink expensive beans, it is very competitive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to high-quality coffee beans, another key point in product selection is to allow customers to drink coffee with high cost performance. Mingyue is trying to improve the price-performance ratio of the coffee in the store as much as possible. For example, the Americano coffee sold in its store is priced at 68 yuan. It uses green label Geisha beans. &quot;Customers who know the product will think that I sell it very cheaply when they see it in the store.&quot; The price of this bean in the market is 88 yuan. Yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/9bb65a681121dcf9ca50165b21d30b73.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/9bb65a681121dcf9ca50165b21d30b73.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258783&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to passing high quality In addition to providing coffee drinks, selling coffee beans is also the main way for some independent cafes to make money. Some cafes will buy green coffee beans and roast them themselves, making them into cooked coffee beans before selling them, but the coffee beans are usually sold to regular customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nandu·Wancaishe reporter learned from many coffee practitioners that, excluding all processing costs, the selling price of cooked beans is about three times that of green beans, and a green coffee bean sells for 100 -120 yuan/kg, so converted, the selling price of this cooked coffee beans is about 300 yuan/kg, and the specific situation will be different in each coffee shop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Bill, he would rather sell coffee beans than sell coffee. Bill roughly estimated that 50% of his store&#39;s turnover comes from selling coffee beans, and 50% comes from consumption in the store. &quot;The people who buy beans are mainly regular customers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill’s coffee menu has a full three-page hand-brewed coffee bean list. In addition, he also took out more than a dozen beans from the cabinet that were not on the bean list and introduced them to reporters in detail. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7567eda950cc92f0e34c20047344c3c3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1067&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7567eda950cc92f0e34c20047344c3c3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258788&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While making Regarding coffee, Bill doesn’t have many coffee equipment in his shop. An Italian machine is his main tool for making American coffee and milk coffee. Bill said frankly, “When I opened the store, I planned not to sell coffee drinks, but I decided to do it after thinking about it.” This decision was the right one. Half of Bill’s current sales volume in the store still comes from these coffee drinks. “These are what we use.” To stabilize the basic market.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bill sells hand-brewed coffee, with prices ranging from more than 30 yuan a cup to 100 yuan a cup. He said that the price of beans is directly linked to the quality of coffee. Expensive beans will have obviously rich and lovely flavors, such as bergamot, lemon, and tropical fruits. Cheap beans have a relatively bland flavor and are priced low. Just expect that the flavor of this cup of coffee will not be that rich. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ming Yue’s store also sells coffee beans. 70% of her turnover comes from in-store consumption and 30% from selling beans. However, Mingyue said that since the store has only been open for a short period of time, it has not accumulated many regular customers, and there will be greater room for growth in this part of the business in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d892ab5957be5431c882bca384a1a444.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;1067&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d892ab5431c882bca384a1a444.jpeg&quot; data- key = &quot;258787&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;P STY le = &quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The prize Mingyue won in the coffee competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the ability to obtain high-quality coffee beans has helped Bill and Mingyue a lot, because the quality of coffee beans varies and there are many supply channels, it is not easy for novices to understand the process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Li calculated an account for the reporter and opened a cafe. In addition to investing about 300,000 yuan in decoration and equipment in the early stage of opening the store, the price range of coffee beans on the market is very wide - raw materials. Beans range from 30 yuan/kg to tens of thousands of yuan/kg, and cooked coffee beans range from 80 yuan/pound to tens of thousands of yuan/pound. “It is difficult for a layman to tell the true price of a bean. As for what price it should be sold in a store, I don’t know the beans... and there are many companies that specialize in coffee shop opening planning. If people who don’t know the business buy beans directly from them, they will basically make money.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Conclusion: &lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;Consumers have more choices&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;The era of coffee segmentation may have begun&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As coffee competition becomes increasingly fierce, the practitioners of these independent cafes They are also thinking about where to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After discussing with his boss, Lin Li plans to terminate the store&#39;s operations in November this year and wants to reopen it in a smaller store. As for the store&#39;s future competitive direction, he said he is still thinking about it, &quot;Maybe it depends on how to make the products more refined, instead of just making Italian, milk coffee, special blends, and hand-brewed everything.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f7624557efce35d6d08cf44daf90061e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1067&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f7624557efce35d6d08cf44daf90061e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258789&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Those who are in it know best how fast the coffee market is changing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ming Yue is glad that she initially targeted the high-end specialty coffee track. Mingyue revealed that a year ago, a senior told her that opening a chain of popular coffee shops was the most profitable trend, but just recently, the senior told her that his chain of coffee shops could no longer continue, and was replaced by Luckin and others. The big chain coffee brands are losing competition, and he needs to find a new outlet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mingyue has seen that the coffee market is gradually segmented, and some customers’ tastes are already “very advanced”, such as its previously launched Combo product (ie “one bean, more”). It&#39;s exactly what the customers suggested. Mingyue said frankly, &quot;We need to be very precise in a very narrow field, rather than doing everything. Customers have already learned how to choose. If we do it seriously, there is still a lot of room for development.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mingyue&#39;s The plan is to wait until this hand-brew store can make a stable profit before opening a new store specializing in special blends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(At the request of the interviewee, Lin Li and Bill are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[果敢四大家族：这群地头蛇是怎么炼成的？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260889]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Rebel Alliance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The so-called four major families are fighting in Kokang The rise of the region, from its beginning to its fame, has only happened in the past ten years. Among them, I have to mention the Bai family, which ranks first among the four major families. If it were not for the head of the Bai family, Bai Zhicheng, I am afraid that there would not be any existence of the four major families in the Kokang region. Now the political and business affairs in the Kokang Autonomous Region The relationship map comes entirely from Bai Suocheng&#39;s betrayal in 2009. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The eldest son of the Bai family, Bai Suocheng, is an authentic Kokang man. He was born on April 1, 1950 in Hongyan, Kokang, Myanmar. Since Peng Jiasheng established the &quot;Kokang People&#39;s Revolutionary Army&quot; in 1965 to fight guerrillas with the government forces, Bai Suocheng began to follow Peng Jiasheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Song, who had been a guard for Peng Jiasheng for many years, recalled: Bai Suocheng fought bravely in those days and was willing to use his brain, so he was promoted quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1967, Peng Jiasheng joined the Communist Party of Myanmar. During the People&#39;s Army of the Communist Party of Myanmar, Bai Soucheng was promoted step by step from soldier to battalion commander under Peng Jiasheng. In 1989, Peng Jiasheng led his troops to withdraw from the Communist Party of Myanmar and ceased war with the Myanmar government. The Myanmar government recognized the autonomous status of Kokang, and Peng Jiasheng served as the chairman of the Shan State First Special Administrative Region of Myanmar and the commander-in-chief of the Kokang National Democratic Alliance Army. At this time, Bai Suocheng was promoted by Peng Jiasheng to serve as deputy commander of the Kokang Allied Forces, becoming the veritable second-in-command of the Kokang Alliance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The famous Kokang &quot;88 Incident&quot; occurred in 2009. Bai Soucheng reached a private agreement with the Myanmar government forces, appointed himself chairman of the Kokang Autonomous Region, and united with the Myanmar government forces to merge with the Allied Forces loyal to Peng Jiasheng. . Peng Bu was defeated and fled away from home. With the support of the Myanmar government, Bai Suocheng became the leader of the Kokang region. This was the beginning of the era of the four major Kokang families. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The four major Kogang families established in 2009 are actually Bai, Wei, and Er Liu. Among them, Bai Suocheng of the Bai family, Wei Chaoren of the Wei family, and Liu Guoxi of the Liu family were all former members of Peng Jiasheng. People conspired with the Burmese government forces to expel Peng Jiasheng, just like the three families of Zhao, Wei, and Han who were divided into Jin. Liu Abao (Liu Zhengxiang) of the Second Liu has always been a pro-Myanmar government strong local force, so theoretically he is not a traitor to the Allied Forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Bai Suocheng came to power, he changed Peng Jiasheng&#39;s policy towards the Myanmar government. During Peng Jiasheng&#39;s era, the Kokang area was completely independent of Myanmar, and government troops were not allowed to enter the Allied Defense Zone. Bai Socheng declared his obedience to the leadership of the Myanmar government and allowed Myanmar government troops to station in the Kokang Autonomous Region. The local armed forces were reorganized into pro-government forces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/40zhgHxze9VBwBlEypc2k0byDSf1aipFbDa0AeuX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/40zhgHxze9VBwBlEypc2k0byDSf1aipFbDa0AeuX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258754&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Kokang Public Network/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Peng family left Kokang, although the Myanmar government nominally gained control of the Kokang area, the main ethnic groups in the area For the Han people in Myanmar (known as the Kokang ethnic group in Myanmar), the Myanmar government’s decrees still need to be implemented by the local powerful. Under this modern chieftain system, the four major families began to thrive in Kokang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Bai family, the largest family, has made the first bold move to surrender, so power is naturally indispensable. Not only did Bai Suocheng serve as the chairman of the Kokang Autonomous Region in 2009, his eldest son Bai Yingneng served as the party committee secretary of the Kokang Gongfa Party (the ruling party established by the military government) and served as the chairman of Baijia Industrial Yum Group. The second son Bai Yingcang serves as the deputy director of the Kokang Finance Bureau, the captain of the Kokang Militia Brigade, and the general manager of Yum Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called Yum Group is actually a political and business industrial organization that has obtained the qualifications to operate monopoly industries such as gambling, entertainment, and real estate development in the Kokang area. The Kokang area is located in an inland mountainous area with harsh natural conditions and inconvenient transportation. Since the anti-drug era during the Peng Jiasheng era, the local pillar industries have been gambling and surrounding entertainment industries (prostitution), and the main target customers are Chinese tourists who share the same culture and ethnicity as Kokang . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Myanmar, gambling and other industries are actually illegal industries, but northern Myanmar is not under the direct jurisdiction of the central government of Myanmar, so these gray industries can flourish. The main source of income for the four major Kokang families also comes from such gray industries and related peripheral economic activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Chaoren, the second-ranked member of the Wei family among the four major families, once served as the commander of the First Brigade of the Northeast Military Region during the Burmese Communist Party. During Peng Jiasheng&#39;s rule in Kokang, he served as the chief of staff of the Kokang Allied Forces and was the third-in-command of the Allied Forces. After the establishment of the Kokang Autonomous Region, Wei Chaoren served as the leader of the political and legal system of the autonomous region and participated in the &quot;88 Incident&quot; that expelled Peng Jiasheng in 2009. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/BS6OERsyvFXUlEz3A3aWySgbbPFwsAGIFc45bJdd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/BS6OERsyvFXUlEz3A3aWySgbbPFwsAGIFc45bJdd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258753&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2022, Wei Chaoren (third from right) at home&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Kokang Dazhong.com/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;After becoming one of the four major families, Wei Chaoren also actively took the upper-level route. He served as a member of the Parliament of the Union of Myanmar and a member of the Kokang Autonomous Region Committee. He has always firmly controlled the political and legal system of the Kokang region. Wei Chaoren&#39;s third brother, Wei Huairen, serves as the commander of the Kokang Border Guard Battalion. He has a private armed force of 2,000 people and controls the police force in the Kokang area. Wei Chaoren&#39;s daughter Wei Rong is the chairman of Henry Group, which operates hotels, entertainment and tourism, real estate development, mineral development, gold and jewelry and other industries in Southeast Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relying on Wei Chaoren’s position in Myanmar’s political arena, Henry Group’s development has long gone beyond the Kokang region. It has a large number of hotels, casinos, finance, and jewelry businesses in Lower Myanmar, Cambodia, Wa State and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wei Rong is also good at using new media methods for publicity. Not only does she spend a lot of money to invite celebrities to endorse her, and she brands herself as a beautiful CEO and philanthropist, she also makes many Myanmar anchors famous, and promotes and recruits people to travel to northern Myanmar to work. ——The most famous among them is Internet celebrity Li Saigao. This person is an Internet celebrity anchor recruited by Henry Group in the Wa State. He claims to be a descendant of the expeditionary force. He is somewhat handsome in appearance. He plays and sings Chinese patriotic songs. Later, Exposed by netizens as an accomplice of a fraud group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Henry Group can be said to have created a model for gray industries to use social media, and it has also attracted many Chinese people’s attention to northern Myanmar. It is worth noting that Wei Chaoren’s eldest son Wei Qingtao has been captured by the Chinese police and publicly confessed via video. Wei Rong, who has always been high-profile, may have fled the Kokang region and temporarily avoided the limelight in Lower Myanmar or other Southeast Asian countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Guoxi of the Liu family is also an old subordinate of Peng Jiasheng, but he has been a civilian cadre during the Burmese Communist Party. He served as the Finance Minister of the Northern Bureau of the Burmese Communist Party, and was also an official in charge of finance and border trade in the Northeastern Military Region of the Burmese Communist Party. . During Peng Jiasheng&#39;s rule in Kokang, Liu was also a government official but did not hold military power. After the &quot;88 Incident&quot;, Liu Guoxi served as vice chairman of the Kokang Autonomous Region and was elected as a member of the National Council of the Union of Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/KvugCKzgBB7Orw4SCl1jRDNXs0w8QTeUsgr6kQuU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/KvugCKzgBB7Orw4SCl1jRDNXs0w8QTeUsgr6kQuU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258752&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2018, the Kokang Gongfa Party held a public meeting, and Liu Guoxi delivered a speech at the meeting&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Kokang Public Network/Photo)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Liu Guoxi is an old subordinate of the Communist Party of Myanmar, the Kokang Allied Forces are less hostile to him because Liu has always been a government official in charge of finance. When Bai Socheng fought with the Kokang Allied Forces, This person did not participate in any battle. Mr. Song, who was once a guard of Peng Jiasheng, also revealed to me: Liu did not have the blood debt of the Kokang Allied Forces in his hands. He was a civil servant and had no choice but to surrender to Lao Burma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Guoxi passed away in 2020. His three sons and one daughter run mining, casino, hotel and other businesses in the Kokang area. Among them, the third son Liu Dehong is a member of the Kokang District Parliament. Although Liu Guoxi is regarded as one of the four major families, it is a relatively low-key one. Especially after Liu Guoxi&#39;s death, his children did not hold actual positions in the Kokang government. The influence of his family was not as good as that of Ming Dynasty, which had just been uprooted. Home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only one of the four major families that is not directly related to Peng Jiasheng is the Liu family of Liu Abao (Zhengxiang). Liu Zhengxiang was originally the deputy head of Hongyan Township, Kokang, and used his status as head of the township to do business and founded a welfare company in 1992. Lai Group is said to be the richest man in Kokang. Its main business operations include cultural tourism, hotels, commerce, real estate, finance, etc., with more than 10,000 employees across Myanmar and Southeast Asia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/JWOm8W7PsWNX9VEiShuGQ2DtGw9wNrF2BNCmOKOB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/JWOm8W7PsWNX9VEiShuGQ2DtGw9wNrF2BNCmOKOB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258755&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 7, 2023, Liu Zhengxiang, director of the Kokang Autonomous Region Urban Construction Development Supervision and Management Committee, inspected road construction work&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Kokang Public Network /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Zhengxiang is a model of both politics and business. On the one hand, he uses government relations to do business, and on the other hand, he uses commercial profits to manage government relations. He belongs to the most powerful family among the four major families in Lower Myanmar. One of the people&#39;s connections is also closely related to the Burmese military. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, since Liu Abao did not participate in the rebellion against Peng Jiasheng, the Allied Forces did not have high hatred towards him. It is rumored that after the Kokang Allied Forces launched &quot;Operation 1027&quot; this time, they did not target Liu Abao, and Shortly after the war started, Liu Abao expressed his surrender and was willing to cooperate with China in clearing up his business involving electricity fraud. Other industries are still operating normally. It can be said that he is a typical chameleon businessman. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Ming family came from behind&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;If we look at Ming Xuechang’s political and business influence in the Kokang area during his lifetime, the Ming family has long surpassed the Liu Guoxi family and established One of the powerful new entrants. However, this person has relatively junior qualifications and has always been considered low in the Kokang political and business circles. Therefore, the Ming family is not among the four major families that are generally mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Burmese Communist Party period, Ming Xuechang was just the correspondent of Zhao Ming, commander of the Northeast Military Region. Although the leader trusted him, his position was very low. When Peng Jiasheng was in power in Kokang, Ming Xuechang&#39;s highest position was only the deputy county magistrate of Kokang County. It can be said that he was still far from the core power circle of Kokang and was not a cadre who could directly report to Peng Jiasheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was not until the &quot;88 Incident&quot; in 2009 that Ming Xuechang followed Bai Socheng to defect to Peng Jiasheng and defected to the Myanmar government. After that, he was promoted to the vice chairman of the Kokang Autonomous Region and a member of the Shan State Parliament of Myanmar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is rumored that Ming Xuechang has a good relationship with the Myanmar government army. This man had very little experience in the military during the Kokang Allied Forces era, but he began to take control of the Kokang Autonomous Region Police Force after 2009. His eldest son Ming Guoan served as The commander of the Kokang Police 21st Battalion was later unable to take charge due to injury, and was replaced by his second son Ming Guoping (who had been handed over to the Chinese police). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to his lower seniority, Ming Xuechang was not as high-profile as the Wei family and the Bai family. It was not until his 69th birthday that many Hong Kong and Taiwan stars recorded VCRs to celebrate his birthday, and he became widely known on the Chinese Internet. Later, it was rumored that his eldest grandson Ming Guangzhong was admitted to Peking University (not true), and he became famous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/kEn6BvHJkmpDppX96cUCJ8cUqDWsPm7tHiRzu3aV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/kEn6BvHJkmpDppX96cUCJ8cUqDWsPm7tHiRzu3aV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258756&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 23, 2023, Ming Xuechang and his wife celebrated their 69th birthday&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Kokang Dazhong.com/Picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Crouching Tiger Villa of the Ming Xuechang family is a notorious base for telecommunications fraud, and may be involved in cases of kidnapping, extortion, intentional injury or even killing of multiple Chinese citizens. The Ming family has also become the primary target of the Chinese police&#39;s crackdown on telecommunications fraud. After surrounding Laojie, the Kokang Allied Forces took the lead in launching an attack on the Ming family&#39;s territory, which became the last straw for the Ming family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the suicide of Ming Xuechang and the arrest of many people, it can be seen that the family’s political and business influence in the Kokang area has basically been reduced to zero. &lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h2>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Agent Politics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of the political and business paths of the five major families, in addition to Except for Liu Abao, who is a businessman, the other four companies all grew rapidly after the Peng family members left during the &quot;88 Incident&quot; in 2009. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This has a lot to do with the special political environment in the Kokang region. Although the Myanmar government gained nominal control of the Kokang region in 2009, most of the local residents are not Bamar and have always been quite dissatisfied with the Myanmar government. Hostility, national identity is not strong. This is a common situation in non-Burmese areas in northern Myanmar after Myanmar’s independence, and the Myanmar government is well aware of this. In order to rule such areas at low cost, the Burmese government generally appoints local agents of their own ethnic origin as representatives of the Burmese regime. These agents thus obtain higher-than-normal political rights to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the past to the present, various gray and black industries have existed in Myanmar’s border ethnic areas, all caused by the local independent or semi-independent political status quo. This situation is not unique to Kokang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, in addition to telecommunications fraud, Myanmar&#39;s border areas also had a series of serious black and gray problems such as drug trade, illegal smuggling, protected wildlife trade, prostitution, and illegal gambling. Kokang is a typical example. Under the protection of the dual political and business identities of the five major families, the huge profits generated by his business empire enable him to obtain protection within the Myanmar government through corrupt means. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/wSDHIJ4OPByuFsuP6QRLBtUU3vJ0ZmNV82qku2YA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/wSDHIJ4OPByuFsuP6QRLBtUU3vJ0ZmNV82qku2YA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258757&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Since September 2023, the public security agencies in Xishuangbanna, Pu&#39;er and other places in Yunnan have carried out border police law enforcement cooperation with relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar. A large number of overseas fraud dens have been successfully eradicated. A large number of telecommunications network fraud suspects were handed over to our side &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the Ministry of Public Security)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But they obviously underestimated the impact of international political pressure on own influence. Telecom fraud is not a phenomenon unique to the Kokang region. There are also a large number of telecom fraud parks in surrounding areas such as Wa State and Myawaddy. The Philippines, Cambodia, and Laos also had rampant telecom fraud businesses. However, with the trend of international cooperation to combat telecommunications fraud, such activities have begun to shrink significantly, and a large number of suspects involved in telecommunications fraud have been handed over to the police of relevant countries for processing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Wa State Autonomous Region, also in northern Myanmar, quickly responded to the call to crack down on electronic fraud. After raiding more than 40 industrial parks, it handed over more than 4,000 electronic fraudsters to the Chinese police. China has provided tens of thousands of computers and mobile phones used in the electronic fraud business, which contain millions of pieces of intelligence and evidence about the fraud group. It has even dismissed officials involved in electronic fraud in the Wa State area for investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this series of anti-email fraud storms of multi-national cooperation, the Kokang region has violated law enforcement actions and only provided a few hundred people to China in a symbolic manner. Under Myanmar&#39;s comprehensive crackdown on e-mail fraud, , and even plans to expand against the trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/yuoxPEO6H3BM0dOJDaasqkuB5VI9UZtakYijObuf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/yuoxPEO6H3BM0dOJDaasqkuB5VI9UZtakYijObuf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258758&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In order to resolutely curb the high incidence of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, the Ministry of Public Security deployed the Yunnan public security agencies to strengthen border police cooperation and continue to carry out multiple rounds of crackdowns. The picture shows the fraud suspects handed over to us &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by the Ministry of Public Security)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, the criminal suspects in the Kokang area and even the entire Myanmar The reason why the telecom fraud business has expanded rapidly in recent years is because neighboring countries such as the Philippines, Cambodia, and Laos have cracked down on telecom fraud, which has led to a large number of practitioners fleeing from former &quot;telephone fraud centers&quot; such as Sihanoukville, Cambodia, to conduct business in northern Myanmar. After the Wa State and other surrounding areas cooperated with China in cracking down on e-mail fraud, Henry Group and Crouching Tiger Villa still had little luck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although strong dragons will not suppress local snakes, it is another matter if local snakes take the initiative to cross the line and bite people and refuse to restrain themselves after being warned. After this reorganization, the political and business relations landscape in the Kokang region will be reshuffled again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 18:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一方提分手，另一方都应同意：或体面结束，或不受要挟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260903]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is not uncommon for someone to break up when they are in a relationship. The question is, should I agree? My opinion is that when one party proposes a breakup, whether it is a real breakup or a breakup to coerce the other party into accepting their conditions, the other party should agree. 36Kr’s “2022 Chinese Couples Breakup Report” shows that more than 60% of girls break up first. We will use the woman to break up for analysis, but the opposite is true, and it also applies to the man to break up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some young netizens discovered an interesting phenomenon around them: when girls propose breaking up, boys basically agree. TA further said that because some girls like to use breakup as a means, but boys generally use breakup as the result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We will discuss it on a case-by-case basis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first situation, a girl is serious about breaking up, but in the general perception of boys, breaking up is equivalent to announcing a breakup. You have informed me, so what if you don’t accept it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Besides, if you really want to break up, wouldn’t it be nice if the other party behaves decently and doesn’t keep pestering you? If one party wants to break up and the other party refuses to let go, it may lead to tragedy, which is what many people in love fear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I agree with the sentiment that &quot;breakups are serious.&quot; Breaking up is equivalent to the death of love. A person who cherishes life should naturally cherish feelings. He should not talk about &quot;breaking up&quot; unless it is no longer possible and must be said. In other words, if you don&#39;t say &quot;break up&quot;, don&#39;t leave any room for it - when you say &quot;break up&quot;, it means &quot;sealing the throat with a sword&quot; to the old relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second situation, the girl’s proposal to break up is false and the purpose is to make her boyfriend submit. On Himalaya, some netizens complained: My girlfriend often threatens to break up with me in order to get me to give her gifts. What kind of mentality is this? A group of netizens commented: This kind of girlfriend just wants something from you. If you are not in too deep, it is better to leave decisively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, it is often the case that girls who break up with them use the breakup as a game to force boys to compromise and satisfy their own needs. In this case, boys&#39; indiscriminate pleading is &quot;cooperating&quot; with the game&#39;s tactics, and it is also a meaningless sacrifice of self-rights and due stance. This can lead to various passive situations. From the perspective of human nature, if a girl unreasonably breaks up with her, she will get very good results - for example, her boyfriend will obey her words and not dare to violate them at all. For example, her boyfriend will buy things to compensate her to make her happy. Then it will be difficult for this girl not to gain a sense of accomplishment and deliberately make it a kind of inertia, making the other person keep flapping according to the owner&#39;s wishes like a bird locked in a cage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as a person is not a masochist, it is unlikely that he can endure all kinds of teasing and belittling by the other party without breaking down. To fully accept unfair demands is to dig a hole for yourself. It’s so easy to give in and compromise when you’re in love. After getting married, if the other party files for divorce if they don’t get along, what should you do? Someone has said it well: &quot;Breakups are mentioned frequently now, and divorce will definitely be mentioned frequently in the future.&quot; If this is the case, should we continue to compromise? If this is the case, how much happiness and trust can there be in a marriage? I&#39;m afraid it has long been overdrawn by one party&#39;s willfulness, tyranny and one party&#39;s weakness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that whether it is a true score or a false score, directly agreeing is the best choice. When a person is in front of someone who doesn&#39;t love him, or in front of someone who is always trying to &quot;test&quot; himself, there is no other way for him to do anything but be tough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, people’s hearts are made of flesh, and after being together for a long time, it is indeed difficult to make a break. Human nature is always complicated. Being &quot;kicked&quot; by the other party when you still love the other party deeply is indeed shocking and painful. Therefore, some people who have been broken up with want to stay out of nostalgia for the past relationship. This is not It&#39;s strange, but facts show that long-term pain is worse than short-term pain. It is wise to leave the person who &quot;mispaid&quot; the relationship as soon as possible. No matter how difficult the decision is, no matter how painful the heart is, it is better than letting yourself fall into an emotional quagmire and be unable to get out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You must know that hesitating and insisting on breaking up will not only make you and the other party extremely tired, but you are also more likely to be laughed at and affect your work and life because you cry and feel depressed all day long. future. After all, stalking itself means losing self-esteem and &quot;lowering to the dust&quot;. In addition, being indecisive and being weak can also bring about bad situations and even negative consequences. In life, some couples &quot;will get together if they are separated for a long time, and they will break up if they are together for a long time.&quot; After wasting their great youth, they eventually ended up breaking up, which is equivalent to a wasted effort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In my hometown, some rural couples have been quarreling all their lives. Often one party wants to leave and the other refuses. As a result, the two people cannot reconcile until they grow old, which also affects the lives of their children. If they break up early, they can Is there such a thing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparing these results, resolutely agreeing to break up will not only save a lot of unnecessary troubles, but also &quot;let go&quot; both parties. Isn&#39;t this the best result? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s more, the firm consent of the person being broken up is also a lesson to the other party. A psychology expert told a story that one of her friends was broken up in love and was in a very low mood. He thought she had been dumped, but when he asked, he found out that she was the one who initiated the breakup. The point is, she didn&#39;t want to break up, she just threatened her boyfriend again, but this time her boyfriend didn&#39;t keep her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Breaking up reveals one&#39;s character.&quot; As the saying goes, don’t do to others what you don’t want others to do to you. It’s not easy for two people who truly love each other to come together. They should manage their relationship well and jointly resist various risks encountered in the journey of life. How can you create risks and disturbances by yourself and let yourself fall into trouble? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that some people like to talk about breaking up casually and use breakup to control others. This is not only disrespectful to the other party, but also completing a kind of discipline. Some people just enjoy the sense of accomplishment of &quot;taming the other person under their feet and treating them like a dog.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the discipline does not set a time limit, this situation should make people vigilant. Resisting discipline is the responsibility of every person in the &quot;Emotional Castle&quot;. Getting together and staying together easily is the simplest and most practical love rule. Life is not long, and we can be prepared to spend this life with someone, or we can be prepared to let go when the opportunity arises. This is what we should do in order to avoid being troubled and constrained by a marriage that lacks quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[领航鲸“搬家”分几步？为啥要抹凡士林？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260907]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 17, two pilot whales more than 4 meters long and weighing about 800 kilograms arrived from Hangzhou Departing from a polar ocean park, &quot;relocated&quot; to an ocean park in Zhoushan more than 200 kilometers away, and moved into a more spacious &quot;new home&quot;. With a head weighing 800 kilograms, it is quite a battle to &quot;move&quot; such a big man over a long distance. It not only requires cranes and large trucks, but also requires more than 20 adults to carry it. So the question is, how many steps does it take to &quot;move&quot; a pilot whale? What is the greatest difficulty? What preparations have the staff made to protect the pilot whales? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What are the steps to “move” a pilot whale? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is not an easy task to &quot;move&quot; a pilot whale weighing about 800 kilograms, and to move both animals together. So, what are the steps to &quot;move&quot; a pilot whale? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The staff said that there are five steps to &quot;moving&quot; the pilot whale this time. The first step: Capture and transportation, after capturing the pilot whale from the breeding tank, transport it to the box; The second step: Putting into the box and hoisting; The third step: Inspection before transportation, including the pilot whale’s breathing frequency, Check the mental state, etc.; Step 4: Monitoring during transportation, including monitoring of water temperature, air temperature, mental state, activity state, respiratory rate, etc. of animals during transportation; Step 5: After arriving at the destination, hoist into the water . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What are the living habits of pilot whales? Why did it get its name? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;To successfully &quot;move&quot; a big guy like a pilot whale, you need to understand its physiological characteristics and living habits. Next, let’s get to know the large marine creature-pilot whale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pilot whales are mammals in the family Cetacea, Delphinidae, and are also called &quot;pilot whales&quot; because of their huge size. Pilot whales are divided into two types: long-limbed pilot whales and short-limbed pilot whales. Long-limbed pilot whales are mainly distributed in high-latitude waters, while short-limbed pilot whales are distributed in tropical and temperate waters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/22f69f961e179bf7552d09428fac69b7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;659&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/22f69f961e179bf7552d09428fac69b7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258780&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sun Dong, associate researcher at the Second Institute of Oceanography of the Ministry of Natural Resources:&lt;/strong>;Pilot whales generally like to gather in large groups in the natural marine environment. The size of this group can usually reach 200 to 300. , this is a very large scale, which is rare among whales. Pilot whales are the liveliest among cetaceans. Pilot whales are often seen by sailors willing to accompany sailboats or ships when the ship is sailing on the sea. Their playful behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, due to the destruction of the marine environment, the number of pilot whales has been declining, and they have been included in the second level of my country&#39;s &quot;List of National Key Protected Wild Animals&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;What are the difficulties for the &quot;big&quot; pilot whale to &quot;move&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to their large size and heavy weight, what are the difficulties in &quot;moving&quot; pilot whales? Come on and listen to the expert’s introduction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sun Dong, associate researcher at the Second Institute of Oceanography of the Ministry of Natural Resources:&lt;/strong>;From the most professional perspective, the most important thing about the &quot;movement&quot; of whales is that we call this whale Cetaceans need to use their lungs to breathe, so the vent on its back, or in layman&#39;s terms, its nostrils must be exposed above the water to prevent it from drowning. Cetaceans can drown. But the water cannot be put in very little. If it is put in very little, one will cause its skin to become dry and dehydrated. Dehydration is a very serious event for cetaceans. The second is the huge body of cetaceans. , it needs the buoyancy of water to support its weight. Another factor is temperature. For cetaceans, especially when the temperature rises, it will cause them to suffer from overheating shock. This should be strictly avoided. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why do pilot whales need to apply Vaseline when they “go out”? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When it comes to &quot;moving&quot; a &quot;big guy&quot; like a pilot whale, every detail is important. There is such a detail in the transfer process that the reporter just photographed. After the pilot whale came out of the water, the staff smeared Vaseline on the pilot whale. Why did they do this? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Quansheng, technical director of a polar marine park in Hangzhou:&lt;/strong>;The pilot whales apply Vaseline to prevent dehydration, because when the temperature is too high, cetaceans can easily dehydrate. After covering it with Vaseline, it will prevent moisture from dispersing. After applying Vaseline, we will cover it with a layer of wet towel. In this way, it has a water-retaining effect, that is, one is to prevent dehydration and the other is to moisturize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts told reporters that this time the two pilot whales &quot;moved&quot;, they were smeared with medical Vaseline which had almost no harm to their skin. The main area of ​​application was the back skin exposed to the air, but Avoid air vents when applying. Two pilot whales arrived at their &quot;new home&quot; in Zhoushan. Before entering the water, the staff used a towel to wipe off the Vaseline on the pilot whales. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to reduce the stress response of pilot whales during transportation? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From Hangzhou to Zhoushan, it spans more than 200 kilometers. To ensure the safety of the animals, the vehicle must maintain a stable speed of 90 kilometers per hour during transportation. This extended the original drive of more than 2 hours to 5 hours. How can pilot whales reduce their stress response during long-distance transfers and reach their &quot;new home&quot; safely? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liu Quansheng, technical director of a polar marine park in Hangzhou:&lt;/strong>;We will stop eating 24 hours before transportation, and gradually reduce the amount of food in the first three days. This is the first ; Second, we will ensure appropriate water and air temperatures during transportation. This time we set the water temperature for the pilot whale at 23.5°C, which is a water temperature that is more suitable for raising it; third, we We need to ensure that the air in this transport vehicle circulates, that it cannot be too hot or too windy, and that it must be enclosed. Fourthly, we will have accompanying veterinarians and keepers who have raised it for a long time, who will caress and carry it out. An exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to allow the pilot whales to adapt to the new environment as quickly as possible, the room temperature, water temperature, lighting and other aspects of Zhoushan&#39;s &quot;new home&quot; are set according to the natural environment in which they live. However, in the first two days after arrival, the staff will feed a small amount of food, and then resume a normal diet after the pilot whales slowly adapt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>