<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[俄乌电子战，矛与盾的游戏丨军事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/22/zqImXE6gdbuSrUQOzIL5LmQgEpT8WQnfaDCzBvY9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1795&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/zqImXE6gdbuSrUQOzIL5LmQg EpT8WQnfaDCzBvY9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 16, 2023, in the Donetsk region, unmanned troops of the Ukrainian army Aircraft operators are training not far from the front line &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the Ukrainian military claimed that it had Soldiers drove out their positions on the east bank of the Dnieper River in the occupied Kherson area and established multiple bridgeheads. Russia also admitted for the first time that the Kiev army had crossed the Dnieper River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is of course a result worthy of attention, because the establishment of a bridgehead on the east bank of the Dnieper River poses a great threat to Crimea. If Ukraine can deploy long-range weapons on the east bank, Crimea may It’s hard to stick with it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;General Zaluzhny, Commander-in-Chief of the Ukrainian Armed Forces, emphasized in an interview with The Economist that Ukraine needs to develop and deploy its own advanced technology to regain the upper hand in the war. Behind the establishment of the bridgehead It is the tactical advantages brought about by a series of technological updates, especially in electronic countermeasures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the outbreak of the Russo-Ukrainian War, Ukraine has been engaged in invisible electronic countermeasures with Russia. The battle in the Kherson area is the forefront of this confrontation, because the two sides can often only use it across the river. Long-range firepower exchanges, so drones become the key to victory, because both sides rely heavily on drones to find targets and correct artillery. Whoever can use electronic countermeasures to suppress the opponent&#39;s drones will gain an advantage in the battle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the most efficient way to fight drones is to suppress them through electromagnetic interference, which will directly cause the drone to crash. It has been previously reported that the area near the Dnieper River has become a no-fly zone for drones, because both sides will use electronic jamming methods to suppress and interfere with the flight of drones. On this invisible battlefield, the two sides have been engaged in a very complex and cruel battle. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For nearly a century, electromagnetic interference has been an important part of warfare. Traditional electronic warfare methods are to find the radio frequencies being used by the enemy and create overwhelming noise on the same frequencies, making it impossible for the opponent to attack use. In World War II, electronic warfare mainly targeted radio communications and radar. As long as the opponent was unable to communicate and detect, the mission was completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern communication technology has developed various means to combat electronic interference, but the main reason is not just for electronic warfare, but because there are a large number of electromagnetic signal sources in human society. During World War II, a 50-watt radio could easily carry out point-to-point communications in China and even East Asia. However, now it is difficult for a 50-watt radio to cover even one province - this is not because the radios back then were more advanced, but because the radios were more advanced. It was because the electromagnetic environment was good back then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electromagnetic communication can be regarded as a conversation between two parties. If the room is very quiet, the two parties can hear what the other party is saying without making a loud sound. If there are not only many people chatting in the room, but also people watching movies, shooting balls, playing and singing, then the two parties must raise their voices or be very close to each other when communicating. The reason why modern communication technology attaches great importance to anti-interference is because the electromagnetic background environment is too complex, making it impossible to complete communication simply by increasing power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Software technology is also improving. For example, in the past, changing the frequency and signal characteristics of a radio station required replacing hardware. However, with the softwareization of radios, only changing the encoding can completely change the spectrum of the equipment. In other words, problems that in the past required major repairs after being interfered with can now only be solved by adding a patch to the software, or even reusing the software to replace the encryption method. In the past, to change the encryption method, each receiving end needed to change the machine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;UAVs used in the military generally use more complex control methods to combat interference. For example, frequency hopping is used to connect back-end control, which can skip the interfered frequency band. This is commonly used in radio communications. Anti-interference means; you can also use inertial navigation in the case of interference, continue to execute the original flight path, and then connect satellite navigation and rear control when the interference weakens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, as the ability to resist interference becomes stronger, the ability to resist interference will also become stronger accordingly. Spears and shields compete with each other and develop with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Theoretically, as long as your electronic warfare capabilities are strong enough, you can construct an electronic golden bell that prevents all drones from flying in and prevents precision-guided weapons from hitting targets in the golden bell. If the interferer&#39;s equipment reaches 100% power, anti-interference methods are often difficult to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the reality is that interference means cannot provide full-level signals in all areas, which depends on the location of the interference source, the orientation of the antenna and its own power. The drone is a mobile platform that can continuously fly for reconnaissance and interfere with weak signal locations to find better flight routes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And sometimes the problem can be solved in less &quot;electronic&quot; ways, such as using radio triangulation to directly find the approximate location of the interference source, and using long-range firepower to cover the opponent, even if it misses the target. It can force the opponent to shut down temporarily to avoid the blow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, there are many tactics in actual combat that can weaken the effect of the opponent&#39;s electronic interference, and these tactics themselves are also an important part of electronic warfare. Therefore, there is no omnipotent secret weapon. On the invisible battlefield of electronic warfare, only by continuously strengthening technology and constantly changing and updating countermeasures can we gain an advantage in action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冒充专家行医十年，靠秘方自制抗癌药：无证“神医”的罪与罚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261144]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省人大常委会原副主任李春生受贿案一审开庭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261154]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 17:08:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 23, 2023, the Chenzhou Intermediate People’s Court of Hunan Province held a public hearing of the first instance against the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People’s Congress The bribery case involving Li Chunsheng, deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/Dy5aZvlOMRVyYAUfsfjGBCWb00SM7RUhnQLJTWZT.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;755&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/Dy5aZvlOMRVyYAUfsfjGBCWb00SM7RUhnQLJTWZT.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259415&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; The Chenzhou Municipal People’s Procuratorate alleged that from the second half of 2001 to May 2022, the defendant Li Chunsheng used his position as county magistrate and county party committee secretary of Xin County, Henan Province, deputy director of the Political Department of the Ministry of Public Security, director of the Personnel Training Bureau, deputy governor of Guangdong Province, and provincial Director of the Public Security Department, deputy secretary and deputy director of the Party Leadership Group of the Standing Committee of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Congress, etc., and provide convenient conditions for the formation of authority and status to provide assistance to relevant units and individuals in matters such as business operations, project promotion, project contracting, job promotion, etc. , illegally accepting property from others, equivalent to a total of more than 79.4 million yuan in RMB. The procuratorate requested that Li Chunsheng be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, the procuratorate presented relevant evidence, and the defendant Li Chunsheng and his defender conducted cross-examination. The prosecution and defense fully expressed their opinions under the auspices of the court, and Li Chunsheng made a final statement. He also expressed his guilt and repentance in court. At the end of the trial, the court adjourned and announced the verdict at a later date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 30 people including NPC deputies, CPPCC members and people from all walks of life attended the trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刘红兵任广东省副省长]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261150]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 15:33:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On the afternoon of November 23, the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th Guangdong Provincial People’s Congress voted , decided to appoint Liu Hongbing as deputy governor of the Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Government. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 15:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A·S·拜厄特：“即便我死了，春天还会继续到来”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261141]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/23/y6qQYTfj2g7DgTOzkyJwXOlLmaHQGdT151yVDL2i.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/y6qQYTfj2g7DgTOzkyJwXOlLmaHQG dT151yVDL2i. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259387&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;AS Byatt&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Visual China/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Perhaps no novelist has made as important a contribution to expanding the boundaries of English fiction as she has.&quot; (Philip Henschel)&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;On November 16, 2023, local time, British writer and scholar A.S. Byatt passed away peacefully at home surrounded by his relatives at the age of 87. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1990, Byatt won the Booker Prize for his novel &quot;Possession&quot; and made a sensation in the literary world. In the same year, she was awarded the Order of the British Empire, and in 1999 she was awarded the title of Dame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The almost obsessive research ethos prevalent in contemporary English writing owes a great deal to Possession’s majestic, engrossing demonstration, a work of romantic literature from the archives; at the same time, The science fantasy of &quot;Morpho Eugenia&quot; has powerfully proven its immense instructive significance for young writers... No one can write about both Darwin&#39;s theory and the ancient inexhaustible theme of love. &quot;So brilliantly.&quot; Philip Henschel, a reporter from &quot;The Paris Review&quot; who once interviewed Byatt, recalled, &quot;Few writers have such strong intellectual curiosity; except for her, perhaps no one can view spiritual life so decisively. It is a pleasure to be enjoyed, and it is equal in absorption and release.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his 60-year writing career, Byatt also published &quot;Angels and Insects&quot;, &quot;The Children&#39;s Book&quot; and Her representative works include the tetralogy of female growth (&quot;Virgin in the Garden&quot;, &quot;Still Life&quot;, &quot;Tower of Babel&quot; and &quot;The Whistling Woman&quot;), as well as short story collections such as &quot;Eye of a Nightingale&quot; and &quot;Matisse Stories&quot;. Her works have been It has been translated into 38 languages ​​and won many world-class literary awards. Confidently moving between literature, religion, science, art, and theoretical insights, Byatt is recognized as &quot;one of the most important writers and critics of our time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/muZTpXilvlTUurXYtz23y4l913KVOooAqwbWUI04.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1030&quot; height= &quot;1542&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/muZTpXilvlTUurXYtz23y4l913KVOooAqwbWUI04.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259395&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Medusa&#39;s Ankles&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021, Byatt&#39;s last book , the short story anthology &quot;Medusa&#39;s Ankles&quot; was published. &quot;These stories are charming and sparkling, intoxicating and trembling. They comfort you and awaken you.&quot; The famous British novelist David Mitchell commented in the introduction: &quot;If you compare &quot;Medusa&#39;s Ankles&quot; to For an artist’s retrospective exhibition, the museum does not need to provide a tour guide, nor does it need to place exhibition labels next to the works - because these stories are just there, so perfect and bright.”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;I don’t like it. Spiritual Director&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“A lot of what I write has to do with the need, fear and desire for solitude.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A. S. Byatt was born Ann Antonia Susan Drabble was born in Sheffield, England in 1936. Her father was a judge and her mother taught Victorian poetry. Byatt graduated from the University of Cambridge and the University of Oxford. He taught English literature at University College London in 1972. He resigned from his teaching position in 1983 to focus on writing. In the same year, he became a member of the Royal Society of Literature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt is the eldest daughter in the family. Her parents and three younger siblings are also Cambridge graduates. &quot;I was lucky in Cambridge. A university English degree often makes people discouraged from writing. Graduating the degree greatly suppressed my desire to write and made me feel embarrassed. But at the same time, it greatly strengthened my desire to write. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/DOKvCJtmvmkSaQNItA7o6YMTBOWPfG8k5ZkQ6iQI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/DOKvCJtmvmkSaQNItA7o6YMTBOWPfG8k5ZkQ6iQI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259398&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Possession&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the publication of the novel &quot;Possession&quot;, Byatt&#39;s reputation was once shrouded in the shadow of his sister Margaret De La, who is also a writer. Under the aura of Boole, Byatt once admitted in an interview with &quot;The Paris Review&quot;, &quot;Let&#39;s put it bluntly: the response to my first few books was all confused...No one paid attention to what I was doing...She wrote I wrote a lot, and I wrote fast. In the long run, it had a positive effect on me. I didn’t have the anxiety most writers have about repercussions, I just had this simple fear of being thought of as someone’s sister.”&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;In his 1967 novel The Game, Byatt tells the story of a pair of competing sisters (just two years earlier, Drabble had published a novel on a similar theme). Byatt explained that the inspiration for &quot;The Game&quot; came from a board game that her friend&#39;s sister used to play with imaginary fragments, &quot;much like Henry James&#39;s game of climbing stairs to find fragments of information.&quot; The novel is also a reference to Brown. &quot;I found the Brontë sisters&#39; solitaire imagination to be extremely terrifying.&quot; &quot;The Game&quot; also points to people&#39;s creativity in childhood. According to Byatt&#39;s recollection, when she was a child, she wrote about men in disguise sneaking into Adventures in a girls&#39; school, but &quot;most of those exercises were burned before I left boarding school.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1958, Byatt married British economist Ian Byatt (first husband, divorced in 1969), and the two lived in Durham, a city in northeastern England. It is a place where the legacy of the Middle Ages still exists. In that era, if you were a woman, they would take away the benefits they gave you for getting married, but if you were a man, they would increase it. So, there I lost my benefits, and from some hidden In a sense, I am secretly happy about it, because I actually want to be a writer rather than a scholar.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt gave birth to two children after marriage, during which she gave birth to her first child. The manuscript of &quot;The Shadow of the Sun&quot; that had been put in the drawer was taken out and &quot;rewritten over and over again in a slow and unpleasant way...At the same time, one or the other baby was placed in a small chair on the desk and rocked gently with one hand. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1964, Byatt published her first novel &quot;The Shadow of the Sun&quot;. In her own words, &quot;a novel about a young woman at a university who wants to write a novel.&quot; In this debut novel, Byatt writes about a girl trying to escape from her controlling father. Tense family relationships and women&#39;s independent growth have since become important issues in many of her works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;“I don’t want to belong to any group...I don’t like a spiritual guru, someone who asks you to follow or worship him. I like someone who asks you to think for yourself.”&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Is he &quot;possessing&quot; her, or is she &quot;possessing&quot; him&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Possession&quot; was conceived by me for 15 years. I gave up UCL for 11 years I wrote it in two months after I started teaching. It&#39;s the only novel I&#39;ve ever written that was generally coherent, with no one getting sick, no disasters, no awards, no book promotions. It had a terrible energy, and from the first sentence to the last, the whole book was in my mind.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to Byatt, &quot;early writing&quot; means Works before &quot;Possession&quot;. In 1990, when this work became a best-seller and won the Booker Prize, Byatt finally &quot;occupied&quot; an important position in the literary world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The creation of Possession began with the title of the book. I was sitting in the old-fashioned round table reading room of the British Museum, watching the great Coleridge scholar Catherine Coburn in the circular catalog area Walking around, round and round. I suddenly realized that her whole life was dedicated to this dead poet. I thought: Did he &#39;possess&#39; her, or did she &#39;possess&#39; him? Then I thought, This could be written as a novel, about the &#39;possession&#39; relationship between the living and the dead. It would be a fascinating story of possession.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Possession&quot; revolves around two contemporary people. The scholar&#39;s research unfolds: a pretentious young academic and a reserved feminist. While tracing the letters exchanged between Victorian poets, the two unearthed a secret love affair of that era. Falling in love in the process...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The word &#39;possession&#39; also has a very direct interest level that can be discussed: who &#39;possess&#39; the manuscript of a dead writer? Moreover, &#39;possession&#39; also applied to sexual relations. At that time , I was studying the letters of Browning and his wife, and I thought of two pairs of lovers, one modern and the other ancient - the Victorians, and having them embody &#39;possession&#39; in these senses.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The publication of &quot;Possession&quot; (full title &quot;Possession: A Romance&quot;) heralds the emergence of a &quot;new Byatt&quot;. She has great narrative talent, and the novel is full of humorous satire on the academic circle. , like a suspenseful detective story, or a touching (as its subtitle suggests) romantic legend. &quot;I originally planned to write an experimental novel, about literary theory and an ambitious biographical text... What changed everything was my reading experience of Eco&#39;s &quot;The Name of the Rose&quot; and its ironic medieval detective story... The secret I found in it is: a great story that can put whatever you need to put in it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the text of &quot;Possession&quot;, Byatt also boldly inserts herself Poetry imitating the style of Victorian poetry. &quot;The novel required real poetry in form, but I don&#39;t write poetry. My editor at the time said: Don&#39;t be ridiculous, write it yourself! So, I went home and wrote a Victorian poem about spiders... I have always been fascinated by the poetry of Tennyson and Browning. I read it as a child because my mother was a Browning expert. Their rhymes sang in my head, and those Victorian verses just clicked in my novel. came out of nowhere.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the time Byatt completed Possession, publishers on both sides of the Atlantic were deeply troubled and almost sceptical. &quot;They begged me to cut out those poems and writings about the Victorian era. The only American publisher brave enough to accept it reminded me: &#39;You ruin all the suspense with these cumbersome words.&#39; Early in the morning, I cried. . Later, the novel won the Booker Prize, to everyone&#39;s surprise (including myself), it became a bestseller, and people wrote essays using my imaginary poet. &quot;Possession&quot; was translated into thirty Multiple languages. I owe Eco a huge debt.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/lVwV5oiE7YyAk81DJaL91Dxb3tBmm8PecdppoaHu. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/lVwV5oiE7YyAk81DJaL91Dxb3tBmm8PecdppoaHu.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;259392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Matisse&#39;s story&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Still Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Byatt once said in an exclusive interview with the New York Times: &quot;I am not an academic who accidentally wrote a novel. In fact, I happen to be a moderately academic novelist.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt&#39;s early literary creations were modeled after George Eliot and Iris Murdoch. Like the former, she regards novels as an ideal art form because &quot;you can absorb the whole world from them&quot;; influenced by the latter, she tries to portray characters who are entangled and struggling with various ideas; at the same time, following the example of her two predecessors, she admires Utter writes dense, detailed novels that are challenging to read even for her smart, patient fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The difficulty lies in the fact that sentences like this can be seen everywhere: a dense collection of unknown knowledge and the author&#39;s delicate and rigorous subjective feelings; specialized terms in the fields of classics, mythology and art are randomly picked up... ...long sentences contain alternating long and short clauses...familiar words have long-abandoned meanings or obscure meanings.&quot; Yang Xiangrong, the translator of Byatt&#39;s works, once &quot;complained&quot; that the translation of &quot;The Virgin in the Garden&quot; was difficult, But I was impressed, &quot;When I read it for the second time, I gradually fell in love with the complex and regular language style, the unremitting capture of subtleties, and the almost aristocratic style of writing in which the writer never creates simple sentences. Restraint.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/HOQMyggc4ie4BhAyeJxX1TyLYm626qhZpLHfTrPc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;428 &quot; height=&quot;616&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/HOQMyggc4ie4BhAyeJxX1TyLYm626qhZpLHfTrPc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259390&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Virgin in the Garden&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1978, &quot;The Virgin in the Garden&quot; was published. Byatt inscribed on the title page - &quot;Dedicated to me&quot; The son of Charles Byatt (1961.7.19-1972.7.22).&quot; &quot;I came up with the idea of ​​​​creating &quot;Virgin in the Garden&quot; around 1961, when my son was born. I suddenly realized that I had experienced a certain period. History.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt set the background of &quot;The Virgin in the Garden&quot; in 1953, when Queen Elizabeth II ascended the throne. In the very short time span from rehearsal, performance to completion of a historical drama, Bo The three children of the Te family have undergone fundamental changes. The eldest daughter Stephanie got married and had a child, the 18-year-old second daughter Frederica lost her virginity, and the youngest son Marcus was deceived and became insane... They all experienced dangerous growth. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the novel, Byatt begins with &quot;National Portrait Gallery: 1968&quot;, &quot;I experienced the early 1950s. I lived in the 1960s, and I don&#39;t regard the 1960s as A time for a revolution, but as a time when I can look back on the history in which I lived... What is personal is not political, although the participants in politics are individuals. Politics is not personal at all.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In 1972, Byatt&#39;s son Charles, who was just over 11 years old, died suddenly in a car accident on his way to school. After losing her beloved son, she experienced landslides and ice cracks in her life. She wrote a sentence at the end of the prologue of the novel. A woman whose son was seriously injured in the collision said, &quot;That woman used to be a good teacher, but not anymore. She used to have many friends, but now she doesn&#39;t have them. She used to have a lovable body, but now she doesn&#39;t. She was scared and angry. Exhausted, I can&#39;t let go for a moment...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/uuSqPK3CD0KxF4AfyCabNroUPI4TaeGozkVUYusl.jpg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1565&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/uuSqPK3CD0KxF4AfyCabNroUPI4TaeGozkVUYusl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259393&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Still Life&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1985, Byatt published &quot;Still Life&quot;. The scene in the first chapter of the novel is set in obstetrics and gynecology. In the hospital, while waiting for a prenatal check-up, Stephanie witnessed the miscarriage of another woman beside her. The little life ended, &quot;motionless and silent&quot;... Stephanie gave birth successfully, but when she was looking forward to a new life, she was accidentally electrocuted. Death. The English title of the novel &quot;Still Life&quot; is interpreted literally - &quot;still life&quot; - that is, death. In the book, Byatt once lamented through the mouth of a character: &quot;Perhaps, we can also look at still life in this way. The so-called still life painting is synonymous with natural death.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have already conceived it. Stephanie&#39;s death in 1961. I thought I was going to write a series of novels in which I would make that death a central awareness, so that readers would feel the pain of a real death, as you did, rather than having to deal with a real death. A fictional death. Every two or three months I get a letter from a reader saying, how dare you do this to me. I sit down and cry all night long. You know, you have no right to kill in a novel like Real people kill people like that. That&#39;s not fair.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Resisting &quot;The Winter&#39;s Tale&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;——What&#39;s the point of surviving one day and another? What kind of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;——The lives of many people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt&#39;s &quot;Female Growth Quartet&quot; which took 30 years to complete has a certain autobiographical color. Among them, the obvious main line is the growth and awakening of the intellectual woman Frederica. This series of novels explores almost all the confusions and issues that women face throughout their lives. &quot;I don&#39;t want to write about little women, but I want to write novels that are liberating to people&#39;s minds.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/23/ehzmAdk2KOaeQaXp0gRWIWnCCMTJlENqAEk9qTLm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1413&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 23/ehzmAdk2KOaeQaXp0gRWIWnCCMTJlENqAEk9qTLm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Children&#39;s Book&quot; original English version&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/DfygYILTg42wQEqb7uMgNau9wkx9zHeW16kmUs5H.jpg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;605&quot; height=&quot;826&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/DfygYILTg42wQEqb7uMgNau9wkx9zHeW16kmUs5H.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259394&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Children&#39;s book&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Continued After &quot;The Virgin in the Garden&quot; and &quot;Still Life&quot;, Byatt continued to write about Frederica&#39;s various struggles after studying in Cambridge, getting married, and becoming a mother in &quot;The Tower of Babel&quot; in 1996. &quot;People &quot;Always marry with your own yearning for marriage.&quot; After experiencing several domestic violence from her husband, Frederica decided to run away. &quot;The place we longed for and tried our best to beautify may be the place we will escape from.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cOlUEd2YPcSKnURCwtx52nKi4nOPXBWHnLcB3sDE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;556&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/cOlUEd2YPcSKnURCwtx52nKi4nOPXBWHnLcB3sDE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Whistling Woman&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the tetralogy finale &quot;The Whistling Woman&quot; (2002) , Byatt continues to tell the story of the lives of free women in the whirlpool of social change. In the 1960s, the emerging television media occupied the forefront of popular culture. The 33-year-old single mother Frederica began to look for new ways to satisfy her intellectual needs. She whistled in the exquisite box of television and became the star of the talk show &quot; The sharp and knowledgeable host of &quot;Through the Looking Glass.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Images of survival and innovation permeate the entire novel &quot;The Whistling Woman&quot;. The work is based on the cultural academic circle dominated by psychoanalytic thought from Cambridge in the 1950s to the 1980s, and involves difficult and complex topics. In the novel&#39;s acknowledgments, Byatt records exchanges with scholars in different fields: snails and genetics, physiology and cognition, the possibilities of television, the ethnology of birds, religious culture, etc. Together with her heroines, she explores new worlds beyond literature and art. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/9dAAI9mIPjzGJqN11hUrf64NO8ee2Xg70zTnOaGk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;435&quot; height= &quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/9dAAI9mIPjzGJqN11hUrf64NO8ee2Xg70zTnOaGk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tower of Babel&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I read an article that asked:&#39; Is there no support for rationality? &#39;I guess I&#39;m a rationalist. But I don&#39;t think our description of the world is appropriate.&quot; Byatt once expressed his distaste for astrology, &quot;I think the zodiac represents The most absurd and arbitrary poetic imaginings of mankind... They are not at all - God help us - a ram or a virgin, they are just a series of dots... I don&#39;t understand why humans need these systems, but They just need it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/xgcQwvEkzA0lbpfpVTnRnRSmESBFazHUIXBYJELo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1308&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/xgcQwvEkzA0lbpfpVTnRnRSmESBFazHUIXBYJELo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259396&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Angels and Insects&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/NTjZvRwzCLL6SQKYbUonukZnTHRRAcsgJCjxxj9x.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/NTjZvRwzCLL6SQKYbUonukZnTHRRAcsgJCjxxj9x.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259397&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Nightingale Eye&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The novella &quot;Morpho Eugenia&quot; published in 1992 (collected together with &quot;The Engagement Angel&quot;) In &quot;Angels and Insects&quot;, Byatt tells the story of William, a naturalist who studied ants and butterflies in South America. After returning to England, he married Eugenia, the daughter of a squire, only to discover that his wife was involved in a terrible relationship with her half-brother. In the end, William broke with the decadent aristocratic life and returned to the primitive Amazon forest...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the publication of &quot;Morpho Eugenia&quot;, critics praised it one after another. Some say that Byatt, through William, put together the fragments of evidence of true evil. God and science, humans and insects, Amazon and England... Byatt uses her intelligence and imagination to weave everything into this gentle and poetic comedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt once recalled that after the death of her youngest son Charles, she began to pay attention to comedy, &quot;When you are in a lonely and desolate world, those great comedies - Shakespeare or Jane Austen&#39;s Comedy - is strangely becoming more and more important.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In that interview, she mentioned what happened to the heroine Hermione in Shakespeare&#39;s late comedy &quot;The Winter&#39;s Tale&quot;: She was The jealous husband, King Leontes of Sicily, suspected adultery and ordered his death. He survived the catastrophe and was hidden in a sculpture in the cellar. After 16 years, the injustice was overturned and the family was finally reunited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have spent most of my life writing to resist &quot;The Winter&#39;s Tale.&quot; That kind of deception is so bad! It takes away a woman&#39;s most fertile and sexually demanding years. Lock her in a cellar and say it would be nice if she came back as a sculpture, that would be a comfort. It pissed me off.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Byatt admitted that when she was 30, she had I feel scared because &quot;spring comes carelessly, and I will grow old and die&quot;, &quot;But now that I have reached such an age, this fact makes me more gratified: even if I die, spring will continue to come... still There are rocks and trees... As long as we don&#39;t destroy this planet, spring will continue to come; even if we destroy this planet, maybe spring will continue to appear on other planets...&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(References: &quot;The Paris Review·Writer Interview 6&quot;, &quot;Possession&quot;, &quot;Angels and Insects&quot;, &quot;Virgin in the Garden&quot;, &quot;Still Life&quot;, &quot;Tower of Babel&quot;, &quot;The Whistling Woman&quot; &quot; &quot;Eye of a Nightingale&quot;, &quot;Matisse Stories&quot;, &quot;Medusa&#39;s Ankles: Selected Stories&quot;, etc.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[检察机关依法对周建琨涉嫌受贿案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261146]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 15:09:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Reporters learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate on November 23 that Zhou Jiankun, former deputy secretary and vice chairman of the Guizhou Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, was suspected of The bribery case was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, it was reviewed and prosecuted by the First Branch of the Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate. Recently, the First Branch of the Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Chongqing Municipal No. 1 Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ notified the defendant Zhou Jiankun of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant Zhou Jiankun, and listened to the opinions of the defender. The prosecution charged: The defendant Zhou Jiankun used his position as deputy secretary, mayor and municipal party committee secretary of Duyun Municipal, Guizhou Province, deputy director of the Economic and Information Technology Commission of Guizhou Province, deputy secretary-general of the Guizhou Provincial People&#39;s Government, deputy secretary of the municipal party committee and municipal committee of Anshun, Guizhou Province Mayor, Secretary of the Municipal Party Committee, Secretary of the Bijie Municipal Party Committee of Guizhou Province, member of the Guizhou Provincial Political Consultative Conference Party Group, Deputy Secretary of the Party Group, Vice Chairman, etc., seeking benefits for others and illegally accepting property from others, with a particularly huge amount , he should be held criminally responsible for accepting bribes according to law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从抢姓“周”到员工互殴，中国金行的“商战”有多激烈？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260958]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, some media released a video saying that a Wanda Plaza in Binzhou, Shandong Province There were many people fighting in the building, and it was suspected that employees of Chow Tai Seng and Lao Fengxiang were fighting each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, the Bincheng Branch of the Binzhou Municipal Public Security Bureau issued a situation report stating that a dispute occurred between the staff of two stores during the process of soliciting business, and multiple clerks from both parties broke into each other. conflict. Netizens ridiculed Jinxing&#39;s fighting behavior to attract business, &quot;Is this a &#39;business war&#39;?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, Jinxing&#39;s &quot;business war&quot; has always been quite controversial. Fierce, from competing for the surname &quot;Zhou&quot; to now &quot;fighting&quot; to compete for the market. Is such low-quality competition really conducive to the long-term development of domestic jewelry companies? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/wGz3dhhd4CDXkvhPLQvgDrkH4GxKYoxNfI5u1tMC.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/wGz3dhhd4CDXkvhPLQvgDrkH4GxKYoxNfI5u1tMC.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259328&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Robbing for the surname &quot;Zhou&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many consumers who don’t know much about gold brands have inevitably encountered such confusion: Why do so many gold companies have the surname &quot;Zhou&quot;? For example, Chow Tai Fook, Chow Sang Sang, Chow Tai Sang, Saturday Fook, Chow Jin Sang, Chow Pak Fook, Chow Fu Sang... In fact, the founders of many of them are not named &quot;Chow&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chow Tai Fook is a well-known old brand. As early as 1929, Chow Tai Fook&#39;s founder Zhou Zhiyuan founded the first &quot;Chow Tai Fook Gold Store&quot; on Hongde Road, Guangzhou, mainly selling traditional gold jewelry. In the 1930s, due to the current situation, Zhou Zhiyuan moved Chow Tai Fook Bank from Guangzhou to Macau, and later opened a branch in Hong Kong. In 2011, Chow Tai Fook was listed in Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chow Sang Sang is also an old brand, and the founder is also named Zhou. In 1934, Shunde native Zhou Fangpu founded Jinhang in Guangzhou. From the 1930s to the 1940s, Chow Sang Sang had opened many branches in Hong Kong and Macao. Chow Sang Sang was listed in 1973. It was the first listed gold and jewelry company in Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chow Tai Sang was established much later than Chow Tai Fook and Chow Sang Sang. It opened its first counter in Wangfujing Department Store in Beijing in 1999 and was listed on the Shenzhen Main Board in 2017. The founder of Zhou Dasheng, Zhou Zongwen, is from Fuqing, Fujian Province, but his surname is indeed &quot;Zhou&quot;, so there is nothing wrong with naming the gold bank Zhou Dasheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Saturday Fu&#39;s surname is &quot;Zhou&quot;, which has caused a lot of controversy. In 2004, Li Weipeng and Chen Chuangjin jointly invested in the establishment of Saturday Fortune. In 2005, Chen Chuangjin transferred 50% of the equity held by Li Weipeng to Li Weizhu, Li Weipeng&#39;s brother. In other words, the founder and current head of Saturday Fortune is named &quot;Li&quot;. The name of Luk Fook will also cause consumers to confuse it with &quot;Luk Fook Jewelry&quot;. Lukfook Jewelry was established in Hong Kong in 1991 and listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange in 1997. It is more senior than Lukfook. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some jewelry brands named &quot;Zhou&quot; that appeared after 2000 did not have founders named Zhou. For example, the founders of Zhou Jinsheng are surnamed Li, the founders of Zhou Baifu are surnamed Ye, and the founders of Zhou Fusheng are surnamed Zheng... The founders of these brands must be well aware of whether there is a motive for &quot;taking advantage of&quot; the brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The rush to surname &quot;Zhou&quot; reflects a dilemma of domestic jewelry brands: There is still a lack of domestic jewelry brands that are truly out of the circle, and consumers fail to understand some of the problems. Some brands generate real loyalty. Gold banks look similar, and consumers don’t care that much. This gives those who “fake” the brand an opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/3q8lLZ1kdijbLfTD5NOyZfbGST9i21Ndx4qJPKzJ.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/23/3q8lLZ1kdijbLfTD5NOyZfbGST9i21Ndx4qJPKzJ.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259329&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Seize for the sinking market&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only are they competing for the surname &quot;Zhou&quot;, China&#39;s major gold banks are also competing for the market. This time, the employees of Zhou Taisheng and Lao Fengxiang fought over soliciting business, which is a microcosm of the current situation of jewelry brands competing for the sinking market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Whether it is Lao Fengxiang, China Gold, or a group of gold banks named &quot;Zhou&quot;, they have opened stores in the sinking market. Some netizens posted that their hometown is a small county, but “seven or eight gold stores have opened on one street.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chow Tai Fook&#39;s first quarter financial report of this year shows that in the first quarter, Chow Tai Fook opened 248 new retail points in the mainland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chow Tai Sang&#39;s financial report shows that as of the first quarter of 2023, the number of Chow Tai Sang&#39;s terminal stores has increased by a net of 133 stores compared with the end of the same period last year, and by a net increase of 21 stores from the beginning of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;China Gold&#39;s 2023 first quarter financial report shows that China Gold added 21 direct-operated stores and 325 franchise stores in the first quarter; Chow Sang Sang also predicted in the financial report , the group will have a net increase of approximately 100 branches in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Most of these branches are in third- and fourth-tier cities. For example, in 2022, more than half of Chow Tai Fook&#39;s new stores will be located in sinking markets, and the proportion of retail value in third-tier, fourth-tier and other cities has reached one-third. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The reason why we target the sinking market is that on the one hand, the gold and jewelry market in first- and second-tier cities has gradually become saturated, and there is no shortage of gold banks and gold stores. Expand market share and begin to extend to lower-tier markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, in addition to investment and self-wear, a very critical part of the consumer demand for jewelry is wedding demand. In small counties, there are customary requirements for &quot;three golds&quot; (gold necklaces, gold rings, gold earrings) or &quot;hardwares&quot; (gold bracelets and gold headdresses are added to the &quot;three golds&quot;) for weddings. Gold consumption of 10,000 yuan is &quot;standard&quot; in many places. This is a big cake. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the sinking of gold brands has also brought new problems. The first thing to bear the brunt is brand management. Many new stores are franchise stores of the brand. The management level of the franchisees varies. Once a problem occurs, it becomes a brand problem and has an impact on the brand image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is even more embarrassing is that for consumers in the sinking market, whether you are the senior Lao Fengxiang, Chow Tai Fook, the much younger Chow Tai Seng, or the local There is no fundamental difference between some &quot;no-name&quot; gold banks. Consumers &quot;buy whichever one is cheaper&quot;. Anyway, they are all gold, so whoever you buy is not buying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Therefore, the &quot;business war&quot; of gold banks in the sinking market sometimes involves simply and crudely grabbing customers, which may lead to conflicts. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Need to work hard on craftsmanship and brand management&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;No matter Whether they are competing for the surname &quot;Zhou&quot; or the outrageous conflicts caused by low-quality competition, they have jointly exposed the common dilemma of domestic gold brands: the brand premium is not high, consumers&#39; brand loyalty is not high, and competition is still in the &quot;reckless&quot; stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Precisely because the brand premium is not high, the profit margins of domestic gold brands are not high. No matter how the gold price outside rises, buying gold at a gold bank only adds a labor fee to the gold price. According to industry analysis, the retail gross profit margin of gold is 10%-20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As for profit margins, they are even lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, Lao Fengxiang&#39;s first quarter financial report for 2023 shows that during the reporting period, the company achieved total operating income of 24.558 billion yuan, net profit attributable to the parent company of 716 million yuan, and a profit margin of 2.9%; China Gold’s operating income in the first quarter of 2023 was 16.139 billion yuan, net profit attributable to the parent company was 300 million yuan, and the profit margin was 1.86%...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In comparison , some foreign luxury jewelry brands, such as Tiffany, Bulgari, and Van Cleef &amp; Arpels, have enviable retail gross profit margins, which can reach 50%-60%. The materials used are obviously ordinary materials that are cheaper than gold, but the price is eye-popping, and consumers still flock to it. Labeling consumers as &quot;foolish people with too much money&quot; is just the self-comfort of those who are lagging behind. Domestic gold brands need to face the gap head-on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Where do these luxury brands “win”? On the one hand, luxury brand craftsmanship and innovation have elements of originality and originality. For example, Van Cleef &amp; Arpels&#39; &quot;Four-Leaf Clover&quot; series has become a hit because of its classics. Domestic gold brands have also been exploring craftsmanship in recent years. For example, Chow Tai Fook&#39;s &quot;ancient gold&quot; is very popular among young consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Unfortunately, following the trend in China is still too serious. Nowadays, almost every mainstream gold brand has an ancient gold series, and the distinction between brands is even worse. Disappeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The other is the continuous cultivation of brand image. Nowadays, many gold brands co-brand with brands that young people like, such as Harry Potter and Zootopia. This is of course one way, but the co-branding itself relies more on the power of other brands and cannot be converted into the value of its own brand. . Consumers will buy co-branded models, but they will not become loyal users of gold brands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the final analysis, to enhance brand power, we must avoid short-sightedness, avoid eagerness for quick success, avoid following the trend, be calm, sit back, and work hard on craftsmanship. Enhance the artistry and sense of nobility of the brand, making it difficult for other brands to copy it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Otherwise, if you blindly follow the trend, blindly expand the market and open franchises, it may seem that you have a large market share, but in fact, you will still earn money through hard work. fee. In the end, no matter how fierce the &quot;fight&quot; is, consumers will still buy the cheaper one - and your &quot;fight&quot; is in vain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿童医院人满为患，国家卫健委回应]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261135]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In view of the recent increase in the number of outpatient and emergency visits in hospitals and the increase in the number of children infected with respiratory diseases in some places, the National Health Commission In an exclusive interview with Xinhua News Agency on November 23, the relevant responsible comrades of the Health Committee answered some questions that the public, especially families of children, are concerned about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Recently, many local children’s hospitals have been overcrowded, and the National Health Commission has taken measures What measures are in place to provide relief? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Recently, we have continued to pay attention to the diagnosis and treatment of vulnerable groups in children during the period of high incidence of infectious diseases, and guided all localities to strengthen overall planning and implement hierarchical diagnosis and treatment. system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some community hospitals have recently opened examinations for children services, but some parents are worried that community hospitals have insufficient diagnostic and treatment capabilities and may delay their children’s condition. What should they do? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The National Health Commission has required all localities to play the role of medical consortiums to strengthen technical guidance to grassroots medical and health institutions and improve the prevention and control of general infections. Diagnosis and treatment capabilities and critical illness identification and referral efficiency. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Which hospitals are qualified to accept children with respiratory tract infections? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The National Health and Medical Commission has guided all regions to publish information on medical institutions that can provide pediatric diagnosis and treatment services in the region to facilitate nearby medical treatment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What should I do if my child has a fever or cough? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Large hospitals are densely staffed, have long waiting times, and have a high risk of cross-infection. It is recommended that children with mild symptoms first go to primary care. Institutions, general hospital paediatrics, etc. After a diagnosis and treatment plan is determined at a children&#39;s specialized hospital, the patient can also be referred to a primary medical institution for follow-up treatment or home treatment through the medical consortium. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Question:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are the conditions under which children must go to the hospital for medical treatment? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Answer: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;According to expert advice, if a child has a very high fever or a fever that lasts for more than three days, frequent coughs that affect normal life, poor mental status, or even symptoms of If you experience lethargy, increased respiratory rate or difficulty breathing, frequent vomiting, rash, headache or convulsions, etc., you should take your child to the doctor promptly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大学图书馆应该向公众开放]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261055]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Zhao Kui, a professor at Huazhong University of Science and Technology, said on Weibo recently: I didn’t understand before why so many Chinese scholars I want to go to Harvard to study China. After looking at the collection of the library, I couldn’t help but wonder, just for the Chinese local chronicles, which library in China has so many original local chronicles from the early Qing Dynasty, where you can read them by hand, take photos for free, and each set of rare books has been specially protected. Protected and carefully collected, this is just the tip of the iceberg of Harvard&#39;s many libraries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Zhao Kui said that some of Harvard University’s chronicles were purchased by Yenching University when it was running a school in China in the late Qing Dynasty and the Republic of China, some were purchased from Japanese collectors after Japan’s defeat, and many were purchased by Chinese collectors. The income is directly donated by the family, which is the accumulated income of hundreds of years and generations of research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Regardless of the amount of information, Harvard University’s openness is worth promoting in China. Foreigners who intend to visit the Harvard University Library can enter the library with valid documents after applying for a visit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China&#39;s relevant laws and policies, public libraries must be open to the public free of charge. However, school libraries do not have this obligation. In 2017, the second draft of the Public Library Law was reviewed, and Article 47 stipulated: “The state encourages school libraries, libraries of scientific research institutions, and other types of libraries to be open to the public.” Article 48 of the Public Library Law that was finally implemented stipulates: &quot;The state supports school libraries, scientific research institution libraries and other types of libraries to be open to the public.&quot; From encouragement to support, opening school libraries to the public On the issue of openness, the attitude has become weaker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people believe that libraries in universities and scientific research institutions serve specific teachers and students, and students also pay fees to go to university. Therefore, libraries in universities and scientific research institutions should put the interests of teachers and students first. In the first place, there is no obligation to the public. From the perspective of resources and capabilities, school libraries have limited space. Now many university libraries are overcrowded and it is difficult to find a library. University libraries are unable to assume the responsibility of opening to the outside world. Opening up to the outside world will worsen the experience of teachers and students in schools. After it is opened to the outside world, even if there is access through ID cards, citizen cards, etc., it cannot be strictly managed like subway security inspections. There are great dangers and hidden dangers, which is not conducive to protecting students. In addition, there will be management issues, such as the problem of non-return after lending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, these reasons are not valid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, although students pay tuition fees, the running costs of the university cannot be covered by tuition fees. China&#39;s universities and scientific research institutions are all supported by state funding, including libraries, and state funding comes from taxes paid by each citizen. University libraries are also public libraries to some extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public&#39;s demand for the library is mainly for borrowing, which will not put too much pressure on the venue. In terms of management, the credit system is now very developed and can fully undertake the management of university libraries opening to the outside world. In addition to ID cards, citizen cards, and financial credit systems, social credit systems such as Zhima Fen are now very efficient. Not only can you borrow power banks and shared bicycles without a deposit, you can even rent a car without a deposit. These values ​​are more expensive than books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for security issues, borrowing itself is a screening demand. Those who have this demand are people with some education. Even if it is open, it will not be like a teahouse or bar, and the demand will not skyrocket and the pressure will not be Not big. Of course, there are always more risks when there are more people, but this risk is no higher than college students taking the subway or walking on the street, so the so-called safety issues are not valid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there is another very important reason why universities and research institutions do not open their libraries, that is, they can monopolize scarce information and academic resources, thereby gaining advantages in publishing papers and producing results. But obviously, academic libraries supported by public finance should not become exclusive academic resources. Someone said on Weibo that he went to the National Library and wanted to read the only copy of &quot;The Book of Fishing&quot; from the Ming Dynasty. He only saw it after asking for help. He was not allowed to take pictures. It took him three days to enter it on the computer and spent more than 500 yuan on the remaining part. Copying, and you also need to sign a &quot;no publication&quot; guarantee before you can read it. The original copies of the Ming Dynasty have long lost their copyright. The library should be responsible for disseminating knowledge, but it regards this as an exclusive resource. This phenomenon is more serious in universities and research institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The libraries of universities and research institutions are more professional than public libraries and have more comprehensive subject materials. If they are only used by one family, it will cause waste. If they are open to the public, they can exert greater value and make more people use it. Many people benefit, and it is also conducive to academic competition and innovation. On the other hand, university libraries are independent, which will lead to duplication of construction and is not conducive to the efficient use of resources. Opening up university libraries and sharing resources is conducive to the differentiation of university libraries into professional directions, which is also a good thing for universities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Good Will Hunting&quot;, which was nominated for Best Picture at the 70th Academy Awards together with &quot;Titanic&quot;, tells the story of the growth of a talented boy. In the film, a Harvard college student laughs at the male protagonist, and the male protagonist counterattacks: &quot;The education you spent fifteen thousand dollars on, I can get in a public library for only one and a half dollars.&quot; Open libraries are conducive to education. Fairness and fair opportunities allow more people who have not entered universities or scientific research institutions to easily obtain academic materials and promote the development of China&#39;s science, technology, and cultural knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2017, the Ministry of Education and the General Administration of Sports jointly issued the &quot;Implementation Opinions on Promoting the Opening of School Sports Venues to the Society&quot;, which aims to effectively alleviate the growing sports and fitness needs of young people and the general public. The contradiction between sports venues and insufficient supply of resources promotes the prosperity and development of national fitness. Objectively speaking, the operation of sports venues is a zero-sum game with little flexibility and an either-or for users. But the library is different. If it is just for borrowing, opening it to the public will have little impact on students and researchers. Therefore, since university stadiums can &quot;promote opening to the public&quot;, then there is no reason for university libraries to be closed and refused to be open to the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The library is a public service with strong externalities. It can popularize knowledge, help innovation, and drive the country&#39;s technological and economic progress and social development. The more borrowings there are, the stronger the role of the library. It is a great thing for the country and individuals for libraries to operate at a higher intensity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the state should promote, encourage and even require libraries in universities and research institutions to be open to the public. Nowadays, libraries have a lot of electronic materials, which are open to the public. They do not occupy library space and do not put a lot of pressure on the network. Electronic materials in colleges and universities are open to the public, and this can be done immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这对错置的父女，治愈又温情]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261059]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;There is a new movie recently. George, a 12-year-old hearing-impaired girl, lives alone after the death of her mother. Suddenly, her childish father Jason, whom she has never met, breaks into her life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It was shortlisted for the main competition unit of this year’s Beijing International Film Festival, and also won the Jury Prize in the world cinema feature film unit of this year’s Sundance Film Festival. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Occasionally Echoed&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/866afcc07801117a78c26caa6e83b215.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/866afcc07801117a78c26caa6e83b215.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a niche literary film, &quot;Occasionally Echoed&quot; 》Requires you to be completely immersed in it while watching the movie. Any external actions or sounds may break the continuity of the experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This does not mean that &quot;Oudehui&lt;/span>;ring&quot; has high threshold requirements for the audience. In fact, it does not have a dramatic plot, nor emotional ups and downs, and is even a bit straightforward and monotonous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this is such a movie, but it has something that many current movies lack - truth in details, emotional intimacy, and the opposite of spring breeze. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/10687a29fbb137cc8bf11f0a59aebb10.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/10687a29fbb137cc8bf11f0a59aebb10.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259120&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But this kind of delicate emotional presentation also requires the audience to carefully understand the fleeting arrangements in the movie from the lens language and plot settings. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For example, the instant switching between day and night, documentary-style comments from friends around, and the protagonist’s loneliness when he tried to use bicycle parts to build the Tower of Babel leading to heaven. And the various interactions between her and her sudden appearance of her father all hint at the careful thoughts of director Charlotte Regan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/8192125475f2b4e38c9f0ee66458f3a5.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/8192125475f2b4e38c9f0ee66458f3a5.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259122 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;Oudehui&lt;/span>;Hang&quot; uses the perspective of the little girl George to show her changes in the whole thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her eyes, all her actions such as stealing other people&#39;s bicycles and reselling them, beating up the little girl next door, etc., have a natural legitimacy; while the father who climbed over the wall is an idiot in life. He is the one who needs to be taken care of. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This contrary narration method makes the film full of a childishness that pretends to be mature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/f150d9df5aa87d07e290d3bffcacb8f1.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/f150d9df5aa87d07e290d3bffcacb8f1.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259125&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In our traditional understanding, fathers are often figures of silent giving. For example, in Zhu Ziqing&#39;s novel, the father left a deep shadow after turning over the tracks to buy oranges for his son; for example, the father played by Zhang Yi in the currently released &quot;Priceless Treasure&quot; is very willing to protect and pay for his adopted daughter, even if he faces jail, he still has to protect his daughter&#39;s safety. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;A father from this perspective is always like a mountain, extending his hands when his children need them, and becoming a beacon when their children move forward. Likewise, as children, they should also go Understand their hardship and be grateful for their efforts. &lt;/span>;This is a profound expression of father&#39;s love, and also contains a spiritual expectation of parents for their children, hoping that they will be considerate and filial in return. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;However, &quot;Occasional Echoes&quot; misplaced the maturity of the little girl and her father in an exaggerated way, causing the father to confess that he was not sensible and did not know how to take care of him as soon as he appeared. child. The daughter, on the other hand, cleans the house the way her mother did when she was alive, so that every place in the house always looks like it did when her mother was alive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this contrary misplacement, the movie&lt;/span>; rarely restores the world of a child. There is the joy that only belongs to children here. She dances cutely downstairs to please the neighbors, rolls around on the grass with her friends, thinks she can steal other people&#39;s bicycles seamlessly, and thinks she is confident in bargaining with unscrupulous car dealers. This is a child who forces himself to mature and begins to explore the grand world, full of vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the film generously acknowledges that our parents can also be outrageous. For example, he would join his daughter&#39;s theft, not only to help her look out, but also to start the operation. As a result, the bicycle was not stolen&lt;span>;, but instead the patrolling police were attracted...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/69d49ea63542fb2185386e93591beaa4.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/69d49ea63542fb2185386e93591beaa4.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This pair of parents Women, they use their own ways to understand life, but as a result, they are all inexperienced and at a loss, and they are unable to become better guardians and children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is an atypical father-daughter relationship. The film not only captures the panic and anxiety of children trying to grow into adults, but also captures the panic and fear of men becoming fathers. They are limited to their first time. The father must learn to accompany and the daughter must learn to accept. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Towards the end of the movie, there is a plot that makes people laugh out loud - the little girl&lt;/span>; heard her mother leaving a &lt;span>;message&lt; to her father on the phone&lt; /span>; &quot;Take good care of your daughter&quot;, but in a blink of an eye she found that her father was not in the house. She searched in panic, and finally heard the boy playing football calling &quot;Jason&quot; next to a football field on the corner of the street. The little girl looked inside and found that the father she had been looking for for a long time was actually playing football with a group of children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/26c512d2dd2451a0c5904c13152b6065.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/22/26c512d2dd2451a0c5904c13152b6065.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;259123&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This is the most gratifying part of the film. &lt;/span>;The 1994 director did not try to exploit the pain and ferocity of this subject, &lt;span>;but instead presented it tolerantly&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;. Let us see that adults can also be as fragile as children, and children can also appear mature and steady. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In this misplaced line drawing, there is neither the mountain-like weight of father&#39;s love nor the pain of children&#39;s growth, but that they both want to play the good role in each other&#39;s life hard and clumsily. own role. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[包子铺卖豆腐脑被罚一万五：对小本生意岂可如此“用重典”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261051]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-23 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a Baozi shop in Beijing was confiscated by the municipal supervision department for selling tofu noodles and was fined 15,000 yuan and more than 7,000 yuan. attracted public attention and strong doubts. Selling tofu bread in a bun shop may indeed violate the regulations, but it does not necessarily require a huge penalty. Is there a more humane way? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the China Quality News Network, a subsidiary of China Quality Newspaper and Periodicals, which is in charge of the State Administration of Municipal Supervision, an administrative penalty published on the official website of the Beijing Municipal Supervision Bureau recently showed that the &quot;Beijing Wannan Wenxin Baozi Shop&quot; will be closed in 2022. From April 23 to July 27, 2023, &quot;1,169 orders of tofu nao (salty) were sold on a food delivery platform, priced at 6 yuan/order, with a value of 7,014 yuan.&quot; The Chaoyang District Municipal Supervision Bureau believes that the bun shop sells hot food beyond the scope of its licensed business items and violates Article 16, paragraph 1, of the Measures for the Investigation and Punishment of Illegal Activities on Online Food Safety and the Measures for the Supervision and Administration of Food Safety in Online Catering Services 》Article 4 stipulates that he shall be fined 15,000 yuan according to law; his illegal income of 7,014 yuan shall be confiscated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is undoubtedly surprising that the bun shop cannot sell tofu pudding. As a result, the penalty quickly attracted a lot of attention on social media. Many netizens made fun of it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The clause quoted in the administrative penalty decision stipulates that food operators shall not operate beyond the scope of the food business license. But why is it beyond the business scope of a bun shop to sell tofu? This really leaves a lot of people scratching their heads. According to the Chaoyang District Municipal Supervision Bureau, selling tofu curd is exceeding the permitted scope of selling hot food, but aren’t steamed buns a hot food? Since you can sell steamed buns, it means you have a hot food business license, so why can&#39;t you sell tofu puffs? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public administrative penalty information does not provide any further explanation. Then we can only look up more information. Judging from the industrial and commercial registration information, the business license of this bun shop was registered in 2018, and its business scope includes catering services and food sales. According to the Food Safety Law, food-related business activities require a food business license. Then I checked its food business license information and found that its licensed business item is &quot;manufacture and sales of hot food (limited to staple food products)&quot;. The &quot;restricted to staple food products&quot; in the brackets is probably the reason why this bun shop was fined. Although they are all hot foods, steamed buns are a staple food, so their production and sale are allowed, while tofu curd is not considered a staple food, so they cannot be sold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this point of view, the punishment imposed by the Chaoyang Municipal Supervision Bureau cannot be said to be illegal. However, its rationality is still questionable. First of all, why is the scope of the food business license of this bun shop so narrow? According to the &quot;Food Business License Management Measures&quot; formulated by the former State Food and Drug Administration, the food business license items applied for by catering service operators are divided into hot food production and sales, cold food food production and sales, raw food food production and sales, and cakes. Production and sales of food, homemade drinks and other types of food. Except for the specific varieties approved by the Food and Drug Administration, which should be clearly marked for the production and sale of other types of food, other categories do not need to be specially labeled. So why is the food business license of this bun shop marked as limited to staple food products? If regulations do not stipulate that different business licenses apply to staple food and non-staple hot food, is the license originally issued by the Chaoyang Municipal Supervision Bureau suspected of not being administered in accordance with the law and improperly restricting the business scope of the business? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be noted that information from the official website of the Beijing Municipal Supervision Bureau shows that the food business license of Wannan Wenxin Baozi Shop was issued on October 17, 2023. The penalty decision for operating beyond the scope was made on November 13. The illegal facts in the penalty decision show that Baozipu has been selling tofu nao on the takeout website since April 2022. So, when this bun shop applied for a food business license in 2023, why did it only apply for the production and sale of &quot;staple food&quot; hot food? Knowing that in addition to steamed buns, their store also sells tofu puffs, and that there is no need to apply separately for hot food business licenses for staple food and non-staple food, the store deliberately only applied for a manufacturing and sales license for &quot;staple food&quot; to limit its business scope and Excluding the tofu pudding that you are already selling, are you digging a hole for yourself? Were you misled when you applied for a food business license? Have the staff of the competent department fulfilled their duty of explanation? Is it even possible that when applying for a license, they deliberately misled them to only apply for a staple food license, and then investigated and punished them for selling non-staple food beyond the scope? Considering that he was investigated and fined less than a month after applying for the license, such a timing coincidence can easily lead to other suspicions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if there are no problems with the above process, imposing such a heavy penalty violates the basic principle of administrative punishment that the penalty should be commensurate with the offense. The Administrative Penalty Law clearly stipulates that if the violation is minor and corrected in a timely manner without causing harmful consequences, administrative penalties will not be imposed. Baozi and tofu are both hot foods, and regulations do not make any special distinction between the safety supervision of the two. The sale of tofu in the bun shop has not caused any food safety consequences. Even if there is any violation of law, the circumstances are very minor, and it can be given a warning and ordered to make corrections. At the beginning, more than 7,000 &quot;illegal gains&quot; were confiscated and fined 15,000 yuan. A total of more than 20,000 yuan. How long does it take for a bun shop to make money back? At a time when it is difficult to make a living in a small business, imposing such heavy penalties on small businessmen will of course arouse strong dissatisfaction among the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for small mistakes to be punished heavily. In 2021, a vegetable shop owner in Yulin, Shaanxi Province was fined 66,000 yuan by the market supervision department for selling 5 kilograms of substandard celery. After being exposed by the State Council Supervision Bureau, the deputy director of the city&#39;s Municipal Supervision Bureau admitted that the punishment was too severe and was not proportionate. A CCTV report found that among the more than 50 penalties imposed on small and micro market entities by the city&#39;s Municipal Supervision Bureau since 2021, 21 cases were fined more than 50,000 yuan, and the case value was only tens or hundreds of yuan. The Chaoyang Municipal Supervision Bureau in Beijing imposed a heavy fine on Baozi Shop, which is comparable to the case in Yulin. Is this kind of supervision for supervision or for fines? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Food safety supervision is of course very important, but supervision cannot be for the sake of supervision, let alone supervision for the sake of fines. Under the current economic situation, providing good services to small and micro market entities and creating a good market environment should be the primary responsibility of regulatory authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>