<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[晚明“王学误国”正确吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259199]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/24/IZqRHIooVi8eeNbCb6YtNanNPdrjN4Vi2W6wkWRD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1061&quot; height=&quot;2141&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/IZqRHIooVi8eeNbCb6YtNanNPdrjN4Vi2W6w kWRD. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255084&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Portrait scroll of Wang Shouren in the National Museum. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the Jiajing period, the Ming Dynasty has suffered from internal and external troubles and numerous crises. Some people attribute it to Yangming&#39;s philosophy of &quot;talking about harming the country&quot;. After the Ding Revolution, the survivors of the Ming Dynasty learned from the pain, reflected on the historical lessons of the country&#39;s subjugation, and believed that &quot;Wang Xue&quot; was one of the culprits. The most representative figure among them is Gu Yanwu. In his article &quot;The Master&#39;s Words and the Way of Heaven&quot;, He denounced Wang Xue&#39;s &quot;empty words of understanding one&#39;s mind and one&#39;s nature, replacing the practical knowledge of cultivating oneself and governing others&quot;, which resulted in &quot;the collapse of the Chinese state and the ruins of clans and societies!&quot; Famous Confucian scholars such as Zhang Luxiang, Lu Longqi, Lu Shiyi, and Xiong Cilu all expressed this opinion. , and advocated the revitalization of Cheng-Zhu Neo-Confucianism and the application of practical knowledge to correct the shortcomings of Wang Xue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qian Chengzhi, a survivor of the Ming Dynasty, said unceremoniously in a letter to Gu Yanwu&#39;s nephew Xu Yuanwen that Gu Yanwu&#39;s denigration of Yangming&#39;s studies was just a remnant of the spit of an old student in Wujiang, and had no factual basis. , very emotional. Some modern scholars have expressed doubts about Gu&#39;s statement. The author believes that the &quot;Wang Xue theory of subjugation of the country&quot; is divorced from the facts and is the product of the party struggle at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/dE644zekk4itpgNoM2BQWeY7aFJ8XwkF3LS0IQYz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1790&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/24/dE644zekk4itpgNoM2BQWeY7aFJ8XwkF3LS0IQYz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255083&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The statue of Gu Yan is in the collection of the National Museum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, theoretically speaking, Yangming&#39;s philosophy of mind is not a study of mysterious emptiness and emptiness as Gu and others said, but a study of practical application of the world. In his &quot;Reply to Gu Dongqiao&quot;, Yangming criticized &quot;those stubborn, empty and quiet people&quot; who &quot;cannot govern the country and the world&quot;, and advocated &quot;practicing one&#39;s work&quot; and integrating knowledge and action. He publicly declared that he disdained the study of exegesis, memorization, and verses. He said that practicing verses was &quot;as if he were on the stage of a hundred plays.&quot; It&#39;s shameful.&quot; Wang Yangming had the ambition to help the world since he was a child. He studied riding and archery, and studied the art of war. He once went deep outside the Great Wall to inspect geography. The most outstanding sign of his integration of knowledge and action was the application of the art of mind to military practice. According to his disciple Wang Ji&#39;s &quot;Yu Yu&quot; Recalling the article &quot;Xu Jiang&quot;: When I asked my former master what was the secret behind the saying that he was like a god in using troops, the master said: &quot;I have no secret skills, but I have always believed in conscience. Whenever I take advantage of the opportunity to face the enemy, I only have this little bit of spiritual intelligence and spiritual response.&quot; , I am not moved by the interests of life and death, so my plans are carefully planned, and the enemy does not know where he is coming. I am originally a person who practices my duty, but the world mistakenly thinks that I am a god.&quot; Volume 4 of He Liangjun&#39;s &quot;Siyou Zhaicong Shuo&quot; concludes : Wang Yangming said, &quot;The military is based on lectures and tactics are used, and the administration is based on lectures and political skills.&quot; The mutual complementation of academics and achievements enabled Yangming to achieve great success in the military. During the Jiajing period, in response to the imperial court&#39;s outright rejection of Yangming&#39;s scholarship, Huang Wan pointed out that the essence of Yangming&#39;s scholarship was &quot;to consider what people say and do, and not to just talk in vain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, from a practical point of view, many disciples of the Wang Sect and their followers have made achievements that will be remembered by future generations. Yangming did not regard knowledge as the only criterion for accepting disciples. Among his disciples were potters, farmers, woodcutter, etc. There were knights who &quot;fighted dragons and snakes with bare hands&quot;, counselors who made plans, and generals who led troops in war. For example, Hu Zongxian, a disciple of Ouyang De, led the army and people of Zhejiang to fight against Japanese invaders, and planned to capture and kill the great Japanese pirates Wang Zhi and Xu Hai to quell the Japanese invaders in Zhejiang and Zhejiang. Weng Wanda, governor of Shaanxi and governor of Xuanda, was one of the coffin bearers when Wang Yangming was buried. He was friendly with Yangming&#39;s disciples Ouyang De, Luo Hongxian, Tang Shunzhi, Wang Ji and others. Weng Wanda was in charge of the northern border defense for five or six years, and made outstanding achievements in fighting against the invasion of Mongolia. Guo Zizhang, a disciple of Ouyang De, patrolled Guizhou in the 26th year of Wanli (1598). He worked with Li Hualong to suppress Yang Yinglong&#39;s rebellion in Bozhou and was known as the first famous official in central Guizhou. Luo Rufang, a student of Yan Jun, was criticized by people in the early Qing Dynasty for &quot;talking about nothing&quot;. In fact, he visited many places to study and inspect society in his early years. In the early years of Wanli, the imperial court adopted a policy of appeasement against the expansion and aggression of the Burmese king. According to the &quot;Bureau&quot;, Luo Rufang, who was then the right political participant in Yunnan, planned to encircle the Mang clan of the Burmese king. However, his success fell short because someone slandered the governor Wang Ning. Luo Rufang &quot; He threw himself to the ground in anger and cursed loudly.&quot; This caused serious trouble, and the Burmese army invaded Yunnan in a large scale. Li Cai, who had studied under Zou Shouyi, wiped out pirates and Japanese pirates when he was in Guangdong; when he was in Yunnan, he defeated the Burmese invasion. Luo Hongxian, the number one scholar of the Private Shu Wang Yangming, is described in the original &quot;History of the Ming Dynasty&quot; as &quot;leaping his horse and drawing his bow, examining the history through research&quot;. The rivers and canals, frontier fortresses, battle formations, offenses and defenses, etc. are not studied in detail. Shunzhi of Tang Dynasty in Huiyuan Dynasty, who &quot;heard the words of conscience from Wang Ji&quot;, is said in the &quot;History of Ming Dynasty&quot; to &quot;know everything about learning&quot; and pay special attention to practical learning. He &quot;never forgot the world and the country in his heart&quot;, and until his deathbed, he still thought about the safety of the country and did not care about his private affairs. In the thirty-sixth year of Jiajing&#39;s reign (1557), Zhao Wenhua, a member of Yan Song&#39;s party, supervised the military affairs of Jiangsu and Zhejiang and recommended him as the chief of the Nanjing Ministry of War. Shun Zhi put the country first, regardless of the tarnished reputation, and resolutely came out of the mountain. He inspected Jizhen, verified the number of troops, and put forward many practical suggestions. He also assisted Hu Zongxian in fighting against Japanese invaders, patrolled the sea to inspect the situation of bandits, formulated strategies to attack, intercept and block the enemy, and personally commanded and won great victories such as Yaojiadang. The famous anti-Japanese generals Tan Lun, Yu Dayou, Qi Jiguang, Liu Xian, etc. were all appreciated and promoted by him. In addition, Yan Jun, Xu Wei, disciples of the Wang family, and Zheng Ruozeng, who was influenced by Yangming&#39;s psychology, all served in the Hu Zongxian shogunate and made their own contributions to the pacification of Japan in different ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many military generals with great military exploits are also disciples of the Wang Clan. For example, Governor Wanbiao got his philosophical ideas from Wang Ji, Luo Hongxian, Qian Dehong and Tang Shunzhi. He once personally led the monk soldiers to fight against the Japanese pirates at Yangjing Bridge in Suzhou, and was hit by an arrow without leaving the line of fire. Yu Dayou followed Yangming&#39;s Xinxue in his early years and later studied under Tang Shunzhi. Qi Jiguang was also &quot;a private person of Shu Yangming and a great expounder of conscience&quot;. He once entered Qian Dehong&#39;s family, and Qian Dehong recommended him to Hu Zongxian. Qi Jiguang advocated taking &quot;sincerity&quot; as the work force, &quot;practicing it personally&quot;, and focusing on &quot;treating the mind&quot; in military training. Deng Zilong learned from Luo Hong before he became an official, and he kept it in mind throughout his life. He fought in all directions and made many meritorious deeds. Later, in the war to aid Korea, even though he was nearly seventy years old, he fought bravely to kill the enemy and sacrificed his life for the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen from this that since the Ming Dynasty, everyone in the Wang family has been a person of great achievements. On the other hand, among the Donglin Party members, except for loyal and honest ministers, there are very few capable ministers in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Faced with the grim reality of &quot;the sky collapsed and the earth collapsed&quot; in the late Ming Dynasty, the Donglin Party members mistakenly blamed Wang Xue and believed that Zhu Zixue was the panacea to save the world. They criticize the corrupt Confucians for being &quot;ignorant of affairs and current affairs. They harm one person, harm the whole family, harm one country, and harm the whole world.&quot; (&quot;Chronicles of Donglin Academy· Donglin Theory of Learning&quot;) This is precisely the self-portrait of the Donglin Party members. The Taizhou School founded by Wang Gen, a disciple of Yangming, has long pointed out that &quot;human relations physics&quot; and &quot;common people&#39;s daily needs&quot; are Tao, and the disciples of Cheng and Zhu are the corrupt Confucians who &quot;do not understand affairs and are not familiar with current affairs.&quot; In the second year of Duanping in the Southern Song Dynasty (1234), the Neo-Confucian master Zhen Dexiu paid homage to Zhen Dexiu to consult on political affairs. People had high expectations for him, thinking that he could establish peace. However, after Zhen Dexiu took office, Prime Minister Zheng Qingzhi did nothing and could not save the declining Southern Song Dynasty. Therefore, the Yuan people&#39;s cancellation of the imperial examination for a time had something to do with the empty talk of Song Confucianism that harmed the country. Song Lian, the leader of civil servants in the early Ming Dynasty, advocated the use of Confucianism, but he had to admit in the &quot;Biography of Wu Deji&quot; that Song Confucianism could not do much more in promoting Confucianism, but in the end he did not make much difference to the world. By the middle of the Ming Dynasty, Cheng-Zhu Neo-Confucianism was on the verge of &quot;dying to death&quot; because the late Neo-Confucianists &quot;only discussed it in footnotes&quot;. In &quot;Remembering the Past&quot;, Li Zhi mocked the pedantic Confucians who &quot;have nothing to do in daily life, only do bows and bows, sit on the ground all day long, like clay sculptures and think that they cannot afford distracting thoughts, then they are the real great sages and great sages.&quot; And &quot;when there is a police officer, they look at each other with no color, and even blame each other, thinking they can be wise.&quot; In &quot;The Biography of Mr. Yangming, the Confucian Prince of the Ming Dynasty&quot;, the scholar Shen Shixing sharply criticized those who attacked Wang Yangming: &quot;Most of the Confucian officials in modern times take it for granted that they are well-dressed and well-dressed, but when it comes to their daily use, they often suffer from rigidity and nothing.&quot; To make achievements; to study extensively and listen in order to learn, but to find out the actual results, they are often obsessed with what they have seen and heard without experiencing, and the customs have been immersed in them for a long time!&quot; This kind of person may be morally impeccable, but he is mediocre and incompetent, and only knows how to die in literature. Advice, fight to the death. Donglin Party members equate morality with ability, and due to the limitations of the times, it is difficult to give a fair definition of &quot;morality&quot;. In the face of foreign aggression, they do not know how to adapt and are immoral. Zhang Luxiang&#39;s &quot;Yuan Xue Ji&quot; says that &quot;Yangming used troops mostly to win by deceit, which Confucians would not do.&quot; University scholar Wang Xijue pointedly pointed out: Zou Yuanbiao, the highly respected moral benchmark in Donglin, is just a &quot;student with simple wishes and no other extraordinary ideas.&quot; There is a shortage of talents in the temple, and there is an urgent need to break down barriers and recruit talents in any way. Zhang Juzheng had long been dissatisfied with the &quot;conventional and vulgar Confucianism&quot; and called for &quot;heroic and true Confucianism&quot;. Jiang Yingke said in &quot;Ancient Theory on Employment&quot;: &quot;To achieve great things, do not pay attention to details; to achieve great achievements, do not pay attention to small righteousness.&quot; Some people even want to select talents from the grassland. Li Zhi especially praised the pirate Lin Daoqian, Zhong In &quot;Preface to Water Margin&quot;, Xing also lamented that &quot;there are no Li Kui or Wu Yong in the world&quot; and &quot;every time I recite the autumn wind, I think of the warriors and shout madly for them.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to corrupt Confucianism, pseudo-Taoism is more harmful. Li Zhi had long criticized the pseudo-Confucianism in &quot;The Theory of the Return of Three Religions to Confucianism&quot; that &quot;yang represents Taoism, yin represents wealth and honor, being subdued by elegance, and behaving like a dog and a pig.&quot; The Donglin Party members adhered to their sectarian views. After taking control of the election, &quot;anyone who disobeys Donglin will be accused of being traitorous.&quot; Later, the society was restored to &quot;hijack the government and control the government from afar.&quot; On the occasion of the change of dynasty, many Donglin Party members &quot;changed their rules and changed their ways&quot;, which was surprising. Therefore, Li Zhi said long ago in &quot;Party Stele&quot;: Secular people &quot;only know that villains can harm the country, but they don&#39;t know that gentlemen can harm the country.&quot; Wei Xi&#39;s &quot;On the Song Dynasty&quot; also said: &quot;The disasters of the country are not caused by villains, but by gentlemen.&quot; They are members of the same party and oppose differences. They do not pursue selfish interests, are interested in fame and profit, and do not hesitate to kill themselves to gain fame. This is what Zhang Tingyu said in &quot;Cheng Huai&quot; It is said in &quot;Yuan Yu&quot; that &quot;killing the remains of parents will lead to the tyranny of the country, loyalty and filial piety, and both will be damaged.&quot; Therefore, some knowledgeable people in the early Qing Dynasty believed that the Ming Dynasty did not fall to rogue bandits, but to Donglin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to partisan factors, &quot;The Theory of Wang Xue Misleading the Country&quot; also has a strong regional flavor. In the Ming Dynasty, the Donglin Party and the Zhejiang Party were at odds with each other. Later, the Zhejiang Party relied on the Eunuch Party, and they even fought to the death. In academic terms, Cheng-Zhu Neo-Confucianism and Lu Wang Xinxue were also on the same page. From the late Ming Dynasty to the Qing Dynasty, those who sympathized with the Donglin Party People have the right to speak, and the mainstream ideology is Cheng-Zhu Neo-Confucianism. During the Daoguang period, Liang Shaoren, a native of Qiantang, expressed strong dissatisfaction with this in his &quot;Essays on Two Kinds of Autumn Rains&quot;. He believed that &quot;Wang Wencheng&#39;s achievements are shining brightly, and he is the best of his generation. He only reveals the world with his conscience, which is a little tired of his cleverness, and the debaters are extremely intent on slandering him. How can we say that the world with Ming will not perish by bandits but perish by Yang Ming!&quot; He sighed with emotion: &quot;Today the world is all followers of Zi Yang, no wonder thousands of people gathered together to point it out!&quot; According to Liang Qichao&#39;s &quot;The Recent Three Years of China&quot; According to &quot;A Hundred Years of Academic History&quot;, in the early Qing Dynasty, even righteous men such as Huang Daozhou, Zhang Huangyan, Wang Yi, Qu Shishu, Chen Zizhuang, Zhang Jiayu, etc. who insisted on resisting the Qing Dynasty and restoring the Ming Dynasty did not dare to consider themselves to have &quot;come from the arms of the mother of the Yangming School&quot; &quot;Nurture them out&quot;, but their motivation to resist the Qing Dynasty actually came from the Yangming School. It can be seen that Cheng and Zhu were powerful in the Qing Dynasty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话上野千鹤子：学术是弱者的武器]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259304]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Who is Chizuru Ueno? Searching for the topic of the same name on Weibo, there are 100 million views. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, three female bloggers who graduated from Peking University had an online conversation with Chizuru Ueno, and the resulting controversy put the latter&#39;s name at the top of the hot search list. So far, the entries for this conversation have been read 580 million times on the Weibo platform alone, and the topic about Chizuru Ueno has &quot;broken the circle.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This was launched in 2019. Prior to this, very few of Chizuru Ueno&#39;s books were published in mainland China, and most of them were circulated in the sociology circle. In 2019, Chizuru Ueno spoke at the opening ceremony of the University of Tokyo. After the video circulated on the Internet, she also gained great popularity in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pbMFkPyJfomiNeKNr1xyLeC0o695DUDJQ7hXLarN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/pbMFkPyJfomiNeKNr1xyLeC0o695DUDJQ7hXLarN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255381&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chizuru Ueno, born in 1948 in Toyama Prefecture, Japan, is a Japanese sociologist and a pioneer in the fields of Japanese women&#39;s studies and gender studies. She is currently an honorary professor at the University of Tokyo. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In her speech, she focused on the two incidents of Tokyo Medical University entrance examination fraud and Tokyo University sexual assault. , questioned the widespread gender discrimination in Japanese society, and then pointed out through data that the ratio of male and female students at the University of Tokyo is uneven, but the reason is not that female students are not as good as male students, but that &quot;there are various wrong social concepts and unfair admissions in entrance examinations&quot; question&quot;. Ueno warned the freshmen: &quot;What awaits you in the future will be a society where no matter how hard you work, you may not get a fair reward...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chizuru Ueno was introduced to China in 2015 after a speech at the University of Tokyo sparked discussion. Zi&#39;s ​​old work &quot;Misogyny&quot; was quickly reprinted more than twenty times, becoming an important publishing phenomenon in recent years. Since then, other works by Chizuru Ueno have been introduced and published. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SEwHeYTpgxYro1N6jgVu2AFAc3iQGd594JarO1uR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2000&quot; height= &quot;1621&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SEwHeYTpgxYro1N6jgVu2AFAc3iQGd594JarO1uR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255380&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chizuru Ueno spoke at the opening ceremony of the University of Tokyo in 2019. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the influences of the book &quot;Misogyny&quot; is that &quot;Misogyny&quot; ) such an academic term has been successfully transformed into popular vocabulary. Ueno believes that men often show contempt for women, while women show self-loathing: &quot;If I am 100% not misogynistic, there is no need to be a feminist, because I no longer need to fight. Feminism means constant People who struggle with inner misogyny.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, netizens have often habitually incorporated it into their own life situations to explain the underlying causes of many unpleasant events in life, such as secretly filming women Private photos are uploaded online, gender discrimination in the workplace, product advertising creates body anxiety, celebrities &quot;cheat&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Publisher Chen Xiying published a collection of conversations between Chizuru Ueno and manga artist Nagako Tamafusa in 2021 &quot;From &quot;Feminism from Scratch&quot; has actual sales of more than 200,000 copies and continues to be printed. In Chen Xiying’s impression, after the word feminism entered China, everyone was still relatively unfamiliar with its connotation and denotation. However, &quot;Feminism from Scratch&quot; is a popular work that integrates daily life into Examples are readily available. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dialogue in the book basically revolves around women&#39;s &quot;parental shortcomings&quot;, from the length of the skirts of female students&#39; school uniforms to the fact that women are often accused of &quot;revealing clothing&quot; in sexual harassment cases; from the plots of popular TV series to the dilemma of female childbearing; even when talking about the media&#39;s shaping of teenagers, it makes readers realize that the setting of Shizuka in &quot;Doraemon&quot; both attracting men and rebuking men is also a kind of &quot;misogyny&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese publishing industry published seven Ueno books in 2022, including the best-selling book &quot;Starting at the Limit&quot;. Since 2023, Ueno has published more than ten books in China, including serious academic works, as well as relatively light popular readings and dialogue collections. The content covers Chizuru Ueno&#39;s areas of concern in the past forty years. For example, &quot;Women&#39;s Thoughts&quot;, which combs the ideological context of Japanese women&#39;s studies, &quot;Unpaid Housewives&quot;, which cares about the &quot;unpaid&quot; work of housewives, and &quot;A Man&#39;s Old Queen&quot;, which focuses on the issue of elderly care...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Beijing In an Internet celebrity bookstore that mainly sells best-selling books, Southern Weekend reporters saw that the most conspicuous place at the entrance was Chizuru Ueno&#39;s &quot;Women&#39;s Thoughts&quot;, &quot;Feminism from Scratch&quot;, &quot;Misogyny&quot; and &quot;For Survival&quot;. &quot;Thoughts&quot; and other works are placed together with popular and practical books such as &quot;How to Deal with Divorce&quot; and &quot;Common Knowledge of Civil Code in Marriage and Love&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SrcR5l7rtqhN3frsIcAX3tA9Zg3p67jAex2MFCJF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/SrcR5l7rtqhN3frsIcAX3tA9Zg3p67jAex2MFCJF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chizuru Ueno&#39;s teachings have great influence in Chinese academic circles and the public sphere. Lu Weiwei, a professor at Southeast University who had invited Chizuru Ueno as a visiting scholar, was influenced by her and established a gender research group at the school. The most subscribed female podcast program &quot;Random Fluctuation&quot; on the Xiaoyu App started talking about Chizuru Ueno in the first episode. The picture shows a woman reading a book in the EMI Building in Xujiahui Park, Shanghai, in April 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the focuses of the dispute between the three female bloggers mentioned above and Ueno is that the blogger who is married and has children The Lord asked Ueno, who chose not to get married and have children, &quot;Did you decide not to get married because you were hurt by men?&quot; This type of question is not uncommon in life. It is a misunderstanding that many people have about single women, so it has offended many people on the Internet. Netizens spontaneously posted in defense of Chizuru Ueno, believing that the three bloggers did not understand what feminism was and that such questions were very &quot;misogynistic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;I like communicating with people from the bottom of my heart&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On social platforms, Chizuru Ueno shows off her iconic red hair. She speaks softly and smiles, but her remarks are sharp. For example, she once strongly criticized the gender injustice in Japanese society, exposing the reality of how women are coerced by &quot;maternal love&quot; and extracting &quot;surplus value&quot;, and said: &quot;Shout when it hurts&quot; Pain, human dignity begins here.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I got to know Chizuru Ueno through Professor Toyo Suga of the University of Tokyo. Suga is a famous Japanese folklorist. He told me that Ueno plays an important role in the whole of Japan. Her influence in the field of humanities and social sciences ranks among the top five, so I must read more of her works.&quot; Lu Weiwei, a professor at the School of Foreign Languages ​​at Southeast University, told Southern Weekend reporters. As one of Ueno&#39;s earliest researchers and translators in China, Lu Weiwei was originally engaged in folklore research. In recent years, she has also taken gender studies as her main research direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Weiwei has systematically read more than 30 works by Chizuru Ueno. She concluded: &quot;Ueno and his peers established Japanese women&#39;s studies, and things that were not included in academic vision in the past began to be taken seriously. Research, she identified such an academic field.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After retiring from the University of Tokyo, Chizuru Ueno has been very active, and her research has gradually shifted to issues such as elderly care and care. Lu Weiwei recalled: &quot;When I visited Teacher Ueno in Tokyo in July 2023, she also gave me three new books. She is 75 years old and is still actively working and writing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Lu Weiwei planned The &quot;Todai × Todai&quot; (abbreviations for the University of Tokyo and Southeast University respectively) series of lectures invites Ueno to give lectures at Southeast University in 2019. Classes run from 8 a.m. to 4 p.m. every day, and Ueno often takes the initiative to ask for extra classes. From gender studies to aging studies, Chizuru Ueno &quot;teaches everything&quot; in almost all fields of her research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After finishing the course at Southeast University, Lu Weiwei accompanied Ueno to visit several cities such as Xi&#39;an, Harbin, Changchun and Beijing, and gave sharings at different universities. After 18 days of contact, Lu Weiwei got a deeper understanding of Ueno: &quot;She is very curious and very considerate. I praised the umbrella she brought with her for its practicality and beauty, and she gave it to me before leaving.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media person Qing Qingzi planned and published a collection of dialogues between female scholars, which included her in-depth interview with Chizuru Ueno in 2021. During the exchange, Ueno not only expressed her own opinions, but also listened carefully and listened carefully to the interview. The situation in China is of great interest. Since the video interview was very long, Chizuru Ueno even ordered a cake and said, &quot;If we meet, we can eat it together.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingqingzi felt that Ueno was a very candid scholar. Although she said that she did not want to expose her personal side, she was still very willing to expose herself when the conversation was enjoyable. After getting to know each other through interviews, Qingqingzi and Ueno maintained email communication like friends. &quot;Ueno really likes to communicate with people from the bottom of his heart.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, just a few days after Chizuru Ueno’s discussion about being single and getting married became a hot search topic on Weibo, the Japanese media “Shukan Bunshun” published an article titled “Chizuru Ueno, the founder of single education, naturalizes” The article &quot;Marriage&quot; broke the news that Chizuru Ueno and the late historian Shirkawa Daiyoshi had registered their marriage. Some people began to question Chizuru Ueno, believing that her words and deeds were inconsistent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than 20 days later, Chizuru Ueno responded by publishing the article &quot;The 15-Hour Bride&quot; in the &quot;Woman Public Theory&quot; magazine to clarify the cause and effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seikawa is 23 years older than Ueno. His wife has passed away and his son has lost contact with her. Ueno has taken on the responsibility of taking care of Seikawa and helping him manage his assets. This relationship is exactly what Ueno wants to study about pension issues in his later years. Through practice, she hopes to establish an effective mutual-help relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, because Ueno is legally not related to Shikawa, he cannot sign the consent form for the operation at the critical moment, nor can he help him handle complex property matters. He is subject to Japanese family law. In order to facilitate the process, Various problems before and after Sechuan&#39;s death forced her to apply for marriage. Their marriage only lasted 15 hours before Sechuan passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I didn&#39;t intend to hide this, but there was no reason to disclose it in the first place. Everyone who knows already knows, and my friends are not the kind to sell their friends&#39; privacy. Villain. But if there are outsiders spreading some false rumors, it would be better for me, the person involved, to tell these stories to everyone personally, so I wrote this article.&quot; At the end of the article, Chizuru Ueno wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, Chizuru Ueno&#39;s new book &quot;Marry Me&quot; was published. In this book, she analyzed in detail her views on issues such as marriage and childbirth. On the cover of this new book, there is this sentence written: &quot;Towards a society where you can freely choose whether to marry, get married, or have children!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It is no longer impossible to live without marriage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Can you briefly introduce the background of your writing &quot;Marry Me&quot; and what kind of opportunity it was for you to write it? Have you decided to talk specifically about the issue of being single and not getting married? I&#39;m also curious, has there been any change in Japan&#39;s unmarried group since this book was first published? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Among the female population of the same age, I belong to the less than 5% of unmarried people. Japan&#39;s lifelong non-marriage rate has continued to rise. By 2020, the non-marriage rate for men was 28.25% and for women was 18.81%. The government calls this statistic &quot;never-married.&quot; But I call it &quot;not married&quot;. Because &quot;unmarried&quot; means &quot;not yet married&quot;, implying that &quot;sooner or later you will get married.&quot; However, since there are so many people who are not married, it means that &quot;not getting married&quot; is not a stage of life, but a way of life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether you get married or not, you have children, you don’t have children, you get divorced... There are more choices, which is a good thing. Rather than saying that this book had an impact on society, it is better to say that changes in society created needs that prompted the publication of this book. Because before this, those unmarried men and women have always suffered discrimination and were always asked &quot;Why don&#39;t you get married?&quot; This book aims to encourage those unmarried people to live an upright life, so I chose &quot;Not Married, Again&quot; how? &quot;(Editor&#39;s note: the original title of the Japanese version of &quot;Marry Me&quot;) is the title of the book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The marriage rate in Japan is also getting lower and lower. Do you think that behind the scenes? What is the reason? Are there different reasons why men choose not to marry and why women choose not to marry? If this continues, people&#39;s understanding of marriage will inevitably change. Do you think we have reached such a point now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Not only because marriage is no longer an attractive option, but also because I want to start a family. The cost is simply too high. That&#39;s why the number of men and women who don&#39;t get married will increase. Men and women show an asymmetry in their reasons for choosing not to marry. Men cannot get married, and women do not want to get married. In the past, marriage was a necessity of life for both men and women, and it was impossible to live without marriage. But in today&#39;s Japan, marriage is a &quot;life surplus asset&quot; that makes life richer. People&#39;s expectations for their spouses have also increased a lot compared to the past. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You once said, &quot;Compared to not getting married, I I want to know more about the reasons for getting married.&quot; How do you understand women who enter into marriage? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Having sex because we are in love, having children and becoming parents out of our own will, this experience can make us Life is more abundant. However, many men and women get married and have children when they reach a certain age just for reasons such as obeying traditional customs, &quot;because of parents&#39; requirements&quot;, &quot;because of society&#39;s requirements&quot;. If they have never seen their parents have a happy married life, how can their children be motivated to get married? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If women had more choices, they would not choose to marry against their will. And if their married life is very unhappy, they can also escape from it. For this reason, men must make changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You were also exposed to marriage rumors a while ago, until you later made a statement State the cause and effect of the matter. What impact did this have on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am still opposed to the (Japanese) marriage system. Unfortunately, the barriers to Japanese familialism laws are too thick, so I had no choice but to take advantage of the system to do something. To this day, I still deeply regret it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Marriage will not greatly change a woman’s life, but childbirth will&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When discussing marriage issues, we must also face the issue of fertility. Marriage and childbirth are no longer a must-choose issue in life, but it does not mean that women will no longer be anxious about it. What do you think of this issue? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is no inevitable relationship between marriage and childbirth. However, many people get married for the purpose of having children. Marriage itself will not bring about any major changes in women&#39;s lives, but childbirth will greatly change women&#39;s lives. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Marriage by Me&quot; also discusses unmarried childbirth , compared with the fertility and parenting issues within marriage, what do you think is special about fertility issues outside marriage? In China, some cities have begun to provide policy support for unmarried mothers such as settlement. There is a sentence on the cover of the Chinese version of &quot;Marry Me&quot;: &quot;Towards a society where you can freely choose not to marry, to get married, or to have children!&quot; Is this kind of social form possible? What efforts do people need to make? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many unmarried single mothers mostly do not actively choose not to get married, but after learning the news of pregnancy, they make themselves The pregnant man ran away. However, they did not choose to induce labor, but chose to give birth to the child. The background condition is that he has the support of his parents in his hometown. Of course, there are also some women who actively choose to become unmarried single mothers because they have certain financial strength. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The demand of the Japanese women&#39;s movement is to &quot;establish a society where women can give birth and raise children alone.&quot; However, society still does not provide enough support to single mothers, and even assigns &quot;three, six, or nine&quot; categories to widowed single mothers, divorced single mothers, and unmarried single mothers. Only recently has discrimination between these categories been gradually erased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people believe that policies to support single mothers will encourage men&#39;s &quot;irresponsible&quot; mentality. There is indeed a problem at this level, but the government allocating a certain amount of tax money to support single mothers means that our society has a collective responsibility in raising the next generation, and this collective also includes men who pay more taxes. Some Nordic countries will impose mandatory alimony on the man who got the woman pregnant. If the man is unwilling to pay, the state will advance the payment for him and then hold the man accountable. Japan does not have such a system, which is really a headache. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For many women who are married and have children, they have to work, You have to take on housework; but if you don’t work, you can’t gain so-called “independence.” This seems to be a dilemma of modernity? Do you think there is a solution to this dilemma? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are four ways to share women’s family responsibilities: First, the first point is that men should also assume the same family responsibilities; the second point is that the state should provide public childcare services (such as providing nurseries, etc.) to reduce the childcare burden of citizens; the third point is to use the income earned by both parties from working together to hire someone to do housework; the fourth point is, Relying on the power of (maternal) grandmothers, but this approach simply shifts the responsibility from one generation of women to another. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, none of the above four methods exist. This is exactly why Japanese women are in so much pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Human beings are fragile&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; Your research not only focuses on history, but also radiates to the present, including but not limited to issues such as sexual violence in war, individual sex and love, the situation of housewives, and care for the elderly. I am very curious about the source of your awareness of these issues. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;All my research is based on my own experience. When I was young, I was interested in topics such as &quot;sex&quot; and &quot;love&quot;. As I got older, I began to care about topics such as &quot;old age&quot; and &quot;caregiving&quot;. I also met and talked to many women who were leading different lives. I have experience living in Germany. Both Japan and Germany were defeated countries in World War II, but what kind of relationships did they establish with their surrounding countries after the war? I was struck by the obvious difference between Germany and Japan on this point. To this day, Japan still has not been able to establish full trusting relations with neighboring countries such as South Korea and China, which it has invaded before. For this reason, I feel very sorry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Whether it is women or the elderly, the support for the weak Attention is a focus of your research. What do you think you have always adhered to in your entire research context? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have dealt with many people, and I have deeply understood the truth that human beings are fragile. . Since it is fragile, it should be treated with caution. By thinking this way, we can be tolerant of others and more tolerant of ourselves. This is also the effect of increasing age. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Japan is an aging society, and now in China This question is becoming increasingly important. What are your predictions for the aging East Asian society? What challenges will the elderly face? Now that you yourself have entered the stage of old age, do you have any new understanding of life? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Countries in East Asia are rapidly entering an aging society, and Japan is a developed country with an aging society, so it should be able to use it Just for reference. The long-term care insurance introduced by Japan more than 20 years ago has played a great role in allowing citizens to live with peace of mind in old age. Hopefully we can learn something from it too. For me, growing older is a new experience. If what needs to be protected disappears and there is nothing left to lose, the person will become increasingly free. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You emphasized in the documentary &quot;The Last Lesson&quot; &quot;Feminism is about enabling the weak to survive as the weak&quot;, which reverses many people&#39;s misunderstanding that feminism only focuses on &quot;women&quot; issues. Why does feminism naturally care for and affirm the weak? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No matter how powerful a person is, he is also weak at birth. And one day he will definitely become a weakling. Men are no exception. Women often accompany children, the elderly, the disabled and the sick, so they understand the weak and can imagine their plight. And men just forget these, or just pretend to forget. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You emphasize that this is no longer a matter of hard work. A rewarding society, while emphasizing care for the &quot;weak&quot;, once said, &quot;Please don&#39;t show off your strength, but admit your weaknesses and support each other to live.&quot; Can it be understood that people need to build some kind of community and help each other make society a better place? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;People cannot live alone in the world, and they cannot die alone when they die. Building a community that supports each other to survive is an important matter for everyone, regardless of gender. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are considered to be Japan&#39;s No. 1 &quot;women&#39;s studies&quot; One person, forty years ago, when you established Women’s Studies in Japan, what was the status of women in Japan at that time? After so many years of development, what achievements has Japan’s “women’s studies” research made today? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Forty years ago, there was no such subject for women in Japanese universities. So we, the pioneer generation, learned women’s studies on our own. At that time, some people still ridiculed us, &quot;Is women&#39;s studies a science?&quot; Later, women&#39;s studies entered all professional fields and was established as a discipline, and relevant courses were also offered in universities. It is a pity that Japanese universities have neither “women’s studies departments” nor “women’s studies directions.” Rather than enclosing territory, it is more important to extend gender perspectives across all fields. As a result, we have accumulated theoretical and empirical research on women’s studies and gender studies in many fields, and have trained many researchers. The website &quot;WAN&quot; (https://wan.or.jp/general/corner/papers) we created has collected a list of more than 1,500 dissertations on women&#39;s studies or gender studies over more than 40 years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There is a concept that when it comes to feminism, It seems that it is inevitable to discuss love, marriage and family, and some of your research is also related to this, but is this what feminism is all about? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, it’s because in human society, no group is independent of gender. So when there are women, we use women’s experience as the research object. When there are no women, we study why there are no women. When focusing on men, we study how this characteristic of men is shaped. Therefore, there is no field that gender studies cannot deal with. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Criticism&quot; and &quot;blame&quot; are different&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Marry Me&quot; is a collection of dialogues, and in addition to your serious academic works, you also often have dialogues with people from all walks of life. For example, your previous &quot;Starting at the Limit&quot; caused a lot of discussion in China. What do you think the dialogue means to you? By communicating with people from different generations and backgrounds, what do you want to convey to your readers? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I really like talking to people with different life backgrounds. This can stimulate my curiosity, and during the conversation Sometimes the other person will bring out another side of me that I have never noticed. &quot;Others&quot; are an important catalyst for me to know who I really am. Similarly, when readers read a book in the form of a dialogue, I also hope that they can participate in the dialogue and enjoy the joy and joy of &quot;discovering who they are.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As an academic scholar, you actively Have you ever been questioned because of your involvement in social affairs and your promotion of feminism? Your speech at the opening ceremony of the University of Tokyo in 2019 also had a great response in China. Your speech at the time was very sharp and your criticism of the school was very direct. Why did you deliver such a speech at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The University of Tokyo invited me to attend the entrance ceremony as a guest. Although they asked me to submit the original manuscript of my speech, they did not interfere with the speech at all. content of the manuscript. The content of my speech was all planned out in advance. Because the podium at the entrance ceremony also has a &quot;speaker&quot; effect, I think this is a good opportunity to convey what I have been thinking to a larger audience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After your speech at the University of Tokyo, you became an internet celebrity. &quot;Celebrity&quot; has attracted the attention of intellectual circles in China. Especially in recent years, a large number of your books have been published in China. What do you think of this phenomenon? Why do you think Chinese readers, especially female readers, admire you so much? Do you think it is a good thing that intellectuals have become &quot;popular&quot; due to the Internet? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The goal of feminism is to verbalize and theorize women’s experience. I think it is because the younger generation of women in China have found the language to express their own experiences in my works. One thing that Japan and China have in common is that many girls are carefully raised in a generation with a low birthrate. Under China&#39;s reform and opening up policy, and with the continuous development of marketization, the life experiences of women in the two countries may be getting closer and closer. Moreover, Chinese readers may feel closer to Asian feminism than to feminism in Europe and America. However, I am very much looking forward to seeing the emergence of Chinese-specific feminology and the birth of Chinese feminism. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t think there is anything to worry about when intellectuals become popular people. People who write books naturally hope that more readers will read their works. However, it is a bit distressing to praise or condemn on the Internet without even reading it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;One ​​view is that the status of women in East Asia is compared to that in Europe and the United States. The situation is not ideal. What do you think is the underlying reason? In 2019, you visited and gave lectures in many cities in China. What impression did you leave on Chinese women? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Although they are both East Asian countries, the situations of women in China, Japan, and South Korea are different. Every country has its own unique circumstances. It needs to be studied separately for different societies. Although I have come to Chinese universities to give lectures, I have only met (mostly) elite women from cities who attend mindful universities, and I know nothing about women living in the vast rural areas, so I cannot answer this question. I think this issue needs to be studied by Chinese researchers. My impression of the elite women living in the city is that they are girls who were carefully raised as only children. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have encountered many doubts along the way. How did you respond? Generally speaking, East Asians value &quot;politeness&quot;, but is &quot;quarrel&quot; an effective means for women to fight against injustice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;An argument is not a &quot;quarrel&quot;. I did not take up my position at the University of Tokyo to &quot;teach quarrels.&quot; All kinds of knowledge develop from &quot;dissent&quot;. Women&#39;s studies and gender studies are not afraid of controversy, and to this day and ever since, it has been a field of scholarship that has been hotly debated and thus advanced. &quot;Criticism&quot; is different from &quot;blame&quot;. When facing an object that needs criticism, it is important to present our arguments and criticize the opponent logically and rigorously. I believe that academics are a weapon for the weak. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you feel about your personal influence on social media? various controversies? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chizuru Ueno:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;On social networks, attacks and arguments will be amplified. It is not a place for fair discussion. The world of social networks is not everything, and it’s important to keep your distance from it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“地下偶像”行业解析：一场高性价比的情感体验]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259258]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 21:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Long white ginseng, urala grass, white mountain black water are all treasures! Siberian tiger, sika deer, roe deer, black bear and wild boar!&quot; On the stage, girls wearing puffy skirts and exquisite makeup and hair danced happily to the music; off the stage, the audience followed the rhythm, waved colorful fluorescent sticks, and cheered enthusiastically with slogans with Northeastern characteristics...&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The above scene is from an article called &quot;To promote Northeastern idols, of course you have to use Northeastern dialect to promote them!&quot; ! The video of Changchun underground idol Blossom&#39;s first performance of &quot;Geqie&quot; has been viewed more than 5 million times on station B. In May of this year, the popularity of the video made the term &quot;We also have underground idols in the Northeast&quot; a hot search topic. This was also the first time that the niche culture of &quot;underground idols&quot; appeared on mainstream domestic social platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is an &quot;underground idol&quot;? It originated in Japan and specifically refers to artists or groups that focus on offline performances, usually do not appear on mainstream media such as TV, and have not debuted through a brokerage company. In 2023, with the full resumption of offline performances, &quot;ground puppets&quot; (short for &quot;underground idols&quot;) have gradually entered the lives of young people. More and more fans who love idol groups and singing and dancing performances choose to go to large and small shopping malls, theaters, and live houses on weekends to cheer for their favorite idols. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the &quot;underground idol&quot; industry is quietly emerging and expanding rapidly in China. According to statistics from the @Underground Idol related bulletin board, there are currently about 131 underground idol groups active in China, distributed in 22 provinces, municipalities and special administrative regions across the country, especially in first-tier cities such as Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou (12 in Beijing , Shanghai 21). More than a year ago, in September 2022, the total number of domestic &quot;geido&quot; groups was only about 53. In other words, about half of the &quot;Geo Puppet&quot; groups currently active were formed this year. Because of this, 2023 is also called the &quot;First Year of Ge Puppet&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What unique charm does “underground idol” have? Why did it attract so many fans and rise so quickly this year? How is it different from the traditional idol industry? As an imported culture, what challenges does its localization development in China face? Focusing on these questions, our reporters recently visited relevant fans, operators and new underground idols to help everyone learn more about the slightly new concept of &quot;ground puppets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/046339fad3ec9f1b89ea0efa4819e3c0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;373&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/046339fad3ec9f1b89ea0efa4819e3c0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255294&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What is an “underground idol”? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;All open-mic singing and dancing on the stage, immersive interaction off the stage, and &quot;special talks&quot; at close range&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This year One weekend in the spring, Xiao Zhang (pseudonym) went to watch an &quot;underground idol&quot; offline performance for the first time, and from then on, he &quot;entered the trap&quot; and started chasing &quot;underground idols&quot;. Before that, she had only heard of the term &quot;underground idol&quot;. By chance, she saw the activity information of &quot;Geo Puppet&quot; on social platforms and learned that its performance included Japanese songs that she usually liked to listen to. She became interested and went to the venue with her friends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Very energetic, full of real singing, and highly infectious.” This is Xiaozhang’s biggest feeling after watching the performance of “Earth Puppet” for the first time. &quot;I feel very happy!&quot; Xiao Zhang felt the sincerity and hard work of the performers, and at the same time, she became a fan of one of the young idols. &quot;I feel that her style is more special and eye-catching.&quot; She recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Xiao Zhang was deeply impressed by the way the audience supported him that day: &quot;A group of people would pick up an audience member and rush from the back of the auditorium to the front of the stage to interact with the little idol.&quot; The enthusiastic support scene shocked him deeply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high degree of interaction and various interesting ways of supporting have also become a unique charm of underground idol performances, making the audience and fans feel that they are an indispensable part of the performance. Another &quot;Diido&quot; fan Xiaojie (pseudonym) told reporters: &quot;Underground idols make people feel more involved, or closer (to the idols) and more interactive (with the idols). They There are many people dancing on the stage and off the stage, and the atmosphere is even better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10 /25/6c019e1a06776ae7a95f3dfd96a5e51a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;856&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/25/6c019e1a06776ae7a95f3dfd96a5e51a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there are also noisy &quot;social cows&quot; groups among the audience of &quot;Land Puppet&quot;. Xiao Zhang mentioned that the organizer of that performance set up zones for the audience, including &quot;quiet viewing area&quot;, &quot;free area&quot; and &quot;female area&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the &quot;Free Zone&quot;, fans will support and interact enthusiastically, such as the &quot;take-off&quot; mentioned just now - lifting the audience up and &quot;flying&quot; to the stage; &quot;Quiet Viewing Zone&quot; &quot; is prepared for the introverted &quot;i people&quot; group. They don&#39;t need to do anything, and just want to enjoy the idol&#39;s performance silently in the audience. Xiao Zhang chose to stay in the &quot;female area&quot;, and this part of the audience will wave light sticks in honor of their idols. Calling, but not nearly as intense as &quot;Free Zone&quot;. The setting of partitioned viewing ensures that audiences with different personalities can be immersed in the performance and avoid mutual interference and collision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the performance, Xiao Zhang had his first photo with his idol at the following &quot;special event&quot;. &quot;Special Bonus&quot; is an event held together with the performances of underground idol groups. Fans can purchase idol-related peripheral products at the &quot;Special Bonus&quot; and purchase &quot;Special Vouchers&quot; to take photos and communicate with their idols up close. Chance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/14549802ae615da467c2d59460e18ef7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;421&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/14549802ae615da467c2d59460e18ef7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255299&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Xiaozhang told reporters that the organizers of underground idol performances regularly invite various underground idol groups to perform assorted performances. The ticket prices for the performances range from tens to 200 yuan depending on the size of the event (occasionally there are free performances) , the box office revenue belongs to the show organizer. The income of idol group companies and members mainly depends on fans&#39; consumption at &quot;special events&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She told reporters that fans of &quot;Geo Doll&quot; call taking Polaroid photos with their idols &quot;Paikiri&quot; (translated from the Japanese transliteration of Polaroid), and idols will also &quot;cut&quot; Leave your own signature graffiti on (photo). The average price of a &quot;che&quot; with an idol&#39;s signature graffiti is about 80-100 yuan; the average price of a &quot;che&quot; without a signature graffiti is about 40-60 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Purchasing a &quot;special coupon&quot; will not only give you the opportunity to take a Polaroid photo with your idol, but also means that fans will have the opportunity to chat with their idol up close for about a minute, so the special coupon will be Also known as &quot;Qiaochanghui&quot; (shooting + chatting). Xiaozhang told reporters that while fans are communicating with their idols, there will be staff standing by to count the time. Many fans will buy a dozen or even dozens of special coupons at one time in order to gain more time with their idols. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why do we need “underground idols”? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Emotional value, high cost performance, two-way travel&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When talking about the reasons for &quot;falling into the trap&quot;, Xiaozhang emphasized that &quot;all The importance of &quot;real singing&quot; and &quot;stage appeal&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before, she also went to watch offline performances of some &quot;above ground&quot; idol groups (contrary to &quot;underground&quot;, idol artists who will be exposed in mainstream media). In order to ensure the quality of the performance, the audience rarely gets to see the full stage of singing and dancing. &quot;In comparison, &#39;Dippo&#39; has better stage appeal, and singing on the mic is really important.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/25/db78036bddb3d20628f09a8334734652.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/25/db78036bddb3d20628f09a8334734652.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255296&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through the stage of underground idols, Xiao Zhang can feel that these young idols are coming from their own hearts. I love singing and dancing at heart. &quot;Seeing this person working hard for his beloved dream and shining on the stage makes me feel inspired.&quot; Perhaps many people have had an &quot;idol dream&quot; in their hearts, but they were unable to realize it due to various reasons. &quot;Seeing them When you work hard, you feel good, and you feel that you have to work harder (to live a good life).&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the singing and dancing levels of underground idols vary, some members have made great progress. There is no space, but in the eyes of fans such as Xiao Zhang, daring to open the microphone and sing for real is an attitude worthy of recognition, &quot;At least they work hard to show themselves on stage. And I think she (Xiao Zhang&#39;s idol) has the talent to sing.&quot; Progress can be clearly felt.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with reporters, fan Xiaojie attributed the essence of chasing stars to &quot;obtaining emotional value&quot;: &quot;The purpose of chasing idols is not to say that our aesthetics have How high it is depends on how strong their singing and dancing skills are. They are just chasing an emotional value. Watching idols will make our lives more interesting and make every weekend more fulfilling. When we are so tired from work, we have to think of something to support us. Go down.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/e0574545470994e52f13ffa9b3659f74.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;434&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/e0574545470994e52f13ffa9b3659f74.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255297&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the conversation with reporters, the two fans unanimously mentioned that compared to those mainstream idols who are active in the public eye, chasing &quot;land idols&quot; has a higher cost-effectiveness and allows them to be in the public eye. Get more emotional value with the same effort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the &quot;above ground&quot; idol group SNH48 also uses &quot;face-to-face idols&quot; as its operating model, with theater performances and &quot;handshake meetings&quot; similar to &quot;special parties&quot;, but its prices are much higher than those of the &quot;ground&quot; idol group. I&quot;. Ticket prices, originally priced at only 98 yuan, have been skyrocketed, and tickets for popular events cost tens to hundreds of yuan. If you want a VIP position such as the first row, you need to bid, which can easily cost thousands of yuan. A handshake ticket (which allows you to shake hands and chat with a young idol for 10 seconds) costs 20 to 30 yuan, an autograph ticket costs 100 to 200 yuan, and a photo ticket costs 600 to 700 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, when &quot;Geo Puppet&quot; provides services such as photos, autographs, and face-to-face communication, fans can gain a richer emotional experience at less cost. After all, the number of fans that &quot;ground puppets&quot; have is far less than that of celebrity artists. Most of them have clear impressions of their followers. They will remember almost every fan&#39;s appearance, preferences, topics of communication and other details. There are also many more. Respond with energy and emotion to achieve a true &quot;two-way rush&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/e2ed8f51cdc6b930124e9867fa606f9c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;407&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/e2ed8f51cdc6b930124e9867fa606f9c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255298&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Xiaojie shared with reporters that she once received a fan benefit when she purchased a certain number of &quot;special coupons&quot; - asking her idol to write a letter to her. &quot;Because I wrote her a letter before, she wrote a reply.&quot; In that letter to her idol, Xiaojie mentioned how happy she felt every time she went to watch her idol&#39;s performance, and these contents It was also mentioned one by one by the idol in the reply letter, &quot;She told me (written in the reply letter) that actually when she received my letter, she was very unsure and confused. She said it was mine. That letter gave her a lot of strength.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the idol also expressed her persistence and love for this career and her years of pursuing her dream. &quot;She said that every time she stood on the stage Every time she went on stage, she would feel a sense of tingling excitement. She had very few fans before, and she thought about whether to continue, and was confused for a long time... But in the end she figured it out, as long as she enjoys standing on the stage It’ll be great when you get on.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaojie mentioned that compared to mainstream celebrity artists, the feeling of “Chasing the Earth Puppet” is more pure. Since underground idols are not exposed in the media, the state of being close to amateurs will be more real and relaxed. Without the constraints of the company, the packaging of personality, and the scrutiny of the public, fans can feel &quot;the intimacy like friends&quot; when communicating with idols. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Who is becoming an “underground idol”? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Liu Xiajun: &quot;After becoming an underground idol, I clearly know who is supporting me.&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Have participated in &quot;Creation&quot; Liu Hajun, the singing and dancing idol of &quot;Camp 2019&quot;, experienced &quot;from the ground to the underground&quot; this year and became the captain of the men&#39;s &quot;ground puppet&quot; group &quot;Brick Paw Team&quot;, thus having the opportunity to go on stage again and have close contact with fans. Opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c7291f74ef43b361586608e4792f9681.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;402&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c7291f74ef43b361586608e4792f9681.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255300&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Liu Xiajun (middle)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Xiajun told reporters that since &quot;Produce Camp 2019&quot;, he has rarely been on stage again Opportunity to sing and dance on stage. At first, he was an artist of his former company doing various interviews and filming work. Later, due to the epidemic, the company was disbanded and reorganized, and his work content became live broadcasting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But soon, he was not used to live broadcasts and realized that what he really wanted to do was sing and dance on stage, so he terminated his contract with the company and once again turned his identity into a dance troupe member and dance teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of this year, a friend of Liu Xiajun learned that a men&#39;s &quot;ground puppet&quot; group was recruiting members, and immediately recommended Liu Xiajun to sign up. &quot;He said that when he saw the registration requirements, he felt that it was tailor-made for me - &#39;good at singing and dancing, and loves the stage.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this, Liu Xiajun began to gradually understand the &quot;ground puppets&quot; &quot;This profession. &quot;The most attractive thing about this thing is that I can go on stage.&quot; After searching for information and watching offline, his love and yearning for the stage defeated all hesitations and concerns, and he finally decided to give it a try. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, Liu Xiajun has become the captain of the first men&#39;s &quot;ground puppet&quot; group in China, the &quot;Brick-moving Barking Team&quot;. The group has a total of six members, including students and 9-to-5 workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Xiajun revealed that the team&#39;s rehearsal time is usually set after nine o&#39;clock in the evening, and everyone works hard to get along with each other. &quot;As for the stage, I still demand myself according to the requirements of the past (during the Creation Camp), even better than before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 27, the &quot;Brick-Moving Wangwang Team&quot; successfully ushered in First performance. Liu Xiajun still clearly remembers that many fans who have liked him since the broadcast of &quot;Produce Camp 2019&quot; came to the scene to support him, which moved him very much: &quot;Many fans from 4 years ago still support me now. , has been with me for a long time. At that moment, I really felt that I did the right thing and did not let them down.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a former &quot;above ground idol&quot;, in the process of turning to the &quot;underground&quot; , Liu Xiajun is also slowly adapting to his new identity and constantly learning new skills, such as how to communicate closely with fans at the &quot;special party&quot; after the performance, what topics should he talk to everyone; when there are fans How to communicate with them when talking about life troubles; what patterns should be drawn when signing and graffiti on &quot;Che&quot; (photos)...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/25/120132533396b7f88e39091203bc3585.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/120132533396b7f88e39091203bc3585.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255301&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in Liu Xiajun&#39;s view, being a &quot;land puppet&quot; is more unique The advantage is that he can receive more intuitive, specific and immediate feedback from fans. The relationship between idols and fans has changed from one-way output to two-way interaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When I participated in &quot;Creation Camp&quot;, I knew that some people liked me, but &#39;fans&#39; were more like a concept with a certain sense of distance. But when I was an underground idol, I was able to I know very clearly who is supporting me, her nickname, image, and even her emotions and her story. I can know why everyone likes me and what is not good about my performance today.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When asked &quot;What kind of person is suitable to be a puppet&quot;, Liu Xiajun also mentioned the word &quot;emotional value&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I think to be an underground idol, you must be a very sincere person. You must love this job, respect this job, and sincerely face all the people who support you. Your singing and dancing skills can continue Growth, but attitude is the most important.&quot; He talked about his understanding of the profession of &quot;idol&quot;, &quot;The duty of an idol is to make fans happy, to bring good energy to fans, (to provide them with) &#39;emotional value&#39; &#39;For an idol, it is greater than anything else.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What is the future of &quot;underground idols&quot;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Conversation with performance operators &amp;amp; group producers&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to artists with stage experience like Liu Xiajun, there are also a large number of people who love singing Amateur stage dancers have joined the &quot;ground puppet&quot; industry in recent years. However, it should be noted that as a new industry, underground idols have not yet reached a mature stage. Many relevant reports have mentioned that the income of most underground idols is not considerable, and most of them work part-time to &quot;generate money for love.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Xiajun revealed to reporters that he never regarded &quot;ground puppets&quot; as a way to make money from the beginning. &quot;In fact (now) most of his income still comes from being a dance teacher and performing in a dance troupe. Underground The job of an idol is more out of love.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Xiajun, who has a certain fan base, cannot support himself just by being a &quot;land puppet&quot;, let alone those who need to accumulate popularity from scratch. Amateur idol. Although more and more people are joining in, with the current audience size, &quot;ground puppet&quot; has not yet developed into a stable career that can make a living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Liu (pseudonym), who started hosting &quot;ground puppet&quot; performances in 2021, told reporters that he has always treated the &quot;ground puppet&quot; group as real commercial entertainers. If they are invited to participate in the platter, If they perform, their travel expenses will be reimbursed to ensure that the groups that come to perform do not lose money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;We will share some of the commission for the &#39;special event&#39;, but we will ensure that you will have a certain amount of income as long as you come.&quot; Xiao Liu revealed that this method of operation is different from most situations in the industry. &quot;Other performances The organizers basically ask you to bear the performance costs yourself, but basically most people (the income from the special events) cannot afford their own travel expenses, so it is easy to lose money as a group, and it will also cause a very high income (for the puppets). Unstable.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/a17d7695c9f01ab1fb67614e8a3d3049.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;636&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/a17d7695c9f01ab1fb67614e8a3d3049.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255302 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is more worrying than the meager income is the chaos in the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting this year, in addition to hosting platter performances, Xiao Liu has also begun to create and operate a new &quot;ground puppet&quot; group. Talking about his original intention to join a group, Xiao Liu mentioned that he has seen some bad phenomena in the industry in recent years and hopes to do his best to improve the current situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We feel that there are many children, who may be minors or just adults, as well as freshly graduated college students. They are completely unaware of the sinister side of society and will be deceived and work for others for nothing. The share received is very small.&quot; Xiao Liu also revealed that some companies will even pocket the travel subsidies provided by the event organizers, &quot;asking the organizers to reimburse hotel expenses and actually allowing members to stay in youth hostels.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Liu It is hoped that through the production team, we can find &quot;Earth Puppet&quot; members with real potential, and at the same time, we can provide them with relatively better treatment and protect their living foundation. &quot;We will reimburse them for all travel expenses for performances, including daily rehearsals, costumes, songwriting, etc., all of which will be borne by us, and the income share we give them will be higher than the general level in the industry.&quot; Xiao Liu told reporters, At present, in addition to &quot;land puppets&quot;, he is also engaged in other businesses, and the related income also supports him to continue to be an underground idol. &quot;Because we are not making money from this (land puppets), so as long as we don&#39;t pay particularly hard, , we can do it.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As an imported culture, underground idols still face the test of localization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fan Zhang mentioned in an interview that the current performances of many &quot;ground puppet&quot; groups are still mainly covering songs of Japanese underground idols. Even if they are original songs, many of them are in Japanese. . &quot;There are definitely copyright issues (for performance covers), but it may be because it is difficult for (foreign copyright holders) to come to China to trace back.&quot; Xiao Liu told reporters that his group is also preparing original songs with Chinese lyrics to enrich the performance. content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the localization of performance content, the &quot;ground puppet&quot; industry still faces many problems in its rapid development and expansion, such as the diversification of audiences. Xiao Liu mentioned in an interview that a large part of the current domestic audience for &quot;geol&quot; people have &quot;climbed over the wall&quot; from other cultural circles. Their aesthetic orientations and star-chasing habits are diverse. What should we do? Compatible coexistence? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For another example, he knows that this industry needs relevant treaties to regulate it, but he also bluntly said: &quot;It itself is an &#39;underground culture&#39;. If there is too much intervention in the &#39;above ground&#39; way, there may be no It’s the kind of freedom that everyone loves.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While many fans like Xiaozhang &quot;hope that more people can understand and accept this niche culture&quot;, many people also raise questions and concerns about promoting &quot;Earth Puppets&quot; out of the circle. , to some extent it seems to be contrary to the essence of &quot;Earth Puppet&quot;...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although everything is still being explored, we need to gradually improve it to achieve a certain balance. But what is worthy of recognition is that the &quot;underground idols&quot; that are growing freely and expanding rapidly have provided a new opportunity and possibility for the idol industry that has been in the cold at the moment when domestic entertainment talent shows are suspended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It allows us to see that &quot;star chasing&quot; is not only fans&#39; admiration and following of idols, and the construction and imagination of intimate relationships, but also two-way, equal, and co-creation. Clear business rules and a close interactive experience allow idols who enjoy the stage to see clearly the faces of everyone in the audience, allowing fans to receive real and concrete responses to their efforts. In the world of &quot;underground idols&quot;, &quot;going both ways&quot; is easier to cash in on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 21:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[邱礼涛：香港电影打工人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259250]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After the movie &quot;Moscow Operation&quot; entered preparations, at the internal meeting of Chinese Film Industry, whenever the director&#39;s Ideal candidate, many people will ask, is it possible to find Director Qiu? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film is based on the &quot;China-Russia Train Robbery&quot; in 1993. It combines real historical cases in China with commercial elements. Successful precedents include &quot;Operation Mekong&quot; and &quot;Operation Red Sea&quot;. &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; has a strong pursuit of film industrialization. It took more than half a year to restore many real scenes in Russia at that time, and presented the underground cistern, the Sino-Russian train rail-changing station, and the rocket base 1:1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Producer Gui Youming said that the production team had just watched &quot;Bomb Disposal Expert 2&quot; not long ago and liked the film very much. &quot;It seemed to be somewhat similar to what we wanted.&quot; If it were placed in the 1980s, this candidate might be John Woo or McDonald&#39;s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, (co-producer) Andy Lau helped hand over the script, and Qiu Litao made a decision quickly after reading it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since entering the Hong Kong film industry in the 1980s, Qiu Litao has served as a photographer, editor, screenwriter, and director on the set, covering almost all types of work. He is extremely prolific and has directed nearly 80 films, spanning action films, police films, crime films, horror films, comedies, romance films, etc. At the same time, as a photographer, he has often become a &quot;firefighter&quot; for other Hong Kong directors. Team members&quot; and have an excellent reputation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, including &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; released on National Day, four films including &quot;Anti-Drug 3&quot;, &quot;Jedi&#39;s Pursuit&quot; and &quot;Assassination Storm&quot; filmed by Qiu Litao were released in mainland China, and several films have been filmed. Completed and waiting for release. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hong Kong films are lonely, but Qiu Litao has many film appointments. In 2019, &quot;Anti-Drug 2&quot; and &quot;Bomb Disposer 2&quot; in 2020 both achieved box office of more than 1.3 billion yuan, which was a rare box office performance for Hong Kong films in recent years. &quot;Bomb Disposaler 2&quot; was even more popular that year. ’s market rescue work, ranked among the ten Chinese-language films with the highest ratings on Douban in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao was once regarded as the mainstay of the revival of Hong Kong films - he experienced rigorous training and shaping in the golden age of the Hong Kong film industry system, and always insisted on a high frequency of filming during the trough period of the industry. To this day, it can still bring &quot;the most authentic Hong Kong films&quot; to audiences. However, in the summer of 2023, the box office results of Qiu Litao&#39;s three films were not satisfactory. &quot;Jedi&quot; cost 100 million yuan, but the box office was less than 30 million yuan, which attracted criticism from him as a &quot;bad film&quot; and &quot;a professional director&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting with Director Qiu Litao will be at the end of September 2023. In a small suite at a hotel near Dawang Road in Beijing, Qiu Litao had long hair and wore a black jacket. Unlike usual, he didn&#39;t wear a T-shirt with rock elements. The video shooting equipment was set up for a long time. Qiu Litao, who is a videographer, did not come forward to help, but rested against the window. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the interview, he had a loud voice, a smile and answered all questions. When he heard a Mandarin word he didn&#39;t understand, he pointed to the notebook in front of the reporter and said, &quot;Write it for me.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Fi95Cw8gIzFhHf8WqseP9Fp9EN2whwQpmotkgBQa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/Fi95Cw8gIzFhHf8WqseP9Fp9EN2whwQpmotkgBQa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255316&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the end of September 2023, Qiu Litao was interviewed by a Southern Weekend reporter in Beijing. He said that he &quot;wanted to film Oppenheimer&#39;s story ten years ago&quot; and also wanted to film Shaw. The story of Takovich and Aung San Suu Kyi. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by Pumpkin Vision)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao told Southern Weekend reporters that &quot;Anti-Drug 2&quot; and &quot;Bomb Disposal Expert 2&quot; After the success of &quot;The Movie&quot;, the number of people looking for him to make films was actually as high as before. Even when Hong Kong&#39;s film scene was in dire straits, people were still looking for him to film. &quot;When it comes to quantity, it used to be a little less, but it&#39;s still quite a lot. Not a lot means I can&#39;t finish them all, and I still have some to recommend. But in the past few years, the ones I&#39;ve been approached to shoot are all big productions, and here&#39;s the difference.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Superman&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Gui Youming and Qiu Litao first met in Xishuangbanna. At that time, he and screenwriter Chen Daming went there with the script of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. Qiu Litao, who was still filming another film, had already done his homework in advance. He took a notebook and talked about his ideas one by one. The main opinion was to reduce the script . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Sino-Russian train robbery in 1993 caused a sensation. After the collapse of the Soviet Union, the K3 train, which was responsible for economic exchanges between China and Russia, carried countless &quot;transnational villains&quot;, and robberies and rapes occurred frequently. Screenwriter Chen Daming has personally experienced that period of history, and remembers that all the talk in the phone booth at that time was about reselling color TVs and jeeps. In 1992, he spent six months in Moscow and saw an old man wearing a Soviet Patriotic War medal begging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao hopes to restore the people and style of that era. The policemen and robbers in the movie are all people who have left their hometowns. For a long time, he has wanted to film the subject of Chinese people wandering abroad. For example, the workers who came to North America and Malaysia back then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/u4MErr0xLRjh1yKi9hfAxF515WvyRbCtGwP3fesB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/u4MErr0xLRjh1yKi9hfAxF515WvyRbCtGwP3fesB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255318&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The era when the Sino-Russian train robbery occurred and the story of Chinese people living overseas attracted Qiu Litao to direct the film &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the filming of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, Gui Youming experienced the efficiency of Qiu Litao&#39;s team up close. If the start time is 8:30 in the morning, his car usually arrives at 8:15. “As soon as he gets out of the car, Jason (executive director Wen Zhenwei) runs up to him and tells him that the director has arranged this like this and that. &quot;Start the first shot at 8:30 on time, &quot;then shoot, shoot, shoot&quot;, and half an hour after lunch, &quot;continue to shoot, shoot, shoot&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the new crown epidemic is still spreading. Gui Youming remembered that Qiu Litao had never been infected with the new coronavirus and only had a cold. From July to early October, I had six days off and one day off. I basically worked 14 hours a day on the set, which was &quot;completely superhuman.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Film researcher and film critic Kai Yin is a fan of Qiu Litao. In the early summer of 2021, he visited the crew of &quot;Jedi&quot; in Xishuangbanna, Yunnan. What impressed Kaiyin deeply was that Qiu Litao did not drink alcohol. Even when producers and investors came, he only drank plain water. After dinner, he left the table and said he would be filming the next day. &quot;I can&#39;t imagine how he interacts with people... He doesn&#39;t make people feel awkward. People think he&#39;s quite amiable and are willing to invest money in making movies for him. He definitely has some of his own qualities in social interactions or how he behaves with others. A more interesting technique.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Director Qiu, I can speak on his behalf: &#39;Sorry, I don&#39;t drink when filming, okay? Of course it&#39;s not that I don&#39;t like drinking, it&#39;s just that I don&#39;t drink when filming. , OK?&#39;&quot; Gui Youming explained to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Director Qiu said this very sincerely, and everyone is OK.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Gui Youming&#39;s view, another director and team need Qiu Litao may only need 99 days to complete a task that takes 150 days. He has made nearly a hundred movies, &quot;horror movies, action movies, literary dramas, everything.&quot; In addition, he is a photographer, so he knows the placement of the camera and the cooperation of the team, and rarely needs to stop on the scene. Come to think of it, there are very few retakes and retakes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is an opera scene with strong dramatic conflict in &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, involving complex camera scheduling. There were more than 70 people playing a symphony on the stage, and there were more than 700 extras off the stage. The actors were walking around among them, but Qiu Litao managed every shot in just two or three takes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I asked the director if he wanted to take a few more shots. He said no, yes. It will be very good when it is edited in the future, and there will be no waste.&quot; Gui Youming said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We don’t have to worry about whether the things we shoot are useful or useless. If you worry every day that the task is not completed, or too much money is spent, or the money spent does not match the output at all, then Is there any room to make things better?&quot; Gui Youming explained that this is why many investors believe that working with Qiu Litao will be much less stressful. &quot;Every penny spent will definitely be shown on the screen, no Any possibility of paying tuition fees”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Xishuangbanna site, Kaiyin felt Qiu Litao&#39;s efficient dispatching ability. The latter often has several things running in the brain at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, when I was shooting this scene, I was thinking about the special effects on the mountain over there and how to move the car in the next scene. In one scene, a gun battle scene involving police and gangsters was being filmed 30 to 40 meters in front of him. At the same time, he was experimenting with the water flow rate and water release position for another scene in which a flood rushed down from a mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whenever the gunfight scene ahead shouted &quot;cut&quot;, Qiu Litao in the tent would open the curtain, use a walkie-talkie to instruct the staff on the mountain to release water, test the effect, and wait until the lighting of the front camera was adjusted. , he closed the tent and filmed the next scene, racing against time. In the afternoon, the position of the water was adjusted, and the camera immediately moved over to take this shot. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Fight for Life&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From 1981 to 1984, Qiu Litao studied film at the School of Communication at Hong Kong Baptist University. He first studied journalism because he was influenced by &quot;All the President&#39;s Men&quot; (a classic film adapted from the autobiography of the Watergate whistleblower in Hong Kong translation) and wanted to become an investigative reporter. The following year, he was influenced by his teacher and switched to film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In that era, students all yearned to intern at Radio Television Hong Kong before graduation. Because the TV program &quot;Under the Lion Rock&quot; produced by the Television Department of RTHK (directed by Maggie Cheung, Ann Hui, etc.) is the dream work of every film student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao also went to Radio Television Hong Kong for an interview, but was unsuccessful. He went to work as an assistant director at Asia Television arranged by the school. After one day of work, he was told not to come. Qiu Litao suffered from polio when he was a child and had difficulty moving. Later he learned that this was a &quot;kind intention&quot; from the TV station to understand him. After several teachers recommended him, he was able to continue working. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If your ability to intern for three months is doubted due to your physical condition, you will have to risk your life to enter the film industry in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After entering the industry, Qiu Litao worked as a photography assistant, and later became the photographer of director Huang Tailai. &quot;When the Hong Kong film industry took off in the 1960s, a studio apprenticeship system was formed.&quot; Kai Yin told a Southern Weekend reporter. As shown in the documentary &quot;Dragon and Tiger Warriors&quot;, in the golden age of Hong Kong movies where action scenes dominated, a large number of martial arts practitioners came from poor backgrounds and had no chance to study. They relied on physical strength and blood and sweat to maintain the operation of &quot;Oriental Hollywood&quot;. Qiu Litao was one of the few college students in the industry at that time, but he quickly put in intense labor to prove himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was a photographer in the 1980s, Qiu Litao tried to move a lamp up a hillside. If it was 2.5K, the person asking would ask if it was enough light, and not have to change it later. If you move a 4K one, they may say that 4K is so heavy, so a 2.5K one is just fine, and you have to toss it back and forth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day he met Southern Weekend reporters, Qiu Litao walked with a huge stride. This may be a habit formed over the years. Kaiyin explained that in the film era, a 35mm film box itself weighed several kilograms. Photographers often carried more than ten kilograms while exercising, and their hands could not shake. &quot; It&#39;s hard for me to imagine how he did this... He must have worked harder than others.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhongzhi, the action director of &quot;Moscow Operation&quot;, was born in a family and is a famous action director in Hong Kong. He has won the Hong Kong Film Awards and the Taiwan Film Golden Horse Award for Best Action Design many times. He and Qiu Litao met on the set in the 1980s. One is a martial artist and the other is a photography director. In his words, Qiu Litao is &quot;a person who can walk faster than a person with convenient legs and feet.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that after 2000, Qiu Litao once filmed in the Himalayas, &quot;The air in that place was very thin, and you couldn&#39;t walk fast. You would run out of air very quickly. But after shooting a scene, , I saw him running alone in the snow, and immediately after the next shot, he started walking down again.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is also what the times Qiu Litao experienced shaped him. At its peak, the annual output of Hong Kong films exceeded 200. American scholar David Bordwell described in &quot;The Secret of Hong Kong Film&quot; that this city of six million people has one of the largest film kingdoms in the world, &quot;exporting The number of movies is second only to the United States.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the high-speed development period of the Hong Kong film industry from the 1980s to the first half of the 1990s, participants had a huge workload. In a recent interview, Qiu Litao said that he could go without sleep for three days, just make up for the 15 minutes between meals every day, and survive the 10 minutes after waking up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I think the training Qiu Litao received in the 1980s is very important, and he knows better than others that if you want to be on the rise in such a special film environment, you can only do better. Efficiency matters. So his reputation since he started as a photographer in the late 1980s is that he is good at efficiency, and he can do it once and never twice,&quot; Kaiyin explained. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Limited talent&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Before officially entering the industry, Qiu Litao longed for films such as &quot;Yellow Earth&quot; and &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, but he quickly understood the environment in Hong Kong at that time. are not allowed. Kaiyin described that the prevailing industry atmosphere at that time was not about pursuing artistic quality and ideological expression. &quot;Commercial movies are just a commercial product.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of the 1990s, affected by multiple factors such as the Asian financial crisis, the prevalence of piracy, and the impact of Hollywood, Hong Kong movies began to decline. After filming the &quot;Yin Yang Road&quot; series, Qiu Litao went through a period of psychological depression. He explained to Southern Weekend reporters that this is like in the mainland film and television industry, if a certain type of subject matter - such as ancient costumes and time travel - cannot be started for a period of time, then these practitioners will face tension and uneasiness - he is worried that there will be no more movies. Can be photographed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trough of the industry, Qiu Litao completed a film with authorial expression. At that time, the audience was already bored with traditional action and martial arts-themed movies. In the 1990s, as a producer, Lee Soo-hyun developed the Strange Case series of bloody third-level movies at a lower cost. In 1993, Qiu Litao&#39;s masterpiece &quot;Eight Immortals Restaurant: Human Meat Barbecued Pork Buns&quot; was released. This film, &quot;Taxi Judge&quot; and &quot;Ebola Virus&quot; were later called the &quot;Perverted Trilogy of Hong Kong Cult Films&quot;, but the third-level film The commercial type elements imply the author&#39;s concern for the bottom and marginalized people in Hong Kong society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I think this subject matter helped Qiu Litao a lot. He realized that he could do something different, because the character itself is very outstanding and the subject matter is very cold-blooded or very cruel.&quot; Kaiyin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to his proficiency in craftsmanship, Qiu Litao had already honed a set of &quot;economic aesthetics&quot; through a large number of low-cost practices. Kaiyin explained that Qiu Litao, who was born as a photographer, knew how to use camera movements and angles to make up for the cost shortcomings of scenery and costumes. &quot;Qiu Litao made everyone&#39;s brains turn. We don&#39;t have to film Jackie Chan chasing and crashing cars all over Hong Kong in order to attract the audience... You only need to give me a mental violence to replace the excitement. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Film critic Lin Zhenyu believes that since &quot;Eight Immortals Restaurant: Human Meat Barbecued Pork Buns&quot;, &quot;Qiu Litao&#39;s films on some of the more intense social issues have focused on processing and showing extremely bloody scenes and the torture of life ( His films in the early 1990s reached a state of madness and control, while his films from the late 1990s to 2000 turned cruelty into a dark satirical symbol.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kai Yin believes that the core basic point running through Qiu Litao&#39;s different films is an instinctive emotion of anger. This may come from his cultural influence from rock music and anarchist movements, but for the audience, it is a kind of relief from daily life. &quot;You may have accumulated a lot of anger or dissatisfaction in your daily life, and there is no way to vent it in a normal form. When you watch a movie, this emotion is released purposefully.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Qiu Litao received his PhD in literary studies from Lingnan University in Hong Kong. In the book &quot;Cultural Thoughts and Practices of a Film Director&quot;, Qiu Litao once explained that the idea of ​​what he called &quot;filmmaking as cultural research&quot; originated in the late 1980s. He was in Macau working on a commercial film. &quot;At that moment I was thinking: Why make a movie? Movies should have more possibilities... So, I made some movies: About an industry that is regarded as &#39;abominable&#39; &quot;Yin Yang Road 3: Raising a Coffin to Make a Fortune&quot; is a story about a funeral practitioner, &quot;Give Them a Chance&quot; about marginalized youth, and &quot;The Decameron of Sex Workers&quot; about a discriminated community.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; &quot;Bomb Disposaler 2&quot; is also an example of successfully combining commercial action films with social expression. One viewer described the film on Douban: You can tell that its creators have gone through rigorous and complete industrial training. It’s not tiring, and it’s just the right amount of fun. If you dig deeper, it will give you space to think about the relationship between man and society, justice and evil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with Southern Weekend reporters, Qiu Litao responded to many external controversies. Talking about the intensive release of four movies in one year, he said that this used to be a common thing in Hong Kong. There used to be three of his movies in the cinema on the same day, and &quot;the audience was used to it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He refutes the notion of a bad shoot and believes that it is not accurate to say that he rushed the work. He raised his head and recalled, counting next to each other - &quot;&quot;Assassination&quot; was filmed in 2018, &quot;Anti-Drug 3&quot; was filmed in 2021, &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; was filmed in 2022, and &quot;Pursuit&quot; was filmed in 2021. Filmed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;You can say that I have some multitasks and do a lot of things at the same time... But we have been working on this script for &quot;Jade Chase&quot; for more than a year. If it doesn&#39;t come out well, this is ours. I can admit that my talent is limited, but the time it takes is not as short as people think, and it takes as long as other productions. I hope it can be faster, and I can shoot more if I can,&quot; Qiu Litao said. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Travelers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In Qiu Litao’s story, it seems difficult to avoid his companions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of his partners are old &quot;masters&quot; in the industry. In addition to Li Zhongzhi, photography director Chen Guanghong has served as the photographer of &quot;A Better Tomorrow&quot; and is also Qiu Litao&#39;s partner for many years, from &quot;Yin Yang Road&quot; and &quot; &quot;The Heroic Heroine Qiu Jin&quot;...we worked all the way to &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;. He was over 70 years old, &quot;running around the scene like a young man.&quot; Gui Youming said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kaiyin described Qiu Litao&#39;s team as having an unusual tacit understanding, and it was even difficult to know how they communicated with each other. Because they rarely speak, they understand each other&#39;s needs. After many years of cooperation, Li Zhongzhi knew that what Qiu Litao needed was real texture. In &quot;Operation Moscow&quot;, there was a scene where a person fell out of a train. It was not in the original script. Qiu Litao asked if it would be added to the whole set of action design. No effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The first thing you’ll see when you fall out is that it’ll look good, and the second thing will be more shocking and a bit exciting to the audience.” Li Zhongzhi understood what Qiu Litao meant, so he walked around in the train and considered what kind of action would be more reasonable. . &quot;The glass is so small, and it has to be thrown out reasonably. The last thing I want to do is hit the door in the train compartment, the door smashes the glass, and the person is pushed out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http ://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/yoUie951kErBJFzaNXG2Th8X9sAhQvMpUAQLa5d9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/yoUie951kErBJFzaNXG2Th8X9sAhQvMpUAQLa5d9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255317&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Movies The train fight scene at the beginning of &quot;Operation Moscow&quot; incorporated Qiu Litao&#39;s on-the-spot creativity. The picture is a still from the film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the film producer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zhongzhi is director Chen Musheng&#39;s golden partner. He believes that the two directors are very similar and both can be &quot;People who don&#39;t sleep when filming&quot;. The difference is that director Chen Musheng will &quot;squeeze people to the bone&quot;, while Qiu Litao&#39;s method is gentler. On the set, Gui Youming found that even though they were very familiar with each other, Andy Lau and Qiu Litao always communicated in low voices, discussed and discussed, and were &quot;very professional.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, Li Zhongzhi&#39;s martial arts actors are almost all from the mainland. There are few martial arts actors in Hong Kong now, and &quot;slowly they are all broken up.&quot; When he was filming, he would sometimes be pregnant for ten months. During the COVID-19 epidemic, executive director Wen Zhenwei has been helping Qiu Litao handle work in the Mainland for a long time. Over time, a senior on the team said that he has seen him more than his wife in the past two years. &quot;Slowly, we have become like a big family.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the cold winter of the industry, some people will inherit their past majors and also draw warmth from the community. Qiu Litao once said: &quot;If you have a team, you must ensure that there is always work. Without frequent work, it is difficult to form your own team. So sometimes in order to maintain the team, I will take over the work as long as it does not violate the principles.&quot; &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In this sense, Kaiyin believes that Qiu Litao may have made mediocre films, but he does not think they are bad films - because his attitude is serious and he does not deliberately fool the filmmakers or the audience. &quot;It is precisely because of directors like Qiu Litao who are constantly making films and incorporating new people into the industry that they can gradually be trained into talents and maintain the basic operation of the Hong Kong film industry.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Wen Zhenwei graduated from Hong Kong Baptist University in 2014. He started from basic field management and gradually became Qiu Litao&#39;s executive director. During work, Qiu Litao repeatedly emphasized to his younger generations, &quot;Don&#39;t learn those fancy things first.&quot; &quot;For example, to be an assistant director, you need to know how to read and dismantle the script. You need to understand why many things are arranged this way and that way. First, you need to understand this aspect. Practice your kung fu well.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao grew up in the film age. He will tell his younger generations that one of the legacies of the film age is not to shoot randomly, because money is money as soon as you turn on the camera. &quot;Director Qiu often tells us a concept, that is, we should not think that we can be casual now that we have enough budget. We still have to remain precise and spend money wisely.&quot; Wen Zhenwei said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I’m lucky to have made a lot of films, but if you ask representative (directors), I’m convinced that there are some, but I don’t think I’m one yet. At least for most movie fans, I Definitely not the best director in Hong Kong.&quot; He admitted to Southern Weekend reporters that his desire to make good films in recent years has been much greater than before. In the past, I was afraid that I would not be able to make a film, and that others would think that the industry was in decline; but if the film did not do well at the box office and was scolded by the audience, as a director, it is not that I have no feelings, but I will not jump off the building due to depression. But now he feels that movies live longer than people, &quot;Don&#39;t leave bad things in the world.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qiu Litao’s answer to why he has always maintained such a strong motivation to make films is that he is fulfilled on the set and feels &quot;alive&quot;. He recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that when he first entered the industry in the 1980s, his mother was always worried that he would have a hard time working outside because of his health. &quot;But she didn&#39;t know that there were many people taking care of me on the set.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;David Bordwell believes that Hong Kong films have created the most vibrant and imaginative popular films in the world since the 1970s. When a Southern Weekend reporter asked, what kind of good movie do you most want to make? Qiu Litao answered in four words—appreciation for both refined and popular tastes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[知名潜水员韩颋遗体已被打捞上岸]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259302]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 20:27:32&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;About Jiudun Skylight, Daxing Town, Du&#39;an Yao Autonomous County&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;One person&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Report on the search and rescue situation of lost contact during diving&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han, a well-known person in the diving industry After Ting lost contact while diving in Jiudun Skylight, Daxing, Du&#39;an on the evening of October 7, Du&#39;an immediately organized relevant departments and domestic professional search and rescue teams to participate in the search and rescue. At 18:33 on October 25, an underwater intelligent robot salvaged the body ashore, and it was confirmed that it was Han Ting himself. We are deeply saddened and deplored by this. At present, relevant accident investigation and aftermath processing are in progress. Thank you to the vast number of netizens for their concern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Du&#39;an Yao Autonomous County Emergency Management Bureau&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 25, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首批博士诞生40周年启示录：不应仅是量的扩张]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259272]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/BPzHgFihCdHzGeLCnnQ5SVXaV4XQ3lwzvhmcV0He.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;799&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/BPzHgFihCdHzGeLCnnQ5SVXaV4XQ3lwzvhm cV0He. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255363&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Fudan University professor Ge Jianxiong is the first doctor of history in New China. (People’s Vision/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 27, 1983, 17 students walked into the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. They received 200 yuan in clothing fees in advance. One of them bought a suit specially, but he couldn&#39;t tie it, so he had to ask his instructor for help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are the first batch of Ph.D.s in New China. Except for one who was doing postdoctoral research in the United States and did not attend, these 17 people received the &quot;Doctorate Degree Certificate&quot; with the golden national emblem at the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the reform and opening up, doctoral training started in a hurry, and the research fields of the first batch of 18 PhDs also highlighted a country&#39;s yearning for modernization. 17 of them were PhDs in science and 1 was a PhD in engineering. . &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;40 years later, the questions that confused Su Buqing are also asking more people. According to the &quot;2022 National Education Development Statistical Bulletin&quot;, 82,300 doctoral students will graduate in 2022, and 556,100 doctoral students will be studying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 is the 40th anniversary of the graduation of the first batch of doctoral students in New China. The birth of the first batch of Ph.D.s witnessed the development of China’s degree system from scratch. Nowadays, facing the huge group of doctoral students, further improving the quality of training has become a new development focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Gang, a professor at the School of Education of Central China Normal University, believes that doctoral education should not only expand quantity, but &quot;quality must be the lifeline of doctoral training.&quot; In his view, China has spent 40 years going through the path of exploration that other countries have taken for hundreds of years, and has formed a doctoral education system that is in line with China’s reality and is still gradually improving. “The 40-year development history of doctoral education is also a doctoral education system. A History of Educational Reform.” &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Twisted Exploration&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The establishment of China’s doctoral system has been full of twists and turns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China, although there was a degree system covering bachelor&#39;s, master&#39;s and doctoral degrees, no doctorate was awarded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Gang explained that although the system had been established, the country was poor and weak at that time, and the number of undergraduate and master&#39;s students was limited, which &quot;was not enough to support the development of doctoral education.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 1956, the seventh year after the founding of New China, the &quot;Degree Regulations of the People&#39;s Republic of China (Draft)&quot; were submitted to the central government for approval, dividing degrees into master&#39;s and doctoral levels. However, due to various reasons, the regulations were not formally promulgated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the exploration of the associate doctorate system is also underway. In 1955, the Chinese Academy of Sciences officially proposed to learn from the Soviet Union and establish an associate doctorate system, and announced the first batch of 65 admissions the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Soviet Union, an associate doctorate was second only to a doctorate, and was also called a &quot;candidate doctor.&quot; A doctorate was not obtained through postgraduate education, but was applied for after accumulating many years of work experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the &quot;First Five-Year Plan&quot; had been implemented, which clearly proposed the establishment of a preliminary foundation for socialist industrialization. Zheng Gang told Southern Weekend reporters that there is an urgent need for high-level talents in both industry and higher education. Under the background of learning from the Soviet Union, associate doctoral students came into being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But this exploration also failed to continue. Soon after, the former Ministry of Higher Education issued a notice, &quot;It was decided not to use the name &#39;associate doctoral students&#39;. All associate doctoral students recruited last year (1956) will be called graduate students.&quot; More than a month later, it was decided not to award an associate doctorate. Zheng Gang learned that &quot;the vast majority of associate doctoral students who had enrolled at that time only received graduation certificates and no degree certificates.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind this are not only the influence of international politics, but also the difficulty of connecting the associate doctorate system with the mainstream international degree system. In addition, some universities recruit associate doctoral candidates who are not part-time workers, causing many university teachers and hospital doctors to have their work affected in order to obtain a degree. Ai Zhisheng, then deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Tsinghua University, once described him as &quot;ignoring what is going on outside the window and focusing on getting a doctorate degree.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the establishment of China’s degree system ushered in another opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 12, 1961, Nie Rongzhen, then Vice Premier of the State Council and Director of the State Science and Technology Commission, proposed to the central government “suggestions on establishing a system for degrees, academic titles, engineering and technical titles, etc.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He elaborated on four reasons in his suggestions, including urging intellectuals to march towards the peak of science and culture, encouraging and promoting the rapid growth of a large number of young intellectuals, and accelerating the formation of China&#39;s strong scientific and cultural team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also believes that the implementation of the degree system is also an effective way to directly promote the development of science and technology, &quot;Because in order to give degrees, it is necessary to make academic evaluations of the research work of relevant scientific and technical personnel. Through this Academic evaluation can promote academic prosperity and improve the level of science and technology in our country.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eleven days later, in his speech on &quot;Promoting a Large Number of Young Technical Cadres&quot;, Deng Xiaoping proposed, &quot;It seems that we can&#39;t do it without a degree. You can make a plan first.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Benxia, ​​former director of the Office of the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council, once wrote an article recalling that at the end of 1963, the Ministry of Education received a call from the responsible comrade of the Science and Technology Cadres Bureau of the State Council. Deng Xiaoping had reviewed and approved the &quot;Degree Regulations (Draft)&quot; and reported Other leading comrades of the Central Committee circulated it and &quot;everyone felt very excited.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The excitement did not last long. Due to various reasons, the draft failed to enter the national legislative process and was once again shelved. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to determine the award criteria? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 1978, postgraduate enrollment resumed. Although the degree system has not yet been established, some schools have begun to train doctoral students with good foundation before admission and outstanding achievements after admission according to the requirements of doctoral students. Zheng Gang told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The practice of doctoral training is earlier than the system, which reflects society&#39;s eager need for doctors.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What kind of students are taking the lead in pursuing doctoral degrees? Among the first batch of 18 doctoral degree recipients, 7 are from the University of Science and Technology of China. The article &quot;Some Experiences of the First Batch of Doctoral Training in Our School&quot; published by the Graduate School of the school in &quot;Degrees and Graduate Education&quot; provides more details. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the seven graduate students at the University of Science and Technology of China as an example. Their average age is 34 years old, they have family burdens, some have not completed formal university courses, and their studies were useless after graduation, but their basic qualities are very good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The University of Science and Technology of China realized that the seven graduate students were not admitted according to degree standards. &quot;Are they supporting and encouraging them to become doctoral students, or are they all indiscriminately restricted to the master&#39;s degree? This is a test of our Can we adhere to the principle of starting from reality?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While exploring doctoral training, the establishment of a degree system has once again been put on the agenda. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 24, 1979, Hu Qiaomu reported to Deng Xiaoping on the issue of establishing a degree system, &quot;It would be a great good thing if the decision can be announced soon.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Benxia participated in the drafting work. He wrote that the drafting team collected archival materials from the previous two Degree Regulations (Draft) and investigated the development of foreign degree systems since the mid-1960s. A symposium was held to conduct on-site research on the current situation of higher education, and it took nearly 7 months to complete the first draft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 1, 1980, the State Council submitted the &quot;Degree Regulations (Draft)&quot; to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress for review. Wu Benxia attended the meeting as a non-voting delegate. &quot;Everyone unanimously raised their hands and applauded warmly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Degree Regulations&quot; are scheduled to come into effect on January 1, 1981. This is the first law in the field of education in New China, clarifying that degrees are divided into three levels: bachelor&#39;s degree, master&#39;s degree, and doctoral degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, the State Council approved the first batch of 151 doctoral degree-granting units, 812 disciplines and majors, and 1,155 instructors. Among the disciplines and majors, there are 265 engineering, 233 science, and 153 medicine. Shen Wenqin, deputy director of the China Doctoral Education Research Center at Peking University, told Southern Weekend reporters that the first batch of disciplines and majors are concentrated in basic fields and are urgently needed by the country. &quot;The selection of doctoral supervisors is also very strict.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After becoming the first batch of doctoral degree-granting units, the University of Science and Technology of China wants to take another step forward and award doctoral degrees to graduate students recruited in 1978 who have reached the academic level of a doctoral degree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 5, 1982, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council responded to the Ministry of Education and the Chinese Academy of Sciences, agreeing to provide doctoral degree course education and thesis defense for individual graduate students with higher academic levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, 8 units including the University of Science and Technology of China, Fudan University, and East China Normal University were approved for pilot testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the real problem for these schools is how to judge the criteria for awarding a doctorate? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to make the opinions more representative, the University of Science and Technology of China hires up to 9 experts at a time when reviewing graduation thesis. When reviewing Li Shangzhi&#39;s paper, the opinions of experts were not unanimous. Three people believed that it had reached a doctoral level, and another one believed that it had reached a &quot;master&#39;s degree or above.&quot; Li Shangzhi then wrote two more papers, which finally passed the review smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/jJQqzvhOzZtwDScsCXl9N0nfnrzijZCdTBzvPhhZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;643&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/jJQqzvhOzZtwDScsCXl9N0nfnrzijZCdTBzvPhhZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Among the first batch of 18 Ph.D.s in New China, 7 are from the University of Science and Technology of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Who will train doctors? &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Who trained the first batch of PhDs? Since the establishment of the degree system in 1981, a method has been formulated and implemented for the unified review of doctoral supervisors (hereinafter referred to as &quot;doctoral supervisors&quot;) by a national organization. After five batches of reviews, 8,043 doctoral supervisors were approved nationwide, and by the end of 1993, a total of more than 14,000 doctoral supervisors had been trained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a doctoral supervisor qualification review process was once helpful in ensuring the quality of doctoral training, but it has gradually exposed problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Zhanjun, former deputy director of the Degree and Graduate Education Development Center of the Ministry of Education, once analyzed that with the increase in doctoral authorization units and doctoral authorization points, the scale of doctoral student enrollment has gradually expanded, and the doctoral supervisor review cycle is long, the procedures are cumbersome, and the positions are Shortcomings such as alienation are increasingly mismatched with the development situation of higher education, and &quot;the enthusiasm of higher education institutions cannot be fully mobilized.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The corresponding change is that in the 1990s, several batches of Ph.D.s mainly stayed in universities after graduation. Shen Wenqin told Southern Weekend reporters that they were already equipped to take over the academic field. Developing the capabilities of the next generation of Ph.D. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Underlying the discussion on the qualification review of doctoral supervisors is the issue of &quot;unity over control&quot; of universities, which is directly related to the autonomy of universities in running schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 1993, the &quot;Opinions on Further Reforming the Examination Methods for Degree Authorization&quot; reviewed and approved by the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council stated that doctoral supervisors should be determined by the degree-granting units themselves in accordance with the basic standards and conditions established by the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two years later, the power to approve doctoral supervisors will be delegated to all doctoral granting units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To solve the problem of who should train doctors, we must also solve the problem of positioning of doctorate training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A typical case is that because the medical doctors trained in China focus on experiments and scientific research training, there is a phenomenon that graduated clinical medical doctors are not qualified for clinical medical work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Gang said that society has diverse needs for talents. In addition to people who specialize in academic research, there is also a need for people to solve practical problems raised by society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, doctoral education ushered in another important change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April of this year, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council reviewed and approved the &quot;Several Opinions on Adjusting the Type of Medical Schools and Establishing Medical Professional Degrees&quot;, establishing a professional doctorate in clinical medicine for the first time, requiring a focus on engaging in a specific occupation. Practical work ability, with the goal of cultivating applied talents for senior clinicians, stomatologists, health and epidemic prevention, and new drug research and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above opinions point out that this &quot;is conducive to the targeted training of various specialized talents with different natures and different professional backgrounds, and is conducive to the society&#39;s selection and use of various types of specialized talents.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Fengliang, a professor at the Graduate School of Education at Tsinghua University, told Southern Weekend reporters that the landmark significance of this move is that &quot;doctoral education is developing in a diversified direction.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, China has established six professional doctorate types: engineering, stomatology, education, veterinary medicine, clinical medicine and traditional Chinese medicine. According to statistics from the Ministry of Education, as of 2019, China has awarded a total of 48,000 doctoral professional degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“There is a long way to go”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a doctor at the highest level of academic education, he must be able to deal with the practical problems that the country needs to solve most. “If a doctor can’t solve it, Who else can solve it?&quot; In Zheng Gang&#39;s view, the baton has been passed to the new generation of doctors. &quot;The burdens on them are no lighter than those of their predecessors, or even heavier.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the number of doctors continues to increase, Against the background of growth, in 2007, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council, the Ministry of Education, and the former Ministry of Personnel jointly launched a systematic investigation of doctoral training. As of that year, a total of 240,000 people in China had been awarded doctorates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After going deep into 289 doctoral training units across the country, 69,133 questionnaires were collected, and after interviewing more than 400 people, the investigation team recommended that the development scale of academic doctoral education be controlled and that academic doctoral education should shift from focusing on scale to Shifts that focus on quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this survey, new policies that focused on quality had already appeared in practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 1999, the then Minister of Education Chen Zhili proposed that not only outstanding doctoral theses should be selected, but also other theses should be randomly checked to ensure that the overall quality of Chinese doctoral degrees continues to improve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2000, the Department of Degree Management and Graduate Education of the Ministry of Education has been responsible for conducting random inspections of doctoral theses. The evaluation content includes the innovativeness of the paper, the theoretical basis and expertise embodied in the paper, and scientific research capabilities. Since then, the number of random inspections has been increased. In order to achieve &quot;zero interference&quot; with the inspected units, degree-granting units are no longer required to submit thesis materials, but will be retrieved directly from the National Library after extraction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, it is stipulated that degree authorization sites with a high proportion of &quot;problematic theses&quot; or a large number of papers will be ordered to make rectifications within a time limit. If the requirements are still not met after rectification, the degree authorization will be revoked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council issued the &quot;Some Opinions on Carrying out Periodic Evaluation of Doctoral and Master&#39;s Degree Authorization Points&quot; and decided that starting from that year, the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council would conduct regular evaluations of doctoral and master&#39;s degree authorization points every six years. Regular evaluation, the main content of the evaluation includes &quot;talent training situation, especially the quality of talent training.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Improving the quality of doctoral training is also reflected in the selection of students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, examinations were an important way to select doctors. Shen Wenqin told a reporter from Southern Weekend that candidates with scientific research talents or abilities are not necessarily good at taking exams. If standardized tests are used to screen talents at the doctoral level, &quot;the effect is not so ideal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, the General Office of the Ministry of Education issued the &quot;Notice on Recruiting Doctoral Graduate Students in 2017&quot;, proposing to promote and improve the &quot;application-assessment&quot; enrollment and selection mechanism, and strengthen the professional quality and academic level. , comprehensive evaluation of scientific research capabilities, innovation potential and overall quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;application-assessment&quot; system means that candidates no longer take the entrance examination uniformly organized by the school, but review materials such as academic transcripts, proposed scientific research ideas, and original research results. Afterwards, each department will assess the application through written examinations, experiments, interviews, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the same year, many universities such as Nankai University, Harbin Institute of Technology, and Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications implemented this system. Starting from the 2023 academic year, the University of Chinese Academy of Sciences will fully implement the “application-assessment” system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back on the 40 years of doctoral education in China, from scratch to excellence, &quot;doctoral education has a long way to go&quot; and there are different problems and challenges at each stage. Zheng Gang said that these 40 years of exploration It proves that only &quot;reform can solve problems in the development process.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Reference books:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&quot;History of Graduate Education and Degree System of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&quot;40 Years of Implementation of China&#39;s Degree System&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[轻松筹回应“女童被咬”善款：未使用的所有善款全额原路退回]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259300]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 19:24:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 25, @easilychouweibo issued refund instructions stating that on October 23, the injured girl After being transferred out of the ICU, the situation is relatively stable. After communicating with the sponsor, Easily raised all unused donations and returned them in full. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/399b5d22ab896e0a0c40e1caf050c24d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;1108&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/399b5d22ab896e0a0c40e1caf050c24d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;255520&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“新中国第一号”博士马中骐：做冲不走的“小砖头”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259255]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/25/P7xXNaTDXAkIna4pKxhQtqnW8vXDjgK9QLKN8EGj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;979&quot; height=&quot;734&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/P7xXNaTDXAkIna4pKxhQtqnW8vXD jgK9QLKN8EGj. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255315&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Zhongqi is the first Ph.D. in physics in New China and the &quot;No. 1 in New China&quot; &quot;PhD. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Doctoral profile:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;Ma Zhongqi, a native of Hangzhou, Zhejiang, was born in Shanghai in March 1940&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;1951 -1956, studied at Shanghai Shidong Middle School;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;1956-1961, studied at the Department of Physics, Lanzhou University, majoring in theoretical physics , stayed at the school to teach after graduation;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;1964-1967, studied as a graduate student in the Department of Physics, Peking University, and returned to Lanzhou University after graduation Work; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;From 1978 to 1981, he studied for the second time as a graduate student at the Institute of High Energy Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, and stayed to work after graduation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;On March 4, 1982, the Degree Evaluation Committee of the Department of Mathematical Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences unanimously passed a resolution approving the award to Ma Zhongqi, a graduate student at the Institute of High Energy Physics. Doctor of Science degree. Ma Zhongqi became the first doctorate awarded a degree in New China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;In 1993, he was rated as a doctoral supervisor by the Academic Degrees Committee of the State Council. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;Retired in 2005. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;>;Served as a researcher in Room 4 of the Institute of High Energy Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, doctoral supervisor, member of the academic committee and director of the academic committee of the institute, China Member of the Society for High Energy Physics. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/YcleIKlNGLrq5XGrFLHKlennKjtBLgG4hg4GQqU7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1268&quot; height=&quot;951&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/YcleIKlNGLrq5XGrFLHKlennKjtBLgG4hg4GQqU7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255431&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Zhongqi’s doctoral degree certificate. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sitting in a nursing home by Yangcheng Lake in Suzhou, 83-year-old Ma Zhongqi still remembers 40 years the afternoon before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On May 27, 1983, the first batch of doctoral and master’s degree awarding conferences in New China was held in the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. In the venue, the upper and lower floors were filled with teachers and students from various universities. Ma Zhongqi was the only doctor sitting on the rostrum. He was &quot;extremely nervous&quot; to speak as a representative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason he was selected to speak is most likely because he is the &quot;first&quot; among the first batch of doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Zhongqi comes from the Institute of High Energy Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences. Qian Sanqiang, a nuclear physicist, then director of the Department of Mathematics and Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and a member of the faculty, issued his doctorate certificate. The certificate number is &quot;10001&quot;. New China Number one. Now, this degree certificate is collected by the National Museum of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/PvhSs5QMiwrJaa2O2ggAxEZXIvchQDuFY3sKRytC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1270&quot; height= &quot;762&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/PvhSs5QMiwrJaa2O2ggAxEZXIvchQDuFY3sKRytC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255430&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Zhongqi at the defense of his doctoral thesis. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On that day, a total of 18 people were awarded doctorates. Among them, 6 are from the Chinese Academy of Sciences, 6 are from the University of Science and Technology of China, 4 are from Fudan University, and two are from East China Normal University and Shandong University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“One of the obvious characteristics of the first batch of graduate students who obtained doctorate degrees is that they are older, generally around forty years old.” In his speech at the scene, Ma Zhongqi mentioned age. At that time, Ma Zhongqi was 43 years old. It took him 16 years from his first graduate school to graduating with a doctorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1956, 16-year-old Ma Zhongqi entered the physics department of Lanzhou University and stayed at the school to teach after graduation. In 1964, the state mobilized on-the-job cadres to take postgraduate examinations. Ma Zhongqi was admitted to the Department of Physics of Peking University and studied under Hu Ning, a theoretical physicist and member of the Chinese Academy of Sciences. His studies were interrupted a year later during the political movement. In 1967, Ma Zhongqi returned to Lanzhou University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was not until 10 years later, in 1977, that the State Council approved the Ministry of Education&#39;s &quot;Opinions on the Recruitment of Postgraduate Students in Colleges and Universities&quot; and postgraduate education was resumed. In 1978, 38-year-old Ma Zhongqi was admitted to Hu Ning&#39;s graduate school again and entered the Institute of High Energy Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Institute of High Energy&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I have been holding back for ten years and cannot do scientific research. I am very anxious.” Ma Zhongqi said in an interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend. Due to his previous academic accumulation, this time he became the &quot;big brother&quot; of his classmates in the Institute of High Energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 1980, at the 13th meeting of the Standing Committee of the Fifth National People&#39;s Congress, the &quot;Degree Regulations of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; was reviewed and approved, and three-level degrees including bachelor&#39;s, master&#39;s and doctoral degrees were established. The regulations have been implemented since 1981. The Graduate School of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, the University of Science and Technology of China, Fudan University, Shandong University, and East China Normal University became the first batch of pilot units and began to train doctoral students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Zhongqi recalled that in August of this year, the organization talked with him and decided to select a group of graduate students with good foundations to become doctoral students directly. He was selected as a &quot;pilot&quot; and asked to &quot;write a high-level doctoral thesis as soon as possible.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In four months, Ma Zhongqi completed writing his graduation thesis. On February 6, 1982, Ma Zhongqi defended his thesis in a classroom of the Institute of High Energy. The defense committee has a luxurious lineup, consisting of 7 top experts in the field of physics: the chairman is Peng Huanwu, the father of the &quot;two bombs and one satellite&quot;, and there are also 4 members of the academic department: Hu Ning, Zhu Hongyuan, Dai Yuanben, and Gu Chaohao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduation, Ma Zhongqi stayed at the Institute of High Energy and was engaged in theoretical physics research, focusing on group theory methods and their physical applications, until his retirement in 2005. In 1991, he was awarded the title of &quot;Chinese Doctorate Recipient with Outstanding Contributions&quot;. He has enjoyed special government subsidies since October 1992, and has won the second prize of the Chinese Academy of Sciences Scientific and Technological Progress Award three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Physicist and Nobel Prize winner Yang Zhenning commented that Ma Zhongqi&#39;s research results are &quot;work that can be retained.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s great to leave a hilltop like Mr. Yang did.&quot; Ma Zhongqi said that his work is like &quot;little bricks.&quot; &quot;When the flood comes, the sediment is washed away, but the &#39;little bricks&#39; can stay.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Assigned&quot; to study physics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you were an undergraduate student at Lanzhou University, your chosen major was physics. How did you become interested in physics? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1956, the central government issued a policy on developing the northwest and authorized Lanzhou University to go to Beijing, Shanghai, and Tianjin before the college entrance examination. Each high school selects students. I went to high school in Shanghai Shidong Middle School. Before the college entrance examination, the principal talked to me and asked me to apply for the Physics Department of Lanzhou University. At that time, the party&#39;s needs were my wishes. If I was asked to go to Lanzhou, I went without any objection. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The major was also decided, and I was asked to choose physics. When I was in high school, I heard from my relatives who were in college that the physics department was the best and I could learn a lot. At that time, I wanted to study physics myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A total of 60 students went to Shanghai in that session. We took the train to Xi&#39;an, and then chartered a &quot;stuffy truck&quot;. We got on the train in the morning and arrived in Lanzhou the next evening. As soon as I got off the car, I was hit by a gust of wind carrying loess. At that time, tap water was not yet widely available in Lanzhou, and there were still water trucks on the road, clanging and clanking to deliver water. At school, we lived in a bungalow with no glass, just paper windows. At that time, living conditions were very difficult, but the enthusiasm was very high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How is it going in school? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1956, I studied hard in school for a year. It is a pity that since 1957, with the &quot;Ming Fang&quot; movement, anti-rightist movement, and then the &quot;Great Leap Forward&quot;, people basically stopped studying. I also saw wood, made steel, and carried loads at the waterworks. I didn&#39;t have enough to eat at that time, and I was reluctant to leave the canteen every day. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the school would show movies every night, telling everyone not to study and to rest. But everyone finally got the opportunity to go to school, and they all studied hard. Many people fell ill due to swelling from studying, and even after being admitted to the hospital, they continued to study. It was really hard to study at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What did you do after graduating from Lanzhou University in 1961? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After graduation, the school assigned me to stay at Lanzhou University as a teaching assistant, and the teaching task was very heavy. I taught 3 courses: mathematical methods, theoretical mechanics and electrodynamics, each of which required very high mathematics. There are a total of 240 students. I will correct every assignment. A pile of exercises is handed in every two weeks. When the assignments are handed in, I basically don’t leave the office for two whole days. I also have Q&amp;A classes 4 times a week, once every two hours, and I can’t stop talking. Before I even went to the classroom, students began to line up and surrounded me from all directions to ask questions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for doing laundry on Saturday night, there is no extra time left, not even time for watching movies. We were already &quot;996&quot; at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, I didn’t study well in my own classes, so I just got through in college. The three years I spent as a teaching assistant gave me time to learn the basics of physics in a down-to-earth manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1964, the state mobilized serving cadres to take the postgraduate entrance examination, and you went Graduate student at Peking University. Can you tell us about your experience preparing for graduate school? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The condition for in-service cadres to take the postgraduate examination was that they must return to their original units after graduation. When I took the postgraduate examination in 1964, my employer decided to let me take the exam. Each teaching and research section of the school sent a teacher to take the exam, and the theoretical physics department chose me. I decided which school I should go to, and I chose the Department of Physics of Peking University. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Our theoretical physics exams are quantum field theory, electrodynamics, and quantum mechanics. You choose two of the three professional courses, as well as politics, Chinese, and English. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the three years of teaching, I happened to have learned the physics department courses by heart. Basic knowledge can withstand the test, and when it is familiar enough, students will not be afraid to ask any questions. Therefore, sometimes good things turn into bad things, and bad things turn into good things. It’s hard to explain. When I took on the teaching task at that time, I had no idea that I would still have the opportunity to take the postgraduate entrance examination in 1964. When the opportunity came, I immediately went to graduate school. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Learn to &quot;do scientific research&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , STKaiti;&quot;>;How is life as a graduate student at Peking University? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;My tutor is Hu Ning, who is very good at teaching students. His training method is that he specifies the research direction, and the students find and read the literature themselves. Group meetings are held twice a week, and all students come. Anyone who has read the literature and is willing to report can report it - what new ideas does this literature have, what makes sense, what is wrong, and where should we start? Go ahead and develop your own ideas. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the report, Mr. Hu will discuss it on the spot. If he thinks what you said is reasonable, he will organize a few people to study the issue in depth. Mr. Hu is very democratic, he will listen to our different opinions, and his discussion method is very free. I have been a graduate student for one year and have already published two papers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What influence did Mr. Hu have on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have never done scientific research before, and I learned what it means to do scientific research from Mr. Hu. To engage in scientific research, you just have to have an idea, come up with something, and it is valuable. From then on, I also learned to do scientific research myself. At that time, our students were very conscious and fully unleashed their originality. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned that you studied for one year As a graduate student, what was the situation like at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After studying at Peking University for one year, he was sent to the countryside to carry out the &quot;Four Clean-ups&quot;. In 1967, when the fighting began at Peking University, I returned to Lanzhou University. At that time, the school&#39;s theoretical physics laboratory had been disbanded, the library was closed, and there was nothing left. The students are still there, but they are no longer studying. I give lectures to students at the Workers&#39;, Peasants and Soldiers&#39; College, starting from the most basic middle school mathematics of making negatives plus plus, one course a week, all the way to calculus. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the Cultural Revolution, I was not involved in politics and never participated in it. I didn’t even write a single big-character poster. I study when I have time, and work the rest of the time. I am tall and in good health, and I am among the first to work. I&#39;m kidding. I am neither a driving force for revolution nor an object of revolution. I am just a commodity for labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Graduate student enrollment resumed in 1978. You were 38 years old at that time. How did you resume your studies? What about those who went back to school? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1977, everything began to return to normal. For the first time in my life, I took a train to Dalian to attend a semiconductor research conference. On the way, I ran to Beijing to visit my mentor Hu Ning. Mr. Hu is very anxious. He is engaged in particle physics, but there are no students left and no one is engaged in it. He asked me if I still wanted to engage in particle physics. I said that the school’s theoretical physics department had been disbanded and I couldn’t do it if I wanted to. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the central government had a red-headed document supporting &quot;returning college students.&quot; College students who enrolled in 1964 and 1965 only went to college for one or two years. The central government paid for them to return to school. Tuition for a year or two. Mr. Hu suddenly had a sudden idea and asked me if I would like to be a &quot;returning graduate student.&quot; Of course I do. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1978, graduate students began to enroll students. The enrollment plan stipulates that the upper age limit is 35 years old. I was 38 years old at the time and could not take the exam. Mr. Hu contacted a group of old faculty members and proposed at the National Science Conference held that year that the graduate students admitted in 1964 and 1965 were of good quality but had not completed their studies, and they should be recalled as graduate students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, about 50 days before the exam, I saw a notice in a newspaper advertisement: graduate students admitted in 1964 and 1965 are not subject to age restrictions. After seeing this, I quickly signed up and chose the Institute of High Energy Physics of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, where Mr. Hu also had an enrollment quota. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;There are only 50 days left, how to prepare for the exam? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The difference between taking the postgraduate entrance examination in 1978 and 1964 was huge. It was very difficult to take the postgraduate entrance examination in 1964, but when I took the postgraduate entrance examination in 1978, my opponents were far behind. I was a serious college student, and I had also gone to graduate school, and I had never given up my business. Of course, 38 years old is a bit older, but I am still in my prime, and my brain is still very responsive, so there will be no problem in taking the exam. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This time I am studying for graduate school, just in time for the reform open. What impact do you think the changes in the social environment at that time had on you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>; In 1978, the resumption of graduate student enrollment was launched. This was presided over by Deng Xiaoping, and it was necessary to recruit talents. From the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China to that time, when there was a conflict between the organization&#39;s opinions and my personal opinions, I always relied on the organization&#39;s opinions. The only exception was the postgraduate entrance examination in 1978. If an individual wants to take the exam, the unit will not let him go and it will be based on the individual. This has never happened before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have been holding back for ten years and cannot engage in scientific research. I am very anxious. Given this opportunity, of course I have to work hard. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Complete doctoral thesis in 4 months&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How is the second time studying for graduate school different from the first time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It feels completely different. You’re 40 years old, and you don’t know how to do scientific research, so what else can you do? Since I have basically mastered the methods of scientific research, I choose my own topics and work on them myself, and ride to Peking University to report to Mr. Hu every two weeks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, everyone else had to take professional courses, so I didn’t have to take them. I only had to take political classes, English classes, and differential geometry of my choice, and Mr. Hu gave me my course grades. He told me, &quot;Hurry up and start scientific research. What basic courses should you learn? You already know it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was a very special graduate student during my graduate studies. Everyone knows that I was a graduate student before and I was able to do scientific research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1980, Guangdong held a symposium on particle physics theory. Forty or fifty Chinese professors abroad participated. Li Zhengdao and Yang Zhenning were both present. Who in China could present an academic report? , and speak at the conference? I had a thesis at that time, and after submitting it, I was approved to participate. Those who took the stage to speak were basically teachers, with very few students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When did you know that you were going to become a PhD student directly from graduate school? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1981, the Degree Regulations were implemented. In August, the organization talked to me about finding a group of graduate students to become doctoral students directly. The school decided to use me as a &quot;pilot&quot; and asked me to write a high-level doctoral thesis as soon as possible. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1981, magnetic monopole research was a popular topic, and Mr. Yang Zhenning was doing research in this area. It happened that I saw an article published by Mr. Gu Chaohao (mathematician, member of the Chinese Academy of Sciences) in the &quot;Journal of Fudan University&quot;. He proposed how to use mathematical methods to study the magnetic monopole theory. I suddenly felt that this was an option. The Institute of High Energy specially sent me on a business trip to Shanghai to find Mr. Gu. After reviewing it, he felt that my ideas and principles in selecting the topic were very good. When I returned to Beijing, I used group theory methods and spent about two and a half months completing the calculations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the calculation was completed, the Institute of High Energy Research sent me on a business trip to Shanghai to find Mr. Gu to review whether the result of my calculation was reasonable, whether my level was sufficient, and whether it could be used as a doctoral thesis. He nodded, and I hurried back to write my paper. The paper was submitted in November 1981. In December, the school sent the paper to professors studying magnetic monopole theory across the country for review. After receiving no negative comments, they notified me to prepare for a defense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you still remember the doctoral defense? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;On February 6, 1982, the doctoral thesis defense was held in a classroom of the Institute of High Energy, which was also the first doctoral thesis defense. . My defense committee was the biggest. The chairman of the defense committee is Peng Huanwu, the father of the &quot;two bombs and one satellite&quot;. The defense committee members include my mentor Hu Ning, Gu Chaohao, Zhu Hongyuan, an authority in particle physics at the Institute of High Energy, and Dai Yuanben, an authority in particle physics at the Institute of Theoretical Physics. They are all from the Chinese Academy of Sciences. Faculty member. In addition, there were Professor Hou Boyu of Northwest University and Professor Li Huazhong of Sun Yat-sen University, who were the most outstanding experts in the fields of particle physics and magnetic monopoles at that time. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Basic work is important work&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I noticed that you have a lot of books and photos of Chen Ning Yang in your house. What impact did he have on your academic career? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Mr. Yang has had a great influence on me. In 1984, he invited me to be a visiting scholar at the State University of New York at Stony Brook. On the first day we met, I reported my work plan to him. I said I wanted to continue research on magnetic monopoles. In addition, I made preparations in advance and knew that Mr. Yang was doing research on a very basic theorem of quantum mechanics - Levinson&#39;s theorem. , I said I also wanted to work on Levinson’s theorem. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Yang told me that it is okay to follow others with magnetic monopoles, but Levinson’s theorem is different. This is basic work. Essential work, he said, is important work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, he gave me his article and the 133-page calculation manuscript. It took me two months to completely understand the manuscript. After mastering this method, I then studied Levinson&#39;s theorem, modified its applicable conditions, and extended the theorem to the case of relativity. Later, I became an authority on Levinson&#39;s theorem. After returning to China, I was asked to review articles in this area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I thought at that time that Levinson’s theorem was a topic given to me by Mr. Yang. I just re-calculated it. When I wrote the article, I planned to cooperate with Mr. Yang. If Mr. Yang didn’t do it, he would leave me alone. Write. Later I realized that he cared about young people. If this article was published jointly by us, then people would definitely think it was Mr. Yang’s article, and it would have nothing to do with me. He was very thoughtful and gave young people a lot of opportunities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Yang Zhenning once commented that your research results are &quot;can be retained &quot;Work&quot;, what do you think of this evaluation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;“Basic work is important work.” This sentence is what Mr. Yang told me, and it is also my motto. In my scientific research throughout my life, I have paid more attention to basic tasks. Basic work, as long as the math is correct, it stays. Like Levinson&#39;s theorem, if I calculate it correctly, it stands. This thing is mine, it is clear, and it is in the textbook. This is called a job that can be retained. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If it is a trendy job, the entire direction is wrong, and it will be gone after a while. Just like the magnetic monopole, if it turns out that the magnetic monopole has not been discovered in the end, all the work on the magnetic monopole will be scrapped. This is called a job that cannot be retained. Now 99% of the articles are about jobs that cannot be retained, and there are very few jobs left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of Mr. Yang’s teachings, I paid more attention to finding a basic job. I was very excited to have such a job, and I worked hard to do it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Are you doing any research in recent years? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After living in a nursing home, I published three books, one of which was &quot;Group Theory For Physics&quot; &quot;It&#39;s about group theory. It&#39;s a problem I wanted to solve when I was young, but I was busy at work and didn&#39;t have time to do it. Now I&#39;ve taken the time to thoroughly prove and promote it. In February this year, I received a bill from the publisher. Someone bought 100 copies at once. This shows that it has been selected as a teaching material. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I published a book &quot;Yang-baxter Equation And Quantum Enveloping Algebras&quot; in 1993. The publisher sends me bills every year. , people buy it every year. There aren&#39;t many, but there are. There is a difference between having it and not having it, which means that this thing is established and 30 years later, people are still reading this book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think is the most important thing for today’s college students? ? Any suggestions? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Zhongqi:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am very lucky, I like to study physics. Others joked that I would do it even if they didn’t pay me a salary, let alone a salary (laughs). I really like physics, and that&#39;s all I can do. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大学生应该多听一听，看一看，搞清楚自己喜欢什么，然后在这上面独立地钻研，不能光是玩游戏或者光是找工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[透视我国增发2023年国债1万亿元的深意]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259232]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 18:34:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the 24th, the sixth meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress voted to adopt the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress The resolution approving the State Council’s additional issuance of treasury bonds and the 2023 central budget adjustment plan clarifies that the central government will issue an additional 1 trillion yuan of 2023 treasury bonds in the fourth quarter of this year. What is the purpose of issuing additional national bonds in 2023? Where will the additional national debt be used? How to manage trillions of yuan in national debt funds? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Why additional issuance: A necessary move to support post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and improve disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since this year, many places in our country have suffered from heavy rains, floods, Disasters such as typhoons have severely affected some areas and caused heavy losses, and local post-disaster recovery and reconstruction tasks are relatively heavy. At the same time, various types of extreme natural disasters have occurred frequently in recent years, placing higher demands on my country&#39;s disaster prevention, reduction, and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting on August 17 to study and deploy flood prevention and disaster relief and post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work. The meeting proposed &quot;accelerating recovery and reconstruction&quot; and &quot;further improving my country&#39;s disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These key tasks cannot be separated from the guarantee of &quot;real money&quot;. The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Finance said that although the budget at the beginning of the year had arranged relevant regular disaster relief and disaster prevention and reduction funds, it was difficult to meet the needs of improving disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Liu Yi, director of the Department of Finance at Peking University School of Economics, by combining factors such as resolving local government debt risks and ensuring &quot;three guarantees&quot; expenditures, local governments have more room to significantly increase funding arrangements in related fields through their own financial resources. Small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The issuance of additional treasury bonds in 2023 is a major decision-making arrangement made by the Party Central Committee and the State Council, and an important measure to implement the people-centered development idea.” The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Finance said that with strong funds Ensure the implementation of relevant work, focus on supporting post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and make up for shortcomings in disaster prevention, reduction, and relief, and overall improve our country&#39;s ability to withstand natural disasters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“From an international perspective, many countries will also make some budget adjustments in the middle of the year based on the actual situation of economic and social development.” Shi Yinghua, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Fiscal Sciences, said that based on the disaster situation in our country this year, the central government The government&#39;s issuance of additional national debt and budget adjustments are pragmatic moves that reflect the guidance of the government&#39;s efforts to ensure key expenditures. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to use: All funds from the additional treasury bonds issued in the fourth quarter will be allocated to local governments&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is understood that combined with the needs of post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and disaster prevention, reduction and relief work , and to coordinate fiscal affordability, the central government will issue an additional 1,000 billion yuan in 2023 national debt in the fourth quarter, and arrange all of it to local governments through transfer payments. Among them, 500 billion yuan is planned to be used this year and 500 billion yuan will be carried forward for use next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The central government issued additional treasury bonds, but all the specific funds were used locally. This helped ease the pressure on local fiscal revenue and expenditure, further optimized the fiscal expenditure structure, and further optimized the debt structure.” Shi Yinghua explain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of use of funds, according to the Ministry of Finance, the funds will be used in eight major areas: post-disaster recovery and reconstruction, key flood control projects, natural disaster emergency response capacity improvement projects, other key flood control projects, irrigation area construction and renovation, and key water and soil projects. Loss control projects, urban drainage and flood prevention capacity improvement actions, key natural disaster comprehensive prevention and control system construction projects, and high-standard farmland construction in Northeast China and disaster-stricken areas in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;This fund use arrangement spans this year and next, reflecting the continuity of the policy. The direction of fund use takes into account both the present and the long term. While supporting post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and ensuring people&#39;s livelihood, it also focuses on making up for shortcomings. , strengths and weaknesses, and strengthen long-term capacity building to resist natural disasters, which is conducive to promoting high-quality development.&quot; Shi Yinghua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The additional treasury bonds will be issued in the fourth quarter of this year. &quot;We will start the issuance of treasury bonds in a timely manner. At present, the Ministry of Finance has made adjustments to the treasury bond issuance plan for the fourth quarter to leave room for additional issuance of treasury bonds.&quot; The official said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the National Development and Reform Commission and the Ministry of Finance will work with relevant departments to strengthen project review and control and allocate funds to specific projects as soon as possible. The Ministry of Finance will also issue budgets for national debt projects in a timely manner to accelerate the formation of physical workload. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After the national debt funds are put into use, it will also help drive domestic demand and further consolidate the economic recovery.” Liu Yi said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How to manage: The central budget will be adjusted accordingly and funds from the additional issuance of government bonds will be included in the direct mechanism&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After the issuance of additional government bonds, the central budget in 2023 will also be adjusted accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that central government expenditures at the same level will remain unchanged in 2023, and transfer payments from the central government to local governments will increase by 500 billion yuan compared with the budget at the beginning of the year; local general public budget expenditures will increase by 500 billion yuan accordingly, and the expenditure growth rate will increase from 5.2%. to 7.4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the fiscal deficit has also increased accordingly. In 2023, the national fiscal deficit will increase from 3.88 trillion yuan to 4.88 trillion yuan, the central fiscal deficit will increase from 3.16 trillion yuan to 4.16 trillion yuan, and the fiscal deficit rate is expected to increase from 3% to about 3.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, China’s government debt ratio has been lower than that of other major world economies. In Liu Yi&#39;s view, the Chinese government currently has room for additional issuance of treasury bonds, and the overall risk after this additional issuance is controllable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to manage and use trillions of yuan in national debt funds? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Finance said that in the next step, the direct mechanism will be fully utilized, all government bond expenditure funds will be included in the scope of direct fiscal funds, and the whole process tracking and monitoring will be implemented to ensure that the funds are used according to the prescribed purposes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We will also organize the local supervision bureaus of the Ministry of Finance to establish a normalized supervision mechanism, keep a close eye on the use of government bond funds, strictly investigate illegal activities such as misappropriation of government bond funds, and effectively prevent government debt risks.&quot; This said the person in charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京市委常委、副市长靳伟因北京长峰医院重大火灾事故被问责]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259288]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 17:49:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;A few days ago, with the approval of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the State Supervision Commission issued a Member and Vice Mayor Jin Wei initiated a case review and investigation into the issue of dereliction of duty and dereliction of duty during the &quot;4·18&quot; major fire accident at Changfeng Hospital in Fengtai, Beijing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After investigation, Comrade Jin Wei, as a member of the Standing Committee of the Beijing Municipal Party Committee and deputy mayor in charge of health work, has gaps in the implementation of the Party Central Committee’s instructions and requirements on production safety, which has a negative impact on Beijing. The health department’s safety management strength is weak and medical institutions’ fire safety hazards are outstanding. The city’s health and health department is urged to fulfill its responsibility of “managing safety in the industry” and medical institutions are not fully responsible for the main responsibility for safety production, which plays an important role in the occurrence of accidents. Leadership responsibilities should be held seriously accountable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In accordance with the &quot;Supervision Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, the &quot;Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China on Administrative Punishment for Public Employees&quot; and other relevant provisions, after study by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection at a meeting and reported to the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China for approval, it was decided Comrade Jin Wei was given a political warning by the State Supervision Commission. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“要么赢，要么死” 加沙至暗时刻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259287]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-25 18:03:21&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“Gaza is very dangerous, but my brother insists on going back. Because there is his wife and 4 children there—— The oldest is 13 years old and the youngest is only 1 year old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 23, 2023, Sharif, a Palestinian young man working in Guangzhou, sent his brother to the airport. His brother will fly directly from Guangzhou to Egypt and look for an opportunity to return to his hometown of Gaza when the port opens. There, the Israeli army, which has superior military strength, is launching a fierce attack. In live video footage, bombs fell from the sky and many houses were reduced to fragments and rubble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharif told Southern Weekend reporters that it was his brother&#39;s own decision to go back and &quot;he had no choice.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the Israeli-Palestinian conflict escalates, a humanitarian crisis is unfolding in the Gaza Strip. As of October 24, this round of conflict between Palestine and Israel has killed more than 7,200 people on both sides. According to UNICEF news on the 24th, 2,360 children were killed in the Gaza Strip and another 5,364 children were injured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the conflict broke out, the Israeli military has required residents of northern Gaza to move to the south within a time limit, otherwise they will be regarded as &quot;accomplices of terrorists.&quot; However, many Palestinians, including Sharif&#39;s family, remain in the north. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to disclosures from multiple international rescue organizations, a total of 57 rescue trucks entered Gaza from October 21st to 23rd. But for the more than 2 million Gazans, this is undoubtedly a drop in the bucket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There are blockades everywhere, how do we leave? Even if someone evacuates, they will be killed by air strikes on the road. More importantly, we don&#39;t want to leave our own land.&quot; Sharifou said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In Sharif&#39;s hometown of Beit Hanoun, residents&#39; houses were reduced to ruins after the bombing. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/33047ed953.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/10/25/33047ed953.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255452&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Sharif&#39;s hometown of Beit In Hanon, after the bombing, residents&#39; houses were reduced to ruins. (Photo provided by the interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“I have seen three wars in Gaza, and this is the most difficult”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On October 19, Sharifou lost contact with his family in Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharif&#39;s home is in Beit Hanoun, a small town in northern Gaza, which is close to Israel and is known as a &quot;dangerous place.&quot; On the 19th, Sharifou saw from news reports that his hometown had been bombed. He then contacted his family many times, but the other party&#39;s mobile phone always reminded him that he was &quot;not in the service area.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It wasn’t until 6 hours later that Sharifu contacted them again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to get in touch better, Sharifou bought an ESIM card for his parents. &quot;Just like an international roaming card, you can also use Israeli or Egyptian network services in Gaza.&quot; Sharifou added that such a card would not receive a signal all the time. When using it, people must stand at a high place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharif comes from a merchant family in Gaza. For many years, he and his family traveled to Yiwu, Guangzhou and Gaza to trade in general merchandise such as candy, motorcycle parts, and home appliances. He and his brother have lived and worked in Guangzhou for many years, and his brother&#39;s two children also studied in Baiyun District. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long after arriving in China, Salifu told his parents that they must come to China one day. &quot;My father was originally going to attend the Canton Fair this year. However, the war changed everything.&quot; Sharifou said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A week after the war broke out, Sharifo lost many relatives - &quot;My uncles and aunts passed away, their sons and grandchildren are gone, and the whole family disappeared together.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A week after the conflict began, Sharif lost his family, and his uncle&#39;s family was killed. (Photo provided by interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/25/ed91c84772.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;722&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/25/ed91c84772.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;255453&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A week into the conflict, Sharifou lost Relatives, his uncle&#39;s family were unfortunately killed. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Sharifo’s family members are also gathered together. His parents, 5 brothers, 2 sisters, and children of his brothers and sisters, totaling more than 50 people. &quot;A large family has left their home in northern Gaza and moved to a new location that &#39;cannot be disclosed.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2008, 2012, 2014, and 2021, Gaza has experienced &quot;wars.&quot; But this time it seems different. &quot;My family told me that this bombing was different from any previous one, and the sound sounded like a new weapon.&quot; Sharifou said, &quot;Stop the war. This is the only way to save them.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Also in Gaza, 26-year-old Ismail is worried about his family&#39;s food rations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Late at night on October 23, Ismail sent a message for help to Annie, a Chinese friend who cared about him. He wanted to borrow $1,000 from Anne and promised to &quot;pay it back to you after the war is over.&quot; He and his family are currently in a settlement in a school in Gaza, but aid agencies have provided limited help. Food on the market is scarce and expensive, and must be traded in U.S. dollars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Annie told Southern Weekend reporters that Ismail studied abroad in a university in Zhejiang and understands Chinese. The two met by chance at a party. Not long before the conflict, Ismail had consulted her on how to handle the procedures for his brother, who had graduated from high school, to study in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Annie said that Ismail uses two mobile phone numbers on a daily basis, belonging to operators in Gaza and Israel. After the conflict broke out, communication facilities in Gaza were extensively damaged. Ismail barely got in touch with Anne through an Israeli mobile phone number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When I was contacted, his family was preparing to go to an evacuation site near their home. Because his family did not have a car, it was not practical for the whole family to evacuate on foot,&quot; said Anne. When asked how he was doing, Ismail replied in Chinese, &quot;Not dead yet.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the day on October 24, Anne, who had raised the US dollars, contacted Ismail again, but received no reply. On the morning of October 25, I finally received news that Ismail was safe. According to his description, the fighting there was &quot;very, very severe&quot; and &quot;the sound of bombings and explosions did not stop.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I have seen three wars in Gaza before, and this is the hardest.&quot; He wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Rescue is hampered at every turn&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“In Gaza, we never imagined such a scenario: 2 million civilians would live under heavy bombing and face interruptions in water, food, electricity and medicine. . We should take all measures immediately to avoid this situation from happening.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 9, local time, Fabrizio Carboni, Regional Director of the Near and Middle East of the International Committee of the Red Cross, said on social media Platform to speak out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After two weeks of Israel&#39;s sweeping siege, limited aid has finally arrived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public disclosures, three batches of humanitarian relief supplies entered the Gaza Strip from October 21st to 23rd local time, with a total of 57 trucks shipped. These include medical supplies, disinfectant chlorine tablets for water treatment, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, these supplies are really a drop in the bucket for the more than 2 million people in the Gaza Strip. EU foreign policy chief Josep Borrell said in a speech in Luxembourg on October 23 that under normal circumstances, if there is no war, 100 trucks enter Gaza every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Obviously, 20 (trucks) are not enough.&quot; Borrell called for more humanitarian support to be provided. In particular, fuel support will be provided so that power stations and desalination stations can be operated to &quot;restore water and electricity supplies&quot; as quickly as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tamara Alifa&#39;i, spokesperson for the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA), also said that Gaza&#39;s need for fuel is &quot;as urgent as its need for water and food.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite repeated warnings from international relief agencies, the Israeli side still puts the fuel on the embargo list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mark Regev, a senior adviser to the Israeli Prime Minister, publicly stated in an interview on October 23 that Israel would not allow fuel to enter the Gaza Strip even if all hostages were released. Regev explained the reason for the embargo, &quot;These fuels may be stolen by Hamas and used to power rockets.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the conflicts between the parties difficult to reconcile, the operation of hospitals in Gaza is in trouble. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The level of death, destruction and displacement is shocking.” On October 24, Christoph Hanger, public relations officer of the International Committee of the Red Cross, gave a written interview to a reporter from Southern Weekend The agency’s team in Gaza visited hospitals in the northern region on the ground, it said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People sleep in hospital stairwells. Thousands of people, with nowhere to go, seek shelter in hospitals. Building walls shake from nearby explosions. If the situation does not improve, there is no clean drinking water and crowded shelters, the potential for disease outbreaks increases dramatically,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shortages of electricity and fuel have put hospitals in Gaza in dire straits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Without electricity, the hospital will become a morgue.” Christopher said that after the power outage in Gaza, the hospital also stopped supplying power. Newborns in incubators and elderly patients who require oxygen are at risk. Kidney dialysis was interrupted and X-rays could not be taken. He pointed out that most hospitals in Gaza are no longer functioning and they need electricity to maintain their services. The hospital&#39;s situation has become even more difficult as insufficient fuel supplies have affected power generation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A report from surgeons at Al Shifa Hospital in Gaza showed that they worked 24 hours a day to care for the wounded; when they tried to triage patients, they found that they could not cope with the large number of casualties, and &quot;the entire system was saturated.&quot; All operating theaters are occupied”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Doctors report that there is no precedent for such large-scale casualties in previous escalations of conflict.&quot; Christopher said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 17, a hospital in northern Gaza was bombed, causing some casualties. Gaza&#39;s health authorities and the Israeli Defense Ministry called each other the attackers. United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres later strongly condemned the deadly attacks on Gaza hospitals and said hospitals and medical personnel should be protected by international humanitarian law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Palestinian Red Crescent Society&#39;s disclosure on October 22, the area near the Holy City Hospital was heavily shelled that day. In the video released by it, at the moment of the attack, staff wearing Red Crescent uniforms rushed to find refuge on walls, pillars, ambulances and other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;35 employees of the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East have been killed since the conflict broke out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are speechless.” UNRWA posted on social platforms on October 23, “We pay tribute to the 35 colleagues who were killed in Gaza since October 7. They Not just numbers. They are our friends and colleagues. Many are teachers in our schools.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Win or die&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After conflict breaks out, Israel cuts off Water and electricity supply to the Gaza Strip. On October 9, Israel announced a &quot;total blockade&quot; of the Gaza Strip controlled by Hamas and mobilized 300,000 reservists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the war imminent, Israel issued an &quot;expulsion order&quot; to the people of northern Gaza. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Israel Defense Forces informed the United Nations in the early morning of October 13 that it had notified approximately 1.1 million Palestinians in the northern Gaza Strip and required them to evacuate to southern Gaza within 24 hours. On the morning of the 14th, the Israel Defense Forces issued another notice, requiring residents in the northern Gaza Strip to evacuate through the &quot;evacuation corridor&quot; between 10 a.m. and 4 p.m. that day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On an orange paper leaflet printed with the IDF logo, the Israeli army issued a warning to the Gaza people. It read: &quot;Anyone who does not evacuate from the northern valley of Gaza to the south may be considered a member of a terrorist organization.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Multiple Palestinians interviewed confirmed this to Southern Weekend reporters information. But they believe that not everyone will have convenient transportation to leave in a very short period of time. At the same time, the evacuation route is not safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the video sent by Sharif, people evacuating in large tractor-trailer trucks were attacked on the way. On the open-air compartment that was originally filled with women, children, and children, only stumps and blood were left. In another video, in front of the evacuation road with cars, motorcycles, and donkey carts, yellow flames from bombs suddenly rose, and the vehicles turned around one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Actually, both the south and north of Gaza were bombed.&quot; Sharifou said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guterres said before the Security Council’s closed-door consultation on the Palestinian-Israeli situation held on the 13th that more than 1 million residents would be moved from a completely besieged and densely populated war zone to an area without food, drinking water and Housing areas, which are &quot;extremely dangerous&quot; and in some cases &quot;impossible&quot;. He called for the cancellation of the deportation order and hoped that all parties would avoid further escalation and spread of the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharifou told Southern Weekend reporters that his family will not leave Gaza even if the border is reopened. &quot;If we leave, we will lose our home forever. Like 1948 and 1967, we will not repeat the same mistakes.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;After the people evacuated, the livestock that could not be taken away Stay in the ruins. (Photo courtesy of interviewee)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c40fb05f52.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/25/c40fb05f52.png&quot; data-key=&quot;255454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;After the people evacuated, the livestock that could not be taken away were left in the ruins. (Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sharifou’s view, Israel wants to force residents to leave Gaza... They achieve their goals step by step, “first by closing the border and sending us from the north to the south, and then Tell us to leave Gaza and go to Egypt.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sharif&#39;s worries are not groundless. After the Palestinian-Israeli conflict escalated, when US President Biden visited Israel, the United States and Israel jointly proposed a proposal to transfer Gazans to Egypt, but Egypt clearly opposed this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They (Israel) thought that by blowing up all the bakeries, hospitals and houses, people would leave Gaza and run away. But they are wrong, people here will never leave, win or die .&quot; Sharifu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rasha.G lives in the Palestinian area of ​​the West Bank and runs a chocolate business with her husband and children. Affected by the war in Gaza, the atmosphere here has also become tense. &quot;Business is very deserted and people have nothing to celebrate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As she said, to a certain extent, the West Bank is safer than Gaza because there are &quot;no bombs and no air strikes&quot; for the time being. But Resha felt a deep sense of crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resa told Southern Weekend reporters that in the conflicts between Palestine and Israel, many Palestinians evacuated elsewhere, or moved to neighboring countries, such as Egypt, Jordan, Syria, Lebanon, or moved to the Jordan River west coast. But most of them live in refugee camps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You can’t imagine how difficult life is in the refugee camps. There are many people living in a small space and the environment is very poor.” Resha said that in Palestine, many refugees can only rely on the United Nations Near East for their education. Relief and Works Agency. Refugees can find jobs in Palestine, and a small number can do business, but in other countries, these refugees are &quot;not even treated as citizens.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Resa is well-educated, fluent in English, and has lived in Europe for two years. But she returned to Palestine. &quot;I never thought about evacuating. I would not leave my home and become a refugee. I would rather die.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;DIVISION&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The humanitarian crisis in Gaza is imminent, but All parties still have differences on whether to cease fire and carry out rescue operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of now, Spain, the Netherlands, Ireland, Slovenia and Luxembourg have publicly supported the humanitarian ceasefire. Irish Foreign Minister Michael Martin said that &quot;Gaza urgently needs access to water, food and medical supplies.&quot; &quot;The human suffering is enormous. We must distinguish between Gazan civilians and Hamas civilians.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the leaders of the European Union, Germany did not respond to calls for a ceasefire. German Foreign Minister Annalena Berbock said that providing aid to Gaza was important, but large-scale rocket attacks against Israel were taking place. &quot;We cannot end the humanitarian catastrophe while terrorism in Gaza persists.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;U.S. State Department spokesman Matthew Miller told the media on October 23 that the ceasefire will &quot;give Hamas the ability to rest, reorganize and prepare to continue launching terrorist attacks against Israel.&quot; U.S. President Biden also said on the same day that a ceasefire in Gaza would be possible only after Hamas releases all hostages it has held. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the Israeli government, the purpose of this operation was demonstrated as early as the beginning of the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This should be our last ground offensive in Gaza, for the simple reason that Hamas will cease to exist after this.” Israeli Defense Minister Yoav Galant publicly stated that Israel A ground offensive will be launched in the Gaza Strip that will last for several months, aiming to completely eliminate Hamas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, the Palestinian-Israeli conflict continues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the latest statement from the Israeli army, the Israel Defense Forces air raided more than 400 targets of the Hamas organization in the Gaza Strip on October 23, including its armed personnel assembly areas, command centers and a road leading to the seaside. underground tunnels and killed dozens of Hamas commanders and their armed men. The Israeli army also dispatched tanks, artillery and helicopters to attack Hamas military posts and anti-tank missile launch sites. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 23, in response to a reporter’s question, Foreign Ministry spokesperson Mao Ning said that China is very saddened by the large number of civilian casualties caused by the Palestinian-Israeli conflict and the sharp deterioration of the humanitarian situation. Responding to violence with violence will only lead to a vicious cycle. The top priority is to cease fire and end the war as soon as possible. All parties should earnestly abide by international law and international humanitarian law, protect civilians, and make every effort to avoid serious humanitarian disasters. The international community should provide more humanitarian assistance to the people of Gaza to alleviate the humanitarian disaster they have suffered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, China will continue to support all efforts that are conducive to promoting dialogue and restoring peace, and make efforts to implement the &quot;two-state solution&quot; and promote a comprehensive, fair and lasting solution to the Palestinian issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Gu Yuebing and Southern Weekend intern Zhai Huan also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>