<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[公安部：缅北共向我方移交电信网络诈骗犯罪嫌疑人3.1万名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260984]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 11:23:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/21/7da4b29319035f4df2cd598d3cac1f3c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;7008&quot; height=&quot;4672&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/21/7da4b29319035f4df2cd598d3cac1f3c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258936&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of the current severe situation of telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, the Ministry of Public Security has deployed public security agencies in Yunnan and other places to continue to promote border police We have cooperated with law enforcement and carried out multiple rounds of crackdowns. So far, relevant local law enforcement departments in northern Myanmar have handed over to us a total of 31,000 suspects of telecommunications network fraud, including 63 behind-the-scenes &quot;financiers&quot;, organizational leaders and backbones. There are 1,531 fugitives, and the crackdown has achieved remarkable results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since September this year, under the command and deployment of the Ministry of Public Security and the Yunnan Provincial Public Security Department, public security agencies in Xishuangbanna, Pu&#39;er, Lincang and other places have carried out border police law enforcement cooperation with relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar, and carried out a series of During the crackdown, a large number of telecommunications network fraud suspects were handed over to us one after another, achieving remarkable results. Since November, in order to advance the crackdown in depth, our public security organs have further deepened police law enforcement cooperation between China and Myanmar and launched a fierce offensive against telecom network fraud crimes in northern Myanmar. The results have been remarkable and good news has been reported frequently. Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen, the important leaders of the Kokang telecom network fraud criminal group in northern Myanmar who were publicly wanted by our public security organs, were successfully arrested and brought to justice. The first criminal Ming Xuechang committed suicide in fear of crime. A large number of overseas fraud dens were successfully eradicated, which dealt a severe blow. The arrogance of overseas fraud groups. On November 18, the Dehong Public Security Bureau made an important breakthrough in border police law enforcement cooperation. The law enforcement department in the Muse region in northern Myanmar handed over 571 telecommunications network fraud suspects to us one after another, forming a strong deterrent to fraudsters. So far, with the strong cooperation of all parties in Myanmar, a total of 31,000 telecommunications network fraud suspects have been handed over to us and have been successively taken back by the public security organs of the places involved. The public security organs will thoroughly investigate all illegal and criminal facts and resolutely punish them severely in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ee443362355a261326cc529713496e08.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/21/ee443362355a261326cc529713496e08.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258935&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the public security agency stated that they will always maintain a high-pressure and severe crackdown on telecommunications network fraud criminal groups in northern Myanmar, continue to deepen police law enforcement cooperation on the China-Myanmar border, continue to organize special crackdowns, make every effort to clear out fraud dens, and arrest people in accordance with the law. Those involved in fraud must resolutely safeguard the safety of life, property and legitimate rights and interests of the people, and effectively maintain border security and stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 11:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[奥本海默：电影与传记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260939]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/nb3RZ0KzIfdWagl85AZGBXSuXlgM0RAhLVDd5Haw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1298&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/nb3RZ0KzIfdWagl85AZGBXSuXlgM0RAhLV Dd5Haw. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258848&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Reading &quot;The Biography of Oppenheimer&quot; can help us understand many scenes in the movie. On the left is the poster of the movie &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; and on the right is the movie &quot;The Biography of Oppenheimer&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The movie &quot;Oppenheimer&quot; which has been released globally (except Japan) since the summer of 2023 It is adapted from &quot;Oppenheimer: The Triumph and Tragedy of the Father of the American Atomic Bomb&quot; (CITIC Press, 2023) written by two Pulitzer Prize winners, Kay Byrd and Martin Sherwin. The movie can be said to be very faithful to the original work. There is almost no key dialogue between the characters that is not based on the original work. Of course, due to the time limit of the film, many conversations from different occasions were grafted into one scene. For example, President Truman said that Oppenheimer was a &quot;crying scientist&quot; in a text message to his acting Secretary of State Acheson, not in person in the movie, but Oppenheimer did say this to Truman in person. &quot;I feel like my hands are stained with blood,&quot; and Truman replied, &quot;The blood is on my hands, let me worry about it&quot; (p. 393). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, reading &quot;The Biography of Oppenheimer&quot; can help us understand many scenes in the movie. When Oppenheimer first met his devoted girlfriend Joan Tatlock (a child psychiatrist who committed suicide at the age of 29), Joan discovered that he was very familiar with the different schools of psychoanalysis. If we don’t read the biography, we may generally understand that Oppenheimer is amazingly knowledgeable in both arts and sciences, which is indeed true; but the biography tells us that Oppenheimer understood the different schools of psychoanalysis and his own treatment. It is related to his experience, which also explains the incident in which he gave his Cambridge tutor Blackett (the 1948 Nobel Prize winner in physics and a famous British socialist) a &quot;poison apple&quot; when he had a mental breakdown (p. 61). When the movie deals with this incident, Bohr, a Danish physicist and one of the founders of quantum mechanics, picks up an apple, only to have it snatched away by Oppenheimer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/7y9GAec50FgO29ZkMoUxJCO3Hqq0Uc4lSttAE4xP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height= &quot;1125&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/7y9GAec50FgO29ZkMoUxJCO3Hqq0Uc4lSttAE4xP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258847&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Oppenheimer (1904-1967). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oppenheimer had many mental crises in his youth. It was with his upper-middle-class Jewish family that related to family background. His father immigrated to New York from Frankfurt, Germany in 1888 and gradually became a successful clothing businessman. However, discrimination against Jews was widespread in Western society at that time. In June 1925, when Oppenheimer was preparing to study at the University of Cambridge in England, his Harvard undergraduate tutor wrote this recommendation letter to him: &quot;You can tell from his name that he is a Jew, but there is nothing common about him that is Jewish. Characteristics. He is slender, handsome in appearance, and has the air of a humble gentleman. When considering his application, I don’t think you need to have any concerns because of his Jewish background.” (Page 52) Oppenheimer’s friend La Isidor Rabi (who won the 1944 Nobel Prize in Physics for the discovery of nuclear magnetic resonance, which is now widely used in hospitals) later recalled: &quot;I don&#39;t know if he considered himself Jewish, I think he fancied that he was not Jewish. I I remember he once said to me, &#39;I find Christianity very confusing, its mixture of blood and grace.&#39; He said that was what attracted him&quot; (p. 98). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oppenheimer&#39;s Jewish family background was obviously one of the important factors in his transition from an apolitical physicist to an active participant in political activities after 1936, because he had to rescue several Relatives who were persecuted by the Nazis helped them immigrate from Germany to the United States. But the more important factor that prompted him to care about politics was that California, where he taught at the University of California and the California Institute of Technology, was the home base of radical political movements in Roosevelt&#39;s New Deal. In 1934, the famous author Upton Sinclair almost became governor with his &quot;Plan to End Poverty in California.&quot; In 1938, left-wing Democrat Cabot Olson was elected governor of California with the open support of the state&#39;s Communist Party. His campaign slogan was &quot;Building a United Front Against Fascism&quot; (p. 142). Oppenheimer&#39;s girlfriend, wife, brother and sister-in-law were all dues-paying members of the Communist Party of the United States. The ex-husband of Oppenheimer&#39;s wife joined the Lincoln Detachment funded by the Communist Party of the United States in 1936 and died on the battlefield defending the Spanish republican system. Kenneth May, a doctoral student in the Department of Mathematics at the University of California, Berkeley, was the head of the Communist Party of the United States in Berkeley (page 172). He went to Oppenheimer&#39;s house several times to discuss political issues. Years later, he proved that in democracy The &quot;May&#39;s Theorem&quot; about simple majorities is very important in mathematical theory. Haakon Chevalier, a French literature teacher at the University of California, Berkeley, became a good friend of Oppenheimer. In 1934, he translated into English the novel &quot;The Human Condition&quot; by French writer André Malraux (who later served as President de Gaulle&#39;s Minister of Culture), which was set during the Chinese Revolution in 1927. In the spring of 1937, Chivalier accompanied Malraux on a visit to California. (Page 147) In the subsequent hearings on Oppenheimer in 1954, the &quot;Chivalier incident&quot; became the focus of questioning Oppenheimer&#39;s &quot;national loyalty.&quot; This incident has been prominently shown in the movie and will not be discussed further here. Biography can be helpful in understanding the &quot;Chivalier Incident&quot; in the movie: Chvalier and many of Oppenheimer&#39;s Communist friends believed that the United States should be informed of the plan of the United States to try to build an atomic bomb before Hitler&#39;s Germany. The Soviet Union was the ally that made the greatest sacrifice in the fascist war. Oppenheimer agreed with this view in principle, but he firmly opposed personal leaks through the back door and believed that the US government should inform the Soviet Union (page 282). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/CmZwCvdycnQzIrLl2wwBY1fhuGbElNuCFWucs4Oy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;708&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/CmZwCvdycnQzIrLl2wwBY1fhuGbElNuCFWucs4Oy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258845&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Lewis Strauss, Chairman of the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission (first from left) &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course , we can criticize Oppenheimer for being too naive. However, most scientists who participated in the &quot;Manhattan Project&quot; were deeply disturbed that the achievements of 300 years of modern science were mainly reflected in the creation of atomic bombs that could destroy mankind. On October 5, 1943, Oppenheimer&#39;s spiritual idol, the Danish physicist Bohr, escaped from Nazi-occupied Copenhagen by hiding in the bomb bay of a British bomber. After he came to Los Alamos, the site of the Manhattan Project, he persuaded Oppenheimer to turn his attention to the postwar consequences of the atomic bomb. Bohr believed that the Soviets must be informed of the existence of the nuclear bomb project and ensure that it would not pose a threat to them, in order to avoid a postwar nuclear arms race (p. 319). In the spring of 1944, Bohr held private meetings with Roosevelt and Churchill, but failed to persuade the leaders of the United States and Britain to share plans for atomic bomb production with the Soviet Union. Despite this, most scientists who participated in the &quot;Manhattan Project&quot; still regarded Bohr as God and Oppenheimer as a prophet of God (p. 326). Interestingly, Oppenheimer called the first atomic bomb test the &quot;Trinity Experiment,&quot; implying that man was becoming &quot;God&quot; (p. 679). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Oppenheimer participated in the &quot;Manhattan Project&quot; and became its scientific director in order to build the atomic bomb before the Nazis, then he was already very reluctant to the decision to drop the atomic bomb in Japan (this The reason why he told President Truman that he had blood on his hands). By the summer of 1952, Oppenheimer was clearly and firmly opposed to the United States experimenting with a hydrogen bomb that was thousands of times more powerful than the atomic bomb. &quot;Opposing the development of the hydrogen bomb&quot; was one of the two accusations against Oppenheimer (the other one was the aforementioned &quot;Khiva&quot;) in the 1954 hearings held by U.S. Atomic Energy Commission Chairman Lewis Strauss (the main scene of the movie). Lié incident&quot;). But in fact, opposition to the development of hydrogen bombs is the unanimous opinion of the Advisory Committee of the Atomic Energy Commission, chaired by Oppenheimer, whose members include Nobel Prize winners in physics Fermi, Lawrence, and Harvard University President Conant (page 495) . The hydrogen bomb (fusion reaction), which is more terrifying than the atomic bomb (fission reaction), will definitely escalate the nuclear arms race. As Vannevar Bush, who had a great influence on the formulation of U.S. science and technology policy after World War II, said when testifying in support of Oppenheimer at a hearing in 1954: &quot;I maintain that that experiment (referring to the 1952 U.S. hydrogen bomb experiment ) made it impossible for us to reach the only feasible agreement with the Soviet Union, which was that neither side would conduct experiments again.&quot; (Page 626) George Kennan, the proposer of the &quot;containment&quot; strategy not shown in the movie, also opposed the development of the hydrogen bomb. When he attended a hearing in 1954 to defend Oppenheimer&#39;s participation in the left-wing movement when he was young, he said, &quot;If the church only focused on his youth when judging St. Francis, he would not have become what he later became.&quot; In fact, as early as January 1950, after an in-depth discussion with Oppenheimer, Kennan wrote a report in the form of a &quot;personal note&quot; to Secretary of State Acheson opposing the development of the hydrogen bomb, and Acheson told Kennan He said that after writing this report, it would be best to consider resigning. After leaving the government, Kennan spent the rest of his life at the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton (p. 503). This also shows that the strategy actually implemented by the United States in the Cold War was not Kennan&#39;s &quot;containment&quot; but the National Security Council (NSC) drafted in April 1950 by Paul Nitze, who took over as director of the Office of Policy Planning of the State Department after Kennan resigned. - Document No. 68, which clearly rejected Kennan&#39;s &quot;no first use of nuclear weapons&quot; policy proposition. (Page 507)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The villain in the movie is undoubtedly Strauss. He not only fought against Oppenheimer as chairman of the Atomic Energy Commission, but also continued to fight against Oppenheimer as chairman of the board of directors of the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton. An interesting example is: Strauss opposed Oppenheimer&#39;s proposal to hire Kantolovitch, the author of The King&#39;s Two Bodies, because he refused to require the University of California to require teachers to swear an oath not to join the Communist Party, despite a later U.S. Supreme Court decision UC’s oath requirement is unconstitutional. Strauss was a self-made millionaire. In 1917, when he was 21 years old, he worked as an unpaid assistant to future U.S. President Herbert Hoover. He used this as a springboard to get the opportunity to enter a Wall Street investment bank ( page 427). He was extremely ideologically opposed to the domestic and foreign policies of Roosevelt&#39;s New Deal. At the same time, he is extremely sensitive and has a pathological ego. A scene in the movie is that at his 54th birthday party, he wanted to introduce his son and daughter-in-law to the &quot;celebrity&quot; Oppenheimer, but because that day President Truman denied the objections of Oppenheimer and other scientist advisors. Oppenheimer was in a very bad mood over the hydrogen bomb suggestion and was very rude to Strauss&#39;s son and daughter-in-law. This was one of the reasons why Strauss held a grudge against Oppenheimer. But Strauss was cunning and knew that Oppenheimer, as the &quot;Father of the Atomic Bomb&quot; on the cover of Time magazine, would not be easily brought down completely. Therefore, he only held a meeting within the Atomic Energy Commission to discuss whether to revoke Oppenheimer&#39;s safety. Internal hearings on the permit, without letting Senator McCarthy intervene, because he believed that the extremely hysterical McCarthy might mess things up. Strauss finally got his wish, and the hearing revoked Oppenheimer&#39;s security clearance, but still said he had no doubts about Oppenheimer&#39;s loyalty to the country. Oppenheimer was able to retain his position as director of the Institute for Advanced Study in Princeton, but he was completely eliminated from U.S. technology and defense policymaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Einstein appears at the beginning and end of the movie. Einstein is quoted in the biography: &quot;Oppenheimer&#39;s problem was that he fell in love with a woman who didn&#39;t love him - the U.S. government... The problem was actually very simple. Oppenheimer only had to go to Washington and tell Officials, they&#39;re all fools, then go home” (p. 596). Einstein also suggested that Oppenheimer leave the United States to conduct research in Europe, but Oppenheimer&#39;s response was: &quot;Hell, I love this country deeply.&quot; This is Oppenheimer&#39;s tragedy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 11:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[池田大作 “真正的成功的人生是什么呢？”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260976]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/20/LzbyXRcNYzMvh1Rfw8pMR2QZejt5jYRjMxY1i7mh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/20/LzbyXRcNYzMvh1Rfw8pMR2QZejt 5jYRjMxY1i7mh. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258930&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On April 24, 1979 local time, Daisaku Ikeda held a press conference in Tokyo, Japan , announced his resignation as president of the Soka Gakkai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1996, a &quot;nuclear weapon threat exhibition&quot; was held in San Jose, the capital of the Republic of Costa Rica in South America. hold. At the opening ceremony, just as the participants solemnly sang the national anthem in unison, suddenly, a series of children&#39;s voices came from the &quot;Children&#39;s Museum&quot; across the wall. That was the laughter of primary school students who were impatiently waiting for the opening of the exhibition. The bursts of laughter disrupted the guests&#39; speeches many times. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The lively and energetic laughter of children is a symbol and embodiment of peace. These laughters are filled with the power of hope to fight against the &#39;nuclear threat&#39;.&quot; Daisaku Ikeda at the opening ceremony Listening to the children&#39;s voices, I smiled and said, &quot;This is the indicator of a sound society.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Daisaku Ikeda is the third president of the Soka Gakkai of Japan. He expanded the scope of the Soka Gakkai. scale and developed it into the largest religious organization in Japan. He also actively participated in politics and founded the Komeito Party in 1964. To this day, Soka Gakkai remains the main supporter of Komeito. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Daisaku Ikeda’s greatest contribution was to promote the secularization of Nichiren Buddhism. For Ikeda, Nichiren Buddhism is a philosophy of life that actively integrates into the modern world and society and actively faces all challenges in it. Ikeda devoted his life to promoting culture, education, and peace, and won the United Nations Peace Prize in 1983. Regarding Sino-Japanese relations, he proposed the initiative to normalize diplomatic relations between China and Japan in the 1960s. He was received by Zhou Enlai and Deng Xiaoping, and was awarded the title of &quot;Peace Envoy&quot; for Sino-Japanese friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aversion to war, the desire for peace, and the exploration of the dignity of life ran through Ikeda’s life until the end of his life. The Soka Gakkai of Japan announced on November 18, 2023 that Daisaku Ikeda, honorary president of the Soka Gakkai and founder of the Komeito Party, passed away on November 15, 2023, at the age of 95. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Dialogue is the foundation of peace&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On January 26, 1975, a special rally was held in Guam. This was one of the bloodiest battlefields of World War II. Soka Gakkai members from 50 countries and regions around the world gathered here and established the International Soka Gakkai International, headed by President Daisei Ikeda. The place was chosen as the venue for the meeting as a symbol of the new peace movement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I was born in 1928, which was a war-torn era. In my young mind, I had already deeply realized that nothing is more tragic and nothing is more cruel than war, so I I made up my mind to never let such inhumane tragedies continue to happen in the future.&quot; In 2020, in an interview with Global magazine, Daisaku Ikeda recalled the origins of his desire for peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1928, Daisaku Ikeda was born in Tokyo. His family made a living from seaweed farming. There are eight children in the family, and Ikeda ranks fifth. The era when Ikeda grew up was a period when Japan was moving towards war under the leadership of the military government. Japan was plunged into the abyss of world war, and all walks of life in the country - from families, factories, schools to religious groups, were forced to serve in the war effort. All opposition voices were brutally suppressed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1937, Japan launched a full-scale war of aggression against China. Ikeda&#39;s eldest brother Kiichi was drafted into the army, followed by his three brothers. Ikeda often mentioned Kiichi in his conversations and writings. He said that when Kiichi returned home on a vacation, he described to him the brutal behavior of the Japanese army in China, his tone full of disgust. He also mentioned that after the war, the whole family was looking forward to Kiichi&#39;s return, but in the end they waited for the news that he had died on the battlefield. The scene of his mother silently accepting Xiyi&#39;s white urn was something he would never forget in his life. &quot;Aside from anger... I deeply understand how cruel, ignorant and meaningless war is.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a boy, Ikeda&#39;s home was destroyed twice in air raids. He also personally experienced the Tokyo bombing on March 9-10, 1945, in which more than 100,000 people were killed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of World War II, Ikeda was 17 years old. He described: &quot;The young people at that time were left with an indelible spiritual void. It was not just the country that was burned. The hypocrisy of the fanatical militaristic values ​​that had been instilled since before the war was exposed after the war. There was nothing left, so it immediately fell apart.&amp;nbsp;Many young people fell into the despair of &quot;not believing in anything&quot; because of this. This seems to be an inevitable conclusion.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such despair also occurs in Regarding Ikeda, he wrote, &quot;For those who once glorified war and sacrificed many young people on the battlefield, but after the war they transformed into intellectuals pursuing peace and democracy. No matter how they dressed themselves, I absolutely cannot believe the rhetoric of these powerful people.&amp;nbsp;”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the turbulent international situation of the last century, Ikeda has always played the role of a messenger of peace. He firmly advocated: dialogue is peace fundamental. Since 1970, he has been engaged in dialogue activities with representatives from all over the world in the humanities, politics, traditional beliefs, culture, education and academia. He seeks consensus from dialogue and finds solutions to the complex problems facing humanity. More than 70 of these conversations have been published in books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During his lifetime, Ikeda co-authored &quot;Looking into the Twenty-first Century&quot; with the British historian Toynbee, co-authored &quot;Spiritual Lessons of the Twentieth Century&quot; with the last leader of the Soviet Union, Mikhail Gorbachev, and co-authored with Jin Yong Author of &quot;In Search of a Glorious Century&quot;. Since November 16, 1995, Ikeda and Jin Yong have met many times in Hong Kong, China and Japan, during which they even exchanged letters and never stopped communicating. Jin Yong once said: &quot;The conversations are impromptu, sometimes at the dinner table, sometimes during tea talks, sometimes while admiring the beauty of the landscape and the garden.&quot; They focused on many issues such as the return of Hong Kong, Buddhist philosophy, literature, etc. There was a serious discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1993, shortly after the end of the Cold War, a research institution was established on the east coast of the United States adjacent to Harvard University. Originally named &quot;Boston 21st Century Research Center&quot;, it was renamed &quot;Ikeda Center for Peace, Education, and Dialogue&quot; in 2009. The center expands the peace and humanitarian network by inviting experts and scholars from various fields around the world to hold various seminars to conduct in-depth discussions on peace, human rights, environment, education, culture and other issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Advocating Sino-Japanese friendship as a common man&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 8, 1968, at a rally attended by more than 10,000 Soka Gakkai students At the meeting, Daisaku Ikeda made a speech that was considered &quot;bold&quot;. He called for the normalization of diplomatic relations between Japan and China and proposed specific steps to achieve this goal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, many Japanese regarded China as an enemy country, and China was relatively isolated in the international community. Ikeda&#39;s suggestion drew criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, this suggestion also attracted the attention of some people in China and Japan who were concerned about the restoration of diplomatic relations between the two countries, including Zhou Enlai. In addition, Kenzo Matsumura, a member of the Japanese House of Representatives who supported the restoration of normal relations between the two countries at the time, also contacted Ikeda after his speech and urged him to visit China. However, Ikeda believes that politicians should start this matter, so he suggested that a delegation of Komeito members should visit China. Sino-Japanese relations began to improve, and the two countries finally restored diplomatic relations in 1972. In May 1974, Ikeda led a delegation to visit China, and he led delegations to visit China many times in the following decades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 1974, during their second visit to China, Ikeda and his delegation were received by Deng Xiaoping, then Vice Premier of the State Council. Zhou Enlai, who was hospitalized due to illness, met with Ikeda and all members of the Soka Gakkai&#39;s second visit to China in Beijing despite the objections of the medical team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years later, Daisaku Ikeda still remembered this interview vividly, &quot;Premier Zhou once said to me when looking forward to the 21st century that the last 25 years of the 20th century will be the most important period for the world. The whole world must respect each other on an equal footing and encourage each other for mutual benefit. Premier Zhou also said clearly in a bold voice, &#39;I hope that the China-Japan Treaty of Peace and Friendship can be concluded at an early date.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The year after the meeting with Premier Zhou, that is, 1975, since there were no universities in Japan open to Chinese students to study abroad at that time, Ikeda personally acted as a guarantor, so that the first batch of six publicly funded overseas students in New China could smoothly study at Soka University he founded. Soka University was the first school in Japan to accept publicly funded international students from China, and has since continued to accept publicly funded and self-funded international students from China to this day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the world was in a tense period of confrontation between superpowers, and nuclear weapons seriously threatened the survival of mankind. Ikeda expressed his hope that as a common man, he could do his best to ease the tense situation at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda visited China, the Soviet Union and the United States in 1974 and 1975, and was received by Chinese Premier Zhou Enlai, Soviet Prime Minister Kosygin, and U.S. Secretary of State Kissinger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He described the situation at that time:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“From 1974 to 1975, I visited China, the Soviet Union and the United States one after another, directly having dialogues with the heads of state, and exploring the situation from the perspective of a private person. A way to ease tensions. At that time, in addition to the confrontation between the United States and the Soviet Union, there was also tension between China and the Soviet Union, which made the world face a crisis of tripolarization.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&quot;When I visited China for the first time in May 1974 , visited the large-scale air-raid shelter built by Beijing citizens and was known as the &quot;Underground Great Wall&quot;, and felt firsthand the threat posed by the Soviet Union to the Chinese people. In September of the same year, I visited the Soviet Union for the first time. When meeting with Prime Minister Kosygin, I frankly Asked him if the Soviet Union had any intention to attack China. Prime Minister Kosygin asserted that the Soviet Union had no intention of attacking or isolating China.&quot;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&quot;In December of the same year, I visited China again with this information. During this visit to China During this period, I had the honor to meet with Premier Zhou Enlai. During the meeting, we jointly confirmed the importance of Japan and China working together for world peace and prosperity.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&quot;Here, I heard Premier Zhou Enlai say that China We will definitely not become a superpower. Based on the content of my previous dialogue with Prime Minister Kosygin, I am convinced that the day of Sino-Soviet reconciliation will not be too far away. In fact, history has proven that my prediction was right.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br >;&lt;br>;&quot;In January 1975, I visited the United States and met with Secretary of State Kissinger in a lightly snowing Washington. During the meeting, I told him that Premier Zhou earnestly hoped to conclude a treaty of friendship between Japan and China at an early date. Dr. Kissinger expressed his great Agree.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br>;&lt;br>;&quot;On the same day, I met Prime Minister Ohira Masayoshi (then Minister of Finance) in Washington. I conveyed Dr. Kissinger&#39;s words to him and emphasized the importance of concluding a treaty. Prime Minister Ohira I fully agree and will work hard to realize it. Three years later, in August 1978, the &quot;Sino-Japanese Treaty of Peace and Friendship&quot; was finally formally concluded.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;A society eager for change&lt;/strong >;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In mid-August 1947, defeated Japan was under the control of the Allies. At night people can only see dim lights flickering in temporary shacks or bomb shelters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Daisaku Ikeda’s later recollection, at a time when everything was in dire straits, the entire Japanese society was eager for change. Calls for democracy could be heard on every street corner, and the faith of a generation collapsed. At this time, young people are eager to read classics to enrich their spiritual world and build confidence. People started exchanging books and forming reading groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this time, 19-year-old Daisaku Ikeda met his life mentor and the second president of the Soka Gakkai, Toda Josei. It was a Buddhist exchange meeting. Toda Castle left a deep impression on Ikeda: his hoarse and warm voice, steady demeanor, and the content of his speech was not like other religious leaders, and it did not contain empty terms and theories at all. It is very down-to-earth, as if the highest truth exists in daily life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Toda was rebuilding the Soka Gakkai, the organization he had founded in 1930 with fellow educator Tsunesaburo Makiguchi. During World War II, Toda was imprisoned along with Makiguchi. The Japanese military government forced its people to accept state Shinto ideology as a means of sanctifying its war of aggression. The two men still adhered to their religious beliefs under oppression, and Makiguchi died in prison. The Soka Gakkai collapsed when Toda and Makiguchi were arrested by the military government during the war. Toda was convinced that Nichiren Buddhism, which focused on the infinite potential within each person, was the key to transforming Japanese society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda and Toda met each other late in life, and have been friends since then. Ikeda was deeply interested in literature since childhood and began writing poetry as a teenager. When he was unable to continue his studies due to various reasons, Toda, a knowledgeable educator, personally taught him. Ikeda quickly accepted the teachings of the Soka Gakkai and joined 10 days later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Toda, Ikeda has unwavering confidence in Nichiren Buddhism and believes that its emphasis on the Buddha nature and unlimited potential of every human being can revitalize the decadent post-war Japanese society. . The key is a process of &quot;human nature transformation&quot; that unfolds in people&#39;s hearts. In that process, when a person decides to take action for his or her life and happiness, the surrounding environment and community will change for the better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the company run by Toda was on the verge of bankruptcy, Ikeda devoted himself to helping him manage the business. Unable to receive their salaries, employees left Toda&#39;s company one after another. Ikeda insisted on not leaving and was running around to negotiate with the company&#39;s creditors on debt repayment. &quot;I haven&#39;t received a salary for half a year, my leather shoes are tattered, I don&#39;t have formal clothes, and my body is extremely weak. Even so, I thought that as long as I can protect Mr. Toda, it doesn&#39;t matter even if I suffer the torture of the hungry ghost world and the hell world, Determined to never regret.&quot; Ikeda recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In such a difficult period, Toda revealed his idea of ​​running a school to Ikeda - to establish a series of education from elementary school to university based on the Soka pedagogy concept of his teacher Makiguchi Tsunezaburo. School. Such an idea seemed unrealistic at the time, but Ikeda, who was only in his twenties, took Toda&#39;s words to heart. Twenty years later, Ikeda turned Toda&#39;s ideal into reality and founded a Soka education institution from kindergarten to university. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1960, two years after Toda&#39;s death, 32-year-old Daisaku Ikeda was appointed as the third president of the Soka Gakkai. Fifteen years later, Daisaku Ikeda founded the Soka Gakkai International. Today, Soka Gakkai International is an international organization composed of 12 million members in more than 190 countries and regions. Ikeda wrote: &quot;Everything depends on people. Therefore, we must resolutely and thoroughly expand the alliance of good people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some media commented that Ikeda has led a &quot;Buddhist secular movement&quot; on a global scale. Movement”, established a complete education system based on religion and its values ​​to inspire individual potential and teach the importance of peace and contribution to society. The system runs from kindergarten to graduate school, with institutions including universities in Tokyo and California, USA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda has stated many times that the mentor-disciple relationship with Toda has affected his life. Unlike other religions that highlight the importance of suffering in life, Ikeda emphasizes the positive and optimistic side. He often said that by helping others gain happiness, he would also gain happiness. For Ikeda, happiness means &quot;being true to oneself&quot;, and he believes that only in this way can happiness be increased in an infinite way. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Fundamental Dignity of Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“One person’s great human transformation can change the fate of a country or even all mankind.” Ikeda put this sentence Written in the preface to the novel &quot;Human Revolution,&quot; Ikeda&#39;s masterpiece, this novel describes the history and ideals of the Soka Gakkai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the decades of developing the Soka Gakkai, Ikeda’s job was not easy. His wife, Kamineko, recalled that whenever Ikeda came home after a day at work, he was often so exhausted that he could barely take off his shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda was invited to give a lecture at the University of California, Los Angeles in 1974. The following year, he gave a lecture on &quot;New Paths for East-West Cultural Exchange&quot; at Moscow State University and received an honorary doctorate from the university. When the world was in the grip of the Cold War, Ikeda did not choose to take sides in the political confrontation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda valued the fundamental dignity of life as the key to lasting peace and human happiness. He believes that to achieve world peace, it ultimately depends on the inner change of each person, rather than solely on the reform of social and organizational structures. He firmly believes that this seemingly long road is the only way to build a lasting culture of peace. The philosophy held by the Soka Gakkai can be summed up in the term &quot;human revolution.&quot; According to the meaning contained in this concept, a spontaneous inner change will have a positive impact on the external environment and promote the growth of human society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, the number of honorary doctorates and honorary professorships awarded to Ikeda by academic institutions around the world has exceeded 300. His peace writings are now selected as university textbooks in Argentina and the United States, and more than twenty research institutes are dedicated to studying his philosophy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ikeda founded a series of &lt;span>;&lt;span>;Soka education institutions from kindergarten to university&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;. These schools are non-religious schools. Their educational purpose is to treat each student as a unique being, strive to explore their potential to create value, and instill in them concepts such as peace, social contribution and global citizenship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Ikeda’s view, children’s lives are a mirror of society: If adults promote a chaotic and decadent outlook on life to teenagers, it is equivalent to the buds of hope that will be full of longing for the future. Trampled ruthlessly. &quot;Isn&#39;t it true that the hearts of children who are unsatisfied and desolate can easily be misled unconsciously into the kind of cold values ​​​​that only determine their success or failure based on the abundance of money?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&quot;What is a truly successful life?&amp;nbsp;What is a truly wealthy society?&quot;&amp;nbsp;Ikeda feels about the era he has experienced, which was a society with long-term hollowing out of values, and this is what he always recalls. They all described it as a &quot;painful&quot; experience, but regarding happiness and the dignity of life, he chose to spend his life &quot;sincerely searching for the correct answers (to these questions).&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Source: Soka Gakkai Global Network, &quot;Sowing the Seeds of Hope&quot; by Daisaku Ikeda, &quot;The Wisdom of the Lotus Sutra&quot; (Volume Six)&quot;.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[心脑血管发病年轻化，看看这份防治“地图”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260972]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/20/ae893efa1f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 20/ae893efa1f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258929&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The National Center for Cardiovascular Diseases is investigating the incidence of acute myocardial infarction and stroke. In the patient survey, it was found that the age of first onset of disease has a downward trend. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;By 2030, the awareness rate of hypertension among residents over 30 years old will be no less than 65%, and the rate of standardized management of hypertension patients will not be low. More than 70%, the mortality rate from cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases has dropped to less than 190.7 per 100,000, and the overall 5-year cancer survival rate in the field of cancer has reached more than 46.6%.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left ;&quot;>;The above new goals come from the &quot;Healthy China Action - Cancer Prevention and Control Action Implementation Plan (2023-2030)&quot; and the &quot;Healthy China Action - Cardiovascular and Cerebrovascular Disease Prevention and Control Action Implementation Plan (2023-2030)&quot;. On November 15, 2023, two sets of plans were jointly issued by 13 departments including the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters compared the plan released in 2019 and found that the new version of the plan has further improved the main goals. In the cancer prevention and treatment plan, the overall 5-year cancer survival rate is nearly 3 percentage points higher than the 2019 plan; the mortality rate from cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases was previously required to drop to 209.7/100,000 in 2022. In terms of prevention and treatment methods, more emphasis is placed on moving the frontier forward and integrating medical and prevention, focusing on the entire process of health, and putting people&#39;s health at the center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;We all know that prevention is the most economical and effective health strategy. Both plans insist on prevention as the main focus, strengthen the control of risk factors of chronic diseases, and improve the Full-process management from prevention of chronic diseases, screening of high-risk groups to early diagnosis, standardized treatment and integrated rehabilitation services.&quot; said Guo Yanhong, director of the Medical Emergency Department of the National Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Expand the coverage of cancer screening and improve the accessibility of HPV vaccine&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Promoting cancer prevention and treatment to move forward&quot; is the new cancer prevention and treatment plan A major feature. As of 2022, the early diagnosis rate of key cancer types in high-incidence areas in China has reached more than 55%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The main method used in cancer screening is &quot;risk stratification&quot;, which is to conduct organized screening for areas with high cancer incidence and key groups with higher risk, and at the same time, through Opportunistic screening and standardized cancer prevention physical examinations will expand screening coverage. Zhang Yong, Secretary of the Party Committee of the National Cancer Center, suggested that residents with a relatively high risk of cancer, such as those with a family history of cancer, long-term smoking and drinking, a history of occupational exposure, or patients with hepatitis B and precancerous diseases, should undergo regular cancer screening. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with the previous version of the plan, the new version of the cancer prevention and treatment plan also mentions that qualified areas will be promoted to incorporate HPV vaccination into local policies to benefit the people. For those who meet the requirements The review and approval of the domestically produced HPV vaccine will be accelerated, the accessibility of the HPV vaccine will be improved, and various channels will be used to ensure vaccination for people of appropriate age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Regional Exploration and Improvement Strategies for HPV Vaccine Benefit Policies&quot; released by the Vaccine Delivery Research and Innovation Laboratory of Duke Kunshan University mentioned that if vaccination can Further optimization of the strategy can further enhance the policy influence on public health. For example, many local policies apply to girls with school registration or household registration, but provide insufficient protection for migrants or girls who have dropped out of middle school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Shenglan, founding director of the Global Health Research Center at Duke Kunshan University and head of the Vaccine Delivery Research Innovation Laboratory, told Southern Weekend reporters that it is necessary to protect poor areas or poor people The only feasible and effective way to improve the vaccination coverage of HPV vaccine among people of appropriate age is to include HPV vaccine in the national immunization plan, that is, it will become a first-class vaccine for free vaccination. The source of funds can be through national financial support or subsidies from medical insurance funds. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Provinces such as Guangdong, Hainan, Jiangxi, Fujian, Tibet, and Chongqing have successively launched or announced that they will launch free HPV vaccination programs across the region. Most regions have established a collaborative mechanism of &quot;government leadership, department coordination, and social participation&quot; to not only reduce the economic cost of HPV vaccination for school-age girls in a free or subsidized manner, but also through multiple departments and institutions such as the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, hospitals, and schools. Participation and the cooperation of media publicity have improved public awareness of the HPV vaccine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;These policies also bring about a wind vane effect, which also plays a leading role in the HPV vaccination of local people not covered by the policy.&quot; National Cancer Center, said Zhao Fanghui, director of the Epidemiology Research Office of the Cancer Hospital of the Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Improve the first aid system and strengthen the provision of AEDs in public places&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;National Cardiovascular Disease Center’s investigation of patients with acute myocardial infarction and stroke , a downward trend in the age of first onset of disease was found. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hu Shengshou, director of the National Center for Cardiovascular Disease and academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering, believes that the main reason is the urbanization process of my country&#39;s economic development over the past 40 years of reform and opening up. The impact of lifestyle changes. For example, in terms of diet, the proportion of fresh fruits, vegetables and milk in the diet of Chinese residents has indeed increased significantly, but the proportion of whole grains and beans continues to decline, while the proportion of fat intake and energy supply continues to increase. &quot;In short, we eat less and less whole grains and more and more fats.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new version of the cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease prevention and treatment plan mentions, It is necessary to vigorously promote healthy lifestyles and promote scientific sports; promote the construction of food nutrition standard systems and strengthen the guiding role of food nutrition labels. And we must actively promote the construction of a smoke-free environment and continue to promote tobacco control measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In medicine, it is often said that time is the heart and time is the brain. This is because cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases are chronic diseases with acute attacks. In the early stages of the attack, life-saving treatment is crucial. closely related to time. Therefore, strengthening the frontier movement and improving the first aid system are also one of the focuses of the new cardiovascular and cerebrovascular prevention and treatment plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2022, the National Health and Health Commission issued a document requiring county-level hospitals to speed up the construction of &quot;five major emergency centers&quot;, including chest pain centers and stroke centers. The new version of the cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease prevention and treatment plan mentions that by 2030, all stroke centers in secondary hospitals and above will carry out intravenous thrombolysis technology. Where conditions permit, &quot;first aid maps&quot; for chest pain and stroke can be established to effectively improve treatment efficiency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the public level, strengthen the provision of first aid facilities and equipment such as automated external defibrillators (AEDs) in public places, and strengthen inspections of the equipped first aid equipment to ensure emergency response Available. &quot;We are promoting the international &#39;BEFAST&#39;, which means difficulty in balancing, unclear vision, incorrect face, difficulty in arm leveling, and difficulty in speech. If one of the five symptoms occurs, it means that you have cerebrovascular disease. At this time, you must treat it as soon as possible. For emergency calls, call 120 and go to the hospital.&quot; Wang Yongjun, director of Beijing Tiantan Hospital affiliated to Capital Medical University, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new version of the cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease prevention and treatment plan also requires expanding the scope of community cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease prevention and treatment services, and exploring the secondary prevention and treatment of patients with coronary heart disease and stroke. Rehabilitation treatment is included in the scope of services contracted by family doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The causative basis of cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases is atherosclerosis. It is very important to prevent and treat them at the same time, and to diagnose and treat them early. Wang Yongjun also called for the establishment of vascular health management centers at the grassroots level to jointly manage the high-risk groups of cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, and to establish diagnosis and treatment centers for cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases in large medical institutions. If you have cardiovascular disease, cerebrovascular disease or comorbidities If the patient is ill, he can see different experts after registering once to jointly solve the problem of common cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江苏无锡一纺织厂起火致7人死亡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260982]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-21 07:55:40&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;According to the official WeChat account of Wuxi Huishan District Emergency Management Bureau, on November 20, 2023 at 18:00 pm At about 1:30 a.m., a fire broke out at Tiantianrun Textile Technology Co., Ltd. in Qianzhou Street. Rescue operations at the accident site have ended, resulting in a total of 7 deaths. Accident investigation and aftermath are underway. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“形式确权”到“伪忙碌”：形式主义为何总是趋向内卷]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260951]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the issue of heavy non-teaching tasks for primary and secondary school teachers has triggered continued heated discussions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A discussion initiated by &quot;Fat Killer Whale&quot;, a Sina Weibo celebrity who is familiar with the education field, shows that the additional &quot;tasks&quot; that primary and secondary school teachers undertake in addition to their own teaching work can be described as diverse in scope, including But not limited to cleaning, statistics, attending meetings (non-teaching). Of course, the most important thing is to &quot;prepare&quot; and &quot;meet&quot; various audits and inspections. From a classification point of view, these &quot;tasks&quot; are as small as a feather. From a jurisdictional level, they include provinces, cities, districts and even streets. From a jurisdictional department point of view, there are both education authorities. , there are also people from other management departments, and there are even departments that are “incomparable”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you carefully observe these various and minute &quot;tasks&quot;, it is not difficult to find an interesting phenomenon, that is, in administrative management, formalism always naturally tends to be introverted, from top to bottom. The vertical involution is manifested in the &quot;increased pressure at every level&quot; of supervision, that is, subordinates always automatically tend to &quot;work harder&quot; to complete &quot;tasks&quot;, and the closer the management level is to the grassroots, the more serious this &quot;work harder&quot; will be. Horizontal involution manifests itself as competitive pressure. For example, if department A organizes an inspection of a certain unit, department B will soon organize an inspection of a certain unit. Formalism is like an infectious disease that is completed horizontally. After convergence, synchronization is achieved vertically, ultimately transmitting pressure to the most basic levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;meaning&quot; of formalism&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Formalism refers to the phenomenon that in the process of administrative management, managers pay too much attention to form and procedures and ignore the substantive work content and effects. , the interesting phenomenon that &quot;formalism always automatically tends to involution&quot; actually contains two levels of problems: the &quot;administrative authority confirmation&quot; of superiors to subordinates and the &quot;pseudo-busyness&quot; of subordinates to superiors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called &quot;administrative authority confirmation&quot; refers to the phenomenon of higher-level management departments confirming their authority to lower-level departments or units through various &quot;forms&quot;. In addition to the familiar cultural exchanges, there are also The bureaucracy that requires &quot;accounting of everything and leaving traces everywhere&quot; and the &quot;proceduralism&quot; that requires setting up power levels for all relevant departments in simple procedures, ultimately making it cumbersome. In addition, there are catwalks, landscaping, and throwing. Pots and various other styles. The most typical one is the endless repetition of &quot;inspections&quot; and &quot;audits&quot;, which turns the process of superiors&#39; normal exercise of supervisory powers over subordinates into a kind of obedience test. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this case, the authority of the superior needs to be confirmed through this &quot;obedience test&quot; again and again, while the subordinate can only choose unconditional obedience to pass the &quot;test&quot;. This process must be very long. Volume, because &quot;inferior&quot; in form means &quot;inferior&quot; in authority, which is unacceptable to the management department, so naturally the departments mentioned above naturally compete with each other in terms of form. &quot;Lateral involution&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Pseudo busyness&quot; is a response to &quot;formal confirmation of authority&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the process of &quot;formal confirmation of authority&quot; by superiors to subordinates through obedience tests, the grassroots are on the surface The unconditional object in this test of obedience is the unquestionable victim. But if you carefully observe the reaction of the grassroots, you will find that they are not a completely passive party. &quot;Pseudo busyness&quot; is a negative response to &quot;formal confirmation of authority&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called pseudo-busyness refers to being overly busy in grassroots work that is inconsistent with the workload, or simply pretending to be busy, but in fact no substantial progress or results have been achieved. This kind of pseudo-busyness cannot effectively promote work or bring substantial work results, because it is not based on the endogenous willingness to perform duties, but a passive busy state influenced by the external environment. It emphasizes not the execution and completion of the work itself, but the working status of the worker, tending to deliberately create and show a busy working status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there are two types of &quot;pseudo-busyness&quot;. One is the proactive pseudo-busyness of &quot;looking for something to do&quot;, and the other is the &quot;pseudo-busyness&quot; shown in dealing with inspections and reviews by superiors. Passive and pseudo-busy.” The purpose of the former is to reduce the frequency and scale of such &quot;obedience tests&quot; by pretending to be busy. The purpose of the latter is to pass this obedience test by showing a high degree of &quot;obedience&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned above, &quot;formal confirmation of authority&quot; is essentially a test of obedience, in which superiors confirm their absolute dominance over subordinates through some forms that have no practical meaning. The only reason for doing this is simply to prove that you have the right to do so, and this meaningless behavior is usually labeled as a test of organizational and execution capabilities. No matter what kind of test it is, the final performance is that subordinates are busy for an order from their superiors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After subordinates master this &quot;mystery&quot;, they will naturally tend to use &quot;pseudo-busyness&quot; to pass the superior&#39;s obedience test. If the degree of &quot;pseudo-busyness&quot; is not as good as that of others, it means that the degree of obedience is not as good as that of others. This will inevitably lead to some kind of involution of &quot;busy&quot;, that is, &quot;you are busy, I am busier than you&quot;. In the power hierarchy of the entire administrative agency, the higher you go up to the grassroots level, the more levels you face and the more departments you face. Therefore, the grassroots level must be the place where &quot;pseudo-busyness&quot; is most severely involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As educational institutions, the primary and secondary schools mentioned at the beginning of this article face many management levels and many management departments. It is not surprising that they have been pushed to the &quot;extreme&quot;, and similar departments include streets and communities. , and the reason why they are &quot;rolled&quot; is similar, that is, they are all at the lowest level of power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned above, whether it is &quot;formal confirmation of authority&quot; or &quot;pseudo busyness&quot;, no matter how serious and meticulous he appears, this kind of busyness that does not have the purpose of work itself is impossible. Bringing corresponding governance efficiency will instead become an important negative phenomenon in grassroots governance, affecting the output of governance efficiency, increasing the burden on grassroots staff, and causing low efficacy, work burnout, and even more serious psychological problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大学上课“务必前排就坐”，你同意吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260968]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the phenomenon of &quot;students not sitting in the front row&quot; inspected by colleges and universities in many places has triggered heated discussions on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 12, the official website of Changchun University stated that students should be educated and guided to &quot;must sit in the front row.&quot; Those who are absent from class or violate classroom disciplines and refuse to change will be punished in accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;Changchun University Student Disciplinary Punishment Regulations&quot; Disciplinary Actions. Hunan Communications Engineering College issued a notice on its official website as early as March this year, &quot;If the front row is not full, the academic committee will record the list of students in the last row and report it to the teacher and counselor.&quot; Currently, there are Xinxiang Medical College, Henan Institute of Technology, School of Public Art of Sichuan Academy of Fine Arts, School of Life Sciences of Yulin University, School of Transportation Engineering of Changsha University of Science and Technology and other universities have successively issued relevant notices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;When you go to school, do you prefer to sit in the front row or the back row, and why? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold ;&quot;>;Come to the comment area to share your opinions, and I will send you a hot comment immediately! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[交钱就走VIP通道：清代卖官的营销技巧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260931]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/19/bEr8d3zLmTltxXYZcHCJ2aTtpT9dcVqiRS1T7J6z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;667&quot; height=&quot;976&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/bEr8d3zLmTltxXYZcHCJ2aTtp T9dcVqiRS1T7J6z. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258825&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zuo Zongtang, a famous official in the Qing Dynasty, obtained the qualification of supervising students through donations and participated in the Test. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(data map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Donating means selling one&#39;s official position, which was the official title after the institutionalization of selling one&#39;s official position during the Ming and Qing Dynasties. The so-called selling an official position to win a title has been around since ancient times, and history is endless. But what we are talking about here is not the behind-the-scenes operation in the house of cards, but the aboveboard state behavior. Starting from the Wei, Jin, Southern and Northern Dynasties, the government sometimes publicly sold official qualifications to solve financial difficulties. In the middle of the Ming Dynasty, Emperor Jingtai, who ascended the throne because his brother Yingzong was captured by the Mongols during the Civil War, put the qualifications of students from the Guozijian, the country&#39;s highest institution (historically known as &quot;Jiansheng&quot;) on the market for the first time, starting an epoch-making revolution. great changes. Because as long as the supervisory students pass a certain period of probation and do not receive negative reviews, they can obtain official qualifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the Ming Dynasty&#39;s move was far ahead of the previous generation, it was nothing compared to the Qing Dynasty. The Ming Dynasty only allowed donations from prison students and did not dare to directly sell formal official positions. In the Qing Dynasty, for donations, Beijing officials could donate to doctors of the fifth rank, while foreign officials could only donate to Taoist priests of the fourth rank. The so-called heyday of Kangxi and Qianlong, that is, the two dynasties of Kangxi and Qianlong, were precisely the critical periods for the development of donations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Donations in the Qing Dynasty were divided into two types: &quot;current regulations&quot; and &quot;temporary regulations&quot;. The so-called &quot;current routine&quot; refers to the donations that are offered all year round, mainly to donations to supervising students. During the Qianlong period, the annual income from this was about 3 million taels, which was close to one-tenth of the agricultural tax, which was the main part of the fiscal revenue. The &quot;temporary cases&quot; are used to raise specific funds caused by major events such as military expenses, Yellow River management project expenses, disaster relief funds, etc. Temporary donations mainly sell actual official positions, so they are also called &quot;real official donations.&quot; Legally speaking, those who are eligible to report temporary donations are limited to current officials and supervisory students who already have official qualifications, and ordinary people are excluded. But in fact, if ordinary people want to buy an official position, they can first donate a prison student according to the current regulations, thus perfectly avoiding the restrictions. The income from temporary cases can reach tens of millions of taels at a time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Qing government’s donation information is open and transparent, prices are clearly marked, first come, first served, no one is deceived. There is no age limit for those who wish to donate. Newborn babies can also be donated to supervising children, or on this basis, they can donate to official positions. Because there are far more people qualified to hold official positions than there are bureaucratic positions, it is not possible to get an official position right away. You have to submit relevant documents from the Ministry of Personnel and wait in line to &quot;get on the train&quot; according to order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that they have paid for it, everyone hopes to become a Shangguan as soon as possible and get back their capital and profits as soon as possible. This brought additional business opportunities to the Qing government. Donors could add &quot;tricks&quot; to their donation, that is, priority in appointments, which was equivalent to walking in the VIP channel when queuing. There are many types of products, such as &quot;first use&quot;, &quot;use in case of shortage&quot;, &quot;first use first&quot;, etc., which can be chosen by customers with different needs, all with clearly marked prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This transaction of the Qing government has undergone some interesting changes as time has passed. On the one hand, official positions are constantly on sale. For example, in the 39th year of Qianlong&#39;s reign (1774), the price of a Taoist was 16,400 taels. In the second year of Xianfeng&#39;s reign (1852), it was reduced to 9,446.4 taels, almost cut in half. By the 27th year of Guangxu&#39;s reign (1901), it only cost 4,732.1 taels, which was more than 30% off. Low. This is because more and more people are queuing up and the backlog is getting worse. For example, in the 19th year of Jiaqing (1814), in order to raise the cost of regulating the eastern Henan section of the Yellow River, the imperial court launched the &quot;Eastern Henan Case&quot;. However, the &quot;Sichuan-Chu Case&quot; 16 years ago, the &quot;Work Relief Case&quot; 13 years ago, and the &quot;Work Relief Case&quot; 11 years ago The &quot;work balance case&quot; before, the &quot;donation case&quot; 8 years ago, and the &quot;earth excavation case&quot; 6 years ago are all still not digested by people who buy government offices. In this case, waiting in line means that the time it takes for the investment to pay off is getting longer and longer. In order to attract new customers, in addition to lowering prices, the imperial court also invented the method of &quot;suppressing the old with the new&quot; (three new and one old, four new and one old, or even five new and one old). For the government, the temporary cases that have ended have already put money firmly into their pockets. Of course, they cannot turn their backs and abandon the consumers who paid for them and are still queuing up. However, in order to recruit new people, the interests of old customers are expendable. Therefore, in the 19th year of Jiaqing, the imperial court announced the implementation of &quot;four new and one old&quot;, that is, for every five vacant official positions reserved for donors, the first four were designated for the East Henan Province, and the fifth was assigned to many previous Persons left unresolved by the case. In these cases, priority is given not to the buyers of the earliest &quot;Chuanchu cases&quot; who paid, but to the consumers of the latest &quot;Tufang cases&quot;. The fifth vacancy, which was the first official position reserved for the old case, was assigned to the top remaining donor in the &quot;Earthwork Case&quot;. As for the &quot;Chuan Chu Case&quot; 16 years ago, the person who finally reached the top of the team had to wait until the 45th place to take the turn. Until the first year of Xianfeng (1851), more than fifty years had passed since the opening of &quot;Chuanchu Case&quot;, and there were still customers queuing up. It is unknown how many people who were excited because of the opportunity to spend money to buy an official position passed away in the long years without waiting for their dreams to come true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, as a VIP channel, the price of tricks is always strong. For example, in the &quot;Zhenggong Case&quot; in the 13th year of Guangxu&#39;s reign (1887), the magistrate&#39;s price was only 1,998 taels, which was half the price during the Qianlong period. However, the magistrate&#39;s &quot;Before the Deficiency&quot; trick required 3,808.8 taels, which was almost double the qualifications for the magistrate&#39;s appointment. . But the same goes for old tricks. For example, if the &quot;first in case of shortage&quot; purchased by &quot;Earthwork Case&quot; is still in the queue when the &quot;East Yun Case&quot; is implemented, its effectiveness will be greatly faded compared to the &quot;first in case of shortage&quot; in &quot;East Yu Case&quot;. In order to do everything possible to mobilize the enthusiasm of consumers and extract money from the hands of the people, the imperial court creatively designed an incentive mechanism of &quot;adding more money to pay for work&quot;. Assume that the magistrate of &quot;Earthwork Case&quot; &quot;in case of shortage&quot; sells for 5,000 taels, and the magistrate of &quot;Eastern Yudong Case&quot; needs &quot;in case of shortage&quot; for 7,000 taels. The person who originally bought the &quot;Earthwork Case&quot; in the county of &quot;in case of shortage&quot; can According to the standard of adding 30 taels for every one hundred taels, and paying an additional 2,100 taels as over-shift fee, you can be transferred to the &quot;first in line&quot; VIP channel of the magistrate of &quot;Eastern Yudong Case&quot; to queue up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a result, donors who have not bought anything actually have no hope of being ranked. At the end of the Qing Dynasty, &quot;pressing the old with the new&quot; also changed from sorting by new and old examples to sorting by new and old patterns. Moreover, the imperial court considered that no matter whether they bought an official position or passed the imperial examination in ten years, it was everyone&#39;s wish to become an official as soon as possible. Those who qualified for official positions through the imperial examination could also open a special channel as long as they were willing to spend money to buy tricks. In the late Guangxu Dynasty, the &quot;Selection of Wheels&quot;, which records the waiting list for county magistrates, contains more than 20 tricks, among which there are &quot;donating and accepting Jinshi first&quot; - a trick specially prepared for Jinshi to &quot;jump in line&quot;, and &quot;donating and accepting filial piety&quot;. &quot;Fangzhengxian&quot; - Xiaolian Fangzheng refers to a person who is qualified to serve as an official because of his outstanding conduct and special recommendation. If such a person does not spend money to buy tricks, no matter how he practices filial piety, no matter how upright his character is, I am afraid he will not be accepted. It&#39;s time to take the wheel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to raise funds, there were still many links in the appointment process of officials in the Qing Dynasty that could be solved with money. At least since the Han Dynasty, people who have just entered the ranks of the bureaucracy may need a period of time as a transitional internship period. After the probation period is completed, they can be officially appointed. In the Qing Dynasty, an internship period ranging from one to three years was generally required before becoming an official for the first time. If you have money, you can donate to get a free trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When appointing officials in previous dynasties, there were regulations to avoid the place of origin and relatives&#39; official appointments, and the same was true in the Qing Dynasty. However, in the Qing Dynasty, donations could also be waived for avoidance. Even if you designate the province where you want to be an official, or if you are not satisfied with the province where you are appointed as an official and want to change it to another province, you can do it through donations (the former is called a province, and the latter is called changing a province). In the Qing Dynasty, some official positions were under the control of local governors. Candidates could only be appointed within the province. They could also donate a sum of money to leave the province and then donate to another province to switch to another province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Officials appointed by the Ministry of Personnel, ranging from Taoist officials to Qipin Zhizhiguan magistrates (Taoist officials and above are appointed by the emperor), must appear before the emperor and be reviewed by the emperor himself (called an introduction, in fact Often just a formality) before being allowed to take office. As for junior officials such as junior deputies, who were not even close to sesame seeds, the emperor really did not have the time and energy to deal with them, so he commissioned the princes and ministers to check the appearance of each person (called inspection). The purpose of this was to show that the Qing monarch was &quot;arbitrary&quot; and &quot;all employing people, listening to words, and having great power without any excuse.&quot; But as long as you pay for it, introductions and inspections can be dispensed with - even if it&#39;s just for money, you don&#39;t need authority! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to prevent donors from digging too much into the Qing Dynasty, it was originally stipulated that donors with backgrounds should not be recommended by local governors or central ministerial officials (that is, recommended, and the recommender is jointly and severally liable). He cannot serve as a capital official or local official (top leader). In the Qing Dynasty, they even risked their lives for money, and recommendations can also be donated! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for those who are entering the official service for the first time, officials who have resigned due to illness and want to return to their original posts after recovering from illness will have to spend a sum of money to replace them immediately, otherwise they will have to wait in line. If you want to change a position, you have to make two investments, first donate to fill the original position, and then donate to replace the position. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most amazing example is probably the &quot;temporary supervisor&quot;: &quot;Some people want to take the examination, but they are not qualified. By donating one supervisor, you can take the provincial examination, but if the supervisor can make a temporary donation in cash , it also requires dozens of taels of silver, and I am not sure whether it will be successful or not. I am a little reluctant to spend dozens of taels of silver in vain. Moreover, if all the procedures for this kind of donation to supervise students are completed, it will be possible. It took quite a while. So this temporary method was devised. First, a dozen or so taels of silver were handed over to the Imperial College, and the prison would issue a temporary supervisory license (commonly known as a supervisory license). With this license, you can Apply for the Provincial Examination in the Ministry of Rites. If you win the exam in the future, you will have to pay the full fee, and the prison will receive the official license. If you fail to pass, it will be considered as a matter of course, and you will make a cash donation until the next Provincial Examination.&quot; (Qi Rushan&#39;s &quot; Chinese family name&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/E9nBwpbi0PRujzZ6WJFwmdGjvoyB5H6l0WZ2LcK3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;549&quot; height=&quot;1222&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/E9nBwpbi0PRujzZ6WJFwmdGjvoyB5H6l0WZ2LcK3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258824&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Receipt stub from a donation to a prison student in the 17th year of Daoguang reign of the Qing Dynasty (1837). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Donations are not only allowed in many aspects of examination qualifications, official qualifications and official appointment, but also after becoming an official Rewards and punishments are due based on performance - if you do well, you can be promoted, if you do poorly, you will be punished - or you can pay for it. In order to open up financial avenues, starting from the Kangxi Dynasty, not only current officials could donate money to be promoted, but also those waiting in line at the Ministry of Civil Service for appointment could donate money in advance. For example, in the Yimao donation in the 14th year of Kangxi&#39;s reign (1675), a candidate for the county magistrate (deputy of the county magistrate) could pay 300 taels for &quot;first use&quot;, or he could spend 1,000 taels to donate to the county magistrate&#39;s official qualifications. If he was willing to pay an additional 500 taels You can directly enter the &quot;first use&quot; VIP channel of the county magistrate. This system is unique to the Qing Dynasty. After current officials spend money to buy promotion qualifications, they can theoretically queue up at the Ministry of Civil Affairs only after their current term of office expires. Considering that this would dampen the enthusiasm of consumers, the Qing government also launched the donation of resignation, so that as long as you pay for it, you can leave immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can use money to get a promotion, you can be punished for dereliction of duty, or you can spend money to eliminate disasters. In the Qing Dynasty, depending on the content and degree of the fault committed by an official, there were three types of punishment: fine, demotion, and dismissal. Under normal circumstances, only “set-off” or “recovery” can reduce or reduce the penalty. The so-called &quot;offset&quot; refers to officials using the rewards they receive to offset punishment. There are two types of awards: &quot;Additional Level&quot; and &quot;Record&quot;. &quot;Additional one level&quot; or four &quot;records&quot; can be used to offset the penalty of downgrading by one level. &quot;The second record will offset the penalty for one year, and the first record will offset the penalty for half a year.&quot; &quot;Rehabilitate&quot; means that the punishment can be lifted after a certain period of time if the person behaves well. For example, the reinstatement period for those who were demoted and retained in office is three years, and the period for those who were dismissed and retained in office is four years. If you perform meritorious services during this period, you may be reinstated in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both &quot;Additional Levels&quot; and &quot;Records&quot; can be purchased publicly for money. However, the Qing Dynasty stipulated that for the &quot;increased level&quot; or &quot;record&quot; of donations to be used for offset, the payment must have been received before the disciplinary incident was reported. If you go to buy something after being punished, it will be too late. Therefore, before officials took office, they donated Naga level and records. Beginning in the 14th year of Kangxi&#39;s reign, officials were allowed to directly spend money to cancel the punishment after being punished. All officials who have been demoted and retained in office, or dismissed and retained in office (remaining in their original posts after being demoted or dismissed), except for a few exceptions, can donate to reinstatement officers. Officials who should have been demoted (reassigned work according to the downgraded grade) or dismissed, but who were retained in office due to leniency orders, can pay a 50% increase in salary upon reinstatement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to donating to restore the official position, you can also donate to restore the position corresponding to the grade of the original official. This is called &quot;replacement donation&quot;. Retired officials can also donate to a position lower than the original official, which is called &quot;reduced donation&quot;. After the donation is made, there is still an opportunity to donate again to reinstate the official or change the donation, which is equivalent to payment in installments. Officials who have been dismissed from their posts, even if they are &quot;never employed&quot;, can still become officials again through donations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to buying an official position, donating money is clearly marked with a clear price and is straightforward. The price of being demoted and staying in office, from the first to the seventh rank, is twice that of a Beijing official. For example, a first-rank Beijing official is 450 taels, and a second-rank official is 410 liang. A first-rank foreign official is 900 liang, and a second-rank official is 820 liang. The eighth and ninth grades are subject to the unified price of Beijing and foreign officials. The price of donations for those who were dismissed and retained in office was not only much higher, but also more detailed. For the same grade, officials in the capital charged higher prices than officials in foreign countries. For officials who are demoted, transferred or dismissed, the price can be doubled compared to those who were demoted and retained or dismissed. In addition, depending on the specific circumstances of different officials, there is a complex price increase mechanism, ranging from an increase of 20% (20%) to an increase of one and a half times (150%). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the Qing Dynasty, due to widespread financial difficulties in local areas, the imperial court often allowed each province to set up local donations. This resulted in an unintended consequence - inter-provincial competition. In order to expand revenue as much as possible, each province not only accepts donations from residents of other provinces living in the province, but also sets up donation bureaus (sales offices) in major cities outside the province to drum up business, even at the expense of small profits but quick turnover, &quot;reduced (discounted) donations&quot; , starting a price war. At one point, Sichuan and other provinces protested against &quot;dumping&quot; by Gansu and Shaanxi and demanded that the central government prohibit people from their provinces from going to other provinces to report donations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Ciming, a famous scholar in the late Qing Dynasty and a native of Zhejiang, went to the Fujian Donation Bureau to apply for donations in the ninth year of Xianfeng (1859). The price was 9684 taels, and the actual receipt was 815 taels, which was less than 10%. This is a common practice in various provinces: &quot;Henan Province takes rate notes (notes issued by the Ministry of Household Affairs to settle military arrears) and adds 10% in cash, which is about 20%. Huguang, Sichuan, and Zhejiang account for about 10%. The third. Jiangxi and Guangxi account for about three-tenths of the tenths. Yunnan and Guizhou account for about two-tenths. Anhui fully collects rates, accounting for about one-tenth. The remaining provinces do not have more than 30%.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;In Chengdu at the end of the Qing Dynasty, in addition to the Sichuan Relief Bureau (disaster relief) in the province, there were also the Xinhai Defense Donation Bureau (organizing the navy), the Feng (Liaoning) Donation Bureau, the Gui Donation Bureau, the Jiangnan Donation Bureau, and the Shandong Works Relief Donation Bureau (raising funds for Work-relief funds) and the Beiyang Salary and Donation Bureau (Beiyang Military Salary), etc. At that time, newspapers had just been born, and due to fierce competition, some discerning donation bureaus had already learned to publish advertisements. In this situation where there are many donation bureaus and a mixture of good and bad, there is also a phenomenon that some people conduct credit evaluations on different donation bureaus in publicly issued books. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because there are so many types of tricks and there are so many donation bureaus, most people are easily confused, so an intermediary agency was born that specializes in handling donations, with a commission of about 10%. Many gold shops have &quot;transformed into a gathering place for donors and introductions&quot; and have dedicated &quot;donation counters&quot; to handle donations. Gold shops with donation counters are called &quot;public gold shops&quot;, while gold shops without donation counters are called &quot;mother gold shops&quot;. There will be competition among gold shops, and they will also use various means to deceive customers, which is no different from today&#39;s real estate agencies. Everyone knows the prosperity of Shanxi banknotes in the late Qing Dynasty, but few people have noticed that agency donations are one of the keys to the great development of Shanxi banknotes. (The original title was &quot;Marketing Techniques of Donations in the Qing Dynasty&quot;, the current title was proposed by the editor)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿童是世界的主角]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260952]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;Today (November 20) is World Children&#39;s Day, and it is also the day when the famous &quot;Convention on the Rights of the Child&quot; was born. The Lebanese poet Gibran once wrote in &quot;To the Children&quot;: They come through you, but not from you. Although they are with you, they do not belong to you. Children are the protagonists of the world and a beautiful reflection of the city. Be less malicious and more caring, so that the future masters can change the direction of the tide. &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div >;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“14岁当爹”不能只当八卦，保护未成年男性权利应尽快提上日程丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260949]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 19:06:09&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the news that &quot;in order to allow a 4-year-old boy to settle down, an 18-year-old father appeared for a paternity test&quot; has attracted public attention great concern. According to the Anhui Radio and Television Economic Life Channel, a 4-year-old boy in Hefei, Anhui, Wang Zien, had no one to take care of him and played alone on the street all day long. In order to settle Wang Zien&#39;s residence, the child&#39;s father, 18-year-old Wang, finally showed up. He said that he was only 14 years old when Wang Zien was born, and the child&#39;s mother was 20 years old at the time. The two parties broke up a few months after the child was born, and there has been no contact. He had to leave the child to his father to raise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the incident broke out, public opinion mainly focused on Wang giving birth to a child before the age of 14. He was still a child, which was too irresponsible, and the mother of the child was more likely to be suspected of abandoning the child. A lawyer interviewed by the media said that the mother should fulfill her parenting obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These angles cannot be said to be meaningless, but they obviously miss the point. The crux of the problem should be that boys&#39; sexual rights are not protected. According to Wang, he was only 14 years old when the child was born (I don’t know whether he was one year old or not, even if he was one year old, Wang was probably still under 14 years old when they had sex), and the child’s mother was 20 years old. It can be inferred that when having sexual relations, Wang was most likely under 14 years old, while the mother of the child was over 18 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What will happen if the genders are reversed and an 18-year-old man has sex with a girl under 14? I&#39;m afraid online public opinion has already exploded. According to the criminal law, sexual relations with a girl under the age of 14, regardless of whether the girl &quot;consented&quot;, will be severely punished as rape. If the circumstances are serious or cause serious consequences, the death penalty may also be imposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when the genders are reversed and adult women have sex with underage men, the situation becomes very embarrassing. The crime of rape cannot be applied because China&#39;s criminal law stipulates that the victim of rape can only be a female. Even if a man is forced to have sex, the other party does not commit the crime of rape. If the boy is under 14 when he is violated, he can be punished as child molestation. However, the penalty for this crime is only a fixed-term imprisonment of less than 5 years. Even if there are bad circumstances or serious consequences, the maximum sentence can only be 15 years in prison. This is not the same as the punishment for rape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the male victim is over 14 years old, he is no longer a child. Even if he is forcibly violated, criminal law cannot protect his rights. More importantly, in reality, if a minor male has sexual relations with a female, if the other party is an adult, judicial practice will not consider the male&#39;s sexual rights to have been violated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is obviously abnormal. Minor males should receive the same protection as minor females. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quite coincidentally, a case of an adult female teacher sexually assaulting an underage male student recently broke out in Taiwan. Xu, a female teacher who works as a fifth- and sixth-grade primary school teacher, repeatedly sexually assaulted a boy under the age of 14 in her class. She eventually became pregnant and gave birth to a child. The crime was later reported. The judge recently ruled that Xu was guilty of sexual intercourse and forced intercourse with a man under the age of 14, and sentenced her to 17 years and six months in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Analyzing this case, we can find the differences between Taiwan’s criminal laws and mainland criminal laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, having sex with a man against his will also constitutes the crime of rape (called &quot;forced intercourse&quot; in Taiwan). According to the criminal regulations revised in Taiwan in 1999, &quot;Men and women who have sexual intercourse by force, coercion, intimidation, hypnosis or other methods against their will shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than 3 years but not more than 10 years.&quot; In this case, The judge determined that the female teacher surnamed Xu had sex with a male student twice against the male student&#39;s will, so it constituted a crime of forced intercourse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, as long as you have sexual intercourse with a child under the age of 14, even if the child is voluntary, it still constitutes a crime (Article 227 of the Criminal Code of Taiwan, &quot;Any person who has sexual intercourse with a man or woman under the age of 14 shall be punished with 3 to fixed-term imprisonment of not less than 10 years but not more than 10 years”). In the above-mentioned case, the judge held that the female teacher named Xu had sexual intercourse with male students on seven other occasions. Although the boys were consenting, Xu&#39;s use of the girl still constituted the crime of sexual intercourse with men under the age of 14. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Taiwan’s criminal regulations also equally protect the sexual rights of minors of men and women over 14 years old but under 16 years old. “Anyone who has sexual intercourse with a man or woman over 14 years old but under 16 years old shall be sentenced to a fixed-term imprisonment of not more than 7 years.” &quot;. That is to say, having sexual relations with minors between the ages of 14 and 16 is also a crime, but the penalty is lighter than having sexual relations with children under 14 years old. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In mainland criminal law, the protection of men’s sexual rights is much weaker. The sexual rights of minor males over 14 years old (let alone adult males) are not protected by criminal law, and the sexual rights of boys under 14 years old can only be protected by the much weaker crime of child molestation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is another point in Taiwan’s criminal laws that we can learn from, that is, multiple crimes can be punished based on the number of crimes committed, and they can be punished simultaneously. In the above-mentioned case, the judge found that Xu had sex with male students nine times. Although they were only divided into two categories, she was still convicted of nine crimes, and finally she was punished for several crimes. In the mainland legal system, only different crimes will be regarded as multiple crimes, the same crime will be classified as one crime, and the number of crimes will only be used as a reference for sentencing. This may result in a lighter sentence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at history, before Taiwan revised its criminal laws in 1999, the victims of rape could only be women. If a man was sexually assaulted, the perpetrator could only be held accountable for indecent assault. However, Taiwan revised the relevant regulations more than 20 years ago to provide equal protection for the sexual rights of men and women. This is something the mainland can learn from. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑龙江大庆市肇州发生火灾，致7人死亡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260964]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 19:09:39&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reporter learned from the People’s Government of Zhaozhou County, Daqing City, Heilongjiang Province that at 14:00 on November 20, 2023 At 04:00, the county fire brigade received an alarm that a fire broke out in a single-story steel structure simple board house of an individual industrial and commercial household in the south of Shizi Street, Fengle Town, Zhaozhou County. At 14:40, the open fire was extinguished at the scene, covering an area of ​​280 square meters. The fire caused 7 deaths. At present, the cause of the fire is under investigation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>