<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[多地突发“雷暴哮喘”：半小时内发作，蒿属花粉或为元凶]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 23:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 23:55:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[央行年内二度降准：释放中长期流动性超5000亿，效果将脉冲式持续释放]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256718]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 23:00:54&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/FNOA6veUr0UsCJ1nZEs8PhzPpQl XyAcy20uy4Nsu. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 14, 2023, the People&#39;s Bank of China issued an announcement and decided to lower the deposit reserve ratio of financial institutions by 0.25 percentage points on September 15, 2023 (excluding the implemented 5% reserve ratio for financial institutions). This is the second time in 2023 that the central bank has lowered the deposit reserve ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that with the successive efforts of fiscal, taxation, real estate and monetary policies, market expectations have improved significantly in the near future, and the potential for economic stabilization is increasing, but the flexibility of economic recovery still needs to be enhanced. . This RRR cut will release more than 500 billion yuan of medium- and long-term liquidity to the market, further releasing a positive signal to protect the market and supporting the stabilization of the economy and the stability of liquidity in the financial system. This is another important benefit that reflects the regulatory authorities&#39; push for economic recovery after the &quot;big move&quot; of cutting interest rates and optimizing real estate and financial policies. However, this RRR cut is not a &quot;flood&quot;, nor does it exceed market expectations. It is expected that the policy effects of two interest rate cuts and two reserve requirement ratio cuts this year will continue to be released in a pulse-like manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The RRR is lowered on the eve of payment, why is it so urgent? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to relevant regulations, commercial banks should hand over deposit reserves to the People&#39;s Bank of China in three installments on the 5th, 15th and 25th of each month, depending on changes in their deposits. What is the purpose of this new policy of lowering reserve requirements, which was announced on the eve of the payment of deposit reserves by financial institutions on the 15th? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that the just-released macroeconomic data is an important background for the &quot;flash&quot; launch of the new policy of lowering the reserve requirement ratio. This Monday, financial data for August was just released. Among them, the increase in social financing in August reached 3.12 trillion, a significant rebound from July. However, the broad money supply (M2 for short) increased by 10.6% year-on-year, and the growth rate was still slightly lower than that at the end of July and the same period last year by 0.1 and 0.16 percentage points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the balance of RMB loans issued by financial institutions to entities in August was 230.24 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 10.9%. The growth rate is recovering, which shows that investors&#39; confidence in the future has increased. Combined with the previously released August CPI and PPI data, various important economic indicators showed signs of bottoming out around August. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to promote the macroeconomic stabilization and improvement as soon as possible, since August, a combination of macroeconomic policies has been continuously launched, and fiscal, taxation, real estate, and monetary policies have been launched one after another. Among them, monetary policy is particularly eye-catching. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of September, the central bank adjusted the existing mortgage interest rates, aiming to ease residents’ mortgage repayment pressure and stabilize real estate market confidence. The information on this adjustment to the deposit reserve ratio of financial institutions was released on the eve of the payment of deposit reserves by financial institutions on the 15th. The policy benefits were transmitted to the real economy at a rapid speed, and various financial institutions (excluding the 5% deposit reserve that had been implemented) Financial institutions (financial institutions) generally lowered the reserve requirement ratio by 0.25 percentage points. The intensity is consistent with the first reduction in March. The policy has both continuity and stability and the signal is clear. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What goals does the RRR cut in mid-September reflect? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that the central bank chose to lower the reserve requirement ratio at this time for the following three main purposes:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, seize the opportunity to consolidate the recovery of the real economy. A good trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;August data shows signs of bottoming out, which is a critical moment for economic recovery. The central bank decisively cut the reserve requirement ratio again, releasing more than 500 billion yuan in medium- and long-term liquidity. This move injects real money into the real economy through financial institutions, which may encourage financial institutions to further increase their investment in entities. Macroeconomic indicators will show more positive changes, and the sustainability of the steady economic recovery will be further enhanced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to promote a moderate recovery in price levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maintaining a moderate level of inflation is more conducive to economic development. In the first half of the year, as CPI and PPI data continued to fall, concerns about deflation and recession continued in the market. Against this background, the central bank seized the opportunity of recent positive changes in inflation, especially when the year-on-year CPI turned from negative to positive in August and the year-on-year decline in PPI converged for two consecutive months, it promptly lowered the required reserve ratio to continue to enhance the potential of financial support to expand domestic demand. It is conducive to further giving full play to the early leading role of financial resources and supporting the continued moderate recovery of inflation indicators. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to maintain reasonable and sufficient liquidity in the banking system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that in mid-to-late September, under the intertwined influence of factors such as local bond issuance, tax season peaks, and regulatory assessments, the liquidity pressure in the inter-bank market will increase significantly. Among them, local government bond issuance is accelerating. Following the issuance of 1.2 trillion yuan in August, more than 1 trillion yuan will be issued in September. Subscription payments by financial institutions will draw out a large amount of liquidity; the tax payment peak around the 15th of each month will cause market liquidity pressure in stages. Increase; September is still the end of the third quarter, and the needs of financial institutions for liquidity index assessment and other aspects will also increase significantly. After the superposition of multiple factors, the market&#39;s short-term capital supply and demand have increased. The central bank has chosen the time when the demand for liquidity is most urgent, taken timely measures, and played a significant role in protecting the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believe that this RRR cut is moderately forward-looking, which can not only alleviate short-term liquidity needs, but also continue to supplement credit growth, cash injection, and third-party payment institution preparations in the future period. The demand for medium- and long-term liquidity such as payment and back-up payment reflects the positive signal that the central bank is replenishing blood for banks accurately and appropriately and carefully protecting market liquidity. However, judging from the magnitude and pace of the RRR cut, this RRR cut did not exceed market expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;How will the effect of continuous interest rate cuts and reserve requirement ratios be reflected? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since 2023, the central bank has cut interest rates twice and cut reserve requirements twice in a row, and the potential for active monetary policy continues to grow. In the future, how will the effects of relevant favorable policies be reflected? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center believe that the continuous &quot;relaxation&quot; of monetary policy has a direct effect on the continuous decline in financing costs of the real economy. This effect has been achieved. Data from the central bank show that from January to August, corporate loan interest rates have dropped to historical lows since statistics were collected, and personal housing loan interest rates also dropped by 0.95 percentage points year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this move will promote commercial banks to further benefit the real economy. With the introduction of policies such as the central bank&#39;s interest rate cuts and existing mortgage interest rates, commercial banks&#39; net interest margins have narrowed significantly since 2019. As of the end of June, the average net interest margin of the 19 largest A-share listed banks was 1.83, a decrease of 30 basis points or 14% from the end of 2019. The overall profit margin of banks continues to shrink. This time the central bank lowers the reserve requirement ratio again, it will help reduce the cost of funds on the liability side of banks, further open up the downward space for loan interest rates on the asset side, promote the steady and steady decline of corporate financing and residents&#39; credit costs, and may further enhance the ability of financial institutions to transfer profits to entities. It is conducive to stabilizing investment and employment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, with two consecutive interest rate cuts and two reserve requirement ratio cuts, monetary policy, fiscal policy and industrial policy have continued to exert their efforts. Factors conducive to the stabilization and improvement of the macro economy are increasing, and market expectations are quietly rising. changes occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant people close to the regulatory authorities told researchers at the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center that the central bank’s confidence, determination and ability to implement prudent monetary policies accurately and effectively will be further reflected, and the effects of relevant policies will be continuously released in a pulsed manner. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[庄稼地丨云间夜话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256556]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/12/o7vtcUwzK3dRQHvG13YrMqzZUdMvWxRwVhkXDkao.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/o7vtcUwzK3dRQHvG13YrM qzZUdMvWxRwVhkXDkao. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Crop field&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every morning in the community, there is always an old farmer walking out of the door among the endless flow of office workers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His standard equipment is a broken straw hat and a rusty hoe. Of course, it is not only incompatible with the white-collar workers around me, but also particularly dazzling. At first I thought it was the landscaping engineer of the property, but later I found out that it was Tony&#39;s father, Lao Tan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tony drives a Rolls-Royce to work every day. But his father goes out with a hoe every day. I couldn&#39;t help but follow him on my bicycle and found that he had indeed entered the crop field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that the 50 acres of crop land is a well-known large wasteland nearby. Who knows what the project was, but it was rotten anyway. Soon after it became wasteland, it was planted with crops by all kinds of people, so it was called crop land. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The question is, Tony is so rich, what is Lao Tan doing? &quot;I can&#39;t help it.&quot; He said to me. If I can&#39;t smell the smell of the land for a day, I can&#39;t eat or sleep, and I can&#39;t stop yawning. As soon as I arrived at the crop field and smelled the familiar atmosphere, I felt energetic all over. Call me cheap, what can I do? When I first came to Shanghai, all the illnesses I had all over my body were cured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For this matter, Tony had quarreled with him countless times, saying that it would seriously damage his image. But Lao Tan ignored him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The principle of crop land is that whoever opens it can plant as much as possible. Everyone has a playful mentality. The land is still deserted anyway, and the developers may come to work at some time. Only Lao Tan admitted the truth. In order to improve the quality of the soil, he collected dog excrement from all over the street and fermented it in a large vat. Even though he sprinkled maggot killers, the smell was still unbearable to the neighbors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also made his own &quot;vegetable fertilizer&quot;, which was another big vat. He filled the big vat with discarded fruits and vegetables from his own family and neighbors, bought compost strains, and pickled them like pickles. A big lump. Afraid that the soil would become hardened, we even brought in black &quot;soil loosening essence&quot; and spread it everywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Anyway, the nice villa was turned into a toilet by him, and Tony vowed to leave him all day long. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But you have to admit that Lao Tan is a good at growing crops. You can tell whether the soil is alkaline or acidic by looking at it, by tasting the water, you can tell whether it is too hard or too soft, and by looking at the pests and diseases, you can tell by looking at them: inchworms, armyworms, cabbage caterpillars, cutworms, root maggots, and mustard scale insects. , corn borers, rice planthoppers, red spider mites... For a while, &quot;green ecology&quot; was advocated in the crop fields. A few radicals did not use any medicine, saying that they would rather look ugly than be ecologically organic. The problem is that the insects are ruthless and will eat all the vegetables in just a few days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone invited Lao Tan to dinner and asked Lao Baoshi why the garden was still green without him spraying medicine. Who said no medicine? Lao Tan&#39;s throat suddenly straightened. What&#39;s going on? ! What I took was Chinese medicine. You can’t imagine this! For example, when I was a kid, I used Baibu to wash my hair and kill insects. One kilogram was only 12 yuan online. I brewed Baibu tincture in a big pot, sprayed it and poured it in, and it swept away all the germs and pests! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As he spoke, he waved his big hand fiercely, looking very tall at that moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thus, despite being looked down upon in the community, when I arrived at the crop fields, it was like Napoleon of Elba returning to France, and my ears were filled with greetings one after another - &quot;Old Tan!&quot; &quot;Master Tan!&quot; !&quot; Some even call him &quot;Dad Tan&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lao Tan felt very useful at this time. He sat on the small horse, took out the dry tobacco pipe he brought from his hometown, puffed for a while, and smiled, his face full of furrows. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, good times do not last long as usual. Gradually, news came out that the developer would be back at work soon. Lao Tan was so worried that he sat in his vegetable garden in a daze every day. He smoked dry tobacco for a while and then reached out to touch the soil. I advised him that it was just temporary, so don’t take it so seriously. He looked towards me. not talking. Just kept rubbing the soil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until the large machinery came in, he was still sitting there every day. Let me put it bluntly, since you love the land so much, first, why bother leaving your hometown; second, you can still go back now! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He didn&#39;t speak for a long time. Then he said softly, &quot;I only have a son. My wife has died long ago. If I don&#39;t live with him, who will I live with?&quot; Second, let me tell you, the land in my hometown has long been gone, why don’t I still care about the “crop land” here? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He suddenly cried. Tears flowed freely. Crying with a Hunan accent. I panicked and didn&#39;t know how to persuade him. He sat alone until it was completely dark before returning. Then for a long time, there was no trace of him. Tony&#39;s face looked very ugly. I know they were having a heated argument again. Lao Tan even beat his son, so I was embarrassed to ask about Lao Tan&#39;s whereabouts. I guess I should go back to my hometown. I think. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the beginning of winter, I rode an exercise bike and passed by the town of Sijing, 10 miles away from home. The fields were green and white with dew, and the fields in early winter were empty. On a remote road, a tent struggling in the north wind could be seen. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No, it is just a shack made of large plastic sheets tied with ropes. People in southern Guangdong call it &quot;Liao&quot; and people in Shanghai call it &quot;Pi&quot;. An old man was wrapped in a quilt and huddled there. Next to his head was a pile of foam bowls with traces of a lunch box. At his feet was a bottle of leftover &quot;Wuliang Chun&quot;. The food was in a mess. In front of the floor was a pair of mud-stained shoes. , a pair of socks with fuzzy fabric hanging on the uppers of his shoes, the street light shining on his exhausted face, and he was snoring like thunder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I coughed slightly, and he woke up and quickly raised his head. I was stunned for a moment, isn’t this Lao Tan! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How can I become a homeless person if I can’t live in a nice villa? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I cooperate with others to grow rice. He smiled reluctantly. Didn&#39;t I tell you that my life is cheap? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Do I have to stay here all night?&quot; I asked. Could anyone still steal? After all, it&#39;s the beginning of winter, and the chilling north wind is making the plastic shack rattle, huddled inside, and it&#39;s like being in the open air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old Tan sighed and said, you city people don’t understand many things. First, the most fearful thing about harvesting rice is rain. When it rains, even in the middle of the night or early in the morning, I must urgently &quot;gather the rice&quot;, pile it into a pile, and cover it with a tarpaulin. Second, the rice is drying here, and we are most afraid of being crushed by cars. We only dry half of the road, but there are too many heavy vehicles coming from the &quot;crop fields&quot;. Late at night, everyone came to stop temporarily. My ears were pricked all night long, and the sound of road pressure could be heard far away. I had to wave the signal light to ask them to &quot;raise your hand&quot;, so that at least less rice could be pressed...&quot; Chapter Third, keeping vigil does prevent theft.&quot; Lao Tan said, don&#39;t be surprised, some people steal rice - chickens, ducks and geese, they gain weight when they eat rice, and their egg production also increases, so rice thieves are all motor vehicles, and they shovel run. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rice he is guarding is called &quot;Nanjing No. 46&quot;. The seed fee is 1.6 yuan per catty; the charter fee is 500 yuan per mu; the fertilizer is 200 yuan per mu; and the manpower and machine farming fee is 105 yuan per mu; Pesticides are 115 yuan per mu; electric irrigation fees are 50 yuan per mu; harvesting fees are 100 yuan per mu. In order to ensure a fragrant and soft taste, organic fertilizers such as chicken manure must be applied per acre, as well as threshing and rice milling fees... In this way, the cost of rice per kilogram is more than 3 yuan, and our commercial grain price is 4 It costs 20 cents per catty. In fact, you can’t even earn 1 yuan per catty. With 26 acres of leased land, you only earn 10,000 to 20,000 yuan a year. The cost is so high, so you have to keep vigil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Farewell, he said he would have to work hard for another four days before returning to the community. His son has made peace with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the bad news came on the fourth day. That morning, he just got up to pack his things and prepare to go home, but he fell down. Cerebral hemorrhage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Heavy machinery in the crop fields is still roaring. But at the entrance, someone drew a circle and burned a lot of paper money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[鄂尔多斯重大高压气体泄漏事故致10死3伤，国务院安委会挂牌督办]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256691]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 20:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Major production safety accident Notice of Investigation and Punishment of Listing Supervision&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Safety Committee Supervision [2023] No. 11&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot; >;People&#39;s Government of Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region:&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;On September 7, 2023, a major high-pressure gas leakage occurred at Yiding Ecological Agriculture Development Co., Ltd. in Ordos City, your district, causing 10 people died and 3 were injured. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;According to the &quot;Measures for the Supervision of the Investigation and Handling of Major Accidents,&quot; the State Council Safety Committee decided to implement the supervision of the investigation and handling of this major accident. Your district must, in accordance with the &quot;Regulations on Reporting, Investigation and Handling of Production Safety Accidents&quot; and other relevant laws, regulations and rules, promptly organize and carry out accident investigations, quickly identify the cause of the accident, and strictly study and propose handling opinions in accordance with the requirements of accident investigation regulations. Before the accident is closed, the accident investigation report (unfinalized) must be submitted to the Office of the State Council Safety Committee. After review and approval, your district will be responsible for approving the closure of the case and announcing it to the public. After the case is closed, the accident investigation report and the implementation of the accident handling decision must be reported to the Office of the State Council Safety Committee for record in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;>;Contact person and phone number: Huang Yong, 010-83933559. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400; text-align: right;&quot;>;State Council Work Safety Commission&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-weight: 400; text-align: right;&quot;>; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbSP; bsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;September 12, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[已涨破600元/克，盘点近年金价趋势丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256704]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“灵活就业”的毕业生，和一轮针对性核查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256675]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/14/sNHZwMvuADwj1CPQR3Pntdh9Q6ZY5K2couy1rWDi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1142&quot; height=&quot;1068&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/sNHZwMvuADwj1CPQR3Pntdh9Q6ZY5K2couy1r WDi. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250778&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Nongjian/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How can a graduate prove that he is &quot;flexibly employed&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The only proof Yang Yu, a 2023 graduate of a 211 university in Beijing, was asked to provide was a handwritten letter of guarantee, which read: I guarantee that my salary will be higher than 2,420 yuan per month after graduation. 2,420 yuan is the minimum wage in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It wasn’t until one month after Yang Yu graduated that the school informed him that the certificate was not valid enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Bank statements or transfer records of income, chat records about work situations, or photos of work scenes.&quot; At noon on August 5, 2023, the counselor sent a new request. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not an afterthought on the part of the school. One day ago, the Ministry of Education issued a notice and dispatched multiple working groups to various provinces to conduct special employment verification, check the employment data self-check list, verify the self-check report, spot-check relevant employment supporting materials, and opened a supervision and reporting hotline and email address to detect any false employment information. Relevant universities and personnel will be held accountable for violations signed and certified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flexible employment is the focus of this inspection. Yang Yu, who plans to become a food blogger, is one of them. In previous statistics on his graduation destination, he filled in an annual salary of 300,000-500,000 yuan. Yang Yu said that he really &quot;thought about making this amount. Being an Internet celebrity is very profitable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He not only wants to do &quot;eating broadcast&quot;, but also hopes to present the character of a blogger who loves life through long videos. However, the data for long videos is not ideal. Currently, the four videos he posted on a certain social media have the highest likes of 49. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2024 school recruitment season has begun. After delaying entering the job market for a long time, some people have decided to get out of their confusion and re-enter the social chain. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Flexible Employment”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Today, the real life of food blogger Yang Yu is like this:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Monday to Friday , he and his girlfriend shared a two-bedroom apartment in a county near Zhengzhou. The apartment was located in a community with the best conditions in the county, but their lives depended on online loans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early on Saturday morning, he first took the bus, then the subway, then the train, and returned to his hometown to teach children how to swim. This job was recommended by a friend at home who owns a swimming pool. Yang Yu likes this job because &quot;he works less and makes more money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first week after confirming the shared tenancy, Yang Yu and his girlfriend purchased a large bag of oil, salt, sauce, vinegar and pots and pans from the supermarket, moved them from the supermarket to an electric car, and then took them home and moved them upstairs together. . &quot;At that time, I thought that when I finally have my own home, I must cook a lot of my favorite dishes.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But now his concept has changed, &quot;I will measure my time according to the standard of making quick money. If you can earn 200 yuan an hour, then spending an hour cooking is a waste. It is better to spend 20 yuan to eat out.” He started visiting the neighborhood pizza parlor and gained weight compared to when he was a student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the materials given to the counselor, Yang Yu wrote, &quot;As a perfectionist, I have been constantly testing and adjusting to make myself more confident.&quot; He has been three I haven’t updated the video in months, and my phone is full of test shots. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He himself is aware of the contradiction, &quot;I plan to shoot a new video early the next morning, but the reality is that I usually turn off the alarm clock and go to sleep.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the self-certified flexible employment methods, the &quot;income guarantee letter&quot; provided by Yang Yu is only an extremely niche one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meng Lan, who graduated from a 211 college in Wuhan majoring in advertising, provided the transaction flow of selling idle items on Xianyu; Wu Xuan, a Chinese major from a normal college, provided screenshots of income and work chats Records to prove her identity as a freelance writer - she experienced failed postgraduate entrance examinations and failed autumn recruitment before graduation, and then decided to return to her hometown to become a freelancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter food bloggers or online store owners, they are not their first choice. Postgraduate entrance examinations and editing examinations are. But Yang Yu has no specific review plan. His daily study time ranges from one hour to five hours. “Sometimes he doesn’t do much in a day, but the study time is just gone.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meng Lan often doubted herself and even developed neurasthenia and depression. &quot;After graduation, I felt sluggish every day and felt that I was incapable of doing many things well.&quot; Now she decided to fight for the next national examination and signed up for the national examination to get off work offline, &quot;from 8 am to 10 pm every day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since you have to take public and postgraduate entrance exams, why do you call yourself flexible employment? Meng Lan said that before graduation, the counselor and class teacher knew that she would continue to take the civil service exam. They interviewed Meng Lan on the grounds of college employment and suggested that she fill in &quot;self-employment&quot; and the job content was to open a store on Xianyu. &quot;Some of my classmates from World War II were also interviewed by teachers and asked to fill in the form of flexible employment.&quot; According to Meng Lan&#39;s estimate, there are nearly ten people in the class who are in a similar situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Yu’s situation is more complicated. In May 2023, on the school’s employment statistics questionnaire, Yang Yu truthfully filled out “unknown employment direction”. Soon, the counselor contacted him and said that &quot;the college leaders want to help.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two other students in the same major received assistance, and they both got interview opportunities from a unit in Beijing. When he arrived at the interview site, Yang Yu hesitated. &quot;I don&#39;t want to go, the salary is low, and I hate working the night shift. The fundamental reason is that I don&#39;t want to work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, the three students decided to tell the college that they wanted to do self-media. However, unlike Yang Yu, who thought he could earn three to five million, the other two were conservative in terms of annual salary. They filled in &quot;50,000-100,000.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/nPtS9sHGHvCtbsoSM2IBCSTIk58iOpmTPvNLQjfk.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;933&quot; height= &quot;622&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/nPtS9sHGHvCtbsoSM2IBCSTIk58iOpmTPvNLQjfk.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250776&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In November 2018, a &quot;eating broadcaster&quot; appeared in Hangzhou, Zhejiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Rising year by year&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; Than&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Bloggers, online store owners, and freelance writers are all flexible employment. According to relevant documents from the General Office of the State Council, flexible employment refers to flexible and diverse employment methods such as self-employment, part-time employment, and new employment forms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This formulation appeared in 2002. At that time, the Ministry of Education proposed in its employment work to &quot;actively open up various channels such as temporary employment and flexible employment.&quot; Two years later, it was included in graduate employment statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 2021, the &quot;employment rate&quot; of college graduates will be changed to the &quot;graduation destination implementation rate&quot;, which includes the flexible employment rate, which coexists with the agreement and contract employment rate, entrepreneurship rate, and enrollment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One concept that needs to be clarified is that the Ministry of Education’s employment rate statistics are different from those of the National Bureau of Statistics, and it is the latter that is more commonly discussed in the media. &quot;In the unemployment rate statistics of the Bureau of Statistics, only the unemployment rate of people who want to be employed is counted. In other words, people who have no intention of employment are not included in the denominator. However, the denominator of the employment rate statistics of colleges and universities is the total number of graduates, and there is no distinction between employment intention.&quot; Feng Xiliang, vice president of the China Labor Society and professor at the School of Labor Economics at Capital University of Economics and Business, pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In employment statistics, there are more and more graduates with &quot;flexible employment&quot;. According to Zhaopin recruitment data, the proportion of flexible employment among college graduates in 2022 has increased by 10.9% compared with 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Flexible employment is indeed a development trend.” Feng Xiliang said, “In the past, flexible employment was mostly skilled work. Due to the development of information technology, new employment forms have emerged in recent years, relying on There are more and more flexible jobs in information networks.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another trend is the flexibility of standard employment. &quot;The boundaries of jobs are becoming increasingly blurred, such as labor dispatch personnel and contract employees. Mobile work blurs the boundaries of previous positions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Xiliang believes that the statistical standards of colleges and universities should also be adjusted with the development of the times. Three years ago, he suggested that relevant departments appropriately relax the statistical standards of flexible employment. Students who are suitable for the position and those who start their own businesses. For example, Yang Yu and Meng Lan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flexible employment is becoming a &quot;reservoir&quot; in graduate employment rate statistics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that taking universities in Hebei Province as an example, according to the employment quality reports released by each university, the flexible employment rate of undergraduates in Chengde Medical College, Baoding University, and Hebei Normal University for Nationalities in 2022 exceeded 50 %. Among them, the total number of graduates of Hebei Normal University for Nationalities in 2022 is 3,294, and the total number of flexible employment is 1,941, accounting for 58.93%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Xiliang is cautious about the flexible employment rate of nearly 60%. According to Feng Xiliang&#39;s 2021 survey, about 14% of graduates choose flexible employment, of which about 70% are active, and about 30% are &quot;passively&quot; employed flexibly because they cannot find a suitable job or during the transition period. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In that survey, after completing 8,604 valid questionnaires in 30 universities, Feng Xiliang found that the flexible employment rates of different schools and majors vary. “Graduates of art and foreign language majors have flexible employment options. The proportion of employment is higher, and the flexible employment rate is higher in junior colleges than in undergraduate schools.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Half Moon Talk&quot; report, some colleges and universities are cheating on their employment rates. Counselors told students in the WeChat group, &quot;If you can&#39;t find a job, just write flexible employment when filling out the form&quot; and &quot;If you encounter a survey, just write &quot;flexible employment&quot; He said he was doing self-media.&quot; A counselor at a Beijing science and engineering 211 college also told a reporter from Beijing Youth Daily that some &quot;edge balls&quot; will be played in the employment rate, such as registering part-time jobs as flexible employment. This category does not require a tripartite agreement and can be counted. into the employment rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the routine verification of the employment rate of graduates of the Ministry of Education in 2023, flexible employment has become the focus of the verification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/IMonWDCtySveZYKhvmALzex4Z80tSKVUHLiLcnmY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;970&quot; height= &quot;647&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/IMonWDCtySveZYKhvmALzex4Z80tSKVUHLiLcnmY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250777&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 20, 2023, an outdoor night market job fair was held in Guanyun County, Lianyungang City, Jiangsu Province. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Verification&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How to check flexible employment? Southern Weekend reporters noted that the main methods for verifying employment data in each province are intra-provincial inspections, self-inspections within schools, mutual inspections between colleges, and supervision and reporting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take provincial inspections as an example. In early July 2023, the Hunan Provincial Department of Education issued a notice requiring schools with a flexible employment rate of more than 20% to submit a special inspection report. The report includes the reasons, inspection status, Correction results and other information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some universities in Hunan Province have made this ratio even stricter. Hunan Institute of Technology proposed that secondary colleges with a flexible employment rate of more than 15% &quot;need to strictly check the flexible employment categories and submit a written flexible employment verification report.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Xiliang analyzed that the Hunan Provincial Department of Education’s flexible employment rate red line may have been set with reference to the previous flexible employment situation of college students. According to statistics from the National College Student Information Consultation and Employment Guidance Center, flexible employment accounts for 16.9% of college graduates in the country in 2020, and 16.25% of college graduates in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“But 20% is not an absolutely correct red line, and relevant departments can control it more flexibly.” Feng Xiliang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the school level, there are also &quot;self-examinations&quot; and &quot;mutual examinations&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 12, 2023, Jining Medical College issued an announcement stating that when secondary colleges conduct mutual inspections, flexible employment telephone interview verification must &quot;achieve 100% coverage.&quot; The announcement also stated that the Shandong Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security will organize on-site cross-checks between colleges and universities five days before graduates leave school. The team will be led by the leader in charge of employment, carrying laptops and all employment certification materials, and will conduct cross-checks between schools. A list of inspection opinions and issues will be formed, and “if no problems are found during the inspection, but problems are discovered later in the inspection by the superior organization, the relevant inspection units shall bear joint and several liability.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Surveillance calls are another method of verifying employment rates. Southern Weekend reporters contacted seven colleges and universities through the published supervision and reporting hotlines, and the responses they received were all &quot;no reports have been received from students so far.&quot; However, there is not much difference in the verification methods. A staff member of the Employment Office of Yunnan Special Education Vocational College told Southern Weekend reporters that if a student does not have a &quot;formal job&quot; but &quot;his department and major report that he has a job or flexible employment&quot;, then the Employment Office &quot;will step by step Downward, the responsible persons of departments, majors, classes, counselors and teachers are held accountable.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The verification process of student reports is somewhat difficult. The Employment Office of Inner Mongolia Agricultural University told Southern Weekend reporters that students choosing to report with their real names will be more conducive to the school&#39;s investigation and verification one by one. A staff member of the Employment Office of Inner Mongolia Normal University said that the Education Department had reported that there were anonymous reports from students at the school, but because the school was unable to obtain student information, it could only conduct a large-scale investigation to see whether teachers had said or done these things. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Back to the social chain&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Neither really employed nor After preparing for the exam with all their strength, several flexible employment graduates interviewed revealed complex group characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They all have certain financial security provided by their families. The family hopes that Meng Lan will continue to take the civil service exam next year. &quot;We have not considered the option of working directly. Now I am preparing for the exam at home. I have no source of income, but I have sufficient support from my family.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xuan’s father likes his daughter to cook for him at home. “He thinks it would be good for me to be a full-time daughter.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Xiliang’s research found that family economic foundation, digital development and professional matching will all affect students’ tendency to choose flexible employment. &quot;If parents have a certain financial foundation and can give their children space to develop freely, graduates will get more understanding and support. In addition, digital background is the biggest technical factor, and mastering digital technology provides a foundation for college students to find flexible employment.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Compared with flexible employment, Yang Yu and Meng Lan&#39;s status is actually closer to &quot;slow employment&quot;, that is, they neither intend to find employment immediately nor continue their studies after graduation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;2023 College Student Employability Survey Report&quot; released by Zhaopin Recruitment in May 2023, among the 2023 graduates, the proportion of &quot;slow employment&quot; increased from 15.9% in 2022 to 18.9%, which is close to the overall rate. one-fifth of . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We are different from the older generation. We don’t have to worry about survival issues after graduation. I can go to graduate school, make money, start a business as a food blogger, or even take the civil service exam if I can’t. I have many options, so I won’t be anxious,” Yang Yu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The trouble is that he still doesn’t know what he really wants to do. &quot;Although there are many choices in front of me, I need to work hard for any future, and I have nothing now.&quot; Walking on the road, he is often swept away by a sense of emptiness, and has not yet adapted to the fact that he is no longer part of the social chain. College students here.” &quot;I used to think it was not good to go to school for too long. After I graduated, I found that I didn&#39;t want to grow up and wanted to go to school more.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Yu’s latest food shop exploration material was shot on August 4. He made up his mind, “I will definitely post a new video within three days.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My parents said before that if you don&#39;t pass the public examination, you can do whatever you want. But now I still haven&#39;t done what I originally wanted to do. Sometimes, I don&#39;t know到底是家庭的束缚，还是我自己对自己的束缚。”孟兰在大学时一直做约拍摄影师，她一度希望这份热爱变为长久的职业，而如今却在全力准备考公。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京大学教育学院副院长岳昌君曾撰文称，近年来高校毕业生“考研热”“考编热”“慢就业”等现象可以反映出，毕业生对未来就业还没有做好能力上的充足准备。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冯喜良则觉得，这一代大学生的心态与三年疫情的影响不无关系。 “大学在疫情中度过，上课和实习可能都是线上的，他们更倾向利用虚拟网络来认知社会，解决问题，对于现实社会的接触不多。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;真正实现了灵活就业的吴宣，则在两个月的自由撰稿人体验后还是决定去上班。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自由撰稿的收入既不稳定也不可观，吴宣也察觉到自己精神状态的变化，两个月的自由生活里，她的工作意愿越来越低，“缺乏与人的深度链接，逐渐封闭起来”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发现灵活就业生活与预期并不相符后，吴宣最终选择成为家乡的一名初中语文老师。虽然坐班制限制了自由，但她“终于感觉进入了社会链条，不再那么焦虑了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，杨宇、孟兰、吴宣为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 20:25:14 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[癌症老人乘机被拒，哪些情况不能飞？川航称艾滋患者需报备]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256689]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;9月12日，一名癌症旅客在成都天府国际机场办理值机时，被拒绝登机。根据旁观者拍摄的现场视频，被拒绝登机的乘客疑似罹患癌症四个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现场视频显示，当日上午9时45分左右，在EU2205次航班的登机口处，一名老年男子坐在轮椅上，疑似为家属的男子和老年女子坐在地上。男子向工作人员喊道：“承诺书签了，医院证明也写了，我还带了护理工，你不让我走。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随后，该男子疑似与航司另一工作人员通话，“有癌症，四个月，之前你说没有心脏病，没有呼吸道疾病，没有外伤伤口，都可以。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，南都记者向成都航空有限公司致电，客服回应称若乘客为早期、中期癌症，是可以承运的，但若对方为晚期癌症，出于飞机的空运环境、医疗设施等条件限制，便不予承运。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据南都记者查询，在《成都航空有限公司旅客、行李国内运输总条件》的第EU05版中，“癌症晚期患者”确在其中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6P1HD8tOa06hRhDtqm6q5sUkJha11836nXXwSPkt.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1017&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6P1HD8tOa06hRhDtqm6q5sUkJha11836nXXwSPkt.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250781&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南都记者同样致电了成都天府国际机场的客服，对方称不了解此事，“由航空公司来解释。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得注意的是，成都航空有限公司还称若乘机老人年龄高于65岁，则建议在乘机前72小时以内，在县级以上的医院开具健康证明，否则在登机时，若地面地服人员认为老人“精神萎靡”，则有可能被拒载，而拒载后，“责任需要乘客自己承担。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，当南都记者进一步追问“精神萎靡”的判断标准，客服则无法给出具体描述。而在《成都航空有限公司旅客、行李国内运输总条件》中，并未看到相关规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据南都记者查询发现，各家航空公司对于不予承运的标准并不相同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据2021年交通运输部发布《公共航空运输旅客服务管理规定》相关条款：运输总条件至少应当包括的内容有：“旅客乘机相关规定，包括婴儿、孕妇、无成人陪伴儿童、重病患者等特殊旅客的承运标准”。也就是说，航空公司可以就此制定承运标准，但具体标准为何，并无具体规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如中国南方航空便明确规定：水痘病人在损害部位未痊愈，不能乘飞机；脑血管病人。如脑栓塞、脑出血、脑肿瘤这类病人，由于飞机起降的轰鸣、震动及缺氧等，可使病情加重，禁止乘飞机。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四川航空有限公司则规定，由于身体原因需要给予特殊照料，或在满足一定条件下才能运输的旅客，只有在符合川航运输规定，经川航预先同意，并在必要时做出安排后才能接受运输。其中包括重病旅客、担架旅客、需用早产婴儿保育箱者、患有艾滋病且身体无任何外伤的旅客等需要向其出示川航认可医院出具的，并有该名旅客的医生签名的医疗证明。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/PIV3CwEUrih0SedAmv4EdhrI95es9bJz4AbW0ADX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;655&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/PIV3CwEUrih0SedAmv4EdhrI95es9bJz4AbW0ADX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250780&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;厦门航空对拒载乘客的条件则列得更为详细，包括各项医疗指标参数、术后时间等等。在南都记者致电厦航公司客服询问何种情况不能登机时，对方则称“除了喝酒的情况一般都可以登机，没有什么明确的规定。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 19:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[台风拔树树砸车，谁来赔，怎么赔？物业保险、车损险与巨灾险了解一下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256671]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;当台风等灾害发生，往往会给当地居民人身、财产造成重大损失。据新京报报道，9月2日，今年第9号台风“苏拉”以强台风级别登陆广东，受台风天气影响，深圳市福田区北环大道上，路边多棵树木被强风刮倒，一辆汽车被树砸中，造成车内1人死亡2人受伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另据《城市零距离》今年7月报道，受台风“泰利”影响，中山市的吕先生住的小区里有一棵榕树被吹倒，砸中了他的小车，小车受损十分严重。对此，物业称，“希望业主尽快将车辆开去维修点或者4S店去维修，我们自己是有一个&#39;公共责任险&#39;，业主维修完之后将报价、目录同步报给我们，我们报给保险公司。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以上两起事件虽与天灾有关，但因此车辆被砸甚至造成人员伤亡，当事人及家属事后必然会寻求相应救济。以小区为例，车停小区被树木砸中，物业是否担责，之前屡有争议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京海淀法院有这样一个案例。当事人张先生称，当天夜间大雨，树木倾倒导致其停放在小区的车辆受损，且该树木在倾倒之前已经出现树根鼓出地面的情况，故向法院提起诉讼，要求物业公司赔偿各项损失。物业公司辩称，第一，涉案小区为非经营性资产，其不收取物业费和停车费，只提供最低基础保障，物业公司并非树木所有权人及管理人；第二，园林部门规定不可以私自处理树木，故即使之前出现了树根鼓出地面的情况其也无法处理；第三，当天夜间暴雨属不可抗力。此外，张先生的汽车已经通过保险维修完毕，不能再次获得赔偿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，法院审理认为，物业公司系诉争小区的物业服务企业，虽未收取业主交纳的物业服务费或停车费，但仍负有对小区内设备、设施及各项事务的管理职责，系本案中折断的树木的管理人。物业公司虽主张其对于树木折断不存在过错，但提交证据并不足以证明对涉案树木尽到了合理的管理和养护义务，且双方均认可事发前涉案树木已经出现树根鼓出地面的情形，但物业公司并未予以处理。另外，事发当晚虽有大雨，但仍属一般自然力，物业公司抗辩称属于不可抗力不能成立。故物业公司应承担相应责任。但因张先生所主张的车辆维修费已获保险赔付，对于张先生要求物业公司向其支付该部分费用的诉请，法院无法予以支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于物业对小区树木的管理责任，民法典第1257条规定， 因林木折断、倾倒或者果实坠落等造成他人损害，林木的所有人或者管理人不能证明自己没有过错的，应当承担侵权责任。这说明，只要在小区内，树木都属于物业管辖范围。物业如果以所谓遭遇台风、暴雨等不可抗力因素而非日常管理为由拒赔，其理由不成立。因台风等有事先预报，物业应提前对地面露天停车场中栽种的树木进行检查和加固，避免损害的发生。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;显然，物业公司要避免类似情况，最好的办法是学习《南京零距离》报道中的小区物业，购买物业保险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;物业保险是指物业向保险公司交付保险费，双方签订保险合同，在合同规定范围内的事由、事故、灾害发生后，由保险公司在合同规定范围内承担赔偿。物业保险涉及范围广泛，其中的公众责任保险，指投保方在公众活动场所的过错行为致使他人的人身或财产遭受损害，依法应由其承担的对受害人的经济赔偿责任。通过投保这一险种，一旦出现小区树木砸损车辆乃至人员等问题，保险公司将予以赔付。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谁来支付这笔保费？《物业服务收费管理办法》规定，物业服务成本或者物业服务支出构成包括物业共用部位、共用设施设备及公众责任保险费用，也即物业向业主收取的物业费中，已涵盖公众责任保险费用。因此，一旦发生“小区车被树砸”事件，物业应先行赔付，再找保险公司理赔。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，北京海淀法院的判决提供了另一种解决方案，车主如购买了车损险（车辆损失险），即可自行向投保的保险公司理赔。据某保险公司的车损险介绍，对火灾、爆炸、外界物体倒塌、空中运行物体坠落、雷击、暴风、龙卷风、暴雨、洪水等情况造成的车辆损失，均予以赔偿。但车损险属车主自愿投保，目前这一模式还属于小众范围。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在深圳案例中，由于事故发生于公共区域，按照民法典规定，树木的所有人和管理人同样应担责，除非其充分举证事故引发原因属不可抗力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，对于这一市政区域内的“树砸车、树砸人”事故的赔偿成本分摊，还有巨灾险可承接。作为我国首批巨灾保险试点城市之一，宁波市自2014年即启动了巨灾保险试点，宁波市民政局代表宁波市政府作为投保人，与人保财险宁波市分公司签署巨灾保险合同，保障内容既涵盖台风、暴雨等造成的居民家庭财产损失，也包含人身伤亡责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可见，通过物业保险的兜底，以及车损险、巨灾险等多类险种的推广，当台风等灾害发生，造成树砸车等人员财产损失，无论是发生于小区内还是城市公共区域，都能最大限度做到“有灾不再自认倒霉”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[农业农村部：“村播”是乡村振兴的新型人才]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256669]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/QlxZKn8nGYMOEvcJ2FGQKwMnaWciu5CKBUu5vtw3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;714&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/QlxZKn8nGYMOEvcJ2FGQKwMnaWciu5CKBUu5vtw3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250775&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月8日，贵州岑巩县注溪镇的果农通过直播销售金秋梨。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（人民视觉/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农村和城市一样，消费潜力巨大。 2023年9月12日，农业农村部信息中心副主任张国庆表示，农民收入增速已经连续11年快于城镇居民，乡镇和村两级消费市场更占我国消费市场总量的38%，但要在资源与市场之间架起连接通道，推动乡村经济进一步发展，还需要利用短视频、直播工具的“村播”们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当天，张国庆在快手追光大会现场致辞时表示，“村播”作为乡村振兴的新型人才，为乡村振兴带来了人才的“源头活水”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对“村播”的重视在很大程度上与互联网电商的发展趋势密不可分。2023年8月15日的专题发布会上，商务部流通发展司司长李刚曾介绍，2022年，全国农村网络零售额达2.17万亿元，农产品网络零售额达5313.8亿元，与2014年相比，同比增长11倍和4倍之多。截止到2022年底，全国农村网商（店）已达到1730.3万家，全国农村网民规模更超3亿人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仅在河北肃宁县，一个位于中部城市沧州最西端的小县城，靠着6500余家鱼竿渔具网店，就已经解决了当地近四分之一的人口就业问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;河北肃宁县数字经济发展服务中心主任李朝辉介绍，当地34万常住人口中，有3万人直接从事电商，8.5万人间接从事打包、视频制作等相关工作，产品网上销售率达90%以上。而在中国新闻网此前报道中，2023年7月初的一场3小时直播中，肃宁县一位“村播”吸引到了15万人观看，单场成交额即突破10万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月12日， 26岁的“村播”格绒卓姆作为新农人代表，再次回忆起发生在2017年的第一次尝试。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;五千多米的高山上，她在“迷藏卓玛”这个账号下，发出了自己的第一条视频。那是一个飘雪的5月，镜头中，她穿梭于裸露的乱石中，弯腰寻找野生虫草，身后是一片灰蒙蒙的山谷，一条雪白的溪流隐约可见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意外地，次日这条14秒钟的日常记录即获得了五十多万的播放量，私信中，几百个远方的陌生人提出，想要购买虫草。“当时我卖了两千多块钱，特别的高兴”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去六年，越来越多像格绒卓姆一样的新农人，作为“村播”出现在镜头中，他们通过短视频、直播销售农产品。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张国庆介绍，早在2022年，农业农村部就与共青团中央联合快手平台，以提升160个国家乡村振兴重点县的农民收入和壮大县域经济为目标，开展了国家乡村振兴重点帮扶县“农村青年主播”培育工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对乡村人才的重视已被写进2023年中央一号文件。在2023年及今后一个时期的“三农”工作中，要“加强乡村人才队伍建设”，实施乡村振兴人才支持计划和高素质农民培育计划，开展农村创业带头人培育行动已被纳入规划。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“截止到2022年底，全国返乡入乡创业人员数量累计达1220万人，带动乡村就业超过3400万人，农村返乡入乡创新创业覆盖率达到83.6%。”而在张国庆看来，数字技术和数字经济的力量还未发挥到极致，到2025年，全国各类返乡入乡人员有望达到1500万以上，“我相信，在这个数字时代，每一个普通人，每一个村庄，每一种喝彩都能发出热烈的光芒。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[这几种新型网络传销骗局，你要小心了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256639]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 16:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近年来&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着互联网的发展和普及&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;网络传销不断变换犯罪手法&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各种传销骗术层出不穷&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;导致受害者负债累累&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;甚至家破人亡……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如何防范新型网络传销？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;快来学习其中的套路和注意事项&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/1326320865d24dc9c7c7ad08a6351b68.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/1326320865d24dc9c7c7ad08a6351b68.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250768&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/9b0944cdfc1a8bf222144879f8cfc311.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/9b0944cdfc1a8bf222144879f8cfc311.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250771&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6fab457bc4def83a2bfe77fdd5b298bb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/6fab457bc4def83a2bfe77fdd5b298bb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ee25c8147bc94c15ee480062ad941eb4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/ee25c8147bc94c15ee480062ad941eb4.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250766&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4a08c3d88e750d2b6c6157003e1e6fee.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4a08c3d88e750d2b6c6157003e1e6fee.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250767&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/461bf916a64f6b682a7c8c812096dda8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/461bf916a64f6b682a7c8c812096dda8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/89e498d62257cbaf74c03ce93ba3a597.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/89e498d62257cbaf74c03ce93ba3a597.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250770&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/41d7bfced0bc7ff5e8e7ed459e9a6d24.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1138&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/41d7bfced0bc7ff5e8e7ed459e9a6d24.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250769&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中华儿慈会志愿者疑卷走近千万救助款，大病家庭再陷配捐骗局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256685]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 16:40:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4zwOxqpbGWvqHUyXVnrvZHoYrcG1kePsVXTtsk1Z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/4zwOxqpbGWvqHUyXVnrvZHoYrcG1kePsVXTtsk1Z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250787&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，中华少年儿童慈善救助基金会（简称中华儿慈会）被曝光其“河北项目负责人”卷走千万救助款，患者家属疑遭诈骗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月13日，意识到被骗的家长们再次来到中华儿慈会门口。部分家属告诉南方周末记者，他们参与了中华儿慈会“河北项目负责人”柯某孝的配捐活动。按照前期宣传，以“48500配1500”为例，家长自筹48500元“捐”至指定账户，20天至一个月不等的时间后，能收到本金加上1500元配捐共5万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一项目曾有许多病友参与，家属未曾怀疑，直至2023年8月底许诺的资金迟迟没有回款，他们发现被骗。患者家属王军告诉南方周末记者，目前家长初步统计后，发现共有88个家庭受骗，涉及900万余元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月13日晚，中华儿慈会发布声明否认柯某孝为该会工作人员，也从未委托过柯某孝个人为9958儿童紧急救助项目（以下简称9958）筹集资金。而网传的1000万元资金，该声明表示该会账号从未收到过这些资金，“当事人将资金打给柯某孝个人账户，并曾从柯某孝个人账户获得返款”。中华儿慈会工作人员对媒体表示，柯某孝身份为志愿者，警方已对其冒名诈骗的行为立案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/i07q2brvtfYqkvkqU8kr4AGmBBrqgc9slafRzILq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1242&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/i07q2brvtfYqkvkqU8kr4AGmBBrqgc9slafRzILq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250785&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月13日，中华儿慈会发布声明。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（中华儿慈会官网/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;习以为常的“配捐”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;9月13日下午，南方周末记者来到位于北京的中华儿慈会门口时，部分家属代表进入儿慈会办公室沟通，更多患儿家属则在院外等待。他们大都是带着孩子异地求医，从湖北、湖南、四川等地到河北燕达陆道培医院及山东省肿瘤医院治疗，在医院附近租房居住。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李燕的孩子两岁时确诊为神经母细胞瘤，这是一种非常罕见的儿童癌症，为此她们一家从四川到山东省肿瘤医院求医。治疗两年来，家里已花费数百万元，“免疫治疗一个月得几十万，全自费”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孩子确诊以后，李燕加入了病友群，在病友群里，她发现经常有人在群里发大病救助的筹款配捐信息，一直有病友参加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据部分家长展示的页面，这些配捐通知描述简单，如“101500，配2500，一个月回款”“这个月名额只有一个，想做的报名”。李燕说，每次配捐的金额都不一样，参与的名额也不一样。以49000元配捐1000元为例，家长自筹49000元投入该项目中的同时，还要提供5万元的医疗发票，才能获得5万元的回款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位家长称，配捐回款有时打回家长个人账户，有时直接拨付至医院的指定账户，家长凭借报销单据逐笔核销，“不能取出来，只能用于医院治疗”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对家长而言，家里有大病患儿的负担很重。“普通人的感冒只是一件小事，对他们（白血病人）来说，可能要几万块钱治疗”，另一位在现场的家长陈晨说，12岁的女儿患髓系白血病，仅是一盒靶向药便要3万多。“能配捐1000、2000元，付房租，改善一下伙食，我们还是很愿意的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;患儿家属在照顾孩子的过程中，共享治疗经验，互相安慰理解，形成了不一样的信任感。李燕称更早确诊的病友为“前辈”，她知道有些病友已经做配捐好几年了，都是正常回款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有的病友则看重9958项目的“招牌”，它由中华儿慈会举办，几乎患儿家庭都知道。而在拉家长做配捐时，组织者都会问是否已入档。“入档”是指录入儿慈会9958项目的档案，家长们通过扫二维码填写“中华儿慈会9958儿童紧急救助中心申请表（廊坊）”，提供孩子姓名、年龄、病情等信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你知道之前有很多人做过，大家对这个事情持默认态度”，李燕说正是这种常态化的操作方式、病友之间彼此的信任，让她对项目的真实性没有产生怀疑。加上大病患儿需要小心翼翼护理，父母的身心都投入小孩身上，很难有心力核实项目的真伪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月25日，李燕和山东肿瘤医院的几位病友向张某账户转了48500元，由张某逐层转账，汇给柯某孝，约定在9月15日回款5万元。但是9月初，他们得知上一批病友的钱没有及时回款，柯某孝也失联，这才意识到款项无法追回。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;家属在河北燕达陆道培医院治疗的王军告诉南方周末记者，8月30日柯某孝没有及时给病友回款后，十多位家属找到柯某孝要说法。在柯某孝多次推脱后，家长联合向河北燕郊警方报案，警方立案后对柯某孝采取刑事拘留措施。出事后，患儿家庭彼此问了一下，大部分家长参与了“48500配1500”“101500配2500”“126000配4000”的项目，“最少投了4万8，最多的投了30万多”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/t6oBhADmLsHcKeDOgIshQ4Nf6U88M5Q3UTyi9HX9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1079&quot; height=&quot;1079&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/14/t6oBhADmLsHcKeDOgIshQ4Nf6U88M5Q3UTyi9HX9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250786&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;患者家属参与该“配捐”项目的信息记录。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“最佳领导力”的志愿者&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;事实上，类似的公益配捐骗局曾多次出现。（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;详见南方周末报道&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/pOTRdqBYVw-c9-xTie39dQ&quot;>;&lt;u>;《百万款项下落不明，白血病家庭疑遇“公益配捐”骗局》&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;）此次事件引起广泛关注，或因涉及金额较大且牵涉中华儿慈会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中华少年儿童慈善救助基金会于2010年成立，为民政部主管的全国性公募基金会，主要从医疗、成长、教育、文体等方面，对困境儿童、事实无人抚养儿童、留守儿童、流浪儿童等开展帮扶活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9958儿童紧急救助项目则成立于2012年,为中华儿慈会的自主品牌项目，该项目服务于0-18岁的困境儿童群体，整合资讯信息服务、筹资渠道服务、救助执行服务三大功能。据中华儿慈会官网介绍，目前9958主要设立了50多个合作项目，搭建紧急救助通道网络和全国救助分中心25家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据中华儿慈会的声明，柯某孝仅在该会9958儿童紧急救助项目河北廊坊地区合作机构中当过短暂的志愿者，而家长的转账是打给柯某孝个人账户。南方周末记者在现场了解到，受访家长的筹款配捐确实没有转入9958项目的对公账户，而是转入多个不同的个人账户。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管如此，家长们都认为柯某孝行为与儿慈会有关。多位家长告诉南方周末记者，首次参与配捐项目必须扫码填写“中华儿慈会9958儿童紧急救助中心申请表（廊坊）”，60岁的潘昌荣称孙子因白血病在陆道培医院治疗，他们的信息已录入儿慈会的系统，“说明那个码是真的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，家属们说配捐回款的流水单显示拨款人为中华儿慈会，并据此认为这些配捐项目是由中华儿慈会操作执行的正规项目。但未有家长向南方周末记者出示相关的回款单据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王军说，9月7日以前，家长们还能在中华儿慈会的官网上看到柯某孝的个人介绍，说明他是9958项目廊坊团队的主任，但是9月8日与中华儿慈会正式沟通时，家长们发现官网已删除相关信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，中华儿慈会负责人还向前来沟通的家属出具了一份解约文件。该解约文件称，“儿慈会9958救助项目廊坊救助站的签约机构为天津市北辰区天眷公益服务中心，因救助量未达到标准，不符合9958儿童紧急救助项目的发展需求，经过评估于2023年3月31日和廊坊救助站解约，解约后9958救助项目廊坊救助站进行的任何名义募捐、宣传等活动都与中华儿慈会9958儿童紧急救助项目无关”。南方周末记者从照片中看到，该文件上面盖有儿慈会公章，落款时间为2023年3月31日。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王军称，案件被警方立案受理后，警方曾就这一情况询问中华儿慈会项目负责人，对方承认该解约书是这两天补办的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王军指出，目前在9958儿童紧急救助的公众号上，仍有一篇2月发布的全国网络平台培训活动的文章，配图显示柯某孝获颁“中华儿慈会2022年度最佳领导力奖”。签约仪式中，作为廊坊团队代表签约合影的正是柯某孝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月13日下午，中华儿慈会的工作人员称暂不能接受南方周末记者采访，上述信息未能得到证实。在随后发布的声明中，中华儿慈会也未对以上信息做出说明，仅提到柯某孝目前已被河北三河市公安局燕郊治安分局拘押，正在接受调查，他们也向公安机关进行了举报，并积极配合公安机关进行调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与中华儿慈会进行沟通的家属代表告诉南方周末记者，中华儿慈会对家长表示，目前该案已刑事立案，需等到警察调查结束后，能追回多少款项再赔付多少。“但好多家庭等不了那么长时间，孩子都在医院。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同一天，腾讯公益、新浪微公益分别发文回应，称9958涉嫌诈骗的行为未发生在该平台，但基于平台运营规则、行业自律公约及用户为本的原则，对9958所有项目暂停筹款，等待政府部门的调查结果，并根据结果做进一步处理。南方周末记者查阅后发现，腾讯公益平台共上线2939个9958项目，目前均已标注“筹款结束”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中患者家属均为化名，南方周末记者汪徐秋林亦有贡献）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>