<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[孩子被欺负，该打回去吗？谈谈我对孩子的勇气教育]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260544]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My son, who is in fifth grade, got into a fight at school. When my wife told me, my first reaction was surprise. My son has been mild-mannered since he was a child, not competitive, and rarely conflicts with other children. Before the fifth grade, he had never had a fight. The most he had was an argument and a few angry words. My wife and I occasionally worry: We have been competitive for half our lives, and our children will not be bullied if they have such a bad temper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a naughty little boy in the class who loves to tease others. He is strong and full of energy, and other students cannot stop him. My son occasionally complains: This classmate is very annoying and always teases him and touches him. At first we couldn&#39;t hear the big problem, so we didn&#39;t take it seriously. It is normal for boys to collide with each other. If there is no fight or trouble, we as parents will not interfere deeply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My son complained several times. One day, my wife and I told him: &quot;If the teacher can&#39;t control things, you can solve them yourself. If it doesn&#39;t work, just call him back and don&#39;t let others bully you.&quot; The complaints stopped for a few days, and we almost forgot about this little incident. Unexpectedly, my son actually got into a fight. This was the first real fight between him and his classmates since he went to school, and he was the one who started the fight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cause of the incident is very simple: a group of boys were playing in the dormitory, and the usually naughty boy was teased by a certain child and became irritated. The son was also present, and the boy threw an unknown anger at him, swearing and pushing him. The son angrily demanded an apology, but the other classmate refused, so the son punched the classmate in the face, and the two struggled, and then the teacher arrived and took the two away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We told him that if someone scolds you, just scold him back. How can you hit someone? My son’s answer was that he used to scold him, but that classmate was even better at scolding him. He scolded him again and again, and he was caught twice by the teacher. Not only was he scolded, but he was also made to stand in the classroom. It was so frustrating. &quot;What are you scolding each other?&quot; &quot;He called me stupid, and I called him stupid.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remembering it, the teacher did mention this matter, but he just downplayed it, and we didn&#39;t take it too seriously. pay attention to. When we reminded our son at that time, my wife and I secretly complained: The day has come when the child curses. It seems like this has been going on for two or three months. After a long period of patience and protest, the son finally broke out and rushed towards the strong classmate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After talking to our children, my wife and I were filled with shame and fear. We communicate a lot with our children. In order to give our children room to grow, we don’t pay attention to certain small snippets we hear, and ignore the children’s repeated calls for help. His character was originally gentle, but he endured restraint for a long time, leaving a &quot;weak&quot; impression on his classmates (who took it out on him when they were angered), and he was on the verge of being &quot;bullied&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, the son launched a timely counterattack and prevented the situation from getting worse. This incident also surprised the classmates around him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For his first fight, my wife and I did not blame him, but fell into self-reflection. Reflect on the negligence of parents and the key points of educating children. But one thing is very lucky: we always encourage him to have the courage to have conflicts with classmates, not to be submissive, timid, and have to compromise, but to dare to express anger. It can be seen that this kind of teaching has worked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We teach him this way largely because his character is too gentle and needs some &quot;blessing&quot;. A little boy can have no temper, but he must have strength. In order to protect our own rights and dignity, we do not object to children fighting among themselves. It is wrong to actively bully others. Hitting back when bullied is a form of defense and can also establish an effective deterrent. The child asked that time, what should I do if I can’t beat him? Wife&#39;s quick answer: If you can&#39;t beat him, you have to beat him, at least to make him think that you are not easy to mess with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through this incident, we revised a combat &quot;guideline&quot; for children: in the future, if a classmate uses swear words, laughs at you, or insults you, do not use swear words against him. Ask the other person to stop and apologize. If the other person repeatedly refuses to apologize, you can teach him a lesson. It doesn&#39;t matter if you can&#39;t win. If the teacher criticizes you, your parents will bear with you. Don&#39;t get into dirty talk with classmates, it&#39;s too ugly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There must be many people who disagree with this educational concept. Chinese people have always been gentle, courteous, thrifty and accommodating in their interactions. The rules and legal regulations for adults also say that &quot;a gentleman talks but does not use his hands&quot; and &quot;the one who strikes first is at fault.&quot; I don’t need to teach you these principles. Children will gradually understand them as they grow up. We value the education of courage, a quality that is more important than daily academic performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Courage is valuable because it allows children to build daily self-confidence and have the courage to explore and discover; it allows children to get rid of troubles, get rid of worries, and develop a sunny and cheerful personality. When children are in adversity, they can still think and make decisions instead of running away from difficulties, which is conducive to developing the quality of distinguishing right from wrong. It is no accident that a person with courage is often smart and upright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Courage education is certainly not about encouraging children to abuse violence or actively bully others with violence. Allowing children to fight should be limited to conflict resolution, not bullying of classmates. You need to express your anger and give a warning before taking action, rather than fighting randomly. A few simple rules can be understood by children. This kind of reasoning and exchange is far more conducive to improving children&#39;s understanding of the world than a crude prohibition of &quot;fighting is wrong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teaching children to develop courage is actually not easy. It is inevitable for adults to be submissive, but children are weak and often isolated. At this time, they need help from adults (especially parents). After understanding the reason for our son&#39;s fight, we stated the facts to the teacher and expressed our support for the child. The two parents met, apologized and understood, and the matter was resolved satisfactorily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Children fighting&quot; actually does not require much input from parents. The biggest pressure that children face every day comes from school. Teachers misunderstand punishments, cage management during breaks, and unnecessary extracurricular tasks... These need to be examined by parents and help their children withstand the pressure. My wife and I will help our child complete the assigned tasks and reassure him: It&#39;s not your fault that you didn&#39;t do it well, and it doesn&#39;t matter if the teacher asks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Family is the most important place for children to grow, and parents are their best teachers. Courage, integrity, cheerfulness, optimism... these qualities are difficult to learn in school, and may even be erased. Parents need to take responsibility at this time and pass on values ​​to their children. This is not only character education for children, but also a process of constant reflection and re-growth for parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访世界银行原副行长祝宪：中国发展历程是不同于西方的现代化“药方”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260569]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 13:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As the largest source of funds for developing countries, the World Bank’s economic forecast reports and economic warnings have always attracted much attention . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1980, the third year of reform and opening up, China restored its representation and membership status in the World Bank, and received its first loan from the World Bank the following year. In the following thirty years, China became a protagonist on the world economic stage due to its reform and opening up. It transformed from a borrower of the World Bank to a major shareholder and played an important role in global economic cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China is also the third largest shareholder of the Asian Development Bank (&quot;ADB&quot;) and one of the initiators of the BRICS New Development Bank (&quot;New Development Bank&quot;). By participating in multiple international financial institutions, including the World Bank, China has integrated into the international economic order. After regaining its seat in the World Bank, what else did China get besides loans? As the status of the World Bank continues to improve, what has China contributed to the World Bank? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Xian, who is currently the Executive Vice Chairman and Secretary-General of the International Financial Forum (IFF), has served in the Ministry of Finance for a long time, and has successively served as China’s Executive Director of the World Bank, Vice President and Chief Ethics Officer of the World Bank He is the official, vice president and chief operating officer of the BRICS New Development Bank. He is a witness to my country’s long-term cooperation with international financial institutions such as the World Bank. He is also an experienced promoter of my country’s introduction of international funds to accelerate domestic innovation after reform and opening up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the &quot;IFF 20th Anniversary Global Annual Conference&quot; held recently, Zhu Xian accepted an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend and said that the World Bank plays an important role in China&#39;s reform and opening up process, not only providing loans, but also playing an important role in policy Suggestions, institutional innovation and talent cultivation play an important role, and their role cannot be ignored. At the same time, the World Bank began to promote China&#39;s successful experience in reform and opening up, because China&#39;s development process is different from the Western &quot;prescription&quot; for modernization. This is a very important reference for other developing countries. China also actively participates in global governance through international organizations and tells China&#39;s story to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Xian also emphasized that China’s reform and opening up must continue to move forward, relying on innovation and becoming an indispensable part of the world economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/CVbbOeohfYI9YrRiI9o7LXuesKxQ9Q4HWb43a4EE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;766&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/CVbbOeohfYI9YrRiI9o7LXuesKxQ9Q4HWb43a4EE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258178&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhu Xian: Former Vice President and Chief Ethics Officer of the World Bank, former Vice President and Chief Operating Officer of the New Development Bank; currently Executive Vice Chairman and Secretary-General of the International Financial Forum. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;First opening&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;International&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;Pioneering bidding system&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1980, China resumed A legal seat at the World Bank (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;World Bank&quot;). Information shows that at the beginning of reform and opening up, the cooperative relationship between China and the World Bank was mainly about receiving aid. You were working in the Ministry of Finance at the time and served successively as deputy director of the World Bank Department, deputy director of the National Debt Department and director of the International Department, etc., so you became closely associated with the World Bank. What was the first project China received assistance from the World Bank? What is the historical background? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;China is a founding member of the World Bank. In April 1980, Robert Strange McNamara, then President of the World Bank, was invited to visit China and was received by Deng Xiaoping. Deng Xiaoping said a very famous and courageous saying at that time, &quot;We have fallen behind these years, and we have to catch up. I hope the World Bank can help us, but even without this help, we are determined to catch up.&quot; This was Comrade Xiaoping&#39;s words. The original words are also a tone-setting speech. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Soon, China resumed its legal seat in the World Bank. In July of the same year, the World Bank sent its first high-level delegation to China for inspection and subsequently submitted a detailed inspection report to the World Bank Board of Directors. This is the first step for the World Bank to launch a loan project in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Lubuge&quot; Hydropower Station was China&#39;s first project using World Bank loans and implementing international bidding in the early 1980s. As a key national construction project of the year, the &quot;Lubuge&quot; Hydropower Station is known as the &quot;window&quot; for China&#39;s hydropower capital construction projects to open to the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to obtaining a loan, what changes has this project brought? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the era of planned economy, China’s infrastructure construction projects were mainly established through mandatory plans. After receiving financial allocations or budget allocations, Construction of designated state-owned enterprises. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, according to the loan agreement signed with the World Bank, some projects in Lubuge must implement international bidding. This was a completely new thing at the time, and of course there was resistance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I happened to work in the Ministry of Finance in 1984. At that time, with the help of the World Bank, a total of engineering contractors from 8 countries, including state-owned enterprises, participated in the bidding. In the end, Japan&#39;s Dachen Company won the bid, and the winning price was 43% lower than the lowest bid price. After entering the company, it only sent a management team of more than 30 people and used the &quot;on-site recruitment&quot; model to form a construction team of more than 400 people. It managed the company according to a contract system and paid workers according to their work efficiency. This changed the “big pot” model of state-owned enterprises at that time. Workers are no longer paid the same amount, but are distributed according to their work. In the end, not only the construction cost was greatly reduced, but the construction efficiency was also greatly improved, and the project progress was significantly accelerated. The project was completed in 1986, five months ahead of schedule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the introduction of foreign advanced equipment, technology and management experience, the &quot;Lubuge&quot; hydropower station project has become a benchmark for my country&#39;s infrastructure construction to open to the outside world. In 1987, the State Council held a special meeting to require the comprehensive promotion of the &quot;Lu Buge Experience&quot; in the construction industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This incident later became known as the &quot;Lu Buge Shock&quot;. It is the first of its kind in China to launch global bidding, with price, efficiency and quality as its core assessments. It’s not just the World Bank loan we received, but more importantly these institutional changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Help China&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Promote market reform&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In addition to being the first to launch a bidding system, what profound impact has the &quot;Lu Buge Experience&quot; had on China&#39;s reform and opening up? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From the perspective of project management and financing conditions, the &quot;Lubuge Experience&quot; has influenced China&#39;s infrastructure construction for more than 30 years since then. . The bidding system has since been gradually promoted in the country, and today almost all major infrastructure projects in the public budget must go through bidding. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of the World Bank, the impact on China from the 1980s to the 1990s was not only the provision of loans, but also a lot of pioneering work in institutional innovation and talent training. It played an important role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From my experience, this role is no less important than providing loan funds, especially during the transition from a planned economy to a market economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In what aspects is this importance mainly reflected? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time we didn’t quite know how to transform the socialist market economy. The World Bank conducted a comprehensive investigation of the Chinese economy and then wrote targeted recommendations and reports, some of which were praised by the top leadership at the time. The World Bank also recommended that governments at all levels, especially central ministries and commissions such as the Ministry of Finance, the People&#39;s Bank of China and the National Development and Reform Commission, carry out institutional innovation, which has had a relatively large impact. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, in the process of dealing with international organizations such as the World Bank, our country has also trained a group of market reform talents. For example, Zhou Xiaochuan, Lou Jiwei, etc. all gained their knowledge during exchanges with the World Bank and played an important role in market reform. I was still relatively young at the time, but I also got exercise during my exchanges with the World Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, not all World Bank recommendations are in line with China&#39;s national conditions, but many of the policy recommendations put forward at that time were based on economic surveys conducted in China, as well as exchanges with domestic officials and scholars, and after comparison with international experience. Feedback to China. So overall a lot of good advice was accepted and became reality. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;From&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;borrower&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;to&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;significant shareholder&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;From an official of the Chinese Ministry of Finance working in conjunction with the World Bank, to serving as China&#39;s executive director in the World Bank, and even to the world Vice President of the Bank. With the reform and opening up, while your personal role is changing, China&#39;s status in the World Bank is also improving. During your tenure at the World Bank, if you looked at China from a different perspective, what would be the differences? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After the restoration of the legal seat of the World Bank, as a major country, China has obtained a seat on the executive director, joining the United Nations permanent members such as the United States and the United Kingdom. Like the Governing Council members, they have separate offices at the World Bank. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a sense, the Executive Director of the World Bank is an official sent by China, not an official of the World Bank itself. Before and after I took office, many people held this position, such as Li Yong and Zhang Shengman before me, and Zhu Guangyao and Zou Jiayi after me. I feel very honored to be able to perform my duties at the World Bank on behalf of my motherland, and it is also a heavy responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the improvement of comprehensive national strength, China’s influence in the World Bank has gradually expanded. The World Bank began to promote China&#39;s successful experience in reform and opening up, firstly, to get rid of absolute poverty, and secondly, to promote the transformation of the planned economy into a socialist market economy through infrastructure construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a very important reference for other developing countries. At the same time, China is also actively participating in global governance and telling China’s story to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What milestone events remain fresh in your memory? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;During my tenure at the World Bank, there were two milestone events that impressed me deeply: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;First, China’s loan scale from the World Bank reached US$3 billion per year for the first time. That was $3 billion more than thirty years ago. The World Bank&#39;s low-cost funds have become one of the most important channels for my country to introduce foreign investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using these funds, our country built a number of major infrastructure projects at that time. For example, the Beijing-Tianjin-Tangshan Expressway connecting Beijing and Tianjin was my country’s first inter-provincial and municipal expressway built with World Bank loans. This is the first project in China to introduce the construction of a supervisory system. The World Bank insists on giving priority to quality, strictly controls the progress and quality of the project, and will not sign for payment if it does not meet the standards, thus avoiding potential quality hazards caused by the rush period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, China has experienced a change in its role from a borrower to an important shareholder. In 1999, when I first joined the World Bank, China still ranked sixth in terms of voting rights. Now China has become the third largest shareholder of the World Bank. Although we still borrow money from the World Bank, as an important shareholder of the World Bank, our participation in the international financial market has gradually increased, and our influence on world economic development has gradually increased. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend: From a borrower to an important shareholder, how does China currently influence the world economy through the World Bank? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Xian: Compared with developed countries as shareholders, China’s role in the World Bank is different. For other developing countries, China&#39;s successful experience in reform and opening up has strong reference significance. Because China itself is a developing country, China&#39;s development process is different from the Western &quot;prescription&quot; for modernization, providing more practical experience in poverty alleviation and infrastructure construction. Therefore, China plays an increasingly important role in maintaining the international economic order and improving the global governance structure, and its influence in international organizations such as the World Bank is growing. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Compared with the World Bank, the New Development Bank has made breakthroughs and innovations&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have successively held leadership positions in the World Bank, the Asian Development Bank (referred to as &quot;ADB&quot;) and the BRICS New Development Bank (referred to as &quot;New Development Bank&quot;). How does China exert its influence and role through different international financial organizations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are two reasons why I moved from the World Bank to the Asian Development Bank: First, we had fewer senior staff in international organizations at that time; And ADB happens to have a spot. Because I have experience working in the World Bank, the Ministry of Finance recommended me for an interview. Second, my professional ability in participating in promoting the World Bank&#39;s poverty alleviation project in western China has been recognized by all aspects of the World Bank. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind this is the general background that China has been highly recognized by international organizations such as the World Bank because of its reform and opening up. Without China&#39;s reform and opening up, there would be no experience for me and Chinese people like me in international organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From my personal experience, working in the Ministry of Finance in the first half and working in multilateral international organizations in the second half are completely different experiences. I have witnessed China transform from a poor and backward country to the second largest in the world. the entire process of the economy. The experience of working in an international organization, especially promoting China&#39;s experience to other developing countries and promoting the development of poverty alleviation, is a very glorious career for me. In this process, the biggest challenge is how to balance maintaining Chinese characteristics and integrating with international standards. I hope this will attract the attention of young people currently working in international organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The BRICS New Development Bank was officially established in Shanghai in 2015. China is one of the five largest shareholder countries and one of the initiators. Compared with the World Bank and AIIB, what innovations does it have? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;According to the agreement between the five major shareholder countries at the beginning of the establishment of the New Development Bank, the first president will be an Indian, and the other four shareholders will Each country appoints a vice president. As the vice president in charge of business at that time, the first problem I faced was to clarify what kind of services the new bank would provide. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with multilateral international financial institutions such as the World Bank and the Asian Development Bank, the New Development Bank was entirely initiated and established by emerging market countries. However, the main business nature of the New Development Bank is different from that of multilateral financial institutions such as the World Bank. The institutions are relatively similar, and the clients are mainly developing countries. Therefore, we decided to learn from the good experiences and practices of the World Bank and ADB in related business fields, while avoiding the bureaucracy and efficiency problems common in international institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to be different from the World Bank&#39;s practice of attaching policy conditions when approving loan applications from developing countries, we proposed not to set loan conditions at the beginning of the establishment of the New Development Bank and respect the policies of different applicant countries. At the same time, in terms of &quot;environmental and social security policies&quot; and other aspects, the New Development Bank innovatively adopts a &quot;domestic system&quot; and implements it in accordance with the borrowing country&#39;s own lending policy. It is no longer like traditional multilateral financial institutions that impose a &quot;one size fits all&quot; policy on all borrowing countries. &quot;Acceptance effectively reduces the time and cost of borrowing countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another innovation is the adoption of &quot;local currency loans.&quot; Since the New Development Bank&#39;s funds mainly come from the local currencies of the five major shareholder countries rather than US dollars, the New Development Bank&#39;s loans are basically invested in the infrastructure of the host country. If these infrastructures generate income, its income will basically come from the host country and be in the form of It is reflected in the form of the country&#39;s local currency. Therefore, if the country borrows RMB and repays it in US dollars, it will create exchange rate risk. If you borrow local currency and repay local currency, there will be no exchange rate risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although compared with &quot;old banks&quot; such as the World Bank and Asia, the New Development Bank still needs to continue to work hard in many aspects, during my five-year term, the loan scale of the New Development Bank has increased from 0 to 0. $30 billion, pretty good. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;High-end service industry should have characteristics&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(IFF) was initiated and established by leaders of more than 20 countries and regions including China, the United States, Britain, and Japan, as well as relevant international organizations and global financial institutions such as the United Nations, the European Union, the World Bank, and the International Monetary Fund. It is known as &quot;F20&quot;, its permanent venue is located in Nansha, Guangzhou. What role will IFF play in the integrated development and high-level opening up of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;IFF settling in Guangzhou is a mutual achievement. The Greater Bay Area has a developed economy and a high degree of marketization and internationalization, while IFF is globally representative and inclusive. This is also the significance of IFF settling in the Greater Bay Area and Guangzhou, to build a platform for non-governmental exchanges between scholars and enterprises. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Nansha, Guangzhou, Hengqin, Zhuhai and Qianhai, Shenzhen Finance is at the forefront of China&#39;s reform and opening up. What are your expectations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;From a development perspective, Guangzhou should focus not only on investment in the real economy, but also on investment in the service industry, especially in areas such as finance. High-end service industry. In the past, manufacturing industry could attract foreign investment by demarcating a certain area with tax exemptions and other preferential treatment, but it is different now. The service industry needs to be opened up and needs institutional construction. The service industry differs from manufacturing in that services are more mobile. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a certain extent, institutional openness means integrating with international standards. Now when local governments at all levels consider attracting foreign investment, they should not only focus on the manufacturing industry, but also the service industry, and need to explore new institutional opening-up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We also hope that the forum can make a contribution, at least to promote dialogue between the two parties. For example, the Nansha District government hopes to attract investment through us, but we suggest that manufacturing investment is no longer urgent for Nansha District, and what Guangdong needs now is not just manufacturing. While the manufacturing industry should be upgraded, investment in the service industry should have its own characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What special finance do you think should be developed in the Greater Bay Area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The Greater Bay Area has huge demand for financial services. Greater Bay Area finance not only includes traditional bank loans and capital operations, but also digital finance and green financial services. In the process of continuous economic integration in the Greater Bay Area, we will provide enterprises with a full range of financial services, innovate in connectivity, and help the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area become a world-class bay area. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area must become a world-class bay District, what do you suggest? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Xian:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is still a long way to go for the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area to become a world-class bay area. First of all, compared with the Yangtze River Delta, the Greater Bay Area has institutional advantages, namely the three legal systems of &quot;one country, two systems&quot;. Secondly, dare to innovate. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not just the Greater Bay Area. As China continues to move forward, it must rely on reform and opening up, rely on innovation, and become an indispensable part of the world economy. To correctly understand &quot;double circulation&quot;, &quot;inner circulation&quot; and &quot;external circulation&quot; are an organic whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, geographical factors cannot be ignored. The achievements China has made today are the direct result of reform and opening up. In other words, under the new situation, both cooperation and competition are needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国足球的“12岁退役”现象]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260557]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/14/7cca7c7bf41d87e4925b98a3d0ee722d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/14/7cca7c7bf41d87e4925b98a3d0ee722d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258167&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The phenomenon of &quot;retiring at the age of 12&quot; is something that Chinese football, which is full of opportunities, has to face painfully and deeply. A question of powerlessness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the U13 competition of the Key Cities Group of the Chinese Football Association Youth Football Championship (referred to as the &quot;Key City Group Competition&quot;) held in Qingdao at the end of October, tournament officials, coaches, and parents discussed this topic hotly and eagerly sought answers. A competition supervisor from Beijing told reporters that he deplored the changes in a youth team he had followed in the &quot;Hundred Teams Cup&quot; competition in Beijing in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Those 10- and 11-year-old kids can play football better than we did when we were kids, but by the age of 12, half of the kids disappeared; by the time they were 13, they couldn’t play football anymore. He left. I went to ask the coach: &#39;Where are the people?&#39; He said that he spent four years training those children, and they just got a little bit in shape. When they entered junior high school, the team was disbanded.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; &#39;Retiring at the age of 12&#39; is a phenomenon unique to us. If this problem is not solved, youth training will be cut in half and it will be difficult to achieve results,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Since the widespread introduction of campus football, the number of players playing football has increased sharply in primary schools, but by the junior high school stage, that is, after the age of 12, there has been a sharp decline. &lt;/span>;This phenomenon appeared as early as 2018, when the organizers of the Beijing “100 Team Cup” announced a set of numbers about participating teams: there were 229 participating teams in the U8 and U9 primary school age groups, while U13 and U15 There are only 70 participating teams in the middle school age group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Last year, reporters went to Xi&#39;an for research. The person in charge of the youth training of a local district and county football association said that among the echelons affiliated to their football association, there were more than 50 children in the U8 echelon; more than 20 in the U10 team; and only 10 in the U12 team. The left and right children cannot form a team alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A local youth training coach said that parents’ choice determines whether their children play football and also determines the quality of the youth training. He said: &quot;In the past, when we played football, our parents supported us, and the time spent playing football every day was longer than the time spent studying. Now it is just the opposite, and parents focus on studying. &lt;span>; There is no shortage of children with football talents in China. What is the support of parents? All are important. The future of Chinese football is in the hands of parents.&lt;/span>;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Parents&#39; concerns&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Shenzhen U13 women&#39;s football captain Lian Yutong every day Every time you go out to compete, one of your parents must accompany you. This time it was her father who accompanied her to Qingdao to participate in the key city group competition. He carried a projector from Shenzhen, not to play game videos, but to give his children online classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When the child comes out to compete, as long as conditions permit, her mother and I will definitely have someone accompany her, mainly to provide her with extra lessons.&quot; Lian Lian said, &quot;The child is only 13 years old and does not have that much self-discipline. She is strong, someone must supervise her to study during the competition. The pressure to study in junior high school is too great.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/14/0877d562f74bc96a41ede72c6915244c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;650&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/14/0877d562f74bc96a41ede72c6915244c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258168&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;April 15, 2023, Lian Yu Tong practices shooting at Shenzhen Baoan Stadium. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Mao Siqian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Lian said that Lian Yutong started playing football in the first grade of elementary school and spent a lot of time training and competing every week. For example, when I was in the sixth grade of elementary school, I was guaranteed at least four trainings and one game a week. &quot;It&#39;s absolutely fine to balance studying and playing football in elementary school.&quot; But in junior high school, the academic pressure suddenly increased. Lian Yutong was still able to train three times a week in the first grade of junior high school. After entering the second grade of junior high school this year, he really couldn&#39;t find the time. He could only put all the training on two days on the weekend and twice a week, leaving no training for the five days in between. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After children enter the second grade of junior high school, they only sleep 6 hours a day on average. Time is too precious. Sometimes they have to rush to train and have to eat in the car.&quot; Lian Lian said, &quot;In junior high school, if you want to If you play football, you will delay your studies; if you want to study, you will not be able to play well. You cannot have both.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Lian said that Lian Yutong&#39;s school has a high school entrance examination admission rate of only over 40%, which means that This means that she must be in the upper reaches of her class rankings to have any hope of being admitted to high school. This year Lian Yutong spent two months away training and competing, and his academic performance showed a downward trend. This made Lian Lian worried. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now their father and daughter have two choices: focus on studying or focus on playing football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Lian said that focusing on study is a stable choice. Children can enter college and find a stable job in the future. But Lian Yutong likes to play football, and her parents respect her hobby. &quot;She really loves football, otherwise we wouldn&#39;t have to worry so much.&quot; But focusing on football is gambling with the child&#39;s future. There are too many uncertain factors in football and the success rate is too low, so learning cannot be lost. So, they can only do both. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/e51f43f59c69232015bc7fd34005c8c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/e51f43f59c69232015bc7fd34005c8c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258170&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 11, Lian Yutong (second from right) watched the game video with his parents and sister at home in Shenzhen. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Mao Siqian&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But reality keeps reminding Lianlian: You can’t have your cake and eat it too. He was in a dilemma. “We can only walk and watch one day at a time,” he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Lian said that parents of children who play football often get together to discuss how to choose. Everyone is very anxious, and many choose to let their children give up football and study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The club Lian Yutong joined in elementary school had several teams for each age group, with the most teams from A to E5. The children went to play football after school in the afternoon. But in junior high school, there were no People play football, and it takes two age groups of children to form a team on weekends, and most children don’t play football anymore,” said Lian Lian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lian Yutong is still persisting, but the future is full of uncertainty. Lian Lian said that he now needs a kind of certainty to relieve his inner confusion, entanglement and anxiety about his child&#39;s future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/b1ae2351a64afa5ec621c3122e4b072b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/b1ae2351a64afa5ec621c3122e4b072b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258171&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 11, Lian Yutong (upper left) interacted with his teammates during a school team training match at the Shixia Junior High School of Hongling Middle School in Shenzhen Cheer up. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Mao Siqian&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Suzhou Answer&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the key city group competitions, the Suzhou U13 women&#39;s football team is a standout, and it is guaranteed to win every game. , until finally winning the championship. Head coach Zhou Ying said that she has been taking her players to training and competitions since they were in the third or fourth grade of elementary school. As a team, they do not suffer from the &quot;12-year-old retirement&quot; phenomenon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This team receives training at Suzhou Sports School. The reporter asked Wang Jianjun, vice chairman of the Suzhou Football Association and vice president of Suzhou Sports School, about this. His written answer is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The phenomenon of &#39;retiring at the age of 12&#39; has not happened in Suzhou. The main reason is that when we select outstanding talents, we talk to the parents about their children&#39;s future. We will build A good platform allows parents to choose: 1. Help every child go to college, and focus on training, competition, and study. If you can&#39;t go to a professional club, you can find a respected job after graduation through college study. 2. Help particularly outstanding children enter the national team. 3. Can’t enter the national team but can be selected for the provincial team, represent the provincial team in the National Games and get the top three (Jiangsu Province has a policy that the top three in the National Games (can be placed in a job), and also solves the worries. 4. The requirement for coaches is not only to complete training and competition tasks, but more importantly, to cultivate each child to become a plastic talent with comprehensive development of morality, intelligence and physical fitness, so that every family Don’t worry. 5. At the high school stage, if children and parents want to go abroad to play football and study, we will also help them solve it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;So I think as long as the problem of children’s future can be solved, there will be no problem. The &#39;retirement at 12&#39; phenomenon,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/97c4f2bf4f241214f1cd239406ac595f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;657&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/14/97c4f2bf4f241214f1cd239406ac595f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258172&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 15, 2022, the female football team members of Shengping Experimental Primary School in Suzhou City, Jiangsu Province were training. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Microphoto by Hang Xing)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The phenomenon of &quot;retiring at the age of 12&quot; is an unavoidable problem in Chinese football. The Chinese Football Association has begun to take measures to improve the youth training environment in the past two years, and recently established the policy of &quot;making youth training a top priority.&quot; &lt;/span>;The Qingdao venue of this key city group U13 competition specially organized a training class for women’s football coaches. Responsible departments in key football cities have held several similar coaching trainings, with the aim of comprehensively improving the capabilities of grassroots coaches. In addition, they also hope that key cities will open &quot;through trains&quot; for further studies to create conditions for football talents to further their studies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U10 to U15 age group competitions in key city group events provide a key platform for the growth of players of the right age. Without this platform, Lian Yutong may not have the opportunity to participate in high-level national competitions. &quot;She has played a total of 12 11-a-side national matches so far, all of which are in key city groups this year.&quot; Lian Lian said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qingdao U13 women&#39;s football coach Yu Minglei said after the team&#39;s victory over the Wuhan team: &quot;Children&#39;s growth requires such high-level competitions. Such competitions must be held more often.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Even if the youth training environment improves, it is not enough to break the phenomenon of &quot;retiring at the age of 12&quot;. A local football worker said helplessly: &quot;Actually, the Football Association doesn&#39;t have much to do here. You can&#39;t stop other people&#39;s children from going to school.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A coach said that parents need their children to have a secure future in football. , &quot;We can&#39;t provide them with guarantees, and we can only watch some very good young talents leaving football.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Retiring at the age of 12&quot; has led to the loss of a large number of football talents. This phenomenon is not limited to 12 years old, but it is more prominent in this age group. Some children give up football earlier or later. &lt;span>;This is a reflection of the contradiction between learning and training in the field of football youth training, which needs to be solved through a two-pronged approach. Unless this phenomenon is broken, it will be difficult for Chinese football to thrive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[城市漫步丨洛城机密]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260542]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 12:05:41&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/13/gynCLkJT3JTZFvdKWSGUoMmmLVN4e1L8HuQkDoPc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/gynCLkJT3JTZFvdKWSGUoMmLBVN4e1L8 HuQkDoPc. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258153&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Downtown Los Angeles. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1974, when the famous German director Werner Herzog heard that the film critic When his mentor Lotte Eisner was critically ill, he did not board the next plane or train, but insisted on walking from Munich to Paris. It was a winter with blizzards, and this journey would take at least several weeks. However, Herzog firmly believed: &quot;As long as I walk through it with both feet, she will survive.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes. Think of Herzog&#39;s actions as a private bet with fate: If I complete this audacious challenge, you must honor my wish. The English translation of &quot;Of Walking in Ice&quot;, which records this journey, calls Herzog&#39;s walking trip a &quot;pilgrimage&quot; in the introduction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also enjoy long walks. However, many American cities are built for cars and not for walking. There is a similar situation in many cities. The distance from point A to point B seems to be very close in a straight line, but there are no so-called shortcuts. Some are just detours. A ten-minute drive will take an hour to walk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still choose to walk, of course not as a means of commuting every day, but as a way to &quot;empty time&quot; on weekends. In the United States, except maybe a few cities on the East Coast, most cities don&#39;t offer a good &quot;city stroll&quot; experience. But sometimes I feel that the so-called good &quot;city stroll&quot; experience is the discipline of modern business society for consumers. We look forward to marking important landmarks on the map: streets provide &quot;views&quot;, buildings provide &quot;history&quot;, museums provide &quot;condensed knowledge&quot;, restaurants provide delicious food, and coffee shops provide rest. Then we will visit each point one by one and think to ourselves Know this place inside and out. As everyone knows, we are just doing what ordinary tourists do in these places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Real walking is exposing the body to desolation. During my first year in the United States, I was in Iowa, a university town surrounded by large cornfields. Out of curiosity, I walked the way back when I could take the school bus, but what I passed was actually wild grass growing all over the sky. Occasionally, I passed by There are several large box-shaped gymnasiums and school buildings. There is no one on the road, only me and a few birds with colorful wings. The birds seemed to find me strange. They stopped on the branches and stared at me for a long time before flying away. There is no simple dichotomy between good and evil in nature. Several times I have witnessed the corpses of birds after being attacked by wild cats. Sometimes I accidentally entered the &quot;crime scene&quot; and I saw wild cats half-hidden in the grass, using their vicious claws. It looked at me, afraid that I would steal its prey. Another time, I met a small snake &quot;crossing the road&quot; by the river. The hairs all over my body stood up. Should I continue walking forward or go back? I hesitated, and then I realized that the little snake might also be afraid of me. It curled up and was thinking about whether to move forward or backward. This mutual fear actually dispelled my fear. Soon, it ran into the grass on the opposite side, and I continued walking forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In cities, especially in American cities, streets also have a wild and natural feel. Driving people can reduce their &quot;waste&quot; time to a minimum, and they can also use metal and car window glass to build freedom and safety. Walking does not offer this option. In Los Angeles, although there are very convenient buses and light rail services for me to go home from the city center, it still often takes me more than an hour to walk back. The landscape of the city will change immediately. In front of it are still high-rise buildings and Mexican vendors selling food along the street. Across the street are overpasses covered with graffiti and homeless people in ragged clothes talking to themselves. Because you have to pass them by when walking. However, the nasal cavity was invaded by the smell of urine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have no intention of beautifying this kind of walking behavior. I did it partly because I still haven’t passed the driver’s license test, and partly because of my childhood habits. Not only in Los Angeles, but I also walked this way in St. Louis, Detroit, Chicago, and even walked through a few neighborhoods that required a little caution. Such behavior is considered risky by many people. Occasionally, there are reports of delirious homeless people attacking passers-by in the news. But in reality, it&#39;s more of a discomfort than a danger if you&#39;re like me, who looks like a downright poor person (just look at my phone and shoes to keep me from stealing) and is always walking in broad daylight. on the main road below (in case of crisis, you can seek help on the driveway). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also wish I could tell you that I gained countless stories from walking like this, but that is far from the truth. Stories rely on more purposeful interviews, research, and observation. I love Herzog&#39;s &quot;Snow and Ice&quot; because of his honesty. He wrote about the desolation and perhaps meaningless encounters during the walk: &quot;The dark and lonely forest surrounded me, and there was deathly silence around me. Only the wind was howling. .The sky in the west turned yellow, the air was stuffy, as if hail was about to fall, and the sky above was hazy gray-black. Suddenly, a huge red quarry appeared in front of us: red water accumulated in the huge pit. An excavator is parked in the water, rusty and useless.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it can&#39;t be said that I learned nothing. The beggars I met in different places greeted you in different ways. Beggars in Detroit would show off your clothes, while beggars in Chicago would first offer you a favor (someone helped me carry my suitcase directly off the subway). station), panhandlers in Los Angeles will complain to you. With limited experience, my observations of these areas may not be accurate. However, my friends in Detroit also told me that the locals attach great importance to fashion, and even beggars will often praise their clothes. I suddenly felt that I was walking in the real scene of this city. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After all, everyone has their own reasons for walking. The nineteenth-century American writer Thoreau hiked in New England in order to breathe the air of the planet at the height of the stars and gain knowledge of the earth with his feet. However, after Herzog&#39;s three-week stroll, when he arrived in Paris, Lot Eisner miraculously improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I remembered a past event from my childhood. I was probably only five or six years old at the time, and my father especially liked to lie down on the bed and ask me to step on his back with my bare feet, saying it was the most comfortable massage in the world. I was very happy after hearing this and &quot;walked&quot; on his back very seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, my father and I have never been so close. Like my mother, I despise him for being &quot;unmotivated&quot; and &quot;irresponsible&quot;, and even stinks of sweat in summer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps, somewhere in the world, only walking around on the streets makes me feel so intimate with the city beneath my feet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成都崇州被狗咬伤女童已出院，身体各系统恢复顺利]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260555]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 11:12:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 14, reporters learned from West China Hospital of Sichuan University that a dog bitten someone in Chongzhou, Chengdu The girl received active treatment from the hospital and was discharged on November 13. &lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;Currently, the liver and kidney functions are normal, various body systems are recovering smoothly, and the wound is healing well. &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; Follow-up needs to be reviewed regularly according to doctor’s orders. During the hospitalization, the manual payment window of West China Hospital of Sichuan University received a total of 220,000 yuan in advance payment, and used more than 80,000 yuan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大V控诉综艺节目装修“翻车”：普通人装修要踩多少坑？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260540]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The master stood in front of the door, and several dazzling haloes of light shone on the metal round door, and then, The door slides open to one side, and the owner steps in. The lights above his head light up in sequence with the owner&#39;s steps. In the middle of the room, there is a square box. The electric door of the square box opens automatically, revealing a private space equipped with a large-screen TV and a bed. The owner can rest here, watch movies and play games without being disturbed. The lights in the room can change color according to the mood of the owner. Sometimes it is bright white, and sometimes it turns to warm orange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone who has ever dreamed of science fiction would want to own such a cool cyberpunk-style house. Well-known digital blogger Li Jieling is also one of them. Therefore, when he saw the designer&#39;s plan, he immediately decided to participate in the decoration variety show &quot;Miracle Renewal Home&quot; and spend more than one million to renovate his house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the design is beautiful, but it is not that easy to implement. Recently, Li Jieling posted on Weibo, complaining that the decoration was &quot;overturned&quot; and cost a huge amount of money, but it was far from achieving the results he expected. According to the articles, photos, videos and other information published by Li Jieling, as well as the contract he signed with the decorator, the electric door is 150,000 yuan, the lighting system is 185,000 yuan, and the black square device is 290,000 yuan, plus design fees, transportation and installation fees Waiting for miscellaneous charges, the total charge for these three major items is 730,000 yuan, plus the decoration in other places, the total cost exceeds one million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after spending such a large amount of money, we did not get very good results: the electric door only has a simple sliding function, and the promised cool effect was not realized at all; the electric door of the square box opened the door, stretched out the chair, etc. There are also many problems with the structure. Firstly, the gaps are too large to form a complete whole, and the appearance is not beautiful enough. Secondly, the operation is very slow and the sound is loud; only the lighting system can pass the test. Due to the huge gap with psychological expectations, Li Jieling finally refused to take over the house and continue to record the program, and asked the decorator and program owner to make rectifications. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, there have been many programs on new house decoration and old house renovation, which have attracted many viewers. Many people like to watch house building and decoration programs, hoping to provide some inspiration for their own decoration, or simply to see how other people&#39;s homes look like when decorated. But this is not the first time Li Jieling has &quot;overturned&quot; and caused complaints. The last time that the internet went viral was the &quot;Million Dollar Red Brick House&quot; on the show &quot;Dream Renovator&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old man Du from rural Gansu Province hoped that the program team would help him transform his old house into a modern, western-style and exquisite small foreign-style building. As a result, a designer from Beijing designed the house into a &quot;red brick rough house&quot;. There are exposed red bricks and cement everywhere, as well as hollow brick walls. This cost more than 1.32 million. As soon as the program aired, it aroused strong complaints from netizens. However, some people defended the designer, believing that the designer&#39;s work is actually compatible with the environmental style of the northwest countryside, has considerable artistic quality, and has no problem with practicality. Du Laobo and netizens find it difficult to accept it. In fact, it is influenced by traditional concepts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe the designer has his own ideas, and this work is also very &quot;modern&quot;. However, when designing, constructing, and decorating, we receive money and are entrusted by others. Shouldn&#39;t we respect the client&#39;s ideas first? ? At the beginning of the design, the designer should communicate with the client in detail about the requirements. Even if the designer has his own ideas, he should obtain the client&#39;s understanding and consent during communication. He should not completely follow his own ideas and &quot;open the blind box&quot; for the client after the construction is completed. At that time, the work was done, and making changes would be a major undertaking, if not impossible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the situation Li Jieling encountered was different from that of Mr. Du. In Li Jieling&#39;s case, there was no problem with the design. In fact, Li Jieling agreed to participate in the show only after she was satisfied with the designer&#39;s plan. But what I didn&#39;t expect is that the ideal is plump, but the reality is very skinny. When the cool design is implemented in reality, not only the effect is greatly reduced, but even the basic beauty is difficult to achieve. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the decoration program, the effect was not satisfactory, which attracted the attention of netizens and could be corrected. For example, the house of Mr. Du in Gansu received strong criticism after the program was broadcast. The program team responded that the renovation would continue to be improved and the program team would bear half of the renovation costs. Judging from the follow-up program that was broadcast later, the results after the transformation were quite acceptable. As for the situation Li Jieling encountered this time, because Li Jieling himself is a big V and has a strong influence on social media, he has the capital to bargain with the decorator and the program team. The other party currently agrees to complete the renovation before the Spring Festival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What should ordinary people do if they encounter such a situation? In reality, house decoration is really a matter of luck. The decoration market is a mixed bag, and homeowners often have to work hard to achieve satisfactory decoration results. Disputes arising from decoration quality are endless. How do ordinary people avoid pitfalls when decorating? Even if you choose a regular decoration company, the decoration company may outsource the specific work to the decoration team; even if you sign a decoration contract with clear agreements on the decoration effect, construction period, etc., and there are breach of contract clauses, all kinds of wrangling will inevitably happen. Li Jieling&#39;s experience further reflects the many pitfalls faced by ordinary people in decoration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[儿童肺炎支原体高发，囤积阿奇霉素不可取]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260550]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 10:07:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[世界最大地下水漏斗补漏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260534]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/13/cbcc4f6c12.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 13/cbcc4f6c12.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A deactivated shallow water in Zhangzhuang Village, Nanpi County, Cangzhou City, Hebei Province Weeds have grown over the well. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Linsong grinned, with two rows of yellow teeth clearly visible, &quot;Everyone knows which village we are from when we go out. The fluoride content in the groundwater is too high.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;High concentrations of fluoride can damage the ameloblasts of the tooth germ, causing the enamel to turn yellow. Wujiafang Village is located in Wumaying Town, Nanpi County, Cangzhou City, Hebei Province. It entered the coverage of the East Route Project of South-to-North Water Diversion a few years ago. To drink &quot;Yangtze River water&quot;, the villagers no longer need to use yellow teeth as &quot;ID cards&quot;. A big lock is also hung on the deep machine well house in the village, which will only be used during the busy farming season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In many Hebei villages, water from the Yellow River is used for farmland irrigation. The &quot;one reduction and one increase&quot; measure of reducing overexploitation of groundwater and increasing water supply through multiple channels is to control the groundwater funnel - a funnel-shaped concave surface formed by the large-scale exploitation of deep groundwater, the water level drops, and the surrounding groundwater flows toward the center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Groundwater funnels can cause ground subsidence, which can damage railways, buildings, underground pipelines, and even endanger embankment safety. Since the 1960s and 1970s, the &quot;Tianjin-Cangzhou-Hengshui-Dezhou Deep Composite Funnel&quot; has gradually connected into a piece, with the largest area in the world. According to an article published by Zhang Zhaoji and others from the Key Laboratory of Groundwater Science and Engineering of the Ministry of Natural Resources in 2022, the most serious plot in Cangzhou, located in the center of the funnel area, has sunk by a total of 2.5 meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, the Ministry of Water Resources and other four ministries and commissions issued the &quot;Action Plan for the Comprehensive Control of Groundwater Overexploitation in North China&quot; (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot; Action Plan&quot;&lt;/span>;), which proposed that by 2035, we will strive to fully achieve a balance of groundwater extraction and replenishment, and gradually fill the deficit of over-exploitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, the Ministry of Water Resources announced at a press conference that through nearly five years of governance, the trend of year-by-year decline in groundwater levels has been fundamentally reversed, and the short-term goals of the &quot;Action Plan&quot; have been exceeded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in July 2023, Hebei Province’s 2022 annual audit work report (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as the audit report&lt;/span>;) warned : 11 cities and 16 counties have problems such as water abstraction without a license, water abstraction exceeding the license, and slow progress in shutting down water intake wells; 6 cities and 2 counties have problems such as unfinished consumption of river water, and arrears of 3.175 billion yuan in South-to-North Water Diversion fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hebei’s agricultural water accounts for 55%, of which about 70% is used to irrigate winter wheat. Managing winter wheat irrigation well is the key to suppressing groundwater exploitation. Now is the season for winter wheat to be irrigated with overwintering water. Southern Weekend reporters found in interviews that Hebei Province has strictly controlled new wells, shut down old wells, and actively transferred water in recent years. Behind the problems reported in the audit are difficulties in water intake supervision, lagging small water conservancy projects, and water shortages. Problems such as the backward payment system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Strictly control new wells&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wells are the connection between people and groundwater, but in Hebei, it is difficult to drill new wells. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;my country implements a water abstraction licensing system, and drilling wells requires approval. In 2017, Hebei designated prohibited/restricted mining areas. No new water wells are allowed to be dug in the prohibited mining areas, and hierarchical approval is required in the restricted mining areas. In 2018, the &quot;Hebei Province Water Drawing License Management Measures&quot; was revised to transfer the approval authority for groundwater drawing licenses to the provincial level. In 2022, the restricted mining area will increase by more than 36,000 square kilometers, equivalent to 2.5 times the area of ​​Cangzhou City. Hebei also stipulates that when digging new wells in restricted mining areas, &quot;1 minus 2&quot; must be used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the purpose of drilling a well is only for personal use, the policy still leaves a loophole. The &quot;Hebei Province Water Drawing Permit Management Measures&quot; stipulates that units or individuals who draw small amounts of water for household purposes and scattered free-range or captive livestock and poultry for drinking are exempt from applying for a water drawing permit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How to understand this category? When Southern Weekend reporters inquired about drilling wells in a personal capacity, Peng Ping, a staff member of the water resources department of a water conservancy department in Hebei Province, explained that there are two main requirements: first, the wells should only be used for personal use and not for business purposes; second, do not drill. It&#39;s too deep, &quot;even if it&#39;s twenty or thirty meters away,&quot; it cannot touch the deep water layer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deep water generally refers to the water below the aquiclude layer, which is a rock formation with extremely weak water permeability. Shallow groundwater can be replenished through surface water systems, but deep groundwater is generally buried more than 50 meters deep and replenishes slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you want to dig a deep water well, &quot;you need the approval of the county government, and then report it to the city and provincial governments in turn.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters checked the water license approval ledger published regularly by the Hebei Provincial Department of Water Resources and found that 50 or 60 companies were approved within two days, and the vast majority were companies, factories, schools and other legal entities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under heavy pressure, some people still take risks. The audit report reported that there is a problem of unlicensed water abstraction in some areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In late September, Southern Weekend reporters consulted more than a dozen well-drilling teams in the Cangzhou area and surrounding areas about drilling wells. A well-drilling worker in Langfang claimed that he was providing water to some chemical plants in Langfang that did not have water extraction licenses. Drilled a well. Another well-drilling worker in Tianjin also said that when he digs wells for customers, he does not ask them to show their water permission. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Closing old wells&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to strictly controlling new wells, Hebei has also begun to close or reduce water production for old wells. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wangjiakou Village, Chenzui Township, Qingxian County, Cangzhou, Southern Weekend reporters found a locked red brick well house with an area of ​​more than ten square meters. A shiny sign was nailed to the outer wall: Shut down the well. Private activation is strictly prohibited. Through the holes in the iron door, one can see the electricity meter and gate on the brick wall, as well as the wellhead where the pump is installed on the ground. The wires have accumulated a thick layer of dust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/f9b8547100.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/f9b8547100.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In late September 2023, the door of a deep motor-shaft well house in Wangjiakou Village was locked, and the scene inside the room could still be seen through the small hole in the door. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the vast farmland outside the well house, there is a red iron &quot;fire hydrant&quot; every other section of the road - this was once the outlet of underground pipes, which transported deep well water It was transported from the well house to the field and is now abandoned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Hebei Daily&quot; report, as of the end of August 2022, more than 230,000 water wells have been shut down in the province, including urban domestic and industrial water wells and rural domestic water wells in the South-to-North Water Diversion receiving areas. According to the 2023 Hebei Provincial Water Conservancy Work Conference, by the end of 2022, the comprehensive management tasks of 5.97 billion cubic meters of groundwater overexploitation in Hebei Province have been completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a county in southern Cangzhou, a staff member of the agricultural department told Southern Weekend reporters that there were originally more than 9,000 wells in the county, but now the deep wells have been sealed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even so, the audit report still pointed out that the closure of water wells has been slow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Hebei Province Groundwater Management Regulations&quot;, in the deep groundwater funnel area, agricultural irrigation wells that draw deep groundwater must also be shut down as planned. However, Southern Weekend reporters saw that there are still many villages that rely on deep water wells, and the closure period is unknown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of September, Wu Linsong was watering the bottom moisture needed before sowing winter wheat. Southern Weekend reporters saw that sections of yellow plastic floor cages were assembled into a long pipe of tens of meters. One end was connected to a red faucet at the edge of the field, and the other end was flowing with clear groundwater. Wu Linsong adjusts the position of the water outlet from time to time to irrigate along the diagonal line of the field. More than 70 kilometers away, Jinliuzhuang Village, Qingzhou Town, Qing County, Cangzhou City, is also using deep machine-driven wells for irrigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a3ca232ea3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a3ca232ea3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Linsong’s fields are still irrigated with groundwater. To do this, he needed to lay dozens of meters of yellow ground cages and constantly move heavy pipes. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Peng Ping explained that deep machine wells are currently closed seasonally. If there is water in the river that can be used when farming, you cannot use the water from the well. Otherwise, you can use the water from the well. &quot;There will be no hard shutdown.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For those water wells dug illegally, their concealment makes supervision more difficult. Excluding the house and electricity meter, the above-ground construction part of the deepwater well is not large, and the height of the pump is less than knee-high. Shallow wells are even more inconspicuous, with their mouths not as wide as city manhole covers and only ankle-high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of a water conservancy bureau in a county in Hebei Province said that the grassroots water conservancy department is limited by establishment and does not have sufficient manpower. Sometimes there are only about 40 people in the water affairs bureau at the county level, and only a small part of them are involved in water administrative law enforcement. They can only go to the fields from time to time to inspect the sealing and water withdrawal status of wells, and whether there is a water withdrawal permit. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Insufficient capillaries and difficulty in digestion&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In farmers’ perception, warm river water is more suitable for irrigating fields than cold groundwater. For example, Wang Gui, a villager in Wangjiakou Village, Qingxian County, feels that the corn cobs produced this year are indeed longer than last year. However, Wang Gui couldn&#39;t tell whether it was because water from the Yellow River had been diverted into the dry river in recent years or because of increased precipitation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a07e37bd49.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a07e37bd49.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In Hebei, a drought-ridden country with little rainfall, the amount of watering directly affects crop growth. The corn field on the left side of the sweet potato field is irrigated normally and is growing well; the corn field on the right side is stunted because the owner of the field goes out to work and relies on the sky for water. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Hebei Province Water Resources Bulletin&quot; shows that in 2022, Hebei Province&#39;s cross-basin water diversion volume reached 4.128 billion cubic meters, accounting for 22.6% of the total water supply. According to Southern Weekend reporters, in rural Hebei, the &quot;Yangtze River water&quot; from the South-to-North Water Diversion mainly replaces domestic water, while most of the river water extracted for irrigation is diverted from the Yellow River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most farmers are in favor of closing wells if they can use nearly free river water for irrigation. The China Rural Research Institute of Tsinghua University once surveyed 270 farmers in Hengshui, Hebei Province, on their evaluation of groundwater overexploitation control measures. For the measures of filling and sealing wells, the farmers&#39; favorable rate was only 61%; but for the South-to-North Water Diversion Project and the Yellow River Water Diversion, the favorable rate was only 61%. As high as 91% and 95% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cost of diverting water from the Yellow River is lower than that from the Yangtze River, only a few cents per cubic meter at the end of the field. A staff member of the agricultural department of a county in Cangzhou also told Southern Weekend reporters that the county government will transfer water unplanned for irrigation in 2024. This transaction was led by the water conservancy department and paid by the county finance, costing millions of yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters found in interviews that many villages still cannot use external water for irrigation. The main reason is the lack of water conservancy facilities to divert water to the fields, even if the river is just a few kilometers away from the village. The terrain of some villages is one or two meters higher than the surrounding areas, and water from the surrounding water systems cannot be diverted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/69b364a145.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/69b364a145.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the fields of Wangjiakou Village, the corn has just been harvested, leaving a bare land waiting for wheat to be sown. A red cast iron faucet stands on its own, connected to the deep shaft not far away. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Qing, a groundwater research expert at an institute affiliated to the Ministry of Water Resources, explained that Hebei’s rural areas are vast and there are no ready-made urban water conservancy facilities like Beijing and Tianjin. Han Qing compared rivers, ditches and ponds in rural areas to &quot;capillaries&quot; in the last mile. &quot;When external water is transferred to some areas with flat or high terrain, supporting pipe network projects must be provided to supply it. Provincial and county governments must Everyone has to invest, and it won’t be possible for several years.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cost of building rural water conservancy projects is not small. Public information shows that in Qing County, Cangzhou alone, nearly 100 million yuan will be invested in water conservancy projects related to the comprehensive management of groundwater overexploitation in 2023, including channel dredging, reconstruction of water culverts, and new control valves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Finances at all levels are very difficult now, and it would be good to be able to pay wages.&quot; Du Yun, head of the water affairs department of a county in Hebei Province, said, &quot;There is really no way to complete all the water diversion projects at once. We can only Do our best to improve.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For farmers who cannot use water from the Yellow River, can they use the &quot;Yangtze River water&quot; from the South-to-North Water Diversion in their home tap pipes for irrigation? This alternative would be prohibitively expensive and currently not a possibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Jiansheng, former director of the Institute of Hydrogeology and Environmental Geology of the Chinese Academy of Geological Sciences, told Southern Weekend reporters that the fundamental reason why some areas still rely on groundwater is that the cost of replacement surface water sources is too high. &quot;According to current cost calculations, the cost of the South-to-North Water Diversion Project to reach the irrigation plots in the central and eastern Hebei Plain is as high as 5-6 yuan per cubic meter. The cost of water use is impossible to bear unless the government provides high water source replacement subsidies.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The cost of water from the South-to-North Water Diversion Project is much higher than that of water diversion from the Yellow River, and local governments are not active in consuming it. A report from the Audit Office shows that 6 cities and 2 counties have unfinished tasks of absorbing river water and are in arrears with water fees of 3.175 billion yuan for the South-to-North Water Diversion Project. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Accurate measurement, say goodbye to flood irrigation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Whether it is groundwater or external water transfer, many experts believe that moderate charging of water fees can cultivate farmers&#39; awareness of water conservation and can also provide support for construction and maintenance. Provide funding for rural water conservancy projects. However, water fee pricing needs to be cautious to ensure food security, take into account farmers&#39; affordability, and not increase agricultural production costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jiang Wenlai, a researcher at the Institute of Agricultural Resources and Agricultural Zoning of the Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences, said, &quot;Agricultural water prices are higher based on full cost, which is difficult for farmers to accept. Even if they are charged based on maintenance costs, they still face difficulties. This cost The burden should be reasonably shared by the state, local governments and farmers.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Without accurate measurement, there is no rigorous water price system. Water charges for urban residents generally include water resources charges, water company costs and sewage treatment charges, which are measured through water meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most farmers in Hebei still have unclear accounts of their irrigation water consumption. For the use of groundwater, it is common to convert electricity bills into water bills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/bdadd4bd45.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/bdadd4bd45.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In a well house in a village, villagers take the meter counts of their own water usage to settle their electricity bills. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are seven or eight deep machine-operated wells in Wujiafang Village, and Wu Shucai is the manager of two of them. Villagers called him when they wanted to irrigate, and he went to the telephone pole outside the well house and wrote down the numbers on the electric meter. The old and new figures are subtracted to determine the villagers&#39; electricity consumption, which is then converted into electricity bills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the basis of normal electricity prices, some villages will &quot;increase the price&quot; to subsidize the personnel who manage the wells. Southern Weekend reporters found in interviews that the electricity charges for water wells in each village are different, ranging from 0.31 to 1 yuan per kilowatt hour. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using groundwater requires paying electricity bills, while using surface water is almost free. Villagers don’t even know whether the water they use comes from thousands of miles away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Gui did some calculations and found out that irrigating the ground with well water is billed according to the electricity consumption of deep wells. The price of electricity per kilowatt hour is 1-1.5 yuan. The water cost for growing one acre of wheat is It costs more than one hundred yuan. He spent more than 1,000 yuan to buy a diesel pump. The cost of pumping water from the river was only about 2 yuan in gas money, which was almost negligible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/d3c25b3f0b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/d3c25b3f0b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;With the diesel pump, Wang Gui pumps water from the river for irrigation at almost free cost. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some rural areas have begun to try metering. Water meters are installed on the water wells in Nansong Village, Lugongbao Town, Renqiu City, and the water conservancy department can remotely monitor whether anyone is secretly taking water. The village party secretary of Nansong Village told Southern Weekend reporters that during severe droughts, the villagers can apply to the water conservancy department for temporary use of motorized wells. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Peng Ping’s view, establishing an accurate metering system will help the water conservancy department grasp more accurate water consumption. &quot;In the past, it was all estimated. For example, 50 cubic meters of water was used to water one acre of land, and then the estimate was based on the area of ​​cultivated land. But if it had just rained, you might have only poured 40 cubic meters of water.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Shi Jianshe reminded that the installation of metering devices was based on Beijing’s experience, and the long-term effects may not be ideal. “Wellhead metering measures require large investments and are difficult to maintain. If farmers do not understand them, they will cause a lot of damage.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Beijing announced that it would implement metering and charging for 30,000 agricultural wells in the city within three years. In June 2023, the Beijing Municipal Water Affairs Bureau held an open tender for &quot;Construction of Agricultural and Rural Water Use Control and Standardized Management Models for Different Purposes&quot;. The purpose was to solve the problems of vulnerable, broken, stolen and inaccurate measurement of agricultural water metering facilities. Supplement and improve agricultural water use statistics and improve the level of agricultural irrigation water supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shi Jianshi suggested that the implementation of accurate wellhead metering can overcome the idea of ​​flood irrigation, and should be gradually promoted on the basis of the stable operation of the pilot, such as reasonable water use with subsidies and no charges, special water use with moderate charges, and wasteful use of water. High charges for sexual water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/14b3e5248a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/14b3e5248a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;At the China Agricultural University Experimental Station in Wuqiao County, Cangzhou City, Hebei Province, Professor Wang Zhimin began researching water-saving agriculture in the 1980s. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Haiyang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past three years, Han Qing has been paying attention to groundwater levels in Hebei. After analyzing the data from thousands of observation sites, he gave an extremely positive evaluation: &quot;The mining volume has decreased significantly, and the deep water has basically shown a rebound trend. Due to the hysteresis of land subsidence, the subsidence has not stopped, but the degree is also gradually increasing. Reduction. Generally speaking, the management of groundwater overexploitation areas is moving in a good direction.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shijian Province reminds that in the future, after the balance of groundwater extraction and replenishment is achieved, groundwater will not be unusable at all, and the water level will be restored. It may lead to secondary salinization, urban underground engineering immersion and other problems. It is necessary to reasonably and appropriately arrange the extraction and utilization of groundwater according to the needs of suitable water level control to maintain the optimal groundwater level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Wu Linsong, Wang Gui, Peng Ping, Han Qing, and Du Yun are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/ a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[县中振兴的真问题是什么？ | 议教]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260530]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-14 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On April 22, 2011, Book Exchange Station of Zouping County Experimental Middle School, Shandong. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/6ad2e9f377.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/6ad2e9f377.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258114&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;April 22, 2011, Book Exchange Station of Zouping Experimental Middle School, Shandong Province. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;County subsidence is one of the core issues in the field of basic education in recent times. For example, Professor Lin Xiaoying of Peking University&#39;s &quot;Children in the County—— The book &quot;China&#39;s County Education Ecology&quot; paints this picture: College entrance examination scores have seriously declined, high-quality students have disappeared, and the teaching team is aging... Counties that were once an important link in the upward mobility channel for children from poor families have been unable to perform as expected. As a result, the desolation of education in the county has become a spreading reality, and the county is like a hometown that has bid farewell, becoming a relic of the new urban middle class who have completed individual urbanization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I am ashamed to say that during the years when I devoted myself to serving basic education schools, I visited some counties, but I was not aware of the sharp social issue of &quot;county collapse&quot;. problem, but not much in-depth understanding. For example, a certain county in Shandong Province that I once served relied on its rising admission rate and even continued to export students from Qingbei, challenging the &quot;big boss&quot; in the region and province year after year. Not only is it not a &quot;collapse&quot;, but on the contrary, it has soared in the local basic education rankings - often real estate self-media or parents&#39; actual word-of-mouth. It is eventually called a &quot;counterattack&quot; by the education industry media and is considered to have achieved success. A perfect transformation from a county high school located in the suburbs to a &quot;modern school well-known in Qilu and going nationwide.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;You can even read comments like this on social media, talking about an interesting phenomenon in Shandong: enterprising children from urban families often try their best to The solution is to go back and study in the county. Campus life is very rich. &quot;It is not a college entrance examination factory. There are many sports teams, cultural festivals, and art societies, and it has also cultivated many competition experts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, as mentioned in the comments, those who try their best to return to the county may not necessarily be &quot;enterprising children&quot;, but more likely to be &quot;enterprising children&quot;. Enterprising parents.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The factors of the general environment are well known: social urbanization drives educational urbanization, and due to the innate Confucian emphasis on education genes in the East Asian cultural circle, once educational urbanization begins, Its speed must be much ahead of social urbanization. So we see this phenomenon: children from rural areas enter the county, and children from the county town enter the city. The county town between the countryside and the city, among the counties that have created a large number of miracles after the reform and opening up, has lost its aura in the new historical changes. Furthermore, the pivotal value of urban-rural conversion and class crossing has gradually been lost. The process of this underlying logic manifesting itself in reality is reflected in the collapse of the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot;Children in the County&quot;, written by Lin Xiaoying, Shanghai People&#39;s Publishing House, July 2023.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/13/732705cbef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 13/732705cbef.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Children in the County&quot;, written by Lin Xiaoying, Shanghai People&#39;s Publishing House , July 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, in this process of urbanization transformation, there will also be a phenomenon of &quot;counter-urbanization&quot; that rises against the trend: some former counties Expanded into a super school. The former county school mentioned earlier has also emerged as an educational group that can challenge the provincial government and has several branch schools, covering both public and private systems. In fact, the counties that I have visited and served often have the following two characteristics: balanced distance and extreme county mode. The so-called equilibrium distance means that these rising counties are often not far or close to the central city of the central city, or they themselves were once suburban counties of the central city and later became the suburbs of the city. The Ultimate County High School model refers to taking the model from the glory days of the early County High School to the extreme: after competing for high-quality students, using extreme exam-oriented methods, suppressing one&#39;s nature and gaining the psychological motivation to live toward death in order to succeed in the college entrance examination. But this psychological dynamic is often accompanied by strong feelings of resentment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is why some students from super middle schools think of themselves as typical examples of children from poor families. Even though urbanization transformation has been achieved, the ideology of these schools still remains at the county level. Through the confrontation between urban and rural areas, the bottom class and the elite, they have obtained the rationality and motivational support resources to inherit and complete the county education model. . I still remember the famous saying of a student from Hengshui Middle School: &quot;I am just a native pig from the countryside, but I am determined to conquer the cabbage in the big city.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;But this classmate, who regarded himself as a local pig, was picked up by his father in an Audi private car during the vacation. In those &quot;rising counties&quot;, there is also a question mark as to how many children are from the counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The rising counties started with extremely exam-oriented education. After completing primitive accumulation, they began to enter a more diversified development. Even in the face of the new college entrance examination reform, the resources and capital they have are enough to cope with this change. They can even use this as an opportunity to achieve secondary development and complete the complete transformation from rural civilization to urban civilization - the transformation is completed. The sign may be that in the future, on social platforms such as Zhihu, graduates from these schools will no longer lament that after reaching university, there is still a gap between them and students who graduated from the real cities such as Xingshi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, behind the rise of super-secondary counties is often the decline of one century-old county after another. This is the real dilemma of county education. Wang Xinfeng, from the China Education Policy Research Institute at Beijing Normal University, pointed out in the keynote report &quot;County Dilemmas from the Perspective of Access to Higher Education Opportunities&quot; that at present, high-quality students, teachers and other educational resources are gradually gathering in central cities, and the gap in high school education resources continues to widen. , in some areas, the decline in the quality of higher education in counties has become an inevitable trend. This will not only have an impact on the county&#39;s education ecology and social governance pattern, but also explicitly and implicitly exclude access to higher education opportunities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many of the expectations given to the county today are related to our social development stage: after entering the 1980s, the start of China&#39;s urbanization process provided the county with brilliant opportunities possible, but this brilliance diminished with the arrival of the next stage of development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;We might as well extend the timeline longer. Andrew Byron Kipnis, professor of the Department of Anthropology at the Chinese University of Hong Kong, in his book &quot;Desire for Governance Education&quot; describes Zouping, Shandong: Like other places in China, Zouping experienced shocking political ruptures in the 20th century. The end of the Qing Dynasty, the beginning of the Republic of China, the Japanese invasion, and the civil war between the Kuomintang and the Communist Party. Amidst all the ruptures, education showed the continued development of On the one hand, basic education has developed steadily - eliminating illiteracy, first by universalizing six years of primary education, and later by nine years of compulsory education. Although education developed most rapidly in the 1950s and 1970s, education also improved as early as the early 1930s during the rural construction movement promoted by Liang Shuming and others in Zouping. The institutional foundation for the popularization of education was laid even as early as the Republic of China. Finally, after more than half a century of continuous efforts, in January 1995, Zouping achieved two basic goals: nine-year compulsory education, and the elimination of illiteracy among the population under the age of 45. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, in the current discussion of the collapse of many counties, what does it mean to revitalize the county? Is it going back to the peak of the county in the 1980s and 1990s, or even earlier, to become a high point where the cultural context of the place condenses? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, the real problem in the revitalization of the county is not the county itself, but more importantly, the importance of the county&#39;s social ecology and educational ecology in the process of historical change. Shape and coordinate. At the same time, as an important part of social governance, how to achieve good governance in education under a deterministic new value scale is probably the real issue in the revitalization of the county. Specifically, this kind of &quot;good governance&quot;, as summarized by Wang Xinfeng, firstly requires adhering to the system concept, clarifying the characteristics of the social development stage, and re-examining county development issues under the strategic goals of common prosperity and new urbanization; secondly, it must improve education Allocate resources, strengthen comprehensive management of education, and ensure a fair starting point for county middle school students to obtain higher education opportunities on the basis of high-quality development; third, continue to deepen the reform of the examination and enrollment system, expand the implementation scope of special plans, and ensure that county middle school students have higher education in the college admissions process. Equity in educational opportunities and outcomes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The author used to be a college teacher and is now a basic education service practitioner&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 08:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[被砍掉又被续命，只因它是《万神殿》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260482]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Last year, AMC’s animated science fiction drama &quot;Yiban.io&quot; &quot;Temple&quot; detonated the entire Internet, and it still has a super high score of 8.8 on Douban, and even 100% unanimous praise on the Rotten Tomatoes website. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just when the majority of drama fans were eagerly awaiting the second season, the show was not well-received and had poor ratings. AMC, which was already financially weak, decided to cancel the sequel. Fortunately, Amazon took over and injected funds to continue the production of the second season, allowing &quot;Pantheon&quot; to be fully concluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that the second season is online, it is immediately popular, with an opening score of 9.3, making it the strongest animated show this year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/d51400ace003e248fe55a2a3fc03381a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;469&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/d51400ace003e248fe55a2a3fc03381a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258030&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Before analyzing the second season, let us first review the science fiction setting and story background of the first season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The core concept of &quot;Pantheon&quot; is &quot;upload intelligence&quot;, referred to as &quot;UI&quot;. The technology company in the play uploads signal data to the network through precise scanning of neurons in the human brain to generate upload intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from AI tools such as &quot;ChatGPT&quot; that we are familiar with, to a certain extent, uploaded intelligence can be regarded as a brand new life form, but it gets rid of the physical body and travels in the online world with pure consciousness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/638c91e580c26315f242bd7f1075d532.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/638c91e580c26315f242bd7f1075d532.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258026&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Season 1 In it, David, the father of the heroine Mandy, uploaded his neuron signals to the Internet before his death, becoming the earliest uploaded intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Indian engineer Chanda and genius girl Laurie have become uploading intelligence. However, their positions are completely opposite. Chanda wants to expand the world of uploaded intelligence in an extreme way; Laurie is a defender of the real world and wants to join forces with David to resist Chanda&#39;s conspiracy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/5b528a262c1e05d1d08171f2c5e1296c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/5b528a262c1e05d1d08171f2c5e1296c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258027&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Season 1 In the end, David sacrificed himself to preserve human society, but what followed was a global disconnection, and governments around the world were afraid of the unlimited capabilities of uploaded intelligence. Not only that, due to the &quot;integrity defect&quot;, the uploaded intelligence itself is also very unstable, and may completely die as its energy continues to decay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The key to solving the problem falls on the hero Caspian. This is a cloned boy who grew up in design just like Truman in &quot;The Truman Show&quot;. Caspian&#39;s identity is Steve, the founder of the technology giant company &quot;Algorithm Beat&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/633fef39cf5c0fa88f9507f9f04beeca.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/633fef39cf5c0fa88f9507f9f04beeca.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258028&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, no. At the beginning of the second season, two major conflicts emerged. One is that public protests continue, and they believe that the crisis caused by Upload Smart is just a cover, demanding that the government immediately restore the network; the other is that the government still intends to use Upload Smart for its own use, but must address its own shortcomings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, the “safe browsing” software launched by the government has become a prerequisite for people to access the Internet. To put it bluntly, this is an anti-virus software that specifically hunts upload intelligence; as for Caspian, with the help of Mandy, he solved the core problem of &quot;integrity defect&quot; and made the upload intelligence truly immortal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/079b5ca53d39aefa7f1a68cdff536a74.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/079b5ca53d39aefa7f1a68cdff536a74.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258029&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If, The focus of the first season of &quot;Pantheon&quot; was on uploading intelligence&#39;s confusion about self-identity and the complex situation of ethical relationships. In the second season, the depth of thinking and critical consciousness displayed in the series are much broader and deeper. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first is the issue of &quot;integrity defects&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as more than ten years ago, the extremely smart Steve had actually understood everything about uploading intelligence, and even ordered his subordinates to freeze and seal his brain, starting a cloning project, with the purpose of cultivating intelligence. Caspian, let him solve the problem that he can&#39;t do anything about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/df2b3aafe8aa8eb9f8e8c5459044fa69.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/df2b3aafe8aa8eb9f8e8c5459044fa69.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258031&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to history Tiff has the same brain circuit, so Caspian cannot easily break through the mental prison. The most interesting thing about the episode is that it uses Mandy&#39;s words to inspire Caspian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Mandy&#39;s view, &quot;others&quot; are the reason why we are where we are today as a human species, and the reason why we live and die. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To put it more simply, we do not live for ourselves, but become uneven and colorful because of external driving forces. The richness of human nature does not depend on one&#39;s own cultivation and growth, but on the instantaneous changes around us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/c86caf40a7d0894d876aa8cf5ad522f1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/c86caf40a7d0894d876aa8cf5ad522f1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258032&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, when When Caspian analyzed David&#39;s raw data, he realized that concern for his daughter constituted a necessary factor for David to be a complete soul. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is actually similar to the setting of the first season. The reason why David, Chanda and Laurie, unlike other experimenters, have self-awareness is because they came into contact with their family and loved ones. . Emotion bridges the shortcomings of reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/5cf3f9aa69ed948b2eb5caaa0d6265a2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/5cf3f9aa69ed948b2eb5caaa0d6265a2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258034&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another character in the play A setting worth chewing is Mandy’s “sister” Misty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fog is neither AI (artificial intelligence) nor UI (upload intelligence), but CI (cloud intelligence). It sounds a bit convoluted, but it&#39;s actually not difficult to understand. AI is an intelligent agent created by humans; UI is the life form of human consciousness; and CI is a new existence that UI reproduces in the online world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Misty claims to be Mandy&#39;s sister is because she was automatically generated from David and Laurie&#39;s data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/b21304b07717bd09eb69cddc6a6551a2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;603&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/b21304b07717bd09eb69cddc6a6551a2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258035&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mandy knows After this situation, it is difficult to accept. After all, does mist count as a living thing? It is difficult to define. Even if it is regarded as a living body, if a stranger suddenly comes to Mandy and recognizes her, how should the latter treat it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of imaginative ethical setting has almost never appeared in previous film and television works. It not only explores the essence of life, but also asks: Does family ties originate from blood relatives, or does it rely on memory and emotion? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Pantheon&quot; does not deal with this topic perfunctorily, but tells us the mixed feelings in family relationships through the fierce conflict between Mandy and Misty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/f4ad6918b09f6a1493ac0c728419a1c6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;610&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/f4ad6918b09f6a1493ac0c728419a1c6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258036&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Mandy When she placed all her hopes on Misty, hoping that she could defeat Steve, the latter used a set of logical and rigorous arguments to convince Misty. Mandy was very angry about this, and even yelled out that Misty was not her sister at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fact that Miwu left angrily and even ignored Mandy in anger for a long time proved her &quot;humanity&quot; from the side. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is that human beings will feel sad because of the past, but because Misty has no past, she will only feel lonely and lonely about the future. This kind of psychological detail with great speculative significance may be the reason why the drama &quot;Pantheon&quot; often makes our souls tremble and make us realize something. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/57ba95a043a940eb29344ced252608ea.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;602&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/57ba95a043a940eb29344ced252608ea.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258033&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If, The content and themes of the first six episodes are still at the level of binary opposition, that is, the game between the &quot;human faction&quot; represented by Mandy and Caspian, and the &quot;upload intelligence faction&quot; represented by Steve, then The last two episodes completely exceeded the psychological expectations of fans of the drama, crossing over to bold assumptions about the future world in sociology, politics, psychology and other levels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Steve was defeated, the technology of uploading intelligence has not stopped. Just twenty years after Caspian and Steve &quot;died together&quot;, a total of four billion people around the world were uploaded from real society to cyberspace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the reasons why people choose this path are not forced by impending death, but the inevitable result of the rapid increase in productivity and the subsequent changes in production relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/31c9e6070343239a4e00136afdd8dee9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;603&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/31c9e6070343239a4e00136afdd8dee9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Upload smart user The least time cost, the most work tasks can be completed, so in the real society, &quot;the living people are gradually being robbed of their jobs by the dead.&quot; When death becomes immortality, and freedom and wealth become available without any effort, human beings will no longer pity the physical body but yearn for the virtual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, this relationship is fluid. When we follow Caspian&#39;s perspective and quickly understand the changes in the past two decades, we will find that no matter what time it is, hostility, war, and ideological division will always exist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second season of &quot;Pantheon&quot;, like a science fiction accelerator with continuous brainstorming, takes us to imagine the &quot;earth past&quot; that is very likely to happen in the future, and allows love and family relationships to develop over decades and on. In the long span of hundreds to hundreds of thousands of years, incredible flavors are fermented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/12f8e61ae80a884e517ccee74c55ab85.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/12/12f8e61ae80a884e517ccee74c55ab85.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258038&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality , a piece of profound data shows that as of January 2021, more than 500 people around the world have been cryogenically sealed, and more than 3,000 wealthy people have registered for cryogenic projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will this group of people, like the uploaded intelligence in &quot;Pantheon&quot;, become the first batch of &quot;network immigrants&quot; in the metaverse in the future? Perhaps the distance between reality and the world of science fiction has long exceeded our imagination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国肥胖地图出炉：南方人靠会吃比北方人瘦？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257304]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-13 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, the &quot;China Obesity Map&quot; was released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the largest study to date on the prevalence of overweight and obesity and related complications in China. According to the BMI classification standard for obesity in my country, the proportion of obese people is 13.7%. The top five provinces with obesity in the country are: Hebei (21.9%), Inner Mongolia (19.8%), Shandong (19.7%), Tianjin (19.6%), Liaoning ( 18.2%). Compared with northern provinces and cities, the obesity rate in southern provinces is lower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Where does the obesity difference between North and South come from? The &quot;Dietary Guidelines for Chinese Residents (2022)&quot; defines the eating habits of Fujian, Guangdong and other regions as &quot;Oriental healthy dietary patterns&quot;. This model has the characteristics of high food diversity, relatively light diet, sufficient intake of fresh vegetables and fruits, relatively high intake of fish and shrimp, low intake of pork, etc., and enhanced intake of milk and legumes. , resulting in a higher overall meal quality compliance rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with the lighter eating habits in the south, northern cuisine is more flavorful and pays attention to both color, flavor and flavor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, the increase in obesity rate is not only caused by &quot;eating&quot;. From the perspective of scientific research: obesity is determined by system dynamics factors and environmental determinants. This push is amplified or moderated by individual-level genetic susceptibility, psychosocial factors, obesogens and adverse early life exposures and other coexisting underlying risk factors, through unhealthy diet and lack of physical activity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;While paying attention to obesity, the topic #weightloss# often also attracts much attention. For example, on Douyin, Xiaohongshu, Weibo and other platforms, there are Videos and notes on the topic #weightloss# have been read more than 10 million times. Not only that, but various weight loss tools are also emerging in endlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obesity is also a &quot;fulcrum&quot; that drives various diseases. The World Health Organization report believes that overweight and obesity are important causes of high blood pressure. Among endocrine and metabolic diseases, the diabetes rate among overweight people is as high as 20.4%, which is 4 to 5 times higher than that among people with normal weight. Modern research has also proven that obese people are often accompanied by hyperinsulinemia, which may be the root cause of cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Healthy and scientific weight loss and exercise are very important. For your own health, &quot;Know&quot; tells you how to say &quot;goodbye&quot; to excess fat correctly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/a588b511f1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/a588b511f1.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/4926193e5c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440 &quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/4926193e5c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/c2a2877735.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/c2a2877735.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251544&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/1963d6ccc4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/1963d6ccc4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/4b9bb6c400.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/21/4b9bb6c400.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/21/c2675d0556.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 21/c2675d0556.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251547&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 21/300577827d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/21/300577827d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251548&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 13 Nov 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>