<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[《校外培训行政处罚暂行办法》颁布：严管校外培训，能否压缩外力鸡娃的空间？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Ministry of Education promulgated the &quot;Interim Measures for Administrative Penalties for Off-Campus Training&quot;, with 6 chapters and 44 articles, which will be implemented in 2023 It will come into effect on October 15, 2020. As soon as the regulations of this department were promulgated, they attracted concern from all parties, especially training institutions and their employees and even parents, who wanted to know where the legal and illegal boundaries of off-campus training were drawn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common consensus among everyone is that in-service teachers should not engage in off-campus training. Article 16 of the above-mentioned measures stipulates that if the parties involved &quot;are in-service teachers in primary and secondary schools and the training content is subject-based off-campus training&quot;, they shall be severely punished in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There have been cases like this: a teacher did not teach well in class, and then mobilized students to participate in paid private training organized by him, and even put small shoes on students who did not participate. This is undoubtedly against professional ethics. Public school teachers, teaching is their main job, and they have to be worthy of the salary they receive. How can they charge students a second time for the content that should be taught in the classroom? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what are the core contents and provisions of this regulation? The following three points deserve attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, Article 2 of the Measures stipulates: If a natural person, legal person or other organization recruits preschool children, primary and secondary school students over 3 years old from the society, and illegally conducts off-campus training, and shall be given administrative penalties, these Measures shall apply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, if a natural person or institution enrolls infants and young children under 3 years old, it is almost equivalent to day care. It is okay for the children in day care to play educational games and recite Tang poetry. It will be considered as off-campus training or illegal off-campus training. Indeed, logically, only when a child goes to kindergarten or school can there be &quot;school&quot;, and only then can there be &quot;outside school&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for this article, the General Provisions do not define &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. Among the various types of penalties, specific circumstances of &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot; should be punished. The basis for the document&#39;s definition of &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot; is: the 2021 &quot;Opinions on Further Reducing the Homework Burden and Off-Campus Training Burden of Students in Compulsory Education&quot; issued by the two offices in 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;double reduction&quot; programmatic document defines the boundaries of off-campus training as follows: for training institutions, &quot;all localities will no longer approve new subject-based off-campus training institutions for students in compulsory education. All discipline-based training institutions are uniformly registered as non-profit institutions, and the original registered online discipline-based training institutions are changed to an approval system.&quot; For training content, &quot;Establish a training content filing and supervision system, and formulate and release training materials for off-campus training institutions. &quot;Management Measures&quot; &quot;It is strictly prohibited to exceed the standard and advance training, it is strictly prohibited to engage in subject-based training by non-disciplinary training institutions, and it is strictly prohibited to provide overseas education courses&quot;; for students and teachers, &quot;Online training must pay attention to protecting students&#39; vision, and each class period shall not exceed 30 minutes. The interval should be no less than 10 minutes, and the training end time should be no later than 21:00. &quot;The hiring of foreign personnel within the country must comply with relevant national regulations. It is strictly prohibited to hire foreign personnel abroad to carry out training activities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, this measure stipulates that the &quot;off-campus training competent department&quot; shall enforce the law and punish &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. Article 6 stipulates that administrative penalties for off-campus training shall be implemented by the off-campus training authorities of governments at or above the county level, and the off-campus training authorities shall be determined by provincial governments in accordance with relevant national regulations. So, is the “off-campus training authority” the local education bureau or education committee? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This regulation is formulated and promulgated by the Ministry of Education, which also authorizes provincial governments to determine what is the competent authority for off-campus training. There is a trend in administrative law enforcement: instead of allowing each department to enforce the law on its own, a comprehensive law enforcement agency will be established to ensure that law enforcement is carried out within legitimate substantive matters and due procedures, and to reduce the number of departments that rely on the weak and the weak. Create space for rent-seeking to reduce nuisance to natural persons and enterprises and improve the business environment. Therefore, it remains to be seen who will enforce the law on &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, this measure is very strict. It must control and punish &quot;illegal off-campus training&quot;. The subjects include not only institutions, and the identification standards for institutions are strict, but also natural persons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strict standards for the identification of institutions. Article 17 of the Measures stipulates that if a natural person, legal person or other organization conducts off-campus training without approval and meets these three conditions, (1) there is a special training venue for offline training, and a specific website or application for online training, (2) Having more than 2 training practitioners, (3) having corresponding organizational structure and division of labor constitutes &quot;organizing off-campus training institutions without authorization&quot;, and will be ordered to stop organizing, refund the fees charged, and impose a fine of more than double the illegal income A fine of up to five times. This means that a mom-and-pop shop or a partnership shop between friends that handles training and operations, with as few as two people, may be recognized as an &quot;off-campus training institution.&quot; Once recognized as an &quot;off-campus training institution&quot; and without approval before opening, it may It constitutes organizing off-campus training institutions without authorization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Strict control over individuals engaged in subject training. Article 18 of the Measures stipulates that natural persons, legal persons or other organizations carry out off-campus training in subject areas in disguise, but do not meet the conditions stipulated in Article 17 of these Measures and commit any of the following acts: (1) Through instant messaging, online conferencing, live broadcast platforms, etc. (2) Using residential buildings, hotels, cafes and other places to organize paid off-campus training such as &quot;one-to-one&quot; and &quot;one-to-many&quot;; (3) Using consultation, cultural dissemination, quality development, For paid off-campus training in the name of competitions, thinking training, housekeeping services, family education guidance, live-in teachers, crowdfunding private tutors, study tours, study tours, winter and summer camps, trusteeship, etc., the punishment can range from an order to make corrections and a refund of fees to a fine. A fine of not less than 50,000 yuan but not more than 100,000 yuan is imposed. In theory, college students who serve as tutors will also be subject to supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Landlords or business premises that provide premises will also be subject to joint penalties. Article 19 of the Measures: If a natural person, legal person or other organization knows or should know that illegal off-campus training activities exist, but still provides a place for them to carry out off-campus training, the punishment can range from being ordered to make corrections within a time limit to being given a warning or a notice of criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This measure began to solicit opinions in November last year. Now that it has finally been implemented, it will definitely have a profound impact on the form and pattern of off-campus subject training. If implemented to the letter, it will greatly reduce the space for parents to rely on external forces to help their children. Of course, it remains to be seen how much this will shake the parents’ determination and motivation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[仅仅多一项选择，外卖平台就显著减少了污染]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256558]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 8, 2023, the magazine &quot;Science&quot; published a report by the University of Hong Kong, Peking University, etc. The results of the research team, “Green Boosting Reduced Disposable Tableware Use: Evidence from China’s Takeaway Industry.” This paper studies the impact of the green promotion practice of changing the cutlery selection user interface of the Ele.me food delivery platform on the consumption of disposable tableware (SUC) and the reduction of plastic waste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This new study of 10 major cities in China shows that making &quot;no cutlery&quot; the default option when placing orders on food delivery apps and rewarding customers who choose not to use plastic cutlery can significantly reduce the number of orders The waste of sexual tableware. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the surface, the fact that the results of a study involving environmental protection, business, psychology and economics can be published in a world-class journal is enough to show the importance of this research. More importantly, this study answers an important question and provides an idea and method to solve the problem, that is, environmental protection not only requires green promotion, but also requires joint efforts online and offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as September 2017, the Chongqing Green Volunteer Federation took Meituan, Baidu Waimai and Ele.me to court on the grounds of causing waste of resources and environmental pollution. Volunteers believe that the defendant did not provide users with the option of &quot;whether to use disposable tableware&quot;, causing the system to default to distributing disposable tableware, causing huge waste of resources and ecological damage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is first of all focusing on offline environmental protection to online ordering. In response to the green volunteers’ complaints and facing severe environmental protection issues and huge responsibilities, food delivery industry giants have responded positively. In 2018, Meituan and Ele.me launched environmental protection programs such as the &quot;Qingshan Plan&quot; and &quot;Blue Planet Plan&quot; respectively. When ordering meals, users can choose &quot;no tableware required&quot; to help environmental protection. In addition, some takeout platforms encourage merchants to use environmentally friendly paper bags instead of plastic bags for takeout packaging to reduce environmental pressure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if these food delivery companies responded at that time, some people still suspected that it was not easy to solve the pollution problem derived from food delivery. The food delivery platform alone had limited effect and had to go through food delivery merchants and food delivery platforms. Only through the joint efforts of multiple relevant parties, including lunch box manufacturers and consumers, can the problem be alleviated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, the results of scientific research have provided a preliminary answer to these questions and doubts. As long as we do and take action, even if it is just one link of effort, it is possible to reduce plastic pollution and improve the environment, and the results will be Significant, significant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the research results of Chinese and foreign research teams, Alibaba’s online food ordering platform Eleme (similar to Uber Eats and DoorDash) has made adjustments in the application using the concept of green promotion: 1. Add a pop-up window that requires customers to explicitly select the quantity of disposable cutlery in their order; 2. Set the default value of the pop-up window to &quot;no cutlery&quot;; 3. Provide a small non-monetary reward to those who choose not to use cutlery --Some &quot;Ant Forest Green Dots.&quot; These green points can be redeemed for planting real trees in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An analysis of detailed customer-level data on the ordering history of 197,062 randomly selected users in 10 major cities in China from 2019 to 2021 found that these green boosts significantly reduced the use of disposable tableware. The proportion of orders without cutlery increased by 648%. If implemented across China, such an intervention could save more than 21.75 billion sets of disposable tableware, reduce 3.26 million tons of plastic waste, and save 5.44 million trees each year, without affecting the business performance or revenue of Alibaba or individual restaurants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This result is a win-win for all, but it is not just a win-win for all. It provides a feasible measure to reduce plastic pollution that can be used as a reference, especially for countries with large populations and countries that use a lot of plastic products. effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a February 2022 report from the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), global plastic production increased from 2.34 million tons to 460 million tons from 2000 to 2019. The generation of plastic waste has more than doubled, reaching 353 million tons in 2019. According to the United Nations Environment Program, plastics account for at least 85% of total marine debris. In 2019 alone, 22 million tons of plastic were released into the environment, with 6 million tons ending up in rivers, lakes and oceans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, 32% of the world&#39;s plastics were produced in China; more than half of the plastics came from Asia. China&#39;s production alone accounts for 1/3 (32%) of global production. China is also the world&#39;s largest producer and consumer of disposable tableware. In 2022, more than 753 million users will be active users of takeout services, and more than 50 million sets of disposable tableware that have not been fully recycled or processed are consumed every day, including Plastic bags, plastic forks, plastic spoons, wooden chopsticks and napkins. Therefore, reducing disposable tableware is an urgent and important mission. Moreover, China has also set a goal of reducing the use of disposable tableware in takeout food delivery by 30% by 2025. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now it seems that as long as the online ordering platform scientifically sets up the program, it can greatly reduce the use of disposable tableware, and it will not reduce the order volume and the income of the platform and restaurants. This is of course an online platform. It can only be accomplished by the joint efforts of both online and offline. However, there is also a scientific basis for implementing such measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The changes to the user interface of the Ele.me food ordering app reflect the concept of &quot;nudging&quot; in behavioral economics and social psychology, that is, changing the choice environment (or choice architecture) or providing indirect information to influence individuals Methods of behavior and decision-making. The key characteristic of nudges is that they do not limit the choices available to an individual, nor do they alter monetary incentives, but they can provide some kind of boost or promotion, such as environmental protection. Moreover, nudges have been used in many social fields. From this concept, online and offline actions can greatly reduce the use of disposable tableware, thereby protecting the environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the green promotion of the food ordering platform is not perfect, and there are also shortcomings that need to be improved. First, although customers choose &quot;no cutlery required&quot; when ordering, some businesses still provide disposable cutlery. The reason is that this happens when merchants are too busy to check orders one by one or worry that consumers may have chosen the &quot;no cutlery required&quot; option by mistake; second, customers often waste their green energy or fail to accumulate enough green energy. energy to plant trees; third, the impact of the green boost was most evident in the first few months after implementation but declined slightly over time, suggesting that some customers later decided to change the default “no cutlery required” option . This is consistent with previous research on the attenuation effect of default options. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, to solve these problems, more efforts must be made offline. Of course, if green boosting can be tried and promoted on all domestic food ordering platforms, as well as food ordering platforms in other countries, such as DoorDash and Uber Eats, global plastic waste will be greatly reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[幼儿园教师，过剩还是不足？村小撤并与否，有更好的选择吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256611]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/D4VRVbviuSjP6bayt9oNVvccC0GF7KviP5EGKVGV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1116&quot; height=&quot;730&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/D4VRVbviuSjP6bayt9oNVvccC0GF7KviP5EGK VGV. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250676&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 8, 2022, a kindergarten in Zhongmu County, Zhengzhou City. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, Xiong Bingqi, director of the 21st Century Education Research Institute, participated in a training for teachers in small rural schools. A principal told him that the local government was once willing to open small rural schools, but now almost all of them are not in favor of it and believe that they should be withdrawn and merged. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;China Education Statistical Yearbook&quot;, the number of rural primary schools in China dropped from 416,198 in 2001 to 90,603 in 2018, a decrease of 325,595. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A major background for the decrease in the number of rural primary schools is the declining birth rate. The results of the seventh national census show that the proportion of China&#39;s population aged 0 to 14 is 17.95%, which is lower than the standard of 20% of the total population defined by the narrow concept of low birthrate. Correspondingly, the number of kindergarten-age children has also decreased, posing challenges to the development of preschool education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the birthrate continues to decline, how should preschool education respond? With declining birthrate and urbanization, where will small rural schools go? On September 7, 2023, the &quot;Transformation of Education in the New Era&quot; seminar and the &quot;China Education Observation (2022)&quot; new book preview event hosted by the 21st Century Education Research Institute were held in Beijing. Many participating scholars focused on these educational issues. discuss. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;When there are less than&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;56 students, the kindergarten cannot maintain operation&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;If To maintain operations, kindergartens must have a certain scale.&quot; Liu Shanhuai, a professor at Northeast Normal University&#39;s China Rural Education Development Research Institute, came to this conclusion after conducting calculations on an inclusive kindergarten. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The calculation results of that kindergarten show that the monthly education fee for each student is 390 yuan, which is charged for 9 months a year. The government subsidizes kindergartens for 12 months per year at a rate of 365 yuan per student per month. When there are fewer than 56 students, the kindergarten cannot maintain operations. The number of students must be no less than 115 to maintain a good operating level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/zUMeLPqzg70UpAQAOwyp6UDApU0HhqicX4vtgBhx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;855&quot; height= &quot;570&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/zUMeLPqzg70UpAQAOwyp6UDApU0HhqicX4vtgBhx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250675&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 7, 2023, Beijing, Professor Liu Shanhuai (middle) of the China Rural Education Development Research Institute of Northeast Normal University shared at the seminar. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Interviewee/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the impact chain of declining birthrate, preschool education is the first to bear the brunt. Xiong Bingqi believes that the government should increase investment in preschool education and “should not plan future development according to the existing resource guarantee model.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He further suggested that preschool education should be guaranteed in accordance with compulsory education standards, that is, compulsory education should be extended to 12 years, which is conducive to building a child-friendly society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While the number of students entering kindergarten is decreasing, Feng Wanzhen, associate professor at the Department of Education of Beijing Normal University, noticed that the number of kindergarten teachers in China has nearly tripled in 2020 compared with 2010, with an increase of 3.349 million teaching staff. , the number of full-time teachers increased by 1.769 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind the growth data, she found that some areas already have a surplus of kindergarten teachers, but in some areas there is still a serious shortage. As of 2020, there are still 11 provinces including Guangxi, Yunnan, and Sichuan where the ratio of the total number of children in kindergarten to the total number of full-time teachers has not reached the minimum standard for large class configurations stipulated in the &quot;Kindergarten Staff Staffing Standards (Interim)&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Feng Wanzhen’s view, faced with the imbalance of teacher resources, reasonable coordination should be carried out to supplement the structural shortage of kindergarten teachers. In some areas with abundant teacher resources, we can explore the integration of daycare and kindergarten teachers and divert kindergarten teachers into the team of daycare teachers who are in short supply. At the same time, combined with its own actual conditions, the kindergarten&#39;s service forms will be expanded and the benefits of existing teacher resources will be brought into play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although the number of teachers has increased significantly, kindergarten teachers have a high turnover problem due to low salary, insufficient staffing and other reasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response to the above issues, the &quot;Draft Preschool Education Law&quot;, which has been submitted to the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress for first review in August 2023, stipulates kindergarten teachers&#39; salaries, benefits, staffing, etc.: Private kindergartens should refer to local public kindergartens The salary income level of similar teachers should reasonably determine the teacher&#39;s salary standard, and social insurance should be paid in accordance with the law; kindergarten teachers enjoy the same treatment as primary and secondary school teachers in terms of professional title evaluation, job appointment (employment), etc.; local establishment departments at all levels follow the basic establishment standards for kindergarten teachers and staffing standards, the number of teaching staff in public kindergartens is approved and dynamically adjusted, and the local education department, in conjunction with the human resources and social security department, promptly replenishes teachers in public kindergartens. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It is difficult to achieve &quot;small but excellent&quot; in rural schools&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Unlike preschool education, which has begun to face the impact of declining birthrate in recent years, small-scale rural schools also have to face the impact of urbanization. The challenges of globalization and the existential crisis come earlier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If rural education has higher quality, the school-age population will not have to flow into urban areas to choose high-quality education.” Liu Shanhuai believes that the positive interaction between education and population should be achieved by improving the allocation of educational resources. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During research in a county-level city in Northeast China, he learned that the city will have more than 1,200 people born in 2022, and will lose another 300 to 400 people when they enter primary school six years later. The first-grade school-age population will only be There are 800 to 900 people left. This means that “if the distribution of students is not considered, (the city only needs) one primary school is enough.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in reality, students are scattered. When students move from rural to urban areas, the supply of educational resources will not necessarily be more adequate. But it is foreseeable that the number of students in rural schools will become smaller and smaller. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Shanhuai believes: &quot;In the future, small-scale rural schools will be the norm, and more and more central schools will become small-scale schools, and more and more teaching points will disappear.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;In his view, some scholars’ expectations for “small but excellent” rural schools are difficult to realize based on the existing resource allocation, and whether they can offer a complete range of subjects is also a question mark. He gave an example. According to the teacher-student ratio of 1:19, a certain school has 12 students distributed in three grades. &quot;One teacher is simply not enough.&quot; This will lead to low-quality and inefficient operation of small schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only the quality of teaching will be affected, Liu Shanhuai is worried that if the number of students in the school is too small, it will also affect students&#39; social development, mental health and communication skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number of rural schools is indeed continuing to decrease. During the question and answer session, a reporter shared her findings from interviews in a county in Henan. The county will close a total of 70 rural schools in 2023. According to the plan, schools with less than 50 students will be merged this year, schools with less than 100 students next year, and schools with less than 200 students the year after. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Liu Shanhuai’s view, simply using the number of students in a school as the criteria for merging schools is too single and unreasonable. The reduction in the number of schools is more convenient for administrators, but it increases the distance for students to go to school and also brings inconvenience to parents. &quot;The distribution of rural schools should be determined according to the natural population distribution.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The decline in students is difficult to reverse. How to improve the quality of rural schools? Liu Shanhuai believes that public funding standards based on the number of students cannot meet the actual needs of rural schools, and the funding structure should be improved to ensure the economic foundation for the development of rural education. At the same time, we will consolidate diverse supplementary channels for rural teachers through targeted training of rural teachers, special post plans, and retired teaching support. In the information age, the application of information technology can also help improve the level of rural education. The configuration of hardware facilities and the construction of digital resources in rural schools should be further strengthened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2012, the number of compulsory education schools in rural areas was significantly reduced, which led to longer distances for some students to go to school, increased traffic safety hazards, increased financial burdens on students’ families, and caused a shortage of boarding schools in rural areas and some urban To address issues such as excessive school class sizes, the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Regulating the Adjustment of the Layout of Rural Compulsory Education Schools.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The opinions call for resolutely stopping the blind dismantling of rural compulsory education schools. At the same time, the layout of rural compulsory education schools should ensure that students need to go to school nearby. In principle, villages with relatively concentrated populations should set up village primary schools or teaching points. Sparsely populated, Teaching points should be reserved or set up in remote and inaccessible places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the aforementioned training for teachers of small rural schools, several principals from Henan once again strongly called for an end to the one-size-fits-all approach to withdrawing and merging schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After conducting grassroots research, Liu Shanhuai found that in practice, whether to withdraw and merge small schools faces conflicts among many parties, and &quot;there is no best choice.&quot; Education department staff reported to him that the original withdrawal of schools was due to the consideration of integrating educational resources. Criticisms emerged after the merger, arguing that students have to travel further to school and that the cost of education for families has increased. But now many small schools have been retained, and there are different opinions that students do not develop as well as in county schools and township central schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Shanhuai said that in the face of this conflict, there is currently a lack of scientific standards. He suggested comprehensively considering various factors such as the comprehensive development of students, education costs and educational equity, and issuing operational guidelines at the national level to provide reference for various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广西通报“中学小卖部一年经营权卖224万元”：已中止合同，今后不再对外承包]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256607]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In response to the issues related to the contracting of the canteen operation rights by Hezhou No. 5 Senior High School that netizens are concerned about, Pinggui District United The investigation team conducted an in-depth investigation and now reports the relevant situation as follows:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After investigation, the procedures for outsourcing the operation rights of the canteen of Hezhou No. 5 Senior High School did not comply with relevant regulations, and both parties have terminated contract. From now on, the school’s canteen will no longer be contracted and operated by external parties. We will strictly hold relevant responsible units and responsible persons accountable in accordance with laws and regulations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Thank you to the vast number of netizens for their concern, supervision and support for our work! &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Hezhou City Pinggui District People&#39;s Government Office&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span>;September 13, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刑事二审开庭难有望缓解：“两高两部” 专项促改]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256609]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The low rate of second instance hearings in criminal cases is expected to change. On the morning of September 12, 2023, Mao Lixin, a lawyer at Beijing Shangquan Law Firm, noticed a piece of news: the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the Ministry of Public Security, and the Ministry of Justice jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Carrying out Special Work to Promote the Increase in the Rate of Second Instance Trials in Criminal Cases&quot; 》, this work has been carried out since September 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the requirements of the notice, it is necessary to improve the overall low rate of second-instance hearings of criminal cases, promote the establishment of a regular mechanism to increase the rate of second-instance hearings of criminal cases, and give full play to the importance of court trials in ascertaining facts and identifying evidence. effect. The &quot;two highs and two ministries&quot; will carry out a one-year special work to promote the increase in the rate of second instance hearings of criminal cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is a great benefit for lawyers.” Mao Lixin sighed. Five months ago, he participated in a seminar on the difficulties of opening a second trial. At the meeting, he said that except for the cases he represented in the first instance, he basically did not take on criminal second-instance cases. &quot;If there is no trial, there is very little room for lawyers to perform.&quot; This statement resonated with the lawyers present. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mao Lixin plans to start acting as an agent in second-instance criminal cases if the difficulty of opening a second-instance trial cannot be alleviated. &quot;At least I will have a starting point for my work.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/NT944p2PXwAmylBUIwd2Dp1SLgMdA2liQC4Aqe5T.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;865&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/NT944p2PXwAmylBUIwd2Dp1SLgMdA2liQC4Aqe5T.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250674&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 19, 2023, the second trial of the &quot;Wu Xieyu Patricide Case&quot; opened. On that day, citizens passed by the electronic bulletin board of the Fuzhou Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The court opening rate in some places has increased by 75%&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;The low rate of criminal second instance hearings has become a common feeling among lawyers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The book &quot;40 Years of China&#39;s Criminal Procedure Legal System&quot; edited by Sun Changyong, chair professor of Kaiyuan Law School of Shanghai Jiao Tong University, provides data support for this: In 2013, the rate of criminal second instance hearings exceeded 40%, and in 2014 From 2016 to 2016, it basically remained between 30% and 40%. However, since 2017, this figure has dropped below 20%, showing an overall downward trend year by year. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The COVID-19 epidemic has also affected the rate of second instance hearings to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2022, the Henan Provincial High Court issued a reply to the proposal of the Provincial Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference. It mentioned that local courts usually give priority to ensuring the hearing needs of first-instance cases and death penalty, suspended death, and second-instance protest cases. The court hearing resources of other second-instance cases have been squeezed out, and the second-instance hearing rate in some prefectures and cities has dropped by nearly 10% compared with before the epidemic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Southern Weekend reporters noticed that since 2023, before the issuance of the above notice, the local court has begun to explore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to public reports, on February 14, 2023, Hao Zhuo, deputy director of the Fourth Criminal Division of the Henan Provincial High Court, went to Pingdingshan Intermediate Court to investigate the situation of the second criminal trial; on March 8, Hao Zhuo et al. People also went to Puyang Intermediate People&#39;s Court to conduct special research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the investigation, Hao Zhuo mentioned that the work of increasing the rate of second instance hearings is based on the work arrangements made by the Central Committee and the Supreme People&#39;s Court on the reform of the criminal litigation system. &quot;The court session is an exception&quot; principle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 25, 2023, the Xuchang Intermediate Court of Henan Province published an article, which mentioned that the Xuchang Intermediate People’s Court and the Xuchang Procuratorate jointly signed an &quot;Opinions on Increasing the Hearing Rate of Criminal Second Instance Cases&quot; 》. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data released by the Supreme People&#39;s Court, since 2023, as of August 31, the second-instance hearing rate of criminal cases in Henan, Shaanxi, and Hunan courts has increased by more than 75% year-on-year, and the rate of second-instance hearings in Fujian, Chongqing, and Heilongjiang courts has increased by more than 75% year-on-year. 50%, and the courts of Beijing, Jiangsu, Zhejiang, Gansu, and Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps increased by more than 10% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The &quot;change rate&quot; is low, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;the actual effect remains to be seen&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This notice points out that investigation and research must be carried out. Analyze various reasons that affect the low rate of second-instance hearings, take effective measures to reduce the adverse factors that affect the second-instance hearing rate, and ensure that the rate of second-instance hearings increases steadily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2020, the Jinhua Intermediate People&#39;s Court admitted in response to the suggestion of a National People&#39;s Congress deputy that the reason for the decline in the rate of criminal second instance hearings is that the number of defendant cases has increased significantly in recent years. It is difficult for police personnel to meet the needs of court sessions; prosecutors cannot meet the needs of second-instance criminal trials; and post judges are under heavy pressure to open trials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tian Yuan, associate professor at Tianjin University Law School, has been engaged in trial work in grassroots, intermediate and above courts for more than ten years. He also found in his research that, faced with increasingly heavy case-handling pressure, second-instance judges tend to make the choice not to hold court sessions. When hearing criminal cases of second instance, a collegial panel should be formed, and the number of second-instance judges is relatively limited. In order to form a collegial panel, one has to frequently go to the civil court, commercial court, or administrative court to &quot;recruit reinforcements.&quot; Naturally, the effect of the case hearing and subsequent collegial proceedings will be greatly reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Yi, dean of the Law School of Minzu University of China, has also previously written an article calling for the second instance of criminal cases to be heard. After seeing the notice jointly issued by the four departments, he believed that the statements contained in it are relatively principled, and specific details still need to be issued on how to implement it in practice. For example, Han Yi believes that there needs to be supporting policies to follow up on the allocation of judges. In addition, in practice, &quot;the circumstances under which a second instance hearing must be held and under which circumstances do not require a hearing need to be further refined, which will also be more conducive to implementation by the grassroots courts.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some lawyers also believe that given the low rate of criminal cases being revised and remanded for retrial (referred to as the &quot;reissue rate&quot;), it remains to be seen what the actual effect of the second instance hearing will be. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data released by the Supreme People&#39;s Court, in the first half of 2023, the rate of change of first-instance criminal judgments in courts across the country was 1.65%, a year-on-year decrease of 0.22 percentage points. This means that among 100 criminal cases, the average number of cases whose sentences were changed after the first instance was less than 2. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 15, 2023, &quot;Ban Yue Tan&quot; published a report, pointing out that for a long time, courts in various places have used the low reissue rate of cases as an important indicator to evaluate the quality of cases handled by courts and judges, prompting the second-instance courts to Cautious changes to judgments and strict remands lead to &quot;not changing the sentences that should be changed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If we don’t increase the rate of reform, the value of supervision and check in the second instance will still not be realized.” Han Yi also believes that the issuance of this notice is worthy of praise. At the same time, the policy should also be paid attention to in subsequent practice. Whether the implementation is effective. In addition to the low reissue rate, Han Yi also mentioned that attention should be paid to avoid blindly focusing on increasing the second-instance hearing rate. “This may cause the second-instance court to choose to hear some relatively simple cases, while choosing to hear major and complex cases. No court session.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从初代网红到二次出狱：郭美美曾说“不想以这种方式出名”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256605]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Slowly understand the world and slowly update yourself.&quot; On September 12, Guo, who has been silent for nearly three years, Meimei updated her personal social media account to show that she may be released from prison again. On the same day, Guo Meimei confirmed the matter to reporters from Nandu and N Video, saying that everything was fine now and she wanted to &quot;rest for a while first.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to the social platform, she disbanded the fan group she formed. The million-fan account she created after her first release from prison now only has 6 Weibo posts left to view. Prior to this, Guo Meimei&#39;s last appearance was at a public court hearing in August 2021. In October of the same year, she was sentenced for selling poisonous and harmful food. This was the second time she was sentenced in a criminal case. She was sentenced to five years in prison for opening a casino and was released in July 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twelve years ago, a modification of the authentication information made Guo Meimei become the first generation Internet celebrity, and she became famous for a while. At that time, Guo Meimei admitted in an interview with a reporter from Nandu that she had the desire to be famous, but &quot;don&#39;t want to be famous in this way.&quot; However, for more than ten years, words such as &quot;showing off wealth&quot;, &quot;going to jail&quot;, &quot;gambling&quot; and &quot;selling fake medicine&quot; have gradually become entangled with her name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/116df681e74128d4a9bca29fbe552420.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;437&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/116df681e74128d4a9bca29fbe552420.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250672&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 12, Guo Meimei’s personal social account was updated after being discontinued for nearly three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Jailed for the second time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 12, Guo Meimei’s personal social account, which has been disconnected for nearly three years, posted a new message - &quot;Slowly understand the world, slowly Update yourself slowly”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After announcing her return on social platforms, Guo Meimei’s first move was to disband her fan group. She once generously shared her updates in the fan group, and some fans said, &quot;We have been in the group for all these years, and then we disbanded the group.&quot; Regarding this, she explained, &quot;I had some ideas of my own, so I disbanded.&quot; Guo Meimei also told Nandu reporters that everything is fine now and she wants to &quot;rest for a while first.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Meimei’s last Weibo update was in December 2020, and her last public appearance was at a public trial two years ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 13, 2021, the first instance trial of Guo Meimei and others suspected of producing and selling toxic and harmful food was held in the Shanghai Railway Transport Court. Screenshots of the court hearing showed that the defendants Guo Meimei and Wang Zouya were brought into the court by bailiffs wearing protective clothing. During the statement stage, Guo Meimei shed tears and confessed. In the end, she wiped her tears with her hands and was taken away by the bailiff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/482c73cce6e1a98a05c40064770e39c3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/482c73cce6e1a98a05c40064770e39c3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250671&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The court hearing scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 18, the Shanghai Railway Transport Court publicly pronounced its verdict on the case of Guo Meimei and Wang Zouya selling toxic and harmful food in accordance with the law. Guo Meimei was sentenced to two years and six years in prison for selling toxic and harmful food. months and a fine of RMB 200,000; Wang Zouya was sentenced to seven months in prison and fined RMB 10,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Meimei’s “second entry into the palace” can be traced back to 2020 at the earliest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Guo Meimei was running a newly opened social account &quot;Guo Meimei May Work Hard&quot; after she was released from prison for the first time. It attracted the attention of more than one million fans in just over a year. She sells goods through multiple channels by building a fan group and diverting traffic from Weibo to WeChat. &quot;Slimming&quot; is a word that often appears on her Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Meimei’s high-profile actions attracted attention. In December 2020, the Economic Investigation Detachment of Shanghai Pudong Public Security Bureau received a clue that someone was selling fake weight loss pills online. The manufacturing and sales den promotes its products through online advertisements to attract beauty-loving women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a report from the Shanghai police, on March 11, 2021, the Pudong police successfully detected a case of producing and selling weight-loss foods with banned ingredients (sibutramine), and arrested the production worker Guo Moumou (female, 30 years old) and other 32 criminal suspects have been detained in accordance with the law. Nandu reporters confirmed from authoritative sources close to the Shanghai police that the 30-year-old Guo Moumou involved in the report was none other than Guo Meimei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public prosecution agency accused Guo Meimei and Wang Zouya of knowingly knowing that the slimming candies sold at the premises of their previous owner Zhao (handled in a separate case) may illegally contain sibutramine since January and February 2021 respectively. Even under such circumstances, they are still sold at unit prices of 699 yuan per box. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Up to the time of the incident, Guo Meimei had sold more than 100 boxes of slimming candies and received more than 70,000 yuan in payment. During this period, Guo Meimei also helped Wang Zouya order and pay Zhao, and jointly sold 4 boxes of slimming candies, receiving RMB 2,796. After the incident, the public security organs detected sibutramine in the diet candy seized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the first-instance trial, a relevant person from the prosecution revealed to Nandu reporters that before the trial, Guo Meimei had signed a confession of guilt and punishment. However, during the trial, Guo Meimei defended whether she “subjectively and knowingly” knew that the weight loss pills sold contained sibutramine. &quot;Whether this behavior constitutes &#39;repentance&#39; and whether it will be considered as a sentencing circumstance needs to be determined by the judge.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;First arrest&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When Guo Meimei was detained by Pudong police in accordance with the law, she was She was released from prison in Changsha only 607 days ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2014, Guo Meimei and others were criminally detained by the Dongcheng Branch of the Beijing Municipal Public Security Bureau on suspicion of gambling crimes. After investigation, Guo Meimei confessed to the illegal and criminal facts of participating in gambling and organizing gambling during the World Cup football match, and also confessed to the criminal facts of long-term participation in gambling activities and opening gambling bureaus for making huge profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long-term gambling began in 2010, long before the &quot;Guo Meimei incident&quot; that made it famous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The police found that between 2010 and 2014, Guo Meimei traveled to and from Macau, Hong Kong and surrounding countries for gambling more than 60 times. At the end of 2012, Guo Meimei met Kang, a foreign professional Texas Hold&#39;em gambler, at a Macau casino. The two soon developed into lovers and lived together in Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, Guo Meimei changed from gambling to gambling. In February of the same year, Guo Meimei and Kang planned to open a casino in Beijing. Their life assistant Lu Moumou came forward to rent a house in the west tower of Beijing Mansion in Chaoyang District at a monthly rent of 19,000 yuan for the gambling establishment. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After setting up the venue, Guo Meimei and Kang purchased gaming tables, chips, and POS machines, and invited dealers. Later, Guo Meimei personally called her friends to invite her to gamble. The first time, Guo Meimei invited 6 people, and she made a profit of 70,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Meimei was not satisfied with this. Her assistant at the time, Lu Moumou, once revealed that Guo Meimei felt that it was inadequate and said, &quot;A woman still has to be in charge. Next time I will set up the card game myself.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, Guo Meimei hired a professional dealer every time, found someone to be responsible for settling gambling funds, and called or sent WeChat messages to invite &quot;friends&quot; to come and gamble. She herself took 3% to 5%. Rebate points are used as &quot;water money&quot;. According to verification by the Beijing police, the amount of money Guo Meimei opened in each gambling game was more than one million yuan, and she personally made hundreds of thousands of yuan in illegal profits through &quot;extracting money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2014, the 20th World Cup opened. On July 9, Beijing police busted a criminal gang that organized gambling during the World Cup and arrested eight gang members. The gang opened accounts on overseas gambling websites, placed bets through phone calls, WeChat and other forms, and carried out illegal and criminal activities in sports betting. Guo Meimei is one of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/5d97ac8fe5e01fc678810ad328c66a6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;690&quot; height= &quot;460&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/5d97ac8fe5e01fc678810ad328c66a6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250670&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The court hearing scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 10, 2015, the case of Guo Meimei suspected of opening a casino was publicly heard in Beijing Dongcheng Court. The criminal verdict of the case showed that the defendant Guo Meimei (formerly known as Guo Meiling) was sentenced to five years in prison and fined RMB 50,000 for opening a casino with a gambling capital of more than 2 million yuan. His sentence is from July 14, 2014 to July 13, 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The first generation of Internet celebrities&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Nandu reporters have verified from multiple cross-source sources that Guo Meimei has been serving her sentence in Changsha Women’s Prison and has not received a commutation during her sentence. After serving 1,825 days in prison, Guo Meimei was released from prison on July 13, 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, a recent photo of Guo Meimei after she was released from prison was exposed. In the photo, Guo Meimei is wearing a peaked cap and light makeup, but her figure is no longer slender and her face is swollen. She admitted that after she was released from prison, she found herself out of touch with society and gained twenty pounds due to hyperthyroidism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Guo Meimei was not depressed by this. As a former &quot;Internet celebrity&quot;, Guo Meimei&#39;s ability to use the Internet was once again demonstrated. Soon after she was released from prison, she actively tried online platforms such as Weibo, live broadcasts, and short videos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She attributed this to her &quot;survival instincts that were honed&quot; during her five years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Meimei once said in an interview that she did not sleep a wink for two days and two nights after she was released from prison. She has been receiving a large number of messages online. In about a month, she figured out what the most popular software is and how to use it. use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After only more than 2 months of silence, Guo Meimei opened a Weibo account &quot;Guo Meimei May Work Hard&quot; and returned to the public eye. On September 30, 2019, she posted her first Weibo post saying, &quot;I am working hard to transform, learn more knowledge and talents, and then refine myself!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, she also posted A selfie taken while sitting in a car. Her hair has been cut short and dyed, and her makeup is exquisite. The photo is also tagged &quot;Guo Meimei&#39;s comeback.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, luxury goods, luxury cars, star-rated hotels and other &quot;standard equipment&quot; that show wealth have once again appeared on Guo Meimei&#39;s Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2020, she posted a video of looking at cars, saying, &quot;I plan to order a convertible Bentley. You should spend money when you are young. If you save money, you will not be able to take it with you even if you die.&quot;; In November 2020, She also posted a house viewing video, saying, &quot;I accidentally bought a new house when I came to Changsha to perform. I paid for it after watching it in the afternoon.&quot; In February 2021, she posted a pink Rolls-Royce on Weibo, saying It’s “Give yourself a New Year’s gift.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Meimei once said in an exclusive interview with a reporter from Nandu that she is indeed somewhat vain and likes to show off expensive things. But she insisted that her target was not all ordinary people, but fans on Weibo. “Just like good sisters, I am just sharing my daily life.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2019, only two months after her comeback, she created a fan group on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2020, she replied to netizens in a Weibo comment saying that she was an e-commerce company selling &quot;clothes and facial masks.&quot; After experiencing the ups and downs of &quot;entrepreneurship&quot; such as her live broadcast account being blocked and her online clothing store closed due to poor operation, Guo Meimei found a more effective &quot;wealth password&quot;, which is to use Weibo to divert traffic to WeChat to sell goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She actively &quot;does business&quot; on Weibo, posting a large number of photos of herself, and has appeared in the comment area many times to ask netizens to add her assistant&#39;s WeChat account, &quot;My daily outfits are all for sale.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Meimei&#39;s ability to create hot topics can be seen from the first selfie posted at the beginning of her comeback with the label &quot;Guo Meimei Comeback&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under that photo, the most liked comment was &quot;I got plastic surgery as soon as I got out of prison, it&#39;s amazing.&quot; Later, she also generously admitted that she had &quot;had a nose done&quot;. Because she was not satisfied with the results, she took out the prosthesis and adjusted it. She also posted on Weibo the experience of undergoing &quot;rib nose surgery&quot; and the brand name of the plastic surgery hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, the plastic surgery hospital officially became her &quot;partner&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Only one and a half years after Weibo was launched, the number of fans of the &quot;Guo Mei May Hard Work&quot; account has exceeded one million. In addition to posting her WeChat account in her introduction, saying &quot;Performance, weight loss + VX&quot;, she also posted on Weibo many times to promote her WeChat account, declaring, &quot;If you want to become beautiful, come to me&quot; and &quot;If you want to make money, come to me.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/2f0fae35a5347bb78c6658640367eafa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/2f0fae35a5347bb78c6658640367eafa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250673&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Guo Meimei has promoted her WeChat account on Weibo many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Desire to be famous&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned WeChat account is called &quot;Guo Meimei Work Account&quot;, and the circle of friends contains a lot of content promoting medical cosmetic surgery and selling slimming candies. A screenshot of a chat with a &quot;customer&quot; claimed that he &quot;lost seven or eight pounds&quot; after eating a box. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The details of the case disclosed by the Shanghai police show that the manufacturing and sales den where Guo Meimei is located is promoted by posting advertisements online to attract beauty-loving women. The banned ingredient &quot;sibutramine&quot; is added to this weight-loss drug. Although it has a weight-loss effect, it can cause harm to the body. The amount involved in the case exceeded 50 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the account &quot;Guo Mei May works hard&quot; only has 6 Weibo posts left to view. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twelve years ago, a change in authentication information brought the Weibo account &quot;Guo Meimei Baby&quot; into the public eye. On June 20, 2011, Guo Meimei, whose certification information is &quot;Commercial General Manager of the Red Cross Society of China&quot;, showed off her luxurious life on Weibo, claiming to &quot;live in a big villa and drive a Maserati&quot;, causing an uproar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Red Cross Society of China clarified that there is no &quot;Red Cross Chamber of Commerce&quot; organization, let alone &quot;Guo Meimei&quot;, but doubts still arise one after another. Affected by this, one month after the incident, the charitable donations received by the Red Cross societies across China dropped sharply, and their credibility was questioned. Other official charities were also implicated. The amount of donations received by charitable organizations dropped by 86% from June to August. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 4, 2011, Guo Meimei apologized in tears on a TV show, saying that she certified the &quot;Commercial General Manager of the Red Cross Society of China&quot; out of vanity and comparison mentality, and emphasized that everything had nothing to do with the Red Cross Society. . However, a charity trust storm has formed, and a round of discussion on charity system reform has arisen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with a Nandu reporter in the same year, Guo Meimei said that before the incident happened, she &quot;didn&#39;t know much about charity&quot;. She only heard about &quot;godfather&quot; Wang Jun at a dinner in March and April. The name &quot;Commercial General Manager of the Red Cross Society of China&quot; was mentioned. One afternoon in April, Guo Meimei saw the Weibo posts of friends she followed. The certification information said president and general manager, “But I know there are a few people who are not. One of them, a classmate in our class, just took 100,000 yuan to register. A company name became CEO, so I simply changed it to &#39;Commercial General Manager of the Red Cross Society of China&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Meimei once studied at a performance academy. She said that she particularly likes performing. I once had a dream about the industry. She also admitted to Nandu reporters that she has a desire to be famous. &quot;Everyone who studies acting or art doesn&#39;t want to be famous.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after the &quot;Guo Meimei Incident&quot; happened, she cried and said that she would rather turn back time, hoping that she had not changed that certification and not used this &quot;I don&#39;t like this way of becoming famous.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said that after thinking about it, she could understand why it caused an uproar, and she was particularly afraid of saying the wrong thing. She also felt sorry for the Red Cross and the people. In the interview, Guo Meimei also explained her definition of success to Nandu reporters: &quot;My ideal is to find someone who I love very much and who loves me very much, and do some business in a down-to-earth manner.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;At that time, Guo Meimei also talked about her dream of a happy life - &quot;Open a restaurant, jewelry store or something. Just live a happy life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other side, she But he stepped into the abyss of gambling and was imprisoned less than three years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被严重低估的流感]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256591]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Every year in autumn, as the temperature drops and the light decreases, while people enjoy the change of seasons, their bodies are exposed to Resistance to infectious diseases also decreases. Influenza, this familiar “old friend” will also arrive as scheduled. Most people don&#39;t think of the flu as a serious illness. The typical symptoms of a sore throat, runny nose, and muscle aches are often the same as a bad cold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the COVID-19 epidemic, influenza was the first infectious disease to be monitored globally by the World Health Organization (WHO). According to WHO statistics, seasonal influenza kills 290,000 to 650,000 people every year. Part of the reason why influenza is so destructive is that the virus mutates quickly, and people who have been infected with influenza viruses in the past cannot develop defenses against new viruses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In our country, influenza is a seriously underestimated infectious disease. A large number of people are infected with influenza every year, and the health risks and disease burden it brings are far greater than imagined. A meta-analysis by scholars on the results of influenza epidemiological surveys conducted in different cities in my country in different years concluded that the annual number of influenza cases in China from 2011 to 2019 was approximately 84 million to 144 million. From the 2010-2011 to 2014-2015 epidemic season, there were an average of 88,000 excess deaths from influenza-related respiratory diseases in my country every year, of which 80% of the excess influenza-related deaths among the elderly over 60 years old accounted for the entire population. The risk of illness in children is about 1.5-3 times that of adults; pregnant women infected with influenza during pregnancy increase the risk of severe illness and stillbirth. A systematic review analyzed the economic burden caused by influenza in my country. Among them, outpatient cases in all age groups were 768-1,000 yuan/person, inpatient cases averaged 9,832 yuan/person, and direct medical care for children 5 years old and under and elderly people over 60 years old for inpatient cases. The cost is much higher than other groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike many new infectious diseases, influenza scientists are already very familiar with it. The World Health Organization updates the antigenic components of influenza vaccines every year based on global surveillance and provides candidate strains for vaccine preparation. , for industry to develop the latest influenza vaccines. Although the mutation of new strains causes fluctuations in the effectiveness of influenza vaccines, vaccination is still the most cost-effective way to prevent influenza and complications. WHO recommends that countries set vaccination rate targets for recommended vaccination groups such as the elderly. 75%. In my country, the influenza vaccination rate is only 2%-4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The status of influenza vaccination in my country is very unsatisfactory.” Peng Zhibin, associate researcher at the Infectious Disease Management Division of the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, disclosed at the 2022 National Vaccine and Health Conference that during the 2021~2022 influenza season, vaccines The vaccination rate was only 2.46%, a year-on-year decrease. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the vaccination rate is too low, the annual scrap rate of corporate influenza vaccines is as high as 20%-40%. How to improve the vaccination rate of influenza vaccine in my country and protect the public health has been a difficult problem that has long troubled public health researchers. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Three major factors&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, the team of Professor Feng Luzhao, deputy dean of the School of Group Medicine and Public Health of the Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, conducted a study on influenza vaccination in my country. The current situation and problems are summarized, and a series of strategic suggestions are put forward to promote influenza vaccination in my country. This article was published on September 12, 2023 as the output of the &quot;Vaccine Delivery Research Innovation Laboratory&quot; project at Duke Kunshan University . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What factors influence the low influenza vaccination rate? Professor Feng Luzhao’s research pointed out that three factors affect my country’s influenza vaccination rate:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, vaccine hesitancy caused by cognitive misunderstandings about influenza viruses and influenza vaccines. The survey shows that &quot;thinking that you are in good health and do not need to get a flu vaccine&quot; and &quot;even if you get the flu will not cause serious consequences&quot; are the main reasons for people&#39;s flu vaccine hesitancy; more than 40% of public health personnel believe that the flu will not cause serious consequences. disease, 18% of public health workers and 45% of medical workers said they lacked confidence in answering questions about influenza vaccines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, the cost is closely related to the influenza vaccination rate. In my country, the influenza vaccine is a non-immunization program vaccine and needs to be vaccinated at your own expense. In recent years, some provinces and cities have included influenza vaccines as local free services, which has greatly increased the vaccination rate in some areas. According to a survey by the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, the vaccination rate of people in areas with free influenza vaccination can exceed 50%, and the medical insurance reimbursement policy can also increase the vaccination rate to a certain extent, while the vaccination rate of self-paying people is only 1.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Third, the current vaccination system does not match actual needs. It is the best time to vaccinate against influenza before the epidemic season. my country’s annual vaccination work is concentrated between September and December. At present, influenza vaccination services mainly rely on vaccination clinics of the children&#39;s immunization program. Most vaccination sites only provide influenza vaccination for 1-2 half days on working days, which is not suitable for the annual concentrated vaccination demand. From the perspective of vaccination services, demand exceeds supply and it is difficult to make appointments for vaccination services, resulting in poor accessibility and convenience. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Others&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The 1918 influenza pandemic struck with almost unimaginable intensity and speed - infecting one-third of the Earth&#39;s population One (about 500 million people). Since then, all countries have been actively establishing public health systems to prevent influenza and exploring effective promotion measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Getting people to take the initiative to get vaccinated is the top priority of public health actions in all countries. As of 2021, 65% of WHO member states (128 countries and regions) have included influenza vaccination for high-risk groups such as the elderly and medical staff in national immunization plans or public health projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Feng Luzhao was a member of the WHO Advisory Committee on Immunization (SAGE) Influenza Vaccine Working Group and currently serves as an expert on the WHO New Influenza Vaccine Comprehensive Value Assessment Advisory Group. He studied influenza vaccination promotion strategies in many countries and found that many countries have rich experience in policy advocacy, improving vaccination accessibility, motivating vaccination service providers, and monitoring influenza vaccination behaviors and social drivers. The successful experience of the intervention measures effectively increased the influenza vaccination rate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Research found that many countries have included influenza vaccines in national immunization plans or introduced compulsory vaccination strategies. For example, in order to reduce the risk of infection among medical workers and patients, the health administration departments of the United States and Canada require medical workers and nursing home staff to receive influenza vaccines compulsorily. Secondly, we should vigorously increase the number and convenience of vaccination service points. In North America and European countries, influenza vaccination points have covered pharmacies, supermarkets, private clinics, hospitals and other places. Implementing incentive policies for service providers is also an effective means. The United States, the United Kingdom, Australia, etc. use the influenza vaccination rate of key groups as a performance evaluation indicator for medical personnel. The United Kingdom provides general practitioners with influenza-related educational materials and implements a performance incentive strategy to encourage medical staff to achieve the established influenza vaccination rate target and provide financial or material incentives to promote medical staff to vaccinate and recommend influenza vaccines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, some innovative incentives can also increase the willingness of medical staff to be vaccinated. In 2017, institutions such as Birmingham Children&#39;s Hospital in the UK implemented a vaccination campaign. When a medical staff completed the influenza vaccination, Medical institutions will donate 10 tetanus vaccines to children or mothers in developing countries through UNICEF. This measure has enabled the influenza vaccination rate of medical staff in these institutions to reach 95.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the procurement challenges caused by the uncertainty of demand for influenza vaccines and the diversity of strains, the &quot;Vaccine Delivery Research Innovation Laboratory&quot; once summarized the experience of developed countries and found that through quantity commitments during the procurement process, etc. The method of linking quantity and price is often conducive to lowering prices. For example, the UK allows manufacturers to give different quotations based on different purchase quantities during the bidding process (often the larger the purchase quantity, the lower the price), thereby effectively utilizing economies of scale and reducing manufacturer risks. The Canadian government will require each province or region to estimate its demand before awarding contracts to manufacturers, and requires each province or region to purchase at least 75% of its estimated amount, thus forming a quantity guarantee for manufacturers. At the same time, the government uses long-term contracts to reduce manufacturers&#39; risks, lower the price of vaccine procurement and increase the stability of vaccine supply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the public, extensive scientific and educational propaganda is also indispensable. The status of influenza vaccination in 15 European countries reminds that government departments&#39; monitoring of influenza vaccination rates and sending text message reminders for free vaccination are important factors in promoting vaccination among target groups. The United States, through media propaganda, not only increased the influenza vaccination rate among the elderly by 8%, but also advanced the vaccination time by 1.8-4.1 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These state-led measures have achieved remarkable results. Taking the elderly as an example, Brazil’s vaccination rate is as high as 89%; the UK’s vaccination rate for people over 65 years old has remained above 70% since 2004; the United States has maintained a vaccination rate of more than 70% for many years. Maintained above 60%; Canada, Spain, and New Zealand are about 60%-70%, and France, Australia, and Japan are about 50%-60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Strategic Recommendations&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Influenza vaccination can significantly reduce the risk of influenza and complications, and effectively reduce the number of outpatient and emergency visits, hospitalizations and deaths from influenza-related diseases. , the cost-effectiveness is very obvious. Since 2020, scientists have monitored and found that influenza and the new coronavirus are showing an alternating epidemic trend. Multiple studies have confirmed that co-infection with the new coronavirus and influenza virus will increase the risk of hospitalization and complicate the patient&#39;s condition. For years, scientists have emphasized the importance of influenza vaccination, but increasing vaccination rates remains difficult. In view of the low influenza vaccination rate in my country, Professor Feng Luzhao&#39;s team put forward the following strategic suggestions for policy makers to refer to:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Vaccine hesitancy has left many groups who should have received influenza vaccines in a &quot;streaking&quot; state. &quot;Health education should identify effective ways to target the public&#39;s misunderstandings about influenza and vaccines, especially for the elderly, primary and secondary school students and other groups covered by free programs, study the influencing factors of vaccination and effective intervention measures, and carry out precise publicity and science popularization .&quot; In the view of Professor Feng Luzhao, all localities should actively improve the public&#39;s understanding of influenza and enhance vaccine confidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For key groups, the study recommends gradually promoting free influenza vaccination for the elderly, primary and secondary school students, medical staff, etc., and striving to include influenza vaccination within the payment scope of basic medical insurance. They also encourage medical institutions at all levels to set up adult vaccination clinics, continuously strengthen the public health and prevention responsibilities of medical staff through continuing education, vocational training, etc., explore the right of medical staff to prescribe vaccines, and incorporate vaccination work into the evaluation system of medical institutions. Increase the enthusiasm of medical staff in recommending influenza vaccination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in view of the high scrap rate of influenza vaccines every year, we can learn from international experience and sign long-term (such as not less than five years) contracts for influenza vaccines with enterprises, purchase in quantities, and ensure supply based on quantities. , not only can share market risks, but also ensure the stable growth of enterprise production capacity. Avoid the situation of annual production and large amounts of scrapping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People don’t know when we will encounter another influenza pandemic, but it cannot be ruled out that it will happen again. As the WHO says: At the heart of an effective pandemic response is a strong, well-resourced health system. These include well-trained health workers; effective water, sanitation and hygiene systems; quality rapid diagnostic laboratory services; access to medical products, including vaccines; and reliable systems for tracking and reporting disease cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, the US Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices (ACIP) updated the 2023-2024 influenza vaccine ingredient changes and vaccination recommendations, reminding the public that it is best to get vaccinated in September or October. In China, the 2023-2024 batch of influenza vaccines have arrived in various places and are open for reservation. According to the CDC surveillance data, the positive rate of influenza virus testing in some southern provinces has been rising slightly since the end of July. For individuals, facing the seasonal epidemic of influenza, proactive protection and vaccination to minimize the harm of the virus are practical choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[店员控住偷窃女子：这不是执法权而是公民扭送权丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256574]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a netizen shot and uploaded a video:&amp;nbsp;On September 7, in Joy City, Xidan, Beijing, A woman was caught shoplifting in a cosmetics store. Two men (presumably both clerks) grabbed her arms and controlled her. The woman struggled hard and tried to escape and shouted &quot;Help&quot;. When a man called the police as if to call the police, the woman Once she broke away, the second man immediately hugged the woman&#39;s waist. At this time, an aunt who was watching stood up and asked, and the second man replied &quot;thief&quot;. The aunt yelled, &quot;Thieves are human beings too.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On social media platforms, many netizens believe that store clerks or security guards have the right to catch thieves, but aunts are not alone. There are also voices on the Internet that &quot;security guards or store clerks have no law enforcement power and have no right to restrict women&#39;s personal freedom.&quot; For example, some netizens said: &quot;Auntie is right. Although thieves are hateful, these two men are not law enforcement officers. There should be boundaries in their behavior. The behavior seen so far can easily cross the boundary and get themselves into trouble.&quot; This is a very representative point of view, so it deserves analysis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, it is correct that only law enforcement officers authorized by law have the power to enforce the law, but it does not mean that ordinary people have no right to defend their natural rights such as life, property and freedom. Going back to the above case, if these two men are the owners of the store, they are blameless in protecting their property; if they are not the owners, as employees (clerks or security guards) of the store and shopping mall, their duty is to protect the store. Or the goods in the shopping mall are protected from theft, which means that the owner of the goods authorizes them to protect the safety of the property. The cosmetics sold in such stores in shopping malls are generally expensive. If the store staff neglects to take precautions and protection, or just sit back and do nothing when they see someone stealing goods, then they will not only be derelict in their responsibility, but may also be required to bear the cost of the goods. loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people may say that if you see someone stealing cosmetics, just let them keep the cosmetics and then let them go. Why not forgive them? If you do this in a single incident, it seems that the store or shopping mall has no losses, but it undoubtedly creates an incentive: if you steal something from this store or shopping mall, as long as you are not caught, it is yours; if you are caught, it will only be yours. By leaving something behind, the individual can escape unscathed. The mathematical expectation of stealing is positive, which calls the thief to &quot;be stupid, have plenty of money, and come quickly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, store clerks, security guards or ordinary passers-by can control existing thieves, restrict their personal freedom, and either call the police and wait for the police to deal with them, or transfer them to the police. This is not the so-called &quot;law enforcement power&quot; , but the right of citizens to transfer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 84 of the current Criminal Procedure Law stipulates: Any citizen may immediately transfer a person to the public security organ, the People’s Procuratorate or the People’s Court for handling under the following circumstances: (1) While committing a crime or immediately after committing a crime Being discovered; (2) being wanted; (3) escaping from prison; (4) being hunted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, if the above-mentioned woman stole valuable cosmetics, she might fall into the first situation. Article 264 of the Criminal Law stipulates that whoever steals public or private property in a relatively large amount, or commits multiple thefts, burglaries, thefts with weapons, or pickpockets shall be sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of not more than three years, criminal detention, or surveillance, and shall also or solely be fined... …The &quot;Interpretation of Several Issues Concerning the Application of Laws in Handling Criminal Cases of Theft&quot; stipulates that theft of public and private property worth more than 1,000 yuan to 3,000 yuan shall be deemed as a &quot;large amount&quot; as stipulated in Article 264 of the Criminal Law, and also That is to say, the threshold for imprisonment is one thousand yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the case where the above-mentioned woman was caught stealing and suspected of a criminal offence, anyone can exercise the citizen&#39;s right to surrender. During the implementation process, the woman&#39;s personal freedom and freedom of movement will inevitably be restricted, which is also the proper meaning of the citizen&#39;s right to transfer. If a woman &quot;voluntarily&quot; goes to the public security organ or waits for the police to come to her door under the supervision and escort of everyone, the two clerks can certainly behave in a more polite manner, but no matter how &quot;gentle&quot; the clerk&#39;s behavior is, it is based on the fact that the woman&#39;s personal freedom has been temporarily suspended. based on restrictions. A woman is more &quot;gentle&quot; if she cooperates with the clerk, and less &quot;gentle&quot; if she doesn&#39;t cooperate with the clerk. In the final analysis, there is a certain reciprocal relationship between the actions of both parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, a store or shopping mall has the right to formulate and implement rules within its property scope, which is a manifestation of property rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, if the zoo requires visitors not to feed the animals, otherwise they may be asked out on the spot and blacklisted for refusing transactions. Shops or shopping malls require customers not to make loud noises or cause trouble and disrupt the peaceful shopping environment. Do not listen to the advice. You may be asked to leave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These situations also inevitably involve restrictions on customers’ freedom of movement or forced eviction, but this is not a “law enforcement power” but a manifestation of “property rights” because businesses only restrict “their freedom of movement”. The freedom of movement of customers who break the rules &quot;within the property&quot;, that is, refusing such customers to continue to stay &quot;within the property&quot; is like saying to someone who is causing trouble in your home, &quot;Please leave, you are not welcome in my home.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, businesses that restrict the personal freedom of criminals currently in the store or hand them over to the police for processing, or expel unwelcome customers are not exercising the so-called &quot;law enforcement power.&quot; Law enforcement power often involves restricting personal freedom and freedom of movement. However, when restricting the personal freedom and freedom of movement of others, it may be law enforcement officers exercising &quot;law enforcement power&quot;, it may be good citizens exercising their legitimate private rights, or it may be criminals. To commit a crime, as this article demonstrates, we must understand the essential difference between exercising legitimate private rights and committing a crime, and we cannot equate stopping a crime with committing a crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[4000万中央资金建3个民生项目，竟全烂尾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256566]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021071762841&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Focus Interview丨Why did three people&#39;s livelihood projects involving more than 40 million yuan of central funds all come to nothing?.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;&quot; data-url=&quot;http: //1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/9d66c4e85576678021071762841/fz8j2DawytoA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://12514345 07.vod2 .myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/9d66c4e85576678021071762841/fz8j2DawytoA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, in order to promote the development of local economic and social undertakings, the central finance department will Certain investment fund subsidies will be provided to qualified local government investment projects and enterprise investment projects, covering areas such as affordable housing construction, pollution control, energy conservation and carbon reduction. These funds have played a positive role in promoting local construction. However, during an interview in Changyuan City, Henan Province not long ago, the reporter learned that some local affordable housing supporting projects invested by the central government have become decorations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the contents of the &quot;2016 Central Budgetary Investment Plan for the Construction of Supporting Infrastructure for Indemnified Housing Projects in Henan Province&quot;, the projects included in Changyuan, Henan Province at that time included the Puguang community resettlement housing supporting project and the food company The three projects, including the resettlement housing supporting infrastructure project and the Weizhuang shantytown renovation project in Changyuan County, involve a total of more than 40 million yuan in central budget funds. Seven years have passed. How are these projects being implemented? Have they achieved the expected results? The reporter investigated these three projects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/2c5c8dbf497985a7c577e0e7238c94c5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/2c5c8dbf497985a7c577e0e7238c94c5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250499&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;We first came to Hepingli Community in Changyuan, where the supporting project of resettlement housing for food companies in the plan was implemented. According to the plan, three three-dimensional garages were built here using central funds as supporting facilities for the community. However, residents reported that the three-dimensional garage was indeed built, but it was not used at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/80800df64ecbf4c08126c36f5543cf27.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/80800df64ecbf4c08126c36f5543cf27.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250497&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;When I walked into this garage, it was full of dust and flying catkins, and there were no signs of a car parked on the ground. Some places have been damaged, and the circuits have not even been officially connected, and some corners have even become places where garbage is piled. The three-dimensional garage is a mechanical equipment system that can store and store a large number of vehicles, which can solve the problem of insufficient parking spaces on the ground. The built three-dimensional garage is idle and abandoned. What is the reason behind this? The reporter found the property owner of the community to learn about the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Liang Caiyun, manager of the Hepingli Community Property Company in Changyuan City, Henan Province:&lt;/strong>;“So far, the technical management rights have not been transferred to us.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/a5653e7091b5089187f435a828f6dc81.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/a5653e7091b5089187f435a828f6dc81.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250501&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This three-dimensional garage Who actually built it? After it is completed, why not hand it over to the property for use? The property manager said that these garages were applied for construction by the developers of the converted shed community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/495785deec4c3387618896218e02e6b3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/495785deec4c3387618896218e02e6b3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250496&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Changyuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Aoqi&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Head of Real Estate Development Company&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Fu Caiting&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt; /strong>;“Because there are not enough ground parking spaces, since there are government support policies, I applied for three-dimensional parking spaces.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The government support policy the person in charge mentioned is the central government’s special funds. The application materials at that time showed that in 2016, this community, which is the three-dimensional garage project of the food company&#39;s shantytown reconstruction and resettlement housing, and the property and sanitary housing were included in the central budget investment of Henan Province&#39;s affordable housing infrastructure, with an estimated investment of 5.42 million. Yuan. Why do good things come to an end? We found the construction company of the three-dimensional garage to learn about the situation. The person in charge of this company said that most of these three-dimensional garages are not easy to use in actual use. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/e72fa1c5560d65de11ba00bb418e132c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/e72fa1c5560d65de11ba00bb418e132c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250489&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhongyuan&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Aoqi&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Fu Sen, the person in charge of Industrial Co., Ltd.:&lt;/strong>;“It is special equipment and needs to be inspected every two years. Like an elevator, you need to sign up for a professional maintenance team every year. A parking space costs more than 100 yuan. If you keep investing in it, the owner will not spend money to buy this thing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems that when this type of product is actually used, Parking is difficult, has many restrictions, and incurs relatively high operating expenses. Market acceptance is very low, and garage manufacturers are obviously well aware of this. Is this situation clear to the city&#39;s Shanty Town Renovation Office, which is responsible for implementing this project? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/20359fe454dfac9ffdfcf811afdaed52.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/20359fe454dfac9ffdfcf811afdaed52.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250491&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;With the funds, three six-story three-dimensional garages with a capacity of 123 parking spaces were quickly built. The person in charge of the company undertaking the construction of the garage said that it is most appropriate to use special government funds to build a three-dimensional garage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/47aa3363e5e4ee66f308c75fec70618a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/47aa3363e5e4ee66f308c75fec70618a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250488&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Dong Peng, Director of the Shantytown Reconstruction Office of Changyuan City, Henan Province:&lt;/strong>; “If the garage is implemented, it will be beneficial to the people, the government, and individuals. The result will be beneficial to the people. They did not do it well, but they themselves benefited.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no doubt that Aoqi Industrial, the company that built the garage, became the biggest beneficiary of this project. According to the winning bid documents at the time, they won the bid at a price of 4.61 million yuan to build 123 parking spaces, with an average price of nearly 40,000 yuan per parking space. The reporter learned during the interview with Aoqi Industrial that even now, the market price they offer is only about 20,000 yuan per parking space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/a67f6eb37c23d88650bbcbd43ed3fb8c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/a67f6eb37c23d88650bbcbd43ed3fb8c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250492&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The market price is about 20,000 yuan. When the project in this community was implemented, the company won the bid at a price of nearly 40,000 yuan. The profit margin is really not small. Even so, why is the garage still not put into use normally? The reporter&#39;s investigation revealed that the reason behind this is not unrelated to the poor project management of the relevant departments. According to the bidding plan issued by the Changyuan City Shantytown Renovation Office at the time, the bidding content not only included the construction of the three-dimensional garage, but also clearly included &quot;the training, trial operation and delivery of installation and commissioning personnel.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cms-emer-res.cctvnews.cctv.com/image/3003/upload/15a347e52fa44d4aabaac9abe3a47192.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 0.5; &quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cms-emer-res.cctvnews.cctv.com/image/3003/upload/15a347e52fa44d4aabaac9abe3a47192.png&quot; data-key=&quot;media-1694567076243 -8&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only have they not been put into use, in fact, these three garages have not even been completed at the most basic level. The construction of these three garages with a total of 123 parking spaces was completed at the end of 2017. However, in June 2018, the garage builder received a demolition decision from the local planning bureau, requiring them to demolish one of them within 15 days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Deputy Director of the Natural Resources and Planning Bureau of Changyuan City, Henan Province&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Mao Yongxia&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;:&lt;/strong>; “Residents also reported it, saying that it affected the lighting , so he issued a demolition penalty decision, but the 15 days were not up, so he demolished it on his own.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the garage was demolished, the company did not find a place to rebuild it, but piled a pile of waste materials in the community. . However, this does not affect the relevant departments from allocating the remaining nearly one million yuan of project funds to the company in 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/9c6f911d1293bab50ccd767bf8547d2d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/9c6f911d1293bab50ccd767bf8547d2d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250490&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;The number of parking spaces is insufficient and has not been delivered for use, but the company has received all 4.66 million yuan in financial funds. In this way, no one will take care of the later trial operation, delivery operation and other issues. The problem of difficult parking in the community has not yet been solved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first project on the schedule ended up running out of funds and the garage became a decoration. What about the next project on the schedule? Let’s take a look at the Puguang community resettlement housing supporting project. The local government submitted an application to build a kindergarten, a clinic and other related facilities, and the central government allocated a total of more than 18 million yuan. However, the reporter walked around the community twice and found no newly built kindergarten. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/b46d588ea3a34e7f7dda17777fc3f608.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/b46d588ea3a34e7f7dda17777fc3f608.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250494&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Song Guangjun, deputy general manager of Henan Great Wall Construction Company:&lt;/strong>; &quot;Originally, I applied for a location in the south district of the community, but that location in the south district was unrealistic. It turned out that the consideration was very good, but the planning could not be coordinated and adjusted, so I said no Get it. After the two areas are planned, we can&#39;t say that a building will pop up. It certainly can&#39;t be like this, so the application plan was well imagined at that time, but it couldn&#39;t be realized in the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/6d7a56d16158deb86ed87290f37f585c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/6d7a56d16158deb86ed87290f37f585c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250493&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The kindergarten is said to have no space to build, and the sanitation Where is the room? There is a row of commercial front rooms at the entrance of Puguang Community. The developer said that two of the front rooms are health rooms. According to the winning bid documents for the supporting projects in Puguang Community at that time, Great Wall Construction Company won the bid for this project in December 2016, and the completion date of the building where the clinic is located was also December 2016, which means that this project is recruiting When the bidding process was held, the entire building was already completed, so how could there be any talk of a new health room? &lt;p>; &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/1f9dc021ec5ddc8fa6813f3e582b68ed.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/1f9dc021ec5ddc8fa6813f3e582b68ed.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250500&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said to take practical use into consideration , In fact, this so-called health room has not been put into use yet. Dedicated funds are the basic requirement for special fiscal funds in our country. Where did the 18 million yuan of central fiscal funds invested in this project go? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The local government applied for 18 million yuan in central funds for this project in Puguang Community, but only 6 million yuan was actually allocated. It is unknown where the remaining funds were used. According to my country&#39;s &quot;Measures for the Administration of Direct Investment Projects within the Central Budget&quot;, any adjustment of construction standards or investment scale, change of construction location or construction content without approval; transfer, embezzlement or misappropriation of construction funds are all violations. Regarding this phenomenon, how does the local municipal development and reform department responsible for project supervision view this phenomenon? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/a86d3ccb95a64992f60469d79881f8ea.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/a86d3ccb95a64992f60469d79881f8ea.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250495&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Feng, Chief of the Urban Development Section of the Development and Reform Commission of Henan Changyuan City:&lt;/strong>;“Our management of it starts from project establishment and ends with project completion. This is the process of our supervision. Project completion We delivered it after that, and the management issues during their use were beyond my scope of responsibility.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/13/6f75ed3db88f47572a26e11358a5841a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/13/6f75ed3db88f47572a26e11358a5841a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250498&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that after the project is completed, it will not be under the supervision of the development and reform department, but the reporter found during the interview that the plan The third project in the project, the Weizhuang resettlement housing supporting project, has not even been completed. What is going on? According to the plan, a road of about 560 meters will be built locally to connect two municipal roads from Weiba Road to Weishi Road. The central government has allocated a total of 17 million yuan in funds, and it is scheduled to be completed in 2017. However, when we came here to learn about the situation, we found that six years later, this road is still a dead end, with more than 200 meters still not repaired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Feng, Chief of the Urban Development Section of the Development and Reform Commission of Henan Changyuan City:&lt;/strong>;“It is understood that one section has not been completely completed due to demolition issues, and some parts may have stalled.”&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/e6c8e1628a1be5e2666d783a8c864202.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/e6c8e1628a1be5e2666d783a8c864202.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250502&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to build this road, 17 million yuan of funds from the central government has been allocated long ago, but the road has not been completed. At the construction company of this road, the reporter learned that they actually only received more than 6 million yuan in funding. In accordance with the requirements of relevant documents, local development and reform departments and housing construction departments should take measures to strengthen dynamic supervision of project construction implementation, and projects that cannot be completed on time or fail to pass completion acceptance will be criticized through notices, withdrawn or deducted from the central budget Domestic investment and other measures shall be punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the reporter&#39;s interview, the local government rectified these problematic projects, and now garages, health rooms, etc. are gradually being put into use. Central fiscal funds are invested in local people&#39;s livelihood projects. In order for central fiscal funds to be used wisely and truly promote development, benefit the people, and benefit the country, it is necessary to strengthen effective supervision of fund implementation and project implementation. If you treat the funds from the central government as Tang Monk Meat and only apply for them, regardless of project implementation and actual results, how can such a &quot;popular support project&quot; win the support of the people? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[揭示问题与整改同样重要：28省份审计报告中的财政难题]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256582]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/NRuXpg0MK228rq9kxE3yCvLnZ6lFqDOZg1MIH8Zb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/NRuXpg0MK228rq9kxE3yCv LnZ6lFqDOZg1MIH8Zb. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250512&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compulsory education funds were misappropriated 265 million yuan (Inner Mongolia), city commercial banks illegally lent 40.6 billion yuan (Hebei), two counties charged 251 million yuan without basis (Sichuan), and 6 companies were dishonest Enterprises received financial subsidies (Chongqing), and 10 cities and counties owed private enterprises 400 million yuan in accounts (Jilin)...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July 2023, 28 provinces, autonomous regions, and municipalities across the country have successively announced their own The 2022 annual audit report focuses on local budget implementation and other fiscal revenue and expenditures, revealing a variety of problems. The audit report is called the annual &quot;economic check-up.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“On the new journey of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation, auditing bears an important mission. It must be based on the positioning of economic supervision, focus on the main responsibilities and main businesses, and better play the unique role of auditing in promoting the party’s self-revolution. &quot;On May 23, 2023, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, Chairman of the Central Military Commission, and Director of the Central Audit Commission, emphasized at the first meeting of the 20th Central Audit Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meeting pointed out that it is necessary to build a centralized, unified, comprehensive, authoritative and efficient audit supervision system, and omit the audit supervision rights of all localities, departments and units that manage the use of public funds, state-owned assets and state-owned resources. , without exception, forming a normalized and dynamic deterrent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 26, the National Audit Office released the &quot;State Council&#39;s Audit Work Report on the Implementation of the Central Budget and Other Financial Revenues and Expenditures in 2022&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;State Council Audit Report&quot;). Starting from July 20, audit reports from various regions will be released one after another. As of September 10, only Xinjiang, Tibet, and Guizhou have not yet released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The level of detail in audit reports varies from place to place. The audit reports of Henan, Inner Mongolia, and Sichuan have detailed data. When talking about the problems that occurred, Fujian&#39;s audit report only mentioned irregularities and did not specify the specific amounts. The same is true for the Shaanxi audit report. Most of the issues do not state the amount involved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Guangxi published the audit report on the government website, it removed the original text. &quot;A university has received a cumulative financial investment of 131 million yuan in scientific research funds, implemented 862 scientific research projects, and achieved 0 results transformation.&quot; In early August, the above content in the Guangxi audit report became a hot search on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters carefully read 28 audit reports and reported on the outstanding issues in the audit reports of Hebei, Henan, Guangxi, Hunan, Hubei, Sichuan, Inner Mongolia, Jilin, Chongqing and Shanghai (see Southern Weekend App&#39;s &quot;Interpretation of Provincial and Municipal Audit Reports&quot; special topic). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The financial problems presented in the audit reports of 28 regions also have common characteristics, including misappropriation of funds, large scale of temporary fiscal payments, idle special debts, illegal lending by city commercial banks and rural credit cooperatives, etc. How to find a solution is the key to the &quot;second half of the article&quot; in audit rectification. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;22&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Lands involved in misappropriation of funds&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among the 28 provinces that released audit reports, the same problem occurred in 22 places The problem - misappropriation of funds, including transfer payment funds, special debt funds, employment subsidies, project funds, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Two cities and four counties misappropriated 4.491 billion yuan of government special bond funds for 23 projects, which were used for real estate commercial development projects, other debt repayments, and other expenses.” Guangxi audit report wrote. Looking at the audit reports that have been published in various places, 4.491 billion is the highest misappropriation amount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The misappropriation of funds includes the misappropriation of compulsory education funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant agencies in Inner Mongolia audited 469 urban schools and 184 rural schools and found that 21 banner counties misappropriated 265 million yuan of compulsory education funds to make up for the funding gap in other projects; 42 banner counties 991 million yuan Funds for compulsory education are stagnant, resulting in projects such as improving school conditions being unable to be implemented or completed on schedule. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Insufficient funds will cause other problems. &quot;41 banner counties have borrowed 923 teachers on a long-term basis, and 74 primary and secondary schools in 16 banner counties have insufficient staff, and long-term temporary employment of substitute teachers.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chongqing, which is more than a thousand kilometers away from Inner Mongolia, is facing Faced with the same problem, &quot;177 schools in 8 districts and counties illegally used 33.0776 million yuan per student in public funds, training funds, etc. for daily operations and other expenses.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The State Council’s audit report also disclosed the misappropriation of education funds: After an audit of urban and rural compulsory education subsidy funds, it was found that 16 provinces had misappropriated 2.524 billion yuan to balance budgets, repay debts, and issue benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the audit reports of various provinces, the main flow of misappropriated funds is daily expenses or filling a certain funding gap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“19 units occupied 9.7214 million yuan in employment subsidy funds to make up for the lack of unit administrative funds and office building maintenance and other expenses.” The Hubei audit report stated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many places also use false expenditures to obtain funds. The audit reports of 8 provinces mentioned &quot;false expenditures&quot;, with the largest amount involved being in Sichuan, with 4.832 billion yuan of fictitious expenditures in 4 cities and counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Two departments and three affiliated units falsely listed electricity expenses of 1.6293 million yuan.&quot; Heilongjiang audit report introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The audit report of the State Council mentioned that 2 departments and 8 affiliated units obtained 80.7967 million yuan of funds through fictitious expenditures and other methods, of which 4.7185 million yuan was used for food, drink, gifts, etc., or was misappropriated by individuals. . This reflects on one side that behind the false expenditures, there may be corruption issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Budget Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; promulgated in 2019 stipulates that governments at all levels and relevant departments and units are ordered to fail to include all government revenues and expenditures in the budget, or to falsely list revenues and expenditures. To make corrections, the directly responsible person in charge and other directly responsible personnel will be punished by demotion, dismissal, or expulsion in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Hundreds of billions of temporary payments to be solved&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Among the problems found in the provincial audit reports, most of the problems involving the highest amounts are financial temporary payments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters found that the issue of temporary payments was mentioned in the audit reports of six provinces including Inner Mongolia and Hebei. Among them, the temporary payment balance in 5 provinces exceeds 10 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Financial temporary payments are generally funds temporarily lent by the financial department to budget units. It is required that they should not be left on the books for a long time and should be cleared and settled in a timely manner. The Ministry of Finance stipulates that all localities must digest the fiscal temporary payments formed in 2018 and before by the end of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The State Council audit report shows that as of the end of 2022, the balance of temporary fiscal payments in 54 regions reached 148.139 billion yuan, an increase of 8.363 billion yuan over the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Inner Mongolia audit report stated, “The balance of temporary payments in 4 cities reached 47.055 billion yuan at the end of 2021, and the progress of digesting the stock is slow. 2 cities at the same level and 8 banner counties (districts) have not completed the digestion progress. Task&quot;. Among the six provinces that have announced temporary payment issues, Inner Mongolia has the highest temporary payment balance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ministry of Finance stipulates that the newly formed fiscal temporary payment balance after 2019 shall not exceed 5% of the sum of general public budget expenditures and government fund budget expenditures at the same level. Audit reports from Guangxi, Gansu, Inner Mongolia, and Hebei all revealed that some counties and cities failed to meet this requirement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Guangxi audit report shows that as of the end of 2022, the cumulative balance of fiscal temporary payments newly formed after 2019 has exceeded the 5% control line in 10 cities and 54 counties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, the provisional payments in Hubei and Guangxi have not decreased but increased. &quot;As of the end of 2022, the balance of temporary payments in 20 cities and counties reached 26.055 billion yuan, an increase of 1.386 billion yuan over the previous year.&quot; The Hubei audit report revealed that some were used for unbudgeted and over-budget expenditures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2018, the Ministry of Finance issued the &quot;Notice on Strictly Regulating the Management of Temporary Payments of Local Finances&quot;, requiring the financial department not to lend to enterprises, nor to lend to enterprises through other budget units. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, illegal lending to enterprises still exists today. The Inner Mongolia audit report stated that “one city level and three banner districts illegally lent 4.585 billion yuan to enterprises.” The Hebei audit report also showed that four cities illegally lent 1.068 billion yuan to enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Excessive temporary payment balances will crowd out other funds for special purposes and normal treasury funds, creating a situation where &quot;the budget has targets, but the treasury has no cash.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The gap between local revenue and expenditure is widening, and it is difficult to get back the money borrowed.” A financial bureau official in a coastal province told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;2022 Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region Final Accounts Report at the Level&quot; released in July 2023 stated that it is necessary to establish a classified management mechanism for temporary payments, steadily digest the stock, strictly control the increment, and promote the maintenance of temporary payments at the grassroots level. Reasonable scale, gradually replenishing the occupied treasury funds, and ensuring within-budget expenditure needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Tens of billions of special bonds are idle&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As an important means for the government to stimulate consumption and expand domestic demand, special bonds have become the focus of audit reports in various places . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;19 of the 28 provincial audit reports mentioned problems with special debt. Among them, 12 reports stated that special bonds were idle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local government special bonds, also known as &quot;special bonds&quot;, refer to bonds issued by provincial governments for public welfare projects with certain returns. For a long time, it has mainly invested in social basic investment fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If it is a general bond, it is mainly invested in non-profit public welfare projects, and the source of principal and interest repayment is general public budget revenue. In contrast, the repayment funds for special bonds are government fund income, special income and refinancing special bond funds, which are required to achieve a balance between project revenue and expenditure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Audit reports in some regions revealed that some special bond funds have been idle for as long as a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jiangsu audit report stated that the audit agency randomly inspected 62 cities and counties and found that as of the end of 2022, the government special bond funds for 337 projects in 54 cities and counties had not been fully put into use, with a balance of 22.944 billion yuan. Among them, 9.123 billion yuan has a balance of more than one year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Provincial-level bond funds are 1.954 billion yuan, which have been idle for up to 247 days; 29 cities and counties including Nanyang have bond funds of 6.637 billion yuan, which have been idle for up to 300 days.&quot; Henan audit report revealed . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the special bonds are idle, in addition to the original investment goals being unable to be achieved, the local government also needs to pay interest on the funds. If the special debt remains on the books for one more day, it will incur a lot of additional costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the Ministry of Finance, the average interest rate of special bonds is slightly higher than that of general bonds. As of the end of July 2023, the average interest rate on local government bonds was 3.33%. Among them, general bonds 3.31% and special bonds 3.34%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking the Jiangsu audit report as an example, the special debt funds outstanding for more than one year are 9.123 billion yuan. Calculated based on the average interest rate of special bonds of 3.34%, approximately 305 million yuan in interest will be paid per year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What causes tens of billions of special bonds to remain idle? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the audit reports from various places, it is mainly due to problems in the preliminary preparation stage. For example, Jilin admitted in its audit report that due to failure to obtain construction land procedures and other reasons, project preparations were insufficient and it was difficult to start construction on time. 22 projects in 7 cities and counties had 5.993 billion yuan of idle funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jiangsu audit report states that special bonds are idle because &quot;the conditions for starting construction projects are immature, implementation progress is lagging, or bond funding arrangements are ahead of schedule, etc.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Laicheng, a professor at the Central University of Finance and Economics, told Southern Weekend reporters that according to normal procedures, after the project completes all government approval procedures, it will then be reported to the provincial-level finance department to apply for the issuance of special bonds, and the funds will be available immediately. start. However, some local governments begin to declare special bonds when they go through the approval process, and the financial department sometimes agrees to issue them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He explained that special bonds are government investment projects, and more than 20 government departments are involved in the review and approval. If one department disagrees, the project cannot start construction. Even if the special bond funds are in place, there is no way to use them and it is easy to become idle. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;City commercial banks&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Rural Credit Cooperatives lending illegally&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In addition to paying close attention to issues in the financial field , the audit report also focuses on the chaos in the financial system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eight provincial audit reports mentioned that many city commercial banks and rural credit cooperatives have loopholes in risk management and compliance, compliance operations and other sectors. Among them, the largest amount involved was illegal lending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, the competent authorities have been tightening the space for regional commercial banks to lend in other places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Commercial Bank Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China (Revised Draft)&quot; promulgated in 2020 requires that regional commercial banks such as urban commercial banks, rural commercial banks, village and town banks, etc., shall carry out banking operations in accordance with the law within the scope of their residence. Business activities shall not be carried out across regions without approval. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hebei audit department found that eight city commercial banks issued loans in violation of regulations, including issuing loans to customers or related parties whose loans were overdue, and that different branches within a jurisdiction issued loans to the same borrower, violating regulations. The amount of loans involved is 40.6 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nine city commercial banks failed to strictly implement the &quot;three loan checks&quot; system, resulting in greater risks in 5.959 billion yuan of loan funds. &quot;Three Loan Inspections&quot; refers to pre-loan investigation, loan review, and post-loan inspection. This system enables banks to understand the operating conditions of borrowers, determine loan risks, and is also an important basis for subsequent accountability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jiangxi audit report disclosed that 32 rural commercial banks had lax &quot;three loan inspections&quot; and illegally granted loans of 2.502 billion yuan to borrowers who did not meet the conditions such as credit reporting. 29 rural commercial banks failed to effectively track and inspect the use of loan funds, and 4.79 billion yuan of credit funds were misappropriated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to illegal lending, there are also problems in the risk management and control of many city commercial banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the Jiangxi audit report, 28 rural commercial banks concealed loan risks by adjusting loan classification results in violation of regulations and repaying loans with loans, underreporting non-performing loans by 2.552 billion yuan; 8 rural commercial banks expanded credit in violation of regulations and passed We disposed of 1.854 billion yuan of non-performing assets by issuing loans to third parties to assume debts and transferring loans; 23 rural commercial banks wrote off non-performing loans worth 1.626 billion yuan in violation of regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Liaoning audit department focused on investigating the operations of two urban commercial banks and found that &quot;the president and vice president positions of one bank have been vacant for a long time, and some senior managers have not been approved by the regulatory authorities.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Inner Mongolia audit report revealed a detail that 6 leading cadres of a certain county health commission, public security bureau and other government departments and 12 other public officials illegally took shares in 2 rural commercial banks, involving 3.2036 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Do a good job in the &quot;second half of the article&quot; on audit rectification&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The first meeting of the 20th Central Audit Committee emphasized that the &quot;second half of the article&quot; on audit rectification &quot;The first half of the article&quot; is equally important as the problems revealed by the audit and must be promoted in one piece. Supervision and promotion of audit rectification should be regarded as an important starting point for daily supervision, and audit results should be used as an important reference for cadre assessment, appointment and dismissal, rewards and punishments. Those who fail to make rectifications, make perfunctory rectifications, or make false rectifications must be seriously held accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, the official website of the Guizhou Provincial Audit Office released the &quot;Report on the Rectification of Problems Found in the 2021 Provincial Budget Implementation and Other Financial Revenue and Expenditure Audits.&quot; According to the report, in response to the problem of misappropriation of 1.764 billion yuan of ecological and environmental protection funds in 1 city and 10 counties, the relevant regions have cleaned up the misappropriated resources and environment funds, and 475 million yuan has been rectified through the return of the original channels. The remaining funds are planned to be gradually Return in place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the audit reports of 18 provinces in 2023, there are special chapters to introduce the transfer of clues about disciplinary and illegal violations, or the preliminary rectification of problems found in the audit. According to the official website of the local audit office (bureau), about one year after the audit report is released, a special report will be released to focus on the rectification of problems found in the audit report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hainan audit report stated that in 2022, the Provincial Audit Office transferred a total of 28 clues to disciplinary and illegal issues, involving 82 people and 440 million yuan. As of June 2023, 7 cases have been settled, 21 cases are being handled, and 12 people have been dealt with. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The transfer matters manifested themselves as illegal decision-making by public officials and abuse of power for personal gain, etc., resulting in the loss and waste of state-owned funds, state-owned assets and state-owned resources, involving 11 cases, 72 people, and 125 million yuan. In addition, the problems of &quot;mutual collusion&quot; and &quot;internal and external collusion&quot; in the field of engineering construction are hidden and diverse, mainly involving illegal project bidding, illegal subcontracting, and bid rigging, involving 5 cases involving 3 people and 278 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The contradiction between fiscal revenue and expenditure has increased, and how to make up for the misappropriated funds has become a difficult problem in the audit and rectification process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An official working in the Audit Office of a southern province told Southern Weekend reporters that after the local government misappropriated funds and was discovered by the audit department, due to rectification requirements, all funds needed to be replenished. However, due to financial constraints, In some places, other funds have been misappropriated to repay the misappropriated funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past five years, more than 440,000 units across the country have been audited, and more than 38,000 clues on major issues have been transferred to disciplinary inspection and supervision, judicial and other departments, involving more than 920 billion yuan and more than 51,000 people; promoting revenue growth Saving expenditures and recovering losses of more than 2 trillion yuan.&quot; At the National Audit Work Conference in January 2023, Hou Kai, Auditor General of the National Audit Office, introduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 28, in the report on the State Council’s audit report, Hou Kai said that as of April 2023, the problems discovered in the 2021 audit had been rectified with an amount of 850.111 billion yuan, and the system had been improved by more than 2,900 yuan. items, more than 14,000 people were held accountable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that the clues to the key issues under supervision are generally progressing smoothly, and some stubborn diseases that have hindered reform and development and have not been resolved for a long time have been eradicated. &quot;The overall pattern of audit rectification has initially taken shape, and the &#39;second half article&#39; of audit work is more authoritative and efficient.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[国家网络安全宣传周丨这些网络安全知识你应知道！]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256584]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;September 11-17, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is National Cyber ​​Security Awareness Week&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;While enjoying the convenience brought by today’s Internet&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You must also always pay attention&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are huge hidden dangers behind the Internet&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Telecom fraud, information Leakage,&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Internet rumors, malware...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, let’s learn network security knowledge&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/17b6a5d848ae88a0fdda2fb81b23c95c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1211&quot; data-src= &quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/17b6a5d848ae88a0fdda2fb81b23c95c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250637&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/66b4aca389da10a8407dac845cbf1749.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1184&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/66b4aca389da10a8407dac845cbf1749.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250638&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/298f271a3f12321cc2887f5fda60da5c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1190&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/298f271a3f12321cc2887f5fda60da5c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250641&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/13/4a1461b1d4c0eda02bfb166f09e8e5b9.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1193&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/4a1461b1d4c0eda02bfb166f09e8e5b9.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250639&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/13/38d826baf566719d843b60fc65ef0b84.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1182&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/13/38d826baf566719d843b60fc65ef0b84.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250642&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/13/be698fd21125f121cbb7dd417dac3b15.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1186&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/13/be698fd21125f121cbb7dd417dac3b15.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250640&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/13/9f698d8ef576a166b69dd424ac2d0970.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1167&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/13/9f698d8ef576a166b69dd424ac2d0970.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/13/cd946c7dfde6977ae6ee79d1735ec897.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1189&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/09/13/cd946c7dfde6977ae6ee79d1735ec897.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250644&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /13/4d89eef745fff60e069280b0fc21877d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1196&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /09/13/4d89eef745fff60e069280b0fc21877d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250647&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13 /7a7e801bf1af2f5eb3e47eec99da41bb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1179&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /13/7a7e801bf1af2f5eb3e47eec99da41bb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250646&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/eb8967cbb262b19c1f99700884630291 .png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13 /eb8967cbb262b19c1f99700884630291.png&quot; data-key=&quot;250645&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/2823340d1496804d71ff1f6ed2c836b5.png &quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;1196&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/2823340d1496804d71ff1f6ed2c836b5 .png&quot; data-key=&quot;250648&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 18:55:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>