<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[网传湖北襄阳一医院“贩卖出生证明” ，涉事院长正在接受调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260114]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In response to the online rumor that &quot;the director of Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital in Hubei colluded with online intermediaries to use online platforms to openly sell birth certificates and sell babies. &quot;The reporter learned from relevant departments in Xiangyang City, Hubei Province on the 7th that the director of the hospital involved is currently under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 6, an online post reported that Hubei Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital was suspected of selling birth certificates, saying that after more than a year of undercover visits, it was discovered that Ye Moumou, the director of Xiangyang Jianqiao Hospital, colluded with intermediary gangs in many places. Use social platforms to publicly publish birth certificate information, identify customers, and sell birth certificates and vaccine books. According to the online post, the buyer only needs to provide identity information and pay 96,000 yuan, and the hospital will follow the &quot;normal&quot; production process and handle a full set of true information such as filing, prenatal check-up, hospitalization, delivery, and discharge at the hospital. &quot;Two days after being discharged from the hospital, the customer can take the &quot;bought child&quot; to the hospital to collect foot blood (foot blood is collected when a newborn is born), and then apply for a birth certificate. The entire process can be completed in up to 7 days. At the same time, the hospital provides a national version of the vaccination book, and &quot;vaccines&quot; according to the &quot;real&quot; newborn birth process, printing hepatitis B and BCG vaccine injection records, injection dates, vaccine manufacturers, and vaccine batch numbers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the online post was published, it sparked heated discussions among netizens. In response to this, the Xiangyang Municipal Health Commission responded on the evening of the 6th that it had contacted the public security department and the Health Supervision Bureau to intervene in the investigation, and also arranged for dedicated personnel to contact relevant insiders to plead for support. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 7th, reporters learned from the relevant departments of Xiangyang City that the person responsible for the hospital involved has been controlled and the hospital director is under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“募集”资金经由个人账户，流入房地产：河南老基会“吸储”始末]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260106]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The medical care center in the Herong International Health Care Demonstration Park. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/37625adedd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/37625adedd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257257&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The medical care center in the Herong International Health Care Demonstration Park. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From bank president to &quot;scammer&quot;, Zhang Shihe&#39;s life has been like a roller coaster. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shihe is a native of Shangshui County, Zhoukou City, Henan Province, and the former vice president of a commercial bank in the county. After retirement, he joined the Henan Elderly Cultural Development Foundation (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Old Foundation&quot;) and was responsible for collecting private funds from the county. In the eight years he witnessed, people were able to get their principal and interest back as scheduled. Until August 2021, no more money could be withdrawn, and savers began to &quot;visit&quot; every now and then. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At dawn on October 24, 2023, the first guest welcomed into Zhang Shihe’s home was 69-year-old Zhang Fenglan. Six years ago, she deposited the 100,000 yuan she had saved for most of her life into the Lao Foundation and became a &quot;five-star member.&quot; Zhang Shihe is the person in charge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Fenglan’s reminder voucher is not a passbook or an IOU, but two membership certificates. The issuing organization is the Old Foundation. If you deposit money to it, you will receive consolation money, which is interest. In Shangshui County, for every 10,000 yuan saved, you can get 570 yuan/year in consolation payment, with an annualized rate of return of 5.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I thought I had saved my money in the safest place, but I never imagined that something like this would happen.” Zhang Fenglan sighed repeatedly to the Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shihe persuaded the other party in a low voice, saying that he was also a victim and felt very guilty for &quot;losing&quot; everyone&#39;s money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He revealed that the entire Shangshui County involves more than 300 depositors, with a total of more than 41 million yuan in deposits. Looking at the entire Henan Province, the tentacles of the Old Foundation are everywhere. Several insiders of the old foundation revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the old foundation may absorb as much as 500 million yuan in depositors&#39; funds in Henan Province, involving 18 offices in Zhoukou, Nanyang, Luohe, Luoyang and other cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 20, 2023, the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs mentioned in its reply to Li Yazhong and others’ letter of complaint that in June 2020, the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs transferred Henan Herong Industrial Group Co., Ltd. ( (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Herong Group&quot;) suspected illegal financing-related materials were handed over to the Henan Provincial Public Security Department in the name of the Lao Foundation. The official website of the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs also records that on July 28, 2020, the Lao Foundation was included in the list of social organizations with serious violations of laws and breach of trust. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many heads of old foundations confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that under the guidance of the Henan Provincial Public Security Department, public security bureaus in many places have launched investigations into county-level old foundations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In late October, Southern Weekend reporters visited several counties and districts in Zhoukou and Luohe cities and found that the Lao Foundation used local political and private network resources to weave a huge deposit-absorbing network. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did a provincial public foundation “self-raise” such huge sums of money in the past ten years? Where do these huge sums of money ultimately go? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Network&quot; retired cadres and farmers&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How to become a veteran foundation member? A &quot;Membership Instructions&quot; found by Southern Weekend reporters states that applicants fill out the membership application form, and after review and approval by the Old Foundation, register information and pay membership fees. After receiving the membership card, they become a formal member. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shihe said that these membership fees will be returned to members when they expire (one year), and you can also receive consolation money by presenting your membership card to the issuing agency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Membership fees are essentially deposits, and the amount is replaced by points on the membership card. Members are divided into one-star, three-star and five-star, and the corresponding points represent RMB 10,000, RMB 30,000 and RMB 50,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 82-year-old Lu Zhiqiang is a big customer of the old foundation and has 22 membership cards in his hand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He is a retired cadre in Shangshui County. He has a monthly pension of more than 3,000 yuan, plus a front-end house, and an annual rent of more than 30,000 yuan. He and his wife cannot spend this money. How many. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He recalled that in the early days of the establishment of the Lao Foundation, Chen Zhihong, the person in charge in Shangshui County, often invited people to have dinner together to promote the Lao Foundation in order to build momentum. As a fellow villager, he even participated once. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Because it is a public foundation, I think there is no problem. Even if you deposit money in a bank for a fixed period, it doesn&#39;t have much money.&quot; He remembered Chen Zhihong motivating him like this, &quot;This foundation is managed by the Civil Affairs Department, so it can&#39;t be wasted.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Zhiqiang hid the deposits of the old foundation from his children, not even his wife. &quot;If you tell them, they will stop it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Fenghua, 77, is the former head of the financial section of the Shangshui County Industrial and Commercial Bureau. She has deposited 250,000 yuan in the old foundation. She only learned about the old foundation through the introduction of a retired cadre from the Shangshui County Civil Affairs Bureau. &quot;I only knew that the interest rates were high and the certificates issued had the seal of the Civil Affairs Department, so I thought it was more reliable.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I didn&#39;t dare to tell my child at that time, for fear of exposing that my child was asking for the money. I wanted to save it so that I could hire a nanny when I get old.&quot; Guo Fenghua sighed, &quot;It&#39;s too late to regret it now. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to retired cadres in the county, the Lao Foundation has also extended its tentacles to the vast rural areas of Henan Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shang Fugui, 70, is from Chengding Village, Guxiang Township, Linying County, Luohe City. He is responsible for helping the Lao Foundation collect deposits in the village. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that at first the villagers saved little money, &quot;but because of the high interest rates, you saw me saving, I saw him saving, and word spread slowly.&quot; Some villagers even offered to give him cigarettes in order to do something for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He absorbed 2.75 million yuan in funds, involving about 40 depositors, accounting for half of the village&#39;s population. There are also a few savers from other villages who are his relatives. Shang Fugui said that for every 10,000 yuan deposited, depositors can receive a condolence payment of 600 yuan per year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Actually, we are a small bank down there.” A head of the county-level office of the old foundation told a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Luohe, the old foundation showed the first signs of trouble. In October 2015, the Provincial Lao Foundation said that its funds were broken and gradually stopped local principal and interest payments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shang Fugui recalled that after the payment was stopped, the depositors became enemies with him. Seven years later, in October 2022, he was beaten once by villagers. &quot;Sometimes the tricycles are not dared to be released outside. They will poke holes in you and vent your anger.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every Spring Festival, Shang Fugui and his wife would run to the city. &quot;What if I don&#39;t run away? They all gather at the door of my house to ask for money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A depositor has as many as 22 membership cards. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/07/0ef86b4c0e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/0ef86b4c0e .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257258&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A depositor has as many as 22 membership cards. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Using &quot;volunteers&quot; as the starting point&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Intermediaries such as Zhang Shihe and Shang Fugui are called &quot;volunteers&quot; in the old foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They are often retired cadres or former loan officers. Their personal status provides credit endorsement to local people. Choosing such a group of &quot;hands-on&quot; is also a reason why similar foundations can always grow rapidly among the people. One of the &quot;mysteries&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second floor of No. 8 Zhengxin Street, Shangshui County, Zhoukou City is the local office of the Old Foundation. When Southern Weekend reporters visited on October 23, the place was deserted and the door was locked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shihe said that there are five &quot;volunteers&quot; in the office, basically all retired cadres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Chen Zhihong is the person in charge of the Shangshui County Lao Foundation. He once served as secretary of the Party Committee of Tangzhuang Township in Shangshui County and deputy director of the Propaganda Department of the Shangshui County Party Committee. Zhang Shihe is the former vice president of a commercial bank in Shangshui County. The other two &quot;volunteers&quot; have served in the Shangshui County Finance Bureau and the Procuratorate respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A former staff member of Weiji Township Government in Shangshui County told Southern Weekend reporters that he and Chen Zhihong are fellow villagers. I often sit at the same table with Chen Zhihong during meetings in the county. I am familiar with her, so I also saved some money. &quot;He is not like a liar, he is a very down-to-earth person.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a criminal verdict obtained by Southern Weekend reporters, Yang Yiting, a &quot;volunteer&quot; at the Linying County Office in Luohe City, mentioned in his testimony that the old man When the foundation&#39;s Linying office was established, the director of the office, Xue Xiaoge, came to him and said that the provincial veteran foundation hoped to find a local cadre with prestige, popularity, and retirement to serve as the honorary director. &quot;The foundation is engaged in charity. Shang Qi had been retired at home for two years and wanted to do something.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xue Xiaoge confessed that Yang Yiting was the former political commissar of the Linying County Public Security Bureau and the honorary director. &quot;When there is an event, he takes part in it. He doesn&#39;t usually go to work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to retired cadres from government agencies, former rural loan officers are also an important force for the old foundation to sink into the rural market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;70-year-old Feng Junfu is a villager in Guzhuang Village, Daguo Town, Linying County, Luohe City. In 1975, he was elected as a loan officer of Daguo Township Credit Union by the Guzhuang Village Committee and worked there for 34 years until 2009. Get fired. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Junfu said that township residents are accustomed to depositing funds in local rural credit cooperatives or township banks, and loan officers play the role of handling business for villagers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Loan officers must first be ideologically progressive, trustworthy by the people, and have no stains.” Feng Junfu told Southern Weekend reporters that there are 20 old foundation “volunteers” in Linying County, most of whom have worked as loan officers in township banks. , and people from all over the country regard them as their &quot;own people&quot; who are worthy of entrustment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2013, Xue Xiaoge found Feng Junfu and showed him the approval document of the old foundation from the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs, the foundation’s legal person certificate, tax registration certificate, organization code certificate, etc., saying that it was formal. organization and invite him to join. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The most important thing is that we have depositor resources in our hands.” Feng Junfu told Southern Weekend reporters that he thought about staying in his old business and the process was roughly the same, so he readily agreed. In Guzhuang Village, Feng Junfu developed more than 50 villagers into members of the Lao Foundation and collected a total of 1.85 million yuan in savings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Provincial Veterans Foundation stipulates that for every 10,000 yuan taken in, 300 yuan will be set aside for &quot;volunteers&quot; and another 200 yuan will be used for office expenses of the county and district offices. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Origined from the Henan Song Qing Ling Foundation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tracing back to the source, the old foundation is inextricably linked to the Henan Soong Ching Ling Foundation (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Henan Song Qing Ling Foundation&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 2005, the Henan Song Foundation collected deposits from villagers in the name of public welfare medical insurance. (See Southern Weekend’s September 2011 series of reports on “Where is the Money of China’s Most Fundraising Charitable Organization—Who Controls the Henan Soong Ching Ling Foundation”)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2013, the old foundation officially It was established and Lu Dawei was appointed as the president. According to the Henan Provincial People&#39;s Government website, Lu Dawei served as assistant to the governor. In addition, Southern Weekend reporters learned from the Henan Song Foundation website that he is also the vice chairman of the Henan Song Foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A county-level person in charge of the old foundation revealed that the management method of the old foundation is under the leadership of the president, with the secretary-general taking responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge told Southern Weekend reporters that Guo Jianxin is the secretary-general of the Old Foundation and is responsible for the overall work, while the deputy secretary-general Huang Yuejun is responsible for specific work. &quot;Huang Yuejun turned out to be from the Song Foundation. Basically, we follow the management style of Song Foundation, otherwise we wouldn’t be able to get this thing done.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In interviews with reporters from Southern Weekend, we found that most of the county-level directors of the old foundations had working experience in the Henan Song Foundation. After the Henan Song Foundation&#39;s savings-absorbing business ceased, Guo Jianxin and Huang Yuejun recruited these people. “In the past, we were all familiar with the business at the Song Foundation. Huang Yuejun gave us advice and introduced us to the old foundation,” the person in charge said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, a reporter from Southern Weekend contacted Huang Yuejun by phone. The other party said that he had left the Lao Foundation at the end of 2015 and was currently residing in a nursing home in Sichuan Province. He did not know much about the past and then hung up. Disconnect the phone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Cuiyun was originally a depositor of the Henan Song Foundation. After the Song Foundation ceased its deposit-taking business, she withdrew the original 100,000 yuan from the Song Foundation and transferred it to the old foundation. Then save another 50,000 yuan every year until 450,000 yuan. &quot;Generally (every year) I don&#39;t ask for the principal, I get the interest, but I add some money to make up 50,000 and deposit it again.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Left-hand foundation, right-hand open Company&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Tianyancha shows that the Elderly Foundation is located in Zhengzhou City, Henan Province, and its purpose is to &quot;promote the development of social welfare, culture, sports, education and other undertakings for the elderly in Henan Province.&quot; Access to the foundation’s official website is currently closed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters obtained a reply from the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs on the establishment and registration of the Henan Provincial Elderly Cultural Development Foundation (Yu Min Han [2013] No. 47). According to the &quot;Foundation&quot; According to the provisions of the Management Regulations, after review, the old foundation, which was donated a total of 4 million yuan as the original fund by Guo Jianxin, meets the conditions for establishing a public foundation. It is hereby approved to register and obtain the legal person status of the foundation in accordance with the law. Its business supervisory unit is Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 2023, Southern Weekend reporters repeatedly contacted the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs to verify many issues regarding the old foundation, but no one answered the relevant calls. Inquired through &quot;12345&quot;, but still no reply after waiting for many days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For many savers, they are willing to deposit money in the foundation. On the one hand, they trust the &quot;volunteers&quot;, and on the other hand, they see the business scope on the foundation&#39;s legal person registration certificate. On this certificate issued by the Henan Provincial Department of Civil Affairs, the business scope reads &quot;raising social funds in accordance with the law and carrying out elderly cultural activities such as loving and helping the elderly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of many savers and &quot;volunteers&quot;, being able to &quot;raise social funds in accordance with the law&quot; means that they can legitimately accept deposits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A search shows that many foundations do mention &quot;raising social funds in accordance with the law&quot; in their business scope. For example, the business scope of the Henan Province Yellow River Cultural Foundation is “raising funds in accordance with the law, rescuing cultural heritage, and establishing cultural undertakings”; the business scope of the Henan Province Youth Entrepreneurship and Employment Foundation is “raising funds in accordance with the law, subsidizing youth entrepreneurship and employment, and conducting research on youth entrepreneurship, etc. &quot;Related social charity activities&quot;; the business scope of the Henan Province Old District Construction Foundation is &quot;raising funds in accordance with the law and supporting poverty alleviation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lawyer Zeng Jie of Guangdong Guangqiang Law Firm told Southern Weekend reporters that there is an essential difference between raising funds and deposits. Deposits mean a commitment to guarantee principal and interest. “The foundation can absorb funds from the society within its business scope. However, returns cannot be promised, and projects that repay principal and interest are not allowed.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He explained that deposit business requires a formal banking license. The old foundation used consolation money instead of interest without approval, which is a disguised form of absorbing savings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The business scope on the registration certificate makes depositors and volunteers think it is &quot;natural&quot; to save money here. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/11365ba5da.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/11/07/11365ba5da.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257259&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The business scope on the registration certificate makes depositors and volunteers think that saving money here is &quot;natural&quot;. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Zhao Jilin&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2021, the Linying County Court of Luohe City convicted the Henan Elderly Cultural Development Foundation of illegally absorbing public deposits, sentenced it to a fine of RMB 200,000, and ordered the elderly to Participants in the foundation&#39;s compensation fund-raising raised 29.71 million yuan, and Henan Herong Industrial Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Herong Group&quot;) bears joint liability for compensation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is the relationship between Herong Group and the Lao Foundation? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the secretary-general of the Lao Foundation, Guo Jianxin is also the chairman of Henan Herong Elderly Care Industry Group and was once the major shareholder of Herong Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tianyancha shows that Herong Group was established in 2010 and is an enterprise mainly engaged in business services. On March 15, 2010, Guo Jianxin, as the major shareholder, participated in 90% of the shares for the first time. Another shareholder, Wang Shuling, is also a member of the board of directors of the Lao Foundation and holds 10% of the shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;To put it bluntly, Herong Group and the Lao Foundation are one and the same to the outside world, but in reality they are the same.&quot; A person close to Guo Jianxin told Southern Weekend reporters that there are people under the Lao Foundation and Herong Group. Division of labor, top management is a group of people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The registered office address of Herong Group is also the same as that of the Old Foundation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On March 5, 2013, the Lao Foundation and Herong Group officially signed a letter of authorization. The Lao Foundation will authorize Herong Group to invest in projects with the raised funds to ensure the maintenance and appreciation of the funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An investigation by Southern Weekend reporters found that in order to avoid supervision, most of the private funds absorbed by the old foundation went through personal accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As can be seen in a criminal verdict, the financial personnel of the Provincial Veterans Foundation are Zhang Xiaodan and Wang Jie. Wang Jie is responsible for receiving funds (he resigned in September 2015), and Zhang Xiaodan is responsible for disbursing funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xiaodan mentioned in his testimony that the Provincial Veterans Foundation has bank cards in its offices in various counties and districts. The bank card account names are all the names of provincial and ministerial personnel, and most of the funds are transferred through China Construction Bank. Yes, a small part is transferred through ICBC and Postal Savings Bank of China. After the various offices in the county and district paid dues, Wang Jie transferred the money to the Herong Group&#39;s account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Wang Jie swiped directly from the POS machine at the foundation headquarters and transferred it to the account given by Herong Group.&quot; Zhang Xiaodan saw Wang Jie transfer like this with his own eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Xiaodan said that the foundation transfers the dues transferred from each office to Herong Group. &quot;This is the case every day.&quot; Any money received is transferred to the company and transferred to his personal bank card. superior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the available annual reports of the old foundation, from 2014 to 2016, the donation income was 300,000 yuan, 460,000 yuan, and 270,000 yuan respectively, and the corresponding public welfare expenditures were 25,000 yuan. Ten thousand yuan, 220,000 yuan, 360,000 yuan. But by 2017, both donation income and public welfare expenditures were 0. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that the huge &quot;membership dues&quot; of the old foundation did not go through the foundation&#39;s public account, but were transferred privately through personal bank accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If a lawsuit is filed and we check the old foundation&#39;s public account, we will find that our money is not in the account. The old foundation&#39;s public account only accepts donations. Depositors&#39; money cannot be added to it. Even if it’s a donation,” a county-level head of an old foundation told a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Huge sums of money flow into real estate&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;From a province-wide perspective, the difficulties faced by the old foundation in repaying funds are concentrated in the second half of 2021. But there are early signs of bank-run difficulties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, guarantee companies and investment companies in Henan Province went bankrupt on a large scale. &quot;As soon as they closed down, the old foundation was also affected.&quot; An insider close to Guo Jianxin told Southern Weekend reporters that one year after the establishment of the old foundation, the capital chain began to break. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The source revealed that from August to September 2015, depositors began to withdraw money from the county-level offices of the Old Foundation on a large scale. &quot;Not only the customers panicked, but the directors and volunteers of the Old Foundation offices also panicked.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of a county-level office recalled that in October 2015, Guo Jianxin, the head of Herong Group, said at a meeting with county-level leaders that the company had debts and the funds could not be paid temporarily. , let everyone go back and wait, and protect themselves first. &quot;We didn&#39;t tell the depositors when we got back. We thought it would be fine after a while.&quot; In order to repay the interest to the depositors, we also asked relatives and friends for help, did not hesitate to borrow money, and even sold the house, paying more than 1 million yuan in interest to the depositors. It wasn&#39;t until 2021 that he couldn&#39;t survive anymore, then he confessed to savers and stopped paying interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There is no way, in order to encourage depositors to continue depositing. If we stop (payment), we will have to go to (jail). Will ordinary people be willing to not pay interest?&quot; The person in charge of the office said that if we continue to do so, Those who went down were paupers and were in debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 20, 2023, Herong Group issued the &quot;Explanation on the Inability to Redeem the Funds Raised by the Henan Elderly Cultural Foundation on Time&quot;, saying that it held a meeting to study and decide that the payment will be made from the end of February 2023. 10%-15% of the funds will be paid, and 20%-25% of the funds will be paid at the end of February 2024; 30%-35% will be paid in February 2025, and the rest will be paid at the end of 2025. However, the above promises have never been fulfilled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Where did the money go? This is the mystery lingering in the minds of savers and &quot;volunteers&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yi Jiadong is the legal representative of Herong Group. He confessed in a criminal verdict that &quot;Herong Group invested in two real estate projects in Mengzhou City in Jiaozuo and Yuanyang County in Xinxiang , invested in an apartment project for the elderly in Zhengzhou Port District, and also invested in a real estate project in Shangqiu City. All the social funds raised by the Lao Foundation were used in these projects.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the Zhengzhou Port District project is Herong International Health Care Demonstration Park (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Health Care Park&quot;) is considered to be the benchmark project of Herong Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Kangyangyuan is located at the southwest corner of the intersection of Yingang Avenue and Ruyun Road, Airport District, Zhengzhou City. The total land area is 41,398.22 square meters, the total construction area is 76,754.40 square meters, and there are 2,000 designed beds. It mainly constructs 6 elderly apartment buildings, 1 comprehensive service building, 1 elderly research center building, and 1 elderly medical care center building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Chunlai is the head of a county-level office of the Lao Foundation. On September 15, 2022, he was elected as the director of Kangyangyuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the elderly care projects in the port area are positioned as high-end and have received the attention of many local leaders. There is a lot of room for imagination in the future. In addition to construction subsidies, bed subsidies, and nursing subsidies, the land price also has advantages compared with other investors. &quot;I heard that the land price in Zhengzhou Port District cost more than 2 million yuan per acre, but here it was only a few hundred thousand. At that time, the house price was 10% per year. growth, this alone will not make us lose anything.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, its construction was not smooth. Feng Chunlai said that the construction of Kangyangyuan started in 2016, but due to environmental problems such as dust and noise, the superior authorities asked it to stop construction. It was not until December 18, 2019 that the first phase of the park was successfully opened. According to the Henan branch of CCTV, Lu Dawei and Guo Jianxin also delivered speeches at the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Chunlai revealed that the main construction of the nine buildings of the senior care project in Zhengzhou Port District was completed in 2018, but due to financial constraints, there has been no renovation. At the beginning of 2019, eight county-level offices under the old foundation established project promotion teams to continue to collect deposits from the society and provide loans to renovate Buildings 5 ​​and 4. The remaining seven buildings have not yet been renovated due to funding problems. &quot;If we don&#39;t renovate the building, this place will collapse long ago.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, about 80 elderly people live in the No. 5 complex. However, as of now, the Kangyangyuan has not yet been inspected and has not obtained a business license. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Multiple people familiar with the matter confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that in the second half of 2022, Guo Jianxin and several company managers were arrested by the public security organs for involvement in other cases. Subsequently, the offices of the Old Foundation and Herong Group were moved from No. 8 Shangdu Road, Zhengdong New District to Kangyangyuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Now almost no one is working in the Old Foundation and Herong Group. They come if they have something to do, but they don&#39;t come if there is nothing. They basically go back to their homes.&quot; An insider of the Old Foundation said that No. 5 in Kangyang Garden The second floor of the complex building was originally the office space of the bosses, but now it is hard to find anyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 30, a reporter from Southern Weekend contacted an external relations director of Herong Group as an investor. He said that Kangyangyuan currently still has debts of more than 200 million yuan, of which the construction work is in arrears. The team&#39;s project payment is less than 100 million yuan, and the other more than 100 million yuan is funds collected from some elderly customers before the epidemic and needs to be refunded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feng Chunlai said that Kangyangyuan currently has 30 employees and spends 200,000 to 300,000 yuan a month. The largest expense is water and electricity bills. Although we can collect 3,700 yuan per month from each elderly person, &quot;it&#39;s basically not enough, and we are trying every means to delay and owe money.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can this retirement apartment make money to replenish the principal of the old foundation’s depositors? They can&#39;t think that far ahead. At the moment, the operations here are barely surviving on the money of the elderly living in retirement apartments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Zhang Shihe, Zhang Fenglan, Lu Zhiqiang, Guo Fenghua, and Liu Cuiyun are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[消失的课间十分钟，学校何以成樊笼：“绝对安全”发生学丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260132]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In response to the &quot;disappearing ten minutes between classes&quot; for primary and secondary school students in some places, the Ministry of Education stated that it will resolutely correct it to &quot;ensure The practice of simply restricting students’ necessary recess and activities on the grounds of “student safety”. Subsequently, some schools began to respond, such as media reports: The bell rang, and Dang Xinlong, the vice principal of Shanhaitian Experimental Primary School in Rizhao, Shandong Province, kicked out the students who were still in the classroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this chronic disease has been infiltrated for a long time, is widespread and deep, and I am afraid it cannot be cured by a single statement. Article 8 of the &quot;School Protection Regulations for Minors&quot; that will be implemented on September 1, 2021: Schools shall not set up management measures that infringe on students&#39; personal freedom, and shall not impose any restrictions on students&#39; legitimate communication, games, or activities during recess and other non-teaching time. Unnecessary restrictions are placed on freedom of speech and behavior such as classroom activities. The target is the &quot;disappeared ten minutes between classes&quot;. The problem is that it is difficult for students to make their own decisions. No school believes that it is &quot;unnecessary&quot; to restrict students from leaving the classroom, the teaching building, and the playground during recess. So, the problem remains to be solved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beiqing.com recently reported that a parent said: If children want to leave the classroom during recess, they can basically only go to the toilet and get water. They are not allowed to talk loudly or run or jump on the way; some &quot;loose&quot; schools , the child will be allowed to walk in the corridor and cannot go up or down stairs or to the playground; in more serious cases, the child can only stay in the corridor of his own group and cannot cross the boundary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another media reported in July this year that in Beijing, primary schools generally strictly limit the scope and intensity of students’ recess activities. The reporter randomly visited 27 schools in the central city and found that at least more than 20 schools have strict restrictions on students’ recess activities. restrictions on activities during the period. In addition, some schools in Zhengzhou, Henan, Baoding, Hebei and other places have adopted similar regulations, including not being allowed to leave the teaching building, not leaving the classroom, and not allowed to speak loudly or play around inside or outside the classroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was a child born in the 70s and 80s, I could go out for ten minutes between classes to skip rope, play shuttlecock, hopscotch, play freely and even chase each other, letting go of my nature; outdoors, in the playground, be quiet or active No matter what, it is always suitable, with the blue sky above your head, your feet on the earth, let the sun hit your face, let the breeze blow on your face, and be close to nature, which can instantly rejuvenate and heal the body and mind, and also cultivate simple, strong and resilient character and values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And now, while restricting or even prohibiting children from leaving the classroom, leaving the teaching building, or going to the playground for even ten minutes between classes, they still naively ask: Why are our children so mentally fragile? Why are our boys so fragile? A general lack of masculinity? Isn&#39;t this funny? How can we become strong physically and mentally if we are not even allowed to chase, play and fight? Where does masculinity come from? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did this distorted philosophy and practice come to be? On June 1, 2021, the Director of the Department of Physical Health and Art Education of the Ministry of Education responded to CCTV: &quot;We are afraid that students will be easily injured once they move. Now all schools put safety first... This can also be said to be a failure to eat due to choking. .&quot; Viewed in this way, the pursuit of &quot;absolute safety&quot; and its mechanism are worthy of analysis and reflection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, some parents have problems and believe that the school should be responsible for any personal injury to their children while in school. This imposes unlimited liability on the school. Not to mention that schools can’t do it, parents themselves can’t do it either. Theoretically, there is no one in the world who is more concerned about the safety of their children than parents, but under the care of parents, there are endless incidents of children being injured or even killed. No one wants to see something like this happen, but the world itself contains various known and unknown risks, and we cannot make anti-human demands on schools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, identifying risks, preventing risks, responding to risks, and coexisting with risks are an integral part of everyone&#39;s life, and they are also the basic education that every child must learn to grow up. Very young children do not know what risks are. Of course, they must be kept away from risks and isolated as much as possible. However, children are constantly growing and need to learn the skills to identify, prevent and respond to risks as they grow. This is the most important survival skills education. In a way, it is much more important than knowledge education. And so many schools actually succumb to the ideas of some parents of students and strive to build schools into an absolutely safe space that is isolated from any risks. To this end, they do not hesitate to suppress children&#39;s love of freedom and love of play. This is anti-education in itself and also In vain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, there will always be some weird parents who want to blackmail the school financially when their child has an accident at school, even though it is clearly not the school’s responsibility. But this is not the crux of the problem. The key lies in how schools, education authorities, public prosecutors and law respond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If these three parties can handle the matter according to its merits and legal principles, it will not be the responsibility of the school. The school will not shoulder the responsibility, nor will it be allowed to the school. He Xini will resolutely fight back those who mess around. In this way, righteousness can rise and decent values ​​and correct incentives can be established. Does the school still need to engage in &quot;absolute security&quot; that is anti-education and anti-human? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously it was not the school’s responsibility, but due to the parents’ unreasonable fuss, the school had to compensate the loss on its own or under the pressure of superior departments. This is a bad incentive for some parents who have evil intentions or like to shirk responsibility. In order to avoid another hemorrhage, the logical approach for schools and education authorities is to restrict children&#39;s freedom of movement, confine them to the smallest possible space, and approach the &quot;absolute safety&quot; that isolates all risks. This is the root of the problem. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To a certain extent, this is a social issue and a conceptual issue: children who cry have milk to drink. Whoever has a louder voice and can make more noise will get greater benefits. This phenomenon is still prevalent in public opinion and in all walks of life. &quot;I am weak and I am reasonable&quot;, &quot;I am making trouble and I am justified&quot; and &quot;I am loud and I am justified&quot; have become unspoken rules. Pretending to be weak, being miserable, and using the weak to bully the strong has created another jungle. The children locked up in the classroom are just another group of victims of this jungle law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[记者节之思：新闻理想的坚守与开拓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260074]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The annual Journalists’ Day is here. This is also the time for reporters who are working non-stop and running around all year round to stop and reflect. , an important moment for self-examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today&#39;s world is full of chaos, the century-old changes are accelerating, the media field is deeply integrated and reconstructed, instability and uncertainty factors are significantly increasing, internal and external factors are stirring in the hearts of journalists... At this moment, Journalists&#39; Day, Perhaps each of us journalists should ask themselves the question: Do you still have journalistic ideals? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a journalist, the news ideal is the &quot;beacon light&quot; that guides the direction; the news ideal is the &quot;engine&quot; that drives forward; the news ideal is the &quot;ballast&quot; &quot;Stone&quot; has the function of calming the mind; news ideal is the &quot;regulator&quot; and has the function of prompting and warning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, today, the traditional journalism industry is facing an unprecedented industry shock: the circulation of newspapers and periodicals and radio and television ratings have declined, and the influence of the media has declined; the media industry has operating difficulties, and the income of news practitioners has decreased. ; The number of people leaving their jobs has increased, and people quitting the industry have been heard from time to time; the number of enrollment in journalism and communication majors in colleges and universities has been reduced, and the employment situation of graduates has become tighter... There is no shortage of comments on the Internet about candidates who plan to apply for the journalism and communication major. Although it is not without bias, This is by no means groundless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the founding words of &quot;Xiangjiang Review&quot;, Mao Zedong enthusiastically asked: &quot;What is the biggest problem in the world? The biggest problem is the problem of food.&quot; When the traditional journalism industry is climbing up and over the hurdles, a group of people who are confused and emotionally anxious have emerged. Psychological Inevitability – Will Traditional Journalism Die? Is there a future for journalism? Do we still need journalistic ideals? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As long as we carefully study the history, reality and future development trends of journalism, we will find that traditional journalism will not disappear. Journalism still has its own future, and we still need journalistic ideals. This is because: From the perspective of the origin of journalism, news originates from people’s curiosity. As long as people’s curiosity does not die, journalism will not disappear. From the perspective of the evolution of journalism, although the carrier of news is constantly changing, the functional role of journalism has not disappeared. However, compared with the traditional ways of reading newspapers, listening to radio, and watching TV in the past, people now obtain news in a different way. It’s just a new carrier such as a mobile phone. From the perspective of audience needs, news focuses on meeting people&#39;s communication needs. As long as people&#39;s communication needs exist, the demand for journalism will always exist. From the perspective of journalism production, the authoritative news, in-depth reports, news reviews, elegant programs and other products provided by traditional media cannot be replaced by the vast number of new media and self-media. Therefore, traditional journalism is unlikely to disappear in any of the above senses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since it is impossible for traditional journalism to disappear, it is impossible for journalists to disappear. The ideal of journalism will inevitably accompany and advance together with journalists. Otherwise, we will lose our way and lose our way. Without motivation, lack of soul, and chaos, you will be at a loss, useless, muddle along, and do nothing. Therefore, in such a special context of the times, each of us journalists must still have journalistic ideals in mind, promote journalistic ideals, adhere to journalistic ideals, and practice journalistic ideals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Always have a loyal heart. Loyalty means that as a journalist, don’t ask what the country has done for me, but ask what I have done for the country; loyalty means not being confused in the face of major events, not wavering at critical moments, and being able to withstand various complex situations and problems. The test; loyalty means being indifferent to fame and wealth, willing to work as a coolie, working hard, sweating, and traveling thousands of miles for journalism, and striving to become an excellent journalist. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Always maintain a keen sense. Sensitivity is an essential quality for professional journalists. Only journalists who are sharp-minded, have unique vision, are good at seeing the subtleties, react quickly, and have a pen with a sharp eye can effectively enhance the dissemination, guidance, influence and credibility of news and public opinion work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We must always practice seeking truth. The world-famous journalist Farage once said: &quot;A reporter&#39;s duty is to reveal the truth.&quot; In an era of widespread media communication, despite the excess of news information, real news is always valuable. We should always maintain the spirit of truth-seeking, practice truth-seeking skills, and provide the public with truth, true knowledge, true feelings, and truth in a timely and rapid manner in the turbulent world of massive information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Always hold the ruler of justice. Some people say: &quot;The reporter&#39;s pen contains countless fortunes, reputation and reputation, loyalty and villainy, right and wrong, and life and death.&quot; This shows how heavy the reporter&#39;s pen is. Therefore, we reporters should be very clear about why we write, what we write, how we write, and to what extent we write. We must always grasp the yardstick of &quot;fairness&quot; and must not be influenced by some kind of power, money, or interest relationship. Those pens soaked in grease and booze can&#39;t possibly do them justice. This is why we need to always be in awe of &quot;justice&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the occasion of Journalists’ Day, I wish every journalist’s journalistic ideals to be evergreen and never wither! &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is from the media in Hebei)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;span>; 163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 10:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[森林消防“全覆盖”31个省份]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260136]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;(On the morning of November 7, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce Progress in the reform of the fire rescue system. Southern Weekend reporter Li Guitu)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/26de373a44.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/26de373a44.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257291&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;On the morning of November 7, 2023, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce the progress of the reform of the fire rescue system. Southern Weekend reporter Li Guitu)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Firefighting work and the construction of fire rescue teams have undergone all-round and profound changes.&quot; On the morning of November 7, 2023, at the State Council At a press conference held by the Information Office, Qiong Se, member of the Party Committee of the Ministry of Emergency Management and director of the National Fire Rescue Bureau, introduced the construction and development of the national comprehensive fire rescue team in its fifth anniversary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In October 2018, the public security fire brigade and the armed police forest brigade retired from active service and were placed under the Ministry of Emergency Management to establish a national comprehensive fire rescue team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se said that in the past five years, nearly 200,000 teams have successfully completed transfers of subordinates, identity changes, rank changes, title changes, and official positions. work, establish the National Fire Rescue Bureau, implement unified leadership and hierarchical command, clarify the major principles of central construction and local use, and establish a dual management system that combines sections and focuses on sections. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023 is the sixth year for open recruitment of firefighters after the establishment of the national comprehensive fire rescue team. Li Shangyu, head of the Education and Training Department of the Ministry of Emergency Management, said that there was a plan to recruit 15,000 people in 2023, but nearly 110,000 people signed up, marking the fourth consecutive full recruitment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shangyu introduced that the average age of new firefighters is 21.8 years old, and 52.6% have a college degree or above. They are currently undergoing a one-year induction training. So far, the total number of firefighters recruited after the transformation has reached more than 94,000, accounting for 65.3% of the total number of existing firefighters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Forest firefighting adds more than 8,200 people&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;National firefighting After the rescue bureau was officially established, a new mobile team was formed. Xu Zhongshun, deputy director of the National Fire and Rescue Bureau, said that this is &quot;a major decision made based on the basic national conditions of my country&#39;s frequent natural disasters.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Zhongshun said that as a critical force in national emergencies and major disasters, the mobile team is mainly responsible for forest and grassland firefighting duties, supplemented by flood fighting and earthquake and geological disaster rescue. Responsibilities, task arrangements focus on fire fighting in winter and spring, flood control in summer and autumn, year-round disaster relief, seasonal cross-regional garrison, and implementation of preparatory operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The National Fire and Rescue Administration has integrated the forest fire corps and related fire and rescue mobile detachments, forming 10 cross-regional fire and rescue mobile corps and several detachments, brigades, and squadrons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among them, the original establishment of forest firefighting teams is 25,000, mainly deployed in 10 provinces including Inner Mongolia, Jilin, Heilongjiang, Fujian, and Sichuan. On this basis, the Central Organization Office has approved the establishment of more than 8,200 forest firefighting teams, mainly to strengthen the first-line firefighting and rescue mobile forces in key forest areas, national parks, seven major river basins and surrounding areas across the country, and to achieve comprehensive coverage of 31 provinces. &quot;Full coverage&quot; of all administrative regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xu Zhongshun said that as of now, 17 provinces in the first batch of additional mobile teams have basically completed their deployment, and are now organizing the second batch of additional mobile teams. There are teams stationed in 3 provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;All disasters, major emergencies&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Firefighting After the rescue team was reformed and transformed, its functions have also been expanded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se introduced that on the basis of the original fire fighting and emergency rescue focusing on rescuing people&#39;s lives, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau focuses on &quot;all disaster types&quot;. The comprehensive rescue expansion of &quot;big emergency&quot; covers urban and rural and forest and grassland fire fighting, as well as disaster accident rescue such as floods, earthquakes, geology, typhoons, building collapses, and hazardous chemical leakage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Taking 2022 as an example, fire rescue teams across the country received reports and handled 2.092 million disasters of various types, including 824,000 fire rescues and 469,000 emergency rescues. , 597,000 cases of various types of social assistance, 126,000 cases of official duties, and 76,000 cases of other dispatches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this total number of rescues, fire fighting is still the main type of accident that the fire rescue team responds to. At the same time, police situations involving water areas, mountains, production and equipment failures, trapped elevators, and traffic accidents accounted for 87.4% of the total number of rescues. &quot;They are the main types of rescues and are also the key directions for the expansion of functional tasks after the reform and restructuring.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiong Se said that in response to these situations, in recent years, the National Fire and Rescue Bureau has vigorously strengthened the construction of professional forces and established a total of high-rise buildings, underground spaces, large commercial complexes, etc. There are more than 3,500 professional firefighting teams in the body and petrochemical enterprises, as well as earthquake, water, air, and rain, snow and ice rescue teams. Relying on the forest firefighting team, 12 special disaster rescue brigades and 55 affiliated rapid response teams have been established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[中山二院乳腺外科多人患癌？医院通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260152]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 08:35:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On November 7, 2023, our hospital noticed that &quot;Zhongshan Second Hospital Breast Disease&quot; was spread on the Internet. The surgical team is suspected of being affected by the experimental environment and reagents, causing many people to develop cancer.&quot; The hospital quickly organized an investigation and verification, and initially learned that: 3 people who worked and studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center in recent years have suffered from cancer, 2 of whom are now breast surgeons in our hospital and are working in clinical practice; the other 1 is not from us. The employees or students of the institute are those who come to the institute for further study from other places and have returned to work in their original units. No current student in this laboratory has contracted cancer. The specific situation is as follows: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Huang, female, studied for a doctoral degree in our hospital from 2017 to 2022, during which she studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center, and graduated with a doctoral degree in July 2022 Later, he joined the Breast Surgery Department of our hospital and engaged in clinical work. He was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in October 2023 and underwent surgery. His current condition is stable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Liu, male, studied for a doctoral degree in our hospital from 2013 to 2018. During this period, he studied in the laboratory of the Breast Cancer Center. He joined our hospital after graduating from the Ph.D. in August 2018. Breast surgery, engaged in clinical work. In June 2023, he was diagnosed with synovial sarcoma and underwent surgery. He recovered well after the operation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the above two employees became ill, the hospital has been caring about their health and organized expert consultations, visits and condolences. Another researcher is a doctoral student who graduated from a foreign hospital. In 2021, he came to our hospital for a year of further study and worked in the laboratory of the Breast Tumor Center. He completed his further study in April 2022 and left Guangzhou. In 2023, he was diagnosed with breast cancer at his place of work. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Breast Cancer Center Laboratory was opened in 2009 and has trained more than 200 students so far. Since its establishment, the laboratory has been managed in strict accordance with the regulations, and all experimental personnel have been trained on safety and standardized operations before experiments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In response to public concerns about laboratory safety management, our hospital will continue to maintain safety red lines and consciously accept inspections and supervision from superior authorities. We also thank netizens for their opinions and suggestions. . Regarding concerns about linking cancer to laboratory or reagent exposure, given that the causes of individual cancer are extremely complex, relevant departments are sincerely welcome to organize third-party agencies to conduct assessment and investigations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Finally, I would like to thank all sectors of society for their care and concern for the health of medical workers. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Sun Yat-sen Memorial Hospital of Sun Yat-sen University&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;November 8, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[炮弹落在畹町镇：一座边陲小镇活在缅北战火旁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260124]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wanding Town resident Wu Xia photographed the war situation in Myanmar from the roof, blue in the distance The house on the roof is in Myanmar. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/65c4f43e62.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1131&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/65c4f43e62.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257281&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wanding Town resident Wu Xia took pictures of the war in Myanmar from the rooftop. The houses with blue roofs in the distance are in Myanmar. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the fifth day of the civil war in northern Myanmar, Wu Xia, who lives in the border town of Wanding, was so scared when she heard the sound of gunfire not far away that she turned off the iron Snack bar, hiding in a home made of reinforced concrete. Having lived in Wanding for more than 20 years, she told the Southern Weekend reporter that there had been wars on the opposite side before, with mostly gunshots, but the fighting in 2023 was the most fierce, all with heavy shelling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xia climbed to the roof of her house, where she could see Myanmar across the river. In a 39-second video she shot, the sound of gunfire and artillery continued from the valley, and helicopters circled the top of the mountain. At the foot of the mountain were dense houses, stretching from Myanmar to the eastern town of Ruili City, Yunnan Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 27, 2023, government army strongholds in many places in northern Myanmar were attacked by armed forces and exchanges of fire broke out. The fighting was fierce and the stalemate has continued to this day. On the national border, Wanding Town, which borders Bangsai Town in Myanmar, is a Chinese town that has been greatly affected by the war. Stray bullets have fallen into this town of about 10,000 people many times. In order to ensure the safety of residents, the local government arranged for school closures and mobilized residents to leave the town to avoid the war. The town implemented a &quot;only exit, no entry&quot; control policy, and even the town government staff evacuated to work in safe places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wanding Town is located on the border of China and Myanmar. Map by Liang Shuyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/19501b6c86. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;986&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/19501b6c86.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257282&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wanding Town is located on the border of China and Myanmar. Drawing by Liang Shuyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Don’t come out of your home”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the morning of October 28, a shell from Myanmar hit a residential building in Wanding Town, destroying the top four floors. A big hole was blown out of the building. A few hours after the explosion, Mr. Yang, who sells aluminum doors and windows, rushed to the scene out of curiosity. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the shell had exploded and there were no casualties. “An old lady told me that when the shell exploded, It was so shaken that she couldn&#39;t hear anything for two hours.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Peng Qi first heard the sound of shells and gunshots, she didn&#39;t know what they were. She thought someone was setting off fireworks. In June 2023, she was transferred from Ruili City to Wanding Town and worked as a store manager in a chain milk tea shop. The locals told her that it was the sound of war in Myanmar and comforted her: &quot;It&#39;s okay, we hear this sound every year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The locals who are used to the sound of gunfire seem to be also attracted by it. This time the battle was frightening. At two or three o&#39;clock in the morning on October 29, Wu Xia was awakened by several gunshots while she was sleeping. That day, she listened to the sound of gunfire outside and judged that the exchange of fire between the two parties was fierce. The windows of a house about 200 meters away from her home were shattered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wuxia Snack Shop sells some local specialty snacks, such as Pauluda, fried bait cubes, etc. It is only about 200 meters away from Wanding Port. Children in the third grade of primary school are afraid that artillery shells will penetrate the iron sheet and will go home when they hear the sound of artillery fire. Wu Xia believes that hiding at home is not necessarily safe. &quot;If there are really shells coming, you can&#39;t hide anywhere.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan, who lives by the boundary river, seems to be at greater risk. She once saw a picture of a helicopter bombing on the other side of the river on a short video platform. The community administrator also kept telling her not to come out of the house. However, She works at Wanding Town Health Center and still needs to report to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that on October 31, she was at work when she was suddenly informed that a large crater had been blown up near her home, and her son, who was in primary school, was staying at home alone. &quot;It was really urgent at the time. I called my husband and ran home. When I got home and opened the door, I saw that my son was taking a nap.&quot; Tao Wan looked at her son sleeping soundly and felt, &quot;My heart is going to be broken.&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan told Southern Weekend reporters that when she was a child, the sound of fighting on the other side of the river could be heard in Wanding Town. The most intense year.&quot; The scene of community workers and street broadcasts telling residents to retreat and avoid the fighting made Tao Wan feel panic like never before, &quot;I felt like I had to leave this home.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewees told Southern Weekend reporters that on October 27, the night when the war broke out, community members came to persuade them to leave: “If you have family and friends in Ruili, go to Ruili. &quot;Not only that, the community also informed that if you hear the sound of gunfire, please do not go out, and immediately find shelter to take shelter. Do not wait and see out of curiosity, and avoid exposing your body in open spaces to avoid being hit by stray bullets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 3, an on-duty staff member of the Wanding Town Government told Southern Weekend reporters that the staff in the government building had moved to a relatively safe place to work, leaving only a few on-duty staff, and the new place was still open. Within the Wanding area, it is five or six kilometers away from the town government building. The reason why they moved out of the town government building was because the building was &quot;directly opposite Myanmar and posed a major safety hazard.&quot; The person on duty said he was unclear about how many people were transferred in Wanding Town and when students would resume classes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The fourth floor of a residential building in the town was hit by a shell, but fortunately there were no casualties. Photo provided by the interviewee&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/daa5b0ac75.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1050&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/daa5b0ac75.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257283&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Town The fourth floor of a residential building was hit by a shell, but fortunately there were no casualties. Photo provided by the interviewee&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The watermelon business chain is broken&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Residents living in Wanding noticed that this war was different from usual signals. In addition to the fierce gunfire, there were also Students are completely suspended from classes. The milk tea shop where Peng Qi works is only a few hundred meters away from Wanding Middle School. She discovered that on the night of Friday, October 27, all the high school students who were originally on holiday on Sunday were taken home by their parents. Wu Xia&#39;s snack bar is not far from the middle school. She saw many parents driving to the school gate to pick up their students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Lili, a 21-year-old girl who grew up in Wanding, recalled that there was an emergency in the local area a few years ago when classes were suspended due to the war in Myanmar, but she could not remember the time clearly. She only remembered that it was the same time at that time. There are stray bullets flying into the territory. &quot;The most serious thing in recent years is the two incidents of stray bullets flying over. The situation in Myanmar has always been unstable. Once war starts, Wanding&#39;s geographical location is destined to be affected.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Cai In Lily&#39;s impression, there is only a boundary river two or three meters wide, and there are frequent exchanges between Wanding and the Myanmar town of Bangsai on the other side. She recalled that when she was five or six years old, it was easy to travel to Myanmar from the border crossing. When she was in primary school, seven or eight of the more than 40 students in her class were from Myanmar. &quot;We all studied Chinese courses and we all played together.&quot; The boundary river is also one of her recreational areas. She often goes fishing and picnicking by the river with her family and friends. A walking trail is built close to the boundary river, and Wanding residents often go for walks by the river. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that some Wanding residents were indeed accidentally injured, mostly with skin injuries. &quot;After we debridement, we will ask them to go home quickly, because the hospital is located on a relatively high ground and is not safe. Some people were also transferred to higher-level hospitals by ambulances.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xia discovered that since the beginning of the Northern Myanmar War Later, there were fewer and fewer people on the streets, especially tourists. As a famous border town and border port, there are endless tourists here all year round. Her snack bar is not far from the national gate and has about a hundred customers every day. But after the war broke out, only a few old customers who lived nearby came to the store, and &quot;there was no one on this street.&quot; Not only that, on October 30, the &quot;only go out, no go in&quot; rule was implemented in the central area of ​​Wanding Town. However, according to locals, the rule was only implemented for two days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Peng Qi also obviously felt that the flow of people had dropped sharply. In an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter at 16:00 on November 2, Peng Qi said that the store&#39;s turnover that day was only more than 100 yuan, which is the price of about 10 cups of milk tea, and most of the customers were from nearby shops. Before the war, the store&#39;s daily turnover was about one thousand yuan. There are also brave tourists who go to the border to shoot short videos. Wu Xia said: &quot;Many men and women may also be afraid. They basically just take pictures and leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the men and women Wu Xia saw, Perhaps there is also Zhou Feng, a melon seller. On November 2, 37-year-old Zhou Feng also visited the national gate of Wanding, but his destination was the Wanding Watermelon Wholesale Market. As the largest watermelon market in Southeast Asia, from the end of October to May of the following year is the time when Myanmar watermelons are on the market and exported to China. Zhou Feng revealed that during peak periods, the market could have 1,000 vehicles a day, each carrying 16 tons of watermelons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of October 2023, the price of Myanmar watermelon that has just been launched can reach four or five yuan per kilogram, which is not low. After the war broke out, Wanding&#39;s national gate was closed and watermelon could not enter the territory. Zhou Feng analyzed that the most affected people in the watermelon industry chain are melon farmers. The price of contracted land in Myanmar is relatively low, only three to four hundred yuan per mu, so most of the people who plant watermelons on contracted land in Myanmar are Chinese. Zhou Feng has been engaged in this industry for 13 years. He is grateful that it is the early stage of the watermelon market. &quot;If it takes more than a month to start the war, I will be annoyed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In previous years, at the Wanding Watermelon Wholesale Market, the melon stalls were filled with watermelons imported from Myanmar. Oriental IC Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/07/0f278c71c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /07/0f278c71c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257284&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In previous years, the watermelon wholesale market in Wanding was full of melon stalls Watermelons imported from Myanmar. Oriental IC Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Eerily Quiet&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Not all Wanding residents were affected by the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 3 communities and 3 administrative villages within the jurisdiction of Wanding Town. 26-year-old Guo Yu lives with his family in Hunban Village, which is about 5 kilometers away from the border port and one or two kilometers away from Myanmar. Guo Yu runs a B&amp;B. Since the war started, there have been no guests staying. Fortunately, the shells did not fall near them, and the family&#39;s food, clothing, housing and transportation were not affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guo Yu’s mother is from Myanmar, and his father’s ancestral home is in Baoshan City, Yunnan Province. When they were young, they came to Wanding to buy land and build a house, and settled here. Guo Yu told Southern Weekend reporters that his grandmother&#39;s house was not affected by the war and was relatively safe for the time being. Guo Yu also feels safe and has no plans to move away. However, if the shells hit nearby, the family may move to Ruili, 20 kilometers away, and stay with relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan was not prepared to evacuate, but sent her youngest son back to her husband&#39;s hometown in Dehong Prefecture overnight. &quot;We all rely on ourselves to buy a house and a car. This is my home. If I leave, it won&#39;t even have its roots.&quot; Since October 27, Tao Wan has been feeling uneasy every day. She is afraid that if an accident occurs, the house will be lost. . &quot;I don&#39;t know what to do in that situation. When I think of this possibility, I almost burst into tears.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan came to Wanding Town with her mother when she was 5 years old. Now she has Is 40 years old. Because she had to take care of her mother who didn&#39;t want to leave Wanding, Tao Wan, who went to college abroad, came back here again, until now. After the war broke out, Tao Wan placed her mother in a village far away from the border. She planned to wait until the war calmed down before taking the old man home. Tao Wan said that there are some elderly people in the town who have inconvenient legs and feet who are unwilling to move. They have deep feelings for Wanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Dai language, Wanding means &quot;the place where the sun is at the top&quot;. Today, the town&#39;s shine is no longer dazzling. In Tao Wan&#39;s impression, Wanding was prosperous 20 to 30 years ago. Later, due to road planning, administrative divisions and other reasons, Wanding was slowly declining. Tao Wan felt aggrieved for the small town where she lived, &quot;There was an epidemic in the past three years, and now there is this war.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cai Lili never felt that she was a girl who came out of a small town. She felt that Wanding was more like a small city. She remembers that Wanding Town was very lively around 2007, with people coming and going, and the shops on the street would sell Myanmar specialties, such as hot and sour noodles, milk candies, etc. Now, some of the shops that impressed Cai Lili have been closed, and many shops on the street are empty. &quot;After its decline in recent years, I gradually felt that it was really just a small town.&quot; Cai Lili said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, this town is facing another test. On November 6, Peng Qi told Southern Weekend reporters that compared with the chaotic sound of gunfire in the past few days, the streets in Wanding are now &quot;eerily quiet&quot;. Except for the occasional pedestrian passing by, only military green trucks are left on the street. patrol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tao Wan has not heard the sound of gunfire recently, but she feels that the government departments and schools have shown no signs of relaxing. The school has not notified the resumption of classes. Teaching is conducted in the form of online classes. The community still counts daily and has not evacuated. resident information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, the characters in the article are pseudonyms)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“局外人”到“第一个人”：加缪110周年诞辰]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260148]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:45:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRmVSmK7F8E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1241&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/X8roS3vaHvLlXA5wUixtuv0kj5ZOHMRm VSmK7F8E. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257306&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Albert Camus (November 7, 1913 - 1960 January 4), French writer and philosopher, born in Algeria. He won the Nobel Prize for Literature at the age of 44 and died unexpectedly at the age of 47. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, 1913, Albert Camus was born. On January 4, 1960, he died in an accidental car accident at the age of 46. Today, it has been 110 years since Camus was born and more than sixty years since his death, but people do not feel that Camus belongs to a distant era. He used his short writing career to create a series of distinctive contemporary images. , is still closely related to our living situation today. The embarrassment, discord, and sense of powerlessness of &quot;outsiders&quot;, the repeated hard labor in &quot;Sisyphus&quot;, and the struggle and dignity of people facing disaster in &quot;The Plague&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus is both a writer and a thinker. He does not capture readers with the splendor of his words, but shocks them with his postmodern understanding of life. He is the youngest winner of the Nobel Prize for Literature. one. Camus&#39;s enduring popularity is symptomatic. Just like Kafka, he wrote a &quot;clinical diagnosis&quot; of contemporary people&#39;s mental dilemma; just like Lu Xun, he does not provide bright answers, or even It&#39;s a bit dark and cold, but at the end of the coldness is a philosophy of resistance and hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus once worked as a journalist. On January 1, 1940, he wrote an editorial for the last issue of the &quot;Republican Evening News&quot;. You can get a glimpse of his restraint, coolness, and calmness with a sense of power. Words: &quot;This year, hoping for happiness will be in vain, building it through work is the key. Don&#39;t hope for anything, but do something. Don&#39;t wait for others to build your destiny from beginning to end, especially when destiny It is still in our hands. The Evening Republican will not wish you happiness this year, knowing that you are going through a severe physical and mental trauma. But it will ask you to maintain the necessary strength and sobriety to strive to maintain your own tranquility and dignity. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was the darkest moment of World War II. Shortly after Camus wrote this dedication, while fleeing on the border of France and Spain, Benjamin failed to get a pass and came to the end of his life. At the end, although Zweig fled to Brazil, he still committed suicide in despair. Camus belongs to a new generation of young people. He once joined the French Communist Party, fought and resisted, and condensed the power of his resistance into continuous writing. If the deaths of Benjamin and Zweig marked the spiritual boundaries of yesterday&#39;s world, Camus established the starting point of his writing on the wasteland of war and post-war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The postwar world is neither a wasteland nor a new heaven and a new earth. His arguments with his friend Sartre and his ambivalent attitude toward the Algerian War made Camus increasingly lonely while receiving literary honors. When he returned to autobiographical writing and the &quot;first person&quot;, an accident caused this sharp soul to bid farewell in advance. For a writer like Camus, commemorating him at any time is both our condolences and an invitation for him to return. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;France’s “outsider”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 2 a.m. on November 7, 1913, her mother Catalina gave birth to Camus, who was the first child in the family. second son. The next day, at the Mondovi Municipal Government in Algeria, the father registered the birth of his child. He was 28 years old and worked as a wine cellar manager. The mother was 31 years old and filled in the occupation column as a housewife. The birthplace of Saint-Paul Farm is located 8 kilometers south of the city of Mondovi. The nearby city of Bonny is the most important port in French Algeria, not far from the Tunisian border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Algeria became a French colony in the 19th century, most of the immigrants who immigrated here were poor people from all over France, as well as Spain, Italy and other European countries. New immigrants were granted residence rights under French protection and lived among the overwhelming majority of locals. “The French in Algeria are of mixed race. Spaniards, Alsatians, Italians, Maltese, Jews, Greeks gather there,” Camus later wrote. Camus is a mixed-race child, his mother is Spanish, and he believes that his father comes from Alsace, the battlefield where France and Germany have fought for generations. The reason for &quot;thinking&quot; is that my father&#39;s exact ancestral home has been lost and difficult to find. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Camus had never met his father before he could remember. My father is 1.8 meters tall, with brown hair and blue eyes. He works in a wine company, supervising the grape pressing, winemaking, storage, and shipment to the Port of Pawnee for shipment. Not long after Camus was born, World War I broke out, and his father was conscripted into the French army. Almost as soon as he entered the battlefield, he was injured in the Battle of the Marne to prevent the German army from advancing towards Paris. He was hit by shell fragments and was sent to a rear hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 11, 1914, my mother received the bad news by telegram, as well as a small piece of shrapnel removed from her husband&#39;s head that the widow had asked to keep. His father was mysterious to Camus. He often asked his mother: &quot;Am I really like my father?&quot; &quot;Oh, you look exactly like your father.&quot; During the four years of World War I, his mother received no After passing a penny in France, it was only a few months before the end of the war that I received official notification of her husband&#39;s death and a pension check. An accountant next door helped her fill out the pension application form because no one in her family knew how to fill it out. In order to make a living, my mother sorted warheads in an ammunition manufacturing factory until she suffered from rheumatism and was unable to continue this work, so she began to work as a domestic helper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 8 months to 17 years old, Camus lived with his mother and grandmother under the same roof in Algiers, the capital of Algeria. It was Belku, the workers&#39; district of the city, home to people who worked hard in small workshops and port equipment factories, craftsmen, small traders, grassroots civil servants and clerks. As an adult, Camus returned to the house frequently, sometimes to visit the elderly and sometimes as a temporary haven. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was in middle school, football fascinated Camus. He was very brave and liked to tackle from the feet of his opponents, so he was often injured. Camus described a fierce football match, on a pitch adjacent to a cemetery, in which the opposing players pressed forward mercilessly. They “were all on top of me, spikes on my shins, knees on my crotch, squeezing me against the goal post…” “I quickly learned that the ball doesn’t come from where you expect it to. This was very helpful in my life, especially in France, where not everyone is honest,&quot; Camus later wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Camus came to settle in Paris in early 1940, he felt that &quot;I am not from here, nor from anywhere else. The world is just a strange scenery, and my spirit is helpless here. Everything It has nothing to do with yourself.” He was stuck between France and Algeria, between Paris and impoverished Bercoux across the Mediterranean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;969&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/D85zsS7RbQjcftzjyXxFffCFWWU1bBZahgssH1sC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257305&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Camus (first from right) is backstage with two actors during the performance of his drama &quot;Martial Law&quot; in Paris in 1948. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“西西弗”：胜利的失败者&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;当中产阶级出身的萨特做着文学英雄梦，波伏娃享受着她的书籍和糖果店橱窗里的礼物时，加缪却在一个家里没有电、没有自来水、没有报纸和书、没有收音机的世界长大，他曾在日记本里写下：“一穷二白地过上若干年，就足以创造全部的敏感性。”肺结核困扰了加缪一生，但也让他免于服兵役。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1942年，《局外人》和《西西弗神话》相继出版。前者讲述了一个叫默尔索的法裔阿尔及利亚人，经历了两场死亡，第一场是妈妈的死，他甚至记不得日期，也没有流泪，第二场是他在海滩上与一名持刀的阿拉伯人发生冲突，默尔索碰巧拿着一把朋友的枪，被海面和刀锋的反光晃到眼睛时，几乎下意识地朝那人开了一枪。被逮捕后，默尔索困惑地告诉法官，他开枪的原因是太阳，默尔索并没有为自己辩护，而法庭也对命案缺乏兴趣，关注点都在调查他的个人生活上，他的冷漠成了最大的罪证，被宣判死刑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随笔集《西西弗神话》的标题取自《荷马史诗》里的一个故事，国王西西弗违抗神意，被判罚永无休止地推一块巨石上山，每次石头接近山顶时，就会从他手中滑落，再滚下去，他只能重新返回，周而复始。加缪通过西西弗神话，就像弗洛伊德通过俄狄浦斯情结，让神话人物重新深入人心。 《西西弗神话》中最有名的句子可能是：“只有一个哲学问题是真正严肃的，即自杀。判断生活值得还是不值得去过……”多年后的一篇英译本前言里，加缪说，写作这本书是因为“即使在虚无主义的边界之内，也有可能找到超越虚无主义而继续前行的方法”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1944年出版的戏剧《卡里古拉》，通过再现被刺杀的罗马皇帝苏埃托尼乌斯的故事，讨论了被推到极限程度的自由和无意义。这三本书合称加缪的“荒诞三部曲”。它们写作、出版于战争的临界状态和被占领的巴黎，一切都在妥协，一切都在迷失，加缪从克尔凯郭尔的存在主义哲学里，看到了用儿子献祭的亚伯拉罕“无限地放弃了一切，然后又靠荒诞的力量，把一切都夺了回来”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;萨特的戏剧《苍蝇》排练时，加缪主动结识了他，两人一见如故，之前，萨特为加缪的小说《局外人》写过文章，加缪则评论过萨特的《恶心》。波伏娃和萨特发现，加缪是一个简单、快乐的人，谈话时总是有趣而粗俗，十分情绪化，甚至会在凌晨两点坐在下雪的街上，倾诉他的爱情烦恼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“唐·璜从一个女人到另一个女人并非是缺乏爱情，而是以相等的激情去爱她们，且每一次都是全身心地投入，他必须重复这种天禀和探索……为什么必须爱得少才能爱得好呢？”《西西弗神话》里写道。加缪有过两段婚姻，第一任妻子西蒙娜因为无法戒除吗啡，给他造成过巨大的心理创伤，与弗朗西娜再婚后，加缪又与多位女性保持半公开的亲密关系，包括互通八百余封情书的戏剧演员玛利亚·卡萨雷斯。仿佛唐·璜成了推巨石的西西弗的一个化身。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“鼠疫”：终末与反抗&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;二战结束，巴黎解放后，萨特、波伏娃和加缪的声望如日中天，左岸的花神和双叟咖啡馆，笼罩着存在主义作家的光晕，光晕的半径一直延伸到大洋彼岸的美国。他们三人都先后收到了来自纽约的访问邀请。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1946年3月到5月，加缪周游了美国，他比萨特还要紧张，觉得自己总被层出不穷的小麻烦影响。他也是一个细致的观察者，发现美国人喜欢在早晨喝果汁，全国都爱喝苏格兰威士忌和苏打水，热衷于动物，从布朗克斯动物园的大猩猩，到自然历史博物馆的动物标本，都爱，死亡和死者能以最快的速度被打扮好，“死吧，把剩下的事交给我们”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唯一让加缪感到熟悉和安心的地方，是纽约的包厘街道，当时，这里还是一个废弃的地区，到处是廉价酒吧和破败的酒店，高架铁路从二楼的高度经过，阴影盖住了下面的一切。加缪对美国感到厌恶，觉得这里缺少痛苦和悲剧，但在许多评论家看来，《局外人》正是模仿了美国的黑色小说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1947年，长篇小说《鼠疫》出版，深受读者欢迎，两年内重印了八次。之后，《鼠疫》和《局外人》在法国的文学畅销书榜单上，长期名列前茅。 1941年到1942年间，阿尔及利亚流行瘟疫，是加缪酝酿《鼠疫》的起点，而这部小说之所以如此惊心动魄，是因为瘟疫既被描写得真实可怖，又具有象征性，它影射的是二战期间，德国纳粹肆虐逞凶的严酷现实。纳粹和法西斯主义，也是一种政治和精神的瘟疫，它的军事强权、特务系统、专制和种族主义，像死神一样席卷一切，而遭受它摆布后，或屈服，或配合，或知其不可而为之地反抗的人，也像鼠疫中的众生百态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“加缪特别突出了三种生活象征性的境况，一是分离的境况，包括亲属的分离、夫妻的分离、情人的分离，这些意味着隔离、封锁、囚禁、流亡、集中营……二是小说中没有任何一个女性的境况，这意味着失衡、畸形、苦涩、没有生机……最恐怖的氛围与境况还是死亡……”《鼠疫》中文版的译者柳鸣九说，“&#39;人人身上都潜伏着鼠疫，因为，没有人，是的，世界上没有人能免受其害&#39;……这样，加缪在《鼠疫》中也就把他关于荒诞世界的哲理大大拓宽了一步，加深了一步，并将荒诞的根由指向人类的过失和人类社会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二战的绝境中，不只是加缪选择通过瘟疫的背景来书写一种临界状态，德国剧作家布莱希特也创作了《伽利略传》，剧中的伽利略同样经历了瘟疫的九死一生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我试图通过鼠疫来表现我们所遭受的窒息以及我们所承受的威胁着人、将人流放的环境。”加缪说。在末日的阿赫兰城，小说的主人公贝尔纳·里厄医生，因为恪尽职守，成了一位平凡的英雄。加缪通过反英雄的形式重塑英雄，当灾厄降临，我们能期待的，不是一个从天而降的英雄，而是每一个普通人通过最微小的努力去反抗恶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1951年出版的随笔集《反抗者》，更是加缪继荒诞哲学之后，旗帜鲜明地提出反抗哲学，“何谓反抗者？一个说&#39;不&#39;的人。然而，他虽然拒绝，却并不放弃：他也是从一开始行动就说&#39;是&#39;的人。”然而，这本信息量巨大的书，却令他陷入四面楚歌的境地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;回到“第一个人”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《反抗者》涉及对超现实主义的评论，立刻遭到该团体从文学上的批驳。更激烈的批评来自左派思想家，由于不同意加缪对革命和苏联历史的许多看法，萨特主编的《现代》杂志发表了该刊编辑法朗西斯·尚松措辞激烈的批判文章。加缪不得不做出回应，写了一封给萨特的公开信，进行自我辩护。这又引来了萨特的《答加缪书》，极其严厉、刻薄，称加缪“是个资产者”“抛弃了历史”，《反抗者》的出版是一场反革命的“热月政变”。两人多年的友谊毁于一旦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与许多仅仅以“纯文学”来界定写作的作家不同，加缪一直是一位有机知识分子，正是《反抗者》强烈的“政治性”捅了马蜂窝。萨特与加缪这对存在主义作家的决裂，与后来法国电影新浪潮双子星戈达尔和特吕弗的割席，都成了战后文化史上轰动一时又耐人寻味的事件。萨特站在更激进的位置，连对待诺奖，他也更激进，直接拒绝。令人唏嘘的是，加缪这样一位一直属于进步阵营的作家，因为在某些议题上更温和，或者不追随某一原则、教条，提出了个人的理解和判断，就被斥为保守。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1949年，加缪曾创作了一部戏剧《正义者》，剧中一群“恐怖分子”争论在进行政治暗杀时，是否可以殃及无辜。加缪明确表示，这是错的。 1954年，阿尔及利亚爆发独立斗争时，他也认为起义军埋设炸弹、杀死无辜者，与法国政府的暴力、极刑，同样不正当。这个观点让他饱受争议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1957年，在庆祝加缪获得诺贝尔文学奖的讲话中，有人要求加缪解释他不支持反抗殖民主义的阿尔及利亚起义军的原因，他说：“现在人们正往阿尔及利亚的电车轨道上放炸弹。我母亲可能就在其中一条车轨上。如果这就是正义的话，那么我宁愿选择我的母亲。”加缪呼吁在阿尔及利亚建立一个阿拉伯人、柏柏尔人、黑脚法国人（欧洲移民）平等执政的联合政府，这让所有人都讨厌他。法国民族主义者觉得他同情阿尔及利亚人，阿尔及利亚人觉得他代表法国白人，但他的父亲却在29岁无谓牺牲，她的母亲是一个赤贫的文盲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1960年1月4日，出版商米歇尔·伽里玛开车，阿尔贝·加缪坐在后座，汽车撞向一棵树后，翻滚着撞到了另一棵树上，加缪从后窗中被甩了出去。在不远处的泥浆里，人们找到一个公文包，里面有加缪的日记和一部未完成的长篇小说书稿《第一个人》，这部书以阿尔及利亚的童年生活为原型，并想象他的父亲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加缪辞世后，萨特虽然没有原谅他，但在《法兰西观察家》上写了一篇充满溢美之词的讣告：“他是20世纪反历史潮流的伦理主义流派继承人，他的作品或许是所有法国文人中最具原创性的。他那倔强的、狭隘的、单纯的、朴素的人道主义情怀向我们时代里那些广泛而丑恶的秩序发起了未必明智的挑战。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从电话里得到加缪的死讯后，波伏娃吃下已经停用很久的安眠药，但还是无法入睡，于是下了床，冒着巴黎一月刺骨的细雨，在街头徘徊。第二天清晨，她依然神情恍惚：“他看不见今天的早晨了。”但事实上，加缪非但没有离开人世，反而因车祸带来的强烈冲击，成了世人瞩目的中心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《加缪笔记》的最后几页里，有这样几句话：“在给予你的短暂的白天，取暖吧，照亮吧，不要偏离了你的跑道。……其他几百万个太阳前来陪伴你休息。……在快乐的石板下，第一次入眠。……由风来播种，由风来收获，但创造者是人，穿越时代，以刹那的生命为傲。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（参考资料：赫伯特·洛特曼《加缪传》，莎拉·贝克韦尔《存在主义咖啡馆》，柳鸣九编《加缪全集》，郭宏安译《加缪笔记：1935—1959（精选集）》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[再访“山地之王”：高仙芝的西域足迹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260116]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;回历133年（&lt;em>;大唐天宝十载，公元&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;751年&lt;/em>;），朝圣月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朝圣月是回历的12月。这一年的朝圣月正值盛夏，在中亚草原的边缘，一支黑旗大军在塔拉斯河（Talas River）右岸向着圣地的方向跪拜祈祷完成晨礼，然后迎着朝阳布好了阵势：最前方是配备大食骏马的轻骑兵，他们手持大马士革弯刀，徒步站立以恤马力；然后是由呼罗珊人和吐火罗人为主组成的步兵集群，再往后是弓箭手和长矛手；两翼是来自河中诸国的粟特（Sogdian）骑兵，他们虽然斗志昂扬，但毕竟归化未久，又是异教徒，战斗力尚且存疑，因此被用来保护伊斯兰军队的侧翼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在黑旗大军的对面，是来自东方神秘丝绸国度的敌军。他们人数少得多，因此把步兵摆在前面组成防御阵形。这些步兵统一手持东方式的长柄陌刀，两面开刃，在朝阳下反射出刺眼的光芒，那巨大的精钢刀头极为锋利，不亚于大食人的百战弯刀，凭借其重量能够将奔马劈为两半，和长矛手一样足以承受骑兵的冲击。这些步兵也配有马匹用于行军，但这些驮马此刻已经散牧于敌军侧后方的塔拉斯河边。步兵后面是配备强弩的弓弩手，两翼则是来自北方草原的葛逻禄（Qarluks）突厥骑兵。在这些步骑主力的后面是他们的指挥官，分为主将、副将和别将，还有来自拔汗那的附庸军作为预备队——听说就是那些家伙挑起了这场战争。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黑旗军队的统帅并波悉林（Abu Muslim，&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现译阿布·穆斯林&lt;/span>;）是黑衣大食&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（现译阿巴斯王朝）&lt;/span>;首屈一指的开国元勋，也是半路出家的军事天才。他出身为波斯裔奴隶，长期在大食帝国底层传教，六年前才回到故土波斯，起兵反抗白衣大食&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（现译倭马亚王朝）&lt;/span>;。去年冬天，他率军挺进美索不达米亚，在扎卜河战役中以少胜多，先用长矛手阵列顶住对方骑兵的多轮冲击，再发动骑兵冲锋将丧失斗志的敌军步兵逼进了漂着浮冰的河水中，击溃了至少三倍于己的敌人，给享国九十年的白衣大食捶下了最后一颗棺钉，在巴格达建立起了延祚五百余年的黑衣大食。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年他再次从波斯出发，远征中亚，迎战同样远道而来的中国军队，对方的指挥官听说是一个名叫高仙芝的美男子。不过，这场战役的缘起，还得从整整一百年前的波斯说起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/g89DKg3BB0Dayb1jFBC6r4iCeGOueEJD3SKB5SKo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257248&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦的塔拉斯河谷，怛罗斯战役发生地点已不可考，但战役发生在河谷口，地势会比较平坦。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“西方的野蛮人”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大唐永徽二年（&lt;em>;公元&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;651年&lt;/em>;），年轻的“天可汗”李治在长安接见波斯萨珊帝国末代皇帝伊嗣俟派来的求救使臣。使臣说有一伙来自西方的野蛮人正在攻打波斯：他们要求我们在三种情况中选择一种：要么接受他们的信仰，要么交纳人头税，要么就开战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;使臣并不知道，在他恳求唐高宗出兵援救波斯的时候， 伊嗣俟已经死在了逃亡途中。幸免于难的王子卑路斯&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（波斯语意为“胜利者”）&lt;/span>;屡战屡败，最后也逃到了中国，并终老于此，葬于东都洛阳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;攻灭萨珊王朝的“野蛮人”被波斯人称为“大食”（Tachik），其实就是阿拉伯人。 “大食”这个名字来自阿拉伯东部的塔伊部落（Tayyi），被波斯人当成了阿拉伯穆斯林的统称，讹传到唐朝后又因为他们使用白色旗帜，故而中国史书称之为“白衣大食”。波斯人皈依伊斯兰教后又被突厥人称为Tachik，这很可能就是今天同样讲波斯语的塔吉克人（Tajik）名称的由来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即位不满三年的李治对于救援远在天边的波斯并无兴趣。当时大唐尚未完全平定南疆，有限的军事资源必须用于控制葱岭以东的安西四镇，对于葱岭以西还鞭长莫及。而大食攻取波斯后也因国内的争位之战而中止了在东方的扩张势头，直到六十年后方派名将屈底波（Qutaybah ibn Muslim）向东攻取河中地区（Transoxiana）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“河中”地区，顾名思义，乃是中亚两条大河阿姆河&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（古称乌浒水）&lt;/span>;与锡尔河（古称药杀水）之间的平原地区，它北接中亚草原，东南方是天山和兴都库什山两座悠长而高峻的雄伟山脉，西南方则是波斯高原。沿着两条大河走出葱岭的商旅在这里汇集，货物在这里转手，继续经波斯高原前往两河流域和小亚细亚，因此河中地区自古是丝绸之路的重要枢纽。汉代月氏人在匈奴、乌孙的攻击下从蒙古高原一路播迁至此，与当地人融合后形成粟特人，在干旱的河中地区建立了康、史、安、石等多个绿洲国家，中国史书称其为昭武九姓。由于粟特人扼商道而居，成为中世纪融通东西方贸易的杰出商业民族，大批行商坐贾迁居中原——唐三彩驼马上的胡人形象便是粟特人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/zWVM9sgAhdxB6FB4f9sVoP03czN5Ac0gFEb5Mdgw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;唐三彩骆驼载乐俑的粟特人形象&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大唐先天元年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元712年）&lt;/span>;，屈底波从波斯东北部的呼罗珊进军河中，先后攻取萨末鞬&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今译撒马尔罕）&lt;/span>;、石国&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今塔什干）&lt;/span>;、拔汗那&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今译费尔干纳）&lt;/span>;等国。那时唐玄宗李隆基刚刚登基，处心积虑谋划着如何推翻干政的姑妈太平公主一党，对于葱岭以西发生的杀伐就像他的祖父李治一样无动于衷。两年后，军事上势如破竹的屈底波在内乱中意外被杀，白衣大食军队来得急撤得也快。觊觎此地已久的吐蕃趁虚而入，在拔汗那拥立新国王阿了达，此举立刻引起了大唐的高度警惕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这又是为什么呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Gu8dOFRAYyug80Y3jExmNtI4WyKn7reqLtfQmyJc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257246&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乌兹别克斯坦撒马尔罕&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中亚地缘政治&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“拔汗那（Bahanna）”乃是古称，如今叫“费尔干纳（Ferg&#39;ona）”，其辅音“g”还是俄国殖民者给加上的，我听当地人其实念作Fer&#39;ana，发音接近于“福阿纳”。它乃是西天山末端的一块盆地，汉代称为大宛，著名的汗血宝马就出产于此。苏联时代，俄罗斯人为了分裂突厥诸部以便分而治之，强行在中亚细分出五个民族，构建了犬牙交错的五个“斯坦国”，尤其是在小小的费尔干纳盆地，竟将其分割给了乌兹别克斯坦、吉尔吉斯斯坦和塔吉克斯坦三个加盟共和国，而且划出了大量飞地甚至是飞地中的飞地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/33ezPesUQEIzRou4lHGBFQj0Muo9RpprdfQPffuO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257244&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;费尔干纳盆地地图，飞地套飞地，犬牙交错可见一斑。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唐代的拔汗那尚无这些纠纷，乃是单一民族的粟特国家，它位于唐朝西域重镇碎叶与河中诸国之间，是由安西大都护府经葱岭前往河中地区的要冲。更为要紧的是，大唐可以接受大食控制拔汗那，却无法坐视吐蕃由此进入中亚草原——这就涉及到当时中亚地区四个大国间的地缘政治。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拔汗那为大国所环绕，北有突厥，南有吐蕃，西有大食，东有大唐。突厥人是传统的草原征服者，以其强大战力向河中诸国收取保护费；白衣大食是政教合一的新兴帝国，但它在扩张初期既不是为了战争也不是为了敛财，而是为了“给各部族的好战精神找出路”——突厥与大食是新旧征服者之间的零和博弈，无法调和；吐蕃兴起于青藏苦寒之地，素以富庶的中原为目标，但苦于打不开大唐牢牢扎紧的藩篱，因此绕道葱岭，希望与北方的突厥人联手瓜分大唐西域，再沿河西走廊进入中原腹地；而大唐作为四个大国中唯一一个由农耕民族建立的政权，开拓西域的首要目标是以攻为守，保卫自己的领土：由关中经陇西、河西而至安西，最终抵达塔里木盆地的西部边界葱岭，守住高耸入云的葱岭就可以挡住外部势力进入中原。因此，唐朝的诉求并非掠土殖民&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（大食）&lt;/span>;、压榨土人&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（突厥）&lt;/span>;、开辟通道&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（吐蕃）&lt;/span>;抑或保护商路——商路只是唐朝扩张过程中的副产品而非目的——而是简简单单的据险自守，隔断南北通道以阻止强敌结盟来对付自己。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这么一来，吐蕃与突厥一南一北谋求联手进攻共同的敌人大唐，而大唐与大食一东一西各自占据葱岭两侧，井水不犯河水。一旦吐蕃越过了这条东西向的均衡线，有望进入北方草原与突厥人合流，大唐的“红色警报”就被触发了。大唐开元三年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元715年）&lt;/span>;，也就是屈底波被杀、大食军撤走、吐蕃军进占拔汗那的那一年，正在安西都护府巡察的监察御史张孝嵩当机立断，越俎代庖地征发并指挥仆从国附庸军长驱直入数千里，翻越葱岭抵达拔汗那盆地，大败吐蕃重兵，于汉武帝攻略大宛的八百年后再次占领此地，封住了吐蕃进入中亚草原的葱岭西道出口。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后吐蕃又谋求取道勃律打通葱岭东道，同样被时任北庭节度使的张孝嵩所挫败：开元十年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元722年）&lt;/span>;，张孝嵩派四千步骑援救小勃律，大破吐蕃军，此事已在上一篇《探访“山地之王”：高仙芝的高原足迹》中提及，故不再赘述。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;远征葱岭西道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;大唐天宝八载&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元749年）&lt;/span>;，高仙芝收复小勃律后两年，又在播仙&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今新疆且末）&lt;/span>;大破吐蕃。在东线撞得头破血流的吐蕃军不得不调头前往西线的葱岭西道寻找唐朝西域防御体系的弱点。接到情报的高仙芝完全可以前往拔汗那，在那里以逸待劳等待劳师远征的吐蕃军前来并给予迎头痛击，但毕生追求战场主动权的高仙芝并没有那么做：既然葱岭西道尚可走通，那我就彻底切断它！ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/3rArVE0YBeev16pAJzunHE89Ik8YSr6hsWP04pSA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257245&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;巴基斯坦奇特拉尔街景，古代的朅师国所在地。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天宝九载&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元750年）&lt;/span>;，高仙芝第二次出兵葱岭，再次来到小勃律，由此沿娑夷河&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今吉尔吉特河）&lt;/span>;逆流而上，翻越山杜尔山口，前往兴都库什山脉中部东麓的朅师国&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今巴基斯坦奇特拉尔）&lt;/span>;。有历史学家考证朅师国是亚历山大大帝东征的终点，附近Kalasha幽谷中繁衍至今的古老部落据说就是希腊远征军的后裔。从小勃律到朅师超过七百里路程，如今走公路需要两个整天，第一天路况甚好，还有长途车可以坐，第二天就只能与乡人搭乘当地四轮驱动方可成行，沿着马斯图杰河谷（Mastuj Valley）一路向西，北面是兴都库什山脉（Hindu Kush）的连绵雪山，南面则是兴都拉吉山脉（Hindu Raj）高达6542米的雪峰Buni Zom。脚下马斯图杰河深深切入致密的黄土，形成T字形的高耸台地，令人想起嘉峪关外的讨赖河谷——高仙芝麾下将士由中原经河西而至西域途中，一定在讨赖河边饮过马吧，相信他们也发现了两地的神似。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/XKBIVpjK1iLdWvZmVtjxBKcinAQzrDdombTDnHD8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257247&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;嘉峪关外的讨赖河谷&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《两唐书》没有记载高仙芝远征朅师走了多久，《资治通鉴》也仅提到唐军系冬季行军。根据我对朅师沿途地形的估测，古代军队带着辎重至少需要走半个月。而吐蕃军就更艰苦了：由于唐军三年前就控制了小勃律和娑夷河谷，吐蕃军不得不从南面的崇山峻岭中绕行，一个月能不能走到朅师都是问题。朅师国是吐蕃的盟友，位于葱岭西道的中点，过了朅师就可以翻越兴都库什山脉，再沿着喷赤河穿越葱岭西部和西天山的阿赖山脉，最终抵达拔汗那盆地——那又是一个多月的行程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于高仙芝奇袭朅师，截断了葱岭西道，远道而来极为疲惫的吐蕃将士就不用再翻越兴都拉吉、兴都库什、葱岭和西天山这四座伟岸的山脉，更不用在酷热的拔汗那艰难攻打唐军与粟特人联合把守的要塞，可以全须全尾地回到凉爽的青藏高原——这难道不是大唐高将军带来的和平红利吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，在失去朅师这个重要的中继点之后，吐蕃彻底打消了打通葱岭东、西两道的念头，从此将兵力集中于东线，但仍于天宝十二载、十三载被高仙芝的继任者封常清在东线的两条通道分别击破，以至于吐蕃军在此后的十年时间里都无法对大唐西域形成重大威胁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝陆续平定了东西两线的吐蕃攻势，将大唐的军事控制线由葱岭东部外推到了葱岭西部，达成了稳定西域、拱卫中原的战略目的，可以说达到了个人军事成就的巅峰。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而就在此时，他收到了拔汗那的求援书，请求他在班师前顺道讨伐石国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/4NUFlw1iZ78PBTmVSciXzpzLt78lKcF5iugBYzAd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257249&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;费尔干纳盆地的传统茶馆&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“诸胡皆怒”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;拔汗那先被白衣大食灭国，又被吐蕃扶植傀儡政权，最后依靠大唐援军方得以复国，因此是中亚地区对大唐最为忠诚的属国，可以比拟为高丽之于大明。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么拔汗那为什么要吁请唐军攻打石国呢？此事缺乏明确的史料记载，一般认为可能有三方面的原因，一是拔汗那与石国有隙，拔汗那位于药杀水上游的盆地中，而石国位于药杀水流出盆地的下游方向，其首都拓折城就是今天的乌兹别克斯坦首都塔什干（Toshkent），“拓折”就是“塔什/Tosh”，乃是突厥语“石头”的意思。两国同为粟特国家，石国扼拔汗那通往中亚草原的出口，而拔汗那则扼石国的水源，两国或有积怨；二是拔汗那向大唐输诚，趁河中之地陷入权力真空之机予以控制；三是石国位于河中地区与中亚草原接壤的前沿，与突厥的主要部落突骑施的继承者黄姓突骑施交好，而突骑施长期是大唐的威胁，踩到了大唐的红线。总之高仙芝采纳了拔汗那的建议，引军北上进入费尔干纳盆地，再沿着药杀水抵达石国。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;石国属于河中地区的昭武九姓诸国，是大唐的羁縻之地，它们奉唐朝为宗主国，向大唐定期朝贡，但没有行政、财政和军事上的实际管控关系。高仙芝讨伐石国的名义是“无藩臣礼”，但史书上没有列举具体罪状。弱小的石国提出讲和，高仙芝假意应允，却囚禁了亲自前来和谈的石国国王那俱车鼻施——他曾在小勃律之战中使用过相似的计谋，以财货诱捕亲吐蕃的小勃律贵族出城后实施抓捕斩首——然后兵不血刃地占领了拓折城。破城后，高仙芝纵兵大肆杀戮，还掠夺了石国的大量珍宝，光其本人就获得“瑟瑟十馀斛、黄金五六橐驼、良马宝玉甚众，家赀累钜万”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这里所说的“瑟瑟”乃是中世纪最为昂贵的矿石之一：青金石。它原产于乌浒水上游的巴达赫尚地区&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今阿富汗东北部）&lt;/span>;，经河中地区转口贩运至世界各地，既是珍贵的宝石、治病的“神药”，也是稀有的蓝、紫色颜料。 2022年跨年舞蹈《只此青绿》而爆火的青绿色调，其缘起就是宋徽宗以宫廷御藏的珍贵青金石供青年画家王希孟绘制的传世珍品《千里江山图》，而白居易的千古名句“半江瑟瑟半江红”，诵咏的也是江水在夕阳照射下泛出的青金石色彩。高仙芝从石国劫掠了大量青金石，想必是其府库历年蓄积的珍品，尤列于黄金之前，其价值可想而知。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/b1FmncUzLH6tfu6CZ4uaYCNuxrIL4vqFm4MtFpXC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257251&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;北京故宫珍宝馆的青金石雕松泉人物图山子（清&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝将此次远征所俘虏的石国国王、朅师国王、吐蕃酋长以及很可能是在石国一并捕获的黄姓突骑施可汗&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（或可解释高仙芝为何屠戮拓折城以惩罚石国的通敌行为）&lt;/span>;一股脑儿送回长安献俘阙下，战功可谓煊赫。但他的背信之举和残酷屠杀激起了除拔汗那之外河中诸国的公愤，据《资治通鉴》记载，“石国王子逃诣诸胡，具告仙芝欺诱贪暴之状。诸胡皆怒，潜引大食欲共攻四镇”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而根据大食史料记载，战争的起因是拔汗那与石国敌对，向大唐求援；唐军包围石国，石国国王投降，并未受到迫害；大食得知此事后出兵与大唐交战——这一叙述前后缺乏逻辑，难以解释大食出兵的原因。据我看来，那一年大食刚好完成改朝换代，黑衣大食取代了白衣大食，正需要一场对外战争的胜利来弥合内部的分裂。统帅并波悉林则刚刚镇压了安国&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今乌兹别克斯坦布哈拉）&lt;/span>;的叛乱，得以腾出手来以安国为基地出兵侵占他的前辈屈底波曾经征服过的河中地区。如今河中诸国主动前来归顺，正中其下怀。并波悉林遂照单全收吞并了河中之地，然后率领士气正旺的大食雄师与河中诸国的附庸军沿着中亚草原向东进发，兵锋直指大唐在西域的前哨碎叶城。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而高仙芝得知河中巨变，第三次统率安西四镇的主力部队以及葛逻禄和拔汗那的附庸军越过葱岭，前往河中平叛，两支大军遂在拓折城与碎叶城之间的怛逻斯遭遇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;776&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/LV5mMBRraRxnE4FS4opPUvRpUNPCVATVuQfAItbC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257250&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;怛罗斯之战地图，宁远即为拔汗那。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“中亚的关原之战”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“怛逻斯”是石国东部城池的名字，得名于塔拉斯河，后者是西天山余脉中的一条山间河流，水量虽然不大但源远流长，长达一千多里。塔拉斯河的下游沿着河谷向西北方向流淌，最后进入草原地带。如今河谷内的山地属于吉尔吉斯斯坦，河谷以外的平原地带则属于哈萨克斯坦。河谷里有一座吉尔吉斯小镇叫做塔拉斯（Talas），河谷外的草原上则有一座哈萨克大城叫做塔拉兹（Taraz）。苏联时代于1975年在塔拉斯河谷山口修建了一座基洛夫水库，拦住了本就不多的河水——水库深度仅7米，用于河谷内的农业灌溉，因此塔拉斯河进入哈萨克斯坦国境后只剩下涓涓细流，形成一片饥渴的绿洲，最后断流于沙漠之中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;670&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/i0ssPtEHrp7jmmHlYE2eTUJ3Rw4WprHtGo4Lr5yH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257253&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;建于苏联时代的基洛夫水库&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鉴于年代久远，如今已经无法确认唐代的怛逻斯城究竟是今天的塔拉斯镇还是塔拉兹城，抑或位于两者之间的某一点。由于地处吉尔吉斯斯坦和哈萨克斯坦边境地带，作为外国人的我无法抵近塔拉斯河谷出口——怛逻斯之战最有可能发生的地方——开展考察，也无法放飞无人机从空中俯瞰这条河谷。但可以肯定的是，兵力较少的大唐联军占据了地势略高的河谷内侧，用山峦和河流保护自己的侧翼；兵力占优的大食联军则从草原一侧向河谷进攻，双方在塔拉斯河北岸摆开了战场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/Qi7QuQ9GqU7p6cS2EiCHAaHQDek2DTTyYt4N2OjX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257252&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;塔拉斯河&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于双方的兵力对比，史家众说纷纭，目前一般认为大唐联军兵力为2—3万人，鉴于整个安西大都护府的兵力不超过三万人，还要守备偌大的南疆，不可能悉数调往前线，我倾向于《资治通鉴》的记载，高仙芝此次远征的总兵力约三万人，估计其中一半为唐军，以步兵为主，其余系葛逻禄和拔汗那的附庸军，其中葛逻禄军为骑兵，拔汗那军也以步兵为主。或有一种说法是唐军兵力高达六、七万人，这就意味着其中绝大部分是附庸军，并不符合当时大唐在河中地区众叛亲离，仅有拔汗那追随的实际情况，而葛逻禄作为初兴的突厥部落也无法提供这么多兵力。大食方面史料更加缺乏，一般认为有7—10万人，也有认为高达20至30万人的，我认为以当时的后勤保障条件，无法支撑如此巨大的兵力在草原上远征，所以姑且认为这场战争是7万大食联军与3万大唐联军在塔拉斯河边展开的一场野战。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;史载这场战役打了五天，前四天大食军队主攻，但未能突破唐军构成的严密防御阵形，可到了第五天，战场形势发生了戏剧性的逆转。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有日本学者把这场战役比喻为“中亚的关原之战”——关原之战是日本安土桃山时代投入兵力规模最大的一场战役，西军主力以寡敌众，即将赢得战场主动之际，原本按兵不动驻扎在侧翼山顶的友军小早川秀秋部突然倒戈，切入了正与东军激战的西军主力后方，对其形成夹击之势，西军遂土崩瓦解。这一类比虽然不尽确切，但确与怛逻斯之战的逆转颇有相似：唐军精锐的陌刀队挡住了大食军的多轮攻击，原本有望复刻对方主帅并波悉林去年在扎卜河战役中的成功范例，用骑兵反冲锋压垮敌军斗志。只可惜大唐联军的骑兵部队是葛逻禄附庸军，在这个唐军即将赢得战场主动的关键时刻，与大食早有默契的葛逻禄人反戈一击，反而切入了正与大食军激战的唐军后方，对其形成夹击之势，唐军主力遂陷入重围苦战之中，伤亡殆尽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;主将高仙芝不甘心就此失败，还指望用预备队稳住阵脚，收拢前线败兵后再与敌军一决雌雄。他的副将、曾在连云堡战斗中立下奇功的猛将李嗣业在危急关头劝他撤退：将军孤军深入，没有援军，而周围胡人诸国都是追随胜者的墙头草，一定会对我们群起围攻。一旦我们全军覆没，还有谁回去守卫南疆呢？我虽然是个莽汉，也看得清形势危急，将军可不能再拘泥固执了！ &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（《旧唐书·李嗣业列传》：愚者千虑，或有一得，势危若此，不可胶柱）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是，李嗣业拽着高仙芝放弃了被包围的唐军主力，沿塔拉斯河谷向东撤退。地势渐高，山道渐窄，作为预备队最先调头撤退的拔汗那附庸军把道路堵得严严实实，后面的唐军无法通过，眼看就要被大食追兵赶上。这时李嗣业放下陌刀，抡起大棒向拔汗那友军左右开弓，“人马应手俱毙”，拔汗那军纷纷向左右避让，高仙芝得以逃出生天；而唐军的第三把手、别将段秀实挺身而出，责备上司李嗣业为了自己逃命而杀害友军，“惮敌而奔，非勇也；免己陷众，非仁也”，李嗣业这才羞惭地停止杀戮。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是唐军在怛逻斯大败后的惨状。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/31CN9JVyp9irZvMms8DXX6lpHkT9teKviZsTsvFl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257254&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦塔拉斯省的入口拱门&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;尾声&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;怛逻斯战役结束后，两军各自回国，大唐与大食仍以葱岭为界，战略均衡并未发生根本改变。之后的五年里，黑衣大食向大唐先后派出了八批使臣，表明双方仍然维持着密切的外交关系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;葛逻禄：临阵倒戈的突厥部族，在怛逻斯之战后与吐蕃结盟，继承了突骑施的角色，成为草原上新一代的突厥征服者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拔汗那，葱岭一隅的西域属国，在怛逻斯惨败和杀戮后依然效忠大唐，“事唐最谨”。 “安史之乱”爆发后，拔汗那响应唐肃宗邀请，不远万里发兵援助中原。时至今日，费尔干纳仍是世界丝绸重镇，生丝出产量列全球第三，这便是唐代丝路花雨对这个酷热盆地的千年遗泽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;河中诸国，大国博弈下的粟特城邦，大唐在“安史之乱”后退出西域，这些波斯化国家在大食与突厥的影响下又陆续发生了伊斯兰化和突厥化的历史性转变。根据历史学家考证，造纸术早在怛逻斯战役爆发前就已经传播至此，它助力昭武九姓中的安国逐步成为穆斯林世界重要的文化中心，被誉为“伊斯兰支柱”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/HwWknu6XYYuqZHyj0jK92JOOGcjX41w011520Q9r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257255&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;乌兹别克斯坦布哈拉伊斯兰文化中心的象征：Mir-i-Arab经学院&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（王在田/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并波悉林，奴隶出身的战神统帅，在三年后卷入了黑衣大食夺位之争。他支持第二代哈里发打败了对手，却于三个月后被这位哈里发虐杀——诚所谓“飞鸟尽，良弓藏”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;段秀实，直言极谏的儒将，撤回安西后被遭他斥责过的李嗣业提拔为判官，两年后又辅佐封常清攻克大勃律，在平定“安史之乱”和抗击吐蕃前线也屡立大功，64岁高龄时因反对叛臣朱泚而殉国——文天祥《正气歌》中的“或为击贼笏”说的就是他誓死讨贼的典故。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李嗣业，身高两米的猛将，在“安史之乱”中回军中原勤王，曾与中兴名将郭子仪联手，以弱敌强，连战连捷，陆续收复关中平原和东都洛阳，成为积弱唐军中的“救火队员”。大唐乾元二年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（公元759年）&lt;/span>;，他在作战时中流矢，“出血数升，注地而卒”——每当说到李嗣业，我首先会想起“当嗣业刀者，人马俱碎”的勇武场景。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/o19q7tWOXE0R9KIoBQjlAc8soRQ1bTloJUn4PSxy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257256&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吉尔吉斯斯坦塔拉斯省奥特莫克山口，一千二百多年前的“山地之王”没准路经此地。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝，胆识超凡但贪功爱财的名将，怛逻斯战役四年后“安史之乱”爆发，高仙芝与封常清受命统率临时纠集的乌合之众抵挡精锐叛军主力，只得依据坚城死守潼关，却因此被唐玄宗下诏双双斩杀。接替他们俩的另一位名将哥舒翰被迫出兵与叛军野战，结果全军覆没，潼关失守，长安沦陷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高仙芝临死前曾有机会翻盘：当时向玄宗进谗并奉旨到潼关处决高仙芝的太监边令诚率领百余名陌刀手为自己壮胆，却不曾想这些精锐军士齐声高呼：高将军冤枉！ “其声殷地”。高仙芝本可借助于这些忠诚的士兵收捕边令诚，或可迫使玄宗收回成命。但他最终没有这么做，而是望着老战友封常清的尸首慨然长叹，束手赴死。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位盛唐名将，最终随盛唐一并化为泡影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 22:26:40 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一家经营不善的公司，承建了佳木斯5年就垮的体育馆]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260142]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 20:36:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/aPvOHwxqlK0VsO18YBywrmePYpJXnckOoBpgrqzc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/aPvOHwxqlK0VsO18YBywrmePYpJXnckOoBpgrqzc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257295&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;桦南县悦城广场全民健身体育馆塌陷事故现场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年11月6日19时20分左右，黑龙江省佳木斯市桦南县悦城广场全民健身体育馆内发生塌陷事故。当时有7名初中生在里面打篮球，有学生发现屋顶异常并向门口跑去，随即屋顶塌陷，总塌陷面积达675平方米。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7名学生中，有3人自行脱险，1人被救出送医，3人死亡。一位遇难者的朋友告诉媒体，那是个从小爱打篮球、被同学称为“球王”的少年。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月24日，桦南县县长曾到该体育馆检查安全工作，并强调文化市场经营者要履行好安全生产主体责任，时刻紧绷安全生产这根弦。此前一天，黑龙江省齐齐哈尔第三十四中学体育馆发生楼顶坍塌事故——那次事故造成11名师生遇难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次事故发生后，佳木斯市、桦南县两级纪检监察机关第一时间介入，成立调查组开展调查。桦南县政府新闻办对外介绍说，坍塌场馆的经营者为桦南县新阳光健身俱乐部，负责人门雅男已被警方控制，事故原因正在进一步调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;体育馆的建筑所有人曾将场所租赁给他人经营，但从2022年12月起，转让给门雅男经营的新阳光健身俱乐部管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;门雅男是悦城的“老朋友”。她曾在2021年4月成立悦城体育健身俱乐部，8个月后注销该公司，于2022年7月成立新阳光健身俱乐部。她同时在桦南县悦城电影城有限责任公司任监事，该公司实控人为杨巾力，是2017年8月成立的桦南县悦城商厦有限公司的实控人和受益所有人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;悦城广场是桦南县住建部门大力招商来的项目。由北京得意音通技术有限公司投资3.8亿元，投资注册黑龙江省悦城房地产开发有限公司，在原棚户区建设城市商业综合体和高档住宅小区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/vla3O3vp9iiWs3gpanZDcsumuhpp61wNgBa0VvLJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/vla3O3vp9iiWs3gpanZDcsumuhpp61wNgBa0VvLJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257294&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;桦南县悦城广场全民健身体育馆塌陷事故现场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2015年到2022年，桦南县曾有悦城房地产开发有限公司、悦城商厦有限公司和悦城体育文化发展有限公司三家公司接连成立，其中股东、高管多有重叠，但这三家公司先后注销。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据桦南县政府新闻办介绍，事故发生的悦城广场综合体7号楼由黑龙江海峰伟业建筑安装工程有限责任公司（以下简称“海峰伟业”）于2017年7月开始建设，2018年7月竣工，监理单位为佳木斯三江建设监理公司，2020年7月通过验收。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2007年，海峰伟业由朱海、朱波（以下简称“二朱”）出资在鹤岗市成立。 2016年5月，二朱退出公司，26岁的岳城棋接手。一年后，悦城广场综合体开始建设，海峰伟业的市场主体类型从“自然人投资或控股”变更为“自然人独资”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一份案号为“(2018)黑0822民初272号”的民事判决书显示，2016年之前，主要在鹤岗做工程的海峰伟业因负债累累，便以年化利率6%的利息向岳城棋借款。 2016年，二朱彻底放弃海峰伟业，转让给岳城棋。此时，朱海、朱波仍欠鹤岗市工农区地方税务局和国税局税款加滞纳金共计2059920.94元，他们向岳城棋借钱，缴纳了税款。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年10月，岳城棋就偿还这笔借款及利息起诉了二朱，得到法院支持，但二朱称无钱，暂无法偿还。这笔总额为242万元的借款直到2020年才被强制执行完成。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刚接手海峰伟业那段时间，岳城棋折腾了不少赚钱的路子，比如购买已经交付、但被几度倒手转卖的回迁安置房，后法院认为他在购买房屋时没有对实际居住人核实情况、构成重大过失，故不支持他主张对回迁房的实体所有权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还参与过赌博，带着7500元赌资下场，输光后又当场借了1万元，利息为每日300元。后在2016年12月2日被公安机关当场抓获，收缴赌资，受到行政处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岳城棋的社交软件头像是一张写着“人生靠自己”的图片，个性签名为“父母给的叫背景，自己打拼的叫江山，有一种努力叫靠自己”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在接手海峰伟业之前，岳城棋没有管理建筑公司或大型建筑项目的经验。但他通过努力，用一个当时正在被强制执行欠款的鹤岗建筑公司接下了投资1.7亿元的桦南县明星项目悦城广场。这之后，海峰伟业成了桦南县政府的招标大户。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《南方周末》梳理了公开招标信息后总结道：“（海峰伟业）参与的项目也是五花八门。市政工程方面，承建了公共停车场、道路、高铁停车场等，医疗工程有县疾控中心、县医院的传染病区、120急救中心，还有桦南县美丽乡村基础设施建设、县供电局的物资储备库、桦南经济开发区生猪屠宰厂区内的黑土转运土方。此外，还中标了县里的保障性安居工程。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事故发生当晚，岳城棋曾接受《南方周末》的短暂采访。他表示已经知道体育馆坍塌事件，但不确定是不是自己的工程，“需要回去查一查资料。”次日，岳城棋手机持续无人接听，同日下午，佳木斯发布通报，确认海峰伟业为体育馆施工方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/r4q6tNkB09v3ic491piEXK0aHZ11KOMBzq7HBUEx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/r4q6tNkB09v3ic491piEXK0aHZ11KOMBzq7HBUEx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257293&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;桦南县悦城广场全民健身体育馆塌陷事故现场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一家曾承接悦城广场综合体的开发商黑龙江省华优建筑工程有限公司，实为悦城地产的二股东，亦是当地政府项目的招标大户，曾承建佳木斯市中医院修缮医疗用房、桦川县文化广电新闻出版局的文化设施建设项目和桦南县危房改造项目。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事发当日，桦南县委宣传部一名工作人员接受媒体采访时回应，房顶坍塌与降雪有关。桦南县在当日16时47分发布了暴雪红色预警信号，提示必要时停课、停业（特殊行业除外）。根据气象监测，事发地桦南县6日24小时降雪量达到44毫米，打破了11月降雪量纪录。就在两天前，该县曾召开防范应对当前极端天气的工作会议，要求各行业领域按照职责分工，做好各自安全防范工作，最大限度减少次生灾害事故的发生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访港交所前行政总裁李小加：互联互通是香港资本市场成功的基石]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260126]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;李小加被誉为“中国金融证券业改革开放的最早实践者之一”。任职华尔街著名的达维(Davis Polk &amp;amp; Wardwell)与布朗伍德(Brown &amp;amp; Wood)律师事务所期间，他受&lt;span>;中国财政部&lt;/span>;邀请参与了中国第一次全球主权债的发行工作；先后担任美林中国区主席和摩根大通中国区主席时，李小加牵头中海油和中国移动等首批央国企跨境上市；他参与策划发起的中国海洋石油竞购尤尼克事件，被认为“开创了中国企业的新时代”；执掌港交所十余年，他成功推动了港交所历史上至关重要的多项战略举措，包括“沪港通”“深港通”。更令市场印象深刻的是2018年落地同股不同权上市制度改革和&amp;nbsp;2012 年收购伦敦金属交易所。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，他创业“滴灌通”，并根据澳门政府有关行政令设立和运营滴灌通澳交所，寄望“让国际资本与中国小微企业联通”。这是一项全球范围内的革命性金融实验。历时7个月，2023年10月26日，滴灌通澳交所获得伊斯兰教律监管委员会认证，符合禁止收息等伊斯兰教义。 &lt;span>;该认证包含了&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;伊斯兰金融&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;对滴灌通开创的收入分成产品不是贷款收息模式的确认，并认可滴灌通以分成共担风险的投资方式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三十多年前，中国如何首度发行全球主权债？二十多年前，中国首批央国企为何登陆美国资本市场？二十年前，央企首单海外竞购成色如何？十年来，港交所如何破冰与A股实现互联互通？接受南方周末记者专访时，李小加回顾了这些与中国金融改革开放密切相关的重大事件。他表示，国际化、拥抱新经济、实现互联互通，直到今天依然是香港资本市场成功的基石，也是中国资本市场走向世界的改革创新。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/5EWnxZd3yR8XQC3FJ53jIHcDL5jPWsU9tJYHwfSX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;635&quot; height=&quot;794&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/07/5EWnxZd3yR8XQC3FJ53jIHcDL5jPWsU9tJYHwfSX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257287&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;李小加：港交所前行政总裁，现任滴灌通集团创始人、主席&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;以海外上市促改革的整体收益是多边的”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你曾牵头参与我国第一次发行全球主权债，这次发行全球主权债的主要难点是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;发债首先需要一家大评级机构给中国主权进行信用评级。我参与评级工作的两个多月时间，非常紧张。如果评级不合适，中国根本不会发行主权债。其中发生了很多故事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过艰苦努力，1993年，中国拿到A级主权评级，次年年初发债成功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你也牵头主持了首批央国企跨境上市，当时主要为了解决什么问题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那时的诉求非常简单，就是为国企解困。当时大量国企非常困难，三角债严重。最主要的动因是国企改革，需要融资，依靠资金进行改革。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国企改革就要真正进入市场，按市场经济规律运行。在这个过程中，大家很快感觉到，通过上市本身融资，很容易把大家的思想统一起来。然后把境外上市作为一种催化剂，要想去境外融资，央国企就要做各种改革，政府功能、社会功能和企业功能要分开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些改革在央国企海外上市的过程中慢慢变得重要。它是靠融资把大家的认知统一起来，为了达到这个目的，让大家慢慢接受改革必须承受的一些成本、一些影响和冲击。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以海外上市促改革，是否达到了预期目标？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那当然了。首先，这个目的或者说整体益处是多边的。企业本身在最关键的时候融到大笔资金。 1993 年，首批9 家企业，很快有22 家企业。这些企业用海外融资做了大量资本开支，解决了大量发展中需要的资金问题。它非常及时地解决了当时资金的迫切需求。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;央国企跨境上市真的吹响了国企改革的号角，带动和催发了原来启动相当困难的各个方面体制和机制改革。海外上市之后，国企改革慢慢进入到主赛道。大家开始全面接受国企改革。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅如此，央国企跨境上市很快催生了中国资本市场的发展。我们这么多企业不可能全部到国外上市，而且中国这么多资本，老百姓也有钱。为什么我们的资本不能投入到我们自己的企业里呢？从发行人的角度及投资者希望参与改革开放的发展红利来看，它促进了中国资本市场的诞生和发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有一点也很重要，央国企第一次走向世界。外界开始认识中国企业，认识中国经济。然后外资由于投资，深度关心、参与和体验中国经济现代化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得我国央国企内部治理效率方面的提升空间有多大？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;国企也好，央企也好，只是所有权的一种形式。新加坡也有主权基金，但它的运作方式完全市场化，除了出资人身份以外，其他与私营企业一样的运作模式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有的央企也非常高效。要说效率提升，管理者激励机制和其它企业一样吗？我们不能以企业所有权形式简单地说哪个更有效，哪个更好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;世界已经基本上不可能脱钩了&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在，一批央国企可能要从纽交所退市。你怎么看目前这种形势？是否有可能走向“资本脱钩”？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;即便退市，和资本脱钩这个事，依然是相差得太远的事情。它们是如今国际资本参与中国市场发展中极小的少数。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，全世界投资到中国的外资体量如此之大，包含范围是主要民企和在香港上市的央国企。除了科技领域比较明显的脱钩外，其他方面的脱钩会有一些。但完全还没有到老死不相往来的程度。我们已经习惯了与一个高度发达的资本市场之间的相互渗入和连接。现在这个连接比它鼎盛期间已弱了很多。如果从二三十年前看如今，今天这个世界的相连已经基本上不可能脱钩了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全世界像一驾飞机一样，世界经济最大的两个引擎怎么可能脱钩？在极其深度密切合作的20 年后，目前有一些回撤。即便在回撤之后，两国的经济联系远不能用脱钩这样的字形容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“港交所改革的两大核心考量&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;对内地的历史价值和现实意义”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;执掌港交所10年，你主导了多项影响深远的改革。你对哪些改革更满意？ Why? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我平常不这么想问题。在历史大潮中，一个人刚好很幸运地在一个很重要很合适的位置上，然后天时地利人和的条件下做了一些事情。这些不能说成一个人的事情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;任职港交所期间，哪项改革对内地更有历史价值和现实意义？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这是港交所所有改革最主要的两个核心考量。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个大主题就是香港在很长时间作为一种国际市场，应该是帮助内地资本市场国际化，帮助国际市场更多融入内地。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从这个角度讲，每一件事情都要系统性地解决。毕竟这两个市场是两个完全不同的体系，既有极大动力互相融入和互联互通，也有它很强大的内在机制和力量。这使互联互通非常困难。换言之，这两个市场各有自己的管理体制、市场体制和运作方式，愿意融合，但又不愿意为了融合而大量改变自己的制度和系统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;怎么利用香港极其独特的地位呢？我们充分认识到两边市场哪些可以为了互联互通进行一些改变，哪些是不可能改变的，哪些改变是必须的。找到一个最大公约数和最小公倍数，找到在最小成本里边达到最大幅度的互联互通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在所有改革中，我们要考虑很多问题。也许某种形式的互联互通最有效最好，但它的成本可能太高。大家不愿意承受；一些事情可能很容易改革，但没什么特别大意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如，我们开始想选择很小的事情，比如说两边交易所的交易时间段不一样，开市和收盘都不一样。看上去似乎很小的事情，但改革并不容易。它涉及两地不同的生活习惯和工作习惯。看起来大家应该没有什么争议的改革，实际上却是当时最困难的改革之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回过头看，以下几件改革对港交所有重大历史价值和现实意义。首先，港交所不能只是在香港的内地市场，港交所不仅只在亚洲，应该往欧美突破，因为内地希望通过香港市场走向国际；不能只在股票市场，要向内地最需要的大宗商品市场突破。因此，港交所兼并收购了伦敦金属交易所，也尝试过收购伦敦交易所，但没有成功。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二是港交所股票市场本身。因为监管规则，中国科技企业一直无法上市。它们代表先进的生产力，却只能到美国上市。并不是之前的监管逻辑错误，但在全世界都在竞争的时候，我们为什么死死抱住原有的东西不改变呢？美国的监管逻辑原来也和港交所一致，但它可以找到非常现实的原因并允许改变。我们最后进行改革，小米、京东、阿里等等都可以回归到港交所。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A股市值已高居全球第二。这么庞大的市场与香港市场及国际市场怎么能够实现互联互通，但又不改变双方各自的规则和制度？因此，沪港通、深港通、债券通、债券互换通等等一系列改革创新陆续出笼。两个市场之间达到基本互联互通功能。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国际化、拥抱新经济、实现互联互通，直到今天都还是香港市场成功的基石，也是中国资本市场走向世界的改革创新。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对任职港交所期间的工作还留有遗憾吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;现在互联互通是二级市场，即沪港通和深港通可以南下或北上买卖已在港交所或深交所与沪交所的股票。但互联互通没有向一级市场延伸到“新股通”。这是我的遗憾。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个产品的名字，我以前用“新股通”。新股通让中国市场最终和世界资源对接。在香港实现互联互通，能实现巨大的发展。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;让国际&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;资本&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;和中国小微&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;企业充分&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;联通&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;告别港交所，你以一种全球最新的投资模式和交易模式开始创业——2023年8月正式运营滴灌通澳交所。滴灌通澳交所要解决世界性难题——小微企业融资难。为何滴灌通澳交所可以解决这个难题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;滴灌通澳交所是全球首个持牌的收入分成产品（DRO）交易所。滴灌通的愿景与使命是将国际资本与中国小微经济充分联通起来，要让国际传统金融和中国小微经济这两个非常难以兼容的运营体系实现互联互通。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这件事情能突破的基础和前提是中国数字化革命全面普及。无现金社会为一种崭新的、革命性的融资形式提供了可能。有了这个革命性的前提后，加上我们自己创建的滴灌通澳交所，就把这事做成了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;万一我们没做，或者万一我们没把它搞好，一定很快就会有其他人把它搞好做起来。就像没有互联网的时候，马云跳到天上去，他啥也干不了。有了互联网以后，他就做了淘宝，但是很快也有了京东、美团等等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;并不是我们带来了灵丹妙药，一下子破解了大家的难题。只能说我们是第一个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;为什么你们会成为第一个？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;大部分从事金融的人，看不上小微生意，认为这是不可能的；从事互联网或数字化的大部分人不了解金融的本质。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么能做呢？我们知道，全世界的资本市场主要解决两个问题，一是投资的信息准确和真实，一是投资的钱和货进出的安全有保证。具体而言，全世界投资者只会投资股票或债券，而且是大公司的股票和债券，因为投资者关心的上述两个核心问题是投资的前提。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;传统交易所为解决这两个问题，依靠大量的专业人士做研究报告、做年报等等；交收安全则依靠银行、券商和交易所一系列机构背书，保证资金进出安全保障。但这两件事件都极其昂贵。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在这种情况下，小微企业不会通过上市和发债融资。但在中国数字化革命的当下，这两个核心问题可以低成本解决了。一个小店的收入，在支付体系里完全体现出来，即信息的准确。我们就在收入上做文章，我投资你，买你的收入行不行？从收入中分一笔行不行？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于投资进出保障的问题，我们在支付体系里直接扣款，直接在银行分账体系扣款。交收安全问题就解决了。华尔街金融体系里面解决的两个核心大功能，我们通过小芯片就解决了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;解决这个问题不是做慈善，是实实在在把回报拿回来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最近有个别人质疑这个商业模式。几乎与此同时，澳交所获得伊斯兰教律监管委员会认证。澳门金管局行政委员会委员刘杏娟也表示，将秉持“风险为本”的监管原则对澳交所进行日常监控。这种创新模式的法律监管是什么样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李小加：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;投资链条非常清晰：滴灌通通过海外机构进行募资，通过外商直接投资在内地联合经营开店。目前涉及的监管包括有四个国家和地区相关法律：中国内地作为一种民事法律关系有相关法律法规、中国香港证监会监管、中国澳门金融监管条例的相关条款，认购产品的国际投资人这块，受英国法律监管。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>