<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[美伊“换囚游戏”，各有“算盘”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/pXNmTFP3LTBZpdcgUFIz9GGXcNd69gQQhcrdELuM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;701&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/pXNmTFP3LTBZpdcgUFIz9GGXcNd69g QQhcrdELuM. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252249&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 18, 2023 local time, Doha, Qatar, five people were detained in Iran The U.S. citizen was released and arrived at Doha International Airport with his family as part of a Qatar-brokered prisoner exchange deal between Iran and the United States that also freed five Iranians. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;prisoner exchange&quot; between the United States and Iran shocked the international community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 18, 2023, the United States and Iran exchanged five prisoners detained in the United States and Iran, allowing them to see the light of day again. The week before, the United States and Iran publicly reached a &quot;prisoner exchange agreement.&quot; The content of the agreement includes the United States unfreezing $6 billion of Iranian oil funds in South Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This move caused waves in the political arena. The Biden administration has been strongly criticized by US Republicans, saying that unfreezing US$6 billion is equivalent to paying a &quot;ransom&quot; and is an &quot;appeasement policy.&quot; What puzzles the outside world is why the two countries, as &quot;old enemies&quot;, &quot;swap prisoners&quot; during this time period? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many interviewed experts told Southern Weekend reporters that the United States and Iran have their own calculations behind this move, but it remains to be seen whether it can be realized. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Prisoner Exchange&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Who are the arrested Americans? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before his arrest, 51-year-old businessman Siamak Namazi worked as the director of strategic planning at Dubai-based Crescent Petroleum Company. He was arrested by Iran&#39;s Revolutionary Guards in October 2015, while his 86-year-old father Bakr was arrested in February 2016 after Iranian officials allowed him to visit his son in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The British Broadcasting Corporation reported that they were eventually sentenced to ten years in prison by Iran for &quot;cooperating with foreign hostile countries&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In recent years, the United States has repeatedly proposed to rescue or extradite Namazi. Because these people obviously serve the United States or have made great contributions to the United States, the United States is unwilling Give them up,&quot; said Li Shaoxian, director of the China Arab Studies Institute at Ningxia University. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another 59-year-old Iranian-American businessman Emad Shaji moved to Iran from the United States with his wife in 2017. In November 2020, Iran&#39;s Revolutionary Court summoned him and informed him that he would be convicted of &quot;espionage&quot; and sentenced to 10 years in prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April of the following year, his daughters told the Washington Post that their father, Shaji, was in &quot;a deplorable situation&quot; in prison and that prison guards only allowed him to make a few brief, monitored phone calls. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tabaz, a 67-year-old businessman, was arrested together with eight other Iranian environmentalists in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The BBC reported that Tabaz’s organization, a member of the Persian Wildlife Heritage Foundation, has been using cameras to track critically endangered wild Asian cheetahs and was accused of using its environmental projects as a “gathering of confidential information” cover&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tabaz and his colleagues deny Iran&#39;s accusations against them. But in the end Tabaz was sentenced to 10 years in prison in 2019. He is being held in Evin prison in Iran. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, these arrested American businessmen were released due to the &quot;prisoner exchange agreement&quot; between the United States and Iran. The names and circumstances of the other two Americans released have not yet been released. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a statement after his release, Namazi expressed his gratitude and was very interested in knowing the progress of updating mobile phone equipment. &quot;When I was arrested, the iPhone 6S had just come out.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other side of the prisoner exchange, Iranian media confirmed on the afternoon of September 18, 2023 that five Iranian citizens imprisoned in the United States had also been released. . Of the five Iranians released, only two chose to return to Iran. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Cavlani and Kashani were accused of violating &quot;sanctions.&quot; Afrasiabi, a political scientist living in Boston, was arrested at his home in 2021 on charges of being an &quot;agent of the Iranian government.&quot; Ansari and Hassanzadeh were accused of &quot;links to Iranian security forces.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shaoxian said that the prisoner exchange matter contemplated by the United States and Iran is not a temporary decision. In fact, in the US-Iran relationship, the two sides have been fighting for each other to release their own people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States and Iran have always been &quot;old enemies&quot; and have no diplomatic relations. Qatar served as the mediator for this &quot;prisoner exchange&quot;. According to public reports, negotiations between the two parties were also conducted in Doha, the capital of Qatar. After at least eight rounds of back-and-forth between Qatar and Qatar, the United States and Iran&#39;s &quot;air-space negotiations&quot; finally reached a prisoner exchange agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2022, after Iran proposed its latest nuclear agreement plan, the United States believed that Iran had regressed and decided to withdraw from the negotiations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Iran&#39;s reason is that since the United States has withdrawn from the nuclear agreement, Iran is the official representative, so it does not need to face the United States. Face-to-face talks will not occur until the United States resumes the nuclear agreement.&quot; Li Shao said that at that time The EU agrees and agrees with the United States and condemns Iran, so it cannot continue to be the middleman now. &quot;Qatar therefore plays a very important role in this negotiation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Thaw&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The agreement, brokered by the Qatari government, represents It marked an unusual moment of cooperation between the United States and Iran and a rare agreement between two long-time enemies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This deal is an important stepping stone.” Sanan Wakil, director of the Middle East and North Africa program at Chatham House in the UK, said that the months-long negotiations have restarted the US-Iran relationship. Indirect bilateral dialogue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bloomberg reported on September 19, 2023 that according to the prisoner exchange agreement, while the United States and Iran exchanged detainees, Iran’s previously frozen oil export payments of US$6 billion in South Korea were remitted to Qatar through Switzerland. Domestic Iranian bank account. The prisoners were released hours after the funds were unfrozen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;South Korea is a &quot;large consumer&quot; of Iranian oil, and the $6 billion that was unfrozen was previously South Korea&#39;s payment for Iranian oil. In 2010, the Central Bank of Iran opened Korean Won accounts in two South Korean banks specifically to collect payments from South Korea. At that time, Iran could withdraw the funds in the accounts at will. In September 2019, the Central Bank of Iran was included in the sanctions list by the United States, and US$6 billion in payments were frozen in the account. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Iran is rich in oil and natural gas resources. For Iran, US$6 billion is a small amount of money under normal circumstances.&quot; Li Shaoxian analyzed, but for Iran in the past few years, &quot;it is definitely a timely help.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reuters reported that after Qatar and Switzerland confirmed that the funds were in the account, Qatar sent a plane to take five U.S. citizens and two of their relatives out of Iran. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yin Gang, an expert on Middle East issues at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, said that Iran is not only economically difficult, but also diplomatically. At present, Iran can accept such conditions, which shows that Iran urgently needs to ease its international status and change its international balance of payments situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, both the United States and Iran have &quot;different ideas&quot; regarding the implementation of the negotiation results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Washington Post&quot; reported that when the two sides reached a prisoner exchange agreement, Iran also specifically added the validity period of the agreement. That is, if the frozen payment is not received within two months, the prisoner exchange agreement will automatically be invalidated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The two sides have no trust at all, so they just set a deadline.&quot; Li Shaoxian said that this matter is relatively sensitive for both parties, and the United States and Iran have many different voices in the country. &quot;I think the two-month limit is considered from a realistic perspective, and it also reflects that both parties want to accomplish this.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that US Republicans are criticizing the Biden administration&#39;s prisoner exchange. At the time of the move, it was stated that the unfreezing of 6 billion US dollars was equivalent to paying a ransom and may lead to more &quot;hostages&quot; being held. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Although this group of U.S. citizens have been released, there is no guarantee that other Americans who decide to go to Iran despite long-term warnings from the U.S. government will get similar results.&quot; On September 18, the U.S. Secretary of State announced Lincoln warned the people at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Win or Lose&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The outside world has received mixed reviews about this prisoner exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Al Jazeera reported that Sina Tusi, a senior fellow at the Center for International Policy, a Washington think tank, said that the prisoner exchange was an &quot;important first step.&quot; She said, &quot;This creates a basis for the United States and Iran to get rid of hostile and confrontational policies, and is expected to reach a broader diplomatic agreement.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The United States will hold a presidential election in November 2024, and at this stage, the two sides have restarted negotiations Friendly relations are unrealistic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tusi said Biden was unlikely to make concessions to Iran before the vote, which would draw attacks from Republican hawks. Iran, on the other hand, hopes to maintain its influence &quot;in case Trump returns to power.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Washington Post&quot; reported on September 19 that the prisoner exchange agreement was a signal of partial easing of US-Iran relations. It marked a breakthrough in relations between the United States and Iran, long-time enemies, although the two countries remain at odds on a range of issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Objective analysis shows that the United States has made a compromise.&quot; Li Shaoxian pointed out that in addition to US$6 billion, the Biden administration actually &quot;turned a blind eye&quot; to Iran&#39;s oil exports. Therefore, Iran&#39;s oil exports have increased significantly in recent months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;On the one hand, this move can be seen as a sign of the easing of bilateral relations between the United States and Iran. On the other hand, the United States also wants to reduce the diplomatic pressure on South Korea.&quot; Yin Gang analyzed the current relationship between the United States and South Korea Also very important. If South Korea does not pay oil to Iran, it will have great dissatisfaction with South Korea and will bring great difficulties to South Korea&#39;s diplomacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But American Republicans have different opinions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 18, former US President Trump publicly stated, &quot;The United States, which was highly respected three years ago, has now become the laughing stock of the world.&quot; Former Vice President Pence criticized Biden, Allowing Iran to “foment terrorism across the Middle East.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shaoxian analyzed that the struggle between the two parties in the United States is now booming, and the two parties are even more sharply opposed on the Iran issue and the Iranian nuclear issue. Although Biden did not lift sanctions on Iran after taking office, his goal is to restore the nuclear agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Surprisingly, on the day of the prisoner exchange, Biden issued a statement saying that the United States would impose sanctions on former Iranian President Ahmadinejad and the Iranian Intelligence Ministry on the grounds that relevant individuals and Institutions are complicit in “wrongfully imprisoning” American citizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Wall Street Journal commented on September 19 that the Biden administration has been trying to ease tensions with Iran, but it is clear that exchanging prisoners while imposing new sanctions on Iran will complicate the problem again. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the continued sanctions imposed by the United States, it seems to have become the norm for countries around the world to face restrictive measures in certain areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Iranian President Raisi said that the United States has no right to decide how Iran will use the $6 billion in funds that are about to be unfrozen. He emphasized that the frozen funds originally belonged to the Iranian people and the Iranian government, and the use was not determined by the U.S. government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Shaoxian analyzed that Iran’s nuclear technology capabilities have improved very quickly. &quot;The United States is very anxious, and Europe is also anxious.&quot; He said that under such circumstances, although the United States publicly did not lift sanctions, it gradually released its policies to whet Iran&#39;s appetite. Iran also deliberately slowed down the production of highly enriched uranium. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;There have been rumors in the international community that behind the deal, Iran promised to have active dialogue with the United States in the next step on the nuclear issue.&quot; Yin Gang said that at present, the entire Middle East The situation is on the trend of easing, between Iran and Arab countries, and between Iran and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When will there be a breakthrough in the long-stalled Iranian nuclear negotiations? Will the tension between the United States and Iran gradually ease? These issues will also affect the trend of the global political landscape. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Xu Ziyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt; hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[失落的1945——张爱玲“笔误”解谜丨云端]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257677]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/MOoJJcgGQN3BIjhiUWiurpcBJO2W25OAjeX0Mvgd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;726&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/MOoJJcgGQN3BIjhiUWiurpcBJO2W25OAjeX0 Mvgd. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252201&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Manuscript of Zhang Ailing&#39;s novel &quot;Little Reunion&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;I forgot again&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhang Ailing There are many examples of poor memory. Reading the 700,000-word &quot;Collected Letters of Zhang Ailing&quot; edited by Song Yilang and recently published by Crown has deepened this feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, Zhang Ailing’s bad memory focused on dates and numbers. The more famous &quot;public case&quot; is about the &quot;Genius Dream&quot; which gave birth to Zhang&#39;s famous saying &quot;Life is a gorgeous robe, covered with lice&quot;. Until her later years, Zhang Ailing was still bitter about the &quot;unfair treatment&quot; she suffered in the &quot;West Wind&quot; essay competition when she was 19 years old. However, scholars and Zhang fans have verified that she remembered everything wrong, whether it was the limit on the number of words in the essay, the format of the essay, or even the awards. , and maybe I didn’t read the specific terms of the essay advertisement clearly back then. The number of words in the competition was limited to 5,000, but she mistakenly thought it was 500; when she finally won the third honorary award, she wrote it as a &quot;special award&quot;; she even recorded the more than 1,500 words of her award-winning article as more than 490 words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was looking through old magazines at home not long ago and accidentally found the July 2004 issue of &quot;Yin Ke&quot;. In this issue of Zhang Ailing&#39;s album, there was published a letter she wrote to the Chinese Embassy in Washington on June 4, 1966. Letter from the British Embassy. At the time, Eileen Chang was interested in applying for a position as a writer-in-residence at a university and required proof of academic qualifications. Due to the loss of her documents, she wrote to the University of Hong Kong to request a replacement. However, the Registrar of the University of Hong Kong only certified that she had &quot;two ins and two outs&quot; and did not mention that she had received a certificate for her excellent academic performance. Scholarships and other honors, several negotiations failed. At that time, Hong Kong was still under British rule, so she wrote to the British Embassy in Washington for help. To explain his situation, there is this paragraph in the letter of more than a thousand words: &quot;...I immigrated to the United States in 1955, married an American in the 1960s, and obtained American citizenship. My mother has been naturalized as a British citizen, and she was a British citizen in 1958. Passed away in London...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I had never read this letter before, and I was very interested. But I was really surprised when I read this: She and Laiya registered their marriage in August 1956, the second year after arriving in the United States. On August 14th and August 18th, she also wrote to Kuang Wenmei, why did it suddenly become the &quot;60s&quot;? Her mother Huang Yifan died of illness in London on October 11, 1957. On October 24, she accurately reported in a letter to Song Qi and his wife that her mother had &quot;died two weeks ago&quot;, but the letter to the embassy read &quot;1958&quot; in black and white. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/J7ek9M46hhsAvN7cc670HxW3bYAzesTK5Rxozede.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height= &quot;1593&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/J7ek9M46hhsAvN7cc670HxW3bYAzesTK5Rxozede.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252200&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The photo that her mother took with her when she left China returned to Zhang Ailing after her death. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This letter was translated into Chinese by Chen Ziyu, and Su Weizhen wrote the introduction. Neither of them discovered it, so it was also There is no &quot;clerical error&quot; noted in the letter. Indeed, no one would have thought that in 1966, Zhang Ailing was 46 years old and was only middle-aged. No matter how bad her memory was, she would not have mistaken the year of her mother&#39;s death and the year of her remarriage. Moreover, she wrote a formal letter to an official agency. inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, when I saw so many &quot;I remembered wrongly&quot; and &quot;I forgot again&quot; in the collection of letters between Zhang Ailing and Song Qi, I was no longer surprised. Zhang Ailing lives largely on royalties in the United States, but she can&#39;t even figure out whether Crown Publishing&#39;s fixed royalties for a certain period of time are US$2,000 for half a year or a year. What&#39;s even more outrageous is that before leaving Hong Kong for the United States in 1955, with the help of Song Qi, she advanced all the royalties for two scripts from the Telecom Company, but she forgot all about it five years later. Only after being reminded by Kwong Wenmei did she remember that she had done so. This is the case. It is simply unbelievable that a person who is most afraid of owing money or favors would forget such a sum of money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few days, I have been browsing a collection of essays by book reviewer Liu Zheng, and I came across an article titled &quot;Zhang Ailing Remembers Wrongly&quot;, which records the errors in words, sources, plots, and mistakes in Zhang Ailing&#39;s works. , a total of 22 cases, which is eye-opening. Regarding citation errors, I also read in Chen Zishan&#39;s &quot;Cong Kao of Zhang Ailing&quot; that Zhang Ailing quoted Lu Xun&#39;s translation of the Soviet writer Shuxue Jianke (also translated as Zuoqenko) in 1926 in &quot;Talk about Eating and Painting Cake to Appease Hungry&quot;. The short story &quot;Women of a Noble Family&quot; in 2000 was mistakenly written as &quot;Baozi&quot;; while &quot;Baozi&quot; written by Zhang Ailing was actually translated by Lu Xun as &quot;Meat Buns&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both Chen Zishan and Liu Zheng are sharp-eyed and knowledgeable, but they still respect Zhang Ailing. Liu Zheng said: &quot;In terms of human relations and physics, as well as in choosing words and sentences, Zhang Ailing can be said to be a very thoughtful person. However, she did not seem to care much about whether the quotations were accurate. In addition, it was very difficult to check the information at that time, so Zhang Ailing She doesn’t have the habit of collecting books, so it’s normal to have some misremembering when quoting. To put it into perspective, Zhang Ailing obviously doesn’t have a ‘photographic memory’, maybe she just has a poor memory; what she left behind There are really not too many clerical errors.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Zheng explained that he had no other intention in writing down these when he was studying, but just for fun - Zhang Ailing would also remember it wrong! At the end of the article, a sentence from Sontag&#39;s novel &quot;The Volcano Lover&quot; was quoted: &quot;Genius, like beauty, everything, well almost everything, will be forgiven.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interestingly, He attributed the clerical errors to memory and unverified information. On the contrary, Zhang Ailing said in &quot;Contrast Notes&quot;: Freud, the master of psychological analysis, believed that there is no clerical error or an occasional wrong word, it is all what he thought in his heart and revealed it inadvertently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But it was also in &quot;Contrast Notes&quot; that Zhang Ailing left another famous &quot;clerical error&quot;: the well-documented &quot;cool party&quot; in Shanghai on July 21, 1945 The photo taken with Li Xianglan was annotated as &quot;Meet the movie star Li Xianglan at a garden party in 1943.&quot; As if following the Freudian line of thinking mentioned by Eileen Chang, two scholars have tried to analyze whether Chang Eileen&#39;s &quot;clerical error&quot; of &quot;one or two years&quot; was just due to poor memory, or there is another meaningful reason behind it. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;1945&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Cooling Party/1943 Garden Party&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Comparative Notes - Looking at Old Photo Albums&quot; is Zhang Ailing&#39;s last work This work is also her only autobiographical collection of pictures and texts. &quot;Picture 41&quot; in the book is a photo of her and Li Xianglan that has been treasured for nearly 50 years. She wrote: In 1943, she met Li Xianglan at a garden party and wanted to take a photo together. She was too tall and the two of them would complement each other if they stood side by side. , someone asked her to sit down, and Li Xianglan stood aside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/iEioqzjAsX9CGyu33WRvaDrFnNz5X5Lb1h9JvdFX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;693&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/iEioqzjAsX9CGyu33WRvaDrFnNz5X5Lb1h9JvdFX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252202&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1943, Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan (right) took a photo in Shanghai. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The book &quot;After Yun&quot; mentions clothes made from the quilt cover of my grandmother&#39;s bed. This is the one. It was taken down by my aunt and saved. Although the tailor said that &#39;chen silk is like rotten grass&#39;, the tailor did not frown, took it without saying a word, and made it according to Yanying&#39;s design. The beige thin silk was sprinkled with light The ink dots hide a dark purple phoenix, which is very picturesque. I have never seen a similar pattern elsewhere.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;1943&quot;, this year is ridiculously wrong, the correct time and place is: July 1945 On the 21st, a &quot;cool party&quot; hosted by &quot;Magazine&quot; was held at No. 2 Xianyang Road, Shanghai. The basis is &quot;Magazine&quot; in August 1945, which published the article &quot;Records of Enjoying the Cool Coolness&quot;. In addition to this picture of Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan, there is another group photo: Li Xianglan and Zhang Ailing maintain the same posture, and Zhang Ailing&#39;s aunt is also seen. Zhang Maoyuan, his best friend Yan Ying, an unidentified Ms. Chen, and two men in long gowns - Chen Binhe, the president of the Shenbao Press during the Wang puppet period, and Jin Xiongbai, the president of the Pingbao Press. According to Shao Yingjian, a Chinese scholar who studied in Japan and is now a researcher in Japan, in the book &quot;The Legendary Literature and Rumor Life of Zhang Ailing&quot;, Xianyang Road was the name of the current Shaanxi South Road from 1943 to 1945. It was older. The name familiar to Shanghainese is &quot;Yalpe Road&quot;. No. 2 Xianyang Road was the garden of Jin Xiongbai’s private residence at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1994, when &quot;Contrast&quot; was published, it was the year before Zhang Ailing&#39;s death. In her declining years, she had to study the skirt that she had changed from her grandmother&#39;s old quilt cover, from the texture, color, pattern, Patterns, origins, styles, designs, and tailors are all fresh and clear in my memory. Why do I remember the wrong time and place when I took the photo? What kind of information does this 1943, this &quot;clerical error&quot; reveal? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shao Yingjian believes that if you understand Zhang Ailing’s life, this mystery will not be difficult to solve. For Zhang Ailing, 1943 to 1945 were the most glorious days in this life. She wrote &quot;Legend&quot; and &quot;Rumors&quot; in just two years, and she rose to the top of the literary world when she was just starting out. &quot;In the database of the brain, this is a A perfect file, with no details, displayed in its entirety on the screen of memory.&quot; - This statement is very tempting: in the stage of life when the fire is burning, the oil is blooming, and the flowers are blooming, the memory is mixed and unclear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for what Shao Yingjian pointed out, Zhang Ailing wrote &quot;cooling party&quot; as &quot;garden party&quot;, in my opinion, it does not seem to be a clerical error, just like some people say that going to a &quot;theater&quot; or &quot;cinema&quot; to watch a movie is not a mistake. substantial difference. But researcher Shao focused on the difference between the two words and found his answer - interestingly, he also made a &quot;clerical error&quot;. After checking several versions of &quot;Contrast Notes&quot;, Zhang Ailing wrote &quot;Garden Party&quot; Rather than a &quot;garden party&quot; - he found out from the old &quot;Declaration&quot; that on July 8, 1944, the Wang Puppet &quot;Shanghai Press Association&quot; held a party in the central square of Hartung Garden, attended by thousands of people from all walks of life. &quot;Citizen Garden Lecture&quot;, the program includes red star singing and movie card screening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although he did not specifically mention the red star singing that night or the celebrities attending the meeting, Shao Wen determined that the red star was &quot;most likely&quot; the popular Li Xianglan, and Zhang Ailing, who is already a celebrity in the maritime literary world, &quot;naturally&quot; should also Be present. He deduced from this that it was on this occasion that Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan met for the first time: &quot;...the first tangible and tangible meeting was at this garden party. The impression on them was profound and indelible. As the years passed, As time went by, the subsequent impressions became shallow and flat, leaving only this scratch. How many years later, in Zhang Ailing’s brain inventory, all the fate with Li Xianglan was merged into this time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;He further said that when Zhang Ailing stood on the balcony of her apartment (Eddington Apartment, today&#39;s Changde Apartment), she could see a corner of Hartung Garden. Hartung Garden can also be regarded as Zhang Ailing’s neighborhood. Zhang Ailing also mentioned this legendary garden twice in her 1944 serial &quot;Serial Set&quot; in Vientiane. &quot;Although the scale of Jin Xiongbai&#39;s private garden and Hartung Garden are not the same, there are some similarities: they are both Western-style houses with flower beds and lawns. Just based on the background of the photo and the Western-style cushion chairs, in Zhang Ailing&#39;s memory, , unknowingly, the garden of Jin Xiongbai&#39;s private residence was replaced by Hartung Garden, and the &#39;cooling party&#39; also turned into a &#39;garden party.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That&#39;s right. One thing is certain: Zhang Ailing has never mentioned and has not seen any information showing that she has been to the &quot;garden party&quot; in Hartung Gardens. Therefore, Mr. Shao&#39;s discussion based on assumptions has a strong reasoning component and is more like a It is a imaginative fiction. The mystery of forgetting is complicated and confusing, and a convincing analysis comes from Professor Wong Sham-cun, Chairman of the Department of Comparative Literature at the University of Hong Kong. In a wonderful essay, she spent six and a half pages discussing the photo of Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan taken three weeks before Japan surrendered, and put forward a meaningful &quot;maybe&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“I don’t remember a thing in this year”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Picture 50” in “Contrast Notes” is a picture of Zhang Ailing leaving Hong Kong in 1955 In the photo before America, the makeup is exquisite, the side face is lowered and the eyes are downcast. Eileen Chang described taking a boat from Hong Kong and passing through Honolulu. The customs officer was a skinny Japanese young man who clearly filled out her entry form: height 6 feet 6 and a half inches and weight 102 pounds. She laughed at the young man&#39;s carelessness and made a Freudian slip by writing 5 feet 6 and a half inches as 6 feet 6 and a half inches. &quot;I am thin and look very tall. That is the shocking record of this customs officer.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /26/g8ajGWryb6p5fYU92Aa3zTiqI33SZTgtDdLC5XE5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1267&quot; height=&quot;1738&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/g8ajGWryb6p5fYU92Aa3zTiqI33SZT gtDdLC5XE5.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252199&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Contrast Notes&quot; contains photos of Zhang Ailing before she left Hong Kong for the United States in 1955. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Picture 41&quot; in &quot;Contrast Notes&quot;, Zhang Ailing was &quot;careless&quot; and mistakenly recorded as &quot;1943&quot; &quot;Year&quot; frame with Li Xianglan is considered by scholars to be the most important photo of her in Shanghai. Professor Huang Xincun has a paper &quot;Mottled Light and Shadow: Zhang Ailing&#39;s Japan and East Asia&quot;, and his analysis starts from this photo. Taken on July 21, 1945, just three weeks before the end of World War II and Japan’s surrender, “Its strange composition and uncoordinated visual style are also impressive. Viewers who are familiar with the background of the photo even regard it as a depiction.” On the eve of the collapse of the Japanese Empire, a visual allegory of the crumbling Japanese-Chinese combination.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Huang’s analysis of the photo focuses on the different expressions of Zhang Ailing and Li Xianglan, the strange composition of the photo, and their different dressing styles, especially It’s Zhang Ailing’s perverse sitting posture, her downward gaze away from the camera, and all the details. She said, &quot;Zhang Ailing&#39;s facial expressions and body may imply resistance or contempt, but more importantly, she obviously knows how to turn the gaze of the camera lens on her into a help to deepen her own image.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;What I am more interested in is how did Zhang Ailing, her aunt, and Yan Ying go to this &quot;garden party&quot; three weeks before Japan was defeated? Japan unconditionally surrendered on August 15, and the current situation suddenly changed. Hu Lancheng, who had been an important member of the Wang Puppet Government, was wanted by the Nationalist Government and fled hastily. How did it bring shock and panic to Zhang Ailing? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suddenly it occurred to me that I should review &quot;Little Reunion&quot;. What happened in the long summer of 1945 is described in the book. Moreover, at the beginning of Chapter 8, what Zhang Ailing wrote about Jiuli was simply an annotation in advance for her subsequent &quot;clerical error&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;From this time until the end of World War II , for more than half a year, there was a kind of chaos in her heart, which was sealed with a layer of white wax, which was a sense of calm and security on the surface. What happened during this period was always regarded as the previous year or the next year. &quot;...I don&#39;t remember a single thing in this year. It can be called a lost year.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;When she first met him, she knew that he was going to flee after the war, but she became confused when things happened. , also because this was her &#39;lost year&#39; and she was devastated.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despondent, she banished 1945 in her heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Maybe Zhang Ailing herself doesn&#39;t want to believe that this photo was taken on the eve of Japan&#39;s defeat.&quot; Huang Xincun wrote a sentence in the &quot;Notes&quot; of the paper that is heart-stopping. Yes, there is no 1945, only 1943, only the previous year or the next year. Although &quot;Contrast&quot; was published in 1994, half a century after those unbearable and chaotic days, she still remembered that there was a kind of Freudian error. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Psychology has a lot to say about memory and forgetting. Whether Zhang Ailing left defective memories a year before her death was due to retrograde amnesia caused by damage to the hippocampus of the brain, or active forgetting of emotional memories, it is no longer a question. Of course, exploring the secrets involved is not to &quot;disenchant&quot;. As Huang Xinchun said, it is only to &quot;restore a historical Eileen Chang&quot; and &quot;a more complex Eileen Chang&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Subconsciously shielding the unbearable past and deleting the dark aspects on the memory chip. Isn’t it true for us, many ordinary &quot;people&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I strongly agree with this statement: What ultimately constitutes a person&#39;s life is not experience, spirituality, or any events, but the memory, description, and interpretation of all these experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Matsuo Basho has a haiku: The temple bell/stopped, but the lingering sound in the flowers/continues to echo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[二十届中央第一轮巡视完成反馈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257717]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the deployment of the Party Central Committee, the first round of inspection and feedback work of the 20th Central Committee has been completed recently. Feedback from this round of inspections is carried out through a combination of centralized feedback and &quot;one-on-one&quot; feedback from the inspection team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, the Central Inspection Leading Group held a centralized feedback meeting on the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee. The meeting conveyed and studied the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech when he listened to the Central Committee’s first round of inspection reports, informed the common problems discovered during the inspection, and made arrangements for rectification during the inspection. Liu Jinguo, secretary of the Central Secretariat and deputy leader of the Central Inspection Leading Group, attended the meeting and delivered a speech. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From September 20th to 22nd, 15 central inspection teams conducted &quot;one-on-one&quot; meetings with the party groups of 30 medium-sized enterprises, 5 party committees of medium-sized financial enterprises, and the party group of the State Sports General Administration during this round of inspections. feedback. According to the Central Inspection Work Arrangement, each Central Inspection Team notified the principals of the inspected party organizations of the outstanding problems discovered during the inspection, and reported the inspection situation to the leadership team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feedback pointed out that in recent years, centrally managed enterprises and financial enterprises have faced the complex and severe external environment and the impact of the epidemic. They have withstood the test and bravely shouldered heavy responsibilities. They have been successful in winning the battle against poverty and promoting high-level scientific and technological self-reliance. It has made important contributions in building a new development pattern, promoting high-quality development, coordinating epidemic prevention and control, and economic and social development, and has made new progress in building a sports power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The feedback seriously pointed out the outstanding problems existing in the fields of state-owned enterprises, finance and sports. Some fail to implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, do not have a deep understanding of the responsibilities and missions they shoulder, and have gaps in their performance of duties; some do not coordinate development and safety, have weak risk awareness, and have insufficient prevention and control mechanisms; some implement party management The responsibility for party governance is not in place, the pressure transmission is decreasing layer by layer, the implementation of the strict tone is weak, the integrity risks of key positions such as &quot;top leaders&quot; are relatively prominent, the problem of &quot;depending on the enterprise to take advantage of the enterprise&quot; is common, the &quot;four styles&quot; problem is prominent, and it violates the eight central regulations Mental problems still occur; there are weak links in the construction of some leadership groups and cadre talent teams, and the political functions of grassroots party organizations need to be strengthened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The feedback requires that the inspected units should thoroughly study Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, conscientiously study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech when he listened to the inspection report, and fully implement the deployment of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. Uphold and strengthen the party&#39;s leadership, firmly establish and practice a correct view of political performance, completely, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, adhere to functional positioning, focus on main responsibilities and main businesses, and promote high-quality development. It is necessary to resolutely implement the political responsibility to prevent and resolve major risks, establish bottom-line thinking and extreme thinking, comprehensively sort out and investigate hidden risks, plug leaks and fill gaps, resolve risks and recover losses, and effectively safeguard national interests. It is necessary to conscientiously implement the &quot;two responsibilities&quot; of comprehensively and strictly governing the party, strengthen the effectiveness of supervision of &quot;top leaders&quot;, intensify the investigation and handling of corruption cases, seriously correct the &quot;four styles&quot; problem, deepen the use of cases to promote reform, use cases to promote treatment, and integrate We dare not, cannot, or do not want to be corrupted. It is necessary to thoroughly implement the party&#39;s organizational line in the new era and effectively strengthen the construction of leadership teams, cadres and talent teams, and grassroots party organizations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Feedback emphasized that inspections and rectifications should be more serious and tough, and the strict tone, strict measures, and strict atmosphere should be passed on and carried out consistently. The inspected party organization must resolutely shoulder the political responsibility for rectification. The &quot;top leader&quot; is the first person responsible for rectification. Other members of the team must conscientiously perform &quot;one post, two responsibilities&quot;, strictly compare feedback opinions, and establish a problem list, task list, and responsibility list. Combining the problems found during the inspection with the theme education inspection issues and the problems that were not rectified in the last inspection, rectify the system and rectify the whole body, practice the &quot;two maintenances&quot; with practical actions, and reflect the loyalty and responsibility with the rectification results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The feedback requires that the responsibilities of all parties for rectification should be consolidated and efforts should be made in the same direction to solve the problem. Discipline inspection and supervision agencies must strengthen daily supervision of rectification, focus on key issues, focus on specific people and specific matters, strengthen on-the-spot inspections, grasp the real situation, and seize examples of those who deal with perfunctory or false rectifications and seriously hold accountable them. The organizational department should strengthen research and guidance based on the inspection situation, and promote the solution of outstanding problems in the construction of leadership teams, cadres and talent teams, and grassroots party organizations. Relevant functional departments must comprehensively make full use of the inspection results, strengthen daily supervision of common and deep-seated problems reflected in the inspection, deepen reforms in key areas, optimize policy supply, and improve systems and mechanisms. Inspection agencies must strengthen overall coordination and supervision, establish and improve rectification work mechanisms, and report important situations to the Party Central Committee in a timely manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the Central Inspection Team has also received clues about problems reported by some leading cadres, and has transferred them to the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission, the Organization Department of the Central Committee and other relevant parties for handling in accordance with relevant regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 22:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访胡歌：如果不做演员，生活里的我应该什么样？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257715]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Throughout September, Hu Ge’s work was fully scheduled. He had just attended related activities at the Venice Film Festival, and then flew back to Beijing to attend the premiere of the movie &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/i696A6YUsdAgCij7tPH3N2q1voWbuMVhpkbNsLQz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/i696A6YUsdAgCij7tPH3N2q1voWbuMVhpkbNsLQz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252253&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hu Ge (left) and &quot;It&#39;s Worth It&quot; director Liu Jiayin at a business dinner at the Shanghai International Film Festival in June 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to promote this low-cost literary film, Hu Ge traveled to seven cities in nine days, non-stop to Group after group of viewers shared their feelings about the male protagonist Wen Shan. He said: &quot;When I meet a character I like, I am not playing him, but becoming him.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film&#39;s director Liu Jiayin expressed his &quot;jealousy&quot; of Hu Ge: &quot;This character is obviously mine. But I feel like you understand him better than I do. Now I understand that the extra thing is yourself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Shan is nearly forty years old and was once a failed entrepreneur. The screenwriter, because he believes that &quot;ordinary people can also be the protagonist&quot;, has never been able to write a script that satisfies Party A. Over time, he gradually lost confidence in himself and gave up this career. The character that he could not write became a part of his heart, transforming into a boy named Xiao Yin, who often jumped out of his mind to talk to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Wen Shan was in school, he liked to go to funeral parlors and zoos to take notes on his life, which later became a habit. After his life fell into embarrassment, he accidentally found a new job - writing articles for clients to commemorate their deceased relatives and friends. After completing an article, he could get 4,000 yuan, which could just cover his room and board expenses in the suburbs of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Shan always wears baggy clothes that have been washed too many times. He is habitually hunched over and has long hair that covers his eyes. He cuts his nails frequently because of typing all the time. He likes to buy large buckets of mineral water and directly Lift it up and drink. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At first glance, there is not much connection between the frustrated Wen Shan and Hu Ge himself, except that the latter has also come into contact with many screenwriters at work.胡歌有些遗憾地对南方周末记者说：“这个行业有时候是挺畸形的，除非编剧是个大腕儿，否则几乎没有表达的权力，大部分时候只能等着被评价，甚至没有反驳的机会。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在胡歌眼中，闻善是一个不愿意妥协的人，他不是不知道怎么写（剧本）才可以得到青睐，但他不愿意做自己不想做的事情。 “我希望成为这样的人，很多时候却做不到，我很羡慕他。”胡歌说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年初，胡歌在微博上突然公开了结婚生女的消息，很快登上热搜榜，网上议论不断。他不吝分享初为人父的喜悦：“我第一次抱着女儿的时候，就好像抱着一块豆腐，我怕我一晃就把她给晃坏了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“结婚生子的事情以前也考虑过，但没有付诸行动。作这个决定是在出演闻善之后，这个角色带给我挺多改变和影响的。演完这个角色，我就有了很多底气，要去做我认为应该做的选择。”胡歌告诉南方周末记者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出道二十年，胡歌早就不是《仙剑奇侠传》里李逍遥那样的毛头小伙，更接近《琅琊榜》里九死一生的梅长苏。细心的观众会发现，每当《不虚此行》的镜头给到胡歌的特写，右眼的伤疤清晰可见，他早已能够直面2006年那场车祸带给自己的影响。车祸发生后的头两三部戏，胡歌还曾用刘海挡着这道伤疤，后来就放下了：“我自己都过不了这一关的话，怎么让别人接受？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《琅琊榜》《伪装者》等作品后，观众开始关注胡歌的演技，他则决定“停下来”“放下现有的一些工作，专心去体验生活”。时隔数年，《不虚此行》或许可以看作胡歌的答卷，凭借这部影片，他获得了第25届上海国际电影节最佳男演员奖，在颁奖典礼上，他说：“当一个演员真正爱上一个角色的时候，他就会把自己完全地交给这个角色。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/m0wYwiSsUoiV4OaxXvNhtGAIoiNsQ4VHZX5MklBS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/m0wYwiSsUoiV4OaxXvNhtGAIoiNsQ4VHZX5MklBS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252252&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;胡歌在第25届上海国际电影节闭幕式现场休息区。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月中旬的一天下午，南方周末记者通过网络连线的方式采访胡歌，原定采访时间只有半小时，但胡歌却说：“没关系，我很愿意多聊聊。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以下是胡歌的自述：&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;他身上有我不具备的坚定&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;《不虚此行》讲的是普通人，让很多观众从中看到了自己。 （我）跑了七个城市做路演，观众在交流的时候愿意分享自己面对亲友离世的经历，这是我最能够感同身受的地方，这个剧本和我自己的生活有很多交集。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几年前，我母亲去世了，悼词是我自己写的。所以我最初读剧本的时候，代入的不是闻善，而是他的某一个委托人。我到现在也没有从这段经历中完全走出来，还需要很长时间去接受生命终结这件事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此之前，我没有想过生活中还有像闻善这样的人。在我们的传统文化里，我们似乎非常避讳去谈论死亡和生命的终结。因此当至亲离开后，通常情况下，也很难找到人去分享和倾诉，这个剧本给了我温暖的感觉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;闻善对我来说还有另一层意义，用现在的话说他是一个“i人”（编者注：近年流行的MBTI人格测试的一种结果，与“e人”相对，二者近似于分别对应内向的人和外向的人），内向的人。他不善于表达，也不善于和人相处。说实话，真实的我可能就是这样一种性格。但他身上有我不具备的坚定，不会因为外界的评价和所谓世俗的标准去改变自己的选择，这一点是让我羡慕的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在他身上看见了我做不到的自己，是我理想的样子，我很想成为他。你别看他不是一个存在感很强的人，但骨子里还是很轴的。这种轴对我来说是一种勇气，也是一种坚持，更是一种魄力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我骨子里是i人，但看上去不太像，这可能和职业与环境都有一些关系。同样是i人，闻善更能坚持自己的选择，我却经常做不到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为一名编剧，闻善好像没有那么成功，不是因为能力问题，而是选择问题。他坚持自己的审美，不愿意改变自己的创作方向。他整个职业生涯几乎没有自己表达的机会，总是没来得及完成作品就被别人否定了。但难得的是，他从来没有说一定要去征得别人的认同，这是一种内在的坚持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;闻善人生的转机是机缘巧合中有了给别人写悼词的工作，虽然这份工作和做编剧完全是两回事，但同样都是在用文字创作。在工作中，闻善找到了一种认同感，这并不是说大家夸他写得很好，而是他用自己的善意与真诚，在不断交流中带给他人的影响。比如片中的王先生，他通过闻善的悼词，重新理解去世的父亲，这才是闻善工作的意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/pf6D5BNM6E4lSzTB57y1Lxai5d60id3WlXYJbTCa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/pf6D5BNM6E4lSzTB57y1Lxai5d60id3WlXYJbTCa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252250&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电影《不虚此行》中，客户王先生的儿子对胡歌饰演的闻善（右）袒露心中的秘密，闻善由此发现这家人彼此之间无言的爱。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（片方供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我并不认为《不虚此行》主要表达的东西是死亡，它借着死亡讲的是我们怎样书写人生。闻善从一个编剧到写悼词的人，他在用笔创作人物，书写别人的故事。回过头看，我们在用每天的生活书写自己的人生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每一个阶段人会变化，但和具体的年龄无关，反而和经历有关。 2019年，我的母亲去世了，接着我们又经历了三年的疫情，看到了很多生离死别。这个过程中，我想不仅仅是我，很多人都会对生命有更多的思考。 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;大部分人都是主角&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;什么叫普通人？普通人并不是通常理解的特别平庸的人，而是相对于那些带有主角光环的人而言的。后者身上往往有特别强的戏剧冲突，在生活中发生了很多奇迹。但生活中普通人才是大部分，我们生活中很难遇到偶像剧主角那样的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;影片强调的“普通人也能做主角”，就是说大部分人都是主角。我们对于成功的定义好像太标准化了，一切事情都变得很功利。其实每个人的轨迹都不一样，有时候把眼光和目标放得太统一了，很容易就错过人生真正重要的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于个体来说，我们原本就在自己的故事里，在自己的成长轨迹中，你当然就是自己的主角，为什么非要当自己是配角呢？ （为什么）非要把符合所谓概念中的成功的人物形象称为主角呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我是一个经常容易纠结的人，内心的自我和闻善很接近，只不过因为我的各种好运气，让我的人生过得和偶像剧一样。从内心来说，我确实对自己的人生是有问号的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;闻善和我以往塑造的角色都不一样，几乎所有的角色都带有主角光环，即使带着某些缺陷，也一定有特别厉害的能力，是所谓的“悲情英雄”。我以往塑造角色都是在做加法，要在身上叠加各种能力才能抵达人物，但这一次是做减法，需要把现在身上附加的各种东西卸下来，回到最初的自己。说得简单一点，如果我不做演员的话，我在生活里应该是什么样？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次我并没有刻意设计什么动作，我塑造闻善，并不是去演这个人物，而是成为他，所以没有用一些特别外化的方式，而是先靠近人物的内心，其他的东西就是一种自然流露。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小尹是闻善内心的镜像，作为一个倾听者，闻善是孤独的，很少能够找到让他可以倾诉的对象，他不得不学会和自己相处。小尹的存在就是用了一个特别的方式去呈现孤独的人如何与自己相处，这样他至少不是寂寞的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/MC2AiDpZGMtuM4xiW492lOe04yepgJnApFZGdZ0L.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/MC2AiDpZGMtuM4xiW492lOe04yepgJnApFZGdZ0L.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252251&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;电影《不虚此行》中，胡歌饰演的闻善（左）和他内心的小尹（右，吴磊饰）。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（片方供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;真正可悲的是孤独的人还要承受寂寞，孤独却不寂寞，是一个相对理想的状态。小尹是闻善心中更积极大胆的部分，但这一面一直被压抑着，他的内心一直存在着自我对抗和纠结。小尹一直在推着闻善更加勇敢地面对现实。最后小尹消失了，代表闻善找到了自信，可以作为编剧继续创作，让小尹回到了剧本世界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我自己的身体里恐怕不止一个小尹，经常有些小小的分裂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;演员是动物园里的大猩猩&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;闻善会经常观察周围的环境和人物，做生活笔记，片中最重要的两个场景殡仪馆和动物园，都是闻善爱去的地方，他可以静静观察周围的人和物。我自己可能也有所谓的职业病，喜欢观察遇到的人，并不是说我演了某个角色，我才要去找一些人物作为参考，而是和福尔摩斯似的，看见一个不认识的人从眼前走过，忍不住会猜测对方的职业履历和家庭关系，会想象这个人刚才在做什么，又经历过什么。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我不习惯去给过去的角色贴标签，每一个角色对我都很有意义。都说电影电视就是遗憾的艺术，没有办法重来，但我会经常反思，每当演完一个角色，就会去想自己哪里演得不好。可能我并不是一个那么有自信的人，即使别人说如何的好，我还是会给自己挑出毛病来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看完《不虚此行》的剧本，我就开始了和导演刘伽茵长达半年的网络交流。那段时间，我一直在《繁花》剧组，基本每天都要开工，只能和刘伽茵导演通过微信沟通，我们第一次见面就是定妆那天，我都已经进组开工了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;合作过这么多导演，每一位的工作方法都不一样，和演员的交流相处也不一样，我觉得对于导演来说，如何启发演员、引导演员，是工作中特别重要的一部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孔笙导演会给演员特别大的空间，他可能会给你一个大的方向，然后具体的表演方式他会特别放心地交给演员。姜伟导演同时还是非常优秀的编剧，他的剧本所有的台词都无法调整，就连语气词都非常准确。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王家卫导演给我的感觉反而和之前一些媒体报道的不同，他之前的电影在拍摄的过程中可能没有特别具体的方向，但这次我感到他特别知道自己想要什么，也会表达得十分具体。当然有时候他也会让你去突破，如果能够给到他意料之外的火花，也就是更好的即兴的表演，他也会非常欣赏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有时候，角色就是不同形状的瓶子，演员就是水。每次进入到不同的角色里，演员就变成了不同的样子。所以表演是流动的，水进入瓶子之后才被固定成一个形状。我觉得导演最需要的是那个流动的瞬间，从艺术上来说，这一刻才是最美好的表达，而不是那个固定的样子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于演员来说，很多时候因为成名了就忘记如何平视生活。平视生活是非常重要的。忘记自己从哪里来，这是一件特别要命的事情。不演戏、不工作的时候，就是回归生活，要忘记自己的职业和身份。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我很羡慕那种可以卸下自己演员身份的生活状态，所以没事的时候，我总是想往远的地方走走。我每次去青海做志愿者，就有网友说我去捡垃圾什么的。其实我就是想去洗涤一下，把身上一些不属于生活的东西洗掉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多时候大家对演员有想象，往往都带着角色滤镜，以为我们和普通人不一样。当你卸下演员这个职业回到生活里，我日常所处理的东西，无非也是今天这只猫生病了，明天那块墙皮掉下来了，浴室的热水怎么不热了……这些构成了生活，面对这些日常，我经常感到自己能力有限，比不上很多人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我常常思考演员好像是动物园里的大猩猩，一天24小时的一举一动都在大家的关注之下。很多时候大家将自己的各种好奇、审视和监督都投射在演员身上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾想过冲破这个牢笼，不在这个动物园待了，想要跑到大街上去。但你要知道，猩猩在动物园的时候有笼子隔着，跑到大街上可能会受到更多关注，岂不是要被围追堵截了？所以既然选择了这份职业，在得到很多的同时，就要承受它的压力，这是公平的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运中国第39金！体操女队实现亚运会13连冠，乌兹别克斯坦48岁老将晋级跳马决赛]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257719]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 21:01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the women&#39;s qualifying and team competition for gymnastics at the Hangzhou Asian Games The final was held at Huanglong Stadium, and the Chinese team players appeared.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/8a89cb0d56.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/8a89cb0d56.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252259&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the evening of September 25, 2023, the women&#39;s qualifying competition and team finals of the gymnastics event of the Hangzhou Asian Games were held at the Huanglong Stadium, and the Chinese team players appeared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the women&#39;s qualifying competition and team finals of the gymnastics event of the Hangzhou Asian Games were held at the Huanglong Gymnasium. Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, Zhang Jin, The Chinese team composed of Yu Linmin and Tang Xijing won the championship with 161.896 points, achieving the 13th consecutive Asian Games women&#39;s team championship. This is also the 39th gold medal won by the Chinese sports delegation in this Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the Chinese team composed of Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, Zhang Jin, Yu Linmin, and Tang Xijing won the championship with 161.896 points.&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/029c619686.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/26/029c619686.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252260&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 2023 On the evening of the 25th, the Chinese team consisting of Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, Zhang Jin, Yu Linmin, and Tang Xijing won the championship with 161.896 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Chinese team players warmed up before the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/f62058eb4b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/f62058eb4b. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252261&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Chinese team players warmed up before the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Due to competing for Olympic tickets at this year&#39;s World Championships, three all-around masters Ou Yushan, Qiu Qiyuan, and Zhang Qingying, as well as two individual masters Zhou Yaqin and Huang Zhuofan, went to the Antwerp World Championships. In the Hangzhou Asian Games, two senior players who participated in the Tokyo Olympics, Zhang Jin and Tang Xijing, led Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, and Yu Linmin, three teammates with less experience in the international arena, to participate. Among them, Zhang Xinyi, Zuo Tong, and Zhang Jin participated in the all-around competition and competed in all four events in the qualifying round. Tang Xijing participated in the uneven bars, balance beam, and floor exercise, and Yu Linmin competed in the vault. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Yu Linmin competed in the vaulting competition.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26 /a9a52bf896.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/a9a52bf896.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;252262&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Yu Linmin competed in the vaulting competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Jin performed in the floor exercise event.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/26/4b9181b8b2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/ 4b9181b8b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252263&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Chinese team player Zhang Jin performed in the floor exercise event middle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, Tang Qian competed in the uneven bars.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 26/011ce52486.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/011ce52486.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252264&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Tang Xijing competed in the uneven bars competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the Asian Games gymnastics event was held in the Huanglong Stadium. Some spectators raised the North Korean flag and shouted in support of the North Korean team.&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/ad42324924.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/26/ad42324924.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252265&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9, 2023 On the evening of March 25, during the Asian Games gymnastics event in the Huanglong Stadium, some spectators raised the North Korean flag and cheered in support of the North Korean team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Chinese team competed in four categories: vault, uneven bars, balance beam, and floor exercise. After all four competitions ended, the Chinese women&#39;s team won the championship with 161.896 points. , achieving the 13th consecutive Asian Games women’s team championship. The Japanese team and the North Korean team won the runner-up and third place respectively, with scores of 157.229 points and 156.829 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the North Korean team won the third place in the women&#39;s team finals of competitive gymnastics with 156.829 points.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/26/0a3916b339.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/0a3916b339.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252266&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of September 25, 2023, the North Korean team scored 156.829 Won the third place in the women&#39;s team finals of competitive gymnastics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, although Uzbek player Chusovitina&#39;s left leg was bandaged, she still showed high-quality performance in the gymnastics competition of the Hangzhou Asian Games. Action.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/cc88658e26.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1615&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/cc88658e26.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252267&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text- align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, although Uzbek player Chusovitina’s left leg was bandaged, she still showed high-quality movements in the gymnastics competition of the Hangzhou Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 48-year-old Uzbekistan veteran Chusovitina participated in the vault and balance beam competitions, becoming a highlight of the game. She ranked Ranked fifth in the qualifying round and advanced to the vault finals. Chusovitina previously told the outside world: &quot;I cannot end my career before winning a medal on behalf of Uzbekistan. After the Asian Games, I will also participate in the 2024 Paris Olympics. Desire is my biggest motivation. I just Why should I stop doing what I love?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 25, 2023, after the vault, Chusovitina raised her hands above her head to gesture to the audience. My heartfelt regards.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/c8d03ea78a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1615&quot; data- src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/c8d03ea78a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252268&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 25, 2023, at After the vault, Chusovitina raised her hands above her head to express her heartfelt greetings to the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D还原江苏连环龙卷风，两地同日遭袭致10死8伤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257689]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[网暴可能涉及哪五种罪名？组织“水军”从重处罚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/bEFnVbHqKIkc7ECKYwZPIu1A4KbsUEWnZlWHGkCB.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1264&quot; height=&quot;948&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/bEFnVbHqKIkc7ECKYwZPIu1A4KbsUEWn ZlWHGkCB. png&quot; data-key=&quot;252210&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, the &quot;Two High Schools and One Ministry of Education&quot; jointly issued the &quot;About Punishment in accordance with the Law&quot; Guiding Opinions on Internet Violence and Crime&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(People&#39;s Vision/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When cyber violence occurs, victims often feel confused: the subject who commits cyber violence is usually an unspecified person. Moreover, if there are many people and there are many people, will there be a situation where &quot;the law does not punish everyone&quot;? How does the law identify those who play a major role in cyber violence? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 25, 2023, the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate and the Ministry of Public Security jointly issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Punishing Illegal Crimes of Internet Violence in accordance with the Law&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Guiding Opinions&quot;), pointing out that cyber violence For illegal crimes, we must &quot;correct the erroneous tendency of &#39;the law does not punish the public&#39;&quot; and focus on cracking down on malicious initiators, organizers, malicious promoters and those who refuse to change despite repeated admonitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The guidance is clear: when the targets are minors and disabled people; organize &quot;trolls&quot; and &quot;thugs&quot; to implement; fabricate &quot;sexually related&quot; topics; use generative AI technology to publish illegal information; If a network service provider initiates or organizes any of these five situations, cyberviolence perpetrators must be severely punished. According to Yao Jia, a professor at the Institute of Law of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, this represents the attitude towards controlling illegal and criminal acts of online violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Category of cyber violence for the first time&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Cyber ​​violence refers to the behavior of insulting others, spreading rumors and defamation, and invading privacy in cyberspace. It is not a legal concept, so when it comes to online violence, what are the crimes related to it? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This issue is listed in the guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are three categories related to the perpetrators of cyber violence: creating and spreading rumors on the Internet, derogating others&#39; personalities and damaging others&#39; reputations. If the circumstances are serious, they will be convicted of defamation; those who resort to wanton abuse, malicious slander, and disclosure privacy and other methods, openly insulting others, and if the circumstances are serious, they will be convicted of the crime of insult; organizing &quot;human flesh searches&quot; to illegally collect and release citizens&#39; personal information to an unspecified majority of people, and if the circumstances are serious, they will be convicted of the crime of infringing on citizens&#39; personal information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, there are malicious marketing and hype behaviors carried out through cyber violence incidents, which are subject to the crime of illegal use of information networks; network service providers who do not act on the information discovered about cyber violence crimes may be liable to This constitutes the crime of refusing to perform information network security management obligations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yao Jia&#39;s view, this guidance classifies online violence for the first time, &quot;at least it makes it a lot clearer&quot; and also emphasizes which behaviors may constitute crimes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, &quot;After the guidance is issued, cyber violence will certainly not be completely solved.&quot; Yao Jia believes that in practice, cyber violence incidents may involve the intersection of multiple behaviors, and judicial agencies, Law enforcement agencies should strengthen the identification of causal relationships and corresponding damage in cyber violence. In addition, the responsibilities of other social entities also need to be clarified. For example, when cyber violence occurs on campus, the school should also be an important player in participating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the guidance, the boundary between online violence and freedom of speech is also proposed: to report and expose other people’s crimes or violations of laws and disciplines through information networks, as long as they do not intentionally fabricate facts or knowingly If the facts are fabricated and spread intentionally, they should not be considered as defamation. Commenting and criticizing other people&#39;s words and deeds, even if the views are biased or the speech is extreme, as long as it is not wanton abuse or malicious slander, it should not be considered an insult or crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Clear standards for public prosecutions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Criminal Law stipulates that, except for cases that seriously endanger social order and national interests, crimes of insult and defamation are “dealt with upon complaint.” crime. In other words, most of the time, this type of crime requires the victim to collect evidence to file a lawsuit in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, among the 587 criminal defamation cases concluded by courts across the country, 271 cases, accounting for 46%, were not accepted, and only 79 cases were judged, accounting for less than 14%. Among them, only guilty verdicts were 43 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a set of data provided by Zhou Jiahai, deputy director of the Supreme Law Research Office, at a press conference on the afternoon of September 25, 2023. He said that in recent years, there has been a significant increase in the number of criminal cases involving insults and defamation, but the proportion of guilty verdicts is very low. Zhou Jiahai believes that this is due to the difficulty faced by private prosecutors in collecting evidence. On the other hand, it is also related to the lack of detailed guidance and &quot;too high a threshold&quot; for public prosecution standards in criminal cases of insult and defamation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The defamation case of a woman who picked up a courier in Hangzhou in July 2020 is a rare case that has been converted from private prosecution to public prosecution. It was listed as one of the top ten legal supervision cases of the year by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as Zheng Jingjing, the victim’s attorney, saw this guidance, she noticed the clauses detailing the circumstances of “seriously endangering social order” in the crime of insult and defamation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the situations is that &quot;the general public is arbitrarily targeted, and relevant information is widely disseminated on the Internet, triggering a large number of vulgar and malicious comments, seriously damaging the order of the Internet, and having a negative impact on society.&quot;—— This situation is almost completely consistent with the defamation case involving the courier woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the press conference, Li Wenfeng, deputy director of the Legal Policy Research Office of the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, said in response to reporters&#39; questions that the guidance did draw lessons from the Hangzhou woman who was defamed while picking up express delivery when stipulating the prosecution standards for insult and defamation cases. case experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Jingjing recalled that when she represented the case, according to the judicial interpretation on the criminal offense of online defamation issued by the Supreme People&#39;s Court and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate in 2013, more attention was paid to whether the determination of &quot;seriously endangering social order and national interests&quot; It may cause crises in real life, such as mass incidents, public disorder, etc. Finally, the court used the blanket clause of “other situations that seriously endanger social order and national interests” as the legal basis for transferring private prosecution to public prosecution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the release of the guidance, there are more detailed guidelines for the application of public prosecution procedures to crimes of online insult and defamation. In addition to the above-mentioned situation, there are three other specific situations that cause bad social impact: serious consequences such as mental disorder or suicide of the victim or his close relatives; insulting and slandering multiple people or spreading insulting and slanderous information multiple times; organizing and instigating Personnel spread a large amount of insulting and slanderous information on multiple online platforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中秋节临近，广州的这条“灯笼街”充满中国人的节日浪漫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257661]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[北京链家下调中介费率，买卖双方各担1%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257679]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 26, the reporter learned from Lianjia that Beijing Lianjia had recently lowered the agency fee standard and changed the order form The side commission is transformed into a bilateral commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, the Beijing link agency fee standard has been uniformly reduced from 2.7% to 2% of the total housing transaction price. On the other hand, the charging model has been changed from the unilateral payment of the agency fee by the buyer to a joint payment by the buyer and seller, with each buyer and seller bearing 1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, on April 27 this year, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development and the State Administration for Market Regulation jointly issued a document to regulate real estate brokerage services. The document clearly states that real estate brokerage institutions should reasonably reduce the brokerage service fees for housing sales and leasing, and guide both parties to the transaction to share the brokerage service fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, Beijing Lianjia stated that this adjustment to the intermediary fee standards is Lianjia’s response to market changes, responding to ministry documents, proactively adapting to changes, and achieving stable development of the enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia, chief researcher of the Housing Policy Research Center of the Guangdong Provincial Institute of Urban Planning, said that under the guidance of the policy and combined with the current weak market trading sentiment, Beijing Lianjia has adjusted charging methods and standards, actively offered benefits to the market, and reduced Transaction costs boost market sentiment and confidence, which is a reflection of active response to national policy calls. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia believes that Beijing Lianjia’s move will help reduce consumers’ home purchase costs, help expand the market size, better promote a virtuous cycle between new homes and second-hand homes, and promote the healthy and stable development of the real estate market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An intermediary from Beijing Lianjia told the 21st Century Business Herald reporter that on the basis of lowering the agency fee standards and adjusting the charging model, his store currently has additional intermediaries for chain single customers and regular customers. There is a fee discount, that is, serial customers who sell and buy houses on Lianjia can get a 10% discount, and customers who have bought or rented a house on Lianjia in the past year can get a 9.5% discount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Jiang is a serial customer of Lianjia who sells old and buys new ones. She has just paid the down payment and agency fee for her new house. After learning that Lianjia had reduced agency fees, she contacted the house purchase agency on the morning of September 26, hoping to apply for a reduction in the agency fees she had paid. In response, Lianjia Intermediary responded that if the intermediary fee is lowered, it can apply, but it has not yet received a clearer answer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Jiang’s own house is still for sale and has not yet been sold. After Beijing Lianjia implements bilateral commission collection, she will also bear an agency fee of 1% of the total price. In this regard, she told the 21st Century Business Herald reporter that if the seller needs to pay an intermediary fee when selling the house, she will add the intermediary fee to the total house payment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ms. Jiang is not the only landlord who has similar ideas. Li Yujia said that theoretically, owners would have an incentive to pass on agency fees to housing prices, and this has also happened in the past. But whether it can be passed on, or how much it can be passed on, depends on the pricing of housing prices in the micro market. Second-hand housing is a highly decentralized and fully competitive market-oriented transaction. The market information is very transparent, and it is difficult to consider using information gaps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia believes that the current market competition situation is completely different from the past. The number of second-hand house listings in various places has reached a record high. Selling old and buying new, selling small and buying big, and asset transfer are very common. In more cases, owners Reasonable pricing, or even lowering the listing price, in order to sell the house as quickly as possible will make it difficult for the seller to transfer the agency fees to the buyer. If the seller passes the costs onto the house price, it is likely to affect the transaction efficiency of the house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lianjia emphasized that Beijing Lianjia’s adjustment of intermediary rates is an independent adjustment by the company. As for whether other companies will follow suit, it is also the company’s independent market behavior. However, Lianjia is the leading intermediary institution in Beijing, and its adjustments will have a catalytic effect on other institutions and even the entire industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia said that in fact, in most second-hand housing transactions in the world, the intermediary fees are shared by both parties, or the seller pays all costs. With the changes in supply and demand in the real estate market, some property owners in many places across the country have begun to be willing to share agency fees to facilitate transactions. In cities such as Chengdu and Dalian, bilateral charging has been implemented for more than ten years. Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Shanghai, Chongqing and other cities have also implemented bilateral tolling in recent years. It can be seen that this model has become more and more accepted by everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 17:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[徐悲鸿 欲倾东海洗乾坤丨那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访15岁亚运冠军陈烨：“不要放弃，多去尝试”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257675]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/26/n6BzmUN9Dh6lZmOCtTVLbE7rL6I5BEPM9zP1aG3o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/n6BzmUN9Dh6lZmOCtTVLbE7rL6I5 BEPM9zP1aG3o. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252196&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, champion Chinese player Chen Ye (middle) and runner-up Japan Contestant Yuro Nagahara (left) and third runner-up Japanese player Kensuke Sasaoka spin and jump at the award ceremony &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; , take the board, fly... On the afternoon of September 25, 2023, at the Qiantang Roller Skating Center, after performing a series of wonderful skateboarding moves, the 15-year-old Guangdong teenager Chen Ye won the championship in the Hangzhou Asian Games Men&#39;s Skateboard Bowl Final. This is the first gold medal won by the Chinese team in the skateboarding world competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Ye is a high-profile rising star in skateboarding. He was born in 2008 and has been making a mark in national competitions since he was 12 years old. In the 2020 National Skateboarding Championships and the men&#39;s bowl pool event of the 2021 National Games, Chen Ye won second place; in the selection of the 2022 Hangzhou Asian Games Skateboarding National Training Team, Chen Ye was selected with first place . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the preliminaries on September 24, Chen Ye&#39;s competition state was to seek breakthroughs in stability, and advanced to the finals with fourth place in the preliminaries. After the game, Chen Ye said that he would give it all in the finals and perform the most difficult moves, &quot;try to get into the top four, or even the top three.&quot; Facing a field filled with experts, Chen Ye competed with a learning mentality. Didn&#39;t put too much pressure on myself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/JUNbfTebCRVb3G62S8AhCzeh1tcePOy7GmsOmyev.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/JUNbfTebCRVb3G62S8AhCzeh1tcePOy7GmsOmyev.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252192&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, Chen Ye in the finals&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the finals, Chen Ye continued to perform at a high level, breaking through the preliminaries in the first round, scoring 82.82 points, ranking first; in the second round, he set a new high score again, scoring 84.41 points, maintaining his advantage; In the last round, Chen Ye scored 80.62 points. Although it was not as good as the 84.00 points of Japanese player Yuro Nagahara in this round, he won the gold medal with the highest score of 84.41 points in the three rounds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the media interviews and press conferences after the game, Chen Ye repeatedly thanked one person, his father Chen Wanqin. On the road to the championship, his father always supported him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/rMtC7bLDYbb9LaCpTUv2iNfzZVqJ5DW4qOVv7X3W.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/rMtC7bLDYbb9LaCpTUv2iNfzZVqJ5DW4qOVv7X3W.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252197&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Ye (right) and his father Chen Wanqin&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Father and son&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Learning that he won the championship After the news, Chen Ye excitedly put on the national flag, slid around the bowl with a bright smile, and waved to the audience. &quot;I didn&#39;t really think about anything at the time. I was just very happy and very excited.&quot; At the post-match press conference, Chen Ye sat upright in front of the stage and answered reporters&#39; questions unhurriedly with a slightly hoarse voice during the voice change period, acting like a Shy boy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Ye emphatically thanked his father, &quot;He built two venues for me, thank him.&quot; Chen Ye only entered the national training team two months ago. Before that, he was his father. Chen Wanqin was guiding him. Skateboarding was only introduced to China at the end of the 20th century, and it was also relatively late to be listed as an Olympic sport. In 2016, the International Olympic Organizing Committee announced that skateboarding would be officially included in the 2020 Tokyo Olympics. Therefore, when Chen Ye first came into contact with skateboarding, there were almost no professional players and professional coaches in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Ye fell in love with skateboarding by chance. On New Year&#39;s Day in 2016, Chen Wanqin took Chen Ye to the sports mall. Chen Ye tried out the skateboard and liked it very much. Chen Wanqin said, &quot;I will take you to play when you want to play.&quot; A month later, Chen Ye He went to play every day, and Chen Wanqin bought him a skateboard. When Chen Ye persisted in playing for half a year, Chen Wanqin made up his mind to make skateboarding Chen Ye&#39;s longer-term hobby. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with street skateboarding, Chen Ye prefers skating in bowls and pools. “It can fly higher and go faster.” When he first started practicing, Chen Wanqin took Chen Ye on the Internet Find videos of skaters on the internet and practice whatever moves you’re interested in. Chen Wanqin&#39;s experience in learning dance allowed him to break down complex movements one by one and arrange Chen Ye&#39;s training in an orderly manner. They practiced at a public skatepark in Zhongshan City. At that time, there were very few people skateboarding. Most of the time, only the father and son were practicing. In order to communicate with more skateboarders, they would go to Hong Kong and Tokyo during holidays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2016, the International Olympic Committee voted to include skateboarding as an official event in the Tokyo Olympics. The mentality of father and son has quietly changed, from &quot;becoming a skateboard master&quot; to a more professional direction. It was also at this time that national skateboarding competitions began in China, and skateboarding was also included in the 2017 National Games. The first competition Chen Ye participated in was the 2018 &quot;U Series China Youth Skateboarding Tour&quot; and he won third place. They found that &quot;it turns out that if you practice like this, your skills are pretty good.&quot; Does that mean that as long as you work harder, you can achieve better results? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no professional bowl pool in Zhongshan City. The nearest bowl pool is in Guangzhou, which takes two hours from Zhongshan. In 2019, in order for Chen Ye to have a professional training venue near his home, Chen Wanqin made a bold decision to build his own bowl pool. Later in his self-report, Chen Wanqin said that he was afraid of failure before building the project. &quot;I was afraid that I would invest all the money and not be able to make it.&quot; He simulated it with 3D printing and then felt confident. &quot;At that time, I thought, just be I work for my dreams. If I fail, I will fail. Anyway, I don’t have much money saved.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Wanqin rented a warehouse of more than 200 square meters and about 4 meters high, and learned to saw wood. Start by building the structure of the bowl piece by piece. Half a year later, Wanchi was actually made. And Chen Ye lived up to his father&#39;s efforts, honing his movements and techniques to become increasingly sophisticated, and achieving a major breakthrough in Chinese skateboarding at the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2023, Chen Wanqin built a larger and more comprehensive skatepark. While accompanying Chen Ye in training, he accumulated experience and became a professional skateboard coach to guide more skateboarders. Kids enjoy skateboarding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And Chen Ye will continue to challenge a broader arena. After winning the Asian Games, Chen Ye admitted that he had no hope of participating in the Paris Olympics because &quot;the current speed and height are still not enough&quot;, but he will try to &quot;fly higher and accelerate faster&quot; during training and go to more places. The venue is slippery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/cYC3ATrbphgccA0H997dau8HWkQcpgJ1fdk6TcEo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1205&quot; height= &quot;855&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/cYC3ATrbphgccA0H997dau8HWkQcpgJ1fdk6TcEo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252193&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Ye is studying&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Conversation with Chen Ye&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said at the press conference, “When training, you should try to fly higher, accelerate faster, and overcome psychological obstacles. .&quot; So do you still feel scared when you skate? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, if the speed (skating) is fast or very high, it is actually quite scary. When accelerating air (flying into the air), the faster the flying speed, the easier it is to shake and it is difficult to control. Should you jump in or out? It is also possible to jump very far and fall on the flat ground, which is a bit scary. It is necessary to accurately control the take-off position and landing position. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then how do you overcome your fear? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;If you are afraid, start with the short one first and increase the height little by little. There is no need to exaggerate all at once. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you flew up, it was because you had no control Good wrestling? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, especially when I am in a hurry, I think I will fly higher immediately. If I cannot control it well at this time, it is possible It dropped so low that it hit my knees and feet. Wrestling is very common. When you first start practicing each action, you must &quot;practice&quot; wrestling first. This will be safer, otherwise you may be seriously injured if you fall. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You initially followed the video training on the Internet , but complex movements still require on-site observation and learning. What movements did you go to Tokyo to learn? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At first, my father and I watched some simple teaching videos, broke down slow motion, and tried to practice. I went to Tokyo to learn air, because at that time there were no professional bowl pools in China, and U-shaped pools were hard to come by. There was a 4-meter U-shaped pool in Tokyo, and there were many skateboarders, and you could watch their demonstrations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/GHb00IUOhv75Pq0ynXy0pNvlyZJ9mQdU2j8gGtwx.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 980&quot; height=&quot;1709&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/GHb00IUOhv75Pq0ynXy0pNvlyZJ9mQdU2j8gGtwx.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252194&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chen Ye in daily training&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How long did it take you to practice to learn air? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the beginning, you grab the board to jump, and then you click on the board to jump. The most standard thing is to grab the board when you hit the pole. About half a year. There will definitely be boredom. It was okay when I was in Tokyo, there were more skaters practicing together, but there aren’t that many skaters back home. When the moves get boring, just change to another move. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You started skateboarding in 2016. When did you decide? Become a professional skateboarder? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It should be before the National Games. In 2019, in order to prepare for the National Games, my father built a bowl pond for me. The two of us decided to build it together. Because I participated in several competitions at that time and watched the performance of foreign players, I felt that if you want better results, you still need to have a professional venue. After building a professional venue, I felt that I should practice skateboarding seriously and professionally. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your father said before that he took it out All your savings were used to build the bowl pool. Did you make a lot of determination at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No. Anyway, my father still wanted to support me and saw that I had achieved some results, but he did not say that he had particularly high hopes. He mainly wanted me to continue to stick to this hobby and interest. He wouldn&#39;t put too much pressure on me, just let me perform well during the competition, and he didn&#39;t say I must win any awards. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I asked about the training team training and father&#39;s training in the afternoon When talking about the difference, you said the styles are different. What is your father&#39;s training style? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/BDZbqtLsPaCBxBWo2uBBiwtrmRmTpoMkAiHiSPSE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/BDZbqtLsPaCBxBWo2uBBiwtrmRmTpoMkAiHiSPSE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252198&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Interior view of the bowl pool built by Chen Wanqin&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It’s casual, but a bit difficult. I practiced all the basic movements first, and then I could try more new ones. The training is to prepare for the Asian Games and show off my moves. My father knows me better than my coach. He has trained with me since I was a child, and he understands my psychology, movements, and problems better. The coach is a legendary American skateboarder and has more competition experience. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You actually did it in this competition Many attempts will lead to more difficult moves in the second round. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, especially in today’s finals, I have performed steadily in the first round, and I have to fight hard in the second round. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/sQlPLNkqqBKVn3cpqELajezDAZ1uIrbsocvmWHsa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 960&quot; height=&quot;669&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/26/sQlPLNkqqBKVn3cpqELajezDAZ1uIrbsocvmWHsa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252195&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 25, 2023, in the men&#39;s skateboard bowl final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, Chinese player Chen Ye won the championship with a score of 84.41 points&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;From 2016 to 2023, you have witnessed the development of skateboarding in China after it was admitted to the Olympics. Have you personally felt that more and more people are participating in this project? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Definitely. Now more ordinary people are participating, and there are more new star players. I feel that the development of Chinese skateboarding is getting better and better, and I also hope to do my part to promote the development of Chinese skateboarding. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you want to give some encouragement to other skateboarders , what would you say? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Ye: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Come on, don’t give up, try more. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 26 Sep 2023 16:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>