<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[警方通报男子当街性侵醉酒女子：网传信息不属实]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258863]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 14:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/19/lREj0mw3STng0v2EnzvQY0D3hMsQdkBAAiocNZ9O.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2008&quot; height=&quot;4631&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/lREj0mw3STng0v2EnzvQY0D3hMsQd kBAAiocNZ9O. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254586&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[老年相亲的奇观，“等你老了就明白了”｜记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258792]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73058&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;69896&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/c79f0bdf96.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;a0567795b9e103e6d94ea8797e82c17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;September 2023, Shanghai, IKEA restaurant Elderly people inside. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/18/c79f0bdf96.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254344&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 2023, Shanghai, Seniors in the IKEA restaurant. (Southern Weekend reporter Zheng Dan/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; &quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/258371&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;>;In Shanghai’s senior dating site, regulars don’t talk about love&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/a>; p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before I walked into the IKEA restaurant for the first time, I ordered a cup of coffee. Take a deep breath, try to reverse your tired state, and cheer up to deal with a new group - a group of old single Shanghainese, who will definitely be bored. But to my surprise, they were much more interesting than I imagined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First, a man in sunglasses who was over sixty years old came up to me and greeted me. He thought I was looking for company. After all, there are many young women coming to this place.&quot; fishing&quot;. After learning that I was a reporter, he told me mysteriously that he was recently writing an article &quot;The Confusion of Love&quot;. He raised his head and began to sigh, &quot;How much time does a person have to wait for your love? This society is If you don’t have regret medicine, you will be farther and farther away from love when you reach 60 years old.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The man in sunglasses waved his arm and pointed at the dark old age behind him People, the blurry background in my eyes immediately became clear, and the individuals were distinct. &quot;Nowadays, we often don’t talk about the spiritual aspect, but mainly because of the house and the car. Many people have not found a partner, left, and are eclipsed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Indeed, straight to the point is The characteristic here is that everyone talks about their conditions, including financial conditions, physical conditions, physiological needs, etc. After a few sentences, it is clear what the other party is after. 68-year-old Hong Jianming said that everyone knows what level it should go to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Jianming said that the water here is very deep. Men want women to be beautiful, and women want men to be rich. &quot;You see, I am so handsome, but I have not found a partner. Because they know that I can’t support them.” I spent four afternoons in the IKEA restaurant, and most of the people I met described it to me as a dangerous place with all kinds of traps. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are many stories of &quot;liars&quot; circulating here, and the ones most likely to fall for them are Shanghai seniors over eighty years old. &quot;There is a woman in her 30s and 40s who comes here specifically to deceive people in their 70s and 80s. The older the better, the sooner she will die. She just bought several houses like this.&quot; Several women gathered around me and started talking. A common trick used by female swindlers is to make the elderly &quot;take the bait&quot; first with their young and beautiful appearance. Marriage is the most critical step in dividing the property. Frequent sex can accelerate the decline of the elderly, and the steps are steady and ruthless. A woman next to her with heavy black eye shadow interrupted, &quot;Pretty girls are all liars and will kill the old man.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Men seeking mates also believe in this trick. Conspiracy theories, on the one hand, they want to expose their wealth as much as possible to attract the attention of women; on the other hand, they must always be on guard to prevent the bad guys from succeeding. Similarly, there are also &quot;liars&quot; among men who have other agendas. They &quot;fish&quot; by exaggerating their financial resources just to sleep with the women who &quot;take the bait&quot;. From time to time there are men who get into fights in restaurants over a woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nevertheless, they will still dive into the IKEA restaurant without hesitation, because &quot;Vanity Fair&quot; is just the tip of the iceberg here. In the past few years, the staff of the IKEA restaurant tried several times to drive these loud and noisy old people out of the area, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The elderly are too lonely. These people we have now can still walk, but we won&#39;t know in a few years.&quot; Hong Jianming said this As we were talking, a gray-haired old man was passing by in front of us, using a cane to move step by step, &quot;You see, this kind of old man is so weird. What is he doing here? He is just bored. Listen and see.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;IKEA restaurant brings them more than just a place to listen and see. Every Tuesday and Thursday afternoon, someone will organize everyone to have dinner together, especially restaurants that have special offers on Tuesdays. For example, one restaurant will give away a plate of stir-fried beef cubes worth 138 yuan on Tuesday. It is delicately placed on one end of a smooth rectangular plate with more than a dozen beef cubes. For this free signature dish, they have paid Been here dozens of times. There are more people, more food, and it’s cheaper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 19, I came to the IKEA restaurant for the third time. I learned that someone here had organized everyone to travel to other places together, and everyone contributed some money. They are an elderly group, taking care of each other; I also saw them talking about sex and love boldly here, even to the point of making the people discussing it red-faced, but when they went out, no one knew each other. Without that atmosphere, it would be difficult to say some words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After dinner that day, Hong Jianming, who had always been very humorous, suddenly told me in a serious tone that he often came out of the poker hall at around 1 o&#39;clock in the morning, and would Walk around the IKEA restaurant and People&#39;s Park and chat with people. In the bottom of his heart, he actually looked down on the group of old people in front of him who only talked about trivial matters. They were incomparable with his colleagues at his previous job, but there was nothing he could do about it when he was old. When he retired and got sick, he had to retire to the place where old people should go. place, go to the old people to seek a sense of identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What disappoints Hong Jianming the most is that his son dislikes him. &quot;He didn&#39;t explicitly say he disliked me, but I am his father. I don&#39;t know he is there yet.&quot; What are you thinking about? Pretending to be useless.&quot; Every time his son came home to visit him with something, the two of them would repeat a scene: the son would look at his watch from time to time and quickly find an excuse to leave, &quot;I said you can leave, and he would immediately gone&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Hong Jianming can see his son&#39;s dislike in all aspects. His son would never take the initiative to call and ask; his calls to his son were rarely answered, and his son would suddenly call him after a long time and ask him, &quot;What&#39;s the matter, Dad? I was busy in front of me and didn&#39;t hear you.&quot; It was always the same. so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are too many examples like this in IKEA restaurants. I learned from several people one after another that they had children and finally arrived. In his twilight years, he still has to live alone, with the house and pension in his hands being his last source of confidence. The IKEA restaurant is just a microcosm of the elderly group. You can imagine the phenomenon outside this place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 21, I went to the IKEA restaurant for the last time. Until 9:30 in the evening, there were still four old people staying in the restaurant chatting. They said they couldn&#39;t sleep even after returning and it was good to chat. They said that I was still young and did not understand how powerless it felt to push time towards the end. I have heard this sentence several times: &quot;You will understand when you are old.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;I really can’t empathize with it, I just think the topic is heavy. On the other hand, although in their mouths, 80-year-old Song Xiaofei is a confused person who gave 8,000 yuan of his pension to a 40-year-old out-of-town woman just to let her accompany him; 78-year-old Lao Zhang is also a confused person. Man, spending 300 yuan a day on a young woman to keep you company is a waste of money. But in my opinion, maybe it is rare to be sober. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After all, when people reach their twilight years, there is not much time left. &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[视频教你坐地铁：面向全国数亿人的“社会生存学”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258812]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Uncle Chen has been working in Guangdong for more than ten years and almost never takes the subway. If the new construction site hadn&#39;t happened to be near a subway station, Uncle Chen wouldn&#39;t have walked in, even though it was Tiyu West Road, the largest subway station in Asia that handles nearly a million passengers every day. Because he still hasn&#39;t understood the rules of taking the subway. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally arrived at the platform of Tiyu West Road Station. Uncle Chen was carrying a bag of quilts in one hand and a bucket in the other hand, which contained towels, shower gel and other daily necessities, and asked the strangers around him for directions. ——He was going to take the subway to work near Shipaiqiao subway station, which was just one stop away. Uncle Chen is from Hubei. He and his wife rent in Fushan Village, Huangpu District, more than 30 kilometers away from the center of Guangzhou. He usually works as a temporary worker at construction sites in Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Zhuhai and other places. The nearest subway station is 3 kilometers away from his residence. When he goes to work, he usually takes a bus or a taxi, even though the former is a long journey and the latter is expensive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“You can’t ride the subway for long, and it’s very troublesome to go around in circles.” Uncle Chen said. His two daughters worked outside the home, and no one taught him how to confirm the route, transfer trains, or find the station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZOmMx5fvos11SE1narzVKAxCdNCwHi2GycsiJY95.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/ZOmMx5fvos11SE1narzVKAxCdNCwHi2GycsiJY95.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254371&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In June 2023, at Xiuyi Station of Suzhou Rail Transit Line 11, citizens were checking the subway line map and buying tickets by themselves. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Heng, who is studying urban rail operation management at an engineering college in Hunan, is about to graduate. Just took the subway for the first time. In the first month of college, the teacher asked in class if any students had never taken the subway. There were 42 people in the class, and one-third of them raised their hands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Out of surprise, the teacher asked a girl who had ridden the subway to share her feelings. The girl said that the subway was fast, comfortable and convenient. &quot;I was very envious at the time. I had never seen this thing before,&quot; Zhou Heng said. In his hometown and the city where he goes to school, public transportation is not very developed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, teachers still asked the same questions in class from time to time, but almost no one raised their hands anymore. &quot;At that time, I was actually too embarrassed to admit it,&quot; Zhou Heng said, &quot;After all, I learned this by myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time Zhou Heng walked into a subway station was when he traveled to Nanchang with his classmates in his sophomore year. He found that the subway was a little different from what he imagined. It was not as quiet and comfortable as the girl described. It was very crowded during peak hours, the carriages vibrated obviously, and it was very noisy while driving. But he was still very interested and curiously paid attention to the layout of the station and the location of the escape routes. After arriving at the station, they remembered the subway driving process they had just learned in class, and stayed on the platform for a while, waiting to see the driver come out of the cockpit after the door closed, get out of the car, check, and then return to the car. They also took photos. Send the video to the teacher. &quot;The teacher praised us for being studious,&quot; Zhou Heng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;You are 20 years old and have never taken the subway. Are you a failure?&quot; This is one of the most popular comments on David&#39;s video. He made a short video of the process of taking the subway and taught others how to transfer and find the station on social media. There are many &quot;traffic bloggers&quot; similar to him. Search for &quot;subway riding tutorial&quot; and the city name on the short video platform to find subway teaching videos in various cities. If you still don&#39;t understand, you can ask questions in the comment area. , and received precise answers from bloggers and enthusiastic netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Type &quot;how many people in China have never taken the subway&quot; in the search engine, and the answer is &quot;900 million&quot; (Editor&#39;s note: As of September 2023, the 2022 permanent population of all cities in mainland China with subway access The total is 499 million). What does a subway mean to the silent majority? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Those who have never ridden the subway know nothing”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For many people who have never ridden the subway, the first thing to break through is the psychological barrier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ronaldiner works in Chengdu, and his parents have been working in Aba Prefecture, Sichuan for a long time. During the Chinese New Year in 2023, Ronaldinho asked her mother to accompany her from Chengdu to Chongqing. When she proposed to take the subway to the high-speed rail station, her mother refused and asked for a taxi. Ronaldinho didn&#39;t understand that taking a taxi was expensive and crowded, so he argued with his mother. In the end, her mother was a little embarrassed and said that she had never taken the subway and didn&#39;t know how to take it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ronaldiner said simply: &quot;Then I will teach you.&quot; The mother was stunned for a moment, as if she was surprised that her daughter did not laugh at her. The dispute ended with Ronaldinho convincing his mother to accept the instruction. The two rehearsed the entire process at the entrance. The mother asked many questions: how to apply for the bus code and how to use it; water bottles, sunscreen spray, fruit knife, red wine Can I bring a bottle opener? The two of them squatted on the ground and took out the items in the suitcase one by one and counted them. &quot;I was shocked at the time. My mother really didn&#39;t understand this aspect at all. I felt like I didn&#39;t even understand her life.&quot; Ronaldinho said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After getting on the subway, my mother became taciturn. When Ronaldinho explained the details of the ride to her, he just responded with a &quot;hmm&quot;. &quot;She would have a lot of questions before getting on the bus, but when she got inside, although she wanted to ask, she was too embarrassed to ask, so she didn&#39;t speak.&quot; She silently sent a text to Ronaldinho on WeChat, asking when and when she got off the bus. How to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After scanning the QR code and exiting the station, my mother opened Alipay and found that only a few yuan had been deducted. She was surprised and said that taking the subway was so much cheaper than taking a taxi. &quot;I won&#39;t take a taxi anymore. I&#39;ll take the subway from now on,&quot; my mother said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/PwLFZSK0QQPfaNPb6iyu10WhveY0jy4sUqGYM6xm.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/PwLFZSK0QQPfaNPb6iyu10WhveY0jy4sUqGYM6xm.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The earliest subway in the world was the London Metropolitan Subway in 1863, which has a history of 160 years ago. The picture shows the first phase of Lanzhou Rail Transit Line 2 in trial operation in June 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;They don&#39;t know how to look up the map.&quot; He Jingtao said. He works at a travel agency in Guangzhou. In the two months since he created city subway guides on social media, He Jingtao has become half a &quot;traffic help blogger.&quot; He estimated that in the past two months, he had replied to more than 700 people in the comment area alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of the people who come to him for help come from other places to study or travel in Guangzhou. They don’t know that they can check the subway lines on the map because they don’t need to use mobile phone navigation in the local area. Therefore, the question he is asked the most is how to take the subway from the train station to a certain place or business district, or from one district to another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaojun is one of them. When asking He Jingtao for help, she only sent him the name of the school, but she was confused about how to take the subway from the train station to the school: She was from Huizhou, Guangdong, and was about to go to Guangzhou to study at university, but she had no idea where to go or how to get there. go. She told He Jingtao: &quot;The school admission brochure only said that you can take Line 6 to the Botanical Garden Station, and it didn&#39;t mention the distance before that at all. I took the train to Guangzhou Railway Station, and there will be no more.&quot; Next, Xiaojun asked How to get from the train station to the subway station, how to buy subway tickets, how to take the bus, etc. During the summer vacation, He Jingtao received a lot of similar requests for help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many tourists traveling to Guangzhou face the problem that the place name of the destination is different from the name of the subway station. If they don’t know how to read navigation and don’t ask others for help online, they won’t know that to go to the famous scenic spot Shangxiajiu, they need to take Guangzhou Metro Line 6 and get off at the “Cultural Park” station; if they want to go to Beijing Road Pedestrian Street , you need to get off at &quot;Park Qian&quot; station. Aware of this, when He Jingtao was doing the &quot;subway tutorial&quot;, he mapped the common attractions he had compiled to each line, station and exit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ticket buying process is also a challenge. Xiao Wu, a self-media blogger, is from Baotou, Inner Mongolia. Only one city in Inner Mongolia, Hohhot, has access to subway. Once when he was on a business trip to Hohhot and taking the subway, he met a mother with her child who didn&#39;t know how to operate a ticket vending machine. There was a long queue behind her. She was also very anxious. &quot;The more anxious she was, the more mistakes she made.&quot; Xiao Wu bought the ticket for her. This little incident became the inspiration for choosing the topic. Xiao Wu made a similar short video &quot;Tutorial on taking the subway&quot;, using a first-person perspective with narration to show the whole process of taking the subway. The video wasn&#39;t complicated to create, but it gained unexpected attention, with many people saying it was &quot;very helpful.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Wu remembers that the first time he took the subway was when he was traveling to Beijing after graduating from high school and took the Beijing Subway Line 1. When he walked into the subway station, he was at a loss. He didn&#39;t know where to buy a ticket. There were many people in the station. He was embarrassed to stand by and learn how others operated, and he was embarrassed to ask passers-by who were in a hurry. Although I had made a guide online in advance, when I came to the subway station alone, I was still &quot;afraid of making mistakes and showing my cowardice&quot;, so I finally asked the staff for help. He realized that many people were going through similar situations and &quot;found there was a huge demand for this.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/yE7gJXewJ6pBDtDtFVhPCSJhntOn8EWVnmtyrhy3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/yE7gJXewJ6pBDtDtFVhPCSJhntOn8EWVnmtyrhy3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254372&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;According to the official account of the Ministry of Transport, in September 2023, a total of 55 cities in mainland China had 299 urban rail transit lines in operation, completing a passenger volume of 2.49 billion. The picture shows passengers waiting for subway trains at Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport in July 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;David also mentioned the issue of buying tickets. Among the requests for help he received, many people were wondering why the subway did not buy tickets first and then get on the bus like buses, high-speed rails, and airplanes. So when should the money be paid? Someone once asked him in a private message, &quot;If I need to transfer and buy a ticket at a self-service machine, can I buy the ticket directly to the terminal?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the biggest difficulties for help seekers? David thought about it for a long time, and his answer was &quot;They can&#39;t think of these problems.&quot; He also felt confused: he occasionally had trouble with troublesome questions such as directions, transfers, and finding the station, but he was rarely asked about it. Most people often just reported two place names and then asked how to get there. Many people also asked in the comment area: &quot;What software did you use for the route map?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Anyone who watches the video and asks questions really has friends from dozens of cities outside the subway. They. Those who have never sat in it just don’t know anything.&quot; David said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Improving social exclusion in transportation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On social media, there are many bloggers like David and Xiao Wu who create life tutorial content and use short videos to teach people How to go to the cinema to watch a movie, stay in a hotel, send express delivery, etc. They are called &quot;social survival&quot; bloggers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the feedback they received, the most frequently mentioned word was &quot;social fear.&quot; Xiao Wu once received a private message from a girl, saying that she went to school alone in the city and her parents were working in other places. She felt a little anxious and depressed, and wanted to go to the hospital, but she had never been to a hospital alone, didn&#39;t know the process, and didn&#39;t dare to tell others, so she had to ask Xiao Wu for help. Later, Xiao Wu shot a video specifically for this purpose, &quot;How to See a Doctor in the Hospital for the First Time.&quot; Another girl said she suffered from severe depression and that her memory began to blur due to electroconvulsive therapy. Because she was afraid of being embarrassed in public, she began to be afraid to go out and stayed at home for two months. After watching Xiao Wu&#39;s video, she said: &quot;I think you not only warmed me, but also many friends who came out of the countryside for the first time and didn&#39;t know the various procedures.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let Xiao Wu The feedback that impressed me the most was &quot;Do you need to teach me about this?&quot; He was once troubled by this. After the video was posted, many people questioned him and said he was &quot;simplifying traffic&quot;: &quot;Why don&#39;t you teach me how to eat for the first time and how to eat for the first time?&quot; One drink of water?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Everyone thinks that young people should know a lot, but they don&#39;t know everything. Today&#39;s lifestyle is too complicated.&quot; Xiaojiang said. Her content is positioned as &quot;Guidelines for College Students&quot;, teaching newly independent college students various social survival skills. The most popular ones are tutorial videos on taking the subway, high-speed rail, and airplanes, which have hundreds of thousands of likes. Before going to college, Xiaojiang had never used taxi-hailing apps. Her parents would help her call a taxi. Her parents often asked her to go out to buy meat, but she couldn&#39;t tell the difference between various types of meat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Most college entrance examination candidates can only worry about studying.” David once received a private message from a mother saying that her child would fly from Tianjin to Chongqing to take the art exam and asked if he could help. Arranging transportation, because the situation was complicated, David added her WeChat for step-by-step guidance. The other party asked a lot of questions, ranging from whether I could catch up with the exam in the afternoon after landing in the morning, how much transportation time I had to reserve to rush to another city after the exam, and whether I could take paints and drawing boards with me on the plane or subway. She also asked a friend in Chongqing to take care of the entire transportation of her child. &quot;She arranged the whole process. Faced with such a complicated matter, I think this mother is quite methodical.&quot; David said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;She was very happy after she actually entered the pits, and I was also very happy.&quot; Ronaldinho said. Ronaldinho&#39;s mother likes to hear the &quot;beep&quot; sound when swiping the subway code when entering and exiting the station. She was very interested in everything in the subway. After leaving the station, her mother wanted to eat the grilled fish advertised on the subway. When she took the subway again in Chongqing, she was curious why the advertisement in the carriage changed to milk tea. As soon as she got out of the station, she wanted to eat. Ask Ronaldinho to take her to drink the milk tea in the subway advertisement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The whole trip turned into a subway trip. Once, because Ronaldinho had an appointment with a friend and needed to get off the subway in advance, he asked his mother, &quot;Can you take the subway back alone?&quot; Her mother calmly said no, &quot;no problem.&quot; During that journey, her mother took pictures of her every once in a while: &quot;Look, I still remember it.&quot; Later, Ronaldinho asked her if she got home smoothly. Her mother said that she had arrived home, and when she left the station, &quot;I really couldn&#39;t find it.&quot; She asked She asked the subway staff, who enthusiastically pointed her to the exit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Completing the task of leaving the station alone gave her mother a great confidence. She said: &quot;It turns out that taking the subway is so easy.&quot; After returning home, she showed off to her father that she took the subway today and wanted to go there in the future. When going shopping on Chunxi Road in Chengdu, her father does not need to drive her. She can take the subway by herself. Dad said, let Ronaldinho teach him too. After learning how to ride the subway, her mother recorded all the procedures that Ronaldinho taught her on her mobile phone, and even took her colleagues with her when she went shopping. Her colleagues praised her, &quot;We can&#39;t even play with these things, but you can play so smoothly.&quot; My mother was very impressed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When returning from the trip, her mother asked Ronaldinho to teach her how to use 12306 to buy high-speed rail tickets. Ronaldinho sent her a high-speed rail instruction video. Later, my mother bought a high-speed rail ticket and went to Xi&#39;an to visit her old classmates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a tourism practitioner, He Jingtao can understand the importance of transportation issues. &quot;Tourism consists of five aspects: food, accommodation, travel, shopping, and entertainment, and transportation is one of them.&quot; But he admitted that he was surprised after his first subway riding tutorial became popular. “I didn’t know so many people needed it before I made it.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Professor Wang Shijun of Tongji University pointed out that in the context of rapid urbanization, some groups in urban transportation should receive more attention, that is, those with poor mobility in space and the inability to travel freely and conveniently. Destination groups, such as low-income groups, urban migrants, disabled people, elderly people who cannot use smartphones, etc. The lack of mobility in urban transportation not only leads to social differentiation and the formation of marginalized circles, but also affects all levels of social participation such as employment, schooling, and health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the possible consequences of this unfair situation is the social exclusion of transport disadvantaged groups. Professor Wang Shijun believes that the main factor leading to social exclusion in my country&#39;s urban transportation is that the current urban transportation is still in the stage of pursuing efficiency and maximizing traffic capacity, and less consideration is given to social equity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1965, China&#39;s first underground railway, Beijing Subway Line 1, started construction. It took more than ten years from preparation to opening. In the 20th century, only four cities in mainland China, Beijing, Tianjin, Shanghai and Guangzhou, had urban rail transit lines. Entering the 21st century, opening up to the outside world and economic development have driven a boom in subway construction, because building subways can promote the flow of population resources and optimize land allocation. There is a popular slogan among the people: &quot;When the subway rings, there is a thousand taels of gold.&quot; From 2010 to 2020, China&#39;s urban rail transit construction has been booming for ten years. During these ten years, 29 cities across the country have opened subways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, the subway has become an indispensable part of the daily life of many urban residents in China. Rail transit operation data for September 2023 released by the Ministry of Transport shows that 55 cities in mainland China have opened urban rail transit lines, and the subway mileage ranks first in the world. The total passenger volume in 2022 will be approximately 22.42 billion. In the new round of subway construction applications that will be launched in July 2023, more than 30 cities may apply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Shijun believes that various official and private tutorials equipped with new media media are social innovation measures and are conducive to improving social exclusion in transportation, because an important aspect of transportation exclusion is the inability to obtain high-quality Transportation and travel information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this stage, the guidance services provided by the subway mainly rely on platform services and volunteers. Professor Huang Xiaoyan from the Northwest Land and Resources Research Center of Shaanxi Normal University also pointed out that the form of content, the platform on which it is released, and the target group are all important. Many transportation disadvantaged groups are limited by their own human capital and do not have access to this information. &quot;Now it may be necessary to consider both macro and meso levels, as well as from the perspective of inclusiveness, fairness, and refined governance, in order to do this matter better.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhou Heng recently I passed the campus recruitment interview and am preparing to do an internship in the subway system at the end of the year. He felt that it was a pity that the professional internship that was supposed to be completed in his freshman and sophomore years was delayed by the epidemic and did not start until close to graduation. Therefore, he did not know much about his future job. He only roughly knew that he needed to maintain platform order, pick up and depart trains, and serve passengers. . If he passes the internship assessment, he will become an official subway station attendant. He found that many people &quot;didn&#39;t seem to understand and didn&#39;t ask&quot; at the subway station. &quot;When you go in (you should) look for the staff first. This is their job.&quot; Zhou Heng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Uncle Chen, Zhou Heng, David, Xiao Luo, Xiao Wu, Xiao Jiang and Xiao Jun are pseudonyms)&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[什么是中国足球该有的样子？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258730]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 12:25:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;In March 2015, the &quot;Overall Plan for the Reform and Development of Chinese Football&quot; was promulgated. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;For more than eight years, Chinese football has continued to move in the direction guided by the football reform plan and achieved certain results, but there are also problems such as poor implementation and deviations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The former senior executives of the Chinese Football Association, many former middle-level officials and football practitioners were suspected of corruption, which caused setbacks in the reform and development of Chinese football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the 16th, the 12th Member Congress of the Chinese Football Association was held. Chinese football should take this opportunity to reinvigorate its spirit, reflect on itself, sort out the past, and illuminate the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6190e8eea893942bda1db0d9faaf0054.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/6190e8eea893942bda1db0d9faaf0054.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254224&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 16, Song Kai (first from left) spoke at the conference. On the same day, the 12th Member Congress of the Chinese Football Association was held in Beijing. The meeting elected a new executive committee, chairman and vice-chairman. Song Kai was elected as the new Chairman of the Chinese Football Association, and Sun Wen, Yuan Yongqing, Yang Xu, and Xu Jiren were elected as the Vice Chairman of the Chinese Football Association. Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Jia Haocheng&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency reporters recently interviewed dozens of football practitioners and experts. They pointed out the current problems of Chinese football and gave insights. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Football reform shows results&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The Football Association &quot;decouples&quot; and takes the first step towards the association&#39;s physicalization One step&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, the &quot;Football Sports Management Center&quot; was cancelled, and the Chinese Football Association and the State Sports General Administration were &quot;decoupled&quot; and became a corporate legal person. &quot;Two brands, one team &quot;The organizational structure became history. After the &quot;decoupling&quot;, the Chinese Football Association has autonomy in industry planning, institutional setup, personnel recruitment, foreign affairs visits, finance and market development. This also provides reference for the materialization of other sports associations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The China Youth Championship has been successfully held for two years&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Youth Championship hosted by the Ministry of Education, the State Sports General Administration and the Chinese Football Association The Youth Football League has been running for two years. Teams from schools, sports schools, club youth training echelons, and social youth training institutions can participate. This event is an important achievement of the integration of sports and education. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The Chinese women’s football team won the Asian Cup again after 16 years&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, the Chinese women’s football team won the Asian Cup for the ninth time Won the Asian Cup championship and stood on the top of Asia again after 16 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, at the 2023 Women&#39;s World Cup, the performance of the Chinese women&#39;s football team highlighted the gap between them and the world&#39;s women&#39;s football team, and there is still a gap between them and the goal of &quot;women&#39;s football returning to the world&#39;s top teams&quot; in the football reform plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Chinese team won the 2023 East Asian Football Confederation U15 Men’s Football Championship, becoming a highlight of Chinese youth football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Rural football blooms with vitality&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rural football represented by Guizhou’s “Village Super League” blooms with vitality and opens up to the outside world It conveys a spiritually rich and happy emotion, and is a &quot;window to observe Chinese modernization&quot;. It is a new story of China&#39;s rural areas in the new era while promoting national fitness, realizing a comprehensive moderately prosperous society, implementing rural revitalization, and starting a new journey of Chinese modernization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, although my country&#39;s county football has encountered difficulties such as lack of funds, lack of venues, and lack of talent, it has generally shown a positive development trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/22b9d172e4d70b9b4f047171f6a5d378.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;809&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/22b9d172e4d70b9b4f047171f6a5d378.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254225&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;This is the scene of the &quot;Village Super League&quot; finals taken at night on July 29 (drone photo). Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ou Dongqu&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Football venues continue to increase&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;National sports venues in 2022 Statistical survey data shows that there are 135,900 football fields across the country, including 31,200 eleven-a-side fields, 43,200 seven-a-side fields, 61,400 five-a-side fields, and 140 beach football fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The goal of &quot;building two new national football training bases&quot; proposed in the football reform plan has been achieved - the China Football (South) Training Base and the China Football (North) Training Base were unveiled in Haikou and Dalian respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Football professional talents continue to grow&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese Football Association became the second professional-level coach in Asia in 2019 National association that certifies qualifications. According to data from the Chinese Football Association, there are currently 3 A-level coaches and lecturers in China, 11 B-level coaches and 37 C-level coaches. There are 80,000 registered coaches across the country, of which about 70,000 are C- and D-level coaches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——The policy system to support the reform and development of football has initially taken shape&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the football reform plan, the &quot;Medium and Long-term Development of Chinese Football Planning (2016-2050)&quot; &quot;National Social Football Field Facilities Construction Special Action Implementation Plan (Trial)&quot; &quot;Opinions on Deepening the Integration of Sports and Education to Promote the Healthy Development of Youth&quot; &quot;China Women&#39;s Football Reform and Development Plan (2022-2035)&quot; With the release of football-related documents and supporting documents from local governments, football development will have an increasingly complete policy support system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;Confusion and problems&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——Low social recognition&lt;/span>;&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;内蒙古足协主席刘俊清说，足改方案落实不彻底，改革发展短板较多，地方行政部门未把足球列为改革专项工作的情况较为普遍。内蒙古对足球教育文化价值的认可度不够高，普遍存在对足球文化发展重视不够、措施不力的状况，行业发展目标与球迷及社会期待不能同频共振，持续深化足球改革受到制约。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此类情形在中国多地同样存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——地方足协建设乏力&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;某省足协官员认为，希望中国足协对地方足协改革有更为有效的支持。目前各级足协头重脚轻，越往下生存空间越小，缺乏造血能力。市县级足协多无实体，只有一块牌子，工作很难开展，甚至无从开展。足球的城市属性很强，部分城市足协强势而省级足协弱势，后者地位尴尬。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘俊清说，部分地方足球管理体制改革步履维艰，一些基层足协和足球组织普遍面临市场开发资源不足、综合协调力度不够、收入来源不稳定、专业人才匮乏等问题；不少基层足协在自身建设、工作运行、保障机制上未形成固定模式，普遍积极性、主动性较差；基层足球发展多为有情怀的足球爱好者发起组织；行政部门支持力度弱；足协作为社会组织，认同度普遍偏低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——职业联赛发展遭遇瓶颈&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;某职业俱乐部投资人说，联赛发展不好，国家队就是无根之水；目前俱乐部普遍缺乏造血能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，不少俱乐部的欠薪和历史债务问题依然严重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;华南师范大学体育科学学院教授李培说，不少足球俱乐部成为公共资源（以土地为主）交换平台。当无法通过俱乐部获得公共资源时，部分母公司果断甩掉这个包袱。这也是近年来数十家足球俱乐部解散或退出的主要原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受“金元足球”影响，加之转会市场长期被几家经纪公司和个人把持，球员价格长期虚高。包括备案在内的足球经纪人各项制度不够完善，一定程度上助长了“虚火”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——青少年足球功利性尚存&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘俊清认为，青少年球员“过早专项化”、训练目标“单维化”、训练和管理模式“成人化”、重比赛忽视技战术等问题依然存在；“锦标主义”在青少年比赛中仍占主导，导致“领导要成绩，组织要人才”的矛盾时有发生；体教融合不充分，校园足球与专业青训体系衔接不畅；多数俱乐部没有完整青训梯队，足球人才培养出现断层；基层足球人才缺口较大。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艾伦足球学院青训主管艾伦·雷纳德谈到三个问题：一是青训俱乐部互相挖人现象泛滥，有的甚至全国掐尖挖人，损害了球员启蒙俱乐部利益。二是各级足协组织的比赛多为赛会制，高质量比赛缺乏。三是适用于社会青训俱乐部的场地少，新建场地手续繁琐，运营费用高。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;某职业俱乐部投资人说，青少年赛历混乱且低级重复，打乱了孩子训练、学习、生活节奏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，青训补偿机制和联合机制补偿执行不力，损害了青训机构利益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李培说，上大学是不少足球青少年的终极目标，他们通过拿等级证书实现该目标，但往往拿到证书就结束足球生涯。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;武汉市万松园路小学体育老师邓世俊说，国家层面的青少年联赛有了，但基层竞赛体系还亟待完善；踢球的孩子文化学习跟不上，读书的孩子没时间踢球，完善人才培养体系刻不容缓；由于缺乏教练培养体系，虽然很多师范类体育院系学生毕业后参与校园足球推广，但不具备足球教练员资质，其知识结构无法满足校园足球开展；由于缺乏固定赛事，裁判员普遍缺少锻炼平台、水平低下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ec24a71b0a92685fcda5da59eaf1f969.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/ec24a71b0a92685fcda5da59eaf1f969.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254227&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;这是2022年7月10日，在第一届中国青少年足球联赛（浙江赛区）男子小学U11组比赛中，杭州濮家小学的小球员杨皓元（右二）与浙江鸵鸟足球俱乐部的小球员赵奕瑞（右一）拼抢球权。新华社记者江汉摄&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——中国男足连续5届无缘世界杯&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，中国男足表现令人失望，连续5届无缘世界杯，其能力作风、成绩状态同人民群众期盼相距甚远。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——腐败现象敲响警钟&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位从业者涉嫌腐败，为中国足球敲响警钟。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北方某市足协负责人认为，中国足球在用人机制、考评机制、监管机制等方面缺失或不完善，造成行业混乱，为腐败提供空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;足球该有的样子&lt;br>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——树立正确足球价值观&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;足球专业人士说，中国社会的总体足球价值观有些滞后，往往只认识到其在国际比赛带来的荣誉价值，对其全面价值缺乏足够认识，对足球运动的长期性、系统性、艰巨性认识不足，从而出现一些短视行为。竞技成绩其实是足球运动发展到一定阶段的客观结果。通过足球的教育功能，可以提升人的全面发展。青少年参与足球不应是为了评定等级、升学加分，而是享受乐趣，达到以快乐教育培养人的目的。有了正确的价值观，才能构建正确的规则体系等各种体系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——中国足协做好体系搭建&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广西足协执委贾蕾仕说，中国足协应明确自己的定位是做好足球服务，做好基础性工作，如完善联赛、青训、教练、裁判等体系。他举例说，虽然现在已有中超、中甲、中乙、中冠等联赛，但省市县联赛体系并不完善，足球强国有多达十几级甚至几十级联赛，构成可持续发展基础；同时中国足协要更接地气，与各级足协建立工作体系，做好业务衔接；足协部门设置要科学化；将权力下放，更好地发挥执委会、会员协会的作用；各级足协事务应透明化、公开化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/7580afae56cc4e3400db8366b860feec.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/7580afae56cc4e3400db8366b860feec.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254226&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;7月7日，天津津门虎队球迷为球队加油。新华社记者孙凡越摄&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于中冠联赛如何与业余联赛衔接，陕西长安联合足球俱乐部董事长黄盛华说，可考虑既相互独立又有序衔接的“双金字塔”体系，即职业联赛和半职业联赛、业余联赛各自构建独立的联赛金字塔体系，两套体系间通过赛事成绩和准入规定衔接。 “双金字塔”体系一方面给了有意向职业足球发展的城市、俱乐部、投资人、球员一个上升通道；另一方面，拥有独立“金字塔”体系的业余联赛通过赛事规则、球队审核等方式，防止过多职业、半职业球员、职业俱乐部关联队伍下沉至业余联赛，防止过多球队为了升到中冠联赛而巨额投入，避免影响普通足球爱好者参与业余联赛的积极性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——完善各级国家队建设&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;专业人士称，应完善队员选拔机制，选拔为国效力愿望强烈、意志品质一流、能力作风好、年龄结构合理的优秀球员进入国家队；建设国家队人才库，强化选拔科学性；统一各级国家队技战术打法；建立训练监控评估体系，实现对各级国家队队员在俱乐部训练、参赛数据的日常监控和评估等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——增加青少年高质量比赛&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邓世俊说，应加强基层如市、区级竞赛体系建设，如武汉市江汉区的“万超联赛”贯穿全学年，成为青少年球员成长平台。通过学区整合，万松园路小学将其场地、师资与学区内其他小学共享。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还建议，探索师范类高校体育院系学生在大学期间获得教练资质（草根、D、C乃至B级）的培养模式，将部分解决校园足球师资问题；大力培养学生裁判。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雷纳德建议各级足协引进第三方赛事运营体系，鼓励地区青少年赛事分级、全年持续举行；对社会力量参与青训给予场地政策、资金支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在青训补偿方面，专业人士建议，条件成熟时可设立第三方账户，制定相关规则，在完成相应的培训补偿和联合机制补偿后才能转会，以此提高青训机构热情。现阶段加强监管，对拖欠青训补偿款项的俱乐部予以处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——完善体教融合机制&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于体教融合，李培建议：一是明确体教部门的责权利。教育部门在义务教育阶段做好青少年足球普及，体育部门负责进一步提高竞技水平。二是建立监督评估机制。教育部门需完善校园足球各项目评价指标体系，加强内部监督评估机制建设，加强对专项经费的审计与绩效评估，根据评估结果配置资源，对评估不合格单位进行督导整改或取消资格。中国足协具有评定裁判、教练和运动员等级权力，既要加强内部监督评估，还要引入第三方监督评估机制。体育部门应建立青少年教练员、裁判员和队员数据库，根据竞赛表现进行监督评估，作为人才选拔和等级晋升依据。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;——反腐应机制化&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于中国足球腐败现象，北京炜衡律师事务所合伙人周明说，中国足协决策机制须更加透明，同时引入外部监督制约机制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;京师律师事务所律师刘正航建议，加强事发前防范机制和事发后迅速整治机制建设。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，提倡各俱乐部建立内部督查体系，从法律层面来讲就是企业合规建设中的反舞弊机制，这里的舞弊主要指假赌事项。体系建设含俱乐部内部举报机制、内部审查机制及查实后的处理汇报机制。同时建议中国足协建立假球监督监察机制，对投诉举报或通过仲裁委员会、纪律委员会听证、处罚等过程中发现的可能涉嫌假赌的事件，进行独立调查与追责，并与上述俱乐部的内部督查体系相衔接，涉嫌违法犯罪的直接移送相关侦查部门进一步处理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还有法律界人士称，中国足协应与公安部建立常态化合作机制。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方某省足协主席说，应坚定不移地进行足球改革，按照足改方案提出的总体方向、要求、路径走，如能扎实推进，各部门做好联动，怎能做不好呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[成都2岁女童遭恶犬咬伤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258847]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 11:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;成都崇州2岁女童遭恶犬袭击，全身多处咬伤，右肾挫裂伤，右侧肋骨骨折。据悉，伤人黑色罗威纳犬已被捕获，属于多座城市禁养犬。犬主人唐某已被崇州警方依法刑事拘留。</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杨紫琼的新身份]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258842]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;10月17日，国际奥委会投票选举产生&lt;/span>;八名新委员。国际乒联主席佩特拉·索林、华裔演员杨紫琼等此前获得提名的八位候选人悉数顺利当选。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9cb2d4f1eedb51fcb2aa3e67f4c9f697.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/9cb2d4f1eedb51fcb2aa3e67f4c9f697.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254505&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;新当选的另外六位委员是韩&lt;/span>;国的金载烈、秘鲁的塞西莉亚·泰特、以色列的雅埃尔·阿拉德、匈牙利的巴拉兹·富尔杰斯、德国的迈克尔·姆隆兹和突尼斯的迈赫雷兹·布塞延。上个月，国际奥委会执委会批准了上述八人被提名为国际奥委会新委员的提议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;17日是国际奥委会第141次全会最后一天，&lt;span>;与会委员们对获得委员提名的八位候选人逐一投票表决，结果全部获得半数以上的赞成票而当选。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1a3076c3b52177888f3200351405bc4b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/1a3076c3b52177888f3200351405bc4b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254503&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;10月17日，新任国际奥委会委员杨紫琼宣誓。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fc33196a527dcbc4b2d4d6bc6fd20aaa.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/fc33196a527dcbc4b2d4d6bc6fd20aaa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254502&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;10月17日，新任国际奥委会委员杨紫琼接受祝贺。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;国际奥委会主席巴赫表示，这些新委员来自不同行业，他们的共同之处是热爱体育，信仰奥林匹克价值观和国际奥委会所代表的理念。得益于他们在各自领域的丰富经验和专业知识，他们的加入将使国际奥委会的工作变得更有价值。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/bcbc0668265c27c0fb2f45b0ffbab296.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/bcbc0668265c27c0fb2f45b0ffbab296.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254504&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;10月17日，国际奥委会主席巴赫在会上发言。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《奥林匹克宪章》规定，国际奥委会委员由自然人组成，总人数不得超过115人，其中来自国际奥委会运动员委员会的代表不超过15人，来自国际单项体育组织的主席或其领导成员代表不超过15人，来自国家（或地区）奥委会的主席或其领导成员代表不超过15人。此外，国际奥委会从它认为合格的人士中挑选委员，作为国际奥委会在其国家（地区）的代表。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;据国际奥委会介绍，索林和金载烈被提名担任委员与他们各自在国际单项体育组织的任职有关，布塞延被提名与他担任突尼斯奥委会&lt;/span>;主席有关，包括杨紫琼在内的其他五人是以独立候选人的身份被提名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前一天，全会还批准了古尼拉·林德伯格等七位任期即将届满的国际奥委会委员连任的提议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次选举后，国际奥委会委员的总数增加&lt;span>;至107人，其中女性委员占比达41.1%。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一商场电梯坠落致3死17伤，涉事品牌频现维保不善记录]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258849]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 11:05:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月18日，云南弥勒，一商场发生电梯坠落事故。（网络视频截图/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8038ac0186.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;811&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/19/8038ac0186.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254584&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月18日，云南弥勒，一商场发生电梯坠落事故。（网络视频截图/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;3人死亡，17人受伤，2023年10月18日12时许，云南省红河州弥勒市最繁华的商贸中心佛城商都，发生了一起电梯坠落的悲剧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;据弥勒市安全生产委员会办公室在事发后发布的通知，坠落的电梯是佛城商都一期的1号电梯。当天18时许，微信公众号“弥勒发布”公布信息，电梯从四楼掉到一楼，有人受伤。目前事件的发生原因正在调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当地一位经常前往佛城商都的居民王宁（化名）告诉南方周末记者，事发之时，佛城商都和周边正值每周三农村的赶集日，人流密集。即便平日，这家总共四层楼的商贸城也有近千户商家，“进进出出每天上万人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;至于坠落的电梯，虽然在严格意义上被划分为货梯，平时却是“人、货、三轮车混装”的。王宁表示，电梯平时就非常拥挤，“过节直接人挤人，安全隐患太大了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;客货混装，老年人常乘坐&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;18日上午11时50分左右，前来弥勒做生意的梁平（化名）正在佛城商都四楼吃饭，突然听见一声巨响，“所有人就围过去了”。他告诉南方周末记者，当时在心里猜测电梯是不是出事了，后来“过去一问，确实是出事了，掉到一楼去了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;大约20分钟后，救护车来到佛城商都。梁平看到两个被抬出来的老年人，“一个少数民族的阿姨，大概也有七十来岁了吧，已经不省人事了，后来又抬出来一个，也穿着少数民族的衣服，戴着帽子一样的头饰。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;梁平说，他自己去过三次佛城商都，据他观察，出事的货梯有十多平米，“电动三轮车都可以开进去”。电梯客货混装，“当地人平时都会坐，因为客梯用不过来”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他介绍，商城的一楼是菜市，卖菜、肉、水果；二楼卖调料、香料、干货；三楼卖衣服；四楼是最高层，又是一个菜市，卖的东西比较杂，“就像农贸市场一样”。多位受访者反映，平时到这里买菜的主要是当地人，其中老年人大多坐电梯上楼。“（老人）上四楼也挺费劲的，一般都是坐电梯，直接爬楼梯的少之又少”，梁平说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;另一位当地人李成（化名）向南方周末记者描述，商场南、北都有可以搭载三轮车的大货梯，出事的电梯位于商城北门。此外，商场里还有两部扶梯。平时除了拉货卖菜的商贩，也有买菜的居民会乘坐货梯，此外货梯内还有专职人员管理楼层按钮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;弥勒吉盛商业管理有限公司官网显示，佛城商都商业综合体的前身，是弥勒老鸿丰农贸市场，综合体在农贸市场的原址上升级改造而成；建筑面积共计6.4万平方米，共有商铺八百多间，固定、零散摊位六百多个。事发地的农贸市场位于佛城商都一期，四层楼层之间由楼梯、电动扶&amp;nbsp;梯相连。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;梁平回忆，电梯出事前，他曾到三楼上厕所，听到楼梯附近传出滴滴的警报声。据他分析，楼梯距离出事的货梯只有几米远，这个警报声“不知道是不是和电梯有联系”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;涉事品牌遭多地行政处罚&lt;/h2>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;李成记得，此前去佛城商都买东西时，隔几天就能看见商场维护电梯。他表示，出于安全考虑，并不会乘坐货梯，只会乘坐扶梯。王宁印象中，这部出事的电梯平时就有一些小问题，有时去卖货，就看见这部电梯没有开放。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;18日21时许，南方周末记者拨打佛城商都监控室工作人员的联系电话，对方确认，市场中的电梯厂商为上海爱登堡电梯集团股份有限公司（以下简称爱登堡电梯），但出事的电梯型号未知。该工作人员表示，“电梯从佛城商都建起来就开始用了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;公开信息显示，佛城商都第一期于2015年开业，物业运营方为弥勒吉盛商业管理有限公司。事故发生后，南方周末记者拨打了该公司和其母公司云南吉成控股有限公司相关负责人的电话，均被挂断。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者拨打了爱登堡电梯、爱登堡云南分公司和昆明分公司的电话，均无人接听。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;爱登堡电梯曾多次出现维保不善的记录。资料显示，2018年，昆明市质监局曾接到投诉举报，昆明市龙江西路融城昆明湖小区5栋3号梯发生电梯困人事故，爱登堡电梯为该电梯维保单位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;企查查显示，近年来，爱登堡电梯多次因“未按照安全技术规范要求保养电梯”，被成都、莆田、安庆、济南等多地市场监管部门处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;爱登堡电梯最近一次的行政处罚记录在2023年3月。成都市双流区市场监管局抽查发现，某小区电梯的纸质版维修记录中，爱登堡品牌电梯第一次和最后一次维保时间分别为2022年5月和2022年9月。其工作人员表示，后期维保记录都通过手机APP登记，但APP显示，该电梯仅在2023年1月有过一次维保记录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年1月，昆明市呈贡区市场监管局同样以“未按照安全技术规范要求进行电梯维护保养”，处罚了爱登堡电梯的云南分公司，罚金1万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;《中华人民共和国特种设备安全法》规定，电梯作为一种对人身和财产安全有较大危险性的特种设备，其运营使用单位应对设备的使用安全负责，设置安全管理机构或者配备专职的安全管理人员。作业人员发现事故隐患或者其他不安全因素时，应立即向安全管理人员和单位有关负责人报告；当特种设备运行不正常时，作业人员应按照操作规程，采取有效措施保证安全。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;而根据《电梯维护保养规则》，维保单位应制定应急措施和救援预案，每半年至少针对本单位不同类别的电梯进行一次应急演练。维保过程若发现事故隐患，要及时告知电梯使用单位，若发现严重事故隐患，还要及时向当地的特种设备安全监管部门报告。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新来的领导要“立威”？当以能力与公道服人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258690]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;How to establish prestige when you have just been promoted to a leader? One netizen said that this can be divided into three situations. First, the most ideal situation: your appointment is a typical internal promotion. Everyone thinks you are the best candidate to be the leader of the department, so it doesn’t matter whether you establish prestige or not. At this time, you only need to do what a leader should do and let everyone recognize your management methods and abilities. Second, a more difficult situation: because you have been transferred from another department, the employees in your department are still relatively unfamiliar with you. In this situation, you should not first think about how to establish prestige. Instead, you should act as a new member of the department and adopt the concept of learning to adapt to and learn from the situation of this department. Once you have figured it out, you can then think about the next step. matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most difficult situation is the third situation: your appointment has aroused opposition from many people in the department, and many people feel that you are not worthy of being the leader. At this time, if you don’t have strong abilities, it’s better not to think about the self-defeating tactics of Zhaoliwei. You should focus on maintaining the situation first, and then look for opportunities to find ways to break through the resistance that affects you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above classification is still very reasonable, and my experience can also confirm it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Years ago, when I took the position of director of an important department at my former employer and became the leader of many old colleagues, I also thought about this issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first came to this unit, I was still a trainee. Most of my colleagues who later became &quot;subordinates&quot; of my department are already senior employees. After I was promoted to a full-time position in advance and was promoted in advance, I felt tremendous pressure. I was afraid that my colleagues in the department would not listen to me, which would cause great embarrassment. As a person who has worked in the military camp for twelve years and &quot;managed people&quot;, I understand that the environment I am in is different. I don&#39;t think I have the temperament of a &quot;tyrannical CEO&quot; at all, so I choose the most clumsy and dull kind. For example, I lead everyone to work together, occasionally share tasks for colleagues and then give them &quot;work points&quot;, and I also create things in my spare time. On the condition that they are invited to eat and play, and they try their best to help colleagues in need. Strive to win favor with a &quot;passionate leadership&quot; attitude. This approach is very different from that of &quot;smart people&quot; who are good at playing tricks and talking around. I used to think that what I did was a sign of lack of &quot;leadership&quot;, but now that I think about it, what I did was actually not bad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But I doubt whether a leader like me belongs to the &quot;minority&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Needless to say, there is an unknown dream of &quot;tree power&quot; hidden deep in our souls. Wang Xifeng in the Grand View Garden also wanted to establish his authority and used various tricks for this purpose. For many people, the hardest thing to resist is the urge to show off their status in front of others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As I get older, I can better understand the frivolousness of being eager to declare authority when I &quot;reached the top&quot; of the department when I was young. Over the years, I have seen several newly promoted young cadres being &quot;verbally bribed&quot; by frequently calling them &quot;Director X&quot; and &quot;General Manager X&quot;, with visible pride on their faces. There are countless workplace dramas in which, in the eagerness to establish prestige and eliminate &quot;thornheads&quot;, they get into a big fight with their subordinates and find it difficult to deal with the situation. The shortcomings are still due to the lack of knowledge in the heart, and they actually act willfully regardless of their actual situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Considering the circumstances mentioned by the respondent, if everyone is convinced by you, is there any need to show your authority? If everyone is &quot;not cold&quot; towards you, is there any point in showing off your prestige? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What&#39;s more, what some people call &quot;establishing authority&quot; is to use power to suppress others and use &quot;authority&quot; to the extreme. Otherwise, they will feel that their rights do not expire and become invalid. In the workplace, this disease is not as common as Other areas are lighter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A good friend of mine said it well, letting someone be a leader means letting you take the lead in doing things, not letting you deal with others. However, some people who hold leadership positions with dishonorable reputations or unworthy morals care about their &quot;tails&quot; being discovered and stepped on by their subordinates. Therefore, they either play the trick of killing chickens to scare monkeys, or they show off their power. In the attitude of &quot;You have to be afraid of me&quot; and &quot;It&#39;s better to kneel down and lick me&quot;. This is not to establish authority, it is simply to establish enemies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, if some people insist on &quot;controlling others&quot; in the workplace, they will often hit a wall. Even if I can&#39;t survive your actions, isn&#39;t it okay to change departments and leave? How many people&#39;s resentment and disdain are hidden in the narrative here between the iron-clad &quot;workplace&quot; and the smooth &quot;beating workers&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, it is not a bad thing for a person to have prestige, or to want to establish prestige. However, it is open to speculation as to where a person&#39;s prestige should come from - whether it comes from power and the means designed to display power, or from character and ability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, no matter what circumstances you become a leader, whether you are inside or outside the system, you cannot do without this question: Is your judgment better than that of your subordinates? , whether what you do is more beautiful than what your subordinates do. In the final analysis, as a leader, whether you have authority or not is determined by your professional ability and character. When you are well-equipped with both political integrity and talent, and do things well, even if you are an &quot;airborne soldier&quot; or a rising star, you will still be respected by your subordinates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, when faced with hesitation, it is inevitable to make decisions with leadership authority and let subordinates follow the arrangements. However, in a normal context, leaders must not only be good at forming consensus with subordinates, but also be good at forming consensus with subordinates. Have the awareness and courage to advance and retreat together, and must defend the legitimate rights and interests of subordinates at all times. As an old friend said, a leader cannot protect his subordinates from wind and rain. What do you want the leader to do? Is it just a decoration? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than ten years ago, when my &quot;power&quot; was at its greatest, the department consisted of three or four departments, with dozens of employees, and the management situation was quite complicated. I don’t know if I have built up any prestige during my years as a department leader, but after I left my job, I overheard praise from my old colleagues: I dared to take on tasks for my subordinates. In addition, some colleagues also said to me, &quot;You have resigned, so why are we still here?&quot; and they finally left after me. I am often inexplicably moved by these sincere words and true nature, and feel that I am worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In reality, it is not uncommon for leaders to have great ambitions but little talent, and for laymen to lead experts, and such leaders are particularly indifferent to the rights and feelings of their subordinates. They either give credit to themselves and pass the blame to their subordinates, squeeze and intimidate them in various ways, and simply treat their subordinates like fools, or they are alienated from their subordinates, suspicious of each other, and have no integrity. For this kind of leader, even if no one dares to say &quot;no&quot; to his face, he will inevitably be scolded behind his back. It should be noted that no one in this world is a fool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, a leader should look like a leader: have good judgment and strong ability to act, be able to make decisions, take responsibility, and have a simple and strong character. Even if such a leader&#39;s ability needs to be strengthened, he can still improve his overall performance and gain the understanding and support of his subordinates. Can a leader who is magnanimous and fair in his actions have a bad reputation? I have lived over fifty years and have never seen an example to the contrary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[五年间，千亿债务“削峰”：地方化债的镇江样本]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258822]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/18/NTydygQiWy1Aa7n58WpDWSaGYxFYkXRNWBLwCKW4.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1800&quot; height=&quot;1201&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/NTydygQiWy1Aa7n58WpDWSaGYxFY kXRNWBLwCKW4. png&quot; data-key=&quot;254417&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the past few decades, Zhenjiang’s economy has mainly relied on heavy industries such as chemicals. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This year, the feeling is very obvious. Mainstream financial institutions have begun to do business in Zhenjiang.” A financial leasing company An employee told Southern Weekend reporters that due to risk control reasons, the company had not done business in Zhenjiang for several years, but this year it allowed it to do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2013, the scale of Zhenjiang’s debt has continued to rise, and it was even once called the “four major Internet celebrities” in the market’s urban investment debt issues, together with Zunyi, Xiangtan, and Dalian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Enterprise Early Warning Data, if the debt ratio is calculated as (government debt + urban investment platform interest-bearing debt)/GDP, Zhenjiang’s debt ratio has increased from 105% in 2018 to 121% in 2020 . In the past three years, its debt ratio has been higher than that of the other 12 prefecture-level cities in Jiangsu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high debt ratio has increased financial pressure in Zhenjiang, and financial institutions have also been deterred, and most have chosen to reduce their business volume in Zhenjiang. However, in 2023, Zhenjiang’s local debt situation showed obvious signs of improvement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An obvious signal is that two urban investment companies in Zhenjiang have just received AAA entity ratings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 13, 2023, the official website of the Jiangsu Provincial State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission issued a document stating that Zhenjiang Industrial Investment Holding Group Co., Ltd. and Zhenjiang Urban Investment Holding Group Co., Ltd. have both obtained AAA subject credit ratings, realizing the credit construction of Zhenjiang City. A historic breakthrough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previously, the highest credit rating of Zhenjiang’s urban investment companies was AA+. Among the 13 prefecture-level cities in Jiangsu Province, Lianyungang, Suqian and Zhenjiang have no urban investment companies with AAA credit ratings. Obtaining an AAA rating means that the financing difficulty of the urban investment platform is reduced and the cost is reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“After the debt situation eased this year, our bank reopened the credit line to a city investment platform in Zhenjiang.” A person who works at a city commercial bank in Jiangsu revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that the city investment company had previously Risk point: His bank had suspended credit to the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, among the 13 prefecture-level cities in Jiangsu Province, Zhenjiang’s GDP ranked fourth from the bottom. Although it is located in southern Jiangsu, its economy is far away from Wuxi, Changzhou and Suzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did Zhenjiang, a relatively weak economy, resolve hundreds of billions of debts? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“There are more difficulties than expected, and the challenges are greater than expected”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang is located at the intersection of the Yangtze River and the Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal, guarding the north-south hub, and is connected with Nanjing, Changzhou, Taizhou and Yangzhou border on each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Jiangsu Statistical Yearbook and the seventh national census data, Zhenjiang covers the smallest area among the 13 prefecture-level cities. Among the population distribution across Jiangsu Province, only Zhenjiang has a permanent population of less than 4 million. In other words, Zhenjiang has the least land and the least people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1983, Zhenjiang became a provincial municipality. In the past few decades, Zhenjiang&#39;s economy has mainly relied on heavy industries such as chemicals. According to the Zhenjiang Municipal Economic and Social Development Bulletin, from 2013 to 2017, the total output value of Zhenjiang heavy industry accounted for more than 80% of the total output value of designated industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2016, in order to protect the ecological environment, Jiangsu Province began to deploy special actions to reduce backward chemical production capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the Zhenjiang Municipal Government, in 2017, the city shut down a total of 53 chemical companies, exceeding the provincial target (6 companies). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For backward and excess production capacity, we must resolutely eliminate those that should be eliminated.” In January 2019, Bu Xiaofang, then director of Zhenjiang Municipal Economic and Information Technology Commission, introduced that in 2018, the city shut down 44 chemical companies, a total of 44 chemical companies were shut down in the past two years. Nearly half of chemical companies have been shut down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under environmental protection regulations, Zhenjiang’s economy has entered a period of pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, its annual fixed asset investment fell by 26.5% compared with the previous year, and private investment fell by 30.4%. In terms of industries, investment in the secondary industry dropped by 28.9%, of which industrial investment dropped by 27.9%; investment in the tertiary industry dropped by 24.3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also this year, Zhenjiang’s GDP growth rate was 3%, ranking last among the 13 prefecture-level cities. Its GDP growth rate was 9.3% in 2016 and 7.24% in 2017. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 2019 Government Work Report introduced that in the past year, the three indicators of Zhenjiang’s GDP, total retail sales of consumer goods, and fixed asset investment have failed to meet the goals set by the People’s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The then mayor of Zhenjiang City, Zhang Yefei, said in his government work report, &quot;Looking back on 2018, there were more difficulties and greater challenges than expected.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people in northern Jiangsu In cities, chemical industry is also an important industry, so why does it have less impact on economic growth than Zhenjiang? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An economist in Zhenjiang told Southern Weekend reporters that unlike the northern Jiangsu region, the Yangtze River flows through Zhenjiang. In the past, many chemical companies were located in areas closer to the Yangtze River. In the past few years, the Yangtze River Under the Great Protection Strategy, environmental protection management has become more stringent, and many chemical companies have had to close down or move away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The upgrading of industrial structure requires a buffer period.” The scholar analyzed that compared with other cities in southern Jiangsu, Zhenjiang’s high-tech enterprises and advanced manufacturing enterprises are small in scale and lack core leading enterprises, which will lead to local The capacity for economic development is limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, after the new leadership team of the Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government took office, Zhenjiang’s development philosophy also changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Zhenjiang will never repeat extensive growth in pursuit of speed, never engage in ‘numbers games’ in pursuit of political achievements, will never borrow blindly for image projects, and will never sacrifice the ecological environment in pursuit of economic interests. .&quot; In January 2019, Zhang Yefei, then mayor of Zhenjiang City, said in an interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While the chemical industry was shut down and reorganized, a large amount of debt burdened by the vigorous development of urban construction in previous years was still accumulating, which put pressure on Zhenjiang&#39;s finances of low revenue and high debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2017, the Zhenjiang Municipal Government’s work report stated, “In the past five years, the urban area has completed a total of 290 billion yuan in urban construction investment.” In comparison, Zhenjiang’s general public budget revenue in 2017 was 28.4 billion yuan. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this period, urban investment debt also increased rapidly. According to the Enterprise Alert, from 2013 to 2017, the interest-bearing debt of Zhenjiang Urban Investment Platform increased from 122.1 billion yuan to 350.3 billion yuan, an increase of 187%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee inspection team inspected the Zhenjiang Municipal Party Committee and found that during a certain period, &quot;the municipal Party committee did not do enough research on debt control, economic layout, major projects, and urban construction.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhenjiang Municipal Party Committee wrote in the inspection and rectification report that in view of the inadequate management of government investment projects, it was made clear that all government investment projects must be managed by the municipal party committee and municipal government through unified decision-making, and a series of documents were issued to build a System system for completion acceptance. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Municipal finance has completely returned to &#39;food finance&#39;&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Economic growth has slowed down, a large amount of money has been invested in urban construction, and there is rigid payment pressure on the finance. Zhenjiang&#39;s local debt problem has gradually exposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In August 2018, Zhenjiang City’s budget implementation in the first half of the year revealed that the scale of municipal fiscal maintenance and operation expenditures has increased year by year. In 2018, the municipal department budget arrangements for personnel, operations and business project expenditures were close to 3.4 billion yuan. &quot;Under the development trend of large total operating expenditure, high proportion, and rapid growth, municipal finance has completely returned to &#39;food finance&#39;.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Food finance&quot; refers to the fiscal revenue of the first-level government, which is only enough to maintain the salaries of personnel in government agencies and institutions, as well as basic daily operations. In 2018, Zhenjiang City’s general public budget revenue was 12.6 billion yuan. 3.4 billion yuan, equivalent to 27% of the general public budget revenue that year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang’s 2018 budget execution report stated that incremental financial resources are limited, and the balance of fiscal revenue and expenditure in recent years has mainly relied on revitalizing existing stocks, coordinating funds, and replacing financial resources. However, there is less and less room to absorb incremental expenditure through existing financial resources. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;China Discipline Inspection and Supervision News reported that on January 18, 2019, Lou Qinjian, then Secretary of the Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee, pointed out that “Zhenjiang City has weak links in supervision of key areas, and the government’s hidden debt risks are prominent. , and there are even corruption issues.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Slowly, Zhenjiang’s debt situation became known to the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Zhenjiang, debts are mainly concentrated in various urban investment platforms, and government debt is still controlled under the limit. If you look at the debt scale of Zhenjiang Urban Investment alone, it is much lower than that of Suzhou, Wuxi, Changzhou and other places, and is not outstanding in Jiangsu Province. The key issue is the debt ratio. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang’s debt ratio is much higher than that of other cities in Jiangsu. According to the aforementioned calculation method, in 2013, its debt ratio was only 41.71%, and in 2020 it reached 121%. If the debt ratio is too high, it means that the local comprehensive financial resources are difficult to repay debts, and cannot even guarantee the existence of debts, which is prone to risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the urban investment debts in Guizhou, Yunnan and other places are concentrated at the county level. But in Zhenjiang, urban investment debts are mainly concentrated in municipal platforms. The enterprise warning notice shows that in 2022, the interest-bearing debt of Zhenjiang&#39;s top four municipal urban investment platforms will be 207.5 billion yuan, and the interest-bearing debt of all urban investment platforms in Zhenjiang will be 340.5 billion yuan, accounting for 61%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This situation is also related to Zhenjiang’s economic structure. Zhenjiang has jurisdiction over 3 districts and 3 county-level cities. The economic aggregate of county-level cities is higher than that of municipal districts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In the past few years, Zhenjiang City has not been as prosperous as the counties (county-level cities) below. Mainstream financial institutions would rather do business in the counties (county-level cities) than invest in the cities. Platform operation.&quot; Wang Li, who works for a financial leasing company in Shanghai, and whose major customers are mainly urban investment companies across Jiangsu, explained to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to alleviate financing pressure, Zhenjiang Urban Investment Platform began to issue a large number of non-standard products. Compared with bank loans and bonds, non-standard financing issuance costs are higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang Cultural Tourism Industry Group (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Zhenjiang Cultural Tourism&quot;) is 100% owned by the Zhenjiang Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission and is a municipal urban investment platform. Zhenjiang Cultural Tourism&#39;s bond prospectus shows that in 2017, its non-standard financing scale was only 2.8 billion yuan, and by 2020, it had climbed to 11.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, Zhang Huan has spent tens of millions of yuan purchasing non-standard products from urban investment companies in various places. He told Southern Weekend reporters that around 2016, he purchased non-standard products in Zhenjiang, and the interest rate was less than 7%. However, at that time, the income from urban investment bonds in Guizhou, Yunnan and other places was higher, and non-standard products in Zhenjiang were not easy to sell. &quot; In order to persuade me to buy, the agent would give me some rebates, such as buying 1 million and getting 10,000 back.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An employee of a financing intermediary company told Southern Weekend reporters that the highest coupon rate for non-standard products in Zhenjiang was around 9%. The employee said that at first Zhenjiang’s district and county urban investment platforms were issuing such products, probably because of the difficulty in financing, but later they were concentrated on municipal platforms with larger assets. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Support from provincial governments&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, the Jiangsu Provincial Government and the Zhenjiang Municipal Government began to solve the urban investment debt problem before the risk occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of 2019, news leaked out of the market that the China Development Bank would replace Zhenjiang’s implicit debt at a cost of 20 billion yuan a year for 2 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of that year, Zheng Zhijie, the former president of the China Development Bank, said at a forum, &quot;Zhenjiang has problems with high repayment pressure and high costs. Zhenjiang also wants to extend the term and reduce the current financial burden. I also We participated in the talks, but the Zhenjiang News plan was not approved by the Ministry of Finance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2019, when talking about how to resolve the existing debt, Finance Minister Liu Kun stated that he would insist that the central government would not bail out. Who is responsible for borrowing money, so that &quot;whose family&#39;s children will be cared for&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the CDB’s plan was not passed, Jiangsu Province began to increase its debt support for Zhenjiang. The specific methods were to increase the scale of special bonds, reduce the financing pressure of urban investment platforms, and avoid relying on high-interest non-standard loans. product. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Special bonds of municipal and county governments are issued by provincial governments on their behalf. After counting the budget implementation status of various regions in Jiangsu, it can be found that the scale of special debt in Zhenjiang in 2019 increased by 34.6 billion yuan compared with the previous year. Among the 13 prefecture-level cities in Jiangsu, Zhenjiang is the place with the largest increase in the scale of special debt. In 2020, the scale of Zhenjiang&#39;s special bonds increased by 42.5 billion year-on-year, also exceeding other regions in the province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the large-scale issuance of special bonds, the scale of Zhenjiang government debt has changed accordingly. According to data such as Zhenjiang City&#39;s budget implementation, Zhenjiang City&#39;s government debt scale was 109.7 billion yuan in 2019, which is not outstanding in the province. In 2021, the debt will rise to 191.8 billion yuan, second only to Nanjing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Zhenjiang also replaced high-cost hidden debts by issuing replacement bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2019 financial accounts of Danyang City and Dantu District under the jurisdiction of Zhenjiang, the replacement of hidden debts was mentioned. According to the final accounts report of Danyang City, the government bonds issued by Jiangsu Province in 2019 totaled 5.3 billion yuan, of which 1.4 billion yuan were replacement bonds, accounting for 26%. The replacement bonds were used to repay the existing implicit government debt of platform companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dantu District also revealed in its final accounting report that it issued 679 million yuan of existing replacement bonds to repay existing hidden debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“In response to financial and debt risks, we have taken measures such as curbing growth, adjusting structure, and reducing costs. The total amount of government debt and costs have ‘double decreased’.” Zhenjiang Municipal Government’s 2021 Work Report wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Enterprise Early Warning Data, Zhenjiang’s urban investment interest-bearing debt increased by 200 million yuan year-on-year in 2021, with little change; in 2022, urban investment’s interest-bearing debt was 340.5 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 9.7 billion Yuan. In other words, the debt scale of Zhenjiang’s urban investment platforms has been controlled and is trending down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many urban investment practitioners in Jiangsu told Southern Weekend reporters that the most critical factor in Zhenjiang’s debt-oriented development is the financial and policy support from Jiangsu Province. For a long time, Jiangsu&#39;s GDP has ranked second in the country and has strong economic strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The official website of the Lianyungang government shows that on May 27, 2022, the north-south paired assistance meeting between Wuxi and Lianyungang was officially held. For more than 20 years, Lianyungang has been supported by Zhenjiang. For Zhenjiang, withdrawing from assistance can alleviate some of the financial pressure. In addition, changing Lianyungang&#39;s sponsor from Zhenjiang to Wuxi also requires coordination from provincial government departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Zhenjiang also has professional cadres handling debt matters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2020, Zhou Kai, then vice president of Bank of Jiangsu, was transferred to deputy mayor of Zhenjiang City. Previously, he worked at China Construction Bank Jiangsu Branch, Bank of Nanjing and Bank of Jiangsu for more than 20 years. According to the official website of the Zhenjiang Municipal Government, Zhou Kai is in charge of the local financial regulatory bureau, the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, municipal state-owned enterprises, etc., and assists in being in charge of the Finance Bureau. The deputy mayor must also be nominated by the Organization Department of the Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reduce financing costs&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2021, Jiangsu Province issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Regulating the Investment and Financing Behavior of Financing Platform Companies&quot;, requiring guidance for financing platform companies to gradually reduce trust and capital costs. management plans, financial leasing, private equity funds and various non-standard products issued on local trading venues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to replacing hidden debt with bonds, Zhenjiang also received assistance from banks to increase credit and reduce financing costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhenjiang Communications Industry Group (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as &quot;Zhenjiang Communications Investment&quot;&lt;/span>;) wrote in the bond prospectus , with the coordination and support of government resources, since 2020, the total amount of corporate bank credit has increased, high-interest non-standard financing has been cleared to a greater extent, the debt composition and financing costs have been better improved, and financing costs have decreased by 0.84% ​​compared with 2019. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After analyzing bond prospectuses, Southern Weekend reporters found that between 2020 and 2023, the top four urban investment platforms in Zhenjiang in terms of asset size have all seen sharp declines in non-standard financing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the one with the largest scale reduction is Zhenjiang Communications Investment. In March 2020, the amount of non-standard financing in Zhenjiang was 15.3 billion yuan, accounting for 25.86% of the total financing scale; in March 2023, the amount of non-standard financing was 5.555 billion yuan, accounting for 10% of the total financing scale. Compared with three years ago, it dropped by 9.745 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Lin works at a municipal urban investment platform in Zhenjiang. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the company had cleared away other high-cost non-standard products, except for short-term emergency financing, which could only be done after filing. According to the person from the above-mentioned financing intermediary company, there are currently no non-standard products for the public in Zhenjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2023, many places in Jiangsu have announced the upper limit of financing interest rates for urban investment. Several people from Zhenjiang&#39;s urban investment platform told Southern Weekend reporters that the upper limit of Zhenjiang&#39;s external financing costs is 6.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, this interest rate is at a medium level in Jiangsu Province. A staff member of an urban investment platform in Nanjing told Southern Weekend reporters that the local urban investment financing limit is 4.2% (five-year LPR), which is almost the strictest regulation in Jiangsu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to people from the above-mentioned financing intermediary companies, some urban investment platforms in Jiangsu can issue fixed financing products with interest rates of up to 7%-8%. &quot;Actually, the upper limit of issuance cost is 6.699%.&quot; Zhang Lin said that if the red line of 6.7% cannot be reached, &quot;lower cost financing must be achieved.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2022, the Zhenjiang Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission issued a document stating that for high-cost financing projects that meet or exceed the financing cost control price determined by the municipal government, the &quot;High-cost Debt Management Approval Form&quot; must be filled out one by one in advance 》, after the enterprise implements the internal decision-making procedures, it can be carried out after being reviewed by the Municipal State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission, reported to the leaders of the municipal government for approval, and reported to the Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision for filing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned Nanjing Urban Investment person also revealed that if the cost of a financing reaches 5%, the district will advise you not to do it. If there is real financial pressure, the district will coordinate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Zhenjiang City State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission’s document also mentioned that it is necessary to clarify the mutual insurance quotas of enterprises based on the financing needs and affordability of relevant enterprises, implement total amount control, and prevent cross-conduction of debt risks and unlimited extension of debt chains. In principle No guarantee shall be provided in excess of the mutual insurance limit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, the mutual guarantee situation among Zhenjiang municipal-level urban investment companies has not been optimistic, with Zhenjiang Cultural Tourism being the most serious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Its bond prospectus shows that as of the end of March 2020, the issuer’s external guarantee balance totaled 16.7 billion yuan, accounting for 97.93% of net assets. The company provides relatively large amounts of external guarantees, mainly to state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Recovering economic losses of nearly 1.6 billion yuan”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the basis of specifying the upper limit of financing costs, Zhenjiang and other places in Jiangsu are further reducing financing intermediary fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2019, the Zhenjiang Municipal Party Committee wrote in a report on the progress of inspections and rectifications that it is necessary to further standardize the decision-making and operating procedures of financing projects, strictly control intermediary agency service fees, formulate intermediary agency service management methods, and adopt intermediary Institutional access system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Incorporate the intermediate business expenses in the credit link into the total cost and determine them together, require all municipal industrial groups to register their accounts in detail, and eliminate the payment of financing and financial advisory fees to third-party non-financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Some urban investment platforms are controlled by intermediaries, and there is no way around them.” Li Yu has worked in many financial leasing companies. He told Southern Weekend reporters that intermediaries generally have a close relationship with the leaders of urban investment companies. Internet, &quot;Even if the cost is low, urban investment will not do business with you, you must go through an intermediary.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu said that after the intermediary participates, it will push up the financing cost. For example, if 6% of the cost can be financed, the final cost will be 8%, and the middle 2% will be between the intermediary, urban investment, and investors. divided into. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An article published on the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission stated that since the launch of a special rectification of corruption issues in the financing field in January 2022, the Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision of Zhenjiang City, Jiangsu Province has filed a total of 22 cases and investigated party members and cadres, including those at the county level. With 3 cadres, nearly 1.6 billion yuan in economic losses were recovered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the special rectification, the Zhenjiang Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision comprehensively reviewed the financing business of platform companies at the municipal, county and township levels in the past ten years, focusing on and verifying financing projects whose comprehensive financing costs significantly exceeded the market interest rate. , sorting out financing projects with major doubts such as illegal payment of intermediary fees and abnormal comprehensive financing costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, it was discovered that a number of fund &quot;brokers&quot; were involved in cross-regional financing business and obtained high intermediary fees, as well as bribing platform company officials. A total of 10 fund &quot;brokers&quot; were investigated and punished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yu revealed that this year, government staff from a certain place in Jiangsu came to a financial leasing company where he previously worked and demanded the return of funds that were higher than the upper limit of financing costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, urban investment platforms across Jiangsu are very sensitive to financing costs. In October, at a financing negotiation meeting of a certain urban investment company in Jiangsu, Southern Weekend reporters saw an executive repeatedly negotiating with bank staff, hoping that the other party could reduce the channel fee of 3‰. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Now when the person in charge of an urban investment company goes to the government for a meeting, the first thing he reports is not the current status of the company’s operations, but the situation of debt repayment.” A Zhenjiang urban investment practitioner said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Wang Li’s view, Zhenjiang Urban Investment’s debt has not been significantly compressed, but the internal debt structure has been well adjusted, non-standard financing has accounted for a low proportion, and the debt can survive stably. “What financial institutions value most is Or debt stability.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Li’s company has conducted statistics and found that the number of new financial leases in Jiangsu in 2022 dropped by 40% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, governments at all levels in Zhenjiang have also revitalized state-owned assets to relieve financial pressure. In 2018, Zhenjiang City&#39;s state-owned capital operating income was only 568 million yuan, and it reached 4.854 billion yuan in 2020, mainly coming from property rights transfer income at the municipal level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the number of high-quality state-owned assets is limited and this income is difficult to sustain. In 2022, state-owned capital operating income will drop to 585 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, with the help of the provincial government and financial institutions, Zhenjiang has improved its debt structure by curbing the increase in debt and replacing high-interest debt. Coupled with the recovery of financing intermediary fees and the establishment of financing cost ceilings and other control measures, the debt ratio has been steadily reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2023, the Zhenjiang Municipal Government’s work report revealed that in 2022, in response to financial debt risks, the government will strengthen the concept of “debt reduction is also political achievement” and further promote “redundancy reduction” and “peak reduction”. Four plans, annual goals and tasks were fully achieved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beginning in 2019, the Ministry of Finance established a local government debt risk rating mechanism, dividing debt risks into red (debt rate ≥ 300%), orange (200% ≤ debt rate &lt; 300%), yellow There are four levels: (120% ≤ debt ratio &lt; 200%) and green (debt ratio &lt; 120%). &quot;Going off the red&quot; refers to the debt risk level that leaves the red. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 16, 2023, in response to issues related to Zhenjiang’s chemical debt, Southern Weekend reporters called the Zhenjiang Municipal Finance Bureau, but the other party declined the interview request. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewees, Wang Li, Zhang Lin and Li Yu are pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; /p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[张之洞为何再三邀请他北上？陶福祥与张之洞的“岭学流传中原”计划]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-19 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/uAHKaAKt8pPKk3GxEarg8QaVt3xFpc5kh1mEol60.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;759&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/uAHKaAKt8pPKk3GxEarg8QaVt3xFpc5kh 1mEol60. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254130&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Portrait of Tao Fuxiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Taken from &quot;Portraits of Scholars in the Qing Dynasty&quot;/pictures)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early days of Zhang Zhidong&#39;s supervision of Hubei, he proposed that &quot;Lingxue spread to the Central Plains&quot; He said that in order to attract scholars from Guangdong Xuehaitang to go north, he particularly valued Tao Fuxiang (alias Chunhai), a disciple of Lingnan scholar Chen Li. Ruan Yuan, governor of Guangdong, founded Xuehaitang. After the mid-Qing Dynasty, the status of &quot;Lingxue&quot; rose rapidly. Xuehaitang does not have a mountain director, but elects many scholars as &quot;seniors&quot;. Zhang Weiping, Tan Ying, Zhu Ciqi, Chen Li, Zou Boqi, etc. have all served as seniors. In the seventh year of Guangxu&#39;s reign (1881), Zhang Shusheng, the governor of Guangdong and Guangxi, petitioned the court to &quot;compliment and commend&quot; two great Lingnan scholars, Zhu Ciqi and Chen Li, and both of them were awarded the title of &quot;Fifth Rank Minister&quot;. When Zhang Zhidong was in charge of Guangdong, he founded Guangya Academy. One of his purposes was to inherit the academic scholarship of Xuehaitang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xuehaitang attaches great importance to &quot;simple learning&quot;, and Chen Li, a native of Panyu, inherited and developed Ruan Yuan&#39;s academic tradition. Scholars during the Qianjia period focused on textual research, while the official ideology promoted Zhu Xi, forming an opposition between Sinology (textual research) and Song Dynasty (righteousness). Chen Li followed the current situation and put forward the slogan of &quot;reconciling the Han and Song Dynasties&quot;, and the &quot;reconciliation theory&quot; was gradually affirmed by the mainstream. Zhang Zhidong&#39;s &quot;Encouraging Learning&quot; written in 1898 emphasized that &quot;old learning is the body and new learning is the application&quot;, which is also a &quot;reconciliation theory&quot; and is in the same vein as Chen Li in terms of thinking and methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Li&#39;s &quot;Study Notes of Dongshu&quot; was once popular all over the world. Wen Tingshi quoted Weng Tonghe as saying that Emperor Guangxu &quot;placed this book on his desk and read it daily.&quot; Yuan Chang, a disciple of Zhang Zhidong, expressed his admiration for Chen Li many times in his diary. In the seventh year of Guangxu&#39;s reign, Yuan Chang &quot;read Mr. Chen&#39;s &quot;East School Reading Notes&quot; and found out that everything he said was profound, practical and feasible, and now Mr. Hu is stable.&quot; Mr. Anding Hu was Hu Yuan, a famous scholar in the Song Dynasty. In the fourteenth year of Guangxu (1888), Yuan Chang called Chen Li and Zeng Guofan together, &quot;the only recent sages can be called Zeng Wenzheng and Chen Panyu.&quot; He called Chen Li &quot;Chen Panyu&quot; without a name, and was compared with Zeng Guofan and highly praised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before this, Zhang Zhidong had met Tan Zongjun, the son of Tan Ying, and Gui Wencan, a disciple of Chen Li. In 1871, Pan Zuyin and Zhang Zhidong launched an elegant gathering at Nagarshu Temple in the capital. Gui Wencan and Tan Zongjun were both guests. Zhang Zhidong wrote to Pan Zuyin, saying that Gui Wencan&#39;s attainments in Confucian classics were &quot;really unattainable.&quot; Chen Li was highly praised by important officials in the court, and Gui Wencan played an irreplaceable role. In the fourth year of Guangxu&#39;s reign, on Chen Li&#39;s 70th birthday, Zhang Zhidong wrote a couplet to congratulate him on his birthday. The couplet said: &quot;Living late and taking care of one&#39;s old age will bring virtue to the world; sharp thinking and thinking are the teachings of scholars.&quot; Although he had never met Chen Li, he I highly admire Chen Li&#39;s academic practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the winter of the 15th year of Guangxu&#39;s reign, Zhang Zhidong moved from Guangdong and Guangxi to Huguang, and planned to build Lianghu Academy based on the model of Guangya Academy. The following year, Zheng Zhitong (also known as Bo Geng), who was appointed to teach economics at Lianghu Academy, died suddenly, which made him turn his attention to Lingnan scholars. Zheng Zhitong (1831-1890), a native of Zunyi, Guizhou, was the son of the famous scholar Zheng Zhen. In his early years, he served as an assistant to Zhang Zhidong in Sichuan academic affairs, and was later hired as the branch of Guangya Bookstore. In Zhang Zhidong&#39;s mind, the best candidate to succeed Zheng Zhitong was Tao Fuxiang, Chen Li&#39;s disciple and Liang Dingfen&#39;s teacher. From this, Zhang Zhidong launched his &quot;relentless pursuit&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《碑传集三编·陶福祥传》言：“文襄移督两湖，设置两湖书院，函电坚招，辞不获已，往为商定归程，评校课卷，三阅月谢病归。”措辞简约。张之洞坚请陶福祥、陶氏反复辞谢、照顾张氏面子短期北上然后坚决回穗的过程，见之于本年王秉恩、陶福祥来往电报，现藏于中国社会科学院近代史研究所，可为陶福祥传增添注脚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王秉恩，字雪岑，四川华阳人，张之洞任四川学政时识拔的得意门生，长期在广东为官，时任广雅书局提调。光绪十六年二月初三日，张之洞发电报王秉恩：“伯更（郑知同）既没，两湖书院经学分教无人，惟陶春海孝廉渊雅端纯，堪居此席，望代请来鄂，修火岁共八百金。此间分教与广雅局面不同，并不另请山长，事权较重，体貌较尊。关聘如允即寄。”（《近代史所藏清代名人稿本抄本》第二辑第41册第26页，以下引用仅注册数、页码）经学为当日学问核心。两湖书院不设山长，经学分教即拥有学科领导人地位，权力较大。张之洞怕陶福祥计较名位，特如此说明。 “渊雅端纯”既是对陶福祥的评价，也是张之洞聘请经学教习的标准。当时有“经师即人师”的说法，经学教师不仅要学问渊深，还要品行高洁，足为诸生法式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陶福祥（1834-1896），字春海，别号爱庐，广东番禺人，少从陈澧问学，光绪二年中举人，笃守师说，邃于经学，藏书十万卷。张之洞督粤，聘为广雅书局总校。两湖书院光绪十七年（1891）春季学期，除经学分教外，史学分教也乏人，张之洞嘱意陈澧另一门生林国赓。林国赓，字飏伯，番禺县穗石乡人，九岁能为诗文，入学海堂为专科肄业生，与乃弟林国赞在史学方面均卓有建树，陈澧称两兄弟“二林，国之宝也”。林国赓于光绪十一年被举为学海堂学长。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陶福祥不欲北上，在电报中辞谢：“福祥以馆为家，现已启馆，散徒移居，暂难就绪。夏秋且营葬事，未便远行。”（第66册第711页）他所开设的学馆已开学，不能让生徒解散，况且夏秋间家中还有葬事，难以接受湖北方面的邀请。十天后，张之洞发电王秉恩，分析陶福祥辞谢原因，除了本人开馆授徒，他还兼着广雅书局总校、学海堂学长、菊坡精舍山长，地位崇隆，入息颇丰。张之洞复电王秉恩，答应为此想办法，给现任两广总督李瀚章打招呼，给他保留三个兼职。 “至菊坡、学海两学长，虽来鄂省，亦可仍兼。陶系粤中学者领袖，此两处绝不能他属也。至书局一席，当为切托李筱帅（李瀚章字筱泉）照旧，务恳允来，聘函即日寄。”（第41册第391页）在张之洞心目中，陈澧既殁，陶福祥即为“粤中学者领袖”，为请动陶福祥，不惜恳求继任两广总督李瀚章，给陶氏保留兼职。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为打动陶福祥、林国赓，张之洞大派高帽，在致王秉恩电报中说：“陶、林同来鄂，亦不寂寞，均望坚邀允来，从此岭学流传中原，想陶、林亦必欣愿也。”（第41册第398页）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张之洞聘请陶福祥，姿态如此之低，就差亲自三顾茅庐，这让陶氏感到不好意思，不得已想出一个折衷办法，即到湖北任教三个月，然后再以“归葬”为由返回广州。陶福祥在武昌三个月时间内，为两湖书院的经学教学定好规模与课程，然后返回广州。临行，张之洞向陶福祥要“替人”，陶福祥推荐了同门、番禺人王国瑞，王最终似乎没有成行。林国赓刚收到邀请时，以父亲老病为由推辞（第66册第714页），最终仍被说动，到两湖书院任史学分教，1892年考中进士，授翰林院编修，离开湖北。陈澧弟子梁鼎芬曾兼两湖书院监督，是张之洞办理湖北学务的主要助手。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;学海堂注重实学，学长之一邹伯奇（南海人）对光学、测量学有湛深研究，曾主持测绘南海县舆图，为我国采用近代方法测绘方志舆图之始。邹伯奇弟子、南海人罗照沧，专擅测绘之学，被张之洞罗致到湖北测绘河道图，留两湖书院任教。此后，张之洞聘请了不少广东学者北上，经学教习杨裕芳（南海）、经学教习马贞榆（顺德）、算学教习汤金铸（花县）皆是。汤金铸专精算学，曾被左宗棠礼聘任教福建船政学堂。学海堂继承了清代经史的正统，又有不少弟子兼擅实学（测绘、算学等），这是他们受张之洞重用的主要因素。 1905年，张之洞与袁世凯奏停科举，学术进入新时代，所谓“岭学流传中原”也就乏人提起。今日而言，知道陈澧者尚有不少，了解陶福祥的已不多见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[数字人“入职”企业，主打“不知疲倦”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258816]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-18 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/BADHEzQtsMAcF3e3m8E5OUM4qs74EoClsS3SbwS0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1249&quot; height=&quot;832&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/BADHEzQtsMAcF3e3m8E5OUM4qs74EoClsS3SbwS0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月8日，杭州亚运会闭幕式，数字火炬人“弄潮儿”由远及近，跑入闭幕式的现场，将主火炬熄灭。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杭州亚运会上，一个巨型数字人火炬手踏着钱塘江水、穿过城区，快步跑向场馆，点亮主火炬。超写实虚拟数字人厘里在电视剧《异人之下》，完成影视剧“首秀”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了荧幕上的数字人外，更多数字人“入职”企业，与人类共事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;市面上虚拟人、数字人、虚拟数字人的概念常常混用，业内也尚未形成统一的认知。通常来说，虚拟人更多指的是现实无真人实体的纯数字形象，而数字人包括无真人实体的虚拟形象，也包括现实真人的数字“分身”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数字人有着拟人或者类人的外形、行为或思维能力，但没有物理实体，仅存在于虚拟空间。因其具有自由定制外观、绝对服从命令、不知疲倦等特点，承载了人类克服肉体凡胎局限性的完美想象。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，从事于数字人制作的，除了数字人技术公司、影视动画公司外，国内外互联网巨头在布局元宇宙时，无例外地选择了数字人，并推出各自的数字人创作平台。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数字人的供应商百花齐放，谁在为数字人埋单？&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;从万元到百万元&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;常见的数字人从外观上可以分为卡通形象、二次元人物、写实或超写实数字人；从驱动方式上，主要可分为真人驱动和AI驱动；从功能定位来看，又可分为演艺型数字人和服务型数字人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同类型的数字人，在技术路线和制作成本上，也会存在较大的差异。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“数字人模型（精度）主要由面数决定。”沈健友告诉南方周末记者。他出生于1995年，在广州虚拟动力担任市场经理，这家公司提供惯性动态捕捉技术和虚拟数字人制作的服务。公司员工以90后居多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈健友解释，建模一个正方体只需要六个面，但模型通常涉及到复杂曲面，需要更多面数才能保证模型的圆滑度。普通的卡通玩偶建模面数少，且不涉及复杂服饰、毛发等制作，越是贴近真人的超写实模型，制作越复杂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;模型的复杂程度关联着实时驱动效果。沈健友举例，一个卡通模型的面部表情主要是眼睛和嘴巴的开合，而人形模型的表情动作通常有52组模型形变参数。也就是说，从确定定制形象开始就决定了后续的工作量和制作成本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一套能够实时驱动的数字人至少得上万元，包括数字人形象定制、动捕设备和虚拟主播系统。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沈健友说，由于客户定制数字人的使用场景不同，具体成本还得结合客户需求来定，要想制作类似柳叶熙那样的超写实数字人造价在百万级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;柳夜熙制作方创壹科技CEO梁子康曾对媒体表示，推出柳叶熙前半年，在研发、人力和技术上的成本投入约为百万级别，首条柳叶熙短视频成本高达几十万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者以客户身份咨询阿里云销售了解到，通过阿里数字造星服务，设计一套适配真人智能驱动、多场景多端口复用的虚拟数字人资产约需50万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由于数字人定制成本不低，沈健友接触到市场的大多数客户还是以B端为主，尤其集中在文旅、教育、政务展馆领域，偶尔有预算较高的C端客户找来。“比如一些不愿抛头露面或想最大程度发挥自身优势的主播。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，很多B站的个人虚拟主播使用Live2D模型（二维动画效果），也被称为主播的“皮套”。制作“皮套”需要完成角色立绘，再制作将其成Live2D模型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;部分画师会提供一些精美的公共立绘，专属角色则需向画师约稿，价格从百元到千元不等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一家提供Live2D模型制作的公司，推出常规模型制作套餐价格为666元，最贵套餐也不超过千元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有了模型后，再借助摄像头即可完成面部和手部的动作捕捉，真人主播在电脑前可以通过面部表情和手部动作操作直播画面中的模型，实现预设表情和简单动作，但模型无法自由行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位B站的虚拟主播表示，如果主播自身有能力包揽画师和建模师的工作，直播的成本仅有硬件的投入。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;数字人演员诞生&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;数字人中，制作精美、多才多艺的数字艺人最为吸睛，造价也最为昂贵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们的形象外观充分迎合市场审美，出道即带有鲜明的人设和身份标签。如擅长歌舞的洛天依、A-SOUL，会美妆还会抓妖的博主柳夜熙，主打时尚的KOL博主AYAYI、翎_Ling，还有古风赛道的数字人天妤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;靠“脸”和“人设”受到关注的数字艺人，意味着要持续投入高昂的制作成本和稳定的运营能力，二者缺一都会让数字艺人沦为互联网上乏人问津的“空壳”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，数字艺人的变现方式与传统艺人并无不同，主要还是品牌活动、商务代言、演出等方面。两者相比，数字艺人的露出机会少、粉丝基础薄弱、知名度和市场号召力有限。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但近年来，真人明星“塌房”对品牌形象造成影响的案件不胜枚举，不少品牌开始牵手数字艺人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诞生于2020年的阿喜Angie是动图宇宙旗下的一名虚拟偶像。她是一位留着齐脖短发，妆容干净清爽的邻家女孩。抖音账号里的作品偏向于记录日常生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出道三年，阿喜已经与钟薛高、雅迪换换、奇瑞、小米、OPPO、花点时间等品牌建立合作关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钟薛高品牌负责人回复南方周末记者，与数字人阿喜合作是实现品牌创新、拉进与年轻消费者距离的一次全新探索与尝试，增强消费者与企业的互动感。数字人代言的优势还在于能够适配品牌特点进行二创，定制符合品牌调性的形象与内容。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里大文娱集团旗下首个超写实数字人厘里，已顺利参演影视剧，成为名副其实的“数字演员”。在剧中，厘里饰演没有四肢，只能靠电磁波行走并控制电磁波的少女二壮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;厘里团队负责人书面答复南方周末记者，厘里的形象最初有八个版本，最终结合用户调研选中当前这一版，甜美可爱中还带有一点酷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;体现厘里“演技”水平的桥段，是二壮从别人口中听到食物时幻想到嘴馋。阿里方面回应这得益于导演的“调教”，在厘里的极限表情中测试出最佳效果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在导演许宏宇的拍摄方案中，二壮这一角色时本来是用传统特效完成，后期才更换为数字人的方案。厘里技术团队负责人表示，相较于传统特效，数字人方案能降低80%的制作成本，主要节约原画设定和IP资产打造的成本；AI技术让后期制作的周期缩短了40%，剧组短时间内多个更多选择和可能性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里大文娱集团CTO郑勇向媒体透露，《异人之下》播出后，厘里在剧中的表现吸引了好几位导演前来询问数字人技术的解决方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;科幻片导演乔飞也关注到厘里在电视剧中的表现，但他认为从大荧幕呈现效果来看，电影叙事对演员微小的表情动作要求极高，细微表演隐含着丰富的信息，而数字人表演程度上的细腻程度还远未及理想。“真人能轻松做到的事情，交给AIGC却要付出极大的成本。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在乔飞看来，数字人演员只是提供类似于传统特效制作的技术替代方案。除非数字人能够积累IP价值，才具有和明星艺人一样的品牌溢出效益。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vLH9Sds1AvaEOKfHLMtuWaQ9l1SmOVUwru5A42vh.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/18/vLH9Sds1AvaEOKfHLMtuWaQ9l1SmOVUwru5A42vh.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254376&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;真人穿上面部捕捉和动作捕捉设备后，能实时驱动数字人形象做出相同的动作。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者麦圈/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;虚拟直播需求激增&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;数字人制作企业接到的需求，更多来自于品牌数字人形象定制或某个项目中的数字人IP。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成立于2014年的世优科技是杭州亚运会数字人的技术提供方。拿到亚运会数字人形象后，世优科技的目标是让这个数字人动起来，并借助AR技术完成数字人跑动点火的视觉画面输出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈冲在2016年来到世优科技，担任市场营销负责人。早期，她的客户主要来自于广电领域，定制实时互动的虚拟主持人，2018年教育领域对教材可视化要求提高带来大量需求，2019年后，疫情让各行业被迫转移到线上，品牌虚拟直播的需求激增。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当品牌的投入比重向线上倾斜时，考虑到更好地实现品牌露出，企业往往会定制一套数字人形象。世优科技曾为京东、天猫、海尔兄弟、苏宁易购等企业提供品牌形象数字人、IP型虚拟数字员工的定制服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月19日，劲牌官宣首个数字人员工——东方劲，同时也作为企业的品牌大使。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初次亮相的东方劲穿着一身红色唐装，下身着黑色西装裤搭配黑色皮鞋，身握一把纸扇，身形魁梧挺拔。这一数字人模型由广州凡拓数创提供技术支持。凡拓数创是一家专注数字展馆展厅设计的公司。凡拓数创2022年财报显示，数字人项目为其新业务，仅占总营收比重的2%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东方劲项目的负责人刘礼兰向南方周末记者表示，数字人是品牌增加一种与用户沟通的途径，比如参与营销活动，在企业展馆全息仓与消费者进行问答互动。“参观企业时，仍会有专门的体验专员接待消费者，涉及住宿、引路、讲解等一系列工作，这是数字人无法替代的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘礼兰后续负责东方劲的营销活动或内容运营工作，凡拓数创作为合作方提供技术支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在劲牌内部，东方劲项目属于数字化转型的典型工程。“（东方劲）项目的内容和预算已都确定，对比一些营销活动项目，这个项目预算不算高。”刘礼兰表示，后续内容运营商有新的需求，仍会追加预算。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“日不落”直播间&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年以来，在短视频平台常能见到这样一段视频画面：办公室一排排工位上没有真人，每张桌上立着一块屏幕，上面的主播不停地介绍着产品。视频中的人提示，屏幕上的主播全是数字人，可以24小时为你工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不知疲倦的数字人击中直播行业从业者的痛点。视频下方，多条留言询问如何购买这样的数字人主播。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各家数字人技术厂商推出的“服务型数字人”，都是能脱离真人、由AI驱动的数字人形象，可以服务于新闻播报、直播、客服等内容输出领域。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;只需要提供图片或视频，AI会自动模拟复刻一个与真人相差无几的2D数字形象，输入文字或者语音，AI能让数字人做出贴合内容的口型、表情和动作。有的AI数字人甚至能自如转换多个国家语音，实现口型的贴合和流畅自然的动作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者检索发现，国内头部的云厂商也已推出类似的AI数字人产品，如百度云、腾讯云、阿里云、华为云、讯飞、京东、火山引擎等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些平台大多数都提供包月服务。普通用户就可以在数字人生成平台上，使用内置的公共模特、声音、动作等，进入后台可以像编辑文字一样编辑生成数字人的短视频。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以讯飞智作平台为例，一个普通会员的价格在399元每月，高频制作需求的用户可购买2999元每月的尊享会员。腾讯智影为非会员提供每月五分钟的数字人播报体验，最贵的专业会员仅598元一年，享有每月30分钟数字人视频，600次AI绘画。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但南方周末记者以客户名义咨询发现，由于直播平台的规则不同，数字人直播还难以跨多个平台实现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;阿里云数字人主要提供淘宝生态内的数字人主播。阿里云销售介绍，淘宝支持数字人主播，对真人主播和数字人主播的流量分配是一视同仁的。杭州谦寻与南京硅基也合作推出数字人主播，弥补真人主播精力有限、成本高昂的问题，数字人在深夜、非黄金时间段的店铺自播，拉长直播时间，提高主播人效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;商家渴望用AI主播来打造一个“日不落”直播间，在一些平台看来则是对直播生态的破坏。火山引擎售前客服则表示，目前还未开通数字人直播业务，“抖音不让做数字人直播”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在抖音上，也有博主反映使用数字人直播引发“封号”的风险。有的是因为平台判定数字人直播为录播，也有的因为使用公共模特混用等。尽管如此，有的数字人直播商家仍在指导商家如何避免触发平台封号。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者匿名向两位购买过数字人直播的抖音用户咨询，一位用户表示，数字人直播开播一周0成交额，另一位则指出数字人直播间无法吸引真实用户观看。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乔飞指出，直播最大的价值在于能给观众带来陪伴，观众能够从真人主播那里捕捉大量的情感信息，而数字人无法提供，这也是数字人留不住观众的原因。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但数字人在批量输出内容上仍有一定的优势。沈健友举例，对于短视频运营者来说，每天要处理大量的视频内容，拍视频、剪视频占据大量的时间精力，数字人短视频只需要更换文本内容，就能快速生成视频文件，提高了工作效率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>