<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[两部门规范大型演出活动管理：面向公众销售门票比例不得低于85%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256578]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 14:24:37&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In order to strengthen large-scale commercial performance activities with an audience of more than 5,000 people (hereinafter referred to as &quot;large-scale performance activities&quot;) To standardize management and promote the healthy and orderly development of the performance market, the Ministry of Culture and Tourism and the Ministry of Public Security jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Further Strengthening the Standardized Management of Large-scale Commercial Performance Activities to Promote the Healthy and Orderly Development of the Performance Market.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; pointed out that at present, the performance market is rapidly recovering and development, and large-scale commercial performance activities such as concerts and music festivals have increased significantly. While meeting the spiritual and cultural needs of the people, ticket speculation in individual performance activities Problems such as ticket scalping, irrational star chasing, and uncivilized viewing are also prominent. It is required that in accordance with the principle of &quot;whoever organizes the performance is responsible&quot;, the performance organizer should strictly implement the responsibility of the safety subject, strictly establish and implement the safety management system, and clarify the person responsible for safety , establish and improve risk assessment and emergency response working mechanisms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; makes the following clear requirements for strengthening ticket management:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Large-scale performance events implement a real-name ticket purchase and admission system. Each performance can only purchase one ticket per ID card. For each ticket, the identity information of the ticket purchaser and the visitor shall be consistent. Performance organizers and performance ticket sales platforms should strengthen the protection of consumers&#39; personal information to prevent unauthorized access and leakage, tampering, and loss of personal information;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Performance organizers should establish a refund mechanism for large-scale performance events and set up Establish reasonable tiered refund fees to protect ticket buyers’ legitimate rights to refunds;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Further increase the proportion of ticket sales for large-scale performance events, and the number of tickets sold to the market by performance organizers shall not be less than the number of approved audiences 85%. For the remaining 15% of tickets, personal information should be bound 24 hours before the performance to achieve &quot;real-name binding and real-name admission&quot;;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The performance organizer should clearly indicate its authorized ticketing agency, Guide consumers to purchase tickets from legal channels. The notification obligation should be fulfilled and consumers should be informed of the rules for ticket purchase, admission and refund;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The culture and tourism administrative departments should urge performance organizers and performance ticket sales platforms to provide ticketing information for large-scale performance events (including but not Limited to the name of the performance, performance time, number of performances, number of tickets, ticket sales plan, box office revenue and other information) are transmitted to the national cultural market technical supervision and service platform in real time to further strengthen the management of ticketing information for large-scale performance events;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Cultural and tourism administrative departments and public security organs should strengthen the management of local work tickets for large-scale performance event organizers and venues, strictly control the scope of issuance, and prevent work tickets from entering the market and being illegally traded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; requires: Cultural and tourism market management departments and comprehensive law enforcement agencies should strengthen on-site inspections of large-scale performance activities, verify actor information and performance content on-site, and it is strictly prohibited to change actors and performance content without authorization. Lip-singing, false playing and other illegal activities; intensify the crackdown on illegal activities; the cultural and tourism administrative departments must strengthen the management of performance ticket sales platforms, and deal with those who fail to perform the obligation to verify the qualifications of ticketing business units and performance approval documents in accordance with the law, and resell tickets for Providing services and other violations; the public security organs should intensify the crackdown on reselling performance tickets, comprehensively collect information on ticket reselling and speculation online and offline, promptly discover clues about price increases and disguised price increases, and crack down on online and offline ticket scalping and fraud. Illegal and criminal activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Notice&quot; also clarifies: The cultural and tourism administrative departments shall, in accordance with the &quot;Cultural and Tourism Market Credit Management Regulations&quot;, handle large-scale performance activities where the number of tickets sold to the public is less than 85% of the approved number or is less than 85% of the approved number. Performance organizers and ticketing agencies that resell tickets, facilitate the purchase and sale of performance tickets, etc., are deemed to be untrustworthy entities in the cultural and tourism market in accordance with the law. To guide the audience to watch performances in a civilized manner, it is recommended that actor brokerage companies and related entertainment brokerage practitioners should strengthen education and reminders for actors, and actively guide actors to always respect the legal red line and strictly abide by the moral bottom line. Actors are encouraged to take the initiative to speak out, guide the audience to abide by the management regulations of the performance site, and jointly maintain the order of the performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[超标七千多倍？小心“毒耳环”里的有害元素]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256570]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/13/Q0cYLBRGe5Z0RfFYjKdB6PdQQ5EScvFfqnc512Pw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/Q0cYLBRGe5Z0RfFYjKdB6PdQQ 5EScvFfqnc512Pw. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The production process of simulated jewelry includes design, molding, sand casting, welding, polishing, In many processes such as electroplating, harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead appear to be excessive, in order to make the jewelry more beautiful and cost-effective. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nong Jian/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Are you here to touch porcelain?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the south of Beijing In a jewelry store near Luogu Lane, when a Southern Weekend reporter inquired about the origin of the earrings, the name of the manufacturer, and whether there was a quality inspection report, the clerk showed an incredulous expression: &quot;It&#39;s just a few dozen yuan, why do you ask? &quot;It seemed like this was the first time she was asked this question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A wall full of earrings, earrings, and ear clips are packed in small grids, densely packed. Under the spotlight, these imitation jewelry, jade and precious metals made of imitation jewelry reflect brilliant light. When the girl picks them up, she also picks up her imagination of beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But behind the beauty, there may be hidden health risks. Many earrings and other imitation jewelry are &quot;three-no products&quot; - no production date, no quality certificate, no manufacturer, and even harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead exceed the standard. Wearing them may cause &quot;allergy&quot; and threaten your health. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mandatory national standard &quot;Regulations on Limits of Hazardous Elements in Jewelry&quot; (GB 28480-2012) regulates harmful elements in non-precious metals (precious metals mainly refer to 8 metal elements such as gold, silver and platinum group metals) Relevant regulations have been set on the limit. Because piercings are in contact with the human body, earrings are more stringent than jewelry such as necklaces that are in contact with human skin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it has been ten years since the implementation of national standards. Due to high testing costs and lack of mandatory requirements, cases and recalls of alloy earrings and other imitation jewelry containing harmful elements exceeding the standard are still common. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The amount of cadmium released in &quot;hot-selling&quot; earrings exceeds the standard by more than 7,000 times&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is the quality of &quot;hot-selling&quot; earrings with a total sales volume of more than 60,000 pieces and an average price of more than five yuan? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, on an e-commerce platform, the non-toxic pioneer team of the environmental organization Shenzhen Zero Waste Environmental Protection Public Welfare Development Center (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;non-toxic pioneer&quot;) placed an order for the top-selling product 10 styles of earrings were sent to a qualified third-party laboratory for testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None of these 10 earrings have quality certificates, product names, manufacturer and other information labels. They are &quot;three noes&quot; products and violate the product quality law. The test report even showed that cadmium content in 3 models exceeded the standard by 6808 times, 6872 times, and 7208 times; nickel release in 4 models exceeded the standard by 0.25 times, 0.5 times, 0.5 times, and 1.8 times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/oYt6uFkA6kDbYxGTmA7M4spKESuOui1aCpS6Apd2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height= &quot;1332&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/oYt6uFkA6kDbYxGTmA7M4spKESuOui1aCpS6Apd2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Test results of harmful elements in 10 earrings. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Non-Toxic Pioneer/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After &quot;Non-Toxic Pioneer&quot; reported to the e-commerce platform, 6 products with excessive heavy metals have been downloaded shelf. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a customer, Southern Weekend reporters inquired about the certificates of other products sold by these merchants. Some said that they “have no quality certificates,” while others claimed that they “have them but it is not convenient to provide them.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for imitation jewelry to contain harmful elements that exceed standards. In 2014, authors from the Zhuhai Quality, Metrology, Supervision and Inspection Institute published a paper stating that after testing 40 pieces of imitation jewelry in Zhuhai’s retail market, 19 items contained excessive levels of harmful elements, indicating “the overall quality problem is very serious.” There is basically no ingredient description on the packaging or markings of jewelry. Even large imitation jewelry processing companies only use names such as &quot;alloy/silver-plated/gold-plated jewelry&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, an author from the Guangdong Product Quality Supervision and Inspection Institute published a paper: 50 batches of simulated jewelry purchased on an online platform and the Guangzhou Jewelry Wholesale Market were tested, and 11 batches of harmful elements exceeded the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing, director of the National Jewelry Quality Inspection and Testing Center, is one of the drafters of the national standard &quot;Regulations on Limits of Hazardous Elements in Jewelry&quot;. She told Southern Weekend reporters that in 2007 and 2010, for domestic imitation jewelry , the U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) twice proposed large-scale recalls, which attracted the attention of domestic regulatory authorities and promoted the introduction of national standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;my country’s supervision of the export of imitation jewelry is also becoming increasingly strict. Starting from January 1, 2011, imitation jewelry has been included in my country&#39;s import and export legal inspection product catalog - the import and export commodities that must be inspected are formulated and adjusted by the national commodity inspection department. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even so, news of recalls of exported jewelry has remained frequent in recent years. On the official website of the &quot;Hebei Provincial Defective Product Recall Management Center&quot;, search with &quot;earrings&quot; as the keyword, from March 2018 to November 2022, there are 62 earring product recall information released by the EU, most of which are produced in China, and the defects are all Excessive levels of harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel or lead. According to statistics from the testing agency &quot;ETC Les Testing&quot;, in the second quarter of 2021, there were 66 recall notifications for imitation jewelry from European countries and Canada, including 41 cases of Chinese jewelry. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There is still a lack of quantitative research on the health effects&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Many people have this experience. Their skin becomes red or even allergic when wearing jewelry, especially earrings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jinliang, a researcher at the Chinese Academy of Environmental Sciences, told Southern Weekend reporters that in addition to being related to personal constitution, another main reason for allergies may be that the amount of nickel released from jewelry exceeds the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jF5c9yTRnuv4kqrnnCTfDps3iCEoNsD9dw89Qzv2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/jF5c9yTRnuv4kqrnnCTfDps3iCEoNsD9dw89Qzv2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Four earrings that were found to have excessive nickel. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Non-Toxic Pioneer/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The production process of simulated jewelry includes design, molding, sand casting, welding, polishing, electroplating, etc. Through multiple processes, harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead appear to be excessive, in order to make the jewelry more beautiful and cost-effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Hua, a designer at a jewelry factory in the south, said that nickel is mainly produced in the electroplating process. The worse the electroplating process, the lower the cost, and the easier it is to release nickel. Zhang Jinliang said that in the production of jewelry, adding cadmium will increase the gloss and have an anti-rust effect. Adding lead can improve the flexibility of the jewelry and facilitate shaping. Lead and cadmium are also the main components of many pigments. If cheap earrings and other jewelry are rich in color, the content of these two harmful elements is more likely to exceed the standard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/guumhbZZDicrgBhye5ii4ryU5TZwZspWZmmQXGHl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;353&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/guumhbZZDicrgBhye5ii4ryU5TZwZspWZmmQXGHl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Three earrings that were found to have excessive levels of cadmium were all around 7,000 times the standard. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Non-toxic Pioneer/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The quality of raw materials is also very important. Zhang Jinliang said that the raw materials of some jewelry are scrap metal or low-quality alloys, which are cheap and may cause excessive heavy metal content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The harmful elements in jewelry exceed the standard and will threaten human health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jinliang said that nickel can easily cause skin contact allergies, and long-term exposure to nickel may cause contact dermatitis, neurasthenia, and cancer reactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cadmium has been certified as a carcinogen by the International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC), and is listed as the sixth toxic substance harmful to human health by the United Nations Environment Program and the International Committee on Heavy Metals in Occupational Health. Chronic intake may cause high blood pressure, increase a person&#39;s risk of diabetes, and even cause severe bone damage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the alloy earrings tested by Non-Toxic Pioneer, 8 models were found to contain lead. Although the content meets the standard, it is still not recommended to wear them. Because lead is a cumulative poison that can enter the human body through the respiratory tract, digestive tract, skin, etc., lead poisoning will occur when the accumulation reaches a certain value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simulation jewelry with substandard quality is more harmful to children’s health. Children like to bite jewelry, and some lead products have a sweet taste. Scientific research has proven that the absorption rate of lead in the respiratory tract and lungs of children is much higher than that of adults. my country and other countries have also specifically set limits on harmful elements for jewelry worn by children ≤14 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there have been cases of recalls of children&#39;s jewelry in recent years. For example, from March 12 to 22, 2021, Health Canada issued 4 recall notices for children&#39;s imitation jewelry, involving 4 products, a total of 3,904 pieces, all produced in China. The reason for the recall was the lead and cadmium content in the products. Exceeds local standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Zhang Jinliang also said that the toxicity of harmful elements is only a theoretical statement. Heavy metals mainly enter the human body through the respiratory tract and digestive tract, and the skin absorption is relatively small. At present, there is no quantitative research data on the impact of heavy metal exposure in earrings on human health; in addition, the piercing part of earrings has a small contact area with the human body. If the heavy metal exceeds the standard, it may cause some adverse reactions, but the probability of causing heavy metal poisoning is very high. Small, &quot;so there is no need to be too alarmist.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jinliang suggested that if you wear earrings and other jewelry for a long time, try to choose precious metals such as gold, silver, and platinum. Their supervision is more standardized and their quality is better. Alloy jewelry with many styles, good shapes and low prices has different usage scenarios from precious metals. You can clean it with alcohol before wearing it, which will help reduce the exposure of heavy metals on the surface of the jewelry. Try not to wear alloy jewelry when exercising, bathing, swimming, etc. , because sweat may increase heavy metal exposure after contact with the alloy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are hidden tricks in the testing industry&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;my country&#39;s imitation jewelry industry started in the 1980s. China is currently the world&#39;s largest exporter of imitation jewelry, forming three major distribution centers in Yiwu, Qingdao and Guangzhou. According to data from Yiwu City, there are more than 300,000 employees in Yiwu&#39;s jewelry industry, with annual sales of more than 20 billion yuan, accounting for more than 2/3 of the total output value of the national jewelry industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gRmBhVAobWJmAbyX2sObDLPh7cQTxyOheciRUyAC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/gRmBhVAobWJmAbyX2sObDLPh7cQTxyOheciRUyAC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In November 2017, Qingdao Airport Inspection and Quarantine Bureau and Liuting Airport Customs sampled a batch of incoming imitation jewelry and sent it to the laboratory for testing. The results showed that the sample of imitation jewelry contained lead. More than 30 times more than the standard. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Simulated jewelry exported for sale on international e-commerce platforms such as Amazon must provide testing certificates that comply with local standards. For example, the European Union and Amazon require merchants to provide statements or test reports that can prove that products comply with &quot;REACH&quot; (Registration, Evaluation, Authorization and Restriction of Chemicals of the European Parliament and of the Council) regulations, including values ​​for harmful elements such as cadmium, nickel, and lead. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many third-party testing companies provide testing services, but a Southern Weekend reporter’s investigation found that there are hidden “tricks” in the testing industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporter consulted as a jewelry manufacturer and found that the charge for testing the release of cadmium, nickel, and lead is between 500 yuan and 800 yuan per sample, and the time required is about 7 working days. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For many imitation jewelry, this testing fee is equivalent to the cost of hundreds of products, so there are &quot;hidden rules&quot; for testing services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s possible to play around with the edges.” The customer service of a testing agency on Taobao said that REACH requires each product to provide a test report, but the agency can only conduct one actual test for multiple jewelry with similar materials, and other &quot; For &quot;Hitchhiking&quot; products that have not been tested, if you replace the photos with them and the test values ​​remain unchanged, you will also have an &quot;exclusive&quot; test report. The above-mentioned customer service stated that the agency can support a maximum of 10 packages for testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The customer service of some institutions also introduced the &quot;hidden rules&quot; for packaging and testing in larger quantities. &quot;More than 100 models (packaged for testing) are a bit exaggerated, because export customs clearance and selling on the platform are risky, and the customs and the platform may doubt the authenticity of the test report.&quot; Yang Le, customer service of this testing agency, said to the south A reporter from the weekend said that this kind of demand from customers is very common. &quot;Considering cost issues, it is impossible to test every product, so our customers will put many products together for testing in the name of &#39;series&#39;.&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Le said that if jewelry companies are worried that the actual measured harmful elements in their products exceed the standard, they can also provide a &quot;certificate package&quot; service and issue a non-actually measured test report, and the test results can be filled in at will. &quot;This test report must also be uploaded and filed. Although we have not tested it, it is exactly the same as the test report of the actual test.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the premise of &quot;guaranteed certificate&quot; is that the customer needs to sign a contract with the testing agency Disclaimer, exempting the testing company from liability. The disclaimer template sent by Yang Le reads: &quot;In consideration of the time relationship of customer needs, after negotiation between the two parties, the testing agency evaluates and issues certificates and reports according to customer requirements. At the same time, the customer promises that the product is qualified and ensures that the products in the sales market meet the requirements. If there is any non-compliance, the testing agency will not assume any legal responsibility or compensation obligations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Le said that the fee for &quot;package certificate&quot; and packaged testing of multiple products are the same, both 700 yuan. Since the &quot;certificate package&quot; does not require actual testing, it only takes 5 working days to complete. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;New standards are being revised&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Similar to most products, the supervision of imitation jewelry is based on laws and regulations such as the Product Quality Law and the Import and Export Commodity Inspection Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Product Quality Law stipulates that producers shall be responsible for the quality of the products they produce; if there are national standards and industry standards to protect human health and personal and property safety, product quality shall comply with such standards. Li Suqing said that the simulation jewelry produced and sold by merchants must meet the national standard requirements, but when it is launched in the country, it is not required to undergo compulsory product certification like food, home appliances and other consumer goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, home appliances must obtain &quot;3C Certification&quot; (China Compulsory Certification, China Compulsory Product Certification) before they can be put on the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing believes that if imitation jewelry is included in the 3C compulsory catalog, there will be difficulties and controversy. For earrings that sell for a few yuan, it is unrealistic to ask merchants to spend hundreds of yuan to detect harmful elements. &quot;It will not only increase the costs for merchants and consumers, but also increase the cost of law enforcement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market supervision department mainly adopts random inspections to supervise imitation jewelry. For example, Yiwu City has carried out several special rectifications on alloy jewelry and carried out supervision and spot inspections on an annual basis. The 17 batches of products randomly inspected in 2022 were all qualified after being tested by third-party testing agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, whether simulated jewelry is sent for inspection mainly depends on customer demand. &quot;Many customers do not need test reports because it will increase costs.&quot; Li Hua said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior person in the testing industry told Southern Weekend reporters that in China, e-commerce platforms such as Tmall and JD.com and some large supermarkets will require merchants to provide quality inspection reports for jewelry, but some e-commerce platforms Commercial platforms and many offline sales venues do not require this. Li Benben, communications director of the Shenzhen Zero Waste Environmental Protection Public Welfare Development Center, said that Toxic-Free Pioneer plans to collect more earring samples from multiple e-commerce platforms in 2024 to investigate product quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing suggested that to improve the qualification rate of imitation jewelry, the illegal costs of enterprises must be increased. According to public information, few jewelry manufacturers have been punished for substandard harmful elements in their products. The Product Quality Law stipulates that those who produce or sell products that do not meet the national standards for protecting human health and personal and property safety may be fined not less than three times the value of the illegally produced or sold products; if the circumstances are serious, the product may be revoked. Business license; if it constitutes a crime, criminal liability will be pursued in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The shapes of earrings and other accessories are becoming more and more complex, and the ingredients are not only simulated metals, but also textiles and even batteries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Suqing revealed that the national standard promulgated 11 years ago is being revised. The new version of the national standard in terms of chemical properties may further tighten the limit requirements on lead content; it may also add some requirements on mechanical and physical properties. For example, there are certain regulations on the position of jewelry needle tips and battery-containing jewelry. The specific changes will be subject to the final standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Li Hua and Yang Le are pseudonyms, Southern Weekend intern Liang Chengyuan also contributed)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx .net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt; /div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公职人员做发型被拒，税务局翌日上门查税：这样的营商环境如何让人安心丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256530]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a woman in Tancheng County, Linyi City, Shandong Province threatened a barber shop by showing photos of her uniform, which became a trend on social media. Search. On September 8, the Tancheng County Joint Investigation Team reported that the woman was a staff member of the County Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, and she was given a major demerit. This incident cannot be taken lightly, because it is not just a matter of &quot;the low quality of individual public officials&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to an interview with Mr. Xu, the owner of the barber shop, by Chinese Business Daily, Dafeng News and other media, on August 30, the woman came to the shop to do a &quot;protein correction&quot; hair care project. The hairstylist assessed her hair and said her hair was too dry to do the job. As a result, the woman showed the &quot;uniform photo&quot; on her mobile phone and threatened to &quot;call people from our brigade to come (investigate and deal with the case).&quot; Mr. Xu thought she was just saying harsh words to scare people, but he didn’t expect that tax bureau personnel would come to check the tax the next day. After confirming that there was no tax evasion problem in the barber shop, they would also ask for every account of Charlie’s hair shop since it opened. Mr. Xu was so angry that he posted the surveillance video online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netizens have speculated who this woman is. She can easily mobilize the tax bureau to investigate taxes if she is unhappy. However, both the Tancheng County Taxation Bureau and the Market Supervision Bureau denied that the woman was their staff. After the video attracted attention online, on September 6, two men who claimed to be the woman&#39;s colleagues went to the barber shop to apologize to the owner, but still did not reveal what company she worked for. It was not until this incident became more and more intense online that Tancheng County issued a notice in the name of the joint investigation team on September 8, confirming that the woman was Wang Moumou, a staff member of the county&#39;s Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What this Wang Moumou did reminds people of the &quot;borrowed personnel&quot; of a certain district transportation bureau in Harbin more than a year ago. Because the online ride-hailing driver refused to allow him to smoke in the car, he called the &quot;brothers&quot; from the Transportation Bureau to check on illegal cars and &quot;deal with&quot; the online ride-hailing driver. Why do public officials dare to call &quot;brothers&quot; to inspect cars when they are not performing official duties, or threaten barbershops by showing photos of themselves in uniform? I&#39;m afraid it&#39;s still a sense of superiority: If you don&#39;t follow my requirements, I can punish you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the one from Harbin is from the Transportation Bureau (although he is &quot;borrowed&quot;) and has the power to investigate and deal with illegally operated vehicles, so he can &quot;handle&quot; online ride-hailing drivers. And this Wang Moumou from Tancheng is from the Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau. How could Wang Moumou mobilize the tax bureau to investigate taxes? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Tancheng County’s official announcement, she called the 12345 citizen hotline to report the incident. However, most netizens are skeptical about this. After the woman made the threat, the tax bureau came to inspect the tax the next day. Moreover, after the tax bureau confirmed that the barber shop had just opened for a few months and had not yet reached the tax filing period and that there was no tax evasion problem, it also demanded every account from Charlie&#39;s hair shop since its opening on the grounds that the whistleblower was not satisfied. If an ordinary citizen calls the hotline to report, will the tax bureau respond so quickly? Will every account within a few months be verified after confirming that there is no tax evasion? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Netizens’ doubts are not unreasonable. Why is the tax bureau so concerned about such a report? Relevant parties in Tancheng County should disclose Wang&#39;s phone recordings or online reporting records to clarify the facts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to showing off his power and threatening the store, netizens also suspected that Wang Moumou was absent from work at will. According to video surveillance, the incident occurred at about 9:40 a.m. on August 30. Tancheng County did not explain in its report why Wang Moumou could go to the barber shop to have his hair done on Wednesday morning. Does the Agricultural and Rural Affairs Bureau&#39;s &quot;lax management of staff&quot; mentioned in the bulletin include its lax management of attendance? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Behind this incident are public concerns about the local business environment. Just imagine, an ordinary public official can show off his power and threaten, and he can torment operators at will with just a phone call. Who would dare to come here to invest and start a business? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, the investigation and processing results reported by the Tancheng County Joint Investigation Team may be difficult to eliminate public doubts about the local business environment. In an interview with CCTV, the barber shop owner said that he &quot;hopes that the normal operation of the barber shop will not be affected in the future.&quot; This also shows that he is still worried about whether he can operate normally in the future and whether he will be retaliated against again. Relevant parties in Tancheng need to disclose the incident more transparently, and at the same time introduce corresponding measures to prevent merchants operating normally from being unreasonably tortured just because of a &quot;reporting phone number.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[IPO收紧撤单潮起：36起超370亿募资喊停]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256518]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since the China Securities Regulatory Commission made it clear at the end of August that it would tighten IPOs in stages, the long-rumored market listing has become more difficult. It started slowly but gradually became solid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comprehensive interviews and research by reporters from the 21st Century Business Herald found that, in fact, as early as July 24, when the Political Bureau meeting of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China first proposed &quot;activating the capital market and boosting investor confidence,&quot; IPOs had already become obvious. Be strict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wind data statistics, from July 24 to September 10, a total of 36 companies planning to IPO on the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges withdrew or terminated their registration. Among them, there are up to 18 companies on the GEM, 4 on the Science and Technology Innovation Board, 11 on the Shanghai Stock Exchange Main Board, and 3 on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange Main Board, raising a total of 37.814 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5a2dfc0c3241535e10176d2e83b60319.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;700&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5a2dfc0c3241535e10176d2e83b60319.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250411&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;The net profit threshold for listing is raised&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A senior insurance agent of a leading brokerage firm who has been in the industry for nearly 20 years told reporters that whenever IPOs are tightened, net profit often becomes a &quot;hard indicator&quot; for listing, and various sectors have The requirements for net profit bottom line have increased. Today, this situation appears again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past, the main board could achieve success with a net profit of 80 million yuan, but now it is basically hopeless if it is less than 100 million yuan. It was more likely that the GEM would be listed at 60 million yuan last year, but now it is almost impossible to achieve less than 80 million yuan. . The fifth set of standards for the Science and Technology Innovation Board has been suspended. Once there is a large loss, even hard-core technology companies will not be able to go public. For companies with technological attributes but not hard enough, as long as they suffer losses, the listing process is likely to be blocked. Moreover, each sector has a negative impact on the listing process. The net profit requirement is not only for the most recent fiscal year. If there has been substandard performance or performance decline in recent years, sustainable profitability will be questioned, and it is also likely to be stopped.&quot; The above-mentioned Baodai told reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from Wind data, the statement of the senior insurance agent has been confirmed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From July 24th to September 10th, a total of three companies on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange main board withdrew, two of which had a net profit of less than 90 million yuan; although the other one had a net profit of 122 million yuan in 2022, it will not be listed in 2021. The annual net profit was only 94 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 20.39%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 11 companies withdrew from the Shanghai Stock Exchange Main Board, 4 had net profits of less than 90 million yuan last year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 18 companies withdrawn from the GEM, 12 will have a net profit of less than 80 million yuan in 2022, accounting for as high as 66.67%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of the four companies withdrawn from the Science and Technology Innovation Board, three have suffered losses in the past two years. Among them, Shugen Internet Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Sroot Internet&quot;), a hard-core technology company focusing on software applications, has no choice but to withdraw. Its losses since 2021 have been more than 700 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For a hard technology company like Shugen Internet, which has suffered huge losses year after year, it is naturally impossible for it to be listed on the main board or GEM. However, it has stepped on the industry trend supported by policies and placed itself on the During the loose period of IPO, it was possible to rush forward according to the fifth set of standards of the Science and Technology Innovation Board, but now that the fifth set of standards is suspended, its listing process can only come to an end.&quot; Baodai said bluntly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the fifth set of standards of the Science and Technology Innovation Board is not universal, but a green channel specially opened for star companies in special industries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the requirements, companies that meet the fifth set of standards need to &quot;break through key core technologies and possess original leading technologies.&quot; Such companies may be listed on the Science and Technology Innovation Board even if they are in the research and development stage without generating revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Baodai said, the fifth set of standards is now suspended, which means that regardless of the technological attributes of a company, if it wants to go public, it must not suffer a significant loss, and must even maintain a stable net profit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“For companies, it will be more difficult to go public and subsequent financing will become more difficult; for investment banks, the number of projects that can be sponsored will decrease and underwriting income will decline. Naturally, they will suffer losses and do not want to see it. &quot;Another industry insider told reporters, &quot;But for investors, it is a kind of protection. Excluding loss-making companies and companies with relatively low profitability from the stock market will, on the one hand, effectively improve the quality of newly listed companies. It helps investors select high-quality stocks; on the other hand, it forces more funds to flow into existing stocks, which helps stabilize stock prices.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/09/12/e594ea773537f379c1452f71c5c2b28e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;606&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/09/12/e594ea773537f379c1452f71c5c2b28e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250412&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>; Image source: Visual China&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Capital-driven companies have little hope of going public&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to investment bank insurance agents, in addition to the increase in net profit requirements, the number of years on the market is also a factor in whether a company can succeed. IPO assessment factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The purpose of assessing the number of years on the market is to determine whether the company is capital-driven.” An investment bank insurance agent told reporters. At present, in addition to emerging fields, hard technology and other industries, regulators expect listed companies to be established for more than ten or even twenty years, rely on their own strength to become stronger and bigger, and become leaders in subdivided industries before listing. Instead of relying on multiple rounds of financing driven by capital, IPO can be achieved in just a few years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason for this is that the insurance agent believes that there are two main points: on the one hand, from the perspective of the purpose of listing, compared with companies that have been operating for many years and then apply for listing, companies that have been established for a shorter period of time and rely on capital to promote, After listing, there is a greater probability that relevant shareholders will reduce their holdings and cash out. On the other hand, companies that have been established for a longer time are more likely to enter the maturity stage, have more stable operating performance, and have relatively less risk of performance changes after listing, which is more conducive to safeguarding the interests of investors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wind, as of September 10, among the 36 IPO projects that have been withdrawn since July 24, 7 projects are located in companies that have been established within 10 years, and 5 were established in 2016 or 2017. Newly established in the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Zhejiang Tongfute Meike Household Products Co., Ltd., which was established in 2017 and plans to be listed on the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange, has performed well in terms of operating income and net profit in recent years. A net profit of 126 million yuan was achieved in 2021, and the net profit in the first half of last year reached 97 million yuan; operating income is also relatively high, with operating income of 1.948 billion yuan for the whole year of 2021, and operating income from January to June 2022 totaling 916 million yuan. Since 2020, operating income and net profit have increased by more than 20% year-on-year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the above-mentioned insurance agent also mentioned that the age of establishment is an important factor in whether a company can successfully IPO, but it is not an absolute factor. If the company has good quality, stable ability to continue operating, and broad prospects in the field, even if it is only established for In a few years, there is also the possibility of going public. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Food, clothing, housing, and pharmaceutical companies concentrated on withdrawing orders&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In mid-August, there was news in the market that there was basically no hope of IPO listing of new shares of food, clothing, housing, and housing companies. At that time, the relevant cancellation data was not yet clear. Now, this statement is gradually supported. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Wind, from September 4th to 6th, three food companies stopped IPOing, one of which has a net profit of over 100 million since 2021 and continues to grow. If the statistical time is advanced to August 14, the number of food, clothing and housing companies that have been forced to terminate the IPO process will reach 7. All seven companies plan to list on the Shanghai Stock Exchange main board. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since July 24, a total of 11 companies have withdrawn orders from the Shanghai Stock Exchange main board. This means that among the companies with orders withdrawn from the main board of the Shanghai Stock Exchange, companies related to food, clothing and housing account for more than 60%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，8月14日止步IPO的大洋世家(浙江)股份公司，成立于2009年，2020年以来，净利润最低1.98亿元，营业收入最低18.35亿元，业绩远超主板利润要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得注意的是，从撤单企业所属行业来看，除衣食住类企业以外，经营业绩良好、成立年限较长的医药类企业撤单也相对较多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月24日以来，共有4家医药制造业企业终止IPO进程。其中，备战创业板的福建省闽东力捷迅药业股份有限公司成立于1997年，2020-2022年，净利润分别为0.87亿元、0.73亿元和0.98亿元，远超创业板既有利润要求，擦线现有利润标准。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;成立于1981年的中药行业老字号天津同仁堂同样未能如愿上市。其自2020年以来营业收入、净利润年年递增。今年1-6月，营业收入、净利润已经分别高达5.77亿元和1.44亿元，较创业板利润要求高出数倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[抗癌且延寿——裸鼹鼠体内的神奇能力]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256544]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;无论古人还是今人，大都希望健康长寿。古人炼丹以求长生不老仙丹，现代科学家则从动物身上探究长寿的奥妙。例如，在一种喜欢在地上生活、毛发稀疏、皮肤皱缩的啮齿类动物——裸鼹鼠身上，科学家就发现了人们长期以来梦寐以求的东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一神奇的故事是从十年前开始的。十年前，美国罗切斯特大学（University of Rochester）的研究人员在《自然》杂志网站上宣布，他们从裸鼹鼠身上找到了一种抗癌成分，高分子量透明质酸(HMW-HA)。十年过去了，2023年8月23日，该团队再次在《自然》杂志网站发表了一项更有意思的研究。他们找到了一个负责制造高分子量透明质酸的基因，并把该基因转入小鼠体内，结果这些小鼠的健康状况得到改善，具有显著的抗肿瘤特性，而且它们的寿命也延长了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/mTnNMgewFJdbzlzWoxQSrfgbcH7NnQM7lEHNpH5d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1231&quot; height=&quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/mTnNMgewFJdbzlzWoxQSrfgbcH7NnQM7lEHNpH5d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250454&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;长寿又抗癌的裸鼹鼠。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;神奇的能力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;罗切斯特大学生物学家维拉·葛布诺娃（Vera Gorbunova）教授和安德烈·瑟卢安鲁夫（Andrei Seluanov）教授之所以研究裸鼹鼠，最初的兴趣并非裸鼹鼠的长寿特征，而是其天生的抗癌机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小鼠和大鼠是最常见的实验动物，但是它们的寿命一般只有3-4年，而且肿瘤发生率比较高，无法用于研究抗癌机制，因此葛布诺娃教授和瑟卢安鲁夫教授共同带领的罗切斯特研究团队就将目光聚焦到裸鼹鼠身上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;裸鼹鼠是一种神奇的啮齿类动物，原产于非洲，大多数时间在地下生活，主要以蚂蚁等昆虫为食。与小鼠和大鼠等常见啮齿类动物相比，裸鼹鼠体毛稀疏，肉色皮肤裸露在外，长相并不好看。令生物学家感兴趣的是，裸鼹鼠寿命长，它们的寿命可达30-40年，是同体型啮齿类动物的10倍以上。裸鼹鼠不仅长寿，而且具有非同寻常的抗癌能力。根据科学家对大型裸鼹鼠群体的多年观察结果显示，至今尚未在裸鼹鼠身上观察到自然发生的癌症，而且难以通过实验诱导其产生癌症，这使得裸鼹鼠成为科学家研究抗癌新方法的理想动物模型。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到底裸鼹鼠为什么不容易罹患癌症呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在之前的研究中，罗切斯特研究团队发现裸鼹鼠细胞具有一种早期接触抑制的能力。接触抑制是一种强大的抗癌机制。一般情况下，当细胞在相互接触之前，细胞表面的受体会感受到其他细胞，并向细胞内部发出一种“刹车”信号，阻止细胞继续生长，但是这种机制在癌细胞中失灵了，使得癌细胞在高密度情况下也得不到抑制，继续疯狂生长直到堆积成多层病灶。裸鼹鼠细胞在较低密度时就会表现出接触抑制现象，而小鼠细胞则需要达到裸鼹鼠细胞浓度的三倍以上才会表现出类似的接触抑制，因此研究团队认为裸鼹鼠具有早期接触抑制，而小鼠等其他哺乳动物细胞只具有常规的接触抑制能力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，裸鼹鼠的早期接触抑制是如何形成的呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员发现蛋白激酶抑制剂P16介导了裸鼹鼠细胞的早期接触抑制，而蛋白激酶抑制剂P27则介导着其他哺乳动物细胞的常规接触抑制。当P16发生突变丧失正常功能时，裸鼹鼠细胞的早期接触抑制机制就会被破坏，只能进行常规接触抑制，更容易发生恶性转化，甚至是癌变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这项研究并没有引起太多的关注，但是却为罗切斯特研究团队打开了研究裸鼹鼠抗癌机制的大门，更大的发现还在后面。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;抗癌的基因&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;罗切斯特研究团队继续观察着裸鼹鼠细胞的生长状况，并与人类、豚鼠和小鼠等哺乳动物细胞进行对比，他们发现相对于其他哺乳动物细胞，培养皿中的裸鼹鼠细胞很快变得黏稠，如同糖浆一样。经过分析，科学家发现裸鼹鼠细胞分泌了大量的高分子量透明质酸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;透明质酸是一种酸性粘多糖，也被称为玻尿酸。透明质酸在哺乳动物的皮肤、软骨和其他结缔组织中很常见，在医药产品、化妆品中用途广泛。透明质酸主要在动物细胞之间充当填充物和支撑物的作用。根据分子量大小，透明质酸一般可以分为高分子量透明质酸和低分子量透明质酸，裸鼹鼠细胞分泌的透明质酸以高分子量为主，是人类、小鼠和豚鼠等其他哺乳动物分泌的透明质酸分子量的2-5倍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;通过进一步研究分析，罗切斯特研究团队发现高分子量透明质酸是裸鼹鼠细胞形成早期接触抑制的关键细胞外信号，即这些细胞通过分泌大量的高分子量透明质酸，使其充斥到细胞之间，形成物理束缚，裸鼹鼠细胞感受到对方分泌的透明质酸信号，生长随之放缓，因此它们能比其他哺乳动物细胞更早地发生接触抑制，难以发生癌变式的疯狂生长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为什么单单裸鼹鼠细胞能大量分泌高分子量透明质酸呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原来，在脊椎动物细胞中，负责制造高分子量透明质酸的透明质酸合成酶有三类，包括HAS1、HAS2和HAS3，其中HAS1和HAS3在各种哺乳动物身上没有什么差别，唯独HAS2分子在裸鼹鼠身上发生了重要突变。HAS2分子由552个氨基酸组成，这些氨基酸序列在其他哺乳动物中高度保守，但是裸鼹鼠的版本出现了两个氨基酸替换的关键突变。这一突变导致裸鼹鼠细胞能够大量分泌高分子量透明质酸。与此同时，裸鼹鼠细胞的透明质酸降解酶活性也比其他哺乳动物的酶活性低很多，导致高分子量透明质酸降解较慢。一旦通过基因工程技术破坏掉裸鼹鼠细胞的HAS2基因，或者让其透明质酸降解酶过量合成，基因改造后的裸鼹鼠体内的高分子量透明质酸将会大幅减少，其早期接触抑制功能随之丧失，这些裸鼹鼠也容易诱发肿瘤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些研究证明高分子量透明质酸是裸鼹鼠身上独有的抗癌因子，将为癌症的预防带来新的路径。2013年7月，这项研究发表在国际著名学术期刊《自然》杂志上，这也是葛布诺娃教授和瑟卢安鲁夫教授研究团队首次在《自然》杂志上发表论文。在这篇论文中，她们还将裸鼹鼠的HAS2基因转入到人的细胞上，观察到转基因人类细胞也能大量合成高分子量透明质酸，为十年后的另一项重磅研究埋下了伏笔。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;双重的惊喜&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;既然裸鼹鼠在丰富的高分子量透明质酸保护下不易患癌，如果让其他哺乳动物也能大量合成高分子量透明质酸，能否重现裸鼹鼠身上的抗癌和延寿效果呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然葛布诺娃教授和瑟卢安鲁夫教授研究团队最终目标是为人类找到抗癌和延寿药物，但是研究尚不成熟时直接用于人体试验显然不合适，前期开展的人体细胞研究也并不能完全模拟人体上的效果，因此先在小鼠身上试试是一个非常不错的选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究思路和过程很简单，结果却有惊喜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;葛布诺娃教授和瑟卢安鲁夫教授研究团队将负责制造高分子量透明质酸的HAS2基因转入小鼠体内，制作成转基因小鼠，结果发现这些转基因小鼠体内的透明质酸含量显著增加，特别是肌肉、心脏、肾脏和小肠等器官中检测到了高分子量透明质酸。不过，转基因小鼠体内的透明质酸含量并没有裸鼹鼠体内那么高，研究人员推测可能主要是小鼠体内的透明质酸分解酶比裸鼹鼠体内的活性更强。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;进一步观察发现，这些转基因小鼠的自发肿瘤发生率大幅降低，而且对人工诱导肿瘤具有明显的抵抗力。不管是转基因小鼠，还是非转基因对照小鼠，都是自然老去，最后大多数死于肿瘤。其中，对照小鼠肿瘤发生率达70%，而转基因小鼠只有57%，当小鼠寿命超过27个月时，转基因小鼠抗肿瘤特性更加显著，其自发肿瘤发生率仅为49%，而对照小鼠则高达83%。当研究人员对小鼠进行皮肤乳头状瘤诱导时，转基因小鼠的乳头状瘤发生率也大大低于对照小鼠，说明转基因小鼠对人工诱导肿瘤也有显著的抵抗力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更令人惊喜的是，转基因小鼠还表现出寿命延长和健康状况改善。相对于对照小鼠，转基因小鼠的中位寿命增加了4.4%，而最大寿命则增加了12.2%。与此同时，研究人员还对参加试验的小鼠进行了一番体检，发现转基因小鼠整体的健康状况显著优于对照小鼠。特别是在衰老过程中，转基因小鼠大多数器官的炎症显著少于对照小鼠，而炎症正是器官衰老的重要指标，而且转基因小鼠肠道健康也得到显著改善。进一步分析发现，转基因小鼠所拥有的高分子量透明质酸可以通过多种途径减少炎症反应，这些途径包括对免疫细胞的直接免疫调节作用、保护氧化应激以及改善衰老过程中的肠道屏障功能等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这项研究为高分子量透明质酸应用于人体临床试验奠定了基础，也为开发抗癌又延寿的药物或治疗手段带来了新的希望。2023年8月23日，葛布诺娃教授和瑟卢安鲁夫教授研究团队将这项研究成果发表在《自然》杂志网站上。从发现裸鼹鼠体内的高分子量透明质酸到证明其能改善哺乳动物的健康状况，整整花了10年的时间，反映出基础研究的不易，也体现了葛布诺娃教授和瑟卢安鲁夫教授研究团队长期努力的回报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;下一步，该团队还计划开展人体临床试验，希望通过增加体内高分子量透明质酸的合成，或者减缓其降解，实现既抗癌又延寿的目标，以将裸鼹鼠身上神奇的抗癌延寿益处带到人类身上，为人类的健康长寿开辟一条新的途径。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国人寿保险（集团）公司原董事长王滨一审被判死缓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256536]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/93c908a94264080cab76402e2672ddba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;3909&quot; height=&quot;2827&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/93c908a94264080cab76402e2672ddba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250449&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月12日，山东省济南市中级人民法院公开宣判中国人寿保险（集团）公司原党委书记、董事长王滨受贿、隐瞒境外存款一案，对被告人王滨以受贿罪判处死刑，缓期二年执行，剥夺政治权利终身，并处没收个人全部财产，在其死刑缓期执行二年期满依法减为无期徒刑后，终身监禁，不得减刑、假释，以隐瞒境外存款罪判处有期徒刑一年，决定执行死刑，缓期二年执行，剥夺政治权利终身，并处没收个人全部财产，在其死刑缓期执行二年期满依法减为无期徒刑后，终身监禁，不得减刑、假释；对查封、扣押、冻结在案的王滨受贿所得财物及其孳息予以追缴，上缴国库，不足部分，继续追缴。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/174fe68c179a8af032bfcdd04fb3ffe6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;4635&quot; height=&quot;2566&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/174fe68c179a8af032bfcdd04fb3ffe6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250450&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经审理查明：1997年至2021年，被告人王滨利用担任中国农业发展银行江西省分行党组副书记、副行长，交通银行北京市分行党委书记、行长，交通银行党委委员、副行长，交银国际信托有限公司董事长，中国太平保险集团有限责任公司党委书记、董事长，中国人寿保险（集团）公司党委书记、董事长兼广发银行董事长等职务上的便利以及职权、地位形成的便利条件，为有关单位和个人在贷款融资、项目合作、人事安排等事项上提供帮助，本人直接或者通过其亲属非法收受财物共计折合人民币3.25亿余元。2012年1月起，王滨违反国家外汇管理制度和国家工作人员境外存款申报制度，将共计折合人民币5642万余元的外币存入其亲属在香港开立的银行和证券账户，隐瞒不报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;济南市中级人民法院认为，被告人王滨的行为构成受贿罪和隐瞒境外存款罪。王滨受贿数额特别巨大，犯罪情节特别严重，社会影响特别恶劣，使国家和人民利益遭受特别重大损失，论罪应当判处死刑；王滨隐瞒境外存款犯罪系自首，可予从轻处罚，并与其所犯受贿罪并罚。鉴于王滨归案后如实供述罪行，认罪悔罪，积极退赃，具有法定、酌定从轻处罚情节，对其判处死刑，可不立即执行。同时，根据王滨犯罪的事实和情节，决定在其死刑缓期执行二年期满依法减为无期徒刑后，终身监禁，不得减刑、假释。法庭遂作出上述判决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[学生不订牛奶要医院证明：别都把锅甩在老师身上丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256542]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，一则“老师要求学生订牛奶”的新闻引发关注。9月7日，河南驻马店遂平县家长爆料称，一所小学老师发布学生订购牛奶消息，网帖中的聊天截图显示，一位老师发消息称，如果孩子因为某种疾病不能喝学生奶，家长需出具县医院或以上医疗机构的诊断及治疗证明。这位老师还表示，全班共53名学生，其中已有15人完成征订，希望剩下38名学生的家长“积极配合工作”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这则消息一经曝光就引发了一波舆情。老师的言辞存在“强制订奶”的嫌疑，多少显得“吃相难看”，“强买强卖”的作风也引发了网友的质疑与嘲讽，唤醒了大家“订牛奶” “订教辅资料”“订指定图书”的“童年记忆”。尤其是“除非自证有病，否则必须订奶”“您期望老师能对53个孩子一视同仁”的措辞，甚至还不无威胁之意，招致舆论的如潮恶评。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;遂平县有关部门9月8日对外表示，县教育局已于7日调查清楚，此事系遂平县沈寨镇中心小学某班主任的“个人行为”，“开医疗证明”也是这位老师个人的不当表述。同时，只有这个班强制要求了，其他班都是自愿订购。目前县教育局已对这名老师进行了批评教育，并要求老师向家长道歉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这并不是驻马店近期唯一一起“订奶事件”。9月7日正阳县有家长爆料称，一小学老师称“有条件积极订购，没条件创造条件订购”，从网传微信群截图来看，这名老师在微信群里发布了“牛奶人人都要订！”的信息，并表示“考虑到家长们的经济压力”，每学期的“订奶指标”从原先的“全份4箱440元”变成“学校商议”后的“每人只订3箱共计330元”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月8日该校校长称，订购牛奶是遵循自愿原则，老师措辞不对，将重新开会研究；当地教育局一工作人员则称，上级部门为了学生健康成长要求订购牛奶，但遵循家长自愿原则；教育局9月8日在情况通报中则称，网友反映问题基本属实，该班对上级文件精神解读出现偏差，涉嫌违背自愿征订原则，因此将立即暂停饮用奶宣传征订工作，对其进行整顿规范，调查处理相关责任人员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几乎在同一时间，驻马店出现了两起老师强制学生订奶的“个人行为”。纵观两起事件的时间线，可以说是大同小异；后来走向也是如此，“强制订奶”被认为是老师的“个人行为”，同时坚持学生饮用奶征订工作遵循了自愿原则。但细审这两起事件，仍有一些疑问有待辨析与追问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，老师要求学生订奶时，真的是他们的“个人行为”吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两起事件曝光的截图里，正阳县老师提到“经学校商议”，正阳县教育局在情况通报中明言这是对“上级文件”的“解读偏差”。如果没有这些“文件”压下来，区区小学老师有何动机化身推销员，有何必要向诸多家长发出“没条件创造条件” “没病就得订奶”这种影影绰绰的威逼利诱之语？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在两起事件中，如果老师冒着曲解上级文件的风险也要干出如此让家长举报的事情，背后图什么？如果没有利益动机支撑的话，“个人行为”的说辞显然就更难成立。在“上级文件”与“自愿原则”之间存在冲突的情况下，老师要如何把握“个人行为”，才能同时让上级与家长都满意？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，教育部门有必要公布当初下发的“上级文件”原文，或是向社会公布征订牛奶这项“工程”的具体指令究竟是怎样的，这样才能更清楚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，两起“强制订奶”事件也显示，基层教师在平常工作中承担了太多的非教学负担，这才是诸多类似事件的一大根源。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在现行教育体制下，老师作为实际上的基层人员、权力链条上的末梢，颇有一种“权小责大”的尴尬：这个“责”是对上负责，而不是向家长与学生负责；“上级部门”负责下指令、发通知，然而却在实际中“权大责小”，拥有极大权力的同时并不对学生负责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期以来，基层教师承担了太多不属于教学的额外任务。左手钉钉群，右手微信群，今天打卡，明天回执，这边文艺汇演，那边教材征订，导致相当多的时间精力都被非教学任务占据，严重影响了教书育人的分内之事。甚至于，基层教师往往还要将自上而下的压力传导到家长那里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以这两起事件为例，姑且不论学生饮用奶征订本身是否合理，这项工作本来也不应该交给老师来做。教育系统的行政人员为数不少，由他们这些专人来负责照看学生的健康、选取更好的奶制品，无疑会是比凭空加给老师一项无关职责要好得多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中小学教师理应从被强加的非教育负担中解脱出来，集中心神教书育人，更好地为学生而不是为上级服务，否则不出事就让老师干各种各样与教学无关的事儿，一出事就是“老师个人行为”，这也太欺负人了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“骂醒恋爱脑”服务：当情感变成生意，爱真的能骂醒吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256554]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/yVwqc8dgVtJ4PixgRy7l4nenvljJ6IFmUtgobDkg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;950&quot; height=&quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/yVwqc8dgVtJ4PixgRy7l4nenvljJ6IFmUtgobDkg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2012年播出的电视剧《薛平贵与王宝钏》近来被网友重新解读，剧情中，王宝钏等薛平贵十八年，以野菜充饥，被称为“恋爱脑鼻祖”。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“来，想怎么骂？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刚和南方周末记者加上好友，Z在聊天框中发来消息。确认了“可以直接一点”和“不要带脏字”的要求后，连性别都没问清，Z就开始连番输出：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“她都不爱你你爱她个什么劲，别人都不想理你，你还巴巴地当ATM机？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;紧跟着是一张阴阳怪气的表情包，然后礼貌地询问：“听得进去么，不行我就换一种。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在南方周末记者告知自己的性别并给出否定答案后，Z才问起具体的情况。在这个聊天世界中，南方周末记者是一个为了男友放弃考研的“恋爱脑”，如今深陷在“被分手”的痛苦之中，渴求被“骂醒”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这不分，留着干吗，送钱给他谈恋爱？”听完这个“故事”，Z极力劝分，并发起一连串质问：“为什么想不明白，为什么还期待，你凭什么要对他期待，他很帅？很有钱？会对你温柔？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;花钱找骂，这个行为听起来似乎有些不可思议。七夕前后，这项被称作“骂醒恋爱脑”的服务在电商平台上成为一门红火的生意，随后流行至小红书、抖音等社交平台，许多用户自行接单，收费开骂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/oSiDa9OXFh1Jmf8pKRUukJzleIavaabhqJpB2R2h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;767&quot; height=&quot;1695&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/oSiDa9OXFh1Jmf8pKRUukJzleIavaabhqJpB2R2h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250476&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在一家销量过万的淘宝店，南方周末记者点单了“骂醒恋爱脑”服务。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者翁榕榕/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最初造出“恋爱脑”这个词的人或许没有预料到，经过无数解读、扩散，这个标签可能让部分本就处在感情挣扎中的人更加煎熬，加剧了他们的自我否定，连向身边人宣之于口都成为难题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不久前，随着电影《消失的她》上映和电视剧《我的人间烟火》开播，主人公的一系列“恋爱脑”行径引起观众的踊跃讨论。如今，“反对恋爱脑”从口头演化为一门生意，许多深陷泥淖中的人探出手，渴求某个陌生人将自己拉出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在淘宝上搜索“骂醒恋爱脑”，可以找到许多提供服务的店家。一家销量上万的淘宝店里，不同级别的陪聊师对应着不同的价格。南方周末记者选定了只能指定性别的“盲盒”，被分配了女陪聊师Z。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Z用微信文字或语音提供服务，收费15元20分钟，她的头像是一位漂亮的女网红，朋友圈看上去很生活化，分享着她的心情感想。在这场短暂的聊天里，Z留下箴言：“收起你的眼泪，没人会喜欢喜欢哭的女孩子，他也不会因为你哭心疼。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当南方周末记者表达了走不出来的痛苦后，Z劝说“你给他加滤镜”“有病”，随即提醒时间到了。Z从添加好友的那一刻就开始了计时，丝毫不顾对话是从五分钟后才真正开始的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你可以的，相信我。我之前聊的恋爱脑都说可以的。”15元的服务戛然而止。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;主动下单，“恋爱脑”&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;清&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;醒了一半&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在店主李雨提供的价格表上，“消除恋爱脑”几个大字在粉红色的背景上十分醒目，底下一行小字写着：“情感大神在线指导”。价格表显示，“恋爱脑”被分为轻、中、重三个等级，顾客可以根据自身程度进行选择。陪聊师的服务时间从15分钟至1小时不等，价格在20元至180元之间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李雨26岁，高中毕业后，从事游戏陪玩，管理着所在公会旗下的陪玩和陪聊师。后来公会解散，她发现做陪聊大有市场，2021年底开起了淘宝店，提供闲聊和情感咨询服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;七夕前后，“骂醒恋爱脑”的新闻引起了她的注意。据报道说，这项服务能月入几万元，李雨嗅到商机，把原本就有的情感咨询服务换了个名头，挂出“骂醒恋爱脑”的新业务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正式开展服务前，李雨特地去其他店铺下单体验。她下了两单，一个陪聊师在她还没说完自己的故事时，就开始骂她“太傻了”，李雨觉得情商太低，第一反应就想给差评；另一个几乎只是闲聊，没有帮忙分析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;基于这些体验，李雨叮嘱自家店里的客服，要尽量派单给情感咨询经验丰富的陪聊师，他们上手快。另外也提醒陪聊师们注意情商，虽然叫“骂醒”服务，但也得小心态度，除非客户自己要求直白和强硬。总的来说，李雨总结，它是一类“比较强势的情感咨询”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;小陆是最早一批开展“骂醒恋爱脑”的店主之一。4月，抖音上开始流行情感劝说类的短视频，通常配上煽情的音乐，博主们语气激动，发起连番质问：“自作多情就是自取其辱”“不主动就是不喜欢”“吊着你就是差点意思”。小陆受到启发，尝试开发“骂醒恋爱脑”服务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他店里的陪聊师背景各异，有全职妈妈、企业HR，也有专业心理工作者，他让他们看抖音视频学习“骂醒”技巧。在这一行，陪聊师的音色很重要，小陆更看重情商和阅历，年龄大一点、有阅历的，聊天通常不会太差。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多位受访店主否认这项服务能月入几万。最多的时候，孟由的淘宝店每天能接到四五十个“骂醒恋爱脑”订单，最高峰一天收入几千块钱，但只持续了几天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，很多做“骂醒恋爱脑”的店家是从陪聊业务衍生而来，由原先的陪聊师提供服务。孟由号称店里有约600位陪聊师，多数是兼职，男女比例约为2∶8。孟由店铺的陪聊师分为盲盒、金牌、镇店、男女神、首席、锦鲤六个等级，按照接单的频率、学历、客户喜爱度等条件排列。等级越高，收费就越高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据孟由观察，下单“骂醒恋爱脑”的顾客里，女性超过90%。顾客的年龄大多在18-28岁，约一半是自己感情有问题，另一半是给朋友代点的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在孟由看来，顾客能主动来下单的，“恋爱脑”已经算清醒了一半，“不清醒的人不会点，他不想被骂醒。”孟由对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5obPocoVwyvkU5ZkT3eHNwqz91VDdxsv7uqhOk9B.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;1972&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/5obPocoVwyvkU5ZkT3eHNwqz91VDdxsv7uqhOk9B.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250477&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“骂醒恋爱脑”在电商平台上成了一门红火的生意，有店主表示，最高峰时日入几千元。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“不管有没有效果，他说出来了”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;刚开展“骂醒恋爱脑”服务时，李雨尝试亲自接了一次单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;客户是一个女孩，她发现伴侣一直在其他社交软件上和别人聊天，两人分手后，她一直走不出来。李雨听完后，没有骂她，她觉得对方已经很难受了，“没必要去攻击人家”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李雨用直白的态度帮忙分析：女孩的伴侣就是喜欢到处聊天，如果女孩能接受，就去挽留他继续在一起；如果不能，那就好好爱自己。女孩没有当场给出答案，说要回去思考一下。后来，女孩找到店铺客服，给李雨留下一笔打赏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陪聊师夏琳有一副偏中性的沉稳嗓音，她是在读博士，表达很有逻辑。生活里，她擅长给朋友提供建议，处理情绪问题，兼职做陪聊已经三个多月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她自认“剥离感”非常强，“骂醒恋爱脑”时，虽然能为顾客共情，但她更习惯理性分析，“我要做的就是帮你解决问题”。李雨也强调，说，不能光骂，要围绕对方的处境，也不能一上来就强势地给出建议，至少要听完他们的故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夏琳一般会首先了解客户的基本情况，让对方倾诉。“如果这个女生或男生有想倾诉的东西的话，不需要你引导他，他自己就恨不得说两小时。”夏琳说，引导对方把细节说清楚很重要，有利于帮忙分析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她接过一个订单，一个男生网恋了一年，没和对方见过面便已谈婚论嫁，分手后才意识到被骗。他几乎每天都下单找夏琳。夏琳劝他不要跟自己较劲，虽然对方在相处过程中有欺骗行为，但没有骗他钱财，也提供了很多情绪价值，希望能让他稍微释怀一些。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“坦白讲好多人愿意听真话，不见得是想来听假话的。”夏琳对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陪聊师陈晴从1月开始从事陪聊，一开始听到“骂醒恋爱脑”的顾客说自己的故事，她的情绪也会受影响，有时实在“劝不动”，她觉得有些无力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着接的单子越来越多，她慢慢看淡了，“那是他们的人生，他们的生活与我无关，我只是一个旁观者，所以再无力我也不能去帮他们做任何事情。那是他们的生活、选择以及态度。”陈晴说，“那是他的人生，你为什么要插手？跟他说你一定要分手，万一错了，这个责任你也承担不了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在小陆看来，“骂醒恋爱脑”其实只是提供了辅助作用，很多下单者只是想找人倾诉，宣泄心里的情绪。“其实就是进行一个吐露。”他说，“不管有没有效果，他说出来了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接单时间长了，夏琳发现，大部分案例大同小异。“共性是可能都有执念，都受过情绪伤害、精神控制、PUA，可能都有，又不肯放弃。”她说，“想和做是两码事，情绪这些是你摆脱不了的。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夏琳曾接过一个案例，一个四十岁的女性喜欢上一位年过七旬的已婚男性，长达几年无法抽身。夏琳感觉到，对方不打算放弃，因此她也不要求对方放弃。“尊重个体的感情，她有她自己的选择，她是成年人。”她说，“她只要同自己和解就好了，她没必要对任何人负责。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在夏琳看来，分析大道理是没有用的，“大道理能不知道吗？”一位顾客曾对她说，找了这么多人，夏琳是唯一能站在他立场上考虑的人。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“该恋爱脑的时候也是恋爱脑”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;李雨做了五年陪聊，听闻过许多别人的感情故事，自认在感情中还算聪明和谨慎。但她也不是从来如此，“该恋爱脑的时候也是恋爱脑的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的上一段感情，按她的话来说，“就是已经没有智商了”。在那段异国恋中，还在暧昧期时，对方曾经突然消失了两个月。那段时间，她经常打对方电话，但电话那头不挂断也不接起。朋友们劝她，这是遇到欺骗感情的“渣男”了，她无法相信。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;某次，对方终于接起电话，面对李雨的质问，他解释自己正在放假旅行，知道李雨一直尝试联系自己，但“就是不知道回什么”。李雨相信和原谅他的“消失”后，他们正式在一起。几个月后男生回国，李雨发现，他另有女朋友。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于下单“骂醒恋爱脑”的人，李雨感同身受。她知道，这个走出来的过程“会很难过”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在她看来，感情的问题很难用理性去控制，“我觉得每一个人都是恋爱脑，在一段感情里面，没有一个人那么理智的，感性就会有恋爱脑的倾向。”李雨告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;分手后，李雨很长一段时间走不出来。和朋友们聊起，她故作潇洒，不敢坦白自己的痛苦。因为朋友们早已劝过她多次，“劝无可劝”，可能会认定她活该。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李雨只能在网上点单请人“骂醒”自己，她不敢找自己店里的陪聊师，他们都认识自己，“这个脸不能丢在自己家里，要丢得找一些陌生人丢”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李雨告诉陌生的接单陪聊师，如果觉得她的行为很傻或有其他感受，可以直接说出真实想法，不用太担心伤到她。一些陪聊师直接骂她笨，“世界上男人那么多，为什么要吊在一棵树上”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;听完这些，李雨内心很撕裂，这些道理其实她很清楚，但就是无法走出来。只是挨骂的时候，她可以暂时平静下来。她反反复复下单了很多次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;周宁宁分手不久，试过在抖音上找人“骂醒”自己。她觉得前任不太喜欢自己，但还是很想挽留他。陪聊师分析了前任的种种不好，她一瞬间也觉得自己“有病”，居然会放下尊严去挽留对方。但没几天后，她还是忍不住又给前任发了挽留信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这是一个阶段的东西，不是说一次两次就可以解决了。”李雨说，可能顾客当时想通了，但之后又“走到感情的深坑里面”，或许会有很多次反复，都是正常的，“骂醒”服务无法一劳永逸。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说出来也许只是第一步。在李雨看来，走出恋爱脑更重要的还是要靠自己，她花了半年时间，才真正走出来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“一个人动心了之后，想脱离这段感情是需要时间的，时间是必需品。”李雨告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，小陆、孟由为行业内圈名，李雨、夏琳、周宁宁、陈晴为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 09:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日防卫费“12连涨”，“美国因素”占几何]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256562]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-13 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/HK6bzwbOV2s1RQb5E3BkZnSKhA1ThU2oKSzZDmUl.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/HK6bzwbOV2s1RQb5E3BkZnSKhA1ThU2oKSzZDmUl.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;250483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;当地时间2023年7月28日，日本防卫相滨田靖一在内阁会议上发布了2023年版《防卫白皮书》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在福岛核污染水排海阴影之下，日本政府提出了史上最高额度的防卫预算。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据日本《每日新闻》2023年9月5日报道，日本财务省当天公布了政府各部门2024财年预算申请金额，其中，日本防卫省提交的2024财年预算申请超过7.7万亿日元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与上一年度6.82万亿日元相比，新的防卫预算一举增加了近1万亿日元，增幅达13.5%，创下二战以来的最高历史纪录。至此，日本防卫预算已连续12年增长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是日本落实“防卫预算翻倍”的步骤之一，也使得岸田文雄政府距离“5年防卫支出总额达到43万亿日元”的目标更近了一步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“早在安倍政府执政期间，日本就一直谋求甩掉二战&#39;战败国&#39;帽子，突破&#39;战后体制&#39;对其发展军事力量的约束，成为真正意义上的&#39;政治军事大国&#39;。”在中国国际问题研究院亚太研究所副研究员孙文竹看来，日本防卫预算大幅度增加并不让人意外，“鉴于自民党在日本国会占据多数，该预算通过审议的概率很大。而在未来几年，如果政坛不发生大的变化，日本防卫预算都将持续保持高增长态势。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“对标北约”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;近些年来，日本经济发展低迷，但防卫预算却节节攀升。如果此次预算通过，日本防卫开支将创下自2013年以来的“12连涨”纪录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从上世纪60年代开始，日本防卫支出一直保持在GDP比重的1%以下。情况从2016财年开始出现变化，当年日本防卫预算突破5万亿日元。在接下来的7年时间，日本防卫费申请额接连“破6”“破7”，且间隔年限不断缩短。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;分析人士指出，在整军扩武的道路上，日本政府已经从“小步快跑”转向“大步狂奔”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，日本防卫费首次突破“GDP1%框架”，成为标志性事件。然而，日本的野心并不满足于此。按照岸田文雄政府的规划，日本不仅要突破“红线”，还要实现“倍增”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年12月，日本正式通过新版《国家安全保障战略》《国家防卫战略》和《防卫力量整备计划》三份安保政策文件，明确提出加紧打造“防区外防卫能力”，将未来五年的防卫费总额增加至约43万亿日元，达到国内生产总值的约2％。需要划重点的是，2%这个数字，正是美国向北约成员国提出的要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“防卫费逐年增长，本质上体现出日本的防卫政策与国家战略，已经严重偏离战后奉行的&#39;和平路线&#39;。”孙文竹指出，日本军力建设已明显“由守转攻”，并不断强化与美国捆绑，试图重新实现自己“能攻能守”的军事大国野心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;防卫预算对标北约，只是日本积极向以美国为首的北约靠拢的冰山一角。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岸田文雄就任首相以来，日本和北约持续深化合作机制，双方高层频繁互动。北约秘书长斯托尔滕贝格毫不掩饰地称，没有哪个亚洲伙伴比日本离北约更近了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了合作机制上深度勾连，双方还不断把合作重点转向军事安全领域。2022年，日本陆海空三大自卫队相继赴北约参加军演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“日本有意通过追随美国以&#39;集团政治&#39;维护自身霸权的战略思路，进一步强军扩武。”孙文竹说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在经济低迷、通胀高企、日元贬值、物价飞涨等一系列严峻挑战之下，不断攀升的防卫费用将成为日本经济难以承受之重。据《日本时报》报道，为支付不断扩大的防卫成本，日本政府或将考虑出售持有的日本最大几家公司的股份，但这很难在内部达成共识。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;美国战略优先？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;日本创纪录的防卫预算，囊括了海军战舰、F-35战斗机和装甲车采购以及新型高超音速拦截导弹开发等“一揽子计划”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“日本防卫预算增加，既有构筑强有力防御体系的意图，也凸显出军事战略向进攻性加速发展的野心。”军事问题专家张学峰告诉南方周末记者，这根本上源于日本“政治大国化”的诉求，同时还有配合美国在西太平洋部署的战略需要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，日本发布新版《防卫白皮书》，继续重申要拥有“反击能力”，并将“防区外防卫能力”和“联合防空反导能力”列为日本自卫队未来五年需要全面发展的前两大能力。相关要求在2024财年防卫预算中均得到体现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日本敲定投入约3800亿日元，用于建造2艘“宙斯盾系统搭载舰”。这两艘搭载舰长190米，宽25米，标准排水量12000吨，将会成为“日本战后最大水面作战舰艇”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“&#39;宙斯盾系统搭载舰&#39;不是一个单纯的防御平台，搭载&#39;12式岸舰导弹二阶段改进型&#39;以及&#39;战斧&#39;巡航导弹后，具备强大的海上作战能力。”张学峰分析，这实际上是日本打着“弹道导弹防御舰”的幌子，建造攻防兼备的巡洋舰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在构筑反导盾牌的同时，日本还多管齐下提升防区外打击能力。据美国《防务邮报》报道，日本计划将约7500亿日元用于增强国家的“防区外”作战能力，主要涉及开发和采购能够在敌方火力射程之外发射的导弹，包括“12式岸舰导弹二阶段改进型”、贾斯姆AGM-158联合防区外空地导弹等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“日本这些举措是为了落实&#39;新安保三文件&#39;中拥有&#39;反击能力&#39;的目标，进而补齐自身在进攻领域的短板。”孙文竹表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但事实上，部署中远程导弹并延长既有导弹射程，不仅是日本“反击能力”所需，而且是美国急于在第一岛链打造的“导弹链”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年2月，美国与日方接触，计划在日本部署中程导弹，大大增强从第一岛链发起进攻的能力。日本产经新闻称，计划部署的导弹可能是美军正在开发的“远程高超音速武器”（LRHW）或“战斧”巡航导弹。加上日本为增强“反击能力”计划部署的导弹，美日或可联手打造一个“中程导弹网络”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，美国的如意算盘正在一步步实现。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月28日，美国国务院批准对日出售“贾斯姆”导弹，价值预计为152亿日元。而早在2023年度防卫预算中，日本就专门拨出2113亿日元，用于采购400枚美制“战斧”巡航导弹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“&#39;战斧&#39;巡航导弹射程只有约1600公里，如果部署在第二岛链，就会出现射程不足的问题，所以美国一直想要在第一岛链进行部署。”张学峰指出，铁了心跟随美国的日本自然是最佳选择。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在日本看来，日美同盟是日本安全的绝对基轴，其自身安全与美国维持在西太平洋的霸权是不可分开的。”孙文竹认为，相关举措就是要维持美国的相对军事优势。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;各有盘算&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;岸田文雄提出将日本防卫预算增加一倍后，2023年1月，美国国务卿布林肯在新闻发布会上公开点赞，并称“日本的战略与我们自己的国家安全战略休戚相关”。美国总统拜登甚至在演讲中说，“是我说服”岸田文雄增加防卫费用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，在日本公布的防卫费用“一揽子计划”中，美国是主要受益者之一。在2024财年防卫预算中，日本不仅将大量采购美制器装备，还计划与其共同开发“极超音速武器”新型拦截导弹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“向日本出售武器，可以让美国军工企业赚取丰厚利润，但更为关键的是，日本军事实力不断增强，更有能力成为美国&#39;印太战略&#39;的&#39;马前卒&#39;。”张学峰说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年底，美军决定从日本嘉手纳空军基地撤出全部两个中队的F-15C/D战斗机，驻日美军空军战斗机力量直接缩减一半。美方给出的理由是战机老旧退役，但美国《星条旗报》称，美国空军撤离F-15战斗机的原因是因为“它们在第一岛链无法躲过中国的打击”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在防御难度不断加大的情况下，美国希望日本持续增强军事实力，发挥更多作用，减轻其在第一岛链上的军事压力。”张学峰分析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而日本，也在积极融入美国的“集团政治”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，岸田文雄不顾国内民众反对，再度出席北约峰会，为北约在东京开设联络处提供便利。刚刚过去的8月，美国总统拜登、韩国总统尹锡悦与岸田文雄在戴维营举行首脑会晤。美联社称，三方签署的戴维营协议巩固了“亚太小北约”，加深了美日韩安全和经济联系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“日本深知，推进&#39;军事大国化&#39;和&#39;正常国家化&#39;，都必须得到美国的认可和支持，因而必须将自己打扮成美国维护所谓&#39;自由开放国际秩序&#39;的&#39;得力助手&#39;甚至&#39;平等伙伴&#39;，以换取西方国家认可其在安全领域的地位和影响。”孙文竹表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但日本同时也有自己的小心思。在2024财年防卫预算中，日本防卫省列入逾500亿日元预算，用于开发新型国产导弹。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙文竹指出，美国退出“中导条约”后，一度有意把导弹部署到日本，但日本并不愿意被动接受，而是希望主开发或者购买中远程导弹。“一旦危机爆发，日本还可以根据实际情况和自身利益，保留一些回旋余地。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从更长远来看，日本的最终目标是尽量摆脱美国控制，夺回自主权。“如果美国放松对日本的警惕，放任其军事扩张，最终很可能会出现脱离掌控的局面，这对美国而言未必是一件好事。”张学峰指出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 13 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[非婚女性可申领生育保险：非婚生育会瓦解婚姻制度吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256520]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;越来越多地方放开了非婚女性申领生育保险的限制。最近，贵州省医保局发布《关于完善生育保障制度的通知》，从2023年10月1日起，参保人生育保险待遇享受与个人婚姻情况全面脱钩；重庆市医保局发布《关于优化生育保险经办服务有关事项的通知》，9月1日起，对参保人员申领生育保险相关待遇，不再收取生育服务证、再生育服务证、结婚证。目前，主流舆论把这种放宽解读为婚姻与生育的脱钩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生育保险作为五险之一，过去是一个独立险种，现已并入了城镇职工基本医疗保险。这个险种的特殊之处在于，个人不用缴费，只由单位缴费。不过，无论以个人还是单位名义的缴费，其实都是单位用工成本的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所有的五险都是强制性的，但强制的买也是买，既然个人已经买了生育保险，当然就应该在生育时享受相应的产假、生育津贴及生育医疗服务等。如果要附加结婚后生育才能享受这些待遇的前置条件，那就应该给那些不准备结婚但想要孩子的人及不婚也不育的人不购买生育保险的选择权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，容许非婚女性申领生育保险，某种意义上只不过是把她们本应享受的权益归还给她们。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更进一步，婚姻与生育脱钩，既不始于各地容许非婚女性申领生育保险，也不始于各地放开生育登记，而是始于2021年6月26日，中共中央、国务院出台的《关于优化生育政策促进人口长期均衡发展的决定》，这是“全面三孩”落地的纲领性文件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该条款对已婚未婚一体适用。从此以后，未婚生育既免于经济惩罚，也不会影响个人前途。生育与婚姻脱钩。在这个大原则之下，对非婚生育的放松及未婚女性生育应享受权益的恢复，就顺理成章，也令婚姻与生育进一步双向脱钩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或有人说在政策与制度上让婚姻与生育脱钩，会降低结婚意愿与结婚率，甚至会瓦解婚姻家庭。这种说法是值得商榷的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;首先，只要婚姻的实质是男女组成家庭合作抚养孩子并让生存资源向下一代转移，那婚姻永远不会消失，消失的只是婚姻的某种表现形式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对婚姻也不要做狭隘的理解。婚姻通常有两个含义。一种是自然法、习惯法意义上的婚姻，男女按照双方认可的习俗、仪式与条款，举办婚礼，组成家庭，得到双方父母及亲友的认可与祝福，互相进入对方的人际圈子，然后生儿育女，享受各种习惯性权利，非常古老，这是婚姻的实质与泉源。另一种是婚姻登记，其主体与实质部分是确立了夫妻共同财产关系，是进入民族国家时代才有的做法。许多人心目中的婚姻是第二种，但显然第一种更为根本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最近，“90后夫妻结婚3年不领证”引发热议。讲的是九零后夫妻睡睡和张硕从大学校园到结婚，婚礼至今三年却迟迟没有领结婚证。王睡睡表示是因为在婚礼上发生了不好的事，让她对张硕这个人产生了犹豫，所以后面两次领证时都借口没带照片“躲”过了领证，反观张硕的态度却好像并不在意，坦言自己能够理解王睡睡的做法而自己也不是很看重这张证。这算已婚还是未婚同居？媒体用的字眼是“夫妻”。除了没有通过婚姻登记确立夫妻共同财产关系，他们与已婚有什么实质差别吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，就算单身生育，也不意味着一个人抚养孩子，只说明没有婚姻登记而已。就算单身生育且一个人抚养孩子，至少在可见的未来这一模式不会成为主流。婚姻家庭仍是主流，较多见的婚姻家庭模式仍是男性作为家庭主要经济来源，给妻子与子女提供转移支付，这仍是抚养孩子社会成本最低的方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，家庭条件好或个人收入高的女性，如果走入婚姻，在经济上或会女强男弱，只要双方不觉得有什么问题，那就没有什么问题；如果决定单身生育且一个人抚养子女，只要本人不觉得有什么问题，那也就没有问题。生育是一项基本权利，重要的是每个人都享有这个权利；至于具体的个人会不会行使这个权利，看个人的经济条件与价值观。更多的选择权利与选择范围，总是好的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后，自权利而上，婚姻也好，生育也好，说到底是一个价值观的问题。如果说有什么能对婚姻家庭与生育构成挑战，那一定是价值观。一个好的价值观，外显应是对婚姻家庭与生育友好、对母婴与母童友好，并且也看到父亲的付出，基底应是生机勃勃，流淌出生命力旺盛与德性丰沛。由个人而家庭，自家庭而国家，生生不息，绵绵不绝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[揭开岳飞初葬之谜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256548]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-12 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;宋高宗绍兴十一年十二月二十九日（1142年1月27日），岳飞被害于大理寺狱中。二十年后高宗禅位，孝宗登基的次月，绍兴三十二年七月十三日（1162年8月25日），下诏为岳飞平反。随后，迁葬岳飞于西湖之畔的栖霞岭。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，栖霞岭岳墓已成为名胜之地。但岳飞初葬在哪里，却成为千古之谜。笔者最近整理宋元岳庙文献，有所发现，遂缀以成文，分享与同好。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;回顾：钱塘门外与大理寺中&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;先回顾一下已知的历史资料。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平反诏书下达时，岳飞遗体下落不明。八天之后，七月二十一日丙辰，临安府传来消息，找到了岳飞葬地。监察御史周必大在日记《龙飞录》里写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;临安访求岳飞坟，在钱唐门外，当时私号“贾宜人坟”。今将以一品礼葬之。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/On3gRoyh69DODwdZt38o7ze2zwoBQAgpUc9ukjBq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;407&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/On3gRoyh69DODwdZt38o7ze2zwoBQAgpUc9ukjBq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250455&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;周必大《周益文忠公集》卷一百六十四《龙飞录》，清金氏文瑞楼抄本，中国国家图书馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是最早的信息。它表明，作为罪臣的岳飞，是被秘密埋葬的，借“贾宜人坟”之名，以避人耳目。遗憾的是，周必大所记过于简略，只有大致方位——钱塘门外。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年，考古部门在西湖六公园发现钱塘门遗址，并修建了一处别致的景观。遗址前的简介说，这是南宋钱塘门，始建于绍兴十八年（1148）。其实，北宋就有钱塘门了，倒是未见有绍兴十八年建造钱塘门的记载。由于考古发掘报告未公开发表，不知其根据为何。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/1jbO33jumNVpNHNCu6noJRy5HLmAmPnX2mNLbXLV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;948&quot; height=&quot;567&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/1jbO33jumNVpNHNCu6noJRy5HLmAmPnX2mNLbXLV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250456&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;钱塘门遗址。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一条线索见于最早的岳飞传记《岳侯传》，作者不详，撰写于宋孝宗时期，收录在南宋史书《三朝北盟会编》里。其中说：“（岳）侯中毒而卒，葬于临安菜园内。天下闻者，无不垂涕。”没有葬地具体位置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，《宝庆四明志·史浩传》讲：“岳飞忤秦桧，死于棘寺，蒿葬墙角。”蒿葬是说草草埋葬。棘寺即最高审判机构大理寺。现在大都根据明代郎瑛《七修类稿》的说法，指大理寺“在车桥西”，即今小车桥一带。这完全失实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;岳飞被害于大理寺，作为见证历史的重要遗迹，有必要多说几句。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南宋绍兴初，高宗驻跸临安，中央机构随之迁来，大理寺被安置在钱塘县治，县治则迁往纪家桥。大理寺丞游佀《重修大理寺记》说：“六飞（编者注：皇帝车驾六马，疾行如飞，故名）初驻跸，寺以钱塘县治为之。”由于距城门、城墙非常近，所以大理寺司直（官名）陈璧《大理寺新渠记》说：“南渡初，寺在今钱塘门内，枕城一隅。”其地在城门内路北，路南对面是金祝庙，约建于建炎四年（1130）。北边是绍兴十一年兴建的太一宫，再北是十三年兴建的景灵宫。两者都是皇家祭祀重地，尤其景灵宫，供奉历朝先帝，每月都要举行先帝正装出巡的“原庙”仪式。作为刑狱部门，大理寺与之相邻，甚不和谐。于是，绍兴二十年八月五日，高宗下诏将大理寺迁走。诏曰：“大理寺刑狱所在，与景灵宫、太一宫相近，令临安府择空地移置，如法修盖。旧基拨入景灵宫。”后来，大理寺迁到仁和县治之西，景灵宫在此建了一座车马门。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/VmiggOLKK4fezrez5RftT9QO6zXjS2qGvY5YpTAM.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1065&quot; height=&quot;644&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/VmiggOLKK4fezrez5RftT9QO6zXjS2qGvY5YpTAM.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250457&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《咸淳临安志》卷首《京城图》，宋咸淳刻本，中国国家图书馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《咸淳临安志》不仅卷首《京城图》有明确标注，卷五十四还有具体记载：“钱塘县：县治旧在钱塘门里三十步（今景灵宫车马门里是也）。”宋韩淲《涧泉日记》所记略同。步是长度单位，五尺为步。宋代官尺合今31.4厘米，浙尺合27.4厘米。30步约合47或41米。如果现在的钱塘门遗址是南宋初城门的话，则大理寺可以精确定位。六公园北边的风波亭，实在应该迁到这里。只是，遗址简介说城门始建于绍兴十八年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“蒿葬墙角”的说法与周必大日记的“钱塘门外”不符。也许，岳飞被害的当时，曾临时掩埋于大理寺的墙角下，亦未可知。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;演绎：九曲丛祠的演绎&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再往后，《朝野遗记》有一段生动的记载：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;其毙于狱也，实请具浴，拉胁而殂。狱卒隗顺负其尸出，逾城至九曲丛祠中。故至今九曲五显庙尚灵（旧在大理寺墙下）。（隗）顺葬之北山之漘。身素有一玉环，顺亦殉之腰下，树双橘于上识焉。及其死也，谓其子曰：“异时朝廷求而不获，必悬官赏。汝告言曰：棺上一铅筒，有棘寺勒字，吾埋殡之符也。”后果购其瘗不得，以一班职为赏。其子始上告官，悉如所言，而尸色如生，尚可更敛礼服也。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《朝野遗记》成书于宋理宗时代，是一部记录社会传闻的杂记，不能视为信史。比如，作者说二十年后，岳飞的遗体仍然面色如生，收殓时还能穿戴礼服，不合常理。毕竟，作者记载此事时，已是百年之后。而淳熙六年（1179）岳飞之子岳霖在《赐谥谢表》中，有“葬以孤仪，起枯骨于九泉之下”的表述。它与可靠的记载“贾宜人坟”，也无法联系起来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/dwX3xCSaviCfY539saYk6H9IGAYvUn2D5XqCAnPf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;789&quot; height=&quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/dwX3xCSaviCfY539saYk6H9IGAYvUn2D5XqCAnPf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250459&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《朝野遗记》，明末刻《说郛》本。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个故事充满了英雄主义和传奇色彩。且不说背负要犯的尸体逃匿，单单私自翻越城墙，即是流放二千里的重罪。但事件也有合理因素，当时临安城墙已破败不堪，“城壁剥蚀，日就摧毁”，“久不修治，颓损至多”，因此绍兴十二年十月下诏筹备重修。此时负尸逾城，确有很大的成功机会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明万历年间的《杭州府志》《钱塘县志》，都收录了隗顺和九曲丛祠的故事。通常，地方志会记录一些传说，以示重视。而清乾隆年间内府刊刻的史书《御批历代通鉴辑览》也记入此事，意味着中央政府认可为信史。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“北山之漘”和“九曲丛祠”，都是范围较大的地理概念。北山指西湖北山。“漘”即水边。“丛祠”是“草木茂盛的祠庙”，司马迁《史记》就有使用。“九曲”则迄今不甚明晰。南宋文献提到钱塘门外有“九曲下湖”“九曲城”“九曲墙下”“九曲路”。对此有两种解释：一是钱塘门外有一座名为“九曲”的城池。二是它指西湖东北、一堤相隔的下湖水系，东边沿城墙向北蜿蜒至余杭门（即武林门），故称“九曲下湖”，沿水的城墙称“九曲城”。无论如何，至少可以确认，“九曲”指钱塘门外一直到宝石山后的一大片地域。南宋行政区划有“钱塘县履泰乡九曲里”，应该就是这里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/nYIKZwN3OhROeKQjNochTMbZVeWq8Zi9QWA5baTq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;684&quot; height=&quot;477&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/nYIKZwN3OhROeKQjNochTMbZVeWq8Zi9QWA5baTq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250463&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《西湖清趣图》（局部），佚名绘，华盛顿弗利尔艺术馆藏。有人认为，左上部的树林及建筑即九曲城，颇有些望图生义。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;九曲有众多祠庙、寺院，有些特别冠以“九曲”二字，以区别于其他同名祠寺。《朝野遗记》的五显庙，供奉婺源五显神，又称灵顺庙，南宋临安近郊有七座，九曲即为其一。但作者只是说此庙至当时仍然灵验，并未指岳飞葬于此处。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;寄托：众安桥下&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;近七百年后，清道光十二年（1832），一位出差杭州的官员——桐城人吴廷康，偶然听说九曲丛祠的初葬墓仍然存在，在杭州城内众安桥下。随后在咸丰九年募资购得其地。浙江巡抚胡兴仁闻说，决定在此修建一座岳飞祠，并带头捐款。岳祠的建设断断续续，直到同治末，方完成主要建筑，是为忠显庙，现已不存，故址在今岳王路岳飞公园一带。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/l6xvbXfimIGoGcUIb2Yy6jn0PBBice1Kww6NU1C6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;675&quot; height=&quot;515&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/l6xvbXfimIGoGcUIb2Yy6jn0PBBice1Kww6NU1C6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250460&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《杭城西湖江干湖墅图》（局部），清佚名绘，大英博物馆藏。岳庙上方，即清初所修满营城城墙。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这处九曲丛祠的确定，依据是本地父老的口耳相传。宋人记载的“贾宜人坟”“临安菜园”，在这里得到影影绰绰的继承。咸丰九年，杭州知府江士松胡《募修墓祠小引》说：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;九曲丛祠，在今城内众安桥下螺蛳山扁担岭，或呼为扁担衖，或呼为下瓦巷，或呼为菜园是也，相传为王墓。旧有石碑，题“宋贾宜人坟”。今碑虽失，而核之志史及故老传闻，均皆确凿可征。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此地在南宋的临安城内，与宋人的“钱塘门外”不符。口耳相传，显然不能作为依据。当然，这无妨立庙于此，寄托民众对岳飞的景仰与怀念。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/sIXZHG8pZ27oZR5WLEQdIxFzeiXHC1haYEvaoaey.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;856&quot; height=&quot;554&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/sIXZHG8pZ27oZR5WLEQdIxFzeiXHC1haYEvaoaey.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250458&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《杭州岳王真坟》明信片，民国间杭州二我轩发行。此即众安桥忠显庙内岳坟，咸丰十年改长冢为圆坟。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;发现：《中兴礼书》&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;新发现的信息见于《中兴礼书》。这部古籍，历尽坎坷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《中兴礼书》是淳熙七年（1180）孝宗皇帝下诏，命礼部和太常寺编纂的，成书于淳熙十一年（1184），汇编了建炎至淳熙年间关于礼制的中央文件，共三百卷，它从未刊刻，一直以抄本形态存于内府。清代以后失传。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所幸，明永乐年间编写《永乐大典》时，几乎抄录了全部《中兴礼书》，分散在各卷中。《永乐大典》现存仅约4%，其中抄录《中兴礼书》只有4处，远无法看到原书的面貌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;又所幸，清嘉庆年间，翰林院编修、上虞人徐松参与编纂《全唐文》，借机从《永乐大典》中辑录出《中兴礼书》。后来他将抄校稿交给文渊阁校理、顺德人龙元任，因为龙家有一副木活字，承诺摆印出版。此后，龙氏调任四川，携书稿至任所，不久故世，书稿遂下落不明。道光十六年（1836），嘉兴钱聚仁改任四川彭山知县，赴任途经重庆府，在书肆发现书稿。他曾担任武英殿校录，见过此稿，知道它的珍贵，于是“急购以归”。可最终，钱聚仁的藏书也失传了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再所幸，海宁藏书家蒋光焴，从钱聚仁处借抄了一部，海盐藏书家沈炳垣帮助作了整理编排。咸丰二年（1852），沈炳垣作跋，记录了手稿流传的经过，附在书前。这部抄本现藏中国国家图书馆，计32册、247卷。此外，国家图书馆还收藏有据蒋本抄录的另一个抄本。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/fGInILAWypqGeinzDELsX17Xw5040hyYyzQmdWbV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;507&quot; height=&quot;1010&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/fGInILAWypqGeinzDELsX17Xw5040hyYyzQmdWbV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250461&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《中兴礼书》，清蒋光焴抄本，中国国家图书馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;涉及岳飞初葬的记载，见《中兴礼书》卷二百九十八《凶礼》六十三《诏葬》二，原文如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（绍兴三十二年八月）八日，礼部言：“准都省札子，奉圣旨：&#39;故岳飞起自行伍，不逾数年位至将相，而能事上以忠，御众有法，屡立功效，不自矜夸。余烈遗风，至今不泯。去冬出戍，鄂渚之众师行不扰，动有纪律，道路之人，归功于飞。飞虽坐事以殁，而太上皇帝念之不忘，今可仰承圣意，与追复元官，以礼改葬，访求其后，特与录用。&#39;本部寻下太常寺勘会。去后，据本寺申：&#39;寻会到所属本官元系少保、武胜定国军节度使、万寿观使，见在临安府钱塘门外宝叔塔后、地名霍山墓园内埋葬。本寺契勘，本官依令系正一品，今欲乞令临安府奏官一员，踏逐高原之地，依丧葬令格式，以正一品礼如法改葬。&#39;”诏：依。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是绍兴三十二年八月八日礼部上奏的请示，称为“申状”。“礼部言”之后即申状全文。“准都省札子”，意思是“遵照尚书省下发的通知”。以下引用通知内容，即七月十三日为岳飞平反的圣旨。接着说：本部随即通知太常寺商议。随后引太常寺商议后的请示，要点是：岳飞葬地已经找到，请求命临安府派员勘访一处墓地，以正一品官员的规格改葬。最后是孝宗皇帝批示：同意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;  礼部掌管礼乐制度和相关重大事务；太常寺则负责办理具体事宜，级别低于礼部。这份文件的性质，决定了它的内容毋庸置疑。它也可与周必大日记互为印证。只是，日记里是最初得到的消息，此件是履行程序后正式上奏的公文及批复，日期在其后第十六天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;太常寺状明确提到，岳飞葬地在“钱塘门外宝叔塔后、地名霍山墓园内”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;徜徉：古今霍山&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;那么，霍山在哪里？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;霍山是座很小的山，在宝石山东北，属宝石山余脉，也是西湖北山的东北尽头。其名最早见于北宋初的《吴越备史》，历代杭州方志都有明确记录。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山上有一处天然泉水，叫“涌泉”。后晋天福五年（940），旁边建起一座寺院，北宋治平二年（1065），敕赐庙额“清心院”。这是岳飞被害那年，山上唯一有记载的寺院。涌泉从清心院门前的石缝中涌出，“味极清甘，亢旱不竭”，高宗每天都要派人到此取水煮茶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/LNv1gr5Dot1j1jLIHXDTiAa11h0Z8QOg55fwBKj2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;578&quot; height=&quot;745&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/LNv1gr5Dot1j1jLIHXDTiAa11h0Z8QOg55fwBKj2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250462&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《咸淳临安志》卷首《西湖图》，宋咸淳刻本，中国国家图书馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;乾道四年（1168），清心院东创建了一座广惠庙，供奉广德王张渤，又称张王庙、霍山祠，落成于绍熙五年（1194）。广惠庙盛极一时，给霍山带来巨大声誉。每年二月初八，士女倾城而出，到此游拜，各色游艺活动争奇斗艳，《武林旧事》《梦粱录》都有详尽的描写。当时诗人也多有歌咏之作。《西湖图》在极其逼仄的空间里，不但标注了张王庙，还画出图示。可惜庙废于元代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;元代，山上建了一座庆忌塔，高丈余，形制似壶，俗称“壶瓶塔”。因此山又被称为“庆忌塔山”。明人认为它是春秋时吴王子庆忌的墓塔。《西湖游览志》将它与《咸淳临安志》记载的庆忌宅混为一谈，大误。康熙三年（1664）庆忌塔倒塌，里面有数千枚“擦擦”（Tsha-Tsha，藏语对梵语的音译，藏传佛教的模制小泥塔）。《康熙钱塘县志》认为是元代番僧所造，用以镇水怪，“庆忌”是水怪之名，很有道理。此塔应是元至元十四年（1277）番僧杨琏真珈担任江南释教都总统，藏传佛教在杭州流行以后的产物。壶形塔，也是藏传佛教的特征。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/JYTS8ecrWD7mri6EjCQ6GlcQepcvhEMpf43ggJZR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;924&quot; height=&quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/JYTS8ecrWD7mri6EjCQ6GlcQepcvhEMpf43ggJZR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250465&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《万历钱塘县志》卷首《钱塘县疆图》（局部），明万历刻本，日本内阁文库藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《万历杭州府志》对有一段稍详的描述：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;霍山于湖北诸山最小，山形多骨，石笋鳞起，与巨石山类。濒湖诸山，至此为断壤矣。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;明《成化杭州府志》记载，山北崖下有石潭，水色澄莹，深不可测。后人又称有三个石池。其一方圆三四亩，以回声称奇，声如小儿啼哭，俗称“哇哇宕”。清康熙年间，山又改称“棋盘山”，最早见康熙十年（1671）张岱的《西湖梦寻》。稍后，陆次云《湖壖杂记·棋盘山哇哇荡》也有描写，绘声绘色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/6PtfxGrKTVs5CimpDDh83zOS2Cf9VYvxI8oShOtR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;931&quot; height=&quot;573&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/6PtfxGrKTVs5CimpDDh83zOS2Cf9VYvxI8oShOtR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250464&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《杭城西湖江干湖墅图》（局部），清佚名绘，大英博物馆藏。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;光绪三年（1877）秋，般若庵僧人释妙然化缘募资，购下山北地段，拟刻《弥陀经》于崖壁。次年春刚有眉目时，不幸病逝。信士沈善登、许灵虚，护国寺释成方、上虞旌教寺释玉峰等继其业，光绪七年刻成。字大六寸，涂以泥金，蔚为壮观。山门、大殿、僧舍等陆续至光绪十八年完工。随后，欲入京请赐额“光寿讲寺”，以不得其人未果，大家便称之为弥陀寺。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/nFp59703FtnRFjmWINvB4mkGl0BvIQQsuKR8bVbT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;899&quot; height=&quot;543&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/nFp59703FtnRFjmWINvB4mkGl0BvIQQsuKR8bVbT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250466&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;弥陀寺摩崖石刻《弥陀经》。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;弥陀寺香火甚盛，以至于霍山再次更名，被称为“弥陀山”，并沿用至今。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/rEhCxnticabzioA6eEwtN026n37UnzDdGjxxUDMX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;951&quot; height=&quot;622&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/rEhCxnticabzioA6eEwtN026n37UnzDdGjxxUDMX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250467&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《实测杭州西湖图》（局部），1929年上海商务印书馆出版。图中弥陀山标高64米，系按1916年浙江省陆军测量局确定的、以杭州紫微园天文点为海拔50米假定高程计算，折合现行海拔标准22.9米。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/F2Dkh38H0dEkyegHmKKbeEcfvAGoynws6eH0DOn6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;940&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/F2Dkh38H0dEkyegHmKKbeEcfvAGoynws6eH0DOn6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250469&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;今日弥陀山。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在的山体，呈西北、东南走向，海拔22米。东西约六十米，南北约二百米，只是百年前的一半，更远非绍兴十一年的面貌了。明代的“石笋鳞起”，尚略略可见。凸起的制高点巨石上，有“南无阿弥陀佛”几个大字，刻于光绪二年，已是山上最久的遗迹。它的旁边，近年重建了庆忌塔。西北的弥陀寺被修葺一新，成为开放式的弥陀寺公园，崖壁上的《弥陀经》完好无缺。三个石池尚存其二，包括山北的哇哇宕，但规模已小，回音亦不可闻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3BAFp8lIIwlGDqJm3G9bg1SMCnaGPmKCWhkfhMXT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;959&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/12/3BAFp8lIIwlGDqJm3G9bg1SMCnaGPmKCWhkfhMXT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250468&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;山北石池——哇哇宕。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一代英灵，曾安厝于此21年。流连山中，忽然想到，霍山在南宋也属“九曲”的范围。那一刻，我觉得隗顺的传说一定是个真实的事件……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 12 Sep 2023 22:25:23 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>