<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“飞越”按摩店：两位盲人的择业折返跑]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258668]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blind masseur Sun Jingrui is massaging a customer. Photo by Wang Xinyi&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/34b826dd72.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/15/34b826dd72.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254113&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Blind masseur Sun Jingrui is massaging a customer. Photo by Wang Xinyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Wenfeng&#39;s 15-year career as a blind masseur can be divided into two periods: in the first period he struggled with &quot;what can a blind person do&quot;, and in the latter period was he answering &quot;what can I do&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interval was a two-year escape - in 2019, he decided to escape from the blind employment paradigm and worked as a barista and telephone recruiter in Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about the same time, another blind masseur, Sun Jingrui, also chose to run away. After they briefly crossed paths in Guangzhou, the two lifelines bifurcated again, but they ended up reaching the same destination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 31, Ren Wenfeng returned to his hometown of Huanggang, Hubei Province and reopened a massage parlor in the small county town. He and his wife manage the small shop, which is about 40 square meters, and entertain three or four customers every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;34-year-old Sun Jingrui also returned to the massage parlor, but he chose to work in the metropolis Guangzhou. His store is also closer to the consumption perception of modern urbanites: warm yellow lighting, the fragrance of essential oils, supplemented by Mindfulness meditation. When there are not many customers, Jingrui will write plans or go out to connect resources, like an entrepreneur, thinking about how to build more chain stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation, as of 2020, there are 17,300 blind health massage institutions in China. In the common discussion of &quot;What can blind people do without massages?&quot; Ren Wenfeng and Sun Jingrui may have many answers to this question, but one thing is for sure, although returning to a massage parlor may not seem to fit the mainstream narrative, it is Doesn&#39;t mean &quot;failed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Falling into Darkness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ren Wenfeng and Sun Jingrui are both acquired blind people, which means that they need one more layer of psychological construction than congenitally blind people. They want to eliminate all their once-visible selves, as well as their past thoughts, and learn to live in darkness from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was 8 years old, a wooden stick flew in while playing and changed the direction of Ren Wenfeng’s life. The surgery failed to save his vision, and retinal detachment was a gradual farewell, which was more painful than a sudden plunge into darkness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He began to worry about his future life: Will he have to rely on his parents for the rest of his life? How will I support myself in the future? These questions all point to the same thing: What can a blind person do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day during the summer vacation, he listened to a radio program that introduced summer training classes to people. He called and asked: &quot;What can blind people do?&quot; The other party told him that he should contact the local Disabled Persons&#39; Federation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, the process of Sun Jingrui&#39;s blindness is like a person struggling in the water. When he was in junior high school, he was diagnosed with retinal detachment. Because it is discovered late, surgery is difficult to reverse the damage, which is almost equivalent to being declared blind. The doctor suggested that he go to a school for the blind to adapt to his future outcome in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Sun Jingrui decided to race against his eyesight. He wanted to get into a good university before he lost his sight, so that he could &quot;choose a major that is not too hard on the eyes and continue to live a normal life.&quot; Before suffering from eye disease, Sun Jingrui’s dream was to major in mechanical engineering at South China University of Technology. This was a place where he could realize his dream of becoming an engineer. But in his sophomore year of high school, the fog in front of his eyes became thicker and thicker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2006 was the year of Sun Jingrui&#39;s college entrance examination. The girl he had a crush on would call him and ask him &quot;When will he come back to class?&quot; She had sorted out the class content and was waiting for him. Sun Jingrui said vaguely &quot;next month.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui could not wait until the day he returned to the classroom. With the disappearance of the last bit of light, he became completely blind. He no longer dares to go out for fear that others will notice the strangeness of his eyeballs. Occasionally, once he goes out every few months, he will outline the surrounding environment in his mind and turn his head frequently, trying to act like he was before he lost his sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For discerning people, career planning is a process of continuous focus: &quot;study-weigh-choose&quot;, and finally choose the track you are best at. But for blind people, massage parlors are one of the most common secular choices and one of the few stable careers for this special group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Blind massage parlors are like blind paths in the city, existing but not noticeable. They are scattered throughout the city, set up at street intersections, on the first floor of residential buildings, or between barber shops and grocery stores. Most stores are simply furnished, with a few lamps, a few beds, and one or two chairs placed in fixed locations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Wenfeng’s first massage parlor job was in Wuhan, and he was contacted by the Disabled Persons’ Federation in his hometown. The massage shop is located on the second floor of a residential area. Four beds and two sofas are squeezed into the 20-square-meter house. At night, he called his mother and complained: &quot;It&#39;s too shabby. I want to turn around and leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But he persisted in the end: &quot;As long as there is a job that a blind person can do, anything can be done.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, Ren Wenfeng came to Shanghai from Wuhan. When customers at the massage parlor talked about urban life, Ren Wenfeng stood aside with envy. In his world, the busiest moment in Shanghai is the store celebration in June. The heat wave carries the crowds, sending the noise and footsteps into the store. The masseurs are busy amidst the waves of people&#39;s voices and the sounds of watches. . After the store celebration, the crowd dispersed, leaving the masseur in the dark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the time is monotonous: working from 8 a.m. to 11 p.m., food and accommodation are included in the store, and most of the time is spent waiting. Time just slipped between the thick and deformed fingers. In the view of Ren Wenfeng at the time, &quot;This is a job with no future, or even a present.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ren Wenfeng first worked, his slender and soft hands with clear joints were evaluated as &quot;a pair of hands that can be used to play the piano&quot;; now, after more than ten years in the massage industry, Ren Wenfeng&#39;s His fingers became as thick as a rolling pin. &quot;A hand that specializes in massage,&quot; someone praised him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Sun Jingrui has also noticed changes in his body. The muscles on the back of the hand are broad and thick, and the top of the thumb nail is slightly buckled due to years of exertion. The skin connected to the nail has shed its skin and is slightly white. In Guangzhou, he relieves the pressure on the shoulders and necks of many white-collar workers who sit in offices for a long time, but his own cervical vertebrae are tingling due to long-term fixed posture massage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui is unwilling to live in a traditional massage shop. Pictures of the lives of discerning people in the past remind him from time to time. If he cannot return to the world of discerning people, he must at least make achievements in the massage industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sun Jingrui&#39;s thumb tip is peeling. Photo by Wang Xinyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/537b790619 .png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;877&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/537b790619.png&quot; data-key =&quot;254114&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Jingrui’s thumb tip is peeling. Photo by Wang Xinyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Beyond Making a Living&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Internet is one of the common channels for visually impaired people to contact the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2018, Ren Wenfeng learned about the &quot;Coffee in the Palm&quot; project of Hemu Innovation Center, a non-profit organization in Guangzhou, through an online forum. This is an activity to train visually impaired people to learn hand-brewed coffee skills and become baristas. As the road was being built in front of the store and business was not booming, Ren Wenfeng closed the massage parlor operating in Wuhan and went to Guangzhou to study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yingzhang, the head of Hemu Innovation Center, was deeply impressed by him: &quot;I resigned from Wuhan and occasionally do some part-time jobs to supplement my income.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Sun Jingrui also used the Internet to The community gained access to the &quot;Dialogue Academy&quot; project organized by &quot;Dialogue in the Dark&quot;, a Hong Kong social enterprise. He sold the massage parlor he was running and went to Hong Kong alone for training as one of the six members who passed the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike Ren Wenfeng who started his career with massage, Sun Jingrui had the consciousness of entering the &quot;mainstream workplace&quot; when he just lost his eyesight. With good English, he once sought opportunities to work as an interpreter through a hotline program on a radio station. This experience ended in failure, which shattered his illusions about employment for the visually impaired. Returning to the field of massage, he also considered entering a hospital. But &quot;total blindness&quot; once again prevented him from getting a stable and decent job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem goes far beyond that. Finding a position that accepts visually impaired people is the first step. After entering the workplace, the challenge really begins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After becoming blind, more than ten years of experience in massage parlors affected Ren Wenfeng&#39;s character. Sensitivity and low self-esteem were the biggest challenges he faced in the &quot;mainstream workplace&quot;. When he was a barista, some customers would initiate conversations, but he could only respond with silence. In Ren Wenfeng&#39;s narration, his perception of the &quot;mainstream world&quot; is contradictory: like a mirror: on the polished surface facing outward, he wants to be recognized and prove that he &quot;can also accomplish many things&quot;; on the coated surface It is his timidity, he is afraid that others will notice his &quot;difference&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hong Kong, in order to adapt to the teacher&#39;s rhythm and language environment, Sun Jingrui needs to listen to class recordings repeatedly. &quot;Going to bed at two or three in the morning, and getting up again at six or seven in the morning, because class starts at eight.&quot; During the course, he was deeply touched by two parts. The first part is &quot;self-advocacy&quot;, where visually impaired students learn how to seek help in the workplace; the second part is skills training, including holding regular meetings, taking notes, organizing activities, etc. These ordinary people&#39;s daily work content is very new in Sun Jingrui&#39;s eyes. &quot;There is no such thing in a massage parlor.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When visually impaired people choose other jobs, they always subconsciously compare them with the massage industry. They use the massage industry as a frame of reference to view the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the practical part of the course in Hong Kong, Sun Jingrui needed to design workshops and course content alone in a social enterprise. With the help of his instructor, he gradually grew from an initial &quot;facilitator&quot; to an &quot;implementer&quot; of the project. By&quot;. He gradually discovered: &quot;I can actually do a lot of things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from Sun Jingrui&#39;s discovery of &quot;what he can do&quot; in the workplace, Ren Wenfeng&#39;s experience as a barista made him discover &quot;what he cannot or cannot do&quot; What do you like to do?&quot; Looking back now, Ren Wenfeng feels that knowing &quot;what not to do&quot; is the beginning of career planning - in this sense, although he failed to become an excellent barista, this experience is not a failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the limited income of a barista, Ren Wenfeng wanted to do something else. His second job is telephone recruitment: 30 phone calls a day that last for more than 30 seconds, corresponding to a basic salary of more than 1,000 yuan; if the other party is willing to submit a resume and successfully joins the job, he will receive a commission. According to Ren Wenfeng&#39;s rough statistics, the call answering rate is about 50%, which means that at least 60 calls need to be made every day. What is more difficult to control is that most of the answerers will hang up the phone in about 10 seconds. Rejection is normal, and what makes Ren Wenfeng even more unbearable are those unfriendly words. After a few months, Ren Wenfeng&#39;s performance was at the bottom of the group because he was not good at speaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Sun Jingrui also experienced telephone recruitment work. He summarized the job as &quot;repetitive&quot; and &quot;boring&quot;: &quot;I keep saying repetitive words every day, and even get scolded.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Guo Siyuan, a teacher at the School of Humanities and Social Sciences of the Zhongkai College of Agricultural Engineering: &quot;The uneven quality of education for blind people is the pain point that restricts the employment of people with disabilities.&quot; Ren Wenfeng also described the problems encountered in the &quot;mainstream workplace&quot; The embarrassment is attributed to the lack of education. Blind people only need to learn the skills of living. As for spiritual nourishment and interpersonal communication skills such as literature, history and philosophy, it seems not so important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sun Jingrui&#39;s &quot;Healing Time&quot; store uses warm yellow as the main color. Photo by Wang Xinyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/da8b8d691c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/da8b8d691c. png&quot; data-key=&quot;254115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Jingrui&#39;s &quot;Healing Time&quot; store uses warm yellow as the main color. Photo by Wang Xinyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Seeing” myself&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2021, after returning to Huanggang from Guangzhou, Ren Wenfeng started a family. Now the massage parlor he runs is facing the road, with a small yard behind it. Although it cannot be seen, he bought green plants and table lamps and carefully arranged this imaginary space. In his free time, he would make himself a cup of coffee with the sound of wind chimes and sunshine, waiting for customers and learning something new at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I returned to the massage parlor because I didn’t feel safe enough.” Ren Wenfeng said, “Many jobs are not only unstable, but may also have no income at all.” The stable income brought by massage parlors means that he Be able to feel more confident in front of parents, loved ones and neighbors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Take what you have learned back and open a store. This may be Wenfeng&#39;s most practical choice.&quot; Liu Yingzhang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the rush of big cities, small cities are more casual. The guests communicated with Ren Wenfeng about the details of the massage in their hometown dialect. Sometimes Ren Wenfeng would take the initiative to ask the guests &quot;does it hurt?&quot; He was no longer content to be a silent backdrop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui’s store in Guangzhou opened in 2022. The store staff are partners who met during charity activities, and are supported by startup resources from the Hemu Innovation Center. The concept of the store is to use mindfulness to guide customers to observe their bodies, highlighting the masseurs Masseurs gain recognition through their professional skills and techniques, and no longer rely on selling essential oils and other peripheral products to gain value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of colleague Zhang Jinlan, Sun Jingrui&#39;s attempt to break through traditional massage parlors is &quot;very meaningful.&quot; Many customers will give gifts to the visually impaired masseuses in return, and will also hold their hands and show them the gifts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;White-collar workers like to call Jing Rui by his English name Ray, and some customers call him &quot;dolphin&quot;. He said he likes this nickname: when humans are drowning, dolphins will lift humans to the surface of the water. In daily life, Jingrui is willing to enlighten his visually impaired friends and lift them out of the &quot;ocean&quot; of emotions. Whenever Zhang Jinlan encounters difficulties at work, Sun Jingrui will list the key points and reason with her one by one. &quot;He is a partner who can fight side by side.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui hopes to help more visually impaired people to see outside, but &quot;support&quot; alone is often somewhat ineffective. He is too embarrassed to persuade directly, and sometimes adopts &quot;circumstantial tactics&quot;. For example, he pretends to be relaxed and says to his friends: &quot;There is a speech club tomorrow, who is free to go and play together?&quot; Friends will find it very novel, but once they arrive, When it came time to perform on stage, they felt &quot;too shy to do it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui also faced such a dilemma. In Liu Yingzhang&#39;s view, Sun Jingrui is considered the &quot;elite&quot; of this group. When he first came to the center to participate in an event, Sun Jingrui wore sunglasses and greeted everyone in fluent English. This &quot;big brother&quot; temperament left a deep impression on Liu Yingzhang at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At work, Sun Jingrui initially had the inertia of &quot;relying on discerning managers&quot;. Currently, the Hemu Innovation Center&#39;s &quot;Palm Coffee&quot; and &quot;Healing Time&quot; massage parlor projects are managed by visually impaired people, who independently lead visually impaired and non-visually impaired employees to participate in market competition. Models of leadership for people with disabilities are fundamentally different. They hope that this model can break the prejudice that visually impaired people can only play subordinate roles in the workplace. One day, with a little guidance, they can actively explore the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sun Jingrui&#39;s personal photos widely circulated on the Internet. Internet pictures&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15 /bd761597be.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/bd761597be.png&quot; data -key=&quot;254116&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Jingrui’s personal photo that is widely circulated on the Internet. Internet pictures&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a photo widely circulated on the Internet, Sun Jingrui is wearing a white shirt, jeans, and sunglasses, holding his chin with one hand, showing his trademark toothy smile. But the image of himself in his memory stayed before the age of 18. Jingrui’s dream is that one day in the future, his eyesight will be restored, and he will be able to see with his own eyes what his partners look like and what he will look like in professional attire. look. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight : bold;&quot;>;(Chen Xin, Liu Yingzhang and Deepin Training Camp also contributed to this article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我们该以什么姿态面对“牺牲者”丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258658]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/z03yFnCJiTOLmMoGQ3hWWPydrAH9HG48GZcsUjV2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1063&quot; height=&quot;681&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/z03yFnCJiTOLmMoGQ3hWWPydrAH9HG4 8GZcsUjV2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254109&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;He Xie (left) and his friends when he was young. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, I went to Aoluguya Ewenki Autonomous Prefecture on the outskirts of Genhe City, Inner Mongolia Interviews with the village revealed that the Ewenki people had moved there for 20 years. The biggest change for the Ewenki people in this relocation is the ban on guns. This meant the end of their traditional safari life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was wandering around the countryside and talking to people about guns. A bystander immediately gave me directions: I have to ask Boss He for this. Who else knows better than him? There was a hint of teasing in the tone - at the time, I didn&#39;t know what the story was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not difficult to find Mr. He. Most of the time, he and his wife Zhuo Ye sit quietly on the bench in front of their home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Boss He&#39;s real name is He Xie, the eldest son of &quot;China&#39;s last female chief&quot; Maria Suo, and the last generation of hunters among the Ewenki people. As soon as I arrived in front of his house, he invited me to sit down and opened a bottle of Hyrule beer for me, which was his way of hospitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later I learned that the gun caused He Xie trouble just last year. When he collected his guns around 2003, he hid a small-caliber gun and sold it to someone else in 2022. After being reported, the court sentenced him for reselling firearms. He Xie couldn&#39;t figure out how the verdict was written, but he remembered that it was &quot;a second sentence with a three-year reprieve&quot; and his pension was gone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fortunately, He Xie doesn’t care about money that much, as long as it’s enough. The couple lives on Zhuoye&#39;s monthly pension of more than 4,000 yuan, and they are a &quot;moonlight family&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A friend of He Xie told me about what happened not long ago. Some time ago, He Xie borrowed 500 yuan from him and said he wanted to use it to repay the money. As a result, He Xie paid back the debt of more than 100 yuan, and the remaining money was spent on braised beef and beer. The couple bought more than 300 pieces of meat, but they didn&#39;t eat much of it, so they fed it all to the dogs in the village. &quot;Isn&#39;t this a waste of money?&quot; This friend was somewhat angry when he mentioned this. He also had nothing to do with He Xie, &quot;This guy doesn&#39;t worry about anything!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of He Xie&#39;s actions were really helpless. During the interview, He Xie and others, I went back to the old Ao Township before the relocation, and stayed in a nearby B&amp;B that night. Even though the no-smoking notice was prominently posted in the lobby of the B&amp;B, He Xie still started smoking as if no one was around. A fellow traveler advised him to go out and smoke, but he persisted again: What&#39;s wrong with having a cigarette? The rules of modern society are basically invalid for him. The owner of the B&amp;B had to remind us repeatedly that we must check He Xie&#39;s stay and that there must be no smoking in the room. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Aoxiang, he became a type of person who &quot;has not made progress&quot;. Bai Lan, a researcher at the Institute of Ethnology of the Inner Mongolia Academy of Social Sciences, has been following the Ewenki people for more than 30 years and has become old friends with He Xie&#39;s family. She told me that in July 2023, she went to Aoxiang to participate in a tourism forum. When he met He Xie, he was almost done drinking. The township head quickly asked the staff to send him home. &quot;With so many leaders coming, (worried) He Xie would be embarrassed to leave him there.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before leaving Aoxiang, I planned to say goodbye to He Xie. As soon as he entered the door, he was lying in the room with his head down and sleeping. Zhuoye told me that He Xie had been lying in bed all day. Two days ago, he had guests. He was happy and drank heavily. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After returning to Beijing, I read &quot;Aoluguya·Aoluguya&quot; written by the documentary director Gu Tao, which is a collection of his diaries while filming the &quot;Ewenki Trilogy&quot;. The He Xie described in the book looked completely different to me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Gu Tao&#39;s book, he is the &quot;little leader&quot; who has the dignity of a hunter in the mountains. &quot;When sawing deer antler, He Xie always had to take a few sips at the blood spurting antler, his eyes narrowed, his hair curly, and his face splattered with blood. Others would be frightened when they saw it, but he enjoyed it very much. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the hunter&#39;s point, He Xie&#39;s aura can calm those who steal wine. &quot;Weijia and Mao Xie (both are Ewenki hunters) did not go looking for deer, but took a ride to Aaron Mountain to look for wine. At noon, Mao Xie and Weijia came back drunk, and when they saw Boss He, they hid quietly back I fell asleep in my own tent.&quot; &quot;As long as He Xie is on point, Mariasuo won&#39;t worry.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;I can’t help but think, if they still had guns and could go hunting in the mountains, why would the association be different from its current status? Of course, this is just an invalid assumption. It will happen sooner or later that the Ewenki people, who have only one to two hundred people, will be integrated into the modernization process. There will always be one or two generations among them who will become victims in this process. Their previous generation had fully enjoyed life in the mountains and forests, while the next generation, without so much baggage, had discovered new ways of living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some scholars believe that from the perspective of national governance, this is a sacrifice that must be made. The rational attitude is to remember those who sacrificed and provide them and future generations with certain compensation. &quot;This is reality.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;Bai Lan said that she has been thinking about how to give the Ewenki people more freedom of choice in the development process and allow the tradition to continue. However, she still has no conclusion yet. &quot;As a researcher, sometimes I feel like I have failed.&quot; My heart skipped a beat when I heard Bai Lan say this. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a reporter, all I can do is record the current living conditions of the &quot;victims&quot; and resist forgetting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/CoPO3sir3sJ83J1WYSZA9THj2LsdK3ILWHYsS49V.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1073&quot; height= &quot;771&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/CoPO3sir3sJ83J1WYSZA9THj2LsdK3ILWHYsS49V.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254108&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of July 23, 2023, He Xie sat on the curb in the settlement and drank. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[民政部：去年办理结婚登记683.5万对，比上年下降10.6％]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258666]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/07130c1404f69430cfe64d18eafb5200.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;597&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/15/07130c1404f69430cfe64d18eafb5200.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254111&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days ago, the Ministry of Civil Affairs released the 2022 Statistical Bulletin on the Development of Civil Affairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The statistical bulletin shows that in 2022, there were a total of 4,310 marriage registration institutions and venues across the country, including 1,103 marriage registration institutions. 6.835 million marriages were registered in accordance with the law throughout the year, a decrease of 10.6% from the previous year. The marriage rate was 4.8‰, down 0.6 percentage points from the previous year. There were 2.879 million divorce procedures handled in accordance with the law, an increase of 1.4% over the previous year, of which 2.100 million divorces were registered by the civil affairs department and 779,000 divorces were adjudicated or mediated by the courts. The divorce rate is 2.0‰. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a638596c90088e4bd210897dc1617082.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a638596c90088e4bd210897dc1617082.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254110&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/f2f977d08aa0a8ce648a89a5e59f8330.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/f2f977d08aa0a8ce648a89a5e59f8330.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254112&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[关于幸福这件事：与“哈佛最受欢迎讲师”沙哈尔谈反脆弱和东方哲学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258577]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/CMxvsLqwcXUy58dsdIxC7UQoClDSXwLnJuFcG6zF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/CMxvsLqwcXUy58dsdIxC7UQoCl DSXwLnJuFcG6zF. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253690&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Shen Yu/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2002, Tyler Ben-Shahar, a young, reserved psychology Ph.D., stood in the classroom at Harvard University and gave his first lecture on &quot;Positive Psychology.&quot; At that time, only eight students took his course, and two more dropped out midway. He persisted. In an empty classroom, he discusses with six students once a week the ultimate question of life - how to make himself and others happier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;By the second academic year, the number of students taking the course increased to 380, and more than 20% of students reported that this course had improved their personal lives; in the second semester of the academic year, 855 Harvard students took the course this course. Within a year, Shahar&#39;s positive psychology course became Harvard&#39;s most popular course, and his other course, &quot;The Psychology of Leadership,&quot; was also one of the school&#39;s most popular courses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This young scholar who just stood on the podium has become one of the most popular mentors in Harvard history. Driven by the spirit of sharing, since 2006, the &quot;Positive Psychology&quot; he teaches (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;is also known as the Happiness Course&lt;/span>; ) was filmed and made into a public course and open to the Internet for free. Its influence quickly overflowed from the Harvard campus and was watched, downloaded, and shared by countless people around the world. Together with Michael Sandel, a Harvard political science professor who teaches a course on justice, Shahar has become a world-renowned scholar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Shahar, 53, was born and raised in Israel. His ancestors were Jewish businessmen living in Europe. During the Zionist movement of the last century, they brought their families back to the &quot;Promised Land&quot; given by God. In Shahar’s childhood memories, his grandfather, a businessman, would spend hours every day studying the Hebrew Bible and Talmud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to the influence of orthodox Jewish culture, his childhood was also shrouded in the clouds of bloody violence and terrorist incidents in the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. &quot;Every morning when we wake up, we worry about bombs on the bus going to school; when we go to the restaurant to eat, we worry about the restaurant being bombed,&quot; he recalled calmly. His first memory of the war came from the sirens outside his window when he was less than 3 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Childhood memories and the tenacity of his parents and grandparents left an indelible impression on Shahar. After studying in the United States and achieving academic success, he resigned from his position at Harvard and returned to his native Israel to establish the &quot;Happiness Research Institute&quot; to promote positive psychology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While studying at Harvard, he studied Chinese philosophy with the famous Chinese scholar Du Weiming. Confucian humanism and Taoist thought made him feel both familiar and &quot;illuminated&quot; by wisdom. In the process of promoting and developing positive psychology, he also drew theoretical and practical wisdom from traditional Chinese classics such as the Tao Te Ching, the Analects of Confucius, and the Great Learning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the outbreak of the new crown epidemic, Shahar came to China to give lectures on average twice a year. The &quot;Happiness Research Institute&quot; he founded had more than 400 students in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After four years, he visited China again at the end of September 2023. In a Shanghai hotel full of quirky 1990s style elements, we discussed trauma, antifragility, Confucianism and Taoism, and how to overcome PTSD (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Trauma &quot;Post-Stress Disorder&quot;&lt;/span>;) and to discuss topics such as growth, he was interviewed by me, a Chinese journalist who is partially skeptical of &quot;happiness science&quot; and instrumental methodologies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/w7Y894iV4LPPLjmkqLk3Qpe60cvMnPnWW9i6SQ6P.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/w7Y894iV4LPPLjmkqLk3Qpe60cvMnPnWW9i6SQ6P.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253681&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On March 27, 2020, due to the impact of the new crown epidemic, the training hall was closed. A mother accompanied her child to train in the community&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;No one is an island - how to deal with trauma and helplessness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Compared with four years ago, this time when you meet and communicate with your students, collaborators and academic colleagues, have you noticed the spiritual and psychological outlook of the Chinese people? Are there some changes? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I feel some. However, what I experienced and observed in China is not unique to China. The past three years have been challenging for people and they have become more anxious, sadder and more worried than before. The challenge we face is not just how to overcome anxiety, sadness, or worry, but also how to potentially become stronger after experiencing it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That’s why the science of happiness is so important today, because it provides us with tools, tips and advice to help us potentially become stronger after going through hardships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the past four years, have you paid attention to the society from China? Psychological investigation reports, or any exchanges on related issues with Chinese psychology colleagues? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2021, during the epidemic, I had a conversation with Professor Peng Kaiping of Tsinghua University. We found that cultural differences certainly exist, but from a global perspective, people are more similar than different. Chinese, like Americans, Brazilians, Germans, and Australians, all have more differences than in the past. Feelings of security and anxiety. The global pandemic affects people in every corner of the world. So, that&#39;s why psychologists, political leaders need to work together to find solutions to the problem. That’s why I’m so looking forward to speaking with Professor Peng again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What kind of societies did you talk about during the epidemic? Psychological problems? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;We talked about a new concept proposed by New York University professor Nassim Nicholas Taleb - &quot;antifragility&quot; , is about how it is possible for us to grow after experiencing hardship, hardship, or trauma. Repair is just returning to the past state. We should also grow from the experience, not PTSD, but PTG (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 混体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;post-traumatic growth&quot;&lt;/ span>;). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, most people do not grow after experiencing trauma. They either suffer from PTSD or other forms of psychological problems, such as anxiety, loss of security, sadness, and even depression. . So, the real question is: What can our schools, institutions, and families do to help everyone increase the likelihood of getting PTG, and what can we do to improve antifragile capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A well-known psychologist put forward an insight. He said : In China, social psychology and cultural psychology are and will continue to be the mainstream of psychological research in the future, because the mental state of Chinese people is almost determined by the era in which they live; while in the United States, clinical psychology is Mainstream, because Americans always want to find a doctor to solve his/her individual mental crisis, such as why he/she just feels unhappy. In these two countries with such different mental and personality profiles, what role can &quot;non-mainstream&quot; positive psychology play? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Indeed. I would like to answer this question from a chapter found in the Confucian classic &quot;The Great Learning&quot;. Zengzi, a disciple of Confucius, said in &quot;The Book of Rites and Great Learning&quot;: &quot;In ancient times, those who wanted to establish virtue in the world first governed their country; those who wanted to govern their country, first organized their families; those who wanted to regulate their families, first cultivated their own bodies. ; If you want to cultivate your body, you must first rectify your mind; if you want to rectify your mind, you must first be sincere in your intentions; if you want to be sincere in your intentions, you must first know how to know, and knowing can be achieved by studying things. After studying things, you will know them, and after knowing them, your thoughts will be sincere. If the mind is sincere, then the heart will be upright; if the heart is upright, then the body will be cultivated; if the body is cultivated, the family will be in order; if the family is in order, then the country will be governed; if the country is governed, then the world will be peaceful.&quot; Confucianism believes that if a person wants to promote good morals in the world, he should start with himself, and then Ascend to the task of governing your family, then to govern your country, and then to the world. Do you know Du Weiming? He was my teacher at Harvard, and I studied Confucian humanism from him. He talked about how Confucius started from the large circle of &quot;the world&quot;, to the country, to the family, and then to himself, starting from self-cultivation. To me, Chinese philosophy is very good at integrating individual people with society. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Confucius was right. If we want to build a better society, we cannot just focus on social matters, and certainly not just on the clinical (treatment plans). We need to look at it holistically, analyzing, understanding, and acting at all levels, including individuals, families, countries, and the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9PlvUXlLLBpC3SxCC6bBVMWoIhmtHCr06tElGUJ7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9PlvUXlLLBpC3SxCC6bBVMWoIhmtHCr06tElGUJ7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253682&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On June 12, 2020, Wuhan, the iron gate leading to the main road was still closed. Residents of the old alley spontaneously danced and worked out in front of their homes after dinner&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;Can you tell me specifically how to act? For example, young people in China are now facing employment difficulties. Many people are taking public exams, editing exams, and postgraduate exams, and the competition has become extremely fierce. If you repeatedly fail in employment, public examinations, and postgraduate entrance examinations, it will lead to what is called &quot;learned helplessness&quot; in psychology. How does positive psychology play a role in this kind of representative psychological state of a specific group? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The most obvious way to deal with &quot;learned helplessness&quot; is to continue to act. Because the typical feature of &quot;learned helplessness&quot; is to stop taking action, just give up, retreat, and trying again becomes a huge challenge. So, even if you fail, still try. If you fail five times, try the sixth time. One of the most important qualities of successful people, such as successful entrepreneurs, is the ability to succeed despite repeated failures. This is for the general case. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More specifically, one of the antidotes to &quot;learned helplessness&quot; is to help others. Let me explain: Over the years, there have been numerous social surveys in the United States focusing on high-risk groups. By &quot;high-risk&quot; we mean residents of poor neighborhoods, where crime rates are often high and children do poorly in school. Researchers first came to these poor areas to provide food, money, etc. to the residents there, and provided them with various funding projects. They found that very few of them had their situation changed. In the end, the researchers found that the most effective way to change their situation was to get them to stand up and help others. When they begin to do this, they can escape &quot;learned helplessness&quot; and become capable of helping others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the words of current Chinese people, this is very positive energy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It does work. Therefore, one of the best ways to make ourselves happier is to think about how we can make others happier instead of always leaving ourselves helpless. As Confucius taught, connect yourself to society and the community. Additionally, it is a way for people to feel better about themselves, which is often what clinical psychology is concerned with. We need to start thinking about the realities that impact society, the realities around us, because helping those around us is actually helping ourselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because no one is an island, we are all part of the whole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/P80kOVKz761jkiIMtGUA8hmR7dKfGgakxO3jtsAn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/P80kOVKz761jkiIMtGUA8hmR7dKfGgakxO3jtsAn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253680&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 11, 2022, in Jerusalem, Israel, medical staff performed nucleic acid tests for people&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Spiritual life&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As As a positive psychologist, how did you spend your time during the epidemic, especially the lockdown period? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;First of all, I struggle from time to time. Life does get tough. You know I&#39;m eager to come to China, and I&#39;m eager to hug my friends. I probably couldn&#39;t see my parents for over a year. We live in New Jersey in the United States, and my parents are in Israel. They are very old, and we are worried about them getting infected with COVID-19, but we cannot travel. I miss them so much and it&#39;s challenging. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I can’t go to a restaurant with my friends to eat either. We had friends visiting our house all the time, the door was always open, and there were a lot of people coming in and out, friends of my wife and I, friends of the kids. Suddenly, the pandemic hit and it was just us and the kids in the house. Of course we have to be grateful for what we have, but it’s always hard not being able to see and be with the people we love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, my main job is to attend classes and give lectures, so I also face challenges on the economic level. So, in a lot of ways, I was struggling with my feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to face these challenges, I returned to the most basic methods of positive psychology: for example, I know that fitness is important for a good life. I used to exercise three times a week, but during the epidemic, I increased it to five times; I used to do mindfulness training every day, and now I add more training, sometimes doing yoga, sometimes Tai Chi, sometimes Qigong, and sometimes meditation; I also try to spend more time with my family as much as possible, and the whole family is together every day Eating dinner, talking, and sometimes crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also continue to work, continue to write, and continue to read. The most important thing is to allow myself to experience all these emotions, not to fight the sadness, not to try to eliminate the anxiety, to accept that they are there, to allow these emotions and feelings to flow through my soul like water, that is the metaphor I use. , don’t try to “block” or block or interrupt them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During the lockdown, you had moments when you lost control of your emotions, such as Kids yelling? After all, being in the same house with three teenage kids all day can be challenging. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is very challenging. I don&#39;t usually yell at kids, but I do get really annoyed by them sometimes. Even now that I can go out freely, I still get annoyed by them sometimes. I think it&#39;s important for parents to love their children but also set boundaries for them. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, during the epidemic, when one of my children didn&#39;t do his homework assigned by school, I got very angry and told him that something had to change because the teacher had complained. People think that if you are a professor of happiness, your home must always be filled with a happy and harmonious atmosphere. But that&#39;s not the case. You have to understand this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I would like to ask a very personal topic, do you have any religious beliefs? ? Personally, positive psychology is a social science that emphasizes value neutrality. However, compared with a set of tools and methods, are values, beliefs and even religion more important for a person to maintain a positive and healthy mental state for a long time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I am religious. But in my classes, one of the main points I emphasize is that each of us can live a spiritual life, regardless of whether we are converted to a certain religion or not. Because when we find the meaning of what we do, we have a spiritual life. I can be a teacher, I can be an institutional administrator, I find meaning in my work and therefore feel spirituality. I was able to find meaning in raising a family and also had spiritual experiences. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, instead of saying that I am a religious person, it is better to say that I am spiritual. I feel meaning and purpose in both my personal and professional life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It seems that we all agree on one thing - in positive psychology Under the iceberg of learning, there must be more basic things, such as values, beliefs, beliefs or religions, etc. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Indeed. These things will give us purpose in life and find purpose in life. Again, we can find it in different areas, some find it in faith, some find it in work, some find it in family, or elsewhere. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, do something that you believe in, is important to you, and is of great significance. That&#39;s the point. If you want to do well and stick with it over the long term, you also need to find where your talents lie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You are from Israel and have a Jewish cultural background. Have you ever summarized some experience or wisdom from the life stories of your own family and ethnic group? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many people ask me why you come to China more than other countries and why you have so many Chinese student. I replied that the first time I came to China was about 20 years ago, and it felt like I was back in my hometown. This is real. Because Jewish tradition and Chinese tradition share many similar values, such as the emphasis on family and family, the concept of family is very important in our history. I feel that I have a strong connection with China, including its history and philosophy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for you asking me what I learned from my ancestors and ethnic history? First, we are able to overcome long-standing suffering by connecting to sources of strength, including nature and community. These are two very critical factors. By nature, I mean both the external world and our nature as humans. So, Lao Tzu talks about the importance of learning from nature. Taoists say that &quot;Tao follows nature.&quot; The Tao of earth and the Tao of heaven are &quot;Tao&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I want to share with you a passage from the Tao Te Ching: &quot;Man follows the earth, earth follows the sky, heaven follows the Tao, and the Tao follows nature.&quot; When we connect with nature, we can gain strength from it. . This is the first source of power, then the second source. Confucianism talks most about community, and talks a lot about the various rituals when communities come together. In Judaism, we also have many rituals when family members are together. When I visit my friends&#39; homes in China, I often sit with their parents and sometimes grandparents. They usually speak Chinese and I don&#39;t understand what they are saying, but I understand the connection because the same scene can be seen in Israel. That is the source of our strength as Jews—nature, community, and that includes family. Just like Confucianism teaches: from oneself to the family, to the larger group-the country and the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I would like to ask a question with more personal experience. I remember that when I was a child, I could see international news about the Palestinian-Israeli conflict on TV almost every day, including suicide attacks. I thought it was very scary. You spent your childhood and adolescence in Israel. Does this kind of violent information or even experience from the outside world bother you and your friends? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;You know I grew up in Israel. Every morning when we wake up, we worry about the bomb on the bus to school; when we go to the restaurant to eat, we worry about the bomb in the restaurant. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My first memory of the war is from when I was less than 3 years old, when sirens rang in the streets and we had to rush to underground shelters to hide for fear of being bombed. Or get blown up. So, you understand what I grew up in and what I went through. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He is less than 3 years old. As a child, how do you face this? The fear of brushing against death every day? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shahar: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Just like you do with all other traumas, hardships and hardships. You have a community around you that supports you. You talk about it, write about it. In the meantime, keep exercising, find things that are meaningful to you, and find things that you can be grateful for. These strategies are always useful when we face a traumatic experience, whether it’s COVID-19, a job loss, or the loss of a loved one. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These are the tools and techniques taught to us by the science of happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[游客擅自穿越被四姑娘山终身禁入：户外探险应合法合规且风险自担丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258650]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, the Siguniang Mountain Scenic Area Administration Bureau in Aba Prefecture, Sichuan reported that two tourists violated regulations and conducted private activities in the scenic area. If you cross on foot, you will be banned from entering for life. In recent years, there have been many such privately organized hiking activities, and there have been many dangerous incidents. For these illegal outdoor activities, on the one hand, the penalties must be increased, and on the other hand, the public&#39;s enthusiasm for adventure must be given an outlet. Some crossing routes can be developed to allow explorers to take risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to a recent report from the Siguniang Mountain Scenic Area Management Bureau, two tourists, Wang and Cai, purchased tickets to enter the scenic area, and then ignored the signage instructions and staff dissuasion in the scenic area and started hiking through the scenic area. But because it snowed that night, the two called the police for help and were rescued down the mountain. The report stated that the two violated the prohibition regulations of the scenic spot and caused certain harm and adverse effects to the protection and management of the scenic spot. Therefore, it was decided to ban the two from entering the Siguniang Mountain Scenic Spot for sightseeing and other forms of tourism for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many netizens agreed with the decision of the Scenic Area Management Bureau. Mount Siguniang is no ordinary scenic spot. It is a world natural heritage and a national nature reserve. The Scenic Area Management Bureau is a public institution that manages the scenic area under the authorization of the Aba Prefecture Government. Although the two tourists purchased tickets to enter the scenic spot legally, they then hiked through the scenic spot privately, violating the prohibitive regulations of the scenic spot. The administration has the right to ban them from entering the scenic spot again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Banning entry has become an option adopted by many scenic spots for serious violations of tourists. Since 2023, many tourists have been banned from the Chengdu Panda Base for one year, five years, and life due to uncivilized behaviors such as spitting water at giant pandas and slapping the glass of giant panda enclosures. In 2021, three tourists carved words on the walls of the Great Wall and were included in the &quot;blacklist&quot; of uncivilized tourism by the Yanqing cultural and tourism department in Beijing. 12 local scenic spots jointly banned entry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, many netizens believe that simply prohibiting entry is not a punishment. Serious violations such as unauthorized crossing should be severely punished and required to bear the cost of rescue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aggravated penalties are also legal. According to the &quot;Nature Reserve Regulations&quot; formulated by the State Council, anyone who enters a nature reserve without approval or fails to obey the management of the management agency within a nature reserve may be fined between 100 yuan and 5,000 yuan depending on the circumstances. In 2019, seven travelers hiked through the Wolong National Nature Reserve in Sichuan without authorization, and one person died. The other six people were fined 5,000 yuan each by the protected area administration and required to bear medical expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Outdoor adventure activities such as cross-country and time-traveling have become more and more popular recently. However, many of these activities involve routes that have been explicitly prohibited by the government, and accidents often occur due to insufficient logistical support and insufficient awareness of risk avoidance. For example, during the May Day holiday in 2021, many &quot;travel friends&quot; lost contact or died while illegally crossing in the Qinling Mountains. The &quot;Ao Tai Line&quot; that travel enthusiasts are keen to cross has long been banned from crossing by the Shaanxi Taibai Mountain National Nature Reserve Administration, the Shaanxi Provincial Forestry Public Security Bureau and other departments. However, these crossing activities are still prohibited frequently, and there are frequent incidents of travelers being in danger, requiring rescue by all parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These rescues often require a huge investment of manpower and material resources. For example, in February 2022, a traveler was in danger while trekking through the mountains in the snow in Tibet. More than 100 auxiliary public security police, grassroots cadres, farmers and herdsmen, more than 20 rescue vehicles, and 9 horses were dispatched to search and rescue 20 people in the ice, snow, and violent storms. Many hours. In May 2021, a male traveler in Shanghai lost contact while crossing the Qinling Mountains. After the incident, more than 10 professional rescue teams with more than 200 people carried drones and other equipment into the mountains to carry out blanket search and rescue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cost of such a large-scale search and rescue operation is very high. Who should pay for these rescue costs? As such incidents increase, official rescue agencies are overwhelmed. Many places have begun to implement paid rescue. The Anhui Huangshan Paid Rescue Measures, which came into effect in July 2018, stipulate that tourists who violate the regulations of scenic spots and enter undeveloped or unopened areas without authorization shall be provided with paid rescue. Tourists who violate regulations are required to bear the labor, pre-hospital treatment, and medical expenses incurred during the rescue process. Transportation, accident insurance, logistics support, introduction of third-party rescue forces, etc. In August 2018, the Ganzi Yading Scenic Area in Sichuan also announced that it would implement a paid search and rescue system for tourists who violate regulations. The search and rescue fees start at 15,000 yuan and 20,000 yuan respectively according to different regions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, paid search and rescue does not mean giving money first and then saving people. When someone is in danger and asks for help, rescue agencies still have to dispatch rescuers as soon as possible. After all, human life is at stake. However, after the rescue is completed, the rescue expenses should be settled and borne by the rescued person. If payment is refused, enforcement can be enforced through court proceedings and other means. If the rescued person dies, it is paid out of his estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, adventure is also human nature. Adventure activities can inspire people to challenge their limits. True explorers are often admired by the public. Simply banning it will not completely prevent travelers from traveling through time travel. It is better to block than to open up. Consider opening some popular crossing routes appropriately and setting up certain emergency facilities along the way to reduce the difficulty of crossing. At the same time, it should be clear that outdoor adventure is a high-risk activity. Even if you are well prepared, unexpected situations may occur. Well-known diving explorer Han Ting died in an accident while diving in a cave in Jiudun Tianluo, Guangxi. Participants in outdoor activities must fully understand the risks, be prepared for logistical support, and bear possible risks on their own. If you need rescue, you have to pay for it yourself. If you can&#39;t bear these risks, it&#39;s best not to play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[高端家教与留守儿童，时髦机车与过期月饼丨人在职场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258648]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Two years ago, after my Harvard internship psychology mentor passed away, I was a little sad and planned to briefly The perspective shifts from laboratory literature to psychological cases in real life. Coincidentally, a teacher from a &quot;high-end tutoring&quot; institution found me, and I was quite interested in it. Between July 2021 and April 2023, I briefly took a peek into this circle. After May 2023, I came into contact with the circle of local charity cram schools for left-behind children. The two circles have different terms, lifestyles, emotional patterns, and family structures, which are worth pondering. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before matching with high-end families, the general process is to prepare a resume in Chinese and English, list your relevant tutoring experience and a one-minute self-introduction video in English. Then, the intermediary agency will conduct a two-way matching. Driver&#39;s license, teacher qualification certificate, and early childhood education certificate can be given extra points. Specialties such as painting, piano, and dancing are also within the requirements of many parents. Generally speaking, parents are quite picky, and as British and American graduates with undergraduate and postgraduate degrees are actively pouring into this industry, it is becoming more difficult to apply for jobs with a target monthly income of 150,000 to 350,000 yuan. It usually takes 8-10 families to interview before we hear back. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the nearly 10 families I interviewed, demand is generally concentrated in the five major cities of Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, Shenzhen and Hangzhou, and other scattered families are also scattered around these cities. Most of these families live in villas or large flats with an area of ​​more than 300 square meters, and are equipped with nannies, drivers, and housekeepers. Most of them are interviewed by the mother alone (only one family is attended by the father, who works to make money), and the father is not at home. Most of the needs of mothers require teachers to formulate work schedules and study plans, supervise their implementation, take their children to and from school and complete extracurricular homework. A small number of parents have competition needs. Families who understand psychology and education better will put forward requirements for developing children&#39;s intelligence and seizing the golden period of language development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, take the example of parents in a certain megacity. Both parents have master&#39;s degrees in Hong Kong. They have three children at home and live in a relatively remote villa group. Their grandparents live with them at home, and their mother stays with their children full time. The father travels between two cities every day and has little time to take care of his children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I took over the care of two children, the children were very proficient in English, studied in private schools, and had a wide range of interests. The 4-year-old boy A is the second child in this family. He likes fashionable cars. His mother will buy a whole wall of fashionable cars and related car picture books. When he sees me, he will say: &quot;Hi, teacher, I hope you like This motorcycle!&quot; The 7-year-old girl B is her elder sister. She likes painting and ballet. She has her own dance practice room and art studio in the basement, and has won rankings in large-scale competitions in nearby areas. In addition to attending classes every week, teachers need to accompany them to football classes, swimming classes, ballet classes and math competition classes on weekends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This mother plans to use her child’s Hong Kong ID card in the future to allow her child to enter top universities in the mainland through the joint entrance examination, or to enter a prestigious Hong Kong university through DSE to study as an undergraduate. If I immigrate in the future, I will stay in the United States to study. I can advance or retreat. Therefore, children do not study hard in private schools and always feel that they are different from ordinary children and have a sense of superiority. It is obvious that the three children are emotionally healthy, lively and positive, love to say hello to others, have no stage fright, and are not afraid of difficulties. They live a carefree life every day and grow up healthily and safely in happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, primary school children still need a nanny to help them brush their teeth, wash their faces, and change their shoes every day. Their mothers also expect tutors to personally help their children clean up their house. From a psychological point of view, I think this will hinder the children to some extent. autonomous development. In May, I quit my job as a family escort and took a short break at home. A relative came to me: Are you interested in using your spare time to teach left-behind children? It doesn’t need to be all day, just three hours a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After learning the basic situation of the children, I readily agreed. My salary ranges from three to five thousand yuan, which can be said to have shrunk significantly. For the left-behind children, a lot of help is needed, and it must start from the most basic level. For example, I initially bought a math tutoring material for primary school to junior high school for girl C, who is in the first grade of junior high school, to help her transition to junior high school knowledge. But she doesn&#39;t know how to calculate fractions, 1/5+1/5, she calculates it to be equal to 1/10. After taking the quiz, I only got about 20 points. The reason was that the teacher said he was playful and lacked basic skills in elementary school. In my opinion, it is very likely that my mathematical intelligence has not been developed in the past few years. Now I have only begun to learn mathematical knowledge seriously at the age of 13. It is likely that I need step-by-step mathematical enlightenment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The left-behind children and I stayed with each other for a while. In terms of English, due to the lack of English teachers in rural primary schools, they have never learned English. Children A and B from high-end families are fully qualified to be their home teachers; they are very poor in mathematics; they have never read extracurricular books in Chinese. Due to financial constraints, I have never used a computer or become addicted to the Internet. Because my parents are not at home for a long time, I don’t get enough sleep, eat poorly, and are often listless. I don’t know how to make good use of tutoring time to interact with teachers, proactively ask questions and talk about my problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Talk about the future with the mother of girl C. The child wants to transfer to a school near her, but that school is very poor and there are no cram schools nearby. &quot;Teacher, do you think my child is good at reading?&quot; My mother expressed her gratitude to me for giving her children inspirational books such as &quot;You Be Like a Bird Flying to Your Mountain&quot; to encourage her to learn more on her own. The girl&#39;s parents both graduated from high school. They are easy to talk to and are very concerned about their daughter&#39;s condition. They send me WeChat messages to chat with me every day and they have a very good attitude. The girl herself has no hobbies and doesn&#39;t like to talk. She has a small smart watch for calling her mother and a worn-out school bag. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just after the Mid-Autumn Festival, a teacher from a local institution sent a box of mooncakes. After a closer look, I found that they had expired the next day. I originally wanted to share a few with the kids, but forget it. Whether it&#39;s a fashionable motorcycle or a mooncake that&#39;s about to expire, every life has its own flavor. Behind these two non-intersecting social classes is a new direction worthy of re-anchoring in my future scientific research life and application practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Family private information in the article has been blurred, any similarity is purely coincidental.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is an undergraduate graduate of City University of Hong Kong)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(&quot;People in the Workplace&quot; of the &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of the Southern Weekend App. Welcome to write in to share your workplace opinions and complain about your workplace experiences. , break stereotypes and reveal industry rules. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[车厢起火冒烟？广州地铁：系乘客充电宝冒烟，已处理]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258652]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/7809a3f28931b06eab226f867823240c.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/15/7809a3f28931b06eab226f867823240c.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254105&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;Live video screenshot&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this regard, the reporter learned from the Guangzhou Metro that at about 11 o&#39;clock on October 14, a passenger&#39;s power bank suddenly started to smoke on the first train of Line 2. There were passengers in the car who helped to water it with water. The staff Arrive at the scene in time to handle the situation. To ensure safety, the dispatching department organized the train to withdraw from service. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guangzhou Metro reminds you to take good care of your power bank when taking the bus. Please do not use it while riding. If you encounter an emergency while riding the subway, please stay calm and press the emergency button on the bus in time. Report to staff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the reporter also learned that the requirements for carrying power banks in the Guangzhou subway are that a single power bank with a rated capacity of no more than 20,000 mAh can be carried into the station, and each person cannot carry more than 5 in total. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[斩断假央国企制造链：严审特殊字词，申报系统联网]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258642]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/K7kmyjC66Fz21g17jBC2jdnV3sBSSd6J7xbrE5y3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;1292&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/K7kmyjC66Fz21g17jBC2jdnV 3sBSSd6J7xbrE5y3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254085&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In order to prevent and stop illegal activities such as counterfeiting state-owned enterprises and central enterprises, the &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; details Prohibitive provisions in enterprise name registration, and it is expressly prohibited to submit false materials or use other fraudulent means to independently declare enterprise names. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nongjian/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From more than 4,700 words to more than 7,000 words, the newly revised &quot;Implementation Measures for Enterprise Name Registration Management Regulations&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Implementation Measures&quot;) will come into effect on October 1, 2023. This is the most significant revision of the Measures since it was promulgated in 1999 and individual provisions were modified in 2004. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In recent years, individual companies have deliberately declared and used names illegally, disrupting the market order and causing great concern... Some deliberately &#39;similar to famous brands&#39;, deliberately counterfeiting the names, abbreviations, etc. of central and state-owned enterprises, infringing on the legality of well-known units Rights and interests.&quot; mentioned in the interpretation of the new regulations issued by the State Administration for Market Regulation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2021, the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of the State Council has announced three batches of lists of counterfeit central enterprises. The website of the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of the State Council stated on August 26, 2023 that since July, according to incomplete statistics, there have been more than 20 The Central Enterprise Group issued a statement, announcing hundreds of counterfeit central enterprise names, unified social credit codes and other information, revealing illegal use of central enterprise names and logos, impersonating the identities of central enterprise cadres and employees, and developing and operating fake APPs. Southern Weekend made a detailed report on this (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details, please see Southern Weekend&#39;s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents /252936?source=131&quot;>;Secrets of Thousands of Fake Central State-owned Enterprises: Buying an Identity with Millions, Fake Central SOEs Transformed into Group Companies&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/253625 ?source=131&quot;>;&quot;Manufacture&quot; fake central state-owned enterprises: Become a &quot;boss&quot; in a week, and you can change your vest even if you are investigated&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/255216? source=131&quot;>;The business strategy of a &quot;fake central enterprise&quot; in Yunnan: the operator of the 35 billion hydrogen production super project&lt;/a>;》.&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the past, in order to prevent In order to prevent illegal activities such as counterfeiting state-owned enterprises and central enterprises, the &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; details the prohibitive provisions in the registration of enterprise names and explicitly prohibits the submission of false materials or other fraudulent means for independent declaration of enterprise names. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Automatic comparison, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Declaration system&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Internet&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Compared with the past, the &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; The requirements for corporate name specifications and independent declaration services are more detailed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, Article 16 stipulates that corporate names must not “use words related to major national strategic policies, causing the public to mistakenly think that they are related to state investment, government credit, etc.” The names (including abbreviations, font sizes, etc.) of others who have a certain influence in the industry are the same or similar.&quot; &quot;It includes the names and trade names of central state-owned enterprises.&quot; Lawyer Han Shuai, a partner at Beijing Strategy Law Firm, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; also require that provincial enterprise registration authorities are responsible for establishing, managing and maintaining the enterprise name declaration system within their own administrative regions, and cooperating with the national enterprise name standardization management system and the national market supervision and management system. Connect with the enterprise name declaration system of the General Administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When an applicant declares a company name independently, the company name declaration system automatically compares the company name submitted by the applicant, and makes bans and restrictions based on the company name prohibition and restriction rules, identical and similar comparison rules, etc. Instructions or risk warnings. At the same time, the interconnected enterprise name declaration system can better compare enterprise names and effectively prevent the illegal registration of enterprise names by exploiting loopholes in cross-provincial information incompatibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past, provinces and cities were not connected to each other. For example, if a central state-owned enterprise is registered in Province A, and you want to be associated with it in Province A, the system may screen it, but if it is in Province B or C Province, if you fake the background of a central state-owned enterprise in Province A, you may not be able to screen because you are not connected to the Internet.&quot; Han Shuai said that after being connected to the Internet, the authenticity, legality and validity of the materials submitted by the company can be more accurately reviewed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Establish a random inspection system&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;an administrative adjudication mechanism for name disputes&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For existing counterfeit central For state-owned enterprises, the &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; also strengthened the supervision and management system, requiring the enterprise registration authority to find that the registered enterprise name does not comply with the relevant provisions of enterprise name registration management, it should make timely corrections in accordance with the law and order the enterprise to change its name. The enterprise registration authority at the higher level may correct the enterprise name that has been registered by the enterprise registration authority at the lower level and does not comply with the relevant provisions on enterprise name registration management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the State Administration for Market Regulation has established a spot inspection system to supervise and inspect the enterprise name registration management and enterprise name declaration services of provincial enterprise registration authorities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Shuai believes that the market supervision department regularly selects a certain proportion of company names for verification. It may be random, or it may be reported by relevant units or individuals. If it is found that there are counterfeit central state-owned enterprises and forged registration materials circumstances, they can be punished in accordance with the law and regulations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another highlight is that the &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; also improve the administrative adjudication mechanism for enterprise name disputes, clearly stipulate the considerations for dispute review, and refine the procedural provisions of the litigation process, including jurisdiction, application and the time limit and process for acceptance, dispute mediation mechanism, factors to be considered in review and processing, summary adjudication procedures, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Han Shuai introduced that there are usually three ways to protect the rights of central state-owned enterprises when they are counterfeited. In terms of administration, the first is to apply for the registration authority to make an administrative ruling; the second is to apply to the administrative authority to investigate and punish the unfair competition behavior of the infringing enterprise. At the judicial level, a lawsuit can be filed in the People&#39;s Court. The Civil Code of the People&#39;s Republic of China also has relevant provisions on the protection of corporate names. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Summary adjudication proceedings are now also possible. The &quot;Implementation Measures&quot; stipulate that for enterprise name disputes where the facts are clear, the dispute is not major, and the case is simple, the enterprise registration authority may apply summary adjudication procedures in accordance with relevant regulations. &quot;After the new regulations, how companies protect their rights has been designed more clearly, which improves administrative efficiency and helps companies resolve disputes.&quot; Han Shuai said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[乾隆资助北美独立战争？封建帝王的眼界和见识不值得吹嘘]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258644]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 16:15:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Not long ago, a certain big V posted on Weibo saying: &quot;After the gunfire in Lexington, Emperor Qianlong should At the invitation of King Louis XVI of France, he funded the North American militia with 1,000 taels of gold... It turns out that the Qing Dynasty contributed a lot to the independence of the United States.&quot; In order to prove that what he said was true, the blogger also listed the sources of relevant historical materials: &quot;The Ministry of Internal Affairs Manufacturing Office File Volume 27. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qianlong, who has always been regarded as a man of great achievements and self-proclaimed, actually had such &quot;far-sightedness&quot; as &quot;joining France to support the United States and resisting the British and barbarians&quot;. This anecdote aroused the interest of many netizens, and many believed it to be true. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this seemingly novel story is actually a very low-level rumor. The blogger listed the words in the so-called letter from Emperor Qianlong to King Louis XVI of France in the comment area, &quot;Bederi &quot;Use money and get wet with rain and dew&quot;, and based on this, he categorically claimed that Qianlong did not use treasury funds, but chose to use private funds to fund the North American militia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, this sentence comes from the second sentence in the &quot;Emperor Qianlong&#39;s Edict to King George III of England&quot;. The original text is: &quot;The products of the Celestial Empire are abundant and everything is available. Originally, they did not borrow goods from foreign countries. Whether there is anything or not. Especially because the tea, porcelain, and silk produced by the Chinese dynasty are indispensable to Western countries and your country, so I showed my kindness and sympathy and opened a foreign business in Macao to provide daily necessities and make a profit.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, this passage has been cited by historians to explain that Emperor Qianlong in his later years was closed-minded and short-sighted, and was ignorant of the drastic changes in the external world. It is completely ridiculous that such a paragraph was cut off by the blogger and placed on the head of King Louis XVI of France to prove that Emperor Qianlong was a far-sighted strategist with an international vision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why so many netizens believe this crude &quot;wonder&quot; is not only because it is indeed a gimmick, but also because of the aura around Qianlong. So does this &quot;King of the Prosperous Age&quot; really have the kind of &quot;international vision&quot; that netizens believe? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Grandfathers who are not far apart&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the Opium War, when Emperor Daoguang ordered Yijing to interrogate British prisoners, he asked him a series of ridiculous questions. It became a joke in history:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How far away is Kashmir (now Kashmir) from the country? Is there a waterway accessible? Does the country have any contact with the British? Why should we comply this time? To Zhejiang?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;How many places are around this country? How many are there in the country it belongs to? How many are the most powerful and independent of the country&#39;s rulers? Is there a dry road from Yingjia to Huijiang? Are there any exchanges? Is there a border with Russia? Is there any trade connection?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, Daoguang, who was devastated by the war, could not understand the concept of &quot;world colonial empire&quot; at all. Although the old and shabby intelligence network left to him by his emperor Ama and his grandfather was still working, the intelligence they continued to send from Kyaktu, Manila and Kashgar about the &quot;British barbarians&quot; not only failed Asking him to figure out who his enemies were made the emperor even more confused. He couldn&#39;t understand why &quot;British barbarians&quot; appeared in all directions of the Qing Empire at the same time, so he asked whether there were any enemies in Britain and Xinjiang. There are issues such as being connected by dry road and whether it borders Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be fair, these ridiculous questions asked by Emperor Daoguang are not worthy of ridicule. The vision and knowledge he displayed were only the normal level of the emperors of the Qing Dynasty. In terms of understanding the world as a whole, he is certainly not better than his father and grandfather, but he is not far behind. Because the system through which they receive education and the channels through which they perceive the outside world are essentially the same. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the world is changing too fast, the concept of &quot;the empire on which the sun never sets&quot; is indeed a bit &quot;over the top&quot; for Emperor Daoguang. So Emperor Qianlong couldn&#39;t figure out where the two cities of Nerchinsk and Yaksa in the &quot;Treaty of Nerchinsk&quot; were, and whether they belonged to the Qing Dynasty or Russia. This only shows that the &quot;international vision&quot; of his grandfather and grandson was not far from each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the fifty-seventh year of Qianlong&#39;s reign (1792), Emperor Qianlong ordered a letter to the then Heilongjiang General Mingliang: &quot;During the Kangxi Dynasty, in order to capture the cities of Yaksa and Nerchinsk, they fought with Russia for several years. The two cities are there. But are these two cities now under the jurisdiction of Heilongjiang? If they are under the jurisdiction of Heilongjiang, who will manage them and who will be stationed there? Send a message to the general and others so that Russia will not notice, quietly find out, and use a toilet Please do not make any announcement. Please accept this. Send a letter in compliance with the order.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Treaty of Nerchinsk&quot; was the first diplomatic treaty signed by the Qing Dynasty within the framework of the Westphalian order. , was also the first time the Qing Dynasty came into contact with the modern international diplomatic system. The treaty not only delineated the national boundaries between China and Russia in the east, but also demarcated the spheres of influence of China and Russia in Northeast Asia. It can be said that the signing of the Treaty of Nerchinsk was a crucial event in establishing the basic territory of the Qing Dynasty. However, a hundred years later, the supreme ruler had no idea where Nerchinsk and Yaksa were. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What’s even more interesting is that Emperor Qianlong’s idea of ​​​​solving this problem was not to retrieve the text of the Treaty of Nerchinsk for review, but to ask the Heilongjiang generals, and the Heilongjiang generals also discussed with Emperor Qianlong Similarly, he was completely confused about the location of Nerchinsk and Jaxar. Similarly, he did not check the treaty, but &quot;ordered people to check&quot; and reported to Qianlong. It can be seen that the emperor and his ministers did not take this crucial international treaty seriously. To them, the Battle of Yaksa was just a border conflict where &quot;foreigners were looking for trouble.&quot; The signing of the treaty was just a means to solve this minor trouble. It was not a code of conduct for the Qing Dynasty in diplomacy, and once the troubles were resolved, the treaty was shelved and completely forgotten over time. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The established national policy of &quot;preventing internal affairs and financing external affairs&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;This kind of indifference and ignorance of the outside world by the Qing monarchs and ministers actually came from the political tradition and political tradition of the ancient autocratic emperors of &quot;preventing internal affairs and financing external affairs&quot; With established national policies, they always believed that the source of their core interests was not outside the empire, but that factors that could threaten and shake their rule were within the empire. Foreigners come from afar, and even if they are tyrannical for a while, in the final analysis they are people without roots. As long as they win over them from the massive benefits obtained from squeezing their own people, they will be able to live in peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, it is entirely possible for the nationals of this country to repeat their path to power and threaten their rule. This kind of political tradition and established decision-making determines that the attention of autocratic kings, including the emperors of the Qing Dynasty, is always inward and not outward. Therefore, when some of them, such as Emperors Kangxi and Qianlong, occasionally became interested in some &quot;strange skills and tricks&quot; in the outside world, it was only as personal hobbies and pastimes. These hobbies and pastimes could neither change their views on The way they perceive the world makes it even less likely that they will have an &quot;international perspective.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most typical example is that during the Qianlong period, Zheng Xin, a Chinese military leader in Southeast Asia, seized power in Siam during the war and requested for canonization from the Qing Dynasty. From an international political perspective, this was a An excellent strategic opportunity, the Qing Dynasty may gain a firm and reliable ally and strategic fulcrum in Southeast Asia, and once and for all eliminate the threat from Myanmar to the Qing Dynasty&#39;s southern border. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Emperor Qianlong&#39;s response to this opportunity was: &quot;(Zheng Xinhe) The king of Siam should be a monarch and his ministers. Now that the country is in ruins and people are perishing, they dare to take advantage of the crisis and no longer care about it. Therefore, he asked his descendants to restore the country and take revenge, and he often thought of self-reliance, and he wanted to grant the imperial edict in vain, thinking that it was a great contract, but it was actually an act that violated the rules and violated the rules.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, Zheng Xin&#39;s act of taking advantage of the chaos and seizing power in Siam as a courtier reminded Emperor Qianlong of the story of the founder of the Qing Dynasty who took advantage of the chaos and robbed the world as a courtier of the Ming Dynasty. He was worried that accepting Zheng Xin&#39;s regime would threaten the Qing Dynasty. The legitimacy of the founding of the country thus gave rise to feelings of disgust and rejection. It can be seen that the thinking mode of an autocratic emperor always comes first to consolidate his rule internally. In this case, how can there be any talk of &quot;international vision&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Earlier in the fifth year of Qianlong&#39;s reign (1740), the Nanyang Chinese, who had been oppressed by the Dutch colonists, rose up in resistance in Indonesia and were massacred by the Dutch colonists on the banks of the Red Creek outside Batavia. Nearly 10,000 overseas Chinese died. After some discussions between the Qing emperors and ministers, they came to the conclusion that &quot;(the Chinese who were killed) were originally native to that place and were no different from the Ban people.&quot; Emperor Qianlong finally approved the disposal plan that &quot;the Bans in Nanyang are still allowed to trade as usual.&quot; Nothing happened and no sanctions of any kind were imposed on the Dutch colonists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above historical facts show that what makes an autocratic king truly superb is his internal skills of protecting, governing, weakening and exhausting the people. To brag about the vision and knowledge of an autocratic king is obviously a lie. It would be even more stupid to misdirect their efforts and spread rumors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[复旦人体科学馆馆长：与标本“交谈”，让人体不再神秘]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258640]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/XcjddVb9DUbrdQ7P2UiaoVzt3pUZ4emkQcuY9TuQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/XcjddVb9DUbrdQ7P2UiaoVzt3pUZ4emkQ cuY9TuQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254082&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Zhou Guomin often personally introduces visitors, and volunteers do so when he is in class or out. Visitors explain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A human science museum hidden in the Fenglin Campus of Fudan University has become popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Many people came here after reading Xiaohongshu and Dianping. Everyone is curious about how a place displaying human specimens has become a &#39;niche check-in place&#39; and an &#39;Internet celebrity museum&#39;.&quot; In order to Not to miss every consultation call, director Zhou Guomin specially bound the landline of the science museum to his mobile phone number. Therefore, Zhou Guomin&#39;s mobile phone almost never stopped ringing throughout the National Day holiday. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What few visitors know is that being the curator of the Human Science Museum is just one of Zhou Guomin’s many jobs. He served as the head of the Department of Anatomy and Histoembryology at Fudan University School of Basic Medicine for nearly two decades. , at the beginning of the fall semester of 2023, he will also be responsible for teaching more than 20 class hours/week, and he also has many anatomy-related positions and titles outside the school. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This year is my tenth year at the Human Body Science Museum. I also want to do a better job in popularizing science and discover more stories so that ordinary people can feel the warmth of medicine.” Zhou Guomin said to the South reporters said over the weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The following is compiled based on the dictation of Professor Zhou Guomin:&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;Tell children how new life is born&lt;strong>;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;Although the Human Science Museum is small, it has a long history and a rich collection, such as tissue sections labeled with Yenching University, a micromanipulator produced in Germany in 1930, a complete skeleton and whole-body plastinated specimens. But the most conspicuous place upon entering is the baby specimen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1944, Professor Yan Fuqing’s daughter-in-law gave birth to a pair of twin baby girls, who died due to premature birth. For a long time, Chinese people have believed that &quot;the deceased is the most important&quot; and there are few body donors. However, Yan Fuqing selflessly donated the bodies of his relatives to medical research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/aruBfaepCDnnJMJ5gjgYQiBs6u5QTNFXISupbcvd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/aruBfaepCDnnJMJ5gjgYQiBs6u5QTNFXISupbcvd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254081&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 9, 2023, Zhou Guomin introduced the specimens of twin baby girls to visitors and the story behind the specimens. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Fuqing is the former National Shanghai Medical College (the predecessor of Fudan University Shanghai Medical College) and the Chinese Medical Association The founder of the company is known as the &quot;Father of Modern Chinese Medicine&quot;. For nearly eighty years, these baby girls have been studied and admired by generations of medical students, and are now placed where they can be seen at first sight when entering the museum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yan Fuqing’s grandson Yan Zhiyuan is also studying and working in medicine. Similar to his sister, he is also a twin, but his brother unfortunately died at birth. In order to fulfill his grandfather&#39;s last wish, Yan Zhiyuan decided to donate his body to his alma mater for autopsy after his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some baby specimens in the Human Science Museum with brain malformations, which are very distressing to see. This was actually because some pregnant women at that time lacked necessary vitamins, resulting in poor fetal brain development. Later, after folic acid supplementation was advocated, the incidence of fetal brain malformations was greatly reduced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the people who visit the Human Body Science Museum are parents who bring their children to learn about human body science. I like to tell children how new life is born, starting with the production of sperm and eggs. Every child is a champion, healthy, strong, hard-working, living in the dream palace provided by his mother, and comes into this world with love and hope. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many doctors are working hard for the birth of new life. If any of these interested children are willing to engage in medicine in the future, I will be even happier. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Both an &quot;alumni&quot; and a &quot;mentor&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Every time a visitor comes, I want to ask them where they come from and why they think of it. Gotta visit this place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, Shanghai’s museum resources are really rich, and the name of the Human Body Science Museum seems a bit scary at first glance, but they come all the way here and have to make an appointment to enter the school, which is more cumbersome; On the one hand, I am also looking for potential connections between visitors and this pavilion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the visitors, some are engaged in medical-related work themselves, some have relatives who are ill and are seeking treatment in nearby hospitals, and they come to visit and study while accompanying them, and some want to learn about body donation. A visitor surnamed Wu once added me on WeChat to learn how to donate a body to his seriously ill mother, which was her mother’s wish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone who studies medicine knows that without corpses, there would be no anatomy, and without anatomy, there would be no modern medicine. Without visible and tangible human specimens, it would be difficult for medical schools to train excellent doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So we are full of respect for body donors and call them body teachers. These general teachers are both our &quot;alumni&quot; and &quot;mentors&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, I have been collecting older body donation certificates. There are many application and volunteer forms from the 1980s and 1990s taped to one wall in the museum. The papers have turned yellow, but the handwriting is still beautiful and clear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest note that can be found is on September 23, 1981. An old man named Zhao Leshi expressed his willingness to contribute his body to the cause of medical science after his death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/1UFIGjNIY2RPt6417kNBRkbOgxLLYYV6m1FDoNcT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/1UFIGjNIY2RPt6417kNBRkbOgxLLYYV6m1FDoNcT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254084&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The earliest body donation record that can be found was on September 23, 1981. An old man named Zhao Leshi expressed his willingness to contribute his body to medical science after his death. cause. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for some experts and professors, most of the donors were ordinary people. There were no telephones at that time. Now can I find the relatives of these early donors and express my gratitude to the doctors? If their family members knew that the name of Teacher Da Ti had been engraved on the monument in Fushou Garden in Shanghai, would they want to pay homage to the deceased and tell them about the pain of separation for thirty or forty years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have found one, and I hope to find more in the future and record the story of Teacher DaTi. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Science popularization should also be innovative and interesting&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For many people, the body is like a blind box. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The onset of the COVID-19 epidemic has made everyone more concerned about their health and more willing to understand their bodies. For example, people know that infection with pneumonia may lead to &quot;white lungs.&quot; Look at the male anatomy teacher in the corner. His lungs are black and gray. This &quot;black lung&quot; is caused by smoking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fudan University has always had a tradition of attaching importance to science popularization. In 2013, the school allocated millions of yuan in special funds to carry out large-scale reconstruction and upgrade of the two original exhibition halls (referring to the Human Science Museum and the Pathological Specimen Museum, founded in the 1930s). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called collections and treasures of the museum are of course important, but I care more about everyone’s experience of coming to this exhibition hall. In addition to various microscopes, we also introduced VR, 3D printing, digital human systems and other equipment to enhance the sense of technology and interactive experience. Some children lingered and came several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to popularize science more interestingly, we have also engaged in several cross-border cooperations. Currently going on is &quot;Open Your Blind Box - Human Anatomy Art Exhibition&quot;, where the creators combine medicine and art. After the opening, the number of visitors who made reservations online increased significantly, and some people came specifically for this purpose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/n9Kvb9iJFI4HrfBABGoZDm5i6mOZaYDDAwc40BVW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/n9Kvb9iJFI4HrfBABGoZDm5i6mOZaYDDAwc40BVW.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254083&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In April 2023, the &quot;Open Your Blind Box - Human Anatomy Art Exhibition&quot; at the Human Science Museum of Fudan University officially opened. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Imagine painting each bone with colorful patterns such as giraffes and Garden of Eden. A blood vessel or nerve can have different colors. Each specimen is sketched with a black pen to form a volume of pictures. At this moment, the human body becomes no longer mysterious and becomes more exciting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe that the same object and the observation perspectives of different disciplines and fields will bring different discoveries and experiences. Art is the constant experimentation and innovation of viewing angles. More importantly, art can give people the courage to observe from conventional angles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[旋转的白森林]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258574]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/CDGLWAR98C8pWtIuxfWnkE9P6QN98wHniNqZbJhv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/CDGLWAR98C8pWtIuxfWnkE9P6QN98wHniN qZbJhv. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253666&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Grassland Sky Road Observation Deck&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All things are one and connected to each other. The signs appear, but their meaning is difficult to decipher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I spent the whole morning roaming in the wilderness. On the rolling hills, oats and sunflowers sway in the wind, waiting to be harvested. Autumn has come to Zhangbei grassland again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under a cement pole, I took off my backpack and sat down to rest. It&#39;s quiet around here. Occasionally a car would pass by silently on the road in the distance. Listen carefully to the hum of wind turbines grinding the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The number &quot;76&quot; is affixed to the pole. This number has special meaning to me - the birthday of a close relative. A few black feathers and a dried neck bone were scattered on the grass. Seven years ago today, I was driving her on the highway and killed a magpie. The night before, she slept in an orchard near the China-North Korea border and had a nightmare - an eye stared at her in the night sky. After waking up, she heard a woman crying all night on the mountain - an eagle owl was crying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2R802a1KiPtLOBbZJKzTQcIEW7CBNMyaP8HyiAaN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;362&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/2R802a1KiPtLOBbZJKzTQcIEW7CBNMyaP8HyiAaN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253667&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mature sunflowers&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the hill Opera and the sound of tractors came from the villages. I looked away from the feathers. The village square became a threshing floor, and shelled oats were spread on the cement floor like kraft paper. Oats like cold, tolerate drought, and are resistant to salt and alkali. They have been cultivated by Guansai border people since ancient times. They are easy to feel full after eating and difficult to digest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the afternoon, I passed a poplar forest and faintly smelled the scent of sheep. There are a group of sheep in the forest, heads gathering together, as if they are performing some kind of silent ceremony. I sneaked into the woods quietly, fearing to disturb them. Unexpectedly, the owner of the sheep suddenly appeared and startled me. A woman wearing pink sneakers holds a mobile phone and a whip in her hands, and a baseball cap on her head is embroidered with the Chanel logo. I asked her what the sheep were doing together, and she said they didn&#39;t like to move when they were full. I said: There are thirty of them, right? She said there were more than seventy of them, clustered in a pile so they couldn’t be counted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;White impeller, circular pointer. Rotating, without beginning or end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/jvmN7nZl3VkQS06XfxjZbn4bpxBAThbh1jGDRrSj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/jvmN7nZl3VkQS06XfxjZbn4bpxBAThbh1jGDRrSj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253668&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Oats waiting to be harvested&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wan On the winding country road, I met another shepherd. He was old and walked slowly. He was leaning on a dead branch in his left hand and holding a ewe in his right hand. The ewe has a stubborn character and keeps wrestling with the old man, trying to break free. The reins connecting them are stretched straight. The old man told me that he went to his daughter&#39;s house in a neighboring village to tend sheep early in the morning. The ewe was two years old and had given birth to two litters of two lambs. One lamb was sold for six hundred. The ewe seemed to be eavesdropping on our conversation, nibbling on the sunflower trays on the roadside and looking at us sideways with her yellow eyes. The old man tightened the reins again and made another circle in his hand. He wore several layers of clothes, and his red baseball cap was embroidered with the logo - ×× Fertilizer. &quot;It will take an hour until we get home,&quot; he put the tip of his tongue against his sunken lips, with a hint of complaint in his tone, &quot;I forgot to put on my dentures when I went out, and my daughter stayed to eat...&quot; I glanced at his dark mouth, with only the lower gums remaining. A loose crooked tooth is like a stone monument in the dark night. I think of another &quot;mouth&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/i3VIfLsnnkMqtKL9vctv3GvstFEtBAhv7dzQi5pi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/i3VIfLsnnkMqtKL9vctv3GvstFEtBAhv7dzQi5pi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253676&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the poplar forest, well-fed sheep&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The autumn wilderness is colorful and full of temptation. Not long after driving out of Zhangbei County, I couldn&#39;t wait to leave the main road and drove toward the distant hills, dragging the yellow dust cloud behind the car. Went around several old elm trees covered with moss, turned two turns, and finally reached a plateau. A van was parked next to a wheat field, with black film on the windows and half-open side windshield of the cab, without a driver. The view here is wide and unobstructed: countless white windmills are spinning lazily; harvesters are raising puffs of dust and smoke in the wheat fields; a box of &quot;Gatling&quot; fireworks tubes are lying quietly on the grass after being discharged. Accompanying them are drink bottles, cigarette boxes, grocery bags and tissues with lip gloss stuck on them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The van started suddenly, turned around suddenly, and drove towards the road at an unusual speed. After the van drove away, I noticed that there was a commanding point on the high ground - a hill covered with grass. The hills are surrounded by wheat fields. I stepped over the wheat stubble and patrolled around the mountains. The locusts in the fields were flying like shrapnel. This is an &quot;artificial mountain&quot; about 4 meters high and nearly 8 meters in diameter. The moment I climbed to the top of the mountain, I was glad I stopped in time. There is a hole the size of a wellhead in the middle of the top of the mountain. The entrance of the cave is circular, and the cave wall gradually becomes a trapezoid as it goes down. When it is close to the ground, the tunnel turns into a side cave. The hole was dug cleanly, with no residual soil around it. The entrance of the cave is like an open mouth, shouting silently towards the sky. I turned up my collar and carefully walked down the hill. A civet cat scurried past me with a black bird in its mouth. I was stunned for a moment, then quickly got into the car and drove towards the highway at the speed of a van. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/osadEbuMuW9R6LvoBjVXPvXnJtI0VJm4orM1Oa9j.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/osadEbuMuW9R6LvoBjVXPvXnJtI0VJm4orM1Oa9j.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253669&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Villers drying oats&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two Soldiers were running cross-country on the road. The short one was leading and the tall one was lagging behind. They gasped and turned to look at me. The confusion on their faces flashed across their faces. A pair of middle-aged men and women with oily hair and powdery faces seemed to have improvised. They were carrying shopping bags. They lower their heads in the forest, pick mushrooms, and shoot videos; groups of well-fed Dauri jackdaws sit on the roadside wires, chattering and quarreling. They like to forage among the domestic animals in the pasture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0DzRNolGF5qAJV0y12AMhteoCXhL88VJq6UwHivu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0DzRNolGF5qAJV0y12AMhteoCXhL88VJq6UwHivu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253671&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hills on the highlands&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Past Two villages later, I turned onto another dirt road to see what lay behind the hills. I parked my car halfway up the mountain and walked to the top of the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some cold-resistant vegetation is still taking advantage of the short time in autumn to quietly grow: cold mugwort clinging to the ground; reborn dandelions; potted white daisy; and royal blue delphiniums whose petals are like birds spreading their wings... …&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Nf1UGFVm7curjSE9vwLBXuHuigfVpjDMIWUBrxOw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Nf1UGFVm7curjSE9vwLBXuHuigfVpjDMIWUBrxOw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253675&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Black feathers under the pole&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Sharp syncopation pierced the airflow - a peregrine falcon performed aerobatics in the air, sometimes hovering, sometimes fluttering high, sometimes spiraling into a dive... It seemed to be performing specifically for me. The peregrine falcon is the fastest hunting bird in the world, with speeds exceeding 300 kilometers per hour. I stood there, holding the telescope and not daring to move. Between the loss of focus and the pursuit of focus, I stared at this unpredictable gray-white elf with almost no blinking. I was completely shocked by its transcendent dance of wind, forgetting the existence of time. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lAtDyNMvEhSKnt4nibWeIMLTMnzDui3oZ5PAkQTm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/lAtDyNMvEhSKnt4nibWeIMLTMnzDui3oZ5PAkQTm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253672&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Prop horse&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/waO37yI04NzNYmclZ8TR08gDoVuU77IUxUGQGAYr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;357&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/waO37yI04NzNYmclZ8TR08gDoVuU77IUxUGQGAYr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253670&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot; >;Circular ruts created by drift&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are mountains beyond the mountains. After climbing two hills in a row, I saw the scenery behind the mountains - a basin as big as a playground that was very different from the surroundings. The flat ground was covered with a layer of black stone chips that looked like volcanic ash, and there was no grass growing on it. A strange circular rut appears in the center of the basin. On a collapsed cliff, a wall made of masonry and reinforced concrete was exposed. I looked around and saw no other buildings except the towering windmill. I guess the purpose of this place is: mining factory, school, pasture, experimental base...it seems none of them. Another possibility suddenly occurred to me - fortifications. In the 1960s, Sino-Soviet relations broke down. In order to prevent a large-scale invasion by the Soviet Union, our country built a large number of defense fortifications along the borders of North China, Northeast China, and Northwest China. Fortunately, a large-scale war did not break out, and the useless fortifications gradually turned into historical relics that no one cared about. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I regret not bringing a tent with me on this trip. This is an ideal camping spot. Open, hidden, leeward, silent, the surrounding scene is shrouded in a mysterious science fiction color. Funnel spiders swung back and forth between the rocks, searching for joints; ant ants dragged the dying wasps forward; white butterflies stood on the porous basalt and fluttered their wings. Every life is the crystallization of billions of years. A blue pebble shaped like a snake egg jumped into sight. After examining it, I knocked it against a rock. Miraculously, the 3 mm-thick &quot;eggshell&quot; split into two and fell off completely. There was a hard stone heart hidden inside, as black as a crow&#39;s feathers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/eOSVuWtlfvdRqjTWJnDAhRPPxmyLunqGyGM0vdMl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/eOSVuWtlfvdRqjTWJnDAhRPPxmyLunqGyGM0vdMl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253673&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xiang Road Station&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rotating white Paddle, the wind catcher of all seasons. White forests of wind turbines spread across the wilderness. In the past decade, they have grown on a large scale in windy areas such as grasslands, Gobis, and oceans. It&#39;s like an extraterrestrial visitor invading the earth. It&#39;s so white that it&#39;s so cold, so white that it&#39;s unexpected. I stood under the wind turbine, looking up at this behemoth a hundred meters high, counting the number of revolutions of the blades, 1, 2, 3... turn - turn - turn - unknowingly getting lost in the superposition of numbers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6cbAFysqlTsaywodYHQSKuPNfo2kU2KuvEEPGROX.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;358&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6cbAFysqlTsaywodYHQSKuPNfo2kU2KuvEEPGROX.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253674&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Waiting in the wind&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Jiang Xiaoming/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wind energy, Electric energy can do anything. Returning to the parking place, the windmill in my mind was still spinning. I sat on the grass and made a pot of tea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ancient time, original silence. In autumn in the north of Saibei, a fish-shaped floating cloud floated in the clear sky, and after a while, it was blown away by the wind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>