<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[亲友借债找我担保：给别人无限兜底，自己终将无法自拔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258565]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“A relative whom I haven’t seen for many years asked me to provide guarantee for his huge personal debt. After being refused, he viciously insulted me. What should I do if I am still scolded by my relatives for not saving my life?&quot; This post on the Internet points to the darkness of human nature and the plight of a soft-hearted person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amplifying one&#39;s own financial problems into problems related to relatives. Once he cannot get what he wants, he will immediately break up and hit the other party with a moral stick, not hesitate to ruin his reputation within the family. He can be described as a philistine, cold and cold person. cruel. Of course, we cannot let such an approach go unchecked. Relative relationships are based on blood and are particularly tender, but this does not mean that one person has the responsibility and obligation to save another person from financial crisis. This is the first thing the questioner who panics after being scolded should understand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This matter is like a wedge, attracting resonance and complaints from many netizens. The story told by a netizen is quite typical. There was once a classmate who had not been in contact for many years. I didn’t know where to get the phone number and found him. I asked him to borrow tens of thousands of dollars. Of course, the respondent politely refused, so the other party downgraded to 10,000, and finally the borrowed amount becomes 1,000. Faced with such moral kidnapping, the respondent hung up the phone and blocked the other party. This situation is quite common, because many people will face a relative or friend who appears out of nowhere and asks for help. If you don&#39;t agree, there is a high probability that you will be teased by the other party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you have the ability, you can consider borrowing money. Even if you don&#39;t pay it back, if the amount is not large, it probably won&#39;t hurt your muscles and bones. However, among all kinds of private economic relationships, guaranteeing for others can be called the most confusing and dangerous behavior. One respondent told such an incident: His cousin and cousin-in-law opened a wood processing factory with others, and asked him to use his marriage certificate as a guarantee for his brother-in-law and sister-in-law to get a loan of 100,000 yuan. He didn&#39;t agree, and his cousin didn&#39;t give up and kept trying in various ways, but in the end he didn&#39;t agree. And inadvertently he learned that his cousin had no such thing as partnering with others to open a factory, and his cousin was already extremely poor. He felt afraid. If he agreed in a hurry, the matter would be on the line. If something happened in the middle, wouldn&#39;t all the pressure be put on him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of those seeking help, in addition to some who wantonly deceive and &quot;trap&quot; their relatives and friends, there are also many who ask for help with the truth of their embarrassment. Therefore, it is not necessary to classify all help seekers as untrustworthy &quot;others&quot;. But even so, we still need to treat others&#39; requests for help with rationality and calmness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, more and more people have started businesses, and the demand for investment, funds, and guarantees has naturally increased. Some people embark on a project with the determination to &quot;go bankrupt&quot;. Once the funds cannot keep up and the overall situation collapses, the first thing they think of when they are anxious is to find relatives and friends to help, maybe with profit, or with love. , in short, I hope relatives and friends will lend a helping hand. This sentiment is understandable, but the specific response is worthy of discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A friend told me that he was asked by his cousin to mortgage his property in exchange for life-saving money to receive a blood transfusion to extend his life. But after careful consideration, he still declined because he only had two apartments, one for himself and one for rent to support his family. He had neither the extra power to help others nor the substantial ability to withstand risks to &quot;cover the bottom line.&quot; The cousin naturally complained a lot. But he felt that he was not capable of not helping his cousin, nor did he cause any harm to his cousin&#39;s interests, so he felt no guilt. What&#39;s more, he later learned that his cousin was not the only one who had spoken to him, nor was he the only one who refused. The stakes of this matter are actually this: the real estate matter is a family&#39;s wealth and life, and it cannot withstand the storm at all. The cousin&#39;s request itself is a bit excessive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes in Guangdong, &quot;If you don&#39;t play the middle, you don&#39;t play the guarantee, and you don&#39;t play the matchmaker, the three generations will be good.&quot; Throughout the ages, many guarantors have suffered so much that their intestines turned green because of a single guarantor, so they left &quot;ancient precepts&quot; to warn future generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Securing a guarantee may seem like a simple matter of signing and making a pledge, but the truth is that it is not the case. Providing a guarantee is indeed a major matter involving serious legal consequences, and its severity often exceeds the financial capacity of an ordinary family. No matter how the guarantee is provided, once the guaranteed person runs away, the corresponding legal consequences are entirely likely to be passed on to the guarantor. There are countless examples of this. A few years ago, the Tianning District Court of Changzhou City, Jiangsu Province enforced a case in which the guarantor paid 255,000 yuan because the borrower &quot;ran away&quot;. It is also common for the guarantor to be restricted from spending too much and taking high-speed trains and airplanes because of being implicated. After the guarantee fails, there are many examples of marital discord and divorce, which is really not worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People in the legal profession remind you that there are many pitfalls in guaranteeing others. For example, if there is no guarantee share when writing the IOU, the guarantor will bear joint liability. The reason why some guarantors make &quot;missteps&quot; is, on the one hand, because they cannot save face, and on the other hand, they agree rashly because they have little understanding of the risks and responsibilities they may bear. As everyone knows, your &quot;loyalty&quot; is making it difficult for you to &quot;protect yourself.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a person is in a realistic economic status and family situation, he should not shoot himself in the foot out of impulse. Instead, he should decisively say &quot;no&quot; to unreasonable requests for help. Undoubtedly, if you can&#39;t protect yourself well, how can you &quot;protect&quot; others? You know, when you get into a lot of trouble because of a wrong decision in a moment, most of the people who asked you to be your guarantee will not come out to save you. In comparison, the reputation you bear for refusing to guarantee is the smallest price to pay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, you have the right to defend your rights if you are insulted, ostracized, and ruined by your relatives because of your refusal to provide guarantee. The worst case scenario is to &quot;swear&quot; him back, or simply break up the family relationship. The best way to deal with family kidnapping is to see the trick first. In short, no matter what the situation, you can&#39;t just pretend to be fat and get involved in other people&#39;s financial whirlpool that has nothing to do with you just because you have a good relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the final analysis, regarding the controversy surrounding guarantees, a sense of boundaries should be established. It is true that we are relatives, and we are true that we are brothers and sisters. We should be cautious about boundaries. We can neither force others nor make unreasonable demands, nor can we be forced by others and agree to unreasonable demands. There is a saying in Nanjing, where I live, that &quot;if relatives don&#39;t share wealth, there will be no sharing of wealth.&quot; This is also derived from many lessons. The essence of this statement is that among people, it is your duty to live your own life and solve your own problems. Relatives and friends can indeed help each other, as long as it is within the scope of their abilities and does not affect their own lives. This is also the meaning of family ties. However, when dealing with major financial issues, you should never cross the boundaries and bottom lines and rashly give unlimited benefits to others. Keeping things secret will eventually make you sink into a quagmire that you can&#39;t extricate yourself from. At this point, not only will your relatives be unable to do anything, your life and family may also be over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is the author&#39;s personal opinion only and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style= &quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[重庆33层高楼底层挖出“四室一厅”，街道要求恢复原状]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258605]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[普通话是满式汉语吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258561]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, the US &quot;National Geographic&quot; published a tweet: &quot;Chinese Mandarin is only Chinese?&quot; This Mandarin Just Disappeared&quot;, which stated that Manchu was once the official language of China&#39;s 300 million people, but now it has disappeared. After this tweet was sent out, it immediately attracted ridicule and complaints from many Chinese netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author has read the general content of this article. To be fair, this tweet is indeed full of errors and omissions. It is obviously stitched together by randomly searching a few Manchu-related articles on the Internet, and the materials used are of mixed quality. Manchu was the official language of the Qing Dynasty. At its peak, the population was more than 300 million. The expression &quot;the official language of a population of 300 million&quot; is not entirely wrong. But the numbers are still debatable. After all, the population in the late Qing Dynasty reached more than 400 million. In addition, there are far more serious errors in this tweet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, one of them says:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Although Manchu has disappeared, Mandarin is actually Mandarin. Chinese, Beijing dialect and Northeastern dialect have many Manchu sounds. The stains left behind after the clothes are stained with dirty things are called He Leng in Northeastern dialect, and the original meaning in Manchu is ripples of water. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The oil has gone bad. It is called &quot;Haweier&quot; in Beijing dialect, which comes from the Manchu har, and its original meaning is The spicy smell hits my nose. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Smoothing out wrinkled things is called Masa in Northeastern dialect, and the original meaning in Manchu is to stretch. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been studying Manchu for a while, and it is not difficult to find that this large paragraph is full of fallacies: 1. The ripple in Manchu is irahi or iren, which is completely different from the pronunciation of &quot;he Leng&quot;. coherent. 2. The use of &quot;ha&quot; to describe the smell of spoiled oil is very common in Xiang, Wu, Min, and Southwest Mandarin. This is obviously a native Chinese word. The original character is (left stink and right harm). Because this character is so uncommon, it was written as the homophone &quot;ha&quot;. 3. As for the word &quot;Masa&quot; in Northeastern dialect, which means soothing, it is obviously the word &quot;Momo&quot;, and there is no doubt about its meaning and pronunciation. The Manchu word &quot;stretch&quot; is sarahvn, which is completely different from &quot;masa&quot; - you have to ask if there is any word in Manchu that has the same pronunciation as &quot;stroke&quot;, and it is true, but the Manchu word &quot;masa&quot; means to play on a swing. It means...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, if you search this paragraph online, you will find that it was copied from various self-media accounts. The original authors of these accounts, as well as the author of this tweet who copied them indiscriminately, obviously do not understand Manchu at all. I don’t know where they got these rumors from and made them up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Mandarin/Beijing/Northeastern dialect is Manchu Chinese&quot; is also a famous old rumor - linguists have long determined that there is basically no Manchu in Beijing dialect and Northeastern dialect. Vocabulary, grammar and pronunciation have not been influenced by Manchu. Missionaries who came to China during the Ming Dynasty recorded the Ming Dynasty Beijing dialect using Western alphabet spelling, and there was no obvious difference from modern Beijing dialect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, rumors like &quot;Manchu is everywhere in the Northeast&quot; are still very popular today. For example, the place name Changchun is often said to be the transliteration of the Manchu &quot;Cha Ah Chong&quot; - however, there is no word &quot;Cha Ah Chong&quot; in Manchu at all. The name of Changchun began with the establishment of &quot;Cha Ah Chong&quot; in Jilin during the Liao Dynasty. &quot;Changchun Prefecture&quot; is obviously a Chinese place name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you really want to count the Manchu words in Beijing dialect and Northeastern dialect, they basically only have nouns like &quot;Shaqima&quot;. However, this kind of vocabulary borrowing is inevitable. Cantonese and Hokkien also have the word Shaqima. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, if you think about it for a moment, you will understand that Manchu will not leave many traces in northern Chinese. This is just like there are basically no Aboriginal words in American English. There are no Austronesian features in Taiwanese Hokkien. Because Chinese is a language that has matured a long time ago and has a very rich and sufficient vocabulary, there is basically no need to borrow words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If there are any concepts that are easier to express in Manchu, they are basically related to fishing and hunting. For example, there are many words in Manchu to describe pigs of different ages, dogs of different colors, and various methods of fishing... But neither the Han citizens in Beijing nor the Han farmers traveling to Guandong need to use these. Fishing and hunting vocabulary. In turn, Manchu words related to agriculture, industry and commerce, academia, and science and technology are basically borrowed from Chinese - for example, the Manchu word &quot;gong&quot; means &quot;gung&quot;, the word &quot;jin&quot; means &quot;gin&quot;, the word &quot;stone mill&quot; means &quot;mose&quot; (mill), and the word &quot;baby&quot; means boobai. ...all borrowed from Chinese. Another example is &quot;body&quot;. Most other Tungusic words are words like beye. But Manchu is ᠪᡝᠶᡝ ᡩᡠᡵᠰᡠᠨ=beye (body) + dursun (physique) = body...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese only used synonymous compounds for redundancy checking after the degeneracy of the medieval phonology system. In Manchu, beye is already a two-syllable word. Wouldn’t it be too verbose to add dursun? What’s even more amazing is that the Manchu word “child” is actually ᡶᡠᠯᡤᡳᠶᠠᠨ ᠵᡠᡳ (fulgiyan jui) – literally meaning “red fetus”...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is a little outrageous to understand child as a red fetus, But I can barely find some ancient books to support it. But the Manchu word for &quot;naked&quot; is also fulahvn beye (light red body), and &quot;barefoot&quot; is fulahvn bethe (light red legs). This is a completely literal mechanical translation, and the wrong meaning is chosen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern genetic testing has found that the Tungusic speaking populations (such as Hezhe, Xibe, Ewenki, Oroqen, etc.) are genetically consistent, but the Manchus are an exception - the Manchus have obvious blood differences with other Tungusic populations, but are more similar to the Han people There is basically no difference. A molecular anthropology institution tested 2,938 Manchus and found that only about 3% had Tungusic ancestry, even lower than their southern Han ancestry (6.57%). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The modern Manchus are basically indistinguishable from the Han in blood, which implies that the Manchus have intermarryed with the Han on a large scale over the past few hundred years, and in the end the Tungus bloodline was diluted to the point that it was negligible. Before the emergence of modern media and compulsory education, anyone’s mother tongue was learned through blood transmission. If every generation of a Manchu family intermarry with the Han people, the bloodline, language, customs, and culture of a group of people will not be any different from those of the Han people, and it will be difficult to distinguish them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[赵红程：无障碍通行，不只有轮椅人士需要]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256808]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;How to understand barrier-free access? She is skilled in wheelchair driving. She has released more than a hundred city accessibility evaluation videos. She has falsified the &quot;need for gratitude&quot; and told the public not to have endless pity. &quot;Give up being condescending and give up false concern. We should be friends.&quot; !&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678020725550870&quot; data-media =&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;People Weekly Issue 766 Youth Power Zhao Hongcheng Video.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/17/f1ecwIvAVZ4NqjMwdtC7yBzco9Htg2T1pO42EUrC.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/5aa5934a5576678020725550 870/cx3pjkQur5oA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot; 360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/5aa5934a5576678020725550870/cx3pjkQur5oA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Accessibility It seems that the only way to attract people&#39;s attention is to take an eccentric approach. Recently, videos of young people from many places “commuting to get off work in electric wheelchairs” have appeared on social media, sparking heated discussions. Suddenly, accessibility became an issue of public concern and in urgent need of “management.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I really don’t understand how the topic ‘Young people focus on electric wheelchairs’ became so popular.” Zhao Hongcheng, an accessibility evaluation video blogger, expressed his doubts. As a former product manager of a major manufacturer, Zhao Hongcheng expressed his doubts. , she thinks this is obviously a marketing tool for businesses, &quot;Can you go out 100 meters in an electric wheelchair? Can people drive here? Open your eyes and take a look at the barrier-free facilities here. Let people who should go out first be able to go out. , and then think about how to &#39;manage&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/uGJx4Wh4nUQk9YhMNtxKakJusCqNwtUHVsim7EIP.jpg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/uGJx4Wh4nUQk9YhMNtxKakJusCqNwtUHVsim7EIP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250533&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/250873&quot; title=&quot;The story of wheelchair girl Zhao Hongcheng &quot;Accessibility&quot; drama: Do I make you nervous? &quot;>;Wheelchair girl Zhao Hongcheng&#39;s &quot;Accessibility&quot; drama: Do I make you nervous? &lt;/a>; 》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Hongcheng contracted polio when she was 1 year old and was in a wheelchair when she was in middle school. Today, she is quite skilled in wheelchair driving. She has been releasing videos on city accessibility assessments since 2019. After resigning from the Internet industry two years ago, she turned into a full-time video blogger. The video she produced, &quot;Black and Red List of Barrier-free Facilities,&quot; was once on Weibo&#39;s hot search list. So far, she has released more than a hundred urban accessibility assessment videos, covering Shanghai, Hangzhou, Guangzhou, Macau, and Taiwan, showing the daily life and travel obstacles encountered by people with disabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation shows that as of 2022, the total number of disabled people in China will reach more than 85 million, accounting for more than 6% of the total population. However, they are rarely seen in public places. On June 28, 2023, the third meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress voted to pass the Barrier-free Environment Construction Law. This law will come into effect on September 1, 2023. On March 1, 2023, the &quot;Shanghai Barrier-free Environment Construction Regulations&quot; came into effect. More and more people are aware of the importance of barrier-free environment construction, but it is not easy for the city&#39;s supporting system to keep up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a Shanghai accessibility evaluation video, when Zhao Hongcheng and her husband went to watch a talk show, they asked the theater staff about the location of the accessible toilets. The staff suggested that you can use diapers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Hongcheng believes that for-profit cultural and artistic venues such as art exhibitions and theaters are the &quot;hardest hit areas&quot; for accessibility. &quot;It seems that as a disabled person, you can confidently make demands when traveling on the subway, but in terms of cultural enjoyment, your confidence will be much weaker.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the evaluation video, Zhao Hongcheng still tried Go swimming, go to Disney, go to Universal Studios, and document it on video. The inconvenience of legs and feet should not ultimately constitute difficulties in the entire living system of the disabled group because the city&#39;s supporting facilities are not in place. She hopes to promote the construction of barrier-free facilities in the country, and also hopes to bring people with disabilities, a long-marginalized social group, into the spotlight, be seen and have their own voice. &quot;Sometimes when I go out and walk on the street, I can find out from many people&#39;s expressions and questions that I am the first person in a wheelchair they have seen in their lives.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 In May, the one-man drama &quot;Where is the nearest barrier-free toilet?&quot; based on Zhao Hongcheng. ” was staged at the Shanghai Grand Theater. It is the first domestic drama adapted from real people with disabilities. The first row of seats under the stage has been opened up as barrier-free wheelchair seats. Audiences in wheelchairs are seated in every performance, including 20 audience members in wheelchairs in one performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the stage, Zhao Hongcheng uses a dramatic performance to present her travel difficulties. Her daily travel is sometimes like an urban adventure: car horns, bus announcements, chaotic voices, and cars passing by. Amidst the noise, she drove her wheelchair around the city, not knowing which direction would be less obstructed. No matter how early she left her home, she was always late. Those praises for &quot;self-improvement&quot;, the prying eyes of strangers, the &quot;good intentions&quot; of others doing good, and the selective ignorance on more occasions... &quot;It seems that I always need to be constantly grateful.&quot; said Zhao Hongcheng, the lead actor in the drama and the prototype of the story. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Of all my expectations for this drama project, the most important point is that I need to make this happen. I want a story about people with disabilities to be staged in the theater.&quot; Successive dramas After the performance, Zhao Hongcheng felt that he finally had his own voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This drama will be performed in Beijing on September 16. Zhao Hongcheng still pays attention to all information about barrier-free access on the Internet, and directly expresses his attitude towards some inexplicable pity, &quot;Give up being condescending and give up false concern, we should be friends!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打开神圣的脑袋，然后看到酸奶？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258555]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/13/guTmGuLhlDxsn6PvXLncoSm5LIiFtvTXlHrYe9hK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/guTmGuLhlDxsn6PvXLncoSm5LIiFtvTXlH rYe9hK. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254029&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2019, a craniotomy in Texas, USA. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I sometimes think of a boy I met in the hospital. He leaned at the window to check in and tried to pay a hefty deposit using WeChat. I asked the middle-aged woman behind me if I should line up behind her. She didn&#39;t quite understand and seemed a little timid. She was guarding a wheelchair that looked like an Iron Throne. There was a long metal rod sticking out of the back of the chair, and something seemed to be hanging on the top. There was a lot of luggage piled on the seat of the chair. The owner must have been transferred from out of town for medical treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The child was unable to pay the fee for a while, but fortunately the staff did not get upset and suggested him to check the limit in a business-like manner. His bones were obviously deformed, his back was severely twisted, and his skull was covered with a metal band. Thick metal wires are twisted at different locations on the hoop, and the one in the middle above the head is particularly tall. Looking at his back, he looks like an adult suffering from bone disease. After he paid the fee and turned around, I determined that he was a child slightly over ten years old. The woman and him should be mother and son, and the extra-sturdy wheelchair was probably made especially for him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a while while waiting to be admitted, I met the boy again. Because of the epidemic, the seats had to be spaced apart, so they were almost occupied, so I walked around to him. He pointed to the only empty seat next to him and made a friendly &quot;please sit down&quot; gesture. A child at such a young age is subjected to severe torture and yet appears to be sensible and self-respecting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With his mother by his side, he can take care of his daily life, but the paperwork involved probably won’t be of much help. The boy has to try for himself and slowly digest the good, evil and bleakness of the world. During the nucleic acid test, we talked about the child and became sad. I said he might be an astronaut, and now he has an antenna that can receive signals from outside. Hopefully it was a passable good-natured joke and he was actually memorable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After we were admitted to the hospital, I never met him again. It was only after I was discharged from the hospital that I determined that those steel brackets were specially used to help correct the bones. A few days ago, when I was about to finish reading &quot;Craniotomy: A Collection of Medical Stories that &quot;Turn on the Nerves&quot;&quot;, I found an illustration of a headband vest in the book, which was very similar to the system I saw two years ago. The Chinese version of this book was published in August 2023, and the original English version was published about a year ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Weird thing in my head&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The hospitalization was upgraded to a craniotomy at another hospital. I had a very large &quot;left middle cerebral artery aneurysm&quot; in my head that was compressing the left temporal lobe, which is responsible for language. I always think of the title of Pamuk&#39;s book &quot;The Strange Thing in My Head&quot;. The &quot;strange thing&quot; that belongs to me is like a pigeon egg. Its size and location are very rare. I don&#39;t know when it started growing secretly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am now particularly interested in patients, stories and social news about cerebrovascular diseases. People with cerebral hemorrhage are always racing against time, experiencing severe headaches they have never experienced before, and the most unfortunate people are experiencing the last days of their lives. In the news, people around them often don’t realize what is happening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above are the reasons why I am particularly interested in &quot;Craniotomy&quot;. The author, Jay Wellens, is the chief physician of pediatric neurosurgery who has performed thousands of various surgeries. There are only 250 practicing physicians in this subspecialty in North America. He has mastered the art of performing neurosurgery on fetuses in the womb, helping them live healthy lives from birth. If the boy I met was so lucky, he would no longer face endless pain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Craniotomy&quot; does not have a strict main line. From time to time, he recalled his father who suffered from ALS. He was in his last year of medical school and &quot;about to embark on an extraordinary residency career&quot; when he discovered his father was ill. His father passed away suddenly a year later, which naturally made him empathize with the patients&#39; families. Nothing is closer to human nature than life and death, and fragmentary stories also contain huge spiritual power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the spring of his 15th year of practice, Dr. Wellens rescued a three-year-old boy who suffered a gunshot wound. He studied creative writing and calmly described the tragedy of the scene:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During the emergency, the breathing tube was fixed OK, the infusion tube has also been left in place. The boy&#39;s head was covered with half-coagulated blood, which pooled under his head and dripped to the ground like wax. As the crowd gathered around him, the bloody footprints became larger and larger. People came and went, holding bulging intravenous blood transfusion bags or saline, and syringes filled with medicine, all trying to help him stabilize. blood pressure. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Emergency rooms are always cruel. The child&#39;s head is beyond recognition and blood gushes out from several points on the edge of the bone. Wellens devotes three-quarters of a page to describing the tense situation, and it takes him only two seconds to see it all. It is a brain with a sophisticated structure (the author describes it as &quot;sacred&quot;). The feat in the eyes of readers is taken for granted by doctors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wellens participated in an operation to treat newborn twins who were joined at the back of their heads. They were born extremely premature and one of the children was in critical condition due to intestinal necrosis. The doctors decided to perform emergency separation, cut the skin, opened the skull and dura mater, and everything went well. But on the third hour of the operation, they suddenly suffered a massive hemorrhage, and eventually all blood flow stopped. He would always remember crying as he resewed the twins back together to give his parents a chance to hold them again. &quot;We should have sacrificed one to save the other, but we wanted to save both, and both died.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Wellens also wrote about mentors who died young and angry patients. Family members, testimonies for victims of quackery, and paranoia about their children’s medical conditions. Along with some less dramatic scenes, he draws inspiration from everyday life. On the one hand, it reflects his wisdom, on the other hand, it is simply the power brought by medicine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two stories that impressed me deeply. They are both humorous and moving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wellens often answers questions from adults and children: What does the brain look like? He would answer: &quot;Like yogurt. Creamy vanilla-flavored yogurt.&quot; Then add: &quot;Like very thick yogurt, the kind where the spoon can stand upright in it.&quot; Everyone&#39;s reaction is likely to be: Oh, this topic That&#39;s it for now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, he went on to expertly describe the land flowing with milk and honey he saw after the craniotomy:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is a sight that not many people have seen before. It will seem strange at first, and the surface of the moon was no different to its early visitors. But unlike the lunar surface, which is a barren gray, the surface of the human brain is awash with color and luster, full of dimension and depth. It takes a moment for your eyes to adjust to the sudden brightness. The surface of the brain is very smooth, indeed cream-colored, with only a faint hint of yellow. It shines under the reflection of the microscope...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another story happened when he was chief resident. He often goes to the department director late at night to &quot;check the list&quot; to understand the patient&#39;s condition and then arrange the next treatment plan. One night, he saw the director outside the office carefully flipping through an anatomy textbook and reviewing the parts for tomorrow&#39;s surgery. Next, he also reviewed anatomy during the final hours of the night before surgery. &quot;This has become a ritual.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Lost Day&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Including anesthesia time, my own surgery took about fourteen hours , there will always be a shallow trench left on the left side of the head. I call this day &quot;The Lost Day.&quot; So I read craniotomy cases very carefully, looking for clues that lasted more than ten hours. I didn&#39;t understand before how the skull opened and in what direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One of the endearing things is what Wellens said: &quot;I removed my first aneurysm and passed the rite of passage as a surgical resident.&quot; I couldn&#39;t fully understand what he explained again and again. nervous system. However, when I saw that the Latin name of dura mater means &quot;strong mother&quot;, the shock of discovering the truth was beyond words, like a wake-up call. By the way, the English words &quot;doctor&quot; and &quot;patient&quot; come from the Latin words &quot;teach&quot; and &quot;patient&quot; respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first thing I heard when I woke up was the intern doctor chatting with his colleagues, saying that I was a reporter, and talking about their overtime wages. The operating table was a little bumpy as it left the elevator, and I fell asleep again. When I woke up, I was in the ICU, a hall-like place with curtains, and occasionally people walking around. When the nurse was about to leave work, I bled a lot. I fell asleep and woke up alternately. Early in the morning, an elderly doctor took off my oxygen tube. There are equipment such as shadowless lights set up above the hospital bed, much like an operating room. I asked a nurse on patrol if the equipment was real. She turned her head and looked up, but did not answer the question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Are these all true? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next step was edema from surgery. My appearance was beyond recognition and frightened some people close to me. I couldn&#39;t use my phone anymore, and I couldn&#39;t type a grammatical sentence into my phone. Over and over, each five-minute round, I surrendered in frustration. Emoji has become one of the greatest inventions in the world. These simple and crude symbols have become the only communication channel between you and the distant place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days later, I started watching the second season of &quot;Secret Forest&quot; on my iPad. Sometimes I even felt that I could understand Korean, but I couldn&#39;t tell the difference between reading the subtitles and listening to the dialogue. Don’t forget, this season is about the struggle between prosecutors and police that may be difficult for Korean viewers to understand. I often mention this hallucination for fun. Needless to say, it was really a surprise at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few days after the surgery I read the autobiography of neurologist Oliver Sacks, and in those pages it seemed like he was coming out. I turned the autobiography to the cover and showed it to Sun Liyong, the visiting surgeon, to show how amazing my recovery was. But I gave up halfway and never opened this book again after I was discharged from hospital. I have long been fond of Sachs’s books that explore the mysteries of brain nerves, and I should continue to read them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I opened the book, it turned out that what I read was the third chapter &quot;Wolf Boy&quot;. The beginning of the paragraph is unruly:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In broad daylight, I am the friendly Dr. Sachs in white robe;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;But when night falls, I will take off my white robe, put on my motorcycle leather jacket, and remain anonymous.&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sneaking out of the hospital like a wolf, wandering the streets, or riding the winding roads up Mount Tamalpais,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Then, under the moonlight, we drove all the way to Stinson Beach. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After discharge, there will be language training and hyperbaric oxygen inhalation. The oxygen chamber is like a submarine. Administrators and doctors can see people taking oxygen through small round windows. There was a bald man who would laugh involuntarily, laughing endlessly, contagiously making everyone laugh. There was no sound when he laughed. Think of the scene in the movie where the sound suddenly disappears and everyone only opens their mouths but cannot hear the words. I can&#39;t remember how the man stopped. He was usually silent and had not yet recovered from his stroke. It was his wife who spoke, telling how his cerebrovascular disease recurred many years after its onset. She and the other wives have always shown extraordinary steadfastness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After I took oxygen, I often went to a New Element restaurant to eat salads and drink juice, and got to know the staff. However, this comforting restaurant closed down during the epidemic. There were sixty nails driven into my head, the shape of which looked like staples. After a while, a serious and professional nurse removed them, thirty pills at a time. After tearing off the tape on my head, I shivered for about half a minute, probably like a calf trembling when it is born. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first scene of aphasia became increasingly blurry, and the &quot;strange thing&quot; was discovered a year later. The words in my head were very clear and grammatical, but what came out of my mouth was just a meaningless sound of Ulu Uru. Does it sound like a crow? During the period when my aphasia became more and more frequent, I whispered &quot;Eat grapes without spitting out grape skins&quot; from time to time to test whether I could speak normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Long after surgery, fear occasionally strikes. It is invisible and fades quickly. Anyway, those brave young people in &quot;Open Skull&quot; are definitely my role models. When I see aneurysm patients in books and in real life, I will secretly identify them as the same kind. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;他的灵魂也慢慢失去了知觉&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;杰罗姆·格鲁普曼在为《纽约客》撰写的书评里回顾了医生们的作品。从儿科专家佩里·克拉斯针对医学生生活的回忆录《不完全良性的手术》，到英国外科医生亨利·马什自我剖析行医三十多年中所犯错误的《医生的抉择》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，韦伦斯行医二十多年时写出的《开颅》就可以放在这两本书中间了。有意思的是，马什同样精于神经外科手术，秉持着“严禁伤害”（即英文版书名，Do No Harm）的自我要求。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无疑，脑是人之为人的关键。而医学一目了然地连接着生死、人性和痛苦，与其他事物的关联没那么直白，但并不出人意料，比如文学。医学和文学的结合非常迷人，韦伦斯在全书起始就引用了《都柏林人》中《死者》的一句话：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;他听着雪簌簌地落在全世界的每个地方，簌簌地落着，就如它们落向最后的归宿，落在一切活人与死者身上；他的灵魂也慢慢失去了知觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于前面提到的不幸去世的连体双胞胎，格鲁普曼想到了理查德·塞尔泽的短篇小说《伊梅尔达》。赛尔泽是外科医生兼作家，在医生中“第一批理解写作、阅读小说在医学中的力量”，曾经指导过约翰·欧文。小说里，一个冷漠、傲慢又奉行完美主义的美国外科医生去洪都拉斯执行慈善任务，计划为腭裂女孩伊梅尔达动手术，但女孩在手术前因麻醉并发症去世。医生晚上潜入太平间为尸体完成了手术，使母亲可以安葬医治完毕的女儿。医生因此一蹶不振，无法从不尽如人意的结果中恢复。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好在韦伦斯接受了师友的鼓励，走出挫败，明白人的局限性。人没法做到无所不能，但可以理解局限并做得更好。担任神外主治医师之余，他还取得了流行病学的硕士学位。 “这个学位开辟了我人生中的一个全新面向，我开始根据种族、社会经济地位和性别的不同，研究神经外科患儿获得的医疗服务差异。”同时，他还关注着枪支泛滥、疫苗怀疑论等众多社会问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哥伦比亚大学内科学教授丽塔·卡伦提出了“叙事医学”概念，即具有叙事能力的临床工作者所实践的医学。叙事能力就是认识、吸收、解释并被疾病故事感动的能力。格鲁普曼特别提到两位医生的短篇小说，即契诃夫的《出诊》与威廉·卡洛斯·威廉斯的《满脸粉刺的女孩》，它们探讨了病人与周遭环境的互动关系。当然，中国读者应该更容易想到“弃医从文”的鲁迅。医生们敏锐地观察到并精确表述世界的真相，邀请公众思考，令个体的改变延伸到整个社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写这篇书评时的某一天，我意外发现了孙医生普及医学知识的抖音号，一条一条地看了很久。除了关于门诊和案例的短视频，他还祝福高考的考生们，说起医科学生将面对的漫漫长路。我结束一次复诊，即将离开诊室时，他提起看过的德剧《夏利特医院》。回到熙熙攘攘的走道前夕，我好像收到了医生突然送来的彩蛋。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[2024国考明起开始报名，共计划招录3.96万人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258599]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 10:43:57&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;记者从国家公务员局获悉，中央机关及其直属机构2024年度考试录用公务员报名即将开始，共计划招录3.96万人。考生可于10月15日8:00至10月24日18:00期间登录“中央机关及其直属机构2024年度考试录用公务员专题网站”(http://bm.scs.gov.cn/kl2024)进行网上报名，公共科目笔试将于11月26日在全国各直辖市、省会城市、自治区首府和部分较大的城市同时举行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本次考试录用公务员工作主要有3个方面特点:一是坚持政治标准放在首位，突出把好新录用人员政治关。其中，笔试、面试内容突出公务员的政治属性，重点测查用党的创新理论指导分析和解决问题的能力;考察全面了解考生的德、能、勤、绩、廉，重点了解政治素质、道德品行、遵纪守法等方面情况。对政治上不合格的坚决不予录用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是录用政策、录用计划向基层一线和高校毕业生倾斜。设置2.6万个计划专门招录应届高校毕业生，服务和促进高校毕业生就业。有近2.7万个计划补充到县(区)级及以下直属机构，根据实际对艰苦边远地区基层职位的学历、专业、工作年限和经历等报考条件进行适当调整，进一步充实基层公务员队伍。设置3000余个计划定向招录服务基层项目人员和在军队服役5年以上的高校毕业生退役士兵，鼓励引导人才向基层一线流动、积极投身国防事业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三是考试录用坚持分类分级考试。考试内容根据不同职位类别、不同层级机关特点分别设置。面试方式和内容由招录机关根据招考职位的性质、特点等研究确定，注重体现履职要求。部分招录机关对考生的专业能力进行测查评价，有9个部门在笔试阶段组织专业科目笔试、40个部门在面试阶段组织专业能力测试。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，国家公务员局提醒广大考生，诚信报名、诚信准备、诚信考试、诚信守约。本次招考不出版也不指定考试辅导用书，不举办也不委托任何机构或者个人举办考试辅导培训班。对于社会上有关公务员考试培训、网站或者出版物等，请广大考生提高警惕、理性对待，避免上当受骗，防止权益受损。国家公务员局将会同有关部门加强管理监督，打击考试作弊，查处违规行为，营造公平公正、安全有序的考试环境。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广州野生动物放生规定来了，随意放生或负刑责！这些动物在列]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258507]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;《广州市野生动物放生管理规定》（以下简称《规定》）将于2023年11月1日起施行。据了解，《规定》结合广州实际，对野生动物放生设立切实可行的管理制度，保护生物安全和生态环境，是国内首部专门规范野生动物放生的地方性法规。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，《规定》对违法放生境外野生动物物种、随意放生境内野生动物可能或者已经造成严重后果、在放生区域以外的其他地方放生境内野生动物的情形设定具体罚则。市民合法放生前，需提前三个工作日登记信息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;立法旨在科学规范放生行为&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;防范外来物种入侵危害&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;2023年中央一号文件提出，严厉打击非法引入外来物种行为，实施重大危害入侵物种防控攻坚行动，加强“异宠”交易与放生规范管理。这也是中央一号文件首次提及“放生”一词。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;放生祈福是我国民间的一种传统文化。不过到了现代社会，由于放生物种及其来源地的多样化和复杂性，不恰当的放生行为给环境、生态、生物、社会和人自身带来了不少问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/741a7c92d83c7e54f97f570272efd5d7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/741a7c92d83c7e54f97f570272efd5d7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253993&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;鳄雀鳝（Atractosteus spatula）。图片来源：中国水产学会科学放鱼科普专家团队&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一方面，野生动物外来物种放生后可能会危害当地生态系统。如果将非原产地的野生动物放生至本地环境中，新物种可能会与本地物种争夺食物和生存空间，繁殖能力强或凶猛的外来物种会对本地物种的生存空间造成威胁，危害当地生态系统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/8648eebe1467d4bd9bdabcac4172d2be.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/8648eebe1467d4bd9bdabcac4172d2be.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253991&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;俗称淡水白鲳的短盖肥脂鲤（Piaractus brachypomus）。图片来源：中国水产学会科学放鱼科普专家团队&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，有毒、凶猛或者未经检疫的野生动物放生后可能会造成他人人身财产损害。如果将有毒、凶猛或者未经检疫的野生动物放生到野外环境，可能会攻击人类或者其它动物，其携带的病毒、细菌也可能通过水域或其它途径传播，给他人人身财产以及生态环境造成危害。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，未经野化训练的野生动物放生到野外后容易导致死亡。如果将未经野化训练的野生动物放生野外或者放生到不适宜生存的野外环境中，可能导致其无法生存而死亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据广州市人大常委会法工委负责人介绍，2022年，广州市人大常委会对《中华人民共和国野生动物保护法》的实施情况进行了执法检查。执法检查中发现一些地方放生活动较为普遍，但没有相应的管理规范，特别是对放生鳄雀鳝、清道夫等外来入侵物种，严重破坏本地生态系统平衡的行为缺乏有效的管理措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法工委负责人表示，目前国家有关生态保护和野生动物保护的法律法规如《中华人民共和国生物安全法》《中华人民共和国野生动物保护法》等对野生动物放生仅做了原则性规定，缺乏可操作的规范。为科学规范野生动物放生行为，防范外来物种入侵危害，有必要进行专门立法。因此，广州市人大常委会将该法规纳入2023年立法工作计划。 &lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;随意放生或将被罚款甚至追究刑事责任&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;市民合法放生需提前三个工作日登记信息&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;为规范放生行为，防止外来物种入侵损害本地生态系统，《规定》明确境外野生动物除法律法规另有规定的，都不能放生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了让公众明确知晓哪些动物不能放生，《规定》还列举了目前较为常见的一些外来野生动物物种，比如鳄雀鳝、豹纹翼甲鲶、齐氏罗非鱼、淡水白鲳、食蚊鱼、埃及塘鲺、泰国鲮鱼、大鳄龟、红耳彩龟、美洲牛蛙等。不仅于此，未列举尽的其他境外野生动物也是不能放生的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/f0308e5e31f51a3c1bcbf2b0304c521a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/f0308e5e31f51a3c1bcbf2b0304c521a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253992&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;红耳彩龟（Trachemys scripta elegans）。图片来源：中国水产学会科学放鱼科普专家团队&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/7090258af338afd1700431e179950547.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/7090258af338afd1700431e179950547.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253995&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;俗称清道夫的豹纹翼甲鲇（Pterygoplichthys pardalis）。图片来源：中国水产学会科学放鱼科普专家团队&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/16a57e10d6beab422ff85a4c80d44fb2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/16a57e10d6beab422ff85a4c80d44fb2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253994&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;美洲牛蛙（Rana catesbeiana）。图片来源：中国水产学会科学放鱼科普专家团队&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法工委负责人表示，放生野生动物应当选择适合放生地野外生存的当地物种，不得干扰居民的正常生活、生产，不得造成他人人身、财产损害或者危害生态系统。适合放生地野外生存的当地物种名录将由广州市林业部门、广州市农业农村部门制定公布并适时更新。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“随意放生是违法行为，要承担相应的法律责任。”法工委负责人介绍，对于随意放生的行为，法规区分三种情形分别作了规定。一是规定违法放生境外野生动物物种的罚则。主要依照《中华人民共和国生物安全法》《中华人民共和国野生动物保护法》等法律法规的有关规定予以处理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，《规定》对随意放生境内野生动物可能或者已经造成严重后果的情形设定具体罚则。即规定可能或者已经造成他人人身、财产损害或者危害生态系统的，由相关部门责令限期捕回；逾期经催告仍不捕回，可能或者已经危害生态系统的，区林业部门、区农业农村部门应当代为捕回或者采取降低影响的措施，所需费用由放生的组织或者个人负担；已经危害生态系统的，处一万元以上十万元以下罚款；造成他人人身、财产损害的，放生的组织或者个人依法承担相应的民事责任；构成犯罪的，依法追究刑事责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，《规定》对在放生区域以外的其他地方放生境内野生动物设定罚则。即未在规定地点放生的，由区林业部门或者区农业农村部门处二千元以上一万元以下罚款。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得注意的是，《规定》也对合法的放生行为提出指引。法工委负责人表示，市民进行合法放生，须遵守三个方面的规定：在放生前，市民需根据相关部门公布的当地物种名录，选择适宜放生的动物物种。同时，需要提前三个工作日将野生动物的图片、种类、数量、来源、放生时间和地点等信息上传至野生动物放生信息管理平台，根据相关部门信息反馈和科学规范的放生指引做好放生。在放生时，市民需前往政府划定的野生动物放生区域按照指引、登记信息放生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为灵活就业准备了四年，还是进了职场丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258569]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/5LO0wHjrJvdtDnMmt7mMmUUSFK4Y9RXb9dsvDl40.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;833&quot; height=&quot;781&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/13/5LO0wHjrJvdtDnMmt7mMmUUSFK4Y9RXb9dsvDl40.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253999&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（农健/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;相关报道详见《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/256675&quot; title=&quot;“灵活就业”的毕业生，和一轮针对性核查&quot;>;“灵活就业”的毕业生，和一轮针对性核查&lt;/a>;》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;创业的想法最早是在2017年，热带的一个午后蹦出来的。那时我正在仰光最大的集市，它的名字曾在1948年变为昂山市场，殖民时期用的外文名不知所终。名字的更换并没有带来建筑风格改变，殖民时期的赭石色屋顶和用光滑鹅卵石铺就的小道，很容易让人联想到乔治·奥威尔在缅甸担任警官的岁月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;整个市场的柜台被木头、琥珀、翡翠、红宝石和一种金色的珍珠占据。当时，实习报社的师兄带我到一位同时拥有华人和缅族血统的木材老板的店铺，她和他的丈夫经营的木头，除了本地的缅甸花梨木外，小叶紫檀和老山檀都来自隔壁的印度邻居。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我无法想象这么多名贵的木头为何会被允许砍伐，但她曾用蹩脚的中文向我形容，在印度和缅甸的边境上，有一片茂密、紧凑的紫檀林，密集程度足以满足中国人的需求。毕竟，西方人往往被昂山市场的民族服饰笼基和青年画家的画吸引目光，这些店铺都在市场的外围，那些赭石色屋顶下随意搭着的大棚里。只有中国人会深入市场的核心寻找宝藏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些勤劳的缅甸人就把这些木头加工成筷子和珠子，即便在阳光下仔细观察，会留意到很多珠子就像鹅卵石一样，细一些，或者胖一些，并不是漂亮的圆形。但架不住它便宜，只要带回中国，那价格可以翻上几番。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回国前，我把行李箱清空，很多用不到的书和药品，都留给缅甸的朋友。最终，我塞了满满的一行李箱木头回国，并在一个月内迅速卖掉，带着几个同学小赚一笔，又在之后的半年陆续进了两三次货。直到缅甸出台严格的木材进出口法令。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生意的魅力在于谈判，讲价是一门博弈的艺术。这个过程能让人极其放松，尤其当顾客反复琢磨你的商品时，你会觉得前期的研判和寻觅物超所值。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很快，三年的读研生活，又让我琢磨卖茶。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时我在成都，当地浓厚的喝茶传统让我自认为发现了一片蓝海。把老家的普洱茶拿到成都，专门给一些茶馆做供应商也不错。除了上课，我每天都在成都各式各样的茶馆里闲逛，交朋友，开茶会，在随意翻阅了几本茶相关的著作后，还大摇大摆地上起了茶课。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我曾想，未来的人生就这样吧。每天的工作是和客户聊天，然后给你的产品琢磨一个又一个的故事，偶尔，春节和中秋的时候，提前给客户们准备好伴手礼，一一拜访，控制好茶叶的品质，以及警惕竞争者的出现。这个圈子的人大多内敛，有人暴富，但没人在花钱上大手大脚，大部分过着清贫的生活，生活的标准可以很低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最重要的是，做茶有一种清贫的自由，哪怕是生意很一般的茶馆老板，春茶季还是会到各地的茶山游历一番，住在茶农家。茶农接待客户的费用，都超过客户买茶的费用，但到了下一个春茶季，茶农照样还是每天捉鱼杀鸡，招待客人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来在一家文化公司求职时，我向人力表达可以低欲望地生活，遭到人力驳斥，要是没啥欲望，那你对公司而言就是低效率的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2022年以来，陆续做了几篇和就业相关的稿子，在与意图灵活就业，甚至慢就业的大学生们交流时，我都能看到曾经的自己，那种始终对人生的可能性保持向往，不希望被一个标准的、现代的公司体系所吸纳的意愿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且，新闻背景的学生大多都知道，新闻机构的招聘往往是在大四或者研三的下学期才陆续开始。当你周围想去互联网大厂的同学在秋天就拿到录用通知时，一个坚定从事新闻工作的人，会陷入无所事事的烦忧之中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在那年秋天结束之前，我在琢磨的事情，都还是做自己喜欢的事儿，做能让人生无限可能的事儿。在一封给某个文艺气息极为浓郁的初创公司投简历时，我还写下这样一段话：找工作自然需要一点自我催眠的功力，特别当同寝室的一干人等，已经跑到深圳做年薪30万元、号称5年内能在市区买房的老师；或者到月薪两万的房地产公司做销售，我一直默默地对自己说：不着急。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但事实上，春天来临之前，这种不着急已经消失殆尽了。我第一次感受到同辈压力是在一个夜晚，宿舍老友回校相聚，当其他人得知我甚至还没有收到面试通知时，已经找到工作的他们不自觉地吸了一口气，眼神里流露出怜惜。我希望他们马上停止这样的眼神，于是和他们说，新闻机构的招聘还没开始呢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来我想了想，这句话是说给我自己听的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但我相信，现如今，如果仅仅看部分高校灵活就业的数据，那么同辈压力可能已经不复存在了，当你周围的人在灵活就业或者慢就业，毕业就是一次漫长的休假，收假的权力一小部分掌握在自己手里，另一部分被一个抽象的、摸不着，姑且可以称之为“社会”的存在所掌控。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于真正意图灵活就业的学生而言，他们更多是被一些来自1980年代，或者2010年代的创业神话所包围。不久前，一位00后朋友很认真地咨询我，如何通过短视频卖茶，这是他毕业后的愿望，但他对短视频的剪辑手段、起号方式、剧本结构、对标账号都不了解。当我把这些都介绍一遍之后，他表示，太复杂了，有没有简单一点的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;老家的云南长辈们有一种极为传统的想法，那就是毕业之后，哪怕找不到好工作，也得到小公司找一个临时的工作，不然的话，用云南话来说，人就飘着了。灵活就业或许能一夜暴富，慢就业或许也能收获人生无限可能，但真实的世界瞬息万变，在经历三年网课之后，被一个组织体系纳入其中，何尝不是一个了解真实世界的途径？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于我，当年认识的那位缅甸木材老板最后一次给我发信息时，她说要去印度，去现场看那片一望无际的紫檀树林，压低进货成本，这已经是五年前的对话了。在拿到工作录用通知之前，相熟的几位成都茶馆老板，则已纷纷转行，他们分别喜欢上了精油、推拿和旅行。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是灵活就业需要面对的现实世界吧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[七堇年：时间不多，玩了再说]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258583]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/dmLaXWsd6pjuYLL4Gpq3kyJRZS9iLevOWd5FyXOJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/dmLaXWsd6pjuYLL4Gpq3kyJRZS9iLevOWd5FyXOJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253689&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个人待着很容易，与他人长时间共享一片空气就难逃交际。从高中时期便开始出版作品、写到如今三十多岁仍过着类似无业生活的七堇年，面对陌生人的打听，总是感到难为情。去理发店躺着洗头，头顶那端或早或晚传来例行问询：“干嘛的呀？”她有时回答老师，有时说是销售，想到什么说什么，不能说真话，又没有事先编排好的完整回答。对方一旦追问，她便无能为力，任由流水声尴尬地哗哗流过。答不上来就不编了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记忆里最好笑的一次，来自去玩滑翔伞时遇到的同路人，对方问你干嘛的呀？七堇年用四川话回答，“做出版的。”由于发音相似，对方接着真诚发问，“那现在最好的厨板好多钱一米哦？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种遭遇更加让七堇年确信，“出版或者书这种东西就是离正常人很远的事情，更不要说你是个作家，我会觉得跟别人说你在写作太奇怪了。”她秉持着隐秘间谍的态度生活在热闹的成都，上午写作，下午看书，间或去健身房锻炼，晚上回来接着看电影看书；不下厨，但要向外地朋友提下馆子建议时也说不大上来。她习惯开火烫一份青菜，再从合口味的、有限的几家里来来回回地点一份外卖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6L3eeOGIdCZDmkV3LLsj1DToDa7r7e0VcFk0hvY7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/6L3eeOGIdCZDmkV3LLsj1DToDa7r7e0VcFk0hvY7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253688&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;各地徒步&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;持不持家毫无所谓，“我们真的不管哦。”她更在意几十平空间外的世界。天气好的时候独自去飞滑翔伞，假期和队友一起洞穴探险、攀岩。几年前她加入了山水自然保护中心，新冠疫情期间也把自己扔到了不同的横断山脉。年纪越大，动物性越加强烈地在她心里生发，对自然的向往和原始渴望，成了比情感更牢固的依恋，她笑称自己蜕化成了“兼职人类”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;爱尔兰女作家克莱尔·吉根（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;七堇年翻译过她的一本短篇小说集《寄养》&lt;/span>;）写过一段话，恰好非常适合拿来形容她。 “写作是个奇怪的职业，尤其在我这个年龄。她们在心里计算着我的年龄，竭力回忆我出生时发生了什么，有谁去世了。她们吃不准，但我肯定不再是个小姑娘了。我现在应该干点别的事，应该把自己拴在某个有稳定收入、有辆好车的未婚男人身上。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写作对七堇年而言，并非从小规划的梦想，不到20岁时的作品《被窝是青春的坟墓》卖了百万册，事情就这么突然发生了。如今想来，她倒是很想拥有体育明星的人生，在攀岩馆遇到攀得不错的小孩时，会心生妒忌，继而懊恼，“我小时候都干嘛去了？9到12岁是最适合攀岩的，自重很轻，个子又合适，但凡有个这种爱好，那不得了！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她由衷羡慕费德勒那样的人生，“退役时可能也才三十多岁，就已经完成了职业生涯的顶峰，然后你的人生其实还很长。”而作家，显然难以在这个年纪陡然收场。 2023年9月，她的旅行随笔集《横断浪途》出版，此前三年没有出书，期间总得面对编辑、读者组成的社会期待。她与艺术家陈萧伊作伴行进横断山脉，一路上两人偶尔也会探讨彼此工作中隐形的出版节奏，“像她们艺术家也得每年不间断地开办个展、或是参与群展，维护一种职业在线状态。不然就会听到外界的猜疑，说这个人还在干吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/X9MaAJCMB12UFxk9962T9eNT5XwhqxiQYCT8kNjt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/X9MaAJCMB12UFxk9962T9eNT5XwhqxiQYCT8kNjt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253691&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;攀冰&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去这种声音会让她慌，但后来她想通了，“创作真的不像织毛衣，一件一件这样织下去对吧？有的人可以，但是对我来说，我确实现在越写越慢了，修改的时间和写的时间一样多，《横断浪途》起码改了一年，反反复复找结构。”客观难度增加，主观心理上也有一番抵挡。 “过了35岁了，成长性变化是蛮大的了。这种创作节奏也是社会对我的一种规训，与其说每年做一本书出来，现在更慌的是怎么趁着身体还比较好的时候能够多体验各种各样的运动、生涯，其实你人越大，真的会越过越收缩。因为写作可以做一辈子，但是你想有些户外运动，甚至只是简单爬个山什么的，到六七十岁时，身体跟二三十岁完全没办法比。”她最理想的人生状态是，“前30年壮游天下，再30年读书，最后30年专心写作。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以下是她的自述：&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;命运就像雨点&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我踏上职业写作道路比较早，也很顺利地被很多读者知道吧，但其实就跟某种品牌效应一样，可能大家对你的印象，或者说提起这个名字能想到的还是你很多年前写的那些东西，跟青春文学标签相关，但不管是“80后”还是青春文学都变得多少不是那么纯正面意义了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这几年想开了，觉得没什么太大不了，你也不能指望一个17岁的孩子写出《战争与和平》，对吧？倒不是说我现在写的是《战争与和平》，只是说对这个过程其实挺无奈的，标签这种东西总有滞后性，你自己在成长，读者们其实也在成长，有互相陪伴的这种感觉也就够了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;去年夏天我参加爱荷华大学的创意写作计划（IWP，International Writing Program），一落地就有两个在那边读博的我的读者，赶来活动现场非常热情地跟我聊天，带我去当地好吃的地方。在国内遇到读者我觉得还蛮正常的，但没想到在那么远的地方（也能遇到），真的让我很感动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/aV2tu07sPsZN2zibW0qi0TKIMsCDocLsamlKOc14.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;607&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/aV2tu07sPsZN2zibW0qi0TKIMsCDocLsamlKOc14.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253685&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;洞穴探险&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我算是因为新概念作文大赛出来（不知道现在新概念还有没有了），当时在我们“80后”那一辈还是挺轰动的。我参加的是第六届，高二那年（2002年），获奖后又非常幸运地加入了郭敬明的团队，赶上那种类型文学的一个浪潮期，所以一路走来都还是挺顺的。然后也挺不禁想的。到现在都快20年了吧？ 15年肯定是有了，挺倦怠的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;写作久了之后，完全进入一种职业状态，出书的感觉对我来说就像升了一年级再升二年级、三年级这样一个按部就班的过程，可能已经找不到那种“啊，你看！你看这是我出的书！”的那种成就感。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最初真的是随意写写，晚自习别人在写作业，我在写作。这些年来也没有长时间间断过出版，一直保持着小说集、散文集穿插的节奏，《横断浪途》之前是2019年《晚风枕酒》那本，这本书主要就是给前面自己三年的一个交代。疫情三年，我觉得大家可能过得都挺不容易的，各有各的领悟吧。对我来说，最大的就是生活的正常秩序被打乱之后，你发现看起来有条不紊的东西其实蛮脆弱的，而你对此可能很无力，只能接纳无常。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0bz6Cl8Ong2mQM9o3jU8GLR44poAeCWfreFETxZO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;643&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0bz6Cl8Ong2mQM9o3jU8GLR44poAeCWfreFETxZO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253677&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;由于我从小就非常喜欢自然，也很喜欢旅行，加上比较怕热，每年夏天基本上都会去其他国家的国家公园，一路自驾、露营、爬山，完全是在大自然里。有时候和同伴一起，比如2017年去加拿大，大部分时间是独自一人，像是去英国、新西兰、挪威等，最近的一次是2018年去阿拉斯加。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;走过了很多地方，疫情的时候，这不都去不成了嘛。好在四川省真的太大了，而且自然资源太丰富了，以前舍近求远，都没有意识到家乡的横断山脉地貌这么丰富，所以这三年反倒以一种收回的目光看看自己身边，发现原来可能你连自己身边的世界都不了解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;川西这边跟我们明明是共同的时空和文化背景，可能我跟一个贡嘎山村里的牧民孩子物理距离只有三四百公里，但是我们的生活太不一样了。我住在成都，困在城市久了之后，视野是相对狭窄的，觉得人生就只能像一条运河一样，上学、就业、成家，好像除此之外的生活都不被认可。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;但其实稍微走进山里看一下，就能体会到越南那句谚语说的，“命运就像雨点一样，有的落在宫殿里，有的落在田野里。”看到那些自在的牧民或僧人，他们的生活像自然的河流一样蜿蜒着，今天该去种地就种地，该收松茸就收松茸，或是挖虫草，至于明天什么的，根本没有想那么多，生活是很多样性的——不必急着像运河奔向终点，你可能发现一片汪洋，其实是一片虚无。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9OcTbSJCq3A1J5wpqhurf8NU5sn8WGGEy1aF9hXm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;1102&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9OcTbSJCq3A1J5wpqhurf8NU5sn8WGGEy1aF9hXm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253678&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;可能你小时候读萨特、读存在主义，其实根本没懂，但是到了现在，我觉得算是差不多活到了开始真正思考“自由是什么、活着到底是为了什么、人生到底有没有意义”，真的能体会到这种虚无带来的拷问的时候了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我认同生活是用自己的每一个选择定义出来的，它本来就有很多丰富的可能性，但是好像你一旦在城市里面长久生活，会很容易把自己也给局限化，反正这是进山带给我最大的一个反哺。过去我在现实生活中多多少少显得是一个比较格格不入的人。首先我的自由职业跟很多上班族的生活可能是不一样的（和其他自由工作的朋友聚在一起，我们从不会聊社保）；再加上可能身边同龄人都已经结婚生子，这些对我来说也很遥远，那你自己在这么一个比较急躁的社会里，你经常会对自己的位置产生很多怀疑。总在想，哎呀，我接下来要干嘛呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有时候早上我看见路边穿着橘红色工作服的清洁工、外卖骑手、低头刷手机的上班族、背着书包睡眼朦胧地过马路的学生，这些日常场景就像一条条轨道，如此正当而坚实；相较之下，我虽不至于成了一截脱轨的车厢，至少也有逃学般的心怀不安——当一个人选择写作为生，选择自由职业，她就选了一条更窄、更难的小路。好在进山的这几年让我对这种按部就班产生了许多顿悟。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;第一次去登山的时候，向导跟我说登山就是一个跟自己对话的过程，实际上你爬的时候真的是很累的，什么都没时间想，就像个走路机器人，平地走路可能背着东西都很累，更不要说海拔高的时候，一上来就很喘很累。欧洲很多高山可能才三千米，但川西这边一个理塘县城的海拔可能都四千米起，很容易产生高反。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;大脑一片空白，最容易想到的是“我为什么要在这儿受这个罪啊！”那个过程其实谈不上跟自己对话，而是一种时间感丧失了的心流体验，完全沉浸于当下，根本不想为什么要在这儿走，也没那么多诗意的思绪，就是想着这一步步先往前，走到今天晚上休息的地方。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;但是回过头来看，这些过程带给我的体验是很丰富的。很多不用写进日记但保留在视觉性的观察里的快乐或者波折甚至是一些很狼狈的时刻，全在这个过程当中，回过头来，路上的每一个片段和瞬间带给我很丰沛的真正旅行的感受，而不是说我成功登顶了，或者说我们今天去看到了哪个景区。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/LrWYOKQMAGpeBi6n3HooHIbgRA61KYP7aUFfOlv4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/LrWYOKQMAGpeBi6n3HooHIbgRA61KYP7aUFfOlv4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253683&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;前几年读韩东，他说到，“剥离了目的的人生，剩下的就是一个有所作为的过程。”我觉得反反复复进山带给我的最深体会也是过程本身的细节的乐趣。每一趟我们都不是在找一个具体的景点，或者目的地。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;过往生活中那些存在主义意义上的困惑：既然活着是无意义的，存在是虚无的，每个人都是自由的但自由又是一种建构而已，你该如何作出选择，发明出意义来。这种困惑不是禅宗那样，一声棒喝就能顿悟的，它本身就是一个过程，而且仅仅是一个过程，就像登山一样，为什么那么苦、那么受罪？上去又下来，图什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;后来我知道了，不是上去是为了下来，而是下来就是为了上去，而且是一再上去。有人说“人生为一件事而来”，找到这个事，把自己投进去，就够了。登山也好，写作也好，飞滑翔伞也好，保护森林也好……意义是不存在的，但你的一生因此被好好度过了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子遭邻居砸门近一年：数十次报警为何换不来警方追责]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258511]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据齐鲁晚报报道，吉林松原一男子称，自己遭邻居砸门咒骂近一年，而报警四五十次后问题仍未得到解决。该男子称，自己孩子已上大学，自己和妻子都要上班，但楼下一位女性邻居总说家里有动静。为此，男子家铺地毯、送走猫，生活中也注意细节，但邻居依旧不依不饶。当地派出所出警多次，但邻居仍然无视。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;邻里间往往会因某些琐事引发矛盾。比如，有人爱养宠物，但宠物嬉戏、吵闹可能会影响他人。从报道看，楼下邻居反馈该男子家中动静较大，男子已送走猫、铺地毯，尽最大可能减少对邻居的影响。如果其认为该男子家中动静仍对其生活造成影响，可以向物业、居委会反映，请其居中协调解决。也可据此向法院提起诉讼，但需拿出对方侵权的真凭实据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，该女子采取的方式是到别人家砸门咒骂，视频中，该女子还用脚踢门，并且拿出棍状物砸门。据当事男子反映，自家门因此损毁严重。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;显然，该女子以他人动静干扰其生活为由，在近一年时间砸门咒骂，不仅会给当事男子生活造成严重影响，还涉嫌损毁他人财物，其行为也影响其他邻居。正因如此，不堪其扰的男子向警方报警。但四五十次报警，女子行为仍未被有效制止，反映出当地警方的处理失当。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《中华人民共和国治安管理处罚法》第九条规定，对于因民间纠纷引起的打架斗殴或者损毁他人财物等违反治安管理行为，情节较轻的，公安机关可以调解处理。经公安机关调解，当事人达成协议的，不予处罚。经调解未达成协议或者达成协议后不履行的，公安机关应当依照本法的规定对违反治安管理行为人给予处罚，并告知当事人可以就民事争议依法向人民法院提起民事诉讼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说，男子当初报警，警方认为该女子的行为情节较轻，尚可仅仅调解了事。但这位邻居并没有接受调解，而是继续骚扰乃至损坏他人财物。显然，其行为已不属于情节较轻的范畴，警方应当依法对其进行处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对此事，警方在处理过程中至少应做到两点。首先，在刚开始的调解过程中，向当事双方宣明各自在法律范畴内的应享权利和应遵义务，男子有不被骚扰的权利，女邻居如果认为男子家中动静干扰其生活，可据此向法院提告。同时，警方应阐述对此事采取调解方式的法律依据，并正告这位女邻居，如不能接受调解，继续砸门等行为，将面临怎样的法律后果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，当调解一而再无效，男子报警、女子不接受调解继续砸门的恶性循环继续，警方应果断按照《中华人民共和国治安管理处罚法》赋予的执法权限，对其进行处罚。连续四五十次报警却阻止不了该女子的行为，且不说让当事男子产生依法维权难的无力感，也是对警力的极大浪费。同时，在该女子眼中，警方反复出警却始终不对其行为进一步约束，更易助其“法律能奈我何”的张狂。或许，正是因为当地警方一次又一次的无所作为，让该女子行为升级，从咒骂到砸门，如果再不加以处理，该女子后续行为不定会演变成怎样的暴力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于此类事件，警方调解无效之后果断处罚该女子，是保护受害者权益的关键。如果警方不能及时依法追责，只会助长违法行为，甚至导致事态进一步恶化，引发更多的社会问题。同时，这也将对其他人产生误导，使得他们误以为此类行为没有法律红线，可以肆意而为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;针对此类事件，警方果断处理，对违法者问责，不是没有先例。据时间视频2023年5月报道，在北京朝阳区一小区，居民楼经常半夜传来敲墙声，导致居民睡不好。民警经过调查，锁定了住户刘某。据刘某交代，因为房屋隔音效果差，与邻居有过矛盾，为了报复，刘某选择了敲墙。因为刘某的行为扰民，又持续时间长，涉嫌寻衅滋事，被公安机关依法予以行政拘留。如果警方没有对刘某处理，恐怕居民仍将长期被其滋扰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有关邻里扰民事件，往往是“公说公有理、婆说婆有理”，有些当事人可能对法律理解不足，这些因素都可能影响警方调解的效果。但是，这并不意味着警方可以放松对法律的执行，尤其是不要因处理对象性别、年龄等区别对待。如果上述事件中是男子近一年时间砸门，女子反复报警，警方是否会容忍此类事件继续？事实上，警方在处理时一视同仁，以事实而非其他因素作为执法依据，方能体现司法公正，更是在全社会范围内维护秩序和公平，让违法者明白法律的严肃性和不可侵犯性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[多名培训机构人员组织研究生考试作弊获刑]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258489]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;2023年10月11日，北京市海淀区人民法院依法对被告人张某等人利用无线传输方式，在2021年、2022年全国硕士研究生招生考试中组织考生考试作弊案作出一审宣判。法院以组织考试作弊罪分别判处张某等9名被告人5年6个月至2年不等有期徒刑，并处5万元至2万元不等罚金；同时，为防止其再次实施此类犯罪，对9名被告人依法宣告职业禁止。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/092024160194962a6d825a8493f855d6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/092024160194962a6d825a8493f855d6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253950&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法院经审理查明：被告人张某、杜某某、牛某某、王某某、张某某、姜某等人从事教育咨询、考试培训等业务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年12月，被告人张某设计以无线电设备传输考试答案的方式，组织考生在2021年全国硕士研究生招生考试中作弊，被告人杜某某、牛某某为张某介绍考生并从中获取利益。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1713fa72ea20a1748b27ff669b9c3b5f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/1713fa72ea20a1748b27ff669b9c3b5f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253951&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年10月至12月，被告人张某以同样的方式组织考生在2022年全国硕士研究生招生考试中作弊，被告人杜某某、牛某某、张某某、王某某、姜某为张某招募考生，并从中获取利益。期间，张某负责招募考生，购买作弊器材，在考点附近登记房间并安置信号发射装置，联系考试题目、制作及发送答案；路某帮助张某整理考生信息及考生反馈问题，整理答案格式并发送，徐某培训考生、试验设备，招募“骡子”（即信号放大器看护人员），考试时为考生发送答案；徐某收发快递，维修设备，指挥“骡子”开关设备。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/64db816c9fe5e43c7325015799d0dff8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/64db816c9fe5e43c7325015799d0dff8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253952&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年12月25日上午，张某组织多名考生在2022年全国硕士研究生招生考试中作弊，安排人员在北京多家大学附近放置信号放大器为考生发送答案。当日，民警接群众举报在考点附近将信号放大器看护人员抓获，后根据线索先后将九名被告人抓获，并起获作案所用无线电设备。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/e25da2523f24c43c3b07a9dc26ae4127.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/12/e25da2523f24c43c3b07a9dc26ae4127.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253949&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法院经审理认为，被告人张某、路某、徐某、徐某、牛某某、杜某某、张某某、姜某、王某某在全国硕士研究生招生考试中，以无线传输的方式组织多名考生进行作弊，情节严重，其行为均已构成组织考试作弊罪。其中，被告人张某、徐某、牛某某、杜某某、张某某、姜某、王某某系主犯；被告人路某、徐某系从犯。法院根据各被告人的犯罪事实、性质、情节和社会危害程度、认罪悔罪态度及退赃情节等因素，依法作出上述判决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;宣判后，各被告人未明确表示是否上诉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;法官释法：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;考试作弊破坏考试制度和人才选拔制度，妨碍公平竞争，破坏社会诚信，败坏社会风气，具有严重的社会危害性。特别是利用信息技术手段实施的有组织的考试作弊活动，危害尤其严重。为此，在《刑法修正案（九）》中增设了组织考试作弊罪、非法出售提供试题、答案罪和代替考试罪等规定，严肃惩处考试作弊犯罪。此后，两高又发布《关于办理组织考试作弊等刑事案件适用法律若干问题的解释》（以下简称《解释》），进一步对考试作弊犯罪的定罪量刑和法律适用作出具体规定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本案涉及的全国硕士研究生招生考试是法律规定的国家教育考试，是我国选拔高层次专门人才的重要渠道，社会关注度高、影响大、涉及面广，属国家级重要考试。 《解释》第二条第（一）项将“在普通高等学校招生考试、研究生招生考试、公务员录用考试中组织考试作弊的”，直接规定为“情节严重”。本案各被告人明知考生参加全国硕士研究生招生考试，仍参与其中，组织作弊，属于“情节严重”。根据《刑法》第二百八十四条之一的规定，组织作弊，情节严重的，处三年以上七年以下有期徒刑，并处罚金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从实践中来看，考试作弊犯罪在一定程度上存在再犯可能性，为防止罪犯“重操旧业”，本案依据《解释》第十二条的规定，依法对张某等9名被告人宣告职业禁止，即禁止9人自刑罚执行完毕之日或者假释之日起五年内从事与教育、考试、培训相关的职业；同时，对被判处缓刑的被告人在缓刑考验期内依法宣告禁止令，即禁止其在缓刑考验期内从事与教育、考试、培训相关的活动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“十年寒窗苦，一朝翰墨香”，考试公平是社会不容触碰的底线。考试作弊不仅破坏考试公平，还影响社会公平，严重损害考生个人和国家利益。 “法网恢恢疏而不漏”，组织者不要心存侥幸，也希望每位考生严格遵纪守法，诚信考试，拒绝作弊，用自己的辛勤付出换得满意的答卷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>