<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[随国，从编钟出发]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259631]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Big Tomb&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Soft light spreads over, falling in men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The man&#39;s face was slightly raised, and under his thick black eyebrows, his small eyes were deep and lively. The bridge of the nose is straight, the lips are pressed tightly, with a faint smile. The man&#39;s expression was three parts confident, three parts complacent, and four parts complacent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The man stands in a corner of the Suizhou Museum, a bronze statue. The text under the statue states that it was reconstructed based on the skull of the tomb owner by the Institute of Vertebrate Paleontology and Ancient Anthropology, Chinese Academy of Sciences. In other words, it is highly similar to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The remains of the tomb owner have been sleeping on a small hill only a few hundred meters away from the Suizhou Museum since they were buried in the loess more than 2,000 years ago. I walked out of the museum and walked for 5 minutes along a quiet road behind the museum. I turned a corner in front of a unit called Ouyang Xiu Kindergarten, crossed a stone bridge, and entered the Leigudun Archaeological Site Park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The green forest directly in front of the park is the lush city that men have dreamed of for thousands of years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The man’s name is Ji Yi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Ji Yi&#39;s name is not well known, then his other title is famous: Zeng Hou Yi. Zeng Hou is the king of Zeng State. Yi is his name. As for why it was asserted that his surname was Ji, there was a tortuous process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/Z6uN2lbCzmre7fP9VjTeOY6HJKemMDswziE55oxF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;619&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/Z6uN2lbCzmre7fP9VjTeOY6HJKemMDswziE55oxF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Statue of Zeng Houyi in Suizhou Museum&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nie Zuoping/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nowadays, beating drums A huge park has been built at the Dun site. According to the scenic spot information, its &quot;protection scope and construction control zone reaches 12 square kilometers.&quot; Around the park and outside the Suizhou Museum, there are also some residential buildings scattered here and there. However, judging from old photos, more than 40 years ago in the 1970s, there were still lush rice fields here. In the middle of the crop fields, there stood two isolated houses, which belonged to a radar repair station of the Air Force. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes, archaeological discoveries are like a saying: When a mouse pulls a shovel, the big head is behind. For example, the Terracotta Warriors and Horses of Qin Shihuang and the Leigudun ruins were discovered due to the expansion of the radar repair shop&#39;s workshop. During the construction process, the workers discovered that there was some white plaster mud and a piece of artificially paved stone slab under the loess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said with certainty that although archaeologists have confirmed that there is a large ancient tomb under the wilderness, they were still deeply shocked when the details of the ancient tomb were revealed. I found an aerial panorama taken during the excavation. In the black and white photo, a large pit was dug out of the gray earth, showing that the tomb entrance was composed of three rectangles. Comparing the crowds around the pit as dense as ants, you can see how big and deep the entrance to the tomb is. Tan Weisi, the head of the archaeological team at that time, recalled, &quot;The entrance to the tomb is in the shape of an irregular polygon, with the widest point from east to west being 21 meters, and the widest point from north to south being 16.5 square meters, with a total area of ​​more than 200 square meters.&quot; As for the coffin that gradually revealed the true face of Lushan Mountain in the pit, It is 6 times larger than the Mawangdui Tomb and 8 times larger than the Wangshan No. 1 Chu Tomb where the sword of Yue King Goujian was unearthed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a conspicuous place in the exhibition hall of Hubei Provincial Museum, on the thick red carpet, two copper-wood structure brackets, one long and one short, are arranged in an L shape. One of them is more than 7 meters long, and the other is 3 meters long. Many, the height is more than 2.5 meters. On the top of the bracket, there are 64 chimes hanging in 8 groups on 3 levels. The total weight of the bronze chimes weighs 5,000 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This set of chimes, which can be called the treasure of the town hall, comes from Leigudun. Its owner is none other than Zeng Houyi. According to custom, it is named Zenghou Yi Chime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the shape, chime bells are divided into button bells, Yong bells and tungsten bells. The bell is the largest, placed on the lower floor, and its sound is rich and distant; the Yong bell is the second, placed on the middle floor, and its sound is mellow and beautiful; the button bell is the smallest, placed on the upper floor, and its sound is clear and melodious. What is amazing is that each bell can strike two different tones, which is called a double-tone bell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since its reappearance in 1978, the bell of Zeng Houyi has rung three times in the past few decades. One time was when the bell was rang for the first time in the local garrison auditorium when it was unearthed. Contemporary ears were fortunate enough to listen to the pre-Qin music that traveled two thousand years. One time was the National Day in 1979, when the bells were transported to Beijing for performance. The first time was in 1997, when the bells rang in Hubei Province to welcome the return of Hong Kong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/MND1ZV7ty87AJFnQDS3S5uumhlpMKKangDVsfoZQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/MND1ZV7ty87AJFnQDS3S5uumhlpMKKangDVsfoZQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The treasure of the Hubei Provincial Museum - Zenghou Yi Chime&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Compared with its own artistic value and cultural relic value, the inscriptions on the chimes may be more precious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tombs in the pre-Qin period did not have tombstones and epitaphs like those in later generations. To determine who the owner of the tomb is, we can only rely on the inscriptions on the burial objects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many cultural relics unearthed from the Leigudun site, including weapons such as Ge and Shu, as well as daily utensils such as bronze plates and beans, all have the word &quot;Zeng Hou Yi&quot; appearing. One of the bells has a 31-character inscription on it, which not only proves that the owner of the tomb is Zeng Hou Yi, but also provides coordinates for the general era of Zeng Hou Yi&#39;s life. These 31 characters are: The fifty and six sacrifices of the king of Kun returned from Xiyang. Xiong Zhang, the king of Chu, became the Yi Zonghou of Zenghou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The general idea is that in the fifty-sixth year of King Xiong Zhang of Chu, when he learned that Zeng Houyi had passed away, he specially made this set of Zongyi and sent it to Xiyang to commemorate him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiong Zhang is King Hui of Chu. He is the only monarch of Chu who has reigned for more than 56 years. In the 56th year of King Hui of Chu, that is, 433 BC. According to the determination of the bones in the coffin, the tomb owner was approximately 42 to 45 years old when he died. Based on this, Zeng Hou Yi was born between 475 and 478 BC. If he was born in 475 BC, that year was the beginning of the Warring States Period. The life of Zeng Houyi roughly spans nearly half a century in the early Warring States period - at that time, although the wars among the princes continued, they were not as violent as the mergers and acquisitions in the middle and late Warring States periods, where they &quot;led the land and ate human flesh&quot;. As the king of a small country, he lived a stable and happy life on earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When archaeologists opened the heavy main coffin, they saw scattered skeletons and many exquisite burial objects. Yes, more than two thousand years later, Zeng Houyi&#39;s body had rotted away, and only the burial objects remained. Most of these funerary objects are jade. The ancients believed that if jade objects were inserted into the ears, nose, mouth and anus of the deceased, the deceased would become immortal. As the saying goes, &quot;If gold and jade are in the nine orifices, the deceased will be immortal.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, all attempts and efforts for eternity are destined to be in vain. Not only will the corpses rot, but the names and deeds will also be forgotten. The traces of the vast majority of people’s existence on this blue planet will be wiped away by the waters of the River of Forgetfulness, as if they had never been there. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/gNZDmcannHVo1VFFjEPalgPWQHvMAiBi5j4GuD7o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;575&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/gNZDmcannHVo1VFFjEPalgPWQHvMAiBi5j4GuD7o.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A corner of Leigudun ruins&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Nie Zuoping/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Bronze&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The discovery of the tomb of Zeng Hou Yi has once again brought to the surface a long-standing question: According to the tomb of Zeng Hou Yi and previous archaeological discoveries, in today’s Suizhou area, there were once There once existed a country called Zeng. Strangely, there is not a single word about Zeng Guo in the historical documents. What is particularly strange is that historical data show that during the same time period, there was a country called &quot;Sui&quot; in the region, but cultural relics related to &quot;Sui&quot; have never been found before. So, what is the relationship between Zeng and Sui? Some people think that Zeng Tunsui; some people think that Zeng Sui was the successor; some people think that Chu destroyed Sui and established Zeng Sui anywhere; still others think that Zeng Sui was the same country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2013, 35 years after the tomb of Zeng Hou Yi was excavated, another tomb group from the Spring and Autumn Period was discovered in Wenfeng Pagoda, only four or five kilometers away from the tomb of Zeng Hou Yi. There are more than 50 tombs in the tomb group, and thousands of cultural relics were unearthed, more than half of which are bronzes, and most of them have inscriptions. The words Zeng, Zeng Zi, Zeng Gongzi, Zeng Sun, Zeng Da Sima, etc. in the inscription indicate that it is a cemetery for high-level nobles of Zeng State. In addition to a batch of bronzes with the inscription &quot;Zeng&quot; unearthed from the tomb numbered M21, what is even more eye-catching is a bronze dagger. The inscription on the bronze dagger is: Follow Da Sima Xianyou on his journey of fighting. This is the first Suiguo cultural relic unearthed in many years. Moreover, the cultural relics of Sui State appeared in the tombs of nobles of Zeng State, providing important evidence that Zeng Sui was one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most direct, or the most conclusive evidence comes from the tomb numbered M1 in the Wenfeng Pagoda Tomb Group. A chime was unearthed from the tomb. The inscription on the chime records the Battle of Wu and Chu in 506 BC. After the defeat of Chu State, he recovered the country with the help of Zeng State. The inscription names the three parties involved as Wu, Chu and Zeng. When &quot;Zuo Zhuan&quot; recorded this incident, the three parties involved were called Wu, Chu, and Sui. It can be seen that Zeng and Sui are different names for the same country. ——It was not uncommon in the pre-Qin period for a country to have two names. For example, Wei was also called Liang because its capital was in Daliang, Han was also called Zheng because its capital was in Xinzheng, and Zhou was also called Chunyu because its capital was Chunyu. To be specific, it may also be called Sui because it is all about Sui. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the origin of Zeng State, or Sui State, the answer was also obtained in the Wenfeng Pagoda Tombs - two chimes unearthed in Cemetery No. It is said, &quot;After Yu Ji&quot;, Ji is Hou Ji, the ancestor of the Zhou people. This shows that the king of Zeng State was derived from the surname Ji and was a descendant of the Zhou royal family. Therefore, Zeng Hou Yi was named Ji Yi. Another record is more detailed, and an expert interprets it as: &quot;On the auspicious day of the first month of the first lunar month, Marquis Zeng said to him: Bo Shi was superior to Yong, and he assisted the civil and military forces. He fulfilled the orders of Yin and pacified the world. The king ordered Nan Gong. Camping in Ruitu, the king is better than Huaiyi, and Jiangxia is close to him.&quot; The general idea is that Bo Shi superiorly assisted King Wen and King Wu of Zhou to overthrow the Yin Shang Dynasty and pacify the world. Later, King Wu of Zhou sent him to the south to build a city and establish a country. He was responsible for monitoring Huaiyi and defending Jiangxia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Who is Bo Shi Shangyong? Bo Shi, also known as Bo Kuo, is Nangong Kuo. Yongtongrong, Shangyong means Shangrong, is the name of Nangong, and Bo Shi is his character. Historical records record that after Nangong Shi followed King Wu to conquer Zhou, King Wu ordered him to demolish King Zhou&#39;s deer platform and open a warehouse to store grain to help the people. According to the inscription, during the Great Enfeoffment in the early Zhou Dynasty, as a meritorious official, Nangong Shi was transferred to the south, which is today&#39;s Suizao area, to establish the Zeng Kingdom. Zeng Guo&#39;s duty was to defend against Huaiyi in the southeast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The so-called Huaiyi are originally a branch of Dongyi. During the Shang and Zhou Dynasties, they lived in the Jianghuai area and established a number of countries, such as Liao, Liu, Shu, Shuyong and Shujiu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Tracing back to their roots, Huaiyi and merchants have a close blood relationship, and the Zhou people were the end of the Shang Dynasty. Therefore, in order to guard against Huaiyi and manage the south, Emperor Zhou enfeoffed many princes in today&#39;s Henan, Hubei and Anhui areas. These princes were generally located north of the Han River and were called Hanyang Zhuji, including Tang, Ying, and Xi. , E, Deng, Chiang, Cai, Shen, Sui and other countries. In the middle, there is the leading big country. It is said that &quot;the princes from the east of Han Dynasty are all big.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/SlSta4V8DgSE6wHmaQ4pe6eNraYMf1lg34RJxea5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/SlSta4V8DgSE6wHmaQ4pe6eNraYMf1lg34RJxea5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Hubei Provincial Museum Zeng Hou Yi Bronze Drum Base&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;After the Huaiyi rebellion was gradually eliminated, the tasks of the concubines of Hanyang turned to guarding against the rising Chu State while maintaining the smooth flow of an important transportation line. This transportation line is the copper-tin road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Pre-Qin Dynasty was the Bronze Age. Bronze was not only the raw material for casting weapons, but also the raw material for casting ritual vessels. In the context of &quot;the major affairs of the country lie in sacrifice and military service&quot;, bronze can be said to be the foundation of a country. However, the area directly under the jurisdiction of Emperor Zhou of Guanzhong, the capital of Guanzhong, does not produce copper. The large amount of copper required can only be transported thousands of miles from the south - Daye, Hubei, and Ruichang, Jiangxi, which is only more than 100 kilometers away. A huge copper mine with extremely rich reserves. Their mining began more than 2,000 years ago and continues to the present day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Copper from the south has to be transported to Guanzhong, a distance of more than 1,000 kilometers. Long transportation lines mean more risks and more uncertainties. The concubines of Hanyang, headed by Sui Guo, have the important task of ensuring the smooth flow of the copper and tin roads and ensuring that the metals mined from the south reach Haojing smoothly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the National Museum of China, there is a bronze vessel named Zeng Boyun. The 簠 is a utensil used to serve rice during sacrifices or banquets. It is also called the 簋, the square one is called 簠 and the round one is called 簋. Zeng Boyun was used by the king of Zeng State. The inscription on it has the following sentences: &quot;... Ke Di Huai Yi, suppress Xie Fan Tang, gold road and tin travel, tools are ready for use.&quot; It means: &lt;span style=&quot;font- family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Uncle Zeng)&lt;/span>; Punished Huaiyi, stabilized the transportation hub Fantang, and restored the copper and tin channels to normal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first to come to the moon near the water tower is not only the boss of the Hanyang concubines, but also controls the most important Suizao Corridor on the road of copper and tin. It is easier for Sui to obtain a large amount of copper than other princes. In a sense, this small country - although it is the largest among the concubines of Hanyang, it is still a small country compared with the real big country - is the real Bronze Kingdom. A total of 6,239 pieces of various bronze vessels were unearthed from the tomb of Zeng Houyi, and together they weighed a total of 10,498.6 kilograms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/LNiEDBxEMDwAkGBduZHlMHEcVKecAt4EeE4WezfR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/LNiEDBxEMDwAkGBduZHlMHEcVKecAt4EeE4WezfR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Part of the bronze plate of Marquis Zeng Yi of Hubei Provincial Museum&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;In the Zhou Dynasty, under the background of Zhou Gong making rituals and music, bronzes not only had practical functions, but also had spiritual value, and were integrated with the rituals and music system. It is a musical instrument for formal music, a ritual vessel for hiding rituals, and a magical instrument for communication between humans and gods. Duke Zhou&#39;s thoughts of respecting virtue and protecting the people were passed down from generation to generation through materialized bronze vessels. The developed bronze culture should have had a profound impact on Sui State - unfortunately, due to the lack of historical data, we cannot learn more details. Judging from the few records about Sui Guo, a clan named Ji Liang is a representative example. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 706 BC, King Wu of Chu attacked Sui and deliberately showed weakness. Sui&#39;s young division fell into the trap and asked Sui to fight with all his strength. Ji Liang reminded Sui Hou that the powerful Chu State suddenly became weak. This was &quot;tempting me, why are you so anxious?&quot; He further gave advice to Sui Hou, and the content of the advice fully reflected Ji Liang&#39;s people-oriented thinking. He said that if a small country wants to confront a big country, it depends on having the Tao; &quot;The so-called Tao means being loyal to the people and trusting in God. Loyalty means to think above the people and benefit the people; trust can also be used to wish the history a correct speech.&quot; - To have the Tao means that those in power must Be loyal to the people and gain trust from the gods. The monarch always thinks about how to benefit the people, which is loyalty; the historian who represents the monarch in sacrifice is truthful, which is faith. Sui Hou was dissatisfied. He said that when he offered sacrifices to the gods, he always chose fat and unvaried sacrifices. The millet and millet used as sacrifices were also abundant and complete, so he had enough faith in the gods. Ji Liang told him, &quot;The people are the masters of the gods. Therefore, the sage kings first became the people and then devoted themselves to the gods.&quot; The people are the foundation of the gods. Therefore, the sage kings of all ages first united the people and then devoted themselves to worshiping the gods. . Ji Liang asserted that Sui Hou thought that the sacrifices he offered to the gods were fat and unmotivated, and the millet and millet were abundant and complete. In fact, they were useless and would not receive the blessings of the gods. Only &quot;serve the three seasons, cultivate the five religions, and be close to the nine tribes&quot; - serve the three seasons, which means to let the people concentrate on farming in spring, summer, and autumn; cultivate the five religions, which means advocating father&#39;s righteousness, mother&#39;s kindness, brotherhood, and brotherhood. The social customs of friends, brothers being respectful, and sons being filial; kissing one&#39;s nine clans refers to harmonizing the relationship between relatives and making them harmonious - using these behaviors to sacrifice to the gods, the gods will bless you, the society will be harmonious, and the country will be strong. Therefore, Ji Liang unceremoniously asked his followers: &quot;If you cultivate political affairs and are close to the country of brothers, you may be able to survive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ji Liang&#39;s words made Suihou frightened and he had to accept the suggestion. After the Chu State heard about it, they had to temporarily give up the invasion plan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Suihou followed Ji Liang&#39;s advice, his most favored one was actually the unnamed young master. When Ji Liang gradually fell out of favor with Sui Hou, Chu State saw hope again. King Wu of Chu personally led an army to the Chu Sui border for the second time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chu was strong and weak, so Ji Liang suggested negotiating peace with Chu. He said that if Chu is unwilling to negotiate peace, it will anger our soldiers and make the enemy&#39;s army slack. The young master was unwilling to negotiate peace. He believed that a quick attack was necessary to demonstrate Sui Guo&#39;s strength. Before the war, Ji Liang reminded the princes that the Chu people&#39;s custom is to respect the left, and the left army must be the elite of the King of Chu. When fighting, we attack the weak right army of Chu first. Once the right army is defeated, the Chu army will collapse. The young master objected that not fighting the King of Chu head-on would mean that we dare not confront him head-on, which would damage the dignity of the country. So, Sui Hou ordered to attack the Chu army&#39;s left army. As a result, Sui&#39;s army was defeated, Suihou fled, and Suihou&#39;s chariot was also captured by the Chu army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/ZPHmYjSkKJEzurgoS5Z1pmscMF07q5xTap5K3uEg.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/ZPHmYjSkKJEzurgoS5Z1pmscMF07q5xTap5K3uEg.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Statue of Ji Liang in Suizhou Cultural Park&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>; Attached&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A batch of 240 bamboo slips were unearthed from the tomb of Zeng Hou Yi, with nearly 7,000 characters on them. According to expert interpretation, the bamboo slips are a list of the chariots, horses, and armor that were buried with Zeng Hou Yi. The list shows that after Zeng Houyi&#39;s death, the king of Chu, the prince of Chu, Ling Yin of Chu, and several princes of Chu, such as Duke Yang of Lu, Duke Yangcheng, and Lord Pingye, presented chariots and horses to him. In short, almost all the important figures in the Chu State expressed condolences for the death of Zeng Hou Yi and presented him with carriages, horses or other gifts. The names given to the King of Chu by the people of Sui in this list confirm that Sui at this time had become a vassal of Chu - only because of this, the kings and ministers of Chu were so close to Zeng Houyi and treated him with courtesy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the rise of Chu State, it has been trying to develop eastward. There are three goals in developing eastward. The first goal is to occupy the Jianghan Plain, which is suitable for farming; the second goal is to capture the copper mines in Daye; the third goal is to control the Suizao Corridor and the Nanxiang Pass, and then go north to compete for hegemony. . Of course, the three goals are step-by-step. Only by achieving the first goal can the second and third goals be achieved. No matter which goal it wants to achieve, what Chu must do is defeat its eastern neighbor Sui. Sui Guo was not only tasked by Emperor Zhou to monitor and defend Chu State, but also had a very important geographical location. &quot;It is bordered by Lian&#39;e to the north, Hanmiang to the east, and between Xiang, Ying, Shen, and An. It is actually an important place. The keys to Yiyang and Nanyang are actually used.&quot; It can be said that from the day the Chu State rose, the life-and-death war between Chu State and Sui State was destined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 800-year history of Chu State, King Xiong Tong of Chu Wu was a strong-armed figure. He stepped on the corpse of his nephew in a pool of blood and ascended to the throne by regicide. For more than half a century, King Wu of Chu focused on developing eastward and northward. Sui Guo, the eldest among the concubines in Hanyang, was the number one enemy that King Wu of Chu wanted to destroy quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In more than ten years, King Wu of Chu attacked his followers three times. In 706 BC, the Suihou listened to Ji Liang&#39;s advice, and the Chu army returned without success; in 704 BC, the Suihou listened to the advice of the young master, and the Sui army was defeated; in 690 BC, King Wu of Chu, who was over seventy years old, died of illness while attacking the Sui. journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although King Wu of Chu failed to annex Sui State as he wished, he greatly weakened Sui State&#39;s power and successively destroyed Quan State, Zhou State, Liao State, Lu State and Yan State, almost all of which occupied the fertile land. Jianghan Plain, and control the Tonglushan Mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;50 years later, King Chu Cheng, the grandson of King Wu of Chu, successively annexed more than a dozen small countries such as Er, Gu, Huang, Ying, Jiang, and Fang, thus realizing his grandfather&#39;s dream for many years - to control Sui. The country became a vassal of Chu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 640 BC, Sui Guo united with a group of small countries east of the Han River to raise troops to fight against Chu. The Chu State&#39;s order Yin Dougu Yu Tu led his army to attack, and his country and allied forces were severely defeated. He was forced to enter into a city-wide alliance with the Chu State and became a vassal of the Chu State. At this time, it was already the twenty-fifth year of King Hui of Zhou Dynasty. The originally powerful Western Zhou Dynasty had to move its capital to Luoyang more than 100 years ago. The strength of Emperor Zhou was greatly reduced, and he was at most equal to a medium-sized prince. Ji, Emperor Zhou already has too much time to take care of himself. From then on, Sui Guo &quot;subjected himself to Chu and had no access to China.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After vassaling the Chu State, Sui State, although its territory was reduced, the wars with Chu State were almost extinct. Sui State survived the wave of annexation that caused a large number of princes to perish and die. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/uFxHxiBjqtNLcxgtCb5LCVA9YjrAYrvYBz4iwOQ3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;615&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/uFxHxiBjqtNLcxgtCb5LCVA9YjrAYrvYBz4iwOQ3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256126&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Suizhou is located in the middle of the Jianghan Plain. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The drama of history lies in the fact that, both for Chu and Sui, the monarchs and subjects of the two countries What no one expected was that one day, Sui Guo, as a vassal, would be the final savior of the suzerain state Chu. Without Sui Guo, Chu State would probably have perished in the late Spring and Autumn Period. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 506 BC, the Great War between Wu and Chu broke out. King Helu of Wu personally led an army up the Huaihe River, and landed in the Huangchuan area of ​​present-day Henan Province. After being led by the troops of Cai and Tang, the Wu army moved south from the north of Chu to the Han River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu State was originally located in the eastern part of Chu State, and Chu State’s defensive focus has been in Yuzhang, which is now the Nanchang area of ​​Jiangxi Province. Unexpectedly, the Wu army avoided its main force and attacked its weak points, catching the Chu army by surprise. The two armies of Wu and Chu fought at Baiju &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (now Macheng, Hubei, also known as Hanchuan, Hubei)&lt;/span>;. The Wu army won five battles and five victories, and the Chu army was defeated. Ten days later, the Wu army captured Ying, the capital of Chu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the entire Spring and Autumn Period, Wu Jun&#39;s victory over Ying was the first and only battle to capture the capital of a major country. When the news came out, the princes were shocked and couldn&#39;t help but look at Wu State, which was originally regarded as a barbarian, with admiration. The main credit for the Wu State&#39;s creation of such a miracle should be attributed to Wu Zixu and Sun Wu. Just as the &quot;Book of Han&quot; said: Helu appointed Wu Zixu and Sun Wu as generals, defeated and captured them, and became famous among the princes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the capital of Chu was captured by the Wu army, King Zhao of Chu fled to Sui. At this time, this small country, which was almost the only remaining one among the concubines of Hanyang, became the last hope for the survival of Chu State. Wu State sent envoys to Sui State, hoping that Suihou would hand over King Zhao of Chu, and reminded Suihou, &quot;If the descendants of Zhou are in Hanchuan, Chu will be completely destroyed.&quot; - You Hanyang concubines are all about to be annexed by Chu State. . Now, God wants to punish Chu State, why did you hide the King of Chu? If he is handed over, the land of Hanyang will belong to Sui Guo. Suihou refused. He said that Sui Guo and Chu State had an alliance for generations, and he could not hand over the King of Chu. The army of Wu State penetrated deeply and its rear was unstable. It did not want to fight with Sui State anymore, so it had to retreat. Later, there was a story about Shen Baoxu crying to the Qin court and begging for the master of Qin, so that King Zhao of Chu could be revived. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of Sui&#39;s protection of King Chu Zhao, after King Chu Zhao returned to the country, the relationship between Chu and Sui began an unprecedented honeymoon period. Originally, after becoming a vassal of the Chu State, even though the Sui State was a prince originally enfeoffed by the Emperor of Zhou, it was already &quot;a private vassal of Chu, not connected with the princes, and conquered the alliance, and was disdained by others.&quot; Out of gratitude to the vassals, &quot;the people of Chu felt his virtue and made the vassals follow him.&quot; In other words, although Sui Guo was still a vassal of Chu State, Chu State allowed it to participate in international activities like a prince. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two pieces of sacrificial vessels from the Spring and Autumn Period collected in the Xiangyang Museum are witnesses of the friendship between Chu and Sui. In the pre-Qin period, when princes and nobles married their daughters, they usually made bronze vessels as dowries, which were called nunnery vessels. The two pieces of nurturing vessels in the Xiangyang Museum are called Zeng Hou Zuo Ji Tang Mi Ding, and the other is called Zeng Meng Mi Jian copper basin. The inscriptions on the two nunnery vessels indicate that a woman named Mi Tang and a woman named Mi Jian from Chu State were married to Sui State one after another. The surname Mi is the surname of the king of Chu State, and is the ancestor of the eighteen surnames of Jingchu. It was once widely known through the TV series &quot;Mi Yue Biography&quot;. Therefore, in the history of the relationship between Chu and Sui, there was a period of mutual intermarriage between Qin and Jin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;63 years after King Zhao of Chu came to Sui, the king of Sui, Zeng Houyi, passed away. At this time, the king of Chu was King Chu Hui, the son of King Zhao of Chu. Also out of gratitude for Sui Guo&#39;s righteous deeds, King Hui of Chu specially made ritual vessels to commemorate. In addition to King Hui of Chu, there were also a large group of Chu kings, princes, and ministers who commemorated Zeng Hou Yi. The originally unknown king of a small country unexpectedly gained honor because of his ancestor&#39;s political stance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/D58Kf2X0gt938eSSt2wEeryVCtZ4tdS5SO6aAcuY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/D58Kf2X0gt938eSSt2wEeryVCtZ4tdS5SO6aAcuY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256127&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The chimes under the night sky, the eternity left by the king of a small country unintentionally by chance. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Time is the enemy of emotion. If feelings are like wine, then time is the water that keeps seeping into the wine. The longer the time goes by, the more water penetrates into the wine, and the taste of the wine becomes lighter, so that in the end it is only the taste of water without the sweetness of wine. The feelings between people are like this, and the feelings between countries are like this. Especially in the face of interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Zeng Houyi and King Hui of Chu Jiuquan knew better, they would definitely regret the choice of their descendants: Sui Guo, who was kind to the Chu State, was eventually annexed by the Chu State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no historical record of when the Chu State was destroyed and it can only be inferred indirectly through unearthed cultural relics. Several hundred meters south of the tomb of Zeng Houyi, archaeologists excavated more than 30 tombs in 1983. These tombs were named Suizhou Leigudun Tomb No. 2. Archaeologists concluded that the artifacts unearthed from the tomb &quot;not only have strong Zeng cultural characteristics, but also have typical Chu cultural elements.&quot; Therefore, it is inferred that &quot;the tombs of Zeng people after the Zeng State was about to perish or was destroyed by the Chu State.&quot; The age of these tombs is roughly late in the early Warring States Period to early in the middle Warring States Period. Therefore, the demise of Sui State should be in The middle period of the Warring States Period. Support for this can also be found in the literature. For example, when Chun Shenjun advised Qin not to attack Chu in 272 BC, he mentioned that &quot;the soil on the right side of the river&quot; was the territory of Chu. Suishui is Guangshui, and the soil on the right side of Suishui is to the west of Guangshui, which is the area under the jurisdiction of Sui State at that time. That is to say, by 272 BC at the latest, Sui State had been merged into Chu State. At this time, a century and a half had passed since the honeymoon period between Zeng Hou Yi and King Hui of Chu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/TIe7DGLaYio4GfVpDTfq4zKoVn9Jexr648fKGk1g.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/TIe7DGLaYio4GfVpDTfq4zKoVn9Jexr648fKGk1g.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256128&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Suizhou Guangshui hilly landform&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The long history of Suizhou In history, except for a few people such as Ji Liang, most princes, nobles and even monarchs have vague faces. Even Zeng Hou Yi, who is famous for his chimes, is unknown to future generations about his life. When I inspected the tomb of Marquis Zeng Yi in Leigudun, what moved me the most was neither the chimes nor the jades, but the 21 young women whose names I will never know. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Besides the main coffin where Zeng Houyi rests, there are 8 auxiliary coffins. Inside the coffins, there is a human skeleton, each of which is a woman between 19 and 26 years old. They may be concubines or attendants of Zeng Houyi. In the west room near the main room, there are another 13 slave coffins. Inside the coffins, there is also a human skeleton, which is a woman between 13 and 24 years old. They are both burial objects, but have different identities and titles. The former is called human sacrifice. Most of the human sacrifices are the wives, concubines and attendants of the deceased, who have a higher status, while the human sacrifices are prisoners of war or slaves. People are buried in the tomb of the deceased, with their bodies intact and with fine burial tools, so that they can continue to serve the deceased in the other world. Human sacrifices were buried in special sacrificial pits, with mostly incomplete bodies and rough burial tools, in order to sacrifice them to the gods of heaven and earth and ancestors. Of course, some people were forced to die, but there were also those who volunteered to be buried with them. As for human sacrifices, it can almost be concluded that none of them were voluntary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A king of a small country who has become a vassal still has to be buried with 21 young and fresh lives after his death. Apart from the splendid splendor of chimes and jades, I vaguely saw that long-gone era. Bloody, ignorant and barbaric. In this context, Ji Liang&#39;s statement that &quot;the husband and the people are the lords of the gods&quot;, although it is difficult for the monarchs to truly put it into practice, is still like a firefly flickering in the distance in the dark night, weak but precious. Because of this firefly, the cold history has a little bit of human warmth. &lt;p>; &quot;Yi Tomb&quot; &quot;Exploring the Origin of Suizhou Culture&quot; &quot;Research on the History of Zeng Guo and Sui Guo&quot; &quot;An Examination of the Destruction of the Chu State&quot;]&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[微信抖音等多家平台将引导“自媒体”账号对外实名丨滚动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259677]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 18:39:31&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;October 2023 18:00 on the 31st&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;WeChat’s announcement on the display of real-name information by “self-media” accounts in the header&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to maintain good network communication order, promote the construction of a healthy and orderly cyberspace, enhance the credibility of top &quot;self-media&quot; accounts, and facilitate public supervision for the public interest. WeChat will guide &quot;self-media&quot; accounts with more than 500,000 &quot;fans&quot; in batches and stages. &quot;Media&quot; accounts will display real-name information to the outside world. In the near future, &quot;self-media&quot; accounts with more than 1 million &quot;fans&quot; will be first guided to display real-name information to the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;fans&quot; status of WeChat official accounts and video accounts, after the user confirms and agrees to display the &quot;self-media&quot; accounts on the platform with more than 1 million &quot;fans&quot;, if the account registration subject is an individual type, the registrant will be displayed Real name. Institutional accounts display the name of the company and institution. Related real-name information can be viewed on the account profile page. The platform encourages &quot;self-media&quot; creators to express themselves authentically and provide users with higher-quality and trustworthy content. &quot;We-media&quot; accounts with more than 1 million &quot;fans&quot; that do not display real-name information to the outside world will have their account traffic and income restricted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The platform will continue to optimize product functions, create a green and healthy content ecosystem, and provide better development space for &quot;self-media&quot; creators. We also welcome the supervision and suggestions of netizens to jointly create a clear online space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;(WeChat Coral Security Public Account)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023 October 31, 18:00&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Douyin’s announcement on “Account real-name information display”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;2&quot; >;In order to enhance the credibility of &quot;self-media&quot; accounts, protect the legitimate rights and interests of users, and maintain a clear and healthy platform order, the number of fans has reached 500,000 and published &quot;self-media&quot; content involving current affairs, society, finance, education, medical and health, justice, etc. &quot;We Media&quot; accounts need to authorize the platform to display authenticated real-name information on the account homepage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;3&quot;>;The specific method is as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;ol>; &lt;li data-track=&quot;4&quot;>;&quot;Self-media&quot; accounts that meet the conditions for displaying real-name information will receive Notification via email, you can perform authorization operations according to the prompts. The real-name information should be the real name or company name for account authentication, and should be consistent with the submitted identity document, business license and other information. &lt;/li>; &lt;li data-track=&quot;5&quot;>;After the platform is authorized, the authenticated real-name information will be displayed on the account homepage. &lt;/li>; &lt;/ol>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;7&quot;>;Users who need to authorize the display of account real-name information will receive an in-site letter notification. The specific online time for authorized display shall be subject to the actual notification. If the account receives the notification but is not authenticated or authorized, it will have an impact on the dissemination of account content, commercial income, etc., until the authentication and authorization display are completed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot; data-track=&quot;25&quot;>;（抖音安全中心）&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;25&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2023年10月31日18:18&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p data-track=&quot;25&quot;>;&lt;strong>;微博发布关于“自媒体”账号实名信息展示的公告&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为营造安全、文明、和谐的网络生态环境，增强平台头部“自媒体”账号的可信度及权威性，站方将于近期引导头部“自媒体”账号进行前台实名展示，以此进一步规范“自媒体”账号运营管理，更便于公众为社会公共利益实施监督。具体说明如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. 站方将于近期引导社会时事、军事、财经、法律、医疗等专业领域100万粉丝以上的“自媒体”账号填写实名信息，后续将逐步扩大到相关领域50万粉丝以上的“自媒体”账号，经用户同意后进行前台实名展示。 &lt;br>;2. 普通用户及以个人日常生活分享为主的领域账号不受前台实名展示的影响。 &lt;br>;3. 用户填写实名信息后，将在个人资料页展示用户的真实姓名。对于未登录的游客用户、未通过真实身份信息验证的用户、行为异常用户以及近期因不友善行为被处置的用户，禁止查看其他用户前台实名信息。 &lt;br>;4. 站方将通过私信告知需进行前台实名展示的用户，用户可通过私信链接引导进行前台实名信息填写。 &lt;br>;5. 接收到私信引导但未进行前台实名信息填写的用户，其账号的流量和收入将受到部分限制，包括推荐流展示限制、热搜展示限制、广告分成限制、打赏收入限制等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;各平台的头部“自媒体”大V因其拥有的社会影响力，在讨论社会时事热点时，具有远超普通用户的舆论引导作用，而前台实名的实施正是为了推动大V承担起与话语能量相匹配的责任，从而进一步推进网络舆论生态治理。后续，站方将不断优化并完善前台实名展示流程及规则，在压实平台主体责任的同时积极提升用户体验。同时，站方也感谢广大用户对前台实名的积极支持与配合，微博愿与各界力量携手，共同营造清朗的网络空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;（@微博管理员）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[韩国酵母又火了！为何“发面馒头”是明星的颜值终点站？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259623]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 17:01:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第十届北京香山论坛，高端对话探讨全球安全]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259661]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 16:37:59&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;第十届北京香山论坛于10月29日至31日在北京国际会议中心举行。 论坛以“共同安全持久和平”为主题，是历届北京香山论坛以来规模最大的一次，外方代表数量达到了历届之最。</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[神舟十六号航天员乘组平安抵京]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259673]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 15:44:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据中国载人航天工程办公室消息，圆满完成神舟十六号载人飞行任务的航天员乘组，于2023年10月31日乘坐任务飞机平安抵达北京。空间站应用与发展阶段飞行任务总指挥部领导到机场迎接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3名航天员抵京后将进入隔离恢复期，进行全面的医学检查和健康评估，并安排休养。之后，将在京与新闻媒体集体见面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:29:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[县文联有奖征文，获奖者多是内部人：如此吃相太难看丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259655]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一个县级文联主办的有奖征文，大半获奖者是文联旗下刊物的编辑部成员，其中主编获奖作品12篇，几近获奖作品的半数。这一文坛“盛事”日前引起了不小的关注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据华商报报道，实名认证为河南方城县文联的微信公众号“裕州心声”（裕州是方城县旧称）10月26日发布一篇题为《“清风方城”文学艺术作品有奖征文获奖名单揭晓》的文章，称由方城县纪监委、方城县文联联合主办的“清风方城”有奖征文活动圆满成功，25篇作品分获一二三等奖及鼓励奖（原文如此，但公布的获奖作品名单实际只有23篇）。令人大跌眼镜的是，在名单所示的23篇获奖作品中，有12篇的作者是同一个人“乔君笠”，其中一等奖1篇、二等奖1篇、三等奖4篇、鼓励奖6篇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一人独揽几乎近半奖项，如此实力，如此天纵英才，乔君笠何许人也？文章最后所附的《裕州心声》编委会名单显示，乔君笠正是这一刊物的主编。而方城县检察院官方社媒账号此前发布的文章显示，乔君笠还是方城县文联副主席。而方城县文联正是这次征文活动的主办方之一，《裕州心声》则是活动的承办方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再细看获奖名单，23篇获奖作品中，至少有18篇的作者是《裕州心声》编辑部成员，除了乔君笠的12篇之外，还有总编郭某栓（方城县文联主席）1篇作品获二等奖；副总编熊某祥2篇作品分别获二等奖、三等奖；副主编李某雁、编委会成员梁某锋、策划武某华也各有1篇文章获奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自己主办有奖征文活动，自己人获奖，还不止一人，还有人十多篇文章同时获奖，实在令人叹为观止。 “清风方城”，清风何在？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;众所周知，各种正规的公开比赛、评选等活动，为了保障公平公正，评委必须保持中立，不应与任何参赛者有利益关联，而且通常会规定一人只能获得一个奖项。就连不少商业企业主办的抽奖促销活动也规定，员工和家属不能参与，否则即使中奖了也要作废。更不用说文联作为一个社会团体，在中国是受公共财政支持的，属于公共机构。作为活动主办和承办方，方城县文联和下属刊物理应保持客观中立的立场，以保证奖项评选的公正性。结果，文联的领导和刊物编辑部成员亲自下场比赛，还获得了大多数奖项。既做裁判员，又做运动员，谈何比赛的公平公正？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2000年《读书》举办的首届长江读书奖，《读书》主编汪晖和作为评委的钱理群均有作品获奖，就曾经引起巨大争议。自评自奖当然是不符合公平原则的，不客气地说，某种意义上就是“分赃”。如果作者认为自己的作品足够优秀，有资格获奖，那也应该避嫌，不仅不应作为评委，甚至有必要辞去主办方的相关职务，否则就不应该参与评奖。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而方城县的这个征文比赛，还可能涉及私分公共资金的问题。单从奖金金额上看，这似乎不是一件大事。比赛一等奖奖金每篇也不过500元，二等奖每篇400元，三等奖每篇300元，鼓励奖每篇200元。乔主编12篇作品获奖，总奖金也不过才3300元。但是，方城县曾经是贫困县，2019年才摘帽。根据方城县2022年政府工作报告，2021年全县GDP293亿元，以该县2020年第七次人口普查时的87万余人计算，人均GDP3.3万元左右，城镇居民人均可支配收入33574元，农村居民人均可支配收入16315元。也就是说，乔主编在这次有奖活动中所得的奖金，相当于该县城镇年人均可支配收入的1/10，农民年人均可支配收入的1/5。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;纪检委和文联联合主办的这一有奖征文比赛，奖金来源恐怕很大可能是财政资金。这样一场征文比赛，获奖者几乎都是自己人，而且一人独得近半奖项，让人不得不怀疑，这是巧立名目用公款为自己发钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，也有一种可能是征文比赛无人问津，文联的领导们才不得不亲自出马。根据上文所说，这一征文比赛自2022年11月20日开始，6月30日截稿。尽管“社会各界文学爱好者积极响应，广泛发动，潜心创作”，但半年多的时间里，也只征集到49部作品。可见，方城县的“文学爱好者”并不是很多，或者大家对这样的比赛不感兴趣，所以没什么人投稿，而且投稿的质量也欠佳。为了避免出现无人得奖的尴尬局面，乔主编才不得不把自己的作品拿来充数。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，如果是这种情况，文联的责任也不容推卸。作为当地的文学艺术工作者的组织，文联难道不应该了解自己县里有多少文学工作者、爱好者吗？征文能有多少响应，也是应该可以估计到的。对于明知可能无人问津的比赛，还要去策划去组织，最后自己人出面撑门面拿奖，那更坐实了“巧立名目为自己发钱”的嫌疑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，类似的现象不仅仅存在于方城县这一件事上，其他更严重的也很多。比如云南某国企的一把手，就曾经以各种名目为自己发放了几千万元的“奖励”，终以贪污等罪名被处罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一征文活动的主办方之一是县纪监委，却出现这样的丑闻，实在是讽刺。舆论关注之下，方城县文联已经删掉了获奖名单，并声称之前是“初评结果”，未经主办方同意就发布了，下一步将组织市里的专家重新评审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;方城县也为此成立了专门的调查组，在10月31日凌晨发布情况说明，初步调查认定评选环节存在问题，评选结果无效，至于后续调查处理情况，将“适时”发布。公众期待调查组的最终处理结果。或许，最合适的处理方案是取消这一征文活动，追回资金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 16:29:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[反向合资，中外车企探索合作新模式丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259659]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 12:02:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/31/PMAhFrUA6OTlsple6X7qVTgBVZcJhXr6oXIcl8wf.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1408&quot; height=&quot;758&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/PMAhFrUA6OTlsple6X7qVTgBVZcJhXr6oXIcl8wf . png&quot; data-key=&quot;256200&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 24, GAC Group issued an announcement that the board of directors reviewed and approved the &quot; Announcement on Related Transactions Regarding the Reorganization of GAC Mitsubishi.&quot; GAC Group acquired 30% and 20% of the equity of GAC Mitsubishi held by Mitsubishi Motors Co., Ltd. and Mitsubishi Corporation respectively for a consideration of 1 yuan. After the reorganization is completed, GAC Mitsubishi will become a wholly-owned subsidiary of GAC Group, and GAC Aian will Utilize the GAC Mitsubishi plant to increase production and expand capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is not just Mitsubishi. With the rise of China&#39;s local car brands in recent years, joint venture brands such as Suzuki, Renault, Acura, Jeep, etc. have gradually withdrawn from the Chinese market. Some car companies will choose to use another model. Cooperate with domestic enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, Stellantis Group, the world’s fourth largest automobile manufacturer, and Leapmotor jointly announced that Stellantis Group plans to invest approximately 1.5 billion euros (approximately 11.6 billion yuan) to acquire approximately 20% of Leapmotor. % of the equity and obtained 2 seats on the board of directors of Leapmotor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with Volkswagen&#39;s acquisition of approximately 4.99% of Xpeng Motors&#39; equity for approximately US$700 million in July, Leapao&#39;s cooperation with Stellantis is more in-depth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Stellantis will not only participate in the Chinese market as a strategic investor of Leapmotor, but the two parties will also form a joint venture company, Leapmotor International, to jointly develop the international market. Leapmotor holds 49% of the shares and Stellantis Group Holds 51% of shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 1984, Beijing Jeep, the first Sino-foreign joint venture car company, was born. Foreign car brands came to China with technology and brands. China&#39;s modern automobile industry has gone through nearly 40 years of development with the &quot;market for technology&quot; model. In 2017, in the face of fierce competition and technological progress in China&#39;s new energy vehicle market, foreign car companies have begun to explore new models of cooperation with Chinese car companies, and &quot;reverse joint ventures&quot; are becoming a new option. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;01&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;]&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://openai.com/blog/frontier -risk-and-preparedness&quot;>;&lt;u>;OpenAI forms new team to assess &quot;catastrophic risks&quot; of artificial intelligence&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;October 26, artificial intelligence Intelligence research company OpenAI announced the formation of a new team, Preparedness, to assess and mitigate &quot;catastrophic risks&quot; associated with artificial intelligence. The team&#39;s main mission is to &quot;track, assess, predict and protect&quot; potential major problems caused by artificial intelligence, and work to mitigate &quot;chemical, biological and radiological threats&quot;, as well as the &quot;autonomous replicating&quot; behavior of artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : With the development and application of artificial intelligence technology, human society is also facing a series of challenges in industrial development models and regulatory models that go beyond traditional experience. Many countries have drafted and formulated new regulatory measures on artificial intelligence, but people must be the ones to untie the bell. The active participation and action of large model manufacturers will be a force to help artificial intelligence develop better. (Recommended by: Tang Jiale)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;02&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;]&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https ://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/cArAd1qxXVblfdwAAqTk5g&quot;>;&lt;u>;Huawei releases unmanned open-pit mine solution&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;October 25 On September 1, Huawei, together with China Huaneng Group, Xingsheng Open-pit Mine, Jiugang Group, and Tongli Heavy Industry, jointly released the &quot;Unmanned Solution for Open-pit Mines&quot;, in which key unmanned technologies such as heavy-duty remote control and driverless driving have been commercialized on a large scale. , the efficiency is the same as that of manual operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remote control of open pit mine reinstallation can realize the transition from human-machine interaction to machine-machine interaction for piercing and shoveling. The piercing operation ranges from 1 person and 1 drill on site to 1 person and 3 drills remotely. The mining and installation site is 100% manual. 80% remote automatic remote control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Pain points such as poor mining conditions and high safety risks have long restricted the development of the coal industry. In March 2020, eight ministries and commissions of the State Council issued the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Accelerating the Development of Intelligent Coal Mines&quot;, proposing that all types of coal mines will be basically intelligent by 2035, and coal mining may become a pioneer in the intelligent transformation of traditional industries. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;03&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;]&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin .qq.com/s/YWywXP_xGCpSUqkijrXv3A&quot;>;&lt;u>;China Telecom Research Institute completed the world’s first operator NR&amp;nbsp;NTN live network test&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;October 25 On the same day, the China Telecommunications Research Institute announced that it would work closely with China Telecom Shanghai Emergency Communications Bureau and China Telecom Satellite Corporation, jointly with Beijing Jiefeng Chuangzhi Technology and Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications to complete the world&#39;s first operator NR&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp; based on geosynchronous orbit satellites. &lt;/span>;NTN (non-terrestrial network) terminals are directly connected to the satellite live network environment test and verification. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The test results show that under the 5MHz low-bandwidth spectrum resource, the NR&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;NTN network based on geosynchronous orbit satellites can still provide stable voice, SMS and broadband data services. As an important portable solution in the national emergency communication service system and comprehensive information service system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Satellite communications are an important part of 5G-Advanced and 6G, and the three major operators are actively exploring them. In September 2023, China Mobile joined hands with ZTE and Keysight Technologies to complete the first domestic operator NR&amp;nbsp;NTN low-orbit satellite laboratory simulation verification. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;[&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;04&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;]&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.excision .bio/_files/ugd/80a6fd_de98df6a38d042658595374af17d658a.pdf&quot;>;&lt;u>;The world’s first HIV gene editing therapy clinical trial data released&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;October 25, American biotechnology company Excision announced positive interim data from its Phase 1/2 clinical trial of its ongoing CRISPR gene therapy EBT-101 in the treatment of HIV-1 (a type of AIDS virus) infection. Among the first three clinical trial participants, treatment with EBT-101 resulted in no serious adverse events or dose-limiting toxicities, and all reported adverse events were mild and reversible; all participants had &lt;span>;&lt;/span>; in their blood. span>; EBT-101 was detected and the treatment resulted in positive biodistribution; these data support advancing this clinical trial to the next dose level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;EBT-101 is a therapy that uses CRISPR gene editing in patients, aiming to cure HIV infection through a single intravenous infusion. It is also the world&#39;s first human clinical trial using CRISPR gene editing to treat AIDS. . The therapy was approved by the U.S. FDA for human clinical trials at the end of 2021 and received fast-track status from the FDA in 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The existing standard treatment for AIDS is antiretroviral therapy, which can prevent the HIV virus from replicating in the body, but cannot clear the HIV virus. Patients need to receive long-term continuous treatment. The discovery of CRISPR was a breakthrough in the search for a potential cure for AIDS, and EBT-101 is the first CRISPR therapy to target an integrated virus in humans. The destination of &quot;curing HIV infection&quot; is still far away, but there are people on the road and continue to make progress. (Recommended by: Luo Xianxian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“快枪手”邱礼涛的反驳：“我花的时间没有人们想象得那么短”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259633]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 15:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[依法查处，数百个非法涉外气象探测站向境外传输数据]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259639]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since this year, national security agencies, together with meteorological and security departments, have carried out special management of foreign-related meteorological detection nationwide in accordance with the law. , investigated more than 10 overseas meteorological equipment agents, inspected more than 3,000 foreign-related meteorological stations, and found that hundreds of illegal foreign-related meteorological detection stations transmit meteorological data overseas in real time, widely distributed in more than 20 provinces across the country, posing risks to our national security Hidden danger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/e51a5a9b001cc3382bde484cf2fecfe1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;725&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/e51a5a9b001cc3382bde484cf2fecfe1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256145&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Illegal weather detection equipment installed by an overseas company&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/31/f149ab4f4378829dd94d0ce3f794c295.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/f149ab4f4378829dd94d0ce3f794c295.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256146&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Set Illegal meteorological detection equipment in our residential areas&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of these illegal foreign-related meteorological detection sites are directly funded by overseas governments, and some observation points are set up around sensitive places such as military units and military industrial enterprises to conduct altitude measurements. Approval and GPS positioning; some are deployed in China&#39;s main grain-producing areas to correlate the growth of China&#39;s crops and grain yields; some are even transmitted to foreign official meteorological agencies in real-time at long-term, high-frequency, and multiple points to serve foreign homeland security and weather monitoring. The relevant equipment is small in size, easy to install, difficult to find, and can automatically collect and transmit over the network in real time. For relevant foreign-related meteorological detection activities, they failed to apply for an administrative license for foreign-related meteorological detection from our meteorological authorities, failed to submit meteorological data to our meteorological authorities, and transmitted meteorological data overseas without the approval of our meteorological authorities, violating the &quot;Foreign-related Meteorological Observations and Data&quot; &quot;Administrative Measures&quot;, &quot;Data Security Law&quot; and other relevant regulations. National security agencies, in conjunction with meteorological and confidentiality departments, investigate and deal with relevant illegal activities in accordance with the law, and promptly block illegal activities of exporting meteorological data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“没有丢下战友的习惯”：走进“生死在一起连”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259573]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 12:30:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The &quot;Life and Death Together Company&quot; of a brigade of the 74th Group Army organized an offensive and defensive drill. Photo by Zhang Yongjin/ &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d8943f6615.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d8943f6615.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The &quot;Life and Death Together Company&quot; of a brigade of the 74th Group Army organized an offensive and defensive drill. Photo by Zhang Yongjin&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In northern Guangdong in September, the hot and humid air after the rain is breathless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the roar of engines, unmanned reconnaissance, firepower raids, impact breakthroughs... According to the company&#39;s &quot;roundabout and outflank&quot; tactics, the Second Company quickly took over Set fire points from multiple directions to complete the mission of seizing control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the second company of a brigade of the 74th Group Army of the Army conducting an offensive and defensive drill. In recent years, the officers and soldiers of this company have participated in various types of offensive and defensive warfare drills and competition exercises for many times. The training footprints have been all over the coast of the South China Sea, the Lingnan jungle, the depths of the desert and the Gobi plateau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Second Company was born in the flames of the Anti-Japanese War and grew up in the flames of war. It has the title of &quot;Life and Death Together Company&quot; and &quot;Unite and Grow Together&quot;. , fight together, live and die together”. Entering the period of peace-building, the company has been reformed and moved three times, but it has always inherited the spirit of &quot;life and death together&quot; and worked hard to forge the company into &quot;a hard piece of steel.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Life and Death Together&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Soldier Wu Shanjie will never forget the scene when company commander Zhang Peijin carried him on the plateau competition field. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2022, the heat in Yunnan was unbearable. At that time, the competition between &quot;good warriors&quot; was in full swing: a ten-kilometer run, bunker construction, reconnaissance, bomb dropping... There were many competitions, and they were very physically demanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At first, Zhang Peijin led six soldiers from his company to participate in the competition and was always far ahead. However, during the last armed three-kilometer run event, Wu Shanjie suddenly suffered from leg cramps and fell to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to regulations, one team member is allowed to fall behind in this project without affecting the overall assessment results. Wu Shanjie, who was in unbearable pain, asked the company commander to put him down so as not to affect the final result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Peijin, who has participated in multiple subject assessments continuously, has already seen his clothes soaked with sweat and his physical strength is close to the limit. Looking at Wu Shanjie who fell to the ground, he gritted his teeth and said, &quot;&#39;Life and Death Company&#39; has no habit of leaving behind its comrades.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As soon as he finished speaking, Zhang Peijin picked up Wu Shanjie on his back and sprinted towards the finish line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the long journey of the last kilometer, Zhang Peijin got tired, so other comrades took over and took turns carrying Wu Shanjie until the end. The second team, which could have achieved better results, only finished fourth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Of course there will be regrets.&quot; Zhang Peijin confessed to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;But compared with the results, it is more important for the comrades to stand side by side and rush to the finish line. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Never abandoning any teammate is a glorious tradition inherited by the Second Company from the smoke-filled war years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the honor room of the Second Company, a sculpture based on the story of a stretcher silently tells the origin of the company&#39;s name and also interprets the meaning of &quot;life and death together.&quot; &quot;The spiritual connotation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 1946, the company was ordered to cover the retreat of the main force. Soldier Zhu Jicai was shot in the leg and injured. Due to the hot weather and lack of medical treatment, his wounds became infected and ulcerated, and he was unable to walk. In order not to drag down the company, Zhu Jicai took the initiative to ask his comrades to put him down and continue marching. But faced with the encircling enemies, his comrades were unwilling to leave him behind. They made a simple stretcher out of branches and vines and carried him while marching and fighting with the red flag. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the critical juncture of life and death, the entire company dealt with dozens of times the enemy for more than 80 days. Not a single soldier was left behind. The mission was successfully completed. After the war, the company was ordered to Awarded the honorary title of &quot;Life and Death Together&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Over the past seventy years, the company has participated in more than 120 battles such as the Benxi Defense War, the Tashan Blockade, and the self-defense counterattack against Vietnam. Entering a new era, it has successively completed major tasks such as adjustment of the organizational structure, relocation of defenses, and cross-regional base-based exercises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The company fought in the north and south, its numbers were adjusted several times, and its location was constantly changed, but the glorious tradition of &quot;living and dying together&quot; has never changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In the war years, my comrades rushed to the battlefield together. They dared to hand their backs to me, and I was willing to take bullets for them. This is the difference between life and death. Let&#39;s &#39;spirit together.&quot; After serving in the army for 11 years, Zi Guangyong has his own views on company spirit. He said that in peaceful times, this spirit is more reflected in daily training and every detail of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He gave an example. On the training ground, if a comrade was feeling unwell, he would help him carry his gun; during the exercise, if the task was difficult, they would complete it together. &quot;It&#39;s like a football match. You can&#39;t win the game just by playing alone.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Officers and soldiers of the &quot;Life and Death Company&quot; review the battle stories of the company&#39;s history. Photo by Zhang Yongjin&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/30/41dc7516ed.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/41dc7516ed .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The officers and soldiers of the &quot;Life and Death Company&quot; relived the battle stories of the company&#39;s history. Zhang Yongjin/photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Practice more with brothers&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >; &quot;These five years in the Second Company have taught me what brotherhood is, and also made me regard the army as my second home.&quot; Tibetan young man Zeren Tashi told Southern Weekend reporters. It’s hard to imagine that when he first came to the army, he couldn’t even speak Mandarin well and “didn’t want to chat with others.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2018, Zeren Tashi enlisted in the army from Ganzi, Sichuan. From the snowy plateau to the southeastern coast, Zeren Tashi clearly felt acclimated to the new environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Worried that others would not understand what he said, and not wanting to worry his family by talking to them, Zeren Tashi, who was already introverted and sensitive, became increasingly withdrawn and depressed. During breaks, he would always go to the basketball court to play alone. When other comrades came over to play, he would quit and give up the court to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Zeren Tashi fell into deep self-doubt, his comrades came. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bing Luojiang came from Guangxi in the same year. He was carefully aware of Zeren Tashi&#39;s emotions and used his own Mandarin as an example, but he was still a &quot;social cow&quot; , encouraging Zeren Tashi. From that time on, the enthusiastic Luo Jiang took Zeren Tashi to chat with his comrades every day to help him actively integrate into collective life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The company also opened &quot;a window&quot; specifically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Whenever I encounter Chinese characters I don&#39;t know during study, my comrades will explain them to me carefully.&quot; Zeren Tashi said, and the company commander also encouraged He must be brave enough to show himself in front of everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, during the subject demonstration activity organized by the Second Company, Zeren Tashi gave a sharing lesson to the company, and his confident behavior won the audience. Applause, &quot;There was a great sense of satisfaction at that time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, the Second Company has more than a dozen ethnic minority soldiers from Tibetan, Zhuang, Li, Mulao and other ethnic groups. Some of them are leaving their hometown for the first time, and some are recent college graduates, with different personalities and physical qualities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How to make them feel the warmth of home in the company, the company has its own &quot;unique secrets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Second Company produces a &quot;Knowledge of Soldiers&quot; for each recruit, including various aspects such as physical condition, family situation, interests and hobbies. &quot;In daily life, the backbone of the company cadres will take the initiative to talk to the recruits, understand their actual situation, and help them solve the difficulties in life.&quot; Instructor Wang Gaosheng told Southern Weekend reporters that during the training process, the squad leader will also teach them hand-in-hand. Integrate into the company as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he first joined the Second Company in 2022, Mulao soldier Qin Guoxing had not had time to get familiar with the company, but reality poured cold water on him. He is a graduate student from 211 College and is regarded as the &quot;proud son of heaven&quot; in the eyes of his parents and friends. However, in Erlian, where there are many experts, his business ability is often only at the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tin Guoxing felt frustrated and often tossed and turned at night and couldn&#39;t sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Comrade Wang Lei saw Tan Guoxing like this and decided to help. Wang Lei is a &quot;veteran&quot; with solid and outstanding abilities and qualities. He took the initiative to play the role of a small instructor, training with Tan Guoxing, and teaching skills step by step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, Qin Guoxing and Wang Lei have become a &quot;pair&quot; with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In daily training, Wang Lei led Qin Guoxing to strengthen physical training, while Qin Guoxing helped Wang Lei answer questions in theoretical study. In helping each other and competing, the two not only improved their performance, but also forged a deep friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Practice more with your brothers and you won&#39;t feel like you are walking alone.&quot; Qin Guoxing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Big things on my mind&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;These are all obtained by our ancestors with blood and sweat. You need to find a way to fill the remaining vacancies. .&quot; On the day of joining the company, the company commander led the recruits to stand in front of the wall of honor, pointing to the wall of honor medals and saying, &quot;If the honor of the company is lost from your hands, it will be a disservice to the revolutionary martyrs of the second company.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;A unit with excellent military training results&quot;, &quot;A top company in basic subject competition training&quot;, &quot;Comprehensive construction of an advanced unit&quot;, &quot;Comprehensive construction of a model company&quot;... Enter the second company In the camp, a &quot;luxurious wall&quot; covered with honorary medals is shocking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Over the past few decades, the Second Company has been rated as an advanced company in comprehensive construction or an advanced unit of the &quot;Four Irons&quot; for 27 consecutive years, and has won the second-class collective merit 7 times, 18 times of collective third-class merit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Lan Zhihao was still in the first company of the recruits, he had seen this wall through the window. He knew that this must be a heroic and honorary unit, and he was very eager to be assigned to the second company after the recruit training was completed. As a result, his wish came true. He was surprised, happy and full of energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zeren Tashi&#39;s mood seems a bit complicated. He is proud to be a member of the &quot;benchmark company&quot; of the entire brigade, but also worried about not being able to keep up. The pace of training. In his words, &quot;I feel like I&#39;m done, and I might be choked in training.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Defending the honor of the heroic company has become a major issue that weighs on the minds of every officer and soldier of the second company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But in the main battle unit with so many strong men, such a goal is easy to say, but to achieve it requires extraordinary hard work and sweat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, a major training mission was held in Yunnan, and company commander Zhang Peijin led the entire company to participate. In order to win the victory, the Second Company began to make key preparations from the beginning of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;One month before the exercise, we organized soldier training during the day and worked overtime at night to deduce plans and study tactics.&quot; Zhang Peijin recalled, &quot;The backbone of the company also accompanied us. Stay up late with me, just to increase the chance of winning in the final battle.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Despite adequate preparation, the accident still happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the live-fire shooting session, Zhang Peijin and artillery technician Xiang Jinwen&#39;s company command vehicle suddenly experienced a transmission failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;When changing the target and shooting, I can only hear the sound of the motor inside, but the shell cannot be fired.&quot; Xiang Jinwen made an instant judgment , &quot;It must be a jammed bullet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Without any hesitation, Xiang Jinwen quickly raised the armored vehicle&#39;s gun, opened the back cover to determine the specific location of the jammed bullet. , and removed the fixing device of the artillery, and took out the shells with bare hands. The entire process, from problem arose to troubleshooting, took just over a minute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the artillery roared and the shells accurately hit the target, Xiang Jinwen&#39;s hanging heart was completely relieved. He said, &quot;This is a super-level performance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the end, the Second Company stood out in the inspection and evaluation and was rated as an &quot;advanced unit against actual troops.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bite the &quot;hard bones&quot; together&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2015 4 In August, the company made personnel adjustments, and Xiang Jinwen was recommended to the Second Company for development because of his &quot;excellent professional quality.&quot; He feels very lucky because the Second Company is the model unit in the division. From the cadres to the recruits, everyone is proud to be here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To date, Xiang Jinwen has stayed in the Second Company for more than eight years, and he has experienced several important milestones of the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2019, in order to adapt to future combat needs, the second company installed brand-new main battle equipment, which has better maneuverability, stronger firepower, and can achieve rapid Intersperse to achieve the effect of surprising and defeating the enemy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;All kinds of new equipment made the entire company excited. However, the ensuing practical difficulties of &quot;lack of teaching plans, lack of standards, and lack of talents&quot; also plagued the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The equipment is highly informatized and coincides with the retirement of many experienced technical backbones. The new equipment has brought us great challenges.&quot; Xiang Jinwen recalled, &quot;Every time the live-fire shooting results were very unsatisfactory.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Short-stop shooting requires that the armored vehicle must pause briefly and fire while moving. Aiming and shooting puts forward higher cooperation requirements for the cooperation of the driver, communicator and shooter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;From parking to launching to destroy the target and then to the vehicle moving, the whole process only takes six to eight seconds.&quot; Xiang Jinwen said, &quot;If the cooperation is not good, , it is easy for the vehicle to impact again before the shell is fired.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The time for training in the field is very tight, in order to squeeze out time to bond with teammates. Xiang Jinwen had almost no rest during that period and stayed on the training ground with his comrades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The heat in July and August is unbearable. After being exposed to the sun, the temperature inside the armored vehicle can reach more than 50 degrees. If you stay in the vehicle for a long time, it will not last long. Clothes can be squeezed out of water. Xiang Jinwen described that as soon as he got off the armored vehicle, he felt dizzy and &quot;wanted to vomit but couldn&#39;t.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fortunately, Xiang Jinwen and his team performed at a high level every time they fired live ammunition, and also achieved excellent results in the assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obviously, the iterative update of equipment brings not only the problem of equipment adaptation, but also the need for matching tactical means and tactics to promote the company&#39;s preparation for war. Transformation and capability upgrading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to form combat effectiveness as soon as possible, the then company commander Wang Xiaolin led the backbone of the company&#39;s cadres to make their own standards and lesson plans, and conduct tactical drills &quot;crossing the river by feeling for the stones.&quot; They stayed at the training ground during the day and in the equipment room at night. They studied hard for more than two months and finally achieved a comprehensive improvement in combat effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;At that time, I stayed up late to study every night, often until one or two in the morning.&quot; Xiang Jinwen still has a vivid memory of staying up late to train. , I didn’t stay in bed early the next morning and continued to get up early to learn new equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the same type of companies, the Second Company was the first to receive inspections and the first to carry out course demonstrations, achieving the brigade&#39;s goal of &quot;forming combat effectiveness that year.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the &quot;model company&quot; in the brigade, there are countless cases where the Second Company worked together to overcome difficulties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The company is responsible for researching multiple subjects and researching tactics on a daily basis. However, these tasks are arduous and complex, and there is no way I can complete them with my own strength. .&quot; Whenever he reaches a bottleneck, his comrades will actively crowd around Zhang Peijin. They will work together on the training ground to optimize tactics and tactics during the day, and work overtime at night to sum up experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Peijin said, &quot;I know that I am not fighting alone. I have a group of brothers to help me share the burden.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;In this year&#39;s platoon tactical assessment organized by the brigade, the first platoon of the second company was selected to represent the company in the assessment. After competing with more than a dozen teams on the same stage, the Second Company relied on its advantages in unmanned equipment operation to leave other units far behind and won the first place in the assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In order to prepare for the assessment, we practiced day and night, especially focusing on the use of unmanned equipment at night. Now all main battle equipment operators have mastered the company&#39;s proficiency How to operate and use unmanned equipment.&quot; Platoon leader Liu Chu was very proud, &quot;We have broken down this hard nut together.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;(Southern Weekend interns Feng Jiayi, Jiang Lai, Lin Xi, and Zhang Xinyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄防长绍伊古：对话应该以公平对等、互相尊重的原则为基础]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259645]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>