<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[在野党党首绝食抗议，日本核污水排海再引韩国朝野纷争]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257212]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 17:39:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/uMBu5GmaGxoYRYoG1X1WJetEUJcrCreencsaMH7u.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/uMBu5GmaGxoYRYoG1X1WJetEUJcrCreencsaMH7u. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Visual China/Picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Congressman Lee, you are no longer alone.&quot; On the afternoon of September 19, 2023, former South Korean President Moon Jae-in appeared at a hospital in Seoul to visit Lee Jae-myung, leader of the opposition Democratic Party of Korea . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moon Jae-in held Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hands tightly and persuaded him to &quot;stop the hunger strike&quot; and engage in the &quot;long-term battle&quot; (of the Common Democratic Party) with a new attitude. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early the morning before, an ambulance took Li Zaiming to the hospital. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Lee was in extremely poor health tomorrow morning and was in a daze and had to make an emergency call.&quot; Park Sang-joon, spokesman for the Democratic Party of Korea, told South Korea&#39;s YTN radio station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;September 18, 2023 was the 19th day of Li Zaiming&#39;s &quot;hunger strike&quot; to demonstrate against the Yin Xiyue government. On that day, the South Korean court once again filed an application for detention of Li Zaiming on the charge of &quot;dereliction of duty.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lee Jae-myung accused the Yoon Seok-yue regime of undermining order and democracy in South Korea, and went on a hunger strike on August 31. As of now, Li Zaiming is out of danger, but his body is still weak. He stated that he would only maintain infusion treatment and continue his hunger strike. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Lee Jae-myung&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;’s “indefinite hunger strike”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“As one of the citizens, I start today to challenge the incompetent and violent regime. &#39;National&#39; resistance.&quot; On August 31, 2023, Lee Jae-myung announced an &quot;indefinite hunger strike&quot; at the press conference for the first anniversary of the Democratic Party of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Zaiming made three demands to the ruling party: Yin Xiyue apologized to the people for destroying people&#39;s livelihood; the ruling party should oppose Japan&#39;s discharge of nuclear-contaminated water into the sea; and reorganize the cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lee Jae-myung is Moon Jae-in’s “successor” within the party. Before entering politics, Li Zaiming was a human rights lawyer and participated in human rights and citizen movements many times. From 2010 to 2021, Lee Jae-myung served successively as the mayor of Seongnam and the governor of Gyeonggi Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2021, Lee Jae-myung resigned as governor of Gyeonggi Province and participated in the South Korean presidential election. He narrowly lost to South Korean President Yoon Seok-yue and later became the leader of the Democratic Party of Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early days of the hunger strike, Li Zaiming set up a tent in front of the Capitol and conducted a sit-in protest. As Lee Jae-myung&#39;s health declined, he began to move into the party leader&#39;s office. Many senior figures from the Democratic Party of Korea and South Korean politicians came to persuade him to stop his hunger strike. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Korean media reports, the ruling National Power Party &quot;took no measures&quot; in response to Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hunger strike. &lt;p>; /p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Central Daily News&quot; editorial criticized the ruling party&#39;s inappropriate stance on &quot;Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hunger strike.&quot; The National Power Party once ridiculed that &quot;a seafood tasting event will be held near Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hunger strike tent.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sit-ins, marches and hunger strikes are common practice in South Korea’s political arena, and both the ruling and opposition parties will express condolences to hunger strikers. In the 1980s, when former South Korean President Kim Young-sam went on a hunger strike, the secretary of the then ruling party went to express condolences and conveyed then President Chun Doo-hwan’s intention to urge an end to the hunger strike; in 1990, when former South Korean President Kim Dae-jung went on a hunger strike to demand the full implementation of local autonomy , Jin Yongsan also went to express condolences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing pressure from public opinion, Kim Ki-hyun posted on social media on September 16, &quot;solemnly requesting Lee Jae-myung to stop his hunger strike&quot; and proposing to hold a meeting between the leaders of the ruling and opposition parties to discuss people&#39;s livelihood affairs after he &quot;recovers his health.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“To avoid prosecution charges”? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;South Korean prosecutors once believed that Lee Jae-myung&#39;s hunger strike was suspected of avoiding the prosecutor&#39;s investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“This is the first time I have gone on a hunger strike after being notified of being summoned by the prosecutor.” Korean Minister of Justice Han Dong-hoon complained that the continued operation of the judicial system cannot be suspended just because a suspect under investigation went on a hunger strike. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 4, South Korean prosecutors investigated Lee Jae-ming in connection with the &quot;Sangling Group Bribery Case.&quot; It is believed that when he was the governor of Gyeonggi Province from 2019 to 2020, he was suspected of soliciting a bribe of approximately 10.6 billion won from Kim Sung-tae, chairman of Sangryong Group, on the pretext of paying for a visit to North Korea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Li Zaiming is related to two cases. From 2014 to 2015, while serving as the mayor of Seongnam City, Lee Jae-myung was suspected of taking care of real estate developers based on his position, causing the Seongnam Urban Development Corporation to lose 20 billion won. In February 2019, Lee Jae-myung was suspected of violating the Public Office Election Act and instigating others to provide false testimony that was favorable to him during his trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of September 18, when Li Zaiming was seeking medical treatment, South Korean prosecutors merged the two suspicions of the &quot;Sangling Group Bribery Case&quot; and the &quot;Real Estate Case&quot; and applied for an arrest warrant against Li Zaiming. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, Yin Xiyue, who was attending the United Nations General Assembly in New York, approved the arrest consent request sent by the prosecutor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a current member of Congress, Lee Jae-myung enjoys the privilege of not being arrested without the consent of Congress. To arrest a member of Congress, more than half of the members must be present and more than half of the members must agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to South Korea&#39;s &quot;Parliament Law&quot;, after receiving the consent for arrest, the Speaker of the National Assembly needs to convene a plenary meeting report on the matter and vote &quot;within 24 hours and 72 hours&quot; after the report. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;South Korean prosecutors are using clues to bite Li Zaiming, but the possibility of him being arrested this time is not high.&quot; Li Jiacheng, associate professor at the School of International Economics and Politics at Liaoning University, analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters, South Korea in February 2023 The prosecutor&#39;s request to arrest Lee Jae-myung for the real estate case was rejected by Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, South Korea has 297 current members of Congress, including 167 members from the Common Democratic Party, accounting for more than half of the opposition parties. This time, Li Zaiming&#39;s hunger strike received concern and condolences from important people within the party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Central Daily News&quot; report, on September 20, the South Korean Congress will hold a plenary meeting to discuss the &quot;Lee Jae-myung Arrest Consent Case&quot; and vote on September 21. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 21, the South Korean Congress will also vote on the &quot;Recommendation for the Removal of Prime Minister Han Deok-soo.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to Lee Jae-myung’s hunger strike, the Democratic Party of Korea submitted a proposal to dismiss Prime Minister Han Deok-soo on September 16, demanding the collective resignation of the ruling party’s cabinet. The move was seen as an attempt by the opposition parties to put pressure on the Yoon Seok-yue government. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The controversy behind the discharge of nuclear-contaminated water into the sea&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On the recent &quot;issue of Japan&#39;s discharge of nuclear-contaminated water into the sea&quot;, the Korean government and the opposition are quite divided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of August 23, before the hunger strike, Lee Jae-myung led more than a thousand people related to the Democratic Party of Korea to hold a candlelight rally. He accused &quot;the East China Sea is turning into the Sea of ​​Japan&quot; and urged the Yoon Seok-yue government to oppose the discharge of Japan&#39;s nuclear-contaminated water into the sea. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The National Power Party represented by Yin Xiyue supports &quot;discharging nuclear contaminated water into the sea&quot; and sends a signal to the international community that &quot;you will not die if you eat aquatic products.&quot; On August 29, the ruling party held a two-day and one-night &quot;eating broadcast&quot; to promote aquatic products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Representative Lee (Jae-myeong) comes to a place like this and eats some (aquatic products)!&quot; Park Dae-chu, chairman of the policy committee of the National Power Party, joked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ordinary people in South Korea strongly oppose Japan&#39;s discharge of nuclear-contaminated water into the sea, and the progressive Democratic Party supports the ordinary people. The National Power Party, which is dominated by conservative forces, is pro-American and pro-Japanese in foreign policy. Yoon Seok-yue The government strongly supports Japan&#39;s discharge of nuclear-contaminated water. The opposition between South Korea&#39;s ruling party and public opinion has become a political opportunity for Lee Jae-myung,&quot; Li Jiacheng told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Jiacheng believes that Li Zaiming’s hunger strike is more like preparation for canvassing votes for the 2024 South Korean parliamentary election. On the one hand, he united the &quot;unknown&quot; forces within the Democratic Party of Korea, and on the other hand, he fought for the &quot;people&quot; and won the sympathy votes of voters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 10, 2024, the South Korean Congress will hold an election. Since Lee Jae-myung&#39;s Democratic Party holds a majority of seats in the National Assembly, the ruling National Power Party hopes to regain control of the National Assembly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Yin Xiyue narrowly defeated Democratic candidate Li Zaiming by a narrow margin of 0.73% in 2022, he has never admitted that Li Zaiming is his &quot;dialogue partner.&quot; The two have not held formal talks since the election. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yin Xiyue disdains talks with the suspect (Lee Jae-myung).&quot; &quot;The Hankyoreh&quot; quoted a core figure of the ruling party as saying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 19, after Lee Jae-myung received medical treatment, according to a South Korean Media Tomato poll, less than 30% of the people gave a positive evaluation of &lt;span>;Yin Xiyue&#39;s administration&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearly half of the people believe that Li Zaiming&#39;s hunger strike is a protest against &quot;Yin Xiyue&#39;s mismanagement&quot;, and nearly 42% of people oppose &quot;the arrest of Li Zaiming&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend intern Lin Xi also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>; &lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a >; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[最高法发布危害药品安全犯罪典型案例]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257158]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The Supreme People&#39;s Court released 5 typical cases of crimes endangering drug safety on the 18th, involving imported drugs, vaccines, and medical beauty. Different drug types such as drugs, special disease drugs, and dental over-the-counter drugs, including typical criminal methods such as cybercrimes, disinfectant products counterfeiting drugs, and medical insurance fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These five typical cases are: the case of Huang Moulin and others producing and selling counterfeit drugs; the case of Yan Mou selling fake and inferior products; the case of Zhang Mousong and others producing and selling counterfeit drugs; the case of Yang Mouyu and Cai covering up , a case of concealing criminal proceeds; a case of producing and selling counterfeit drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Drug safety is related to the health and life safety of the people, the national economy and people&#39;s livelihood, and the overall stability of society. The cases announced this time are closely related to the daily medication safety of the people and are representative to a certain extent. Many of the defendants were sentenced to fixed-term imprisonment of more than ten years and imposed heavy fines, which reflects the people&#39;s court&#39;s clear attitude and firm determination to adhere to the people&#39;s supremacy and severely punish crimes that endanger drug safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, people&#39;s courts at all levels strictly implement the &quot;four most stringent&quot; requirements, give full play to their judicial functions, severely punish crimes that endanger drug safety in accordance with the law, and effectively ensure the drug safety of the people. From 2013 to 2022, courts across the country concluded more than 28,000 first-instance criminal cases involving the crimes of producing, selling, and providing counterfeit drugs, producing, selling, and providing inferior drugs, and obstructing drug management, and sentenced more than 38,000 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next step, the Supreme People&#39;s Court will supervise and guide local people&#39;s courts at all levels to further improve their ideological understanding, consolidate the main responsibilities, conduct trials in accordance with the law, activate justice, and implement the implementation of safeguarding drug safety and protecting people&#39;s health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人文主义地理学之父段义孚终其一生都在思考啥问题？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257005]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/8Gdihs9dKjOZzzDXXM4o2BOpZHSMlsdy5BXwBaHW.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;846&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/8Gdihs9dKjOZzzDXXM4o2BOpZHSMlsdy5B XwBaHW. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251242&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tuan Yifu and his autobiography &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;(Shanghai Bookstore Publishing House, 2023). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing on the pedestrian bridge, looking at the brightly lit city under the night sky, I can&#39;t help but think of Mondrian&#39;s paintings. It is an art composed of colorful grids and lines, and is a visual presentation of the balanced beauty of the universe. I have to think about: What is the connection between cities, landscapes, architecture, art, etc., and people? This is also a question that Yifu Tuan, the father of humanistic geography, has been thinking about throughout his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When talking about Duan Yifu, people may mention his birthplace of Tianjin, his childhood place of residence in Chongqing, his relationship with Duan Qirui, talk about the countries and countless cities he has traveled to, and admire his work in Despite his brilliant academic achievements, he may still lament his long and lonely life. Such a life is complicated - both brilliant and dull, surrounded by others and often alone. He settled in an apartment in a metropolis, but rooted his soul in the desert and the universe...&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;Because of his rich, wise and simple inner world, Yifu Tuan is often called the &quot;little prince&quot; in the field of geography. His most well-known achievement is that in the 1960s and 1970s, when the positivism advocating instrumental rationality swept Western geography, he restored the humanistic spirit of geography in a simple, determined and wise way, and pioneered the study of geography. Humanistic geography, which had a far-reaching influence on later generations, became famous in the world academic circles. Although there have been many differences and tensions between the development of geography and Tuan Yifu&#39;s thoughts since the 1980s, and his own research and writing style is difficult to be inherited by later generations, his knowledge creation and wisdom enlightenment have always been beyond the reach of geography. An overlooked bright color. In other words, if Yifu Tuan had not been born in this world, the light of geography’s wisdom would be much dimmer than it is now. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many scholars have written articles about Yifu Tuan’s life and contribution to geography. In my eyes, one of Yifu Tuan&#39;s most outstanding contributions to geography is that he restored the aesthetics and emotion of geography, thus greatly expanding the scope of geography research and writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before Yifu Tuan, many geographers had emphasized that the expression of aesthetics and emotion is an important channel for understanding the natural environment. This actually goes back to a common question asked by scientists during the Enlightenment: How do people understand nature? Alexander von Humboldt, who had a profound influence on Yifu Tuan, was one of the important figures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/OFo8OX1dEBnqWuulC3E4n7CNjYjYnvhPftAYk0IV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;928&quot; height= &quot;580&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/OFo8OX1dEBnqWuulC3E4n7CNjYjYnvhPftAYk0IV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251241&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Alexander von Humboldt. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humboldt devoted his life to inspiring &quot;love of nature&quot; and advocated that &quot;nature must also be experienced through human feelings&quot;, Because Humboldt himself was greatly influenced by Kant&#39;s transcendental rationalism. Kant emphasized that human reason legislates nature, which naturally shifts the relationship between human beings and the environment to the human side. As a result, Humboldt&#39;s thought first brewed the &quot;people-centered&quot; humanistic geography perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, while Humboldt was in Jena, he lived with the poet Goethe day and night, and influenced each other, which made his study of nature constantly highlight human subjectivity. He shifted from his initial obsession with pure empirical analysis to Develop an understanding of nature, linking precise scientific evidence with emotional responses to landscapes. Furthermore, he also re-examined people&#39;s &quot;imagination&quot; and believed that imagination is as important as rational thinking and is also a necessary tool for understanding nature. These seeds of Humboldt&#39;s thoughts were sown in Tuan Yifu&#39;s thoughts. In many of Yifu Tuan&#39;s works, we can clearly feel the intertwining of reason and imagination, which constitutes an important channel for interpreting the meaning of the environment. For example, Yifu Tuan&#39;s work &quot;Place, Art and Self&quot; explores the bridge of meaning between environment, emotion and self. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If Humboldt inspired Yifu Tuan’s human-centered perspective, then the “semiotics” that attempts to connect people and things helped Yifu Tuan open up the emotional relationship between people and the environment. American philosopher Susan Lange is an important figure in semiotic aesthetics. Her &quot;Emotion and Form&quot; is a book often cited by Yi-fu Tuan. Her influence on Yifu Tuan is reflected in exploring the &quot;form&quot; relationship between human feelings and the environment. This relationship is known in geography as &quot;sense of place.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Susan Lange insists that the human senses are also capable of abstraction. As she puts it: &quot;Eye and ear must have their logic.&quot; Such logic is not a positivist inference of factual evidence. Logic, but the &quot;logic of representation&quot; when people experience environmental materials. For example, although waves have no direct relationship with life on the physical level, the image of never-ending waves is as continuous as life. This is what Susan Lange calls the similarity of representational logic, which is also the form of emotion, a symbol that connects people&#39;s feelings with the environment. Yifu Tuan uses metaphors in many works to describe such connections. For example, Yifu Tuan talked about how people would associate their bodies with the landscape, producing words like &quot;ridge&quot; and &quot;estuary&quot;. Although at the physical level, mountains have no backs and rivers have no mouths, there are similarities in apparent logic between them. Then, artificially creating these words expresses the formal isomorphic relationship between human feelings and natural objects. This kind of &quot;sense of place&quot; is exactly what Yifu Tuan is exploring. For example, the relationship between vision and color, body and architecture, imagination and mountains, etc. Furthermore, at the deepest level, the isomorphic relationship between &quot;identity&quot; and &quot;place&quot; can also be explored. Yifu Tuan summarizes all these relationships into one term - &quot;experience&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YEJQETUdhzENESNAVxpx6BdxfD754p2EkWQeWzaZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height= &quot;848&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/YEJQETUdhzENESNAVxpx6BdxfD754p2EkWQeWzaZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251243&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Susan Lange&#39;s &quot;Emotion and Form&quot; is a book that Yifu Tuan often quotes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What are the attributes of &quot;experience&quot;? In the book &quot;Space and Place&quot;, he pointed out: Experience is like a spectrum, with one end leaning toward emotion and the other end toward thought, but the two blend with each other from beginning to end. Therefore, Yifu Tuan&#39;s definition of the connotation of experience has greatly expanded the scope of geographical epistemology: while recognizing the value of rational analysis (scientific), it also gives equal status to emotional description. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Yifu Tuan’s geographical emotion is an emotion that can communicate with others, can form intersubjectivity, and has an objective logical form. In other words, this emotion starts from the individual and transcends the individual. It is a kind of intentionality with universal significance. It is precisely because of this that Yifu Tuan&#39;s geography can enter the public domain and generate extremely high academic value. Therefore, it is not as criticized by positivists that Tuan Yifu&#39;s geography is only individual and subjective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his academic career of more than sixty years, Yi-fu Tuan created a large number of geographical works rich in emotion and aesthetic form. For example, he successively explored the relationship between alienation and fragmentation between people and the environment (&quot;The Broken World and the Self&quot; in 1982), the coexistence of pampering and manipulation (&quot;Making Pets&quot; in 1984), and the relationship between localism and cosmopolitanism (1996 &quot;The Universe and the Hearth&quot; (1998)), and the relationship of escape (&quot;Escapism&quot; (1998)), etc. These works have greatly enriched the research content of geography. According to Tim Criswell, a former protégé of Yi-Fu Tuan and now a professor of geography at the University of Edinburgh, “When Yi-Fu Tuan was studying the desert landscapes of the American Southwest, few geographers cared about how the landscape reflected human life. Values, and no one will pay attention to people&#39;s emotions of pampering and controlling the environment, and no one will think that the most ordinary things in life, such as houses, gutters and scissors, have beauty.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time , in order to explore these relationships, Duan Yifu not only wandered through various fragments of literature, ethnography, psychology, and ancient urban history, but also used poetic language to skillfully weave the themes he wanted to express. , the scope of geography writing has been greatly expanded, providing rich nutrients for the development of humanistic geography in later generations. Therefore, Tim Criswell said: Yifu Tuan’s influence has transcended the glorious 1970s of humanistic geography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Yifu Tuan’s geographical aesthetic appreciation is not entirely an objectified aesthetic appreciation. He even incorporated his own life experience into it. As Duan Yifu wrote in his autobiography &quot;Who Am I?&quot; &quot;&quot; said that geography helped him overcome the loss of life and find the meaning of life. It was geography that saved him. Therefore, Tuan Yifu&#39;s geography is often a kind of writing that &quot;uses itself as a method&quot;. In other words, he analyzed his life as a practical sample for the world to observe, allowing others to see his own joys, anger, sorrows, life and death, and then formed a kind of environmental aesthetics and emotional expression in which the author&#39;s &quot;subject appears&quot;, which is profound. The intensity and appeal far exceed the object-oriented aesthetic method of simply standing opposite the scenery and maintaining a certain distance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, 92-year-old Yifu Tuan published a booklet titled &quot;Geography from 1947 to 2022: A Travel Record&quot;. He said:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly is my contribution to human geography? That is, I enriched the meaning of the word &quot;person&quot;. In the past, geographers in the field of natural science were people who had the courage to explore inaccessible places. When I was an undergraduate, the geography professors at Oxford and Cambridge were all such explorers. …They have little to no interest in people. When geographers talk about people, they just treat them as another natural force that changes the landscape of the earth. Since the 1930s, talents have been given other attributes. First, under the influence of Karl Saul, people were given cultural attributes; then in the 1960s, under the influence of David Lowenthal and Robert Gates, people were given psychological attributes; and finally in the 1970s, people were given psychological attributes. In the era, people are endowed with aesthetic attributes. But what baffles me is why such an obviously human attribute has been ignored for so long. The fact that it was ignored was due to the prevailing paradigm at the time. Therefore, I urge you once again, young traveler! Be sure to have the courage to steer your ship like a captain, albeit with only life&#39;s confusing clues and stars as your guides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Yifu Tuan’s contribution to geography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 16:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[三年4任董事长，“药中茅台”为何震荡不断？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257180]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/20/rCNgV1xm9msQKl2HYkAS2vgrqM209hWEGqk8Z4kU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/20/rCNgV1xm9msQKl2HYkAS2vgrqM209 hWEGqk8Z4kU. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251259&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Many time-honored traditional Chinese medicine companies face the same anti-corruption problem. (Pien Tze Huang, composed of bezoars, musk, notoginseng, and snake gall, is used to clear away heat. Detoxify, cool blood and remove blood stasis, reduce swelling and relieve pain. This small pill is said to have been introduced from the Ming Dynasty. The company that manufactured it was founded in 1956 and has been on the market for 20 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Pien Tze Huang has reached a turning point again.” Li Bin, a long-term holder of Pien Tze Huang shares, private equity fund manager Li Bin, told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 6, 2023, Lin Zhihui, the new chairman of Pien Tze Huang (600436.SH), with a total market value of more than 164 billion and known as the &quot;Moutai of Medicine&quot; by the market, attended the 6th &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&quot; Traditional Chinese Medicine Development Forum. Investors believe this is his first appearance since becoming the new chairman in early August. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is Pien Tze Huang’s fourth coaching change since 2021. The previous two chairman of the board were investigated by the Discipline Inspection Commission for suspected serious violations of disciplines and laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August, the Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision of Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province released information that Liu Jianshun, who had served as chairman of Pien Tze Huang for seven years, was expelled from the party for violating laws and disciplines. He will retire in 2021. Pan Jie, who succeeded him, was also subject to disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Zhangzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision in May for suspected serious violations of discipline and law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to incomplete statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, five executives of Pien Tze Huang and its subsidiaries have been investigated in 2023. From June 2022 to the present, Pien Tze Huang’s board secretary, chief engineer, chief auditor, etc. Many senior executives have resigned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Lu Dingliang, a lawyer at Jingshi Law Firm, the products of traditional Chinese medicine companies such as Pien Tze Huang leave room for power rent-seeking due to their certain resource nature and scarcity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The number of Pien Tze Huang executives who have been investigated is relatively prominent, which is closely related to the company’s stock price, product selling price and scarcity.” He analyzed to Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Chairman of &quot;Liu Shui&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Zhangzhou Pien Tze Huang Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. was founded in 1999 by the restructuring of Zhangzhou Pharmaceutical Factory, which was established in 1956. , currently has 13 directly held subsidiaries and 9 joint-stock companies. Its controlling shareholder is a state-owned enterprise in Zhangzhou City. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of August, the Zhangzhou Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision released information that former chairman Liu Jianshun was expelled from the party for serious violations of discipline and law. It mentioned that he &quot;received gifts and large amounts of money in violation of regulations; relied on enterprises to support enterprises, and took advantage of his position to provide Others seek benefits and accept huge amounts of property from others.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jianshun is 60 years old and served as chairman of Pien Tze Huang from 2014 to 2021. During this period, Pien Tze Huang’s revenue increased from 1.4 billion yuan to 6.5 billion yuan, and the stock price rose from 21 yuan/share to 4 in 2021. The monthly highest price is around 350 yuan/share. Three months after he left office, Pien Tze Huang experienced a period of intense speculation, with its stock price rising to a new high of 480 yuan per share, and Pien Tze Huang tablets on the market selling for thousands of yuan per pill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2021, Liu Jianshun retired early due to &quot;personal physical reasons&quot; and resigned from relevant positions. Pan Jie, who had served as general manager of Pien Tze Huang and other positions, took over as chairman. But within eight months, Pan Jie resigned from the relevant position on the grounds of &quot;work adjustment.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the &quot;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;http://static.sse.com.cn/disclosure/listedinfo/announcement/c/new/2022-04-16/600436_20220416_6_1FsQWSqY. pdf&quot;>;Zhangzhou Pien Tze Huang Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. 2021 Social Responsibility Report and ESG (Environmental, Social and Corporate Governance) Report&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&quot; mentioned that in 2021, Pien Tze Huang established the &quot;Zhangzhou Municipal Supervisory Committee in Office of the Ombudsman of Zhangzhou Pien Tze Huang Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July of the same year, according to information on Pien Tze Huang’s official website, the Discipline Inspection and Supervision Offices of three Pien Tze Huang-owned enterprises, including Cosmetics Co., Ltd., were established, achieving full coverage of supervision of all public officials exercising public power in the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2021, Lin Weiqi, a member of the Party Committee and Deputy Director of the State-owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission of Zhangzhou City, Fujian Province, became the new chairman of Pien Tze Huang. During his tenure from June to July 2022, the then secretary of the board of directors, deputy general manager, supervisor, chief engineer, and chief auditor resigned one after another. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Less than 17 months after taking office, in July 2023, Lin Weiqi resigned from the company due to &quot;work adjustment&quot;. A month later, Lin Zhihui became Pien Tze Huang&#39;s new chairman. According to the announcement issued by Pien Tze Huang, Lin Zhihui has served as a member of the Standing Committee of the Zhangzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and a member of the Zhangzhou Municipal Supervisory Committee. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking stock of official notifications over the past year: In May, former chairman Pan Jie was subject to disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Zhangzhou Municipal Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision on suspicion of serious violations of discipline and law; in June, the former deputy director of Pien Tze Huang Cosmetics Co., Ltd. Chairman Yang Puquan was put on file for review and investigation for serious violations of disciplines and laws; in August, former chairman Lin Jinsheng of Pien Tze Huang Cosmetics Co., Ltd. was expelled from the party and public office for serious violations of disciplines and laws; at the end of August, former chairman Liu Jianshun was expelled from the party for serious violations of disciplines and laws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In these intensive notifications, words such as &quot;relying on enterprises to eat enterprises&quot; and &quot;seeking personal gain&quot; were mentioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;More corruption problems occur in dealers&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;How much impact does frequent coaching changes have on the company? Pien Tze Huang&#39;s stock price has dropped from the highest of 482.33 yuan per share at the end of 2021 to the current price of 271.98 yuan per share, a drop of 43%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin believes that Pien Tze Huang has a very mature brand, system and customer base, so the role of management is relatively downplayed, and the replacement of senior executives will have little impact on the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the financial report, from 2020 to 2022, Pien Tze Huang’s revenue increased from 6.511 billion yuan to 8.694 billion yuan, and its net profit increased from 1.672 billion yuan to 2.472 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Bin said, &quot;Generally speaking, Pien Tze Huang&#39;s main sales channels are not in hospitals, but in pharmacies and the Internet.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the financial report, in 2021, Pien Tze Huang&#39;s operating income was 8.022 billion yuan, and sales expenses were 650 million yuan. In 2022, operating income was 8.694 billion yuan, and sales expenses were 483 million yuan. Selling expenses account for 8.1%-5.55% of revenue. In comparison, the IPO report of Hanwang Pharmaceutical, a traditional Chinese medicine pharmaceutical company, showed that sales expenses accounted for more than 80% of its main business revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Dingliang believes that traditional Chinese medicine is different from Western medicine and equipment. “The public relations focus of medical equipment and Western medicine is to have a good relationship with doctors and hospitals. But the corruption of traditional Chinese medicine in the C-end market is more about distribution. Corruption issues have arisen in the business chain.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the financial report, Pien Tze Huang’s domestic sales model is mainly OTC, that is, over-the-counter drugs. The main sales channel for prescription drugs is hospitals, and for over-the-counter drugs is pharmacies. Pien Tze Huang&#39;s sales channels include Pien Tze Huang experience centers, retail pharmacies and regional distributors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Pien Tze Huang Experience Center&quot; appeared for the first time in the 2015 financial report. There were more than 20 experience centers that year. By the end of 2020, there were more than 300 “Pien Tze Huang Experience Centers” operating across the country. According to a report by China International Finance Securities in August 2023, there are nearly 400 Pien Tze Huang experience centers across the country, covering more than 100,000 terminal stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Liang became the person in charge of a Pien Tze Huang experience center in 2019. In his view, the changes in Pien Tze Huang’s management will not have a big impact on the experience center he runs. In comparison, the impact of price increases is more direct. &quot;The market is indeed relatively weak now, and the experience center itself does not want to increase prices. After the price increase, sales will decline,&quot; he told a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is still growing, Pien Tze Huang&#39;s revenue growth rate in 2022 is the lowest in five years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2023, Pien Tze Huang stated that due to reasons such as the increase in main raw materials and labor costs, it would increase the domestic market retail price of its main product Pien Tze Huang tablets from 590 yuan/tablet to 760 yuan/tablet, and the supply price would be increased accordingly. About 170 yuan per pill, the largest price increase in history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Pien Tze Huang&#39;s 2003 prospectus, in 2000, the average domestic sales price of Pien Tze Huang was 93.2 yuan per pill. In twenty years, the price increase has been as high as 715%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the ex-factory price is 390 yuan/tablet, the market retail price of Pien Tze Huang tablets is 590 yuan/tablet. How much is the difference between the current ex-factory price and retail price of Pien Tze Huang tablets? Zhang Liang said, &quot;The ex-factory price is confidential, but our price difference is not high and cannot be compared with Moutai.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A long-term investor in Pien Tze Huang told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;This price adjustment (to 760 yuan), as far as I know, the ex-factory price should be 560 yuan.&quot; That is, the difference between the ex-factory price and the retail price is 200 yuan/pill, the same as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of the Pien Tze Huang Experience Center who is familiar with Li Bin also believes that after the price increase, there will be a certain impact on sales within half a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Generally, sales will gradually return to normal after half a year. This year&#39;s price increase directly increases the ex-factory price and retail price by the same amount. In other words, the profit from the price increase belongs to Pien Tze Huang Company, and the profit It will be reflected in the performance, and the dealers will not make more money,&quot; Li Bin said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the 2023 semi-annual report, the gross profit margin of Pien Tze Huang pharmaceutical manufacturing industry was 74.2%. In the 2022 annual report, this figure was 78.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person in charge of a traditional Chinese medicine company told a Southern Weekend reporter, &quot;The high profits of traditional Chinese medicine companies do not mean high profits for dealers. Products that can be sold at the C-end will not have much price difference.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“ &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Depend on the success of the enterprise &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;” &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;A senior person in the pharmaceutical industry told Southern Weekend Reporter, in terms of drug research and development, Pien Tze Huang is a national secret formula with mysterious origin and high price. It seems to be widely used, but the price/performance ratio is unclear, but the sales volume is very impressive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the official website of the State Drug Administration, the protection level of Pien Tze Huang is level 1, which is the highest level. Among the national traditional Chinese medicine varieties, only Pien Tze Huang and Yunnan Baiyao are national top-secret formulas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pien Tze Huang is now known as &quot;Moutai of Medicine&quot;, and the last one to be so called was Dong&#39;e Ejiao. From 2001 to the end of 2018, the price of Dong&#39;e Ejiao has been raised 18 times, an increase of 37 times. The reason for the price increase is &quot;the shortage of donkey skin resources.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of the above-mentioned traditional Chinese medicine company also used Dong&#39;e E-jiao as an example. The profits of Dong&#39;e E-jiao dealers are also very thin. If the dealers stock up, the company will give a slight discount. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The gameplay is to stock up downstream + increase prices. Frequent price increases are also because listed companies want to increase profits. I find Pien Tze Huang (price increases) a bit confusing, but only this type of company can have excess profits &quot;, he told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2018, Dong&#39;e Ejiao&#39;s growth has stagnated, and in 2019 it suffered its first loss in 23 years since its listing. From 2017 to 2019, the company&#39;s book inventory exceeded 3 billion yuan. It began cutting prices and selling stakes in its subsidiaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2023, Dong&#39;e Ejiao (000423.SZ) issued continuous personnel change announcements. The then chairman and vice president both resigned due to &quot;job changes.&quot; This is the third chairman the company has replaced since November 2019. Similar to Pien Tze Huang, three chairmen resigned in three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2020, nine senior executives including Qin Yufeng, the president of Dong&#39;e Ejiao, the assistant president, and the vice president resigned one after another.两年后，秦玉峰涉嫌严重违纪违法，目前正接受华润医药控股有限公司纪委和山东省聊城市监察委员会的纪律审查和监察调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与它们类似的，还有同仁堂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在片仔癀被爆炒的2021年年底，同仁堂（600085.SH）将安宫牛黄丸的终端零售价从780元提至860元，称为中药原材料上涨所致，此后多个品种相继提价。安宫牛黄丸是同仁堂的核心单品，2022年，同仁堂营收154亿元，包括安宫牛黄丸在内的前五大产品实现收入45亿元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年10月，中纪委国家监委网站发布的相关报道中提及，北京同仁堂原总经理高振坤借安宫牛黄丸原料采购牟利1500万余元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;文中提及，在制作安宫牛黄丸、大活络丸、牛黄清心丸等同仁堂招牌成药时，豹骨、麝香、羚羊角、牛黄等成分不可或缺，这些需求量大、利润高的濒危细料，让高振坤看到了巨大的权力寻租空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在同仁堂集团二级企业股份有限公司任职期间，高振坤牢牢把住细料采购权，利用供给优势和信息优势牟取私利达1500万余元。为了维系与高振坤间的关系，多名供应商竞相为其打点吃穿用度，高振坤随口一句“孩子上学远”，就能换来一套两居室出租屋的钥匙。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;裁判文书网发布的同仁堂副总经理、经营分公司经理王清泉受贿的相关信息中提及，其利用职务便利，多次以明显低于集团规定的内部价格向相关方购买安宫牛黄丸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前公布的片仔癀相关高管被查的信息中，也多次提及“靠企吃企”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在卢鼎亮看来，中药产品属于中间环节较多、利润空间较大、专业和技术壁垒较高、采购透明度不足的领域，这些特点给腐败提供了空间。同时，该领域的利益输送方式较为隐蔽，腐败行为发现难度大、线索获取难、证据链形成难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“直面C端市场的中药，产品具有一定的稀缺性和不可替代性，经销商如果拿到了销售权，获利空间就比较大，就给&#39;靠企吃企&#39;提供了可能”，他对南方周末记者表示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，片仔癀股价一度上涨至483.69元/股，截至发稿，报269.81元/股，跌幅已超40%。但对于长期持有片仔癀的李斌来说，他更看好自5月提价起，片仔癀在半年以后的业绩表现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中张亮为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[澳研究发现可致儿童痴呆症的145种遗传病]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257000]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚研究人员近期确定了145种可导致儿童痴呆症的遗传性疾病，旨在提高社会各界对这些疾病严重程度的认识。相关研究结果已发表在《脑》季刊上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿童痴呆症是由一系列遗传性疾病引起的进行性脑损伤造成的。就像成年痴呆症患者一样，儿童痴呆症患者也会出现记忆丧失、精神错乱、性格改变、睡眠严重紊乱，以及在集中注意力、理解能力、学习和沟通等方面的障碍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个由澳大利亚阿德莱德大学领衔的研究团队对该国及海外已发表的数据展开建模和分析，结果显示儿童痴呆症症状通常在患者两岁半时开始出现，平均诊断年龄约为四岁。患者的平均预期寿命仅为9年，70%的患者在18岁之前死亡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员表示，导致儿童痴呆症的这145种遗传性疾病非常复杂且多样，比如克拉伯病、桑德霍夫病、亨廷顿舞蹈病等，但共同点是都会造成进行性神经认知能力下降和预期寿命严重缩短。研究结果更清晰地揭示了哪些人易受到这些极具破坏性且未被充分认识的疾病带来的影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;研究人员呼吁加大资金投入来研究针对儿童痴呆症的有效治疗方法，同时迫切需要改善对受影响家庭的护理和支持。这项新研究将提高研究人员、临床医生、政府和政策制定者对这些疾病严重程度的认识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江苏宿迁遭遇强龙卷风，灾情造成5人死亡4人重伤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257182]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 13:32:55&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;9月19日17时20分许，江苏省宿迁市宿豫区大兴镇、市经开区南蔡乡局地陆续发生强龙卷风，等级判定为EF2级，造成部分地区人员伤亡和财产损失。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次龙卷风灾情主要发生在乡镇镇区，人员稠密、建筑结构复杂，发生时段恰逢下班时间，由于此次龙卷风的侵袭来得突然，灾情共造成5人死亡，4人重伤。经初步统计，此次强龙卷风受灾人口5512人，1646户房屋一般受损，倒塌房屋137户，农作物受损41.8公顷，临时转移安置405人，2000余平方米猪舍部分墙体倒塌、顶部塌陷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;灾情发生后，当地立即统筹指挥相关力量开展现场搜救、伤员转运救治、群众安置、核灾救灾等工作。应急、公安、消防、卫健、住建、供电等部门立即赶赴现场，开展应急救援和善后处置；受灾乡镇迅速组织当地群众开展自救互救。经连夜抢救，伤员已送至医院救治，受灾群众得到妥善安置，受灾地区供电全部恢复、道路交通恢复畅通。宿迁市应急管理局表示，目前灾区社会秩序恢复正常，相关保险公司已赶赴现场开展查勘理赔，其他善后处置工作全面展开。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 13:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电影的滋味丨凝视]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256928]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Iaqqvp92icGKhBxUblF02BEvKPBVKr5dZZKv9GGN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1266&quot; height=&quot;833&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Iaqqvp92icGKhBxUblF02BEvKPBVKr5dZZKv9GGN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251101&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《月光武士》改编自虹影同名长篇小说，讲述了一个始于1970年代重庆、绵延三十几年的故事。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;晚上的时间一般用来读书或看电影，昨天看阿加莎小说改编的电影《尼罗河上的惨案》，发现导演肯尼思·布拉纳即主演侦探波洛，也是诺兰最新电影《奥本海默》中尼尔斯·玻尔教授的饰演者。奥本海默认为自己的导师过分，不让他去听一场期待已久的讲座，在苹果里注入氰化钾，第二天他想起，狂奔而去，发现苹果在教授玻尔手里，玻尔正要吃时，被奥本海默阻止。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人的绝望，怎么理得清？奥本海默那一刻是绝望的。好电影的滋味会让人浮想联翩。家人说遇到我之前，他在南法度假，想人生无常，心里空荡，毫无牵挂，朝河水走去，被好友发现，抓上河岸。没多久，他在英国一个生日宴上认识我，他说你当时头发一半长一半短，很前卫。我说人就是这样，如果你内心极苦，过得不像样，就会借助外在形式稀释这痛苦，比如有意无意偏向非正常，甚至衣服鞋子，好家伙，我有多少年是穿着高跟鞋，留着这样不规则的头发。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;还好，你没有文身。他说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果我有文身，你还会爱上我？我问他。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他说，即便你有，当时我也绝不可能对你反感，人在对的时候遇见，一切都会原谅并包容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这话让我深思。这三年发生太多的事，每个人的命运都发生了变化。之前我是个恋物癖，每到一个地方，会收集纪念物，小到一个瓷器，大到一尊雕塑，喜欢在古董旧货市场淘老明信片老邮票。有一年参加法兰克福书展，和好友欢天喜地在当地最大的露天市场逛，见到老地毯银勺，不还价就收了。现在我不会收，身外之物，何其多，何其累。除了书，我不扔，从去年到今年，一直在清理可要可不要的物品，多余的锅碗筷子，多余的衣服鞋子家具，家渐渐有些留白，我心里一阵轻松。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;活着，比什么都好。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《月光武士》这部电影、这个故事，我五岁第一次听见家人邻居说，中学街宽阔绵长的一坡石阶走着一家人，上方的母亲身着和服，得返回日本，下方是父亲带着三个女儿在后面赶。石阶两侧是观望的人。时光流逝几十年，那情景一直在我心中闪现。我由此写了三千字不到的短篇，之后将它改写为五万字剧本，又由剧本改为二十多万字的长篇小说，每个人物在我心里活灵活现。小说出版后，我打破之前的剧本，重新写，每个场景，根据实地来，按照剧本里人物的形象找演员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影的前期是剧本、筹备资金和班子，然后拍摄，后期是剪辑、声音音乐、调色特效，前期难，后期更难。好多人在这个过程中会失去耐心，我努力吸取新鲜的专业知识，研究思索，让自己的听觉、嗅觉、直觉始终处于敏锐的状态。仿佛从一个遥远的国度走向另一个国度，先确定地点，规划路线，准备一路上所需装备，再抛开一切顾虑，什么人也劝阻不了，都说前面是陷阱、是坑、是万劫不复之路，我却不信。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刮大风下暴雨？这个太经常了，不必害怕。路上出现强盗，路上出现乞丐，路上出现笑面虎。唐僧呀，你去西天取经遇见的是妖怪们，想吃你的肉，为的是长生不老。我呢，遇上的一切事和物，是上天来考验我对电影的一片赤诚。电影是这么苦涩，这么坚硬，完全不可食之，只可统统吞入肚里。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/jMsUG4dRkoKT9WR4Q0OnBQP75lqpYKXZLydTKIQG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;949&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/jMsUG4dRkoKT9WR4Q0OnBQP75lqpYKXZLydTKIQG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251099&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《月光武士》的女主人公秦佳惠是一名护士，在工作中初识12岁少年窦小明。电影《月光武士》（2023）剧照。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初剪定时，给人看，有朋友、有专业人士。定剪后，便有电影宣发公司看，有人喜欢，说它带着1970年代重庆的迷人雾幔，中心街老妈小面馆，那是真正的山城烟火气，滋味麻辣酸甜，值得细细品尝；有人不喜欢，说它不像中国惯常的电影，你胆子太大，居然跨界从作家到电影圈，做这么一部怀旧不讨好的电影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;偶尔我会说说自己的看法，偶尔我会保持沉默。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《月光武士》男主角少年窦小明的扮演者是左航，他的好多粉丝在微博上催促《月光武士》赶快公映，甚至难听的话都说出来。我在微博上发表了看法，谈到做电影的周期不是他们想象的，拍这部电影是2021年底，后期做了一年，因为在疫情中，后期公司包括好多主创都在隔离中。我们的电影从拿到龙标到现在，才不到三个月，一直在做后续工作、找最适合的宣发公司，不是不想上院线、尽早与观众见面。这条微博引来两极分化的评论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苦闷中，我回忆自己喜爱的中外电影，想到《地道战》里日本鬼子进村被打得落荒而逃的情景；想到《简爱》里那在荒原奔走的身影；想到《卡萨布兰卡》里那钢琴弹奏的乐曲；想到《阿拉伯的劳伦斯》里迷人的沙漠；想到《四百击》里少年最后走到海边的长镜头，一望无际的大海，万里无云的天空；想到《甜蜜的生活》中女主走下楼梯时一道又一道阳光。我试着平静，去接受无法改变的事情，试着去改变我能够改变的事情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我沉浸在自己的工作，没来得及关注你们，而你们立刻将我踢出你们的世界，与我背道而驰，本来我们是多么好的朋友和亲人，因为做这电影，我失去了你们，也失去了同一个母亲生的大姐。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是的，我遇到了好多这样让我莫名悲哀的事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不时会遇到人教育我，为什么做电影没有事先找他/她？声称如果找他/她，我的电影会有明星，会有资金，会更有商业价值。我说，如果那时我找你，你不会理我，如果你理我，这时来向我伸出一只手也不迟。这种人说，世上第一流电影，是（造价）五亿以上的电影；第二流电影是五亿以下的，大制作、大演员；而第三流电影，小制作、没明星。虹影，你正是在做这第三流电影，你是作家，做作家就本分了，你要宣发你的电影，是痴人说梦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我打断对方的话：我做什么，是我的事，而你是在讲电影吗？你是在讲钱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱可以生出电影，钱没有一流二流三流之分，钱就是钱，但钱永远不等于电影。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影是艺术，第七艺术，乔托．卡努杜说电影是把静的艺术和动的艺术、时间艺术和空间艺术、造型艺术和节奏艺术全都包括在内的一种综合艺术。电影用镜头讲故事，讲一段渐渐淡忘的人的故事，讲那流转已久的传说，讲历史真相，用视觉音效讲述久远年代存在的正义和理想精神，电影就是实现不可能实现的梦，电影就是造梦，没有梦，我们如何做电影？如何看电影？英格玛·伯格曼说，我的电影不是让你的灵魂感到安逸，而是要让你和你的灵魂战斗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/LgiNtAf5ifho26TMjyirAnkSd4ZK9MOOo7aqn095.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1265&quot; height=&quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/LgiNtAf5ifho26TMjyirAnkSd4ZK9MOOo7aqn095.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251100&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;虹影在电影《月光武士》拍摄现场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电影对我来说，意味着什么？我经常自问，也被人追问。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好多时候感觉电影进入我的身体，在吸用我的血和灵气，我是否怀揣石头，走入河中？可是电影对我不放手，我只能折回头。我看见儿时，自己和父亲坐在长江边，注视江上行驶的船，全是定焦的，一帧帧，向我涌来，它们就是世界，这个世界不像我在江之南岸那么灰暗、无望，那么贫困，这个世界在江之彼岸有鲜亮的色彩和希望、无尽的激情和爱。这是电影，它永远属于那些不屈不挠的人，相信这个世界美好的一面，永远不失爱人爱世界的能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当天夜里做梦，我又站在重庆江边，与执行导演一起，在等船运来拍摄机器。雾气涌来。我朝前走，河水小心流淌着，我听得见自己的脚步，我看见一个废弃的缆车在前面，跟小时我在江边走过千万遍一模一样，甚至有一个桥洞，我走过去，立即从洞里走回来，我看见雾气在散开，对岸的山峦、房子及一些厂棚若隐若现，江水碧绿，荡漾着波浪，往左望去，就是重庆城中心朝天门左侧嘉陵江的景致。我激动万分，而右边是宽阔的沙滩，我手指那里，对身边的人说，为什么我们要去对面拍那场打斗戏，不，就是这儿，这是小时候我最熟悉的场景。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冥冥之中，我觉得这是生我养我的重庆，给我坚定的心的一份礼物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我醒来，清晰地记着那是2021年冬天的一个早上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两年了，好像很久，好像是一瞬。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;写下这篇文章时，读到微博《小凤直播室》主持人小凤的微博：“《月光武士》真是这一年度最神秘的电影，由蜚声国际的罗马文学奖得主虹影根据自己的小说改编，并首次拿起导筒执导，她是有多么爱这个故事。帕慕克喜欢《纯真博物馆》，也不过就建造了一座时空有限的博物馆，无法想象他自己挑选一个芙颂和凯末尔，让他们摇晃在伊斯坦布尔的老街上，但虹影做到了。她不仅在纸上将我们催眠，跟随着窦小明、秦佳惠一脚踏进山城弯曲的斜街，还将他们的故事搬上银幕，让山城的氤氲气息，江河的浩荡之美都流经我们的眼底。祝贺《月光武士》获得美国好莱坞下一代独立电影奖最佳剧本创作奖提名，这是于万千期盼中的又一个好消息。&#39;这个电影奖的最高荣誉授予了来自世界各地的杰出故事讲述者和富有远见的电影制作人。&#39;杰出的故事讲述者，是的，那个五岁时在长江边的细雨里奔跑与呼喊的女孩，那个十八岁才知道自己身世从此定格了一生的河流的女儿，她一直是那个山鲁佐德一般靠讲故事活着的女子啊！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她的话触及我心最柔软处，哪怕有一个人看到我的行走轨迹，有一个人注意到我的电影，我也应该感恩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我像窦小明和秦佳惠一样摇晃在山城最陡峭的石梯上，看到城市的灯光一点点倾洒在江水上，那艘拖轮从暗下来的两江汇合处开过来，拉响气笛，还有人手持喇叭在喊，“停二号码头”，接着用重庆当地的脏话说起来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好熟悉的情景，那不是别人的拖轮，那是父亲的，从他给我看的老照片上，我知道它的模样和形状，当然它早就成了一堆废铁，可我不止一百次想象它出现在江上，我把它复活在电影里，让它永久地存在下来。我的父亲，我相信，你在天之灵会看到这部电影，这部电影是向重庆和重庆人致敬的，又何尝不是向你一样的异乡人、异乡致敬，父亲，我相信，你看到电影最后，你会向我点头，会向我露出少见的笑容。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[汽车4S店被要求“限时搬迁”：优化民营经济发展环境应落到实处丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257007]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, a large number of automobile 4S stores in Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province were &quot;required to relocate within a limited time&quot;, which attracted industry attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The China Automobile Dealers Association recently posted on its official social media that a large number of automobile 4S stores in Shijiazhuang City have received notices from government departments requiring them to relocate to designated automobile parks within a time limit. The article said that according to incomplete statistics, almost all car 4S stores within the Third Ring Road of Shijiazhuang City are involved, and there are more than 100 dealers of various brands. The large-scale relocation and reconstruction are expected to cause direct economic losses of more than 1 billion to the dealers. Yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 15, &quot;Automotive Business Review&quot; magazine reported that according to statistics from the Shijiazhuang Commerce Bureau, the relocation involved 177 sizable 4S stores, affecting almost all 4S stores in Shijiazhuang. The notice, stamped with the bright red seals of the local Natural Resources and Planning Bureau, the Public Security Bureau, the Urban Management Bureau, the Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, the Fire Rescue and the Subdistrict Office, requires that all 4S stores be relocated and vacated before September 30, and the stores must be closed. , those who do not move into the automobile industrial park must close their stores before September 10th; temporary and illegal 4S stores must be demolished by themselves before September 10th, otherwise they will be demolished by force; &quot;Refuse to cooperate, maliciously obstruct and hinder the execution of official duties&quot; &quot; will be &quot;seriously dealt with in accordance with the law, and those suspected of committing crimes will be held criminally responsible in accordance with the law.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, demolition work has begun, and many car brand showrooms have been razed to the ground in the Hebei International Automobile Trade Park, the largest local automobile park. According to reports, the relocation of automobile 4S stores was carried out in the name of &quot;comprehensive improvement of temporary (illegal construction) low-end market&quot;: the government requires existing 4S stores to be closed and demolished, and relocated to four new parks planned by the government. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon in various places to require companies to relocate to new parks planned by the government under various pretexts. A few years ago, a county in eastern Shandong Province required all stone companies in a town famous for stone production to relocate to a newly built &quot;stone industrial park&quot; in the name of &quot;industrial agglomeration.&quot; A few years later, on the grounds of &quot;air pollution control&quot;, all barbecue restaurants in the county were required to move to the newly built &quot;BBQ Street&quot;. If you don&#39;t want to relocate, then close without negotiation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same is true for the car 4S store in Shijiazhuang that &quot;requires time-limited relocation&quot;. Once a document is issued by the city government, the district and sub-district offices will enforce it. If they are unwilling to relocate, they will close the store and demolish it. However, the expenses and costs associated with relocation, as well as the possible impact on industrial development, need to be calculated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What impact may relocation have on companies and industries? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, of course, the renovated business premises must be abandoned and moved to a new location. Not to mention the rent, renovating is a huge expense. According to an estimate from an article by the China Automobile Dealers Association, each new store after the centralized relocation is expected to require an additional construction investment of 10 million to 20 million yuan. In recent years, car sales have dropped from their peak, especially due to the impact of the epidemic. Many dealers were already struggling to survive until the epidemic was relaxed, and they are planning to take advantage of the opportunity to develop their business. Some stores even just opened a few months ago, and were required to dismantle and relocate the store before selling a few cars. The tens of millions of yuan invested just now were in vain. It was difficult for the store owners to invest more funds in the construction of new stores, so they had to Forced into bankruptcy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some shop owners questioned the procedural issues. According to a report by Shijiazhuang Daily in June, the policy formulated at the special meeting of the Municipal Party Committee at that time was to &quot;build first and then destroy&quot;. First, ensure that the new automobile industrial park is completed and put into use by the end of September, and then complete &quot;overdue temporary construction and illegal construction&quot; in October. &quot;4S store relocation and renovation. However, in actual implementation, &quot;establish first and then destroy&quot; has become &quot;first break and then establish&quot;. According to reports, the four new parks currently planned are still under construction. Even if work is rushed 24/7, it will be difficult to complete before the end of September. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Part of the reason why Shijiazhuang City proposed the relocation and rectification of 4S stores is that some current 4S stores have problems such as &quot;extended temporary construction and illegal construction&quot; and are a &quot;low-end market&quot; that need &quot;rectification and improvement.&quot; In fact, the current automobile 4S stores in Shijiazhuang City are relatively concentrated in four parks. Some of these parks are automobile industrial parks previously planned by the government, and some are actively gathered and formed spontaneously during the market development process. The location selection of these stores was a decision made by dealers after investigating factors such as the business district environment and customer needs, and was also in line with the municipal planning at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Requiring time-limited relocation&quot; affects not only 4S stores, but also the millions of existing car owners in Shijiazhuang, as well as new car owners who are preparing to buy cars. Officials require almost all 4S stores to close before the end of September. It is not yet known when the new park will be completed. Even if the new park is built, and even if the 4S store has the money to relocate, the decoration of the new store will usually take at least two to three months. There will be a window of several months in between. During this period, let alone citizens being unable to buy new cars, it is even difficult to ensure vehicle maintenance and repairs for old car owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the central government issued the &quot;31 Articles on the Private Economy&quot;, which requires optimizing the development environment of the private economy, protecting the property rights of private enterprises and the rights and interests of entrepreneurs in accordance with the law, and promoting the development and growth of the private economy. The Hebei Province Private Economy Leading Group also announced the &quot;Hebei Province Private Economy Development Work Points in 2023&quot; in April 2023, proposing to continue to optimize the business environment. As for optimizing the business environment, the most fundamental thing is probably not to provide enterprises with various industrial guidance and policy preferences, but to reduce interference in the market, respect the property rights of enterprises and the autonomy of entrepreneurs, and allow entrepreneurs to make market decisions independently. Only with more services and less guidance, more support and less trouble can the private economy develop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[证监会再出“新招”规范上市公司分红强化制度约束和激励]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256974]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 11:30:49&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It is the common wish of investors to obtain higher dividends within a reasonable range. On September 18, a reporter from 21st Century Business Herald learned that the China Securities Regulatory Commission plans to launch a series of measures to improve the normalized dividend mechanism for listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the China Securities Regulatory Commission has introduced and implemented a &quot;linking&quot; policy between dividends and shareholding reductions. Listed companies have not distributed cash dividends in the past three years, or the cumulative cash dividend amount is less than 30% of the average annual net profit in the past three years. , controlling shareholders and actual controllers are not allowed to reduce their holdings of the company’s shares through the secondary market. According to the person in charge of the relevant department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, it is planned to further strengthen institutional constraints on companies that do not pay dividends or pay small dividends to urge dividends, promote the optimization of dividend methods and rhythm, so that companies that pay dividends can get more incentives, and at the same time, strengthen the supervision of companies that exceed their ability to pay dividends. constraints, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that the amount of dividends paid and the proportion of A-share companies ranked among the top in the world. Data show that in the past five years, the amount of dividends paid by A-share listed companies has increased year by year, with a cumulative dividend of 8.2 trillion yuan, and the amount of dividends has exceeded the amount of financing that year. In 2022, a total of 3,291 Shanghai and Shenzhen listed companies in my country&#39;s domestic market paid cash dividends, accounting for 67.1% of the total number of listed companies at the end of 2022. The total cash dividends for the year reached 2.06 trillion yuan, of which the amount of dividends attributed to A-share shareholders was 1.62 Trillion yuan. From an international comparison, the number of dividend-paying listed companies in the domestic market ranks first among the world&#39;s major securities markets, the total amount of cash dividends ranks second in the world, and the proportion of dividend-paying companies ranks second in the world. In addition, 163 listed companies announced cash dividend plans for their 2023 semi-annual reports, with dividends expected to be 203.01 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cc2cabe70cda1d4f140901286cc0992.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/4cc2cabe70cda1d4f140901286cc0992.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251172&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h4>;Mature companies with continuous improvement in dividends, and companies listed on the main board have a higher proportion of dividends&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In recent years, the sustainability and growth of dividends of listed companies in my country have continued to improve. Data shows that as of 2022, the proportion of companies that have paid dividends for five consecutive years has increased from 20% ten years ago to 48%, and the proportion of companies that have paid dividends for 10 consecutive years has increased from 8% to 31%; 412 listed companies have paid dividends continuously. The proportion of companies that have grown in three years has increased from 3% ten years ago to 12%, and the proportion of companies that have grown in five consecutive years has increased from 1% to 4%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dividend yield and dividend payout ratio also show a fluctuating upward trend. The dividend yield distribution range has gradually increased from 0.5%-1.5% before 2010 to the current 1.5%-2%. In 2022, the average dividend payout rate in my country&#39;s domestic market is 32.5%, and the average dividend rate is 1.97%, which is in the middle and upper reaches of major global markets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which sectors and industries pay higher dividends? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders believe that dividend features are generally in line with the company’s development stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of sectors, the dividend payout rate of main board companies is the highest, reaching about 33%, which is 8 percentage points higher than the Science and Technology Innovation Board and GEM. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of industries, industries with stable performance and low investment demand tend to have higher dividend ratios. Judging from the average dividend payout ratio, energy, major consumption, and public utilities rank among the top three, with dividend ratios as high as 50%, 48%, and 45% respectively. Listed companies in these industries have low new investment needs and relatively stable cash flow. Hence the average dividend payout level is higher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the contrary, the real estate, industry, and information technology industries have greater investment demand, and the average dividend payout ratio is also lower, at 28%, 26%, and 25% respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the dividend level of A-share companies in the start-up and growth stages is lower than that of companies in the mature stage. Due to their relatively weak financing capabilities and strong willingness to save and defend, private enterprises have slightly lower dividend levels than state-owned enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Whether a high proportion of dividends is reasonable or not needs to be viewed comprehensively and accurately&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Dividends of listed companies need to comprehensively consider multiple factors such as profitability, cash flow, debt, growth stage, development goals, etc. Different types of The attitudes and demands of shareholders towards cash dividends are not completely consistent, and it is necessary to balance the interests of the company and shareholders, major shareholders and small shareholders.&quot; The interviewed experts believe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the opinion of this expert, whether a company can pay dividends and how much it pays are mainly affected by three factors: first, the undistributed profits accumulated by the company from its operations in the current year and in the past; second, the cash it currently has; It is whether the retained earnings can meet the company&#39;s future development needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The dividend ratio needs to be determined comprehensively based on the company&#39;s profitability, development stage, and future development needs. According to industry insiders, whether a company pays dividends and how much it pays are not necessarily linked to the profit of the year. Although the dividend ratio of some companies in individual years is relatively high, it is still reasonable. This must be comprehensively analyzed and viewed accurately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, some companies have stable profits and cash flow and have little investment demand, so they maintain a high dividend payout ratio. On the other hand, some companies will keep the amount of dividends unchanged despite declining profits or losses, and stabilize investor expectations through continued dividend payments, which will lead to higher dividend payout ratios in certain years. At the same time, in order to reduce redundant funds, some companies will implement special dividends based on accumulated undistributed profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experts interviewed believe that, of course, it is not ruled out that major shareholders may distribute dividends arbitrarily and hollow out the company regardless of the company&#39;s future development needs. This should be strengthened, but this should be a very small number. To judge whether dividends are reasonable, we need to start from three dimensions: first, we need to see whether the profits are real and whether there is fraud; secondly, we need to see where the cash comes from and whether it is borrowed money to distribute dividends; finally, we must make a comprehensive judgment based on the motivation of major shareholders to pay dividends. A high proportion of dividends cannot be equated with dividends beyond capacity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Therefore, we need to view high-proportion dividends comprehensively and accurately. On the one hand, we must identify dividends based on false profits at the expense of the interests of listed companies; on the other hand, we welcome dividends based on the company’s true profit level and development needs. A high proportion of dividends that can effectively return investors.&quot; said an industry insider. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Four aspects will be followed to further standardize dividends of listed companies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Recently, the China Securities Regulatory Commission plans to review the &quot;Supervisory Guidelines for Listed Companies No. 3 - Cash Dividends of Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Dividend Guidelines&quot;) ) &quot;Guidelines on Articles of Association of Listed Companies&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Guidelines on Articles of Association&quot;) and other rules have been revised. On the basis of the &quot;linking policy&quot; for dividends and shareholding reductions that have been introduced in the early stage, we will continue to improve and optimize the cash dividend supervision system and strengthen information disclosure supervision. , conveniently optimize the mid-term dividend payment process, better play the role of investment side, and continue to enhance investors&#39; sense of gain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the head of the relevant department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, this policy adjustment will proceed from four aspects:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, strengthen institutional constraints and urge companies to pay dividends that do not pay dividends or pay small dividends. The first is to strengthen information disclosure supervision. For companies listed on the main board that do not pay a certain proportion of dividends, they are required to disclose and explain the reasons. The second is to strengthen disclosure requirements for companies with large financial investments, and urge companies to improve the efficiency of asset use and better focus on the main business and return investors. The third is to strengthen inquiries and supervisory interviews. Strengthen regulatory inquiries to help investors make better judgments on dividend information, and urge more dividends through interviews and other methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, promote further optimization of dividend methods and rhythm. Specific measures in this regard can be summarized in two points: First, simplify the mid-term dividend payment procedures to facilitate the company to further increase the frequency of dividends and allow investors to better plan capital arrangements. Second, guide the company to formulate a dividend policy for stable growth. Promote companies to amend their articles of association to improve the operability of dividend policies; guide companies to explore dividend distribution policies with stable growth and reward investors with more stable dividends. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Furthermore, let companies with good dividends receive more rewards and &quot;taste the sweetness.&quot; On the one hand, it gives more &quot;honor&quot; to companies that pay good dividends. The exchange will study how to further favor high dividend-paying companies in the evaluation of information disclosure; the Listed Companies Association will study and optimize the preparation method of listed companies&#39; dividend lists and increase publicity efforts to guide companies to establish a correct value orientation. On the other hand, promote the development of more influential dividend index products; encourage fund companies to issue dividend fund products, and guide market funds to increase their preference for cash dividends from listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, strengthen restrictions on companies that pay dividends beyond their capabilities. Although paying dividends beyond capacity is not a prominent problem in A-shares, the China Securities Regulatory Commission will still pay close attention to it and take multiple measures to strengthen prevention. The first is to work hard to ensure that the company&#39;s performance is true and the basis for dividends is solid, and to effectively prevent listed companies from falsifying their finances and financing dividends. Second, for listed companies that have high asset-liability ratios and insufficient operating cash flow, but continue to pay dividends at a high proportion, detailed disclosure of the rationality of the dividend plan and its impact on the company&#39;s production and operations is required. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当“杀猪盘”受害者决定复仇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256936]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/18/7r1sWaprdhm6KsLiuHJndtO0Uye3iXJ0D57PCasl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;655&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/7r1sWaprdhm6KsLiuHJndtO0Uye3iXJ0D5 7PCasl. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The story of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is inspired by a large number of real cases of &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;. Zhou Ran, played by Zhou Dongyu, decided to take revenge after being defrauded of 550,000 yuan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When we met for the first time, Zhou Dongyu asked Ma Yingxin in a joking tone, what do you think about me? Like a person who has been cheated? It was September 2021, not long after Ma Yingxin returned to China. In the first week after arriving in Beijing, she had a meal with Zhou Dongyu and talked about Zhou Ran, the heroine of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, a victim of emotional fraud. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ma Yingxin felt that the real intention in the witty words was that she thought the audience would not be convinced if she played a deceived person. Ma Yingxin’s answer: When you think you will not be cheated, you are basically increasing your chances of being cheated. After hearing this, Zhou Dongyu did not refute or admit, &quot;But she did go back and think about it for two days and said, let me play this role.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I believe that after the movie is released, the first reaction of the audience will be, will Dong Yu be deceived?&quot; Ma Yingxin told the Southern Weekend reporter, but this was precisely one of the reasons why she chose Zhou Dongyu. &quot;I don&#39;t want to choose someone who everyone will think will be deceived when they see her. Then she acted in this story. I don&#39;t think she conveyed anything. It&#39;s precisely Dong Yu who is like this. Maybe in the audience&#39;s perception, they don&#39;t believe her. If you will be deceived, then it will be more interesting for us to read this story.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It was early autumn in Beijing in September. In an office building near the China World Trade Center, Ma Yingxin wore a black knitted sweater and pushed Wearing a wheelchair, he entered the conference room neatly. After a car accident when she was young, she has been using a wheelchair. Stopping in front of the long white table, she did not say any greetings and only said softly, &quot;Let&#39;s get started.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creation of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is based on a large number of real cases. The background of the story is the emotional scam in telecommunications network fraud, commonly known as &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;. After 2019, Ma Yingxin began to receive relevant news frequently. What puzzled her was that mainstream comments were belittling and blaming the victimized women. They were &quot;love-brained,&quot; &quot;stupid,&quot; and even the word &quot;pig-killing plate&quot; itself was a stigma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Many people, without thinking deeply about this problem, think how could I be deceived. But in fact, so many people have been deceived.&quot; When writing the script, in addition to online information, Ma Yingxin also Ask a friend to find the real victim and chat. She discovered that there were many more victims than she thought, and many of them were very smart and outstanding people. Emotional deception is different from ordinary financial fraud. The victim will feel humiliated and dare not tell others. Some people do not even call the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Emotional fraud usually refers to online fraud that induces victims to make &quot;investments&quot; based on opposite-sex online dating. The long-term process of establishing an emotional relationship is called &quot;pig farming.&quot; In recent years, as more information has been disclosed, people have discovered that the means of emotional fraud are highly specialized and even involve psychological knowledge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A woman working in the financial industry in a big city in China also had doubts when communicating with scammers. The other party claimed to be a colleague. She asked some questions about the industry intentionally or unintentionally, and the other party could answer them appropriately. After being deceived, the woman did not tell her family, and only a few friends vaguely knew about it. She worries that if her colleagues find out, what she says in the company will have no weight in the future. When talking to Ma Yingxin, she always used a relatively relaxed tone, &quot;I thought everyone had passed the financial test, so there should be no problem.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2020, Ma Yingxin finished writing the script of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;. The heroine Zhou Ran, played by Zhou Dongyu, is a female drifter from Beijing who was defrauded of 550,000 yuan. She followed clues to a small coastal town and met the con man Lin Zhiguang, played by Zhang Yu, and his friend Xu Zhao, played by Zhang Youhao. Emotional deception is based on imitation, performance, manipulation, and insight into and gaming of the subtleties of the human heart. Zhou Ran decided to retaliate in his own way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The filming location of the movie was Dongshan Island in Zhangzhou, Fujian. Maying hoped to find an island filled with fog. When writing the script, the first thing that came to her mind was the scene of three people meeting in the fog. She thought that this scene was like the state of a deceived woman - &quot;She was in the fog and couldn&#39;t see anything, but a male voice kept coming. She had been in a heavy fog for nine months.&quot; Until the source of the voice came out of the fog and a specific image of a man appeared, the fog began to disperse. &quot;From this moment on, Zhou Ran saw some things clearly. She wanted to take action. Finally, she was not in a place shrouded in fog and without anything. A situation that cannot be caught. I see you clearly, but you don’t know my situation or my mentality. She took the initiative.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1986, Ma Yingxin was born in Northeast China. She has loved watching movies since she was a child. After online paid movies became available, her father paid two to three thousand yuan in internet fees in one month. As an adult, Ma Yingxin went to Spain to study and study law, where she lived for more than ten years. She likes Almodóvar, has been writing scripts for the past ten years, and has made short films &quot;Dead Words&quot; and &quot;Man in the Chair&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is Ma Yingxin&#39;s first feature film. As a new director living overseas, this project was set up by chance. A few years ago, she met the writer Shuang Xuetao at a literature lecture in Spain. She introduced that she was engaged in film work in Spain and also wrote scripts. Shuang Xuetao said, if you want to hear other people&#39;s opinions, you are welcome to send them to me. At the end of 2020, after writing the script of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, she sent it to Shuang Xuetao on WeChat, &quot;I said that we exchanged WeChat messages when you came to Spain two years ago. Who am I? At that time, you said that you could give the script to Look, I now have a story that happened in China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two days later, they had a long phone call. Shuang Xuetao was on the sidelines preparing to play football at the time, but did not play until the end of the game. &quot;We didn&#39;t talk too much about the script on that phone call. He was actually trying to find out if I could be a director.&quot; Later, Shuang Xuetao became the producer of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot;, and Don He, who had collaborated with &quot;Fire on the Plain&quot;, served as the producer. Producer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the one-and-a-half-hour interview, Ma Yingxin occasionally needed to put her hands on the armrests of her wheelchair and lift her body to relax. Before becoming a director, she may face some labels, &quot;maybe a woman, followed by my personal physical condition&quot;, which she can accept, but in the final analysis, she wants to introduce herself as: an honest creator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title of &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; partly comes from parroting. The liar uses parroting techniques to help teach and complete the deception, which is essentially an act of imitation. She wanted to express, &quot;Women&#39;s appreciation of emotions is not a disadvantage of women, or something that should be eliminated.&quot; This is part of being a woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/TFzP0fFlVRzfYq5kgKfXAqrgeekK3vc1pDTRhA5l.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/TFzP0fFlVRzfYq5kgKfXAqrgeekK3vc1pDTRhA5l.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251123&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Director Ma Yingxin was born in Northeast China in 1986 and has lived overseas for many years. &quot;Parrot Killing&quot; is her first feature film. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;These women are ordinary people&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>; strong>;&lt;strong>;Very smart, even outstanding&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;You once said that you would not make a movie based on a certain social issue, but rather that a certain issue fits the issue you want to discuss and use this issue to develop a story. You think &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; is very much like a fable. What does it contain to you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;When I was watching the news about &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot;, the comments below kept discussing that the victim was stupid and must be It’s some very stupid, love-minded women who get scammed. After seeing these words, I have doubts based on my understanding of people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think it is impossible for a person not to have emotional connections with people in this life. It is not only limited to emotional love relationships, but also has emotional and trusting connections with your friends and people around you. . If this is the case, a group of people come here, and they are deliberately trying to deceive you. What can you do? It has nothing to do with whether you are a smart person, unless you don&#39;t relate to people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, I tried to find out what kind of people the victims were. I read online information and asked friends to contact me. I came to the conclusion that these people were ordinary women, just like me and the people around me. Nothing is different, have normal expectations for life and love. They are very smart, even brilliant women. So I&#39;m not going to create a typical or any kind of spectacle victim image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, regarding why people are deceived, I had a communication with the producer Shuang Xuetao. He said that liars are an ancient industry, and cheating with feelings has been happening since ancient times. , but in a different form today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The process of being deceived involves many essential human issues, such as people’s eternal desire for true love, and the use of emotions to manipulate, deceive, and game between people. This is a very tense relationship. , which is theatrically intense. So this story has two levels. One is that the &quot;pig killing plate&quot; itself is an unfair or biased impression of the female victims, and the other is that this issue also contains other more essential issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You start from the emotional state and inner struggle of the victim after being deceived. , was this perspective formed from the beginning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I spent half a year to a year thinking about the script. I feel that the creation is not a complete representation of reality, and I don’t want to film it. I have so many news materials in my hands and then put them together in the form of a movie. Movies need to have a structure that puts in the things you most want to discuss. Later, I started writing the script after having two relatively clear ideas. One was that I wanted the victim and the liar to meet in reality, and the second was that I wanted to reenact the process of cheating and being cheated. I wrote it on and off for about half a year. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xue Tao is very interested in many liar movies. He feels that this movie is a subversion of liar movies, because they usually focus on liars and describe how powerful liars are. How clever. He said that you did it from the perspective of a victim, which kept the genre of the con man movie and was subversive at the same time. In addition, he also said that liars have existed since ancient times, including big liars, small liars, and industry liars, so this is also a movie about trust. From both perspectives, this issue is worth pursuing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also, he said that I provided a female perspective, because if a man were to make this movie, it might turn out differently. Don He has worked with female directors before and feels that this is a female expression, which is very precious and should be expressed like this. As a male, he could not understand every expression in it very accurately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/JVyo3c1SdHHQFzQ7hQcrX0dpZ8yTatBMEE5bHG7G.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/JVyo3c1SdHHQFzQ7hQcrX0dpZ8yTatBMEE5bHG7G.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The two male protagonists in the story are engaged in &quot;pig killing&quot; in a fraud park, and their true identities are confusing. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Don&#39;t think this movie is going to teach women a lesson&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why did you choose Zhou Dongyu to play Zhou Ran? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After we promoted this project, the first thing we considered was who would play Zhou Ran, because it depends on an actress. Get up drama. At that time Don He recommended Dong Yu because they had collaborated on &quot;Fire on the Plains&quot;. Frankly speaking, I was hesitant at the time. Of course Dong Yu is very good, but in my heart I am a girl, and I think this character is exactly the opposite of her screen image. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, &quot;Fire on the Plains&quot; was shown to friends and family, and I went to see it. In the first half of the movie, Dongyu was still a girl, but in the second half, she showed another state. . Another more important reason is that I found that Dong Yu can handle very complex emotions, which is a very rare ability, because Zhou Ran has to constantly deal with complex emotions, not a simple &quot;I want revenge&quot; character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you understand the complexity of the character Zhou Ran? There are a lot of undercurrents and real and fake games in this story. Do you think she ever hesitated? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think her determination for revenge started from the moment she met the liar, even before she met the liar. Yes, but it was after she met the liar that she decided how to take revenge. Because this liar walked up to her and said, I am sincere, how many difficulties I have, what a special person you are, and he is still using words at this moment. She may have wanted to put him in jail before, and wanted to catch him, but after that scene, something deeper was aroused. She felt that just letting him go to jail was not enough, so she adopted a series of subsequent methods. Including the voices she heard from other female victims in the car, it also gave her a lot of strength and she must do this. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But you said whether she swayed and struggled during the process, I think she did. Because she is an ordinary person, not a well-trained liar, her doing this is beyond the scope of what ordinary people can bear. If she didn&#39;t struggle, it was a revenge, I came to act a scene, without any emotional fluctuations, and finally sent you in, it was not so powerful for me. On the contrary, she struggled a little bit and finally completed it, which I think is a very powerful act. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Through the perspective of female victims, the expression you ultimately want to point to What is it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think we can understand the common experiences of women and the common intellectual and emotional struggles through the experience of this victim. Especially in recent years, with the emergence of the so-called &quot;love brain&quot;, I feel that it has been dwarfing women&#39;s natural appreciation of emotions, and has obscured the real problem in such an incident, which is the use of Those who seek benefits based on emotions are at fault, or this is what society really needs to be vigilant about. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not actually the core of this movie, but my own idea is that I hope that we can at least make a movie with a female protagonist. When the audience walks out of the cinema, they don’t just feel This movie wants to teach women a lesson about how women should not do anything. In the very few screenings we had before, female viewers could understand her way of revenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Uy98gxa2ZovcOK2j2PSY9puf61TbDG6IEi7wbK7s.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;628&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/Uy98gxa2ZovcOK2j2PSY9puf61TbDG6IEi7wbK7s.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Ma Yingxin believes that the &quot;Pig Killing Plate&quot; is a fable that contains more essential issues such as trust and emotion. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;What is sincerity? He doesn’t know either&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Your account at station B There was a special episode about Zhang Yu in &quot;Weekend Movie Party&quot;. How did it feel to work with Zhang Yu this time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Of course, the role of Lin Chiguang is very different from his previous screen image, such as in &quot;The Calm&quot; and &quot;Siberian Tiger&quot; In it, he is a reserved, restrained and even repressed character, or another very reckless, direct, and fierce character. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Zhiguang is completely different. He is a person who thinks very, very much. He is constantly performing true and false performances. He is very good at using language to manipulate others and use language to game or win. deceive others. The same thing is that Zhang Yu himself is also a very good thinker. At that time, he read the script and found it very interesting, but at the same time he had some opinions, so he wrote a page and sent it to Don He. A screenshot of the Don River was sent to me. When I saw it, I was very unconvinced and asked why you had so many opinions. So I wrote him a letter to answer these questions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I think Zhang Yu is such an actor. He has a lot of questions to ask you, but after getting the answers, he can communicate and he will be very happy. Moreover, Lin Zhiguang has a relatively gentle trait in dealing with people. This is also something Zhang Yu himself has. He is also a very gentle person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What was written on that piece of paper? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For example, why should I kill an octopus? Is this directed at me? What is the purpose of this image? I say that movies should not explain things. The more you explain, the less things you will learn. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Did he himself create anything for this character? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ma Yingxin: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The language he created most is Lin Zhiguang’s language. We have fought many times about this matter. He wants Lin Zhiguang to have A very soft, Southern and not-so-Southern accent. This character deceived people and said that he was in Southeast Asia. He should have a unique accent, not Zhang Yu&#39;s accent, and not a Mandarin speaker. This was something he felt was very important to this character. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你对这两个男性诈骗者的形象是怎么理解的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;林致光是一个不相信任何东西的人，他在网上扮演阿昌，生活中又扮演林致光，所以他基本是活在扮演当中的人。他非常善于操纵别人，非常擅长操纵情感，是一个空空荡荡，很无助，很彷徨的人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许照是一个被毁掉的人，比较年轻就到了那个地方，他对这一切没有任何认知，为了生存开始做这些事。他还没有真正体验过什么是爱，什么是真心，就已经在运用它去骗人了，这导致他是一个很混沌的状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以在现实中他面对周冉，面对一个真实的女性，他其实也很混沌，分不清自己到底有没有爱她，有没有珍惜她。林致光有一句台词说，我以为你真的喜欢她。他说我是真的喜欢她，你说的嘛，要真心。但是这个真心到底是什么呢？我觉得他也不知道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/8sZtRFcVewUDgJd1gypnAc9MpeOf7XbGV0wxcK8Z.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/8sZtRFcVewUDgJd1gypnAc9MpeOf7XbGV0wxcK8Z.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251126&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;麻赢心在拍摄现场。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;女性复仇的方式是独特&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;、&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;有力的&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;周冉和林致光在车里接吻的镜头，不是一个很直接的亲吻镜头，甚至有点像“借位”。为什么这样设计？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是有意这样的，因为他们不是肉体关系，是精神上的博弈，所以肢体部分我会尽量往下压。那场戏最重要的是语言上的博弈，情感的博弈，周冉用一轮又一轮语言把林致光瓦解掉，获得他的信任。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最后林致光回到了车厢，他是真的被俘获了吗，还是不得不回来？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;这个问题之前也有人问过我，我不觉得林致光爱上了周冉，在这么短的时间里，尤其是对林致光这样一个人来说，几乎是不可能的。我认为他那一刻是对于这个女性能够原谅他，甚至有可能跟他建立未来的生活，对这件事情产生了妄想。即使他是一个骗子，他也有一刻产生了妄想，所以回到了这个车厢。还有一种可能性是，他需要回到车厢才能拿到那笔钱。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那场戏冬雨处理得也非常复杂，我几乎不太愿意用语言解读那场戏，但我核心的认识是最后的对峙，冬雨的表演非常有力量，她甚至做了一个鬼脸。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那是她自己加的反应？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对，她在那一刻突然有那一个动作，我认为是一个非常强大的反应，而且是只有她会给的一个反应。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对于你来说，周冉最终的复仇是一种女性主义表达吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得我在这部电影里非常诚实，我本身是一个女性，所以一定是女性的表达，但是它是不是女性主义的表达，坦白说女性主义我还在学习。但这部电影至少提出了一种女性看待事情的方式，和她行动的方法。提到复仇，你总会觉得它是一种暴力行为，因为由复仇带来的联想，之前是由男性电影或以男性为主导的电影来给人建立印象的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得这是一个新的印象，女性复仇的方式是独特的。如果你认同情感或者谎言能给人伤害，那她复仇的方式就是有力的。确实有一些观众会觉得是不是不够爽，期待一些更暴力或更剧烈的复仇方式。但对我而言，反而这种方式才是真正有力的，而不是更暴烈、更外化的东西，我觉得她真的用了一个人是如何被摧毁的方式去报仇或回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那你觉得林致光体会到了这种伤害，或者接收到了这个信息吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;麻赢心：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得林致光至少是诧异的，是他意想不到的。至少从表演上来说，最后那一场戏章宇的角色非常用力地看周冉，他就是想要看到一些答案，但是他看不到。我认为至少这个问题会困扰他。而且除了被绳之以法，对过去做的事情，他可能有机会真正地反思。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[211高校女硕士遭杀猪盘被骗138万：财务决策与婚恋决策分开是防骗关键]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256938]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，“211女硕士遭杀猪盘两周被骗138万”冲上热搜第一。当事人雪儿从江苏某211院校硕士毕业后，入职上海某银行。今年五六月份，她在某社交平台发布了择偶的帖子。一男性主动与她联系，称他住在上海杨浦区五角广场，毕业于上海财经大学，在互联网大厂工作，此时在北京出差。在网上交流一段时间后，对方给雪儿发了一个链接，让她点击下载一个名为“luno”的app，教她在上面买币，然后用币买涨买跌，赚点外快。刚开始雪儿赚了一些钱，随后，对方以各种理由让雪儿先后投入130多万，最终雪儿发现陷入骗局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;层出不穷的“杀猪盘”，对各类人群通杀，针对男性的裸聊陷阱，针对女性的婚恋陷阱，显示了骗子对两性心理差异的精准把握。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然拥有高学历、高收入、高颜值，但不少女性也深陷其中。究其原因，某些高知女性在婚恋中，往往没有做好财务决策和婚恋决策，尤其是混为一谈，使骗子有机可乘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓财务决策，涉及资金方面的支出、投资等行为，需对投资项目的合理可行性、投资规模、投资止损标准、投资失败带来的后果等，进行综合考量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“杀猪盘”的变现套路，往往是以高息诱导受害人。然而，你图的是高息，骗子瞄准的是你本金。人们应建立一个投资常识，投资产品的预期收益与投资风险是正相关的。就如日常购买各类理财产品，理财产品会标注不同等级，预期年化收益率不高但标注低风险的理财产品，主要投资于高信用等级债券（如国债）、货币市场等低风险金融产品，而预期年化收益率高但标注中高风险的理财产品，则投资产品组合中股票、商品、外汇等高波动性金融产品的占比高。理财机构在客户购买产品时，还要进行个人投资风险评估，根据其填报的以往投资品类、收入状况等信息，为其推荐更符合其风险偏好的投资品种，避免其盲目投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，当女方听到对方介绍“包赚不赔、利息远超市场平均水准”的投资产品时，就应引起警惕。郭树清曾经提醒过广大金融消费者和投资者：高收益意味着高风险，收益率超过6%就要打问号，超过8%就很危险，10%以上就要准备损失全部本金。另外，就是不要轻信不明信息，不要随意透露个人信息，不要打开不明网络链接，不要轻易汇款转账。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但凡遇到大额资金投资，事先多了解一些投资理财专业知识，或者请具有相关经验的人士或机构提供建议，然后根据自身风险承受能力、资金面等，进行投资与否、投资金额、出现问题如何及时止损等方面的决策，应成为所有人具备的“财商”。尤其是作为高知女性，更应有起码的学习能力。上述案例的雪儿在银行工作，虽然从事IT工作，但找几个懂理财的同事请教并非难事，可她被男方尤其是“投资”最初的获利所惑，一步步深入陷阱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，男女还要做好婚恋决策。一般而言，在婚恋市场，男女双方的诉求排序不同。男性往往更看重女性颜值、年龄等，女性则将男性的财富、家庭背景等标准作为重点。对于高知女性而言，婚恋市场上某方面优秀的男性不少，但富人则很少，兼具外形和财富的高富帅，属于典型的稀缺人群，他们的选择空间极大，所以对“高富帅”的竞争其实是很激烈的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;骗子之所以打造高富帅人设，在于他们深知这一人群身处卖方市场，女性往往求之难得。一旦遇到，某些女性急于将白马王子牢牢抓住，有严重的依赖心理，易对骗子言听计从。部分女性过于追求爱情的完美和投资的高收益，忽视了现实中的风险和不确定性。在面对“杀猪盘”骗局时，受到情感和利益的双重诱惑，从而掉入骗子的陷阱，最终人财两失。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论男性还是女性，进行婚恋决策，至少要做好三点事先评估：其一，客观评估自身条件，自己在婚恋市场的大致排序是什么？不要净想着买两块钱彩票中五百万。知人者智，自知者明，古人诚不我欺。其二，如果对方的言行与人身让你很舒服，如浴春风，那就不要太上头，应该吹一下冷风，用理智判断一下，对方就是这样的人品还是处处在迎合你？贪图情绪价值可以理解，但对方暗中的标价可能昂贵到你难以承受。其三，哪怕认定对方是真命天子，也别将婚恋决策和财务决策捆绑。越来越多走到婚姻这一步的男女，都开始强调婚后财产、生活开支“AA制”，你何以婚前就能将血汗钱交给对方帮忙投资？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 10:25:34 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>