<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[涉56项违规行为，中信银行被罚没超2.24亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 18:40:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;The State Administration of Financial Supervision’s administrative penalty information disclosure table shows that CITIC Bank was fined 224 million yuan. Involved in 56 violations. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bAQDUFr9Qa7UfuPHCnK1xuzCp6Kr5381T8IIU8Vi.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1102&quot; height=&quot;3895&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bAQDUFr9Qa7UfuPHCnK1xuzCp6Kr5381T8IIU8Vi.png&quot; data-key=&quot;260389&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:55:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[基辛格，时代纵横者]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261684]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 12/01/JrAlKuYydBfzmqHvKNPyVrV7ck8oK6BbyenF3EB9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;686&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JrAlKuYydBfzmqHvKNPyVrV7ck8oK 6BbyenF3EB9. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260342&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kissinger&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 29, 2023 local time, the former US National Security Assistant and Secretary of State was a famous diplomat, politician and politician who profoundly influenced the development of US foreign policy and geopolitics in the 20th century. Family and scholar Henry Kissinger died at the age of 100. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/nzs2VAJeIaxcrRWol73AbMPNHNlwqUzj3C28Gigo.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;688&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/nzs2VAJeIaxcrRWol73AbMPNHNlwqUzj3C28Gigo.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kissinger and his brother Walter&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1923, Heinz Alfred Kissinger was born in a German-Jewish family in Fürth, Bavaria, Germany. His father was a teacher and his mother was a housewife. A year later, a younger brother was added to the family, Walter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a child, Kissinger was keen on playing football and once joined the youth training of Fürth Football Club. But with Hitler coming to power in 1933, the Nazi regime&#39;s oppression of the Jewish community intensified. Because he broke into the stadium to watch games in violation of Jewish segregation regulations, Kissinger was often scolded and beaten by guards, and he was also kicked out of the team. Later, Kissinger&#39;s father was also dismissed from his teaching position without reason. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before everything got worse, Kissinger&#39;s family immigrated to the United States in 1938, and he later changed his name to Henry Kissinger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/urcUvA76c5dNtpo6hqBOMmoB02EtHgR8Z7JDixSR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;627&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/urcUvA76c5dNtpo6hqBOMmoB02EtHgR8Z7JDixSR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260334&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 10, 1971, U.S. President Richard Nixon (left) and National Security Advisor Kissinger talked in his office at the White House&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1969, Nixon appointed Kissinger as National Security Assistant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before entering politics, Kissinger was already a well-known international political scholar, and had served in many institutions or think tanks with a background in the US government. He served as the candidate for Nelson Rockefeller’s presidential campaign three times. foreign policy adviser, during which he sharply criticized Nixon as &quot;the most dangerous presidential candidate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But after Nixon became president, the two dramatically became a tacit understanding partner. Faced with the turbulent global situation in the 1960s, Nixon gave Kissinger great room for action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 1971, Kissinger secretly flew to Beijing during his visit to Pakistan, and facilitated Nixon&#39;s visit to China in 1972 that shocked the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39lKQDl4vF2RSxAuLFZ7SuaXJkVKh07cK6toF9xt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;661&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39lKQDl4vF2RSxAuLFZ7SuaXJkVKh07cK6toF9xt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260337&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On February 25, 1972, in Beijing, US President Richard Nixon and his wife attended the dinner and took a group photo. Kissinger was on the right in the front row&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa; &quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/8OmIyZ9ID8DQMC1bf1umluLDmCPENPAoX5WbMgGE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;643&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/8OmIyZ9ID8DQMC1bf1umluLDmCPENPAoX5WbMgGE.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260333 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 3, 1974, in the Moscow Kremlin, during the seven-day summit, U.S. Presidents Nixon (middle), Secretary of State Kissinger (left) and Soviet leader Brezhnev (right) toast &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1972 On February 21, 2011, US President Richard Nixon arrived in Beijing and began his visit to China. On February 28, the Sino-US Joint Communique was released, announcing the normalization of relations between China and the United States. Later studies generally believed that the normalization of Sino-US relations greatly affected the Soviet Union’s diplomatic strategic considerations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under Kissinger&#39;s promotion, shortly after Nixon&#39;s visit to China, he visited Moscow in May of that year and met with Soviet leader Brezhnev, which contributed to the &quot;Soviet-US Joint Communique&quot; and &quot;Soviet-American Joint Communique&quot;. The release of 9 documents including the Principles of Mutual Relations between the United States and the United States. In the following years, leaders of the United States and the Soviet Union had frequent exchanges and reached positive consensus on the use of offensive strategic weapons and nuclear weapons testing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The improvement of relations between China, the United States and the United States and the Soviet Union directly drove the overall global situation to a positive direction. Kissinger’s diplomatic thoughts on balancing the balance of power among major powers to achieve national interests and international peace were fully reflected in this process. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d6FcaaBTeWxWoEz7WkduMF52Df2s0DWpdbN8Mtu6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;647&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/d6FcaaBTeWxWoEz7WkduMF52Df2s0DWpdbN8Mtu6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260336&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;January 23, 1973, Paris, France, Special Advisor to the Delegation of the Democratic Republic of Vietnam Le Duc Tho (front row, second from right) and U.S. National Security Advisor Kissinger (back row, second from left) Signing the &quot;Paris Peace Accords&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger traveled to Vietnam twice from 1965 to 1966 . During his visit, he realized that the United States &quot;neither knew how to win wars nor how to end them.&quot; In the end, the war that dragged the United States into the quagmire ended in his hands. After Nixon came to power, Kissinger conducted a series of difficult negotiations with the leaders of North and South Vietnam. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The normalization of Sino-US relations has greatly promoted the easing of the situation in Indochina. In October 1972, Kissinger and Viet Cong leader Le Duc Tho achieved a decisive breakthrough in secret negotiations in Paris. Kissinger announced that &quot;peace is close at hand.&quot; Nixon&#39;s popularity surged during the presidential election. Finally, he Re-elected by overwhelming margins in 49 states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 1973, all parties signed the Paris Peace Accords. A ceasefire between North and South Vietnam, the United States withdraws all troops from Vietnam, and the North Vietnamese release all American prisoners of war. Kissinger and Le Duc Tho were also awarded the Nobel Peace Prize. Le Duc Tho refused to accept the award, and Kissinger announced that he would donate the prize money to the children of American servicemen killed or missing in the Vietnam War. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/aEHVSSeCESW1K1fSjsluI22dS6GuKWQLx61XkSTe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;651&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/aEHVSSeCESW1K1fSjsluI22dS6GuKWQLx61XkSTe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260335&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 1, 1975, Kissinger looked at the scenery at the hotel in Jerusalem&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/9cpZ0bwTEFEdWXjCAMueQJmkECax1YU41eU989c6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;627&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/9cpZ0bwTEFEdWXjCAMueQJmkECax1YU41eU989c6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260338&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 6, 1975, on a round-trip flight between Egypt and Israel, Kissinger was reading a newspaper when his wife Nancy patted him on the head&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the &quot;Yom Kippur War&quot; (the Fourth Middle East War) broke out in 1973, Kissinger once again ran for mediation First line. Out of American political interests and his own blood, he tried to delay the ceasefire to give the Israeli army more time to expand its results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the war, Kissinger once tried to delay the United States&#39; arms and material compensation to Israel, and was committed to promoting UN Security Council Resolution 242 to achieve peace. After the Middle East oil-producing countries, led by Saudi Arabia, imposed an oil embargo on the United States, Kissinger ended up trying to mediate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 1973 to 1975, Kissinger traveled between the leaders of Egypt, Saudi Arabia, Syria and Israel, carrying out &quot;shuttle diplomacy&quot; and successfully obtained the support of Egyptian President Sadat and others. trust, and promised to sell arms in exchange for Saudi Arabia lifting its oil embargo, leading to two agreements on the Sinai Peninsula issue - Israel would withdraw from parts of the Sinai and gave up its demand to end the state of war, and Egypt agreed to The opening of the Suez Canal with non-military supplies is considered one of the few diplomatic achievements of the United States during the Ford administration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/o1q3WNAyhmZGGEL5Nzv7fAT5ymgO7YXcoQxWZUQS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/o1q3WNAyhmZGGEL5Nzv7fAT5ymgO7YXcoQxWZUQS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260340&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;December 11, 1995, from left: Kissinger, Princess Diana, Colin Powell and news anchor Barbara Walters attended the 41st World Cerebral Palsy Federation Association Awards Night. Princess Diana received the UCP Humanitarian Award at the gala &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kissinger was arrested during the Watergate scandal under Nixon After being forced to resign, he continued to serve as National Security Assistant and Secretary of State in President Ford&#39;s administration. But not long after the Sinai Agreement was reached, Kissinger was replaced as National Security Assistant by Brent Scowcroft in a cabinet reshuffle known as the &quot;Halloween Massacre&quot; in November 1975. . After Ford lost the 1976 presidential election, Kissinger resigned as Secretary of State. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since then, Kissinger has traveled in the three circles of politics, business and academia: he established the China Venture Capital Company and served as chairman and CEO; served as &lt;span>;Philip MacMoran&lt;/span>; ( Freeport-McMoRan); served as chairman of the National Commission on Terrorism in the United States... In addition, he has also included principals, political consultants or board members of various institutions, some of which are even controversial positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, he also released at least 7 books, including his own memoirs, political commentary, and even an observation about artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JYae0XIfuOZUxCQWPlzJTjPnpET6kHVJA6tmXXjh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height= &quot;1367&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/JYae0XIfuOZUxCQWPlzJTjPnpET6kHVJA6tmXXjh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 12, 2000, Texas Governor and Republican presidential candidate George W. Bush (left) and former U.S. Secretary of State Kissinger waved to reporters on the porch of the Governor&#39;s Mansion in Austin Regards&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/12/01/Ed1vgBH06Ddfp1DQZKMlRM4Wymy6WtqU6ULx3DCA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01 /Ed1vgBH06Ddfp1DQZKMlRM4Wymy6WtqU6ULx3DCA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260341&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 10, 2017, US President Trump (right) Meeting with former US Secretary of State Kissinger at the White House &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a man with outstanding contributions and rich experience in American history As a veteran politician with extensive connections in the political and business circles, Kissinger has basically become the “mountain” that every U.S. president since Nixon has consulted or paid a visit to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 17, 2016, Kissinger met with President-elect Donald Trump. They discussed global affairs, and they met again the following year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later in an interview on August 17, 2017, Kissinger said helplessly when talking about the president who the whole world could not figure out and who often took eccentric opinions: &quot;I hope (Special) Trump) had an Augustinian moment. For St. Augustine...he behaved completely differently in his early years than he later did, but one day he was suddenly inspired and became the saint he became. Of course people don&#39;t expect the president to be like that, but You can always think about it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2PTa6qPaaUQlpQGsxzBkOEEHQB6WjdDcyh2u7FBN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2PTa6qPaaUQlpQGsxzBkOEEHQB6WjdDcyh2u7FBN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260339&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 1985, Kissinger visited Qingping Street Market in Guangzhou&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(An Ge/Photo)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ndCunHHZsub4iKGwPsjAt2o4msQiBIyW89wi1unV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;612&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ndCunHHZsub4iKGwPsjAt2o4msQiBIyW89wi1unV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260343&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On May 12, 2005, in Xuchang, Henan, former US Secretary of State Kissinger came to the home of Liang Shuhua, a villager from Group 7, Xuzhuang Village, Dengzhuang Township, to experience the family life of local farmers. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Visual China/Picture）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/12/01/A6Kexysn0JdEdAamq5QldrHwtAwsF6BrCqUPBBQy.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/ A6Kexysn0JdEdAamq5QldrHwtAwsF6BrCqUPBBQy.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 24, 2023, former US Secretary of State Kissinger held a meeting in New York Speaking at the annual awards dinner of the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Until he entered the political arena, Kissinger He has never shown much interest in China, but after gaining an in-depth understanding of China through his work, he began to have a new understanding of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After deciding to promote the development of Sino-US relations, Kissinger carefully studied Chinese culture, history, politics and other national conditions, and paid close attention to China&#39;s political and economic development. From 1971 to 2023, Kissinger visited China more than 100 times, a record unique among Western politicians. He once said, &quot;China is the country with which I have the longest and most in-depth exchanges. China has become a very important part of my life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Kissinger&#39;s death, Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Wang Wenbin said, Dr. Kissinger is an old friend and good friend of the Chinese people, and a pioneer and builder of Sino-US relations. &quot;He has long been concerned about and supported the development of Sino-US relations, and has visited China more than a hundred times, making historic contributions to promoting the normalization of Sino-US relations. The Chinese people will remember Dr. Kissinger&#39;s sincere feelings and important contributions to Sino-US relations. Contribute.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“电玩捕鱼”涉赌案：矛盾的时间点，反转的证词]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261669]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;A game called &quot;Monopoly Video Game Fishing&quot; was banned by Guangxi Cangwu Public Security Bureau Identified as gambling. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bc41c3b44b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/bc41c3b44b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260322&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;A game called &quot;Monopoly Video Game Fishing&quot; was recognized as gambling by Guangxi Cangwu Public Security Bureau. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Monopoly Video Game Fishing” is a game developed and operated by a game company in Beijing. In more than two years, players have recharged a total of approximately 157 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But in the eyes of the public security organs in Cangwu County, Guangxi, this &quot;fishing&quot; is not a game, but gambling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 18, 2022, the actual controllers of the gaming company, Zong Chao, Zhong Liuqing, and seven employees were arrested by the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau on suspicion of opening a casino. On October 23, 2023, the first instance verdict of the Cangwu County Court was that Zong Chao was sentenced to 6 years and 10 months in prison, Zhong Liuqing was sentenced to 5 and a half years in prison, and the remaining 7 people were sentenced to prison terms ranging from 2 years to 2 years and 11 months. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The judgment stated that the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau, based on the clues discovered during the work, confirmed after preliminary inspection that some players of the game involved were from Cangwu County, and the reporter and three witnesses were also from Cangwu County. They The testimony confirmed that the game involved was suspected of gambling, and Cangwu County was the place where the crime was committed and had jurisdiction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned from people who attended the trial that, coincidentally, two of the witnesses were held in the same cell as the defendant. During the first-instance trial, the defendant&#39;s statement of situation showed that both witnesses stated that they completed the transcript under the arrangement of the public security agency staff, and that they had not been exposed to this game before making the transcript. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when the two witnesses were later questioned by the detention center, they overturned their statements in the description of the situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zong Chao and Zhong Liuqing refused to accept the verdict and have submitted an appeal to the Wuzhou Intermediate Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Gray areas and luck&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The persons involved, Zong Chao, Zhong Liuqing, and the start-up employees of the game company were all former colleagues of a major Internet company. In 2018, they resigned from their original units and established Beijing Sihai Interactive Entertainment Technology Co., Ltd. to jointly operate fishing games. In the second half of 2019, the game will be launched online. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gameplay of the fishing game is that after users recharge RMB to obtain game gold coins, they then use the gold coins to fire fish. After successfully fishing, they win gold coins at a multiplier rate. At the same time, in the &quot;Fortunate Beans&quot; mode, users can obtain &quot;Fortunate Beans&quot; when fishing, and &quot;Fortunate Beans&quot; can be exchanged for phone bills, physical goods, JD shopping cards, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance verdict quoted a defendant’s confession. He had an online group with Zong Chao, Zhong Liuqing and others as well as lawyers to discuss whether this game would hit a legal red line. The opinion given by the lawyer is that the gameplay of this game is in a gray area. There is no law that says you can do this, and there is no law that says you can&#39;t do it this way, so you just took a chance at that time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of the defendants and their lawyers, the reason why this game cannot be considered gambling is that although the gold coins won by fishing are proportional to the &quot;explosion rate&quot; and &quot;multiplier&quot;, the gold coins It cannot be used to exchange RMB. The lucky beans that can be converted into RMB have their own generation mechanism, which has nothing to do with &quot;explosion rate&quot;, &quot;bet size&quot; and &quot;magnification&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The case will be heard in public on &lt;/span>; March 28, June 25, and June 29, 2023. Zong Chao&#39;s defense lawyer defended his innocence. The lawyer pointed out in court that the essence of gambling is to achieve &quot;big gains with small things.&quot; In order to ensure that the game operation does not fall into the scope of the crime of opening a casino, the game operator has a limit on the proportion of the recharge amount for the lucky beans that come with the game, and the operator has set up a blacklist to intercept players who try to &quot;compromise with small things&quot;. Outside the game. Therefore, this game cannot achieve &quot;using small to gain big&quot;, so it is not gambling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment of the court found that when players use cannons that consume more gold coins and have higher multiples when fishing, the energy bar will grow faster, and different levels of lucky beans can be produced correspondingly. There is &quot;a small way to make a big difference&quot;. It has a cash withdrawal function and is recognized as a gambling game. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&amp;nbsp;&quot;A moment of negligence&quot;? Conflicts occurred at multiple points in time&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At 15:50 on January 2, 2022, local Pan Jianfeng went to the Shiqiao Town Police Station in Cangwu County to report that he had downloaded the &quot;Monopoly Video Game Fishing&quot; App at home. After registering with a real name, I found that this game can be recharged online, and then you can win &quot;Fu Beans&quot; by playing the game, and the &quot;Fu Beans&quot; can be exchanged for RMB and withdrawn. He told the police that he had recharged 36 yuan and withdrawn 2 yuan, so he thought it was a gambling game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the first-instance judgment, on December 20, 2021, 13 days before Pan Jianfeng reported the case, the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau had noticed this App and conducted a preliminary inspection. After verification, it was found that there were Cangwu members. 41 people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Cangwu County Public Security Bureau opened a case for investigation on the day Pan Jianfeng reported the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case will be heard in public from March 28, June 25 to June 29, 2023. During the trial, defense attorneys for several defendants raised questions about the close time between Pan Jianfeng’s game registration, cash withdrawal, and crime reporting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Game background data shows that Pan Jianfeng registered for the game at 15:15:56 on the day of the report. The screenshot of the withdrawal interface he provided showed that he withdrew the money at 15:49:17. In other words, he had just registered for the game 25 minutes before being questioned, and the time of withdrawal was only 43 seconds after being questioned. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for Pan Jianfeng, the defendant’s defense lawyer believed that there were contradictions in the time when witnesses Wang Kai, Qin Jun, and Chen Tao withdrew cash from the game and were interviewed by the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Kai, Qin Jun, and Chen Tao started at 10:25 on January 7, 2022, 12:10 on January 7, 2022, and 10:30 on January 10, 2022. Shiqiao Police Station for questioning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Kai said when questioned that he had recharged 54 yuan in the game and withdrawn 2 yuan; Qin Jun said he had recharged 36 yuan and withdrawn 2 yuan; Chen Tao also said he had recharged 36 yuan and withdrawn 2 yuan. 2 yuan. All three stated in the inquiry that they could provide screenshots of the withdrawal page. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, the lawyer pointed out that in the screenshots provided by the three people, the withdrawal times of Wang Kai and Qin Jun were both at 21:31 on January 8, while Chen Tao made the withdrawal at 13:27 on January 10. . In other words, their withdrawal time was later than the time when they were asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the above time issue raised by the lawyer, the prosecutor issued a statement from the Cangwu County Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This document explains that Pan Jianfeng first played games at home and reported the case to Shiqiao Police Station around 15:00 on January 2. He cashed out after an on-site operation demonstration. The police station accepted the case at 15:50. The defendant&#39;s defense lawyer also pointed out the issue with the timeline: Pan Jianfeng arrived at the police station around 3 p.m., so the game should have been registered at the police station. During the trial, the prosecution and defense debated this issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The situation statement also pointed out that when the case investigators produced the interrogation transcripts of Wang Kai and Qin Jun, they used the version of the transcripts dated January 7 and forgot to modify the interrogation time. The actual time was January 9; production When Chen Tao took notes, he was also &quot;slip and careless&quot; and wrote down the time of the inquiry incorrectly. The correct time was from 14:30 to 15:40 on January 10. According to this explanation, Chen Tao completed the withdrawal one hour before accepting the inquiry. . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Reversal of witness statement&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, witnesses Qin Jun and Chen Tao were later detained at the Cangwu County Detention Center on suspicion of provocation and were detained together with the defendants Zong Chao and Zhong Liuqing respectively. In a prison cell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both witnesses said that they completed the transcript under the arrangement of the public security agency staff, and even signed the transcript without reading the content. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, Zong Chao submitted a handwritten statement by Qin Jun, describing the process of reporting the case: At the end of 2021, his friend Wang Kai from the same town called him and asked him to take someone to the Shiqiao Police Station. Play a fishing game together. He took Pan Jianfeng to the police station. Wang Kai shared the game download link with them on WeChat, and then they registered, recharged and cashed out, then sent screenshots of the relevant game to the police, and signed and left after all was completed. He said that he had not been exposed to this game beforehand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chen Tao is detained in the same cell as Zhong Liuqing and other three defendants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, all three defendants submitted their own handwritten explanations. One defendant said that four days before the first trial, he received a subpoena in the prison cell. Chen Tao noticed the name of the game company on it and said, &quot;I think I reported it.&quot; The defendant asked Chen Tao why he reported it. Chen Tao&#39;s answer was, &quot;I haven&#39;t played it. I was just called to the police station to sign the transcript.&quot; He also said that he had not read the transcript. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the two men’s statements were reversed in the interviews recorded by the detention center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the record on May 15, 2023, Chen Tao said that after the court session at the end of March, Zhong Liuqing came to him and asked him to write a written certificate or testify in court to prove that he went to the public security organ to report online gambling. The situation is false and does not actively reflect the facts. He didn&#39;t agree because what he said before was true. After that, Zhong Liuqing wrote a written material and asked him to sign it, proposing that as long as he agreed to testify in court and overturned his previous record at the public security organ, he could be given 50,000 yuan, 100,000 yuan or even 500,000 yuan, but he did not agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qin Jun said in the conversation three days later that his statement of situation was &quot;written in a confused way&quot; and &quot;They spoke so artistically and literately, but I don&#39;t know why they were dismissed.&quot; Brainwashed.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first-instance judgment of the Cangwu County Court held that the testimonies of Pan Jianfeng, Qin Jun, Wang Kai, and Chen Tao were objective and true and relevant to the case, and they were recognized. The above-mentioned description of the situation and other materials provided by the defendant are inconsistent with the facts ascertained in the case and will not be accepted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Pan Jianfeng, Chen Tao, Qin Jun, and Wang Kai are all pseudonyms in the article)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江西检察机关依法对李东涉嫌受贿案提起公诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261675]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 15:04:50&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Reporters learned from the Supreme People’s Procuratorate today (1st) that former party members of the National Energy Investment Group Co., Ltd. The case of deputy general manager Li Dong suspected of accepting bribes was investigated and concluded by the National Supervisory Commission. After being designated by the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the case was reviewed and prosecuted by the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Yichun City, Jiangxi Province. Recently, the Yichun City People&#39;s Procuratorate has filed a public prosecution with the Yichun City Intermediate People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the review and prosecution stage, the procuratorial organ informed the defendant Li Dong of his litigation rights in accordance with the law, interrogated the defendant Li Dong, and listened to the opinions of the defender. The prosecution charged: The defendant Li Dong used his position as deputy secretary and manager of the party committee of Shenhua Zhungeer Coal Company, deputy secretary and chairman of the party committee of Shenhua Group Zhungeer Energy Co., Ltd., deputy chief engineer of Shenhua Group Co., Ltd., Shenhua Group Members of the party group and deputy general manager of a limited liability company, members of the party group and deputy general manager of China Energy Investment Group Co., Ltd., seeking benefits for others and illegally accepting property from others, if the amount is particularly huge, should be investigated for bribery according to law. criminal responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[数字金融榜：哪些银保机构更“智慧”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261671]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 14:35:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;No technology, no finance. my country&#39;s digital finance, which has always been at the forefront of its global counterparts, has ushered in a historic opportunity: not only has it stood at the forefront of the historical transformation of the AI ​​​​big model, but it has also ushered in the policy trend - the Central Financial Work Conference clearly requires five major articles such as digital finance to be done well. article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital finance has thus become the strategic frontier for competition among major financial institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Study by Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center found that the large models of domestic financial institutions have entered a &quot;battle of hundreds of models&quot; and have explored smart finance in different vertical fields. (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For details, please see the Southern Weekend App &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/261381&quot;>;Financial Industry&#39;100 The model war is in full swing, how to break through in compliance?&lt;/a>;&quot;&lt;/span>;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which banks have invested the most in technology? Which financial institution has more technology staff? Which financial institutions have already applied AI technology to financial practices? Which insurance company has smarter claims settlement? In order to objectively present the technological strength of various financial institutions, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center has set up indicator evaluation systems for 20 banks and 9 life insurance companies, and based on this, selected the bank financial digital list and the life insurance digital financial list. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bank ranking indicator system: six dimensions and eleven sub-indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to objectively present the competitiveness of 20 banks in financial technology, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center constructed a digital The quantitative and qualitative index evaluation system of the financial list mainly includes four dimensions: technology investment, digital banking, digital risk control and digital payment, and eleven secondary indicators, and gives different weights to each indicator based on the difference in importance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center assigned media factor weights to 20 banks based on a special survey, and invited an external expert jury to conduct an independent real-name assessment of the comprehensive competitiveness of the 20 banks in the field of digital finance. Review. Both scoring weights are 15% each. Among them, the media factor mainly refers to the openness and transparency of the financial institutions under investigation to media research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this basis, researchers from the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center constructed the 2023 banking industry &quot;digital financial list&quot; indicator system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator system of digital financial ranking bank ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /01/e7a07f5b05.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1767&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/e7a07f5b05.png &quot; data-key=&quot;260323&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Indicator system of bank ranking of digital finance ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now for banks The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the ranking index system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Technology investment refers to the degree of investment of financial and human resources by banks in digital finance, including R&amp;D and innovation investment, technical equipment investment and talent team building, etc. Invest. Technology investment reflects the bank’s emphasis on digital transformation and its investment strength. The total weight of the five secondary indicators is 38%, which is the dimension with the highest weight among the six dimensions. It also highlights the intensity and effectiveness of commercial banks’ “real money” investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital banking means that banks use information technology and digital technology to realize the digitization, automation and onlineization of business processes and provide more convenient and efficient financial services. Quantitative indicators of the development status of digital banks include the number of monthly active users of mobile banking, user reviews of mobile apps, etc. Relevant awards awarded by authoritative third-party organizations for bank digitalization can also be used as qualitative indicators of the bank&#39;s digital strength. The total weight of the above three sub-indicators is 16%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital risk control means that banks use big data, artificial intelligence, cloud computing, machine learning and other technical means to monitor and predict risks in real time and take corresponding risk management measures. Digital risk control can improve the accuracy and efficiency of risk management and reduce the risk of non-performing assets. Therefore, we select the non-performing loan ratio indicators and their changes reported by each bank as of the mid-term report of 2023 to reflect the actual effectiveness of digital risk control of each bank; at the same time, from the perspective of information disclosure, we disclose the “digital” or “digital” or The frequency of &quot;intelligent risk control&quot; is calculated to encourage commercial banks that disclose more proactively and adequately in digital risk control. The total weight of the above two sub-indicators is 10%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital payment means that banks realize the digitization and online payment methods through the application of mobile payment, electronic payment and virtual currency and other technical means. Digital payment can provide more convenient and secure payment methods and promote consumers&#39; consumption activities and financial transactions. We conduct a qualitative evaluation on whether each commercial bank has been included in the central bank&#39;s designated operating agency for digital payment. If included, the commercial bank will receive a 6% weight bonus. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Bank list: China Merchants Bank strives to take the top spot among state-owned banks and joint-stock banks&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The 2023 banking industry digital finance list shows: the comprehensive ratings of China Merchants Bank, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Ping An Bank in the field of digital finance. Ranked in the top three. But the more prominent phenomenon is that some joint-stock banks have overcome their disadvantages in scale and strength and are making great efforts in the field of digital finance and are showing initial results. Reflected in the list, China Merchants Bank and Ping An Bank both entered the top three, forming a situation in which they compete with large state-owned banks such as Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and Bank of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Digital Finance List Bank List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01 /39e97963a6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2275&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/39e97963a6.png&quot; data -key=&quot;260324&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Digital Finance List Bank List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, the four major state-owned banks It has always been a &quot;leader&quot; in technology investment. In 2022, ICBC, Agricultural Bank of China, China Construction Bank and Bank of China will all exceed the 20 billion mark in technology investment. Among them, ICBC invested the most, reaching 26.224 billion yuan. The number of scientific and technological talents in major banks is also significantly ahead of most joint-stock banks. Among them, ICBC has 35,000 scientific and technological personnel by the end of 2022, ranking first among all banks. Supported by a very large customer base, the average number of monthly active users on mobile terminals of the four major banks exceeds 90 million, which is almost five times the average of joint-stock banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are already followers or even surpassers in joint-stock banks. For example, China Merchants Bank and Ping An Bank, both headquartered in Shenzhen, are relatively disadvantaged in terms of scale and strength, but their investment in technology is not inferior at all, and they are even more &quot;heroic&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared in terms of absolute numbers, CMB has 10,800 technology talents, almost catching up with some major state-owned banks; from the perspective of proportion indicators, CMB’s technology investment will account for 4.51% of operating income in 2022, which is 1.65 higher than ICBC in the same period. percentage points; at the same time, the bank’s latest NPL ratio remains at 0.95%, which is significantly better than the average NPL ratio of the four major banks of 1.34%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, China Merchants Bank has been the most active commercial bank in technology investment since the &quot;Ma Weihua Era&quot;. On the one hand, from taking the lead in transforming retail banks to proposing a light banking strategy, from a mobile-first strategy to fully implementing digital transformation, they all relied on huge investments in technology that lasted for many years; on the other hand, the introduction of new financial technologies has strongly supported its business expansion and customer Improved experience. In particular, the bank&#39;s retail business advantages have been continuously consolidated and expanded, thereby promoting its industry-leading growth rate in terms of asset size, revenue, profit and other indicators for a long time. As a result, China Merchants Bank has become a benchmark bank on the digital finance list in the banking industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike China Merchants Bank, Ping An Bank has accumulated nearly 6,000 financial technology patents in the past five years, relying on the strong technological research and development capabilities of Ping An Group, ranking first in the banking industry. Ping An Bank has 9,000 scientific and technical personnel, second only to the four major banks and China Merchants Bank. However, scientific and technical personnel account for 10% of the bank&#39;s employees, far exceeding the average of the four major banks of 4.76%. Although it failed to enter the central bank&#39;s list of &quot;Designated Digital Payment Operators&quot;, Ping An Bank ultimately won third place with a clear advantage due to its comprehensive performance in technology investment, digital risk control, digital banking and other dimensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;BoCom’s high investment has not yielded high results&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Only from the evaluation results of qualitative and quantitative indicators, China Merchants Bank, Bank of Communications and ICBC all scored more than 50 points. Among them, Bank of Communications&#39; qualitative and quantitative scores surpassed ICBC and ranked second. Its technology investment accounted for 5.26% of revenue, ranking first among the 20 banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, compared with the top three banks in the comprehensive ranking, Bank of Communications has experienced a long-term sluggish growth rate in terms of scale, revenue and profit, and its non-performing rate has not significantly improved due to its conservative business strategy. This shows that its high proportion of technology investment has not significantly improved the bank&#39;s productivity and has not significantly improved the bank&#39;s business and financial performance. Meanwhile, outside judges gave the bank average marks. The bank&#39;s final score ranked only sixth. This may have something to do with its mediocre business performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to its short establishment, the scores in both technology investment and digital banking are the lowest among the six major state-owned banks. Therefore, the Postal Savings Bank ranked only 13th in the list. However, the bank is accelerating the &quot;digital ecological bank transformation&quot; and strives to explore transformation methods that are consistent with its own endowments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that in terms of digital risk control, the bank’s digital infrastructure and digital risk control system came into effect as soon as they were completed, and its score was second only to Bank of Communications among major banks. The bank&#39;s low non-performing loan ratio of 0.81% ranks second among 20 banks, only higher than Bank of Ningbo, and performs better. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Among the urban commercial banks with the fastest growth in technology investment among joint-stock banks, Bank of Shanghai is far ahead&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The overall digital financial competitiveness of joint-stock banks continues to improve, but the trend of differentiation is obvious&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of total investment in financial technology, joint-stock banks are not as good as state-owned banks, but they maintain a high growth rate in technology investment. In 2022, the investment amount of the six joint-stock banks that disclosed relevant data on financial technology investment increased by an average of 11.2% year-on-year, which was twice the average growth rate of major state-owned banks in the same period. Among them, Industrial Bank’s technology investment in 2022 will increase by nearly 30% year-on-year, ranking first in the industry in terms of growth rate. At the same time, the average proportion of technology investment in revenue of the nine joint-stock banks exceeds 4%, which is higher than the average level of 3.5% for state-owned banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;City commercial banks, which are in the third tier of commercial banks, have always been in a state of catching up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Limited by their own scale, the overall scale of technology investment of city commercial banks is not large, but the technology investment of a few city commercial banks is growing rapidly. Among them, Bank of Shanghai is the leader in digital reform of city commercial banks. Its technology investment in 2022 will be 2.132 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 15.06%, accounting for 4.18% of operating income. The Bank of Shanghai is not only far ahead among city commercial banks, but also not inferior among the 20 banks. It surpasses 6 joint-stock banks and 1 major state-owned bank, ranking among the top ten, ranking ninth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In general, although they are the best among more than 100 city commercial banks, the five city commercial banks are still limited by scale, strength and operating geographical area, and their competitiveness in the digital financial field cannot be compared with that of national banks. . If limited funds can be concentrated into a certain segment of financial technology, the five city commercial banks can still achieve good results in regional market competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Life insurance ranking indicator system: four-dimensional evaluation of eight secondary indicators&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to objectively present the digital competitiveness of the nine life insurance institutions, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center focused on digital capabilities and digital strategies Two dimensions are used to construct a quantitative and qualitative index evaluation system for the life insurance industry’s digital financial rankings. The weight of this item in the overall score is 70%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to the bank ranking indicator system, Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center assigned media factor weights to 9 life insurance institutions based on a special survey and invited an external expert jury to review the 9 life insurance institutions. The weight of the two scores is 15% each. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this basis, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center constructed an indicator system for the digital finance list of the insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The quantitative and qualitative indicators of the life insurance index system are explained as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital capabilities. This dimension refers to life insurance companies relying on digital technology to innovate and upgrade their business models in the entire chain, including product research and development, marketing, channel expansion, operations management, underwriting and claims payment, while also controlling costs more accurately and effectively in order to obtain more Profit margins. In view of the actual information disclosure of nine life insurance companies in terms of digital capabilities, Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center mainly examined comparable data such as the average claims timeliness of life insurance companies directly related to customers, the number of monthly active users of the App, and the version rating of the App. The total weight of the three indicators accounts for 45%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Digital strategy. This dimension means that in the process of promoting digital transformation, life insurance institutions make all-round adjustments and iterations in organizational structure, organizational culture, business models, business processes and technology applications, in order to form a top-level design that adapts to the development needs of life insurance business in the digital era as soon as possible. Since the degree of disclosure of digital strategies by life insurance companies is uneven, from a comparable perspective, the Southern Weekend New Finance Research Center chose to conduct quantitative statistics on the frequency of &quot;digitalization&quot; in regular reports to reflect life insurance institutions&#39; commitment to digital transformation from the perspective of information disclosure. Attention. At the same time, the Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center qualitatively analyzed the digitalization of 9 life insurance companies through four indicators: whether to disclose technology and patent data, whether to apply AI intelligent technology, whether there is any violation of user privacy, and whether to obtain third-party honors in digital technology. strength. The total weight of the above five indicators is 25%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicator system of life insurance ranking of digital finance list (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12 /01/82e671b259.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1487&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/82e671b259.png &quot; data-key=&quot;260325&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Indicator system of life insurance ranking of digital financial ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Insurance ranking : Ping An won the first place, followed by China Life and China Pacific Insurance Co., Ltd.&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The list of digital finance in the life insurance industry shows that Ping An Life has the highest score, with China Life and China Pacific Insurance ranking second and third respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Digital Finance List - Life Insurance List (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01 /2e32db32bb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1185&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/2e32db32bb.png&quot; data -key=&quot;260326&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Digital Financial Ranking - Life Insurance Ranking (Liang Shuyi, Liu Yuyu/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the competition of digital capabilities, China Life Insurance, AIA Life and Ping An Life are equally powerful, with scores between them. Ping An Life App ranks first in terms of average number of monthly active users, with 98% of users making claims online. China Life is even more outstanding in terms of average claims settlement timeliness. The ultra-high claims settlement timeliness of 0.39 days per order is an example of how digital technology has successfully reshaped the entire claims settlement process. As the only foreign-funded life insurance institution shortlisted for the evaluation, AIA Life’s App received the highest score, which shows that users highly recognize the life insurance App’s functionality, security, and operational convenience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the digital strategic dimension, Ping An Life mentioned “digitalization” as many as 40 times in its annual report, which is almost as many times as the combined number of mentions of CPIC Life and Sunshine Life, which followed closely behind. Its emphasis on digital transformation is evident. China Life does not score high in this dimension. One of the reasons is that it is conservative in the application of AI intelligence and its response speed lags behind its peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center found that digitalization has gradually become a key word for the strategic transformation of my country’s insurance industry. Almost all insurance institutions have established digital operations departments or information technology departments, and most of them mention their own &quot;digital transformation&quot; development strategies and digital transformation-related initiatives in their annual reports. Specific to life insurance institutions, the nine life insurance institutions evaluated this time have continued to increase investment in technology, among which China Pacific Life Insurance and PICC Life Insurance have established technology subsidiaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Overall, the life insurance industry still has a long way to go in digital financial transformation. Whether it is the &quot;Tao&quot; at the digital strategic level or the &quot;Technology&quot; of digital capability building, there is still huge room for development in the digitalization of life insurance companies. At the same time, in the face of the certainty of huge investments and the uncertainty of transformation results, life insurance companies face many risks and challenges in their digital transformation. The good news is that in some subdivisions and in certain business indicators of individual life insurance companies, the &quot;honey scent&quot; brewed by technological innovation can already be smelled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend New Financial Research Center believes that from the perspective of industry trends, the technological dividends brought by digital transformation will continue to lead the transformation of the life insurance industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一座湖南县城“利剑出鞘”：近八百公职人员进退公租房]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261658]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[吴秀波终究不是司马懿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261649]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the China Executive Information Disclosure Network, recently, the well-known actor Wu Xiubo and his name Horgos have not Both Culture Media Co., Ltd. have added information on the persons subject to execution, with the execution subject matter being approximately 466 million yuan, and the execution court is the Jiangsu Provincial High Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In response, Wu Xiubo posted responses on Weibo one after another. He exposed the chat records and evidence that one of the original investors of the film crew, General Manager of Jiangsu Huali Culture Media Co., Ltd. Jin, and Zhang, the producer of &quot;Army Master Sima Yi&quot; and deputy general manager of Jiangsu Huali, misappropriated the crew&#39;s funds, accusing him of misappropriating the crew&#39;s funds. The two &quot;fake investment but real misappropriation&quot; deliberately signed the supplementary agreement with a fake seal, and then set up a trap to deceive him, causing him to lose all his money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2015, Wu Xiubo established Fuji Culture, holding 99% of the shares and with a registered capital of 50 million yuan. Wu Xiubo, who is also the director and the leading actor, began to produce &quot;The Great Military Advisor Sima Yi&quot;. Jiangsu Huali is one of the major investors, accounting for 50% of the investment share. Zhang took the initiative to serve as the chief producer and served as the legal representative and general manager of Fuji Culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Phoenix.com’s financial analysis, during the cooperation period, Jin asked to divest because the investment amount was too large. Under Zhang’s operation, Jiangsu Huali signed an agreement with Fuji Culture to transfer 45% of the investment income rights. Transferred to Fuji Culture &quot;without premium&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2017, &quot;Army Master Sima Yi&quot; became an instant hit as soon as it was aired. The number of views once exceeded 7 billion, and its revenue was nearly 1 billion yuan. According to a post on the official Weibo &quot;TV Series Tiger Roar and Dragon Yin&quot;, after the show was confirmed to be profitable, Kim arranged for Horgoswari, which he actually controlled, to sign a &quot;global exclusive distribution agreement&quot; and &quot;information network dissemination agreement&quot; with Fuji Culture. Agency Distribution Agreement&quot;, stipulating that Horgoswari has the right to share half of the proceeds. The relevant agreement was signed by Jin asking Zhang to &quot;help&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2017, Jiangsu Huali demanded payment for the proceeds from the show, but learned that the proceeds from the broadcast of &quot;Sima Yi&quot; by Jiangsu Radio and Television Group did not go to Jiangsu Huali, but to another company. One investor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since October 2017, Jiangsu Huali and Horgos Huali have successively taken another investor and Fuji Culture to court. After investigation by the Yili City Public Security Bureau and court evidence collection, it was found that the official seal included in the previous agreement signed between Jiangsu Huali and Fuji Culture was privately forged by Zhang, the legal representative of Fuji Culture. Zhang was criminally detained for engraving an official seal privately and has not yet been released from prison. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case of Horgoswari suing Fuji Culture was brought to the Jiangsu High Court, and Fuji Culture lost the case. In November 2023, Wu Xiubo waited until the Supreme Court upheld the original judgment of the Jiangsu High Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, whether Wu Xiubo’s accusation is true or not remains to be officially investigated. But at the beginning, he agreed that Zhang would concurrently serve as the legal representative and general manager of Fuji Culture, which also allowed him to take the lead in daily operations. The investor sends someone to serve as the legal representative or general manager of the invested enterprise. Which side this person will take when it comes to conflicts of interest between the investor and the invested enterprise is a major issue related to the development of the enterprise. Wu Xiubo did not have sufficient professional knowledge and experience, and he also did not establish a complete supervision mechanism, such as hiring special personnel to effectively supervise Zhang&#39;s daily operations and investment decisions, which further amplified the risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This can&#39;t help but remind people of &quot;Sima Yi, the Great Military Advisor&quot;, which brought Wu Xiubo to the peak of his acting career, but suffered &quot;an unreasonable disaster&quot; as a result. In the vast sea of ​​history, Sima Yi is undoubtedly a very controversial figure. He led his army twice to successfully resist Zhuge Liang&#39;s Northern Expedition and expedition to pacify Liaodong, which laid the foundation for the subsequent unification of the Three Kingdoms. However, because of his monopoly of power, his son Sima Zhao was granted the title of King of Jin, ousting the royal family of Cao Wei, and his grandson Sima Yan became emperor, thus ending Cao Wei. Wu Xiubo successfully performed Sima Yi, making this role more full and vivid. Whether it is looking like an eagle or a wolf, or facing the respect and love of a troubled wife, Wu Xiubo has shown a high level of acting skills. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why Sima Yi became a powerful minister was inseparable from his wisdom and determination. It&#39;s a pity that Wu Xiubo brought Sima Yi to life, but that was just an artistic creation. In the more complex business world, Wu Xiubo did not have the decisiveness and insight to make a successful transition from an actor to a businessman. As a result, he reported being deceived by the joint efforts of Jin and Zhang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another major setback in Wu Xiubo’s life was his dispute with actress Chen Yulin. In September 2018, actress Chen Yulin posted on WeChat Moments that she had been in love with married actor Wu Xiubo for seven years, and also claimed that Wu Xiubo cheated on actress Zhang Zhixi at the same time. In January 2019, Chen Yulin&#39;s parents issued an open letter stating that after Chen Yulin exposed his relationship with Wu Xiubo, Wu Xiubo, his agent, and lawyer asked Chen Yulin to come forward to clarify and be willing to compensate financially. After the two parties reached an agreement, Chen Yulin went abroad to recuperate in peace. On November 4, 2018, Wu Xiubo took the initiative to let Chen Yulin return to China. The next day, Chen Yulin was arrested at the airport by Wu Xiubo on the pretext of &quot;exposing privacy and extorting money.&quot; Subsequently, Wu Xiubo issued a statement from his lawyer, stating that the content of Chen Yulin&#39;s parents&#39; open letter was untrue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Sina Entertainment’s report on February 18, 2021, the verdict in the case of Wu Xiubo being blackmailed by Chen Yulin was exposed. The verdict showed that Chen Yulin was sentenced to three years in prison and suspended for three years. Judging from the court&#39;s judgment, the fact that Chen Yulin blackmailed Wu Xiubo was established. Wu Xiubo was extorted over and over again, so he called the police because he couldn&#39;t bear it. After calling the police, he did not act harshly, otherwise it would not be a matter of probation. But Wu Xiubo&#39;s acting career also failed to recover. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly in the emotional entanglement with multiple women, Sima Yi, played by Wu Xiubo, knows how to hide his clumsiness and reveal his cleverness, and is soft-hearted towards the concubine Bai Lingjun given by Cao Pi and his wife Zhang Chunhua in the play. Respect the virtuous wife. But in reality, Wu was manipulated by Chen Yulin, ruining his reputation and losing money. It can be seen that the actor&#39;s performance is not equivalent to his behavior as a person. This may also be the illusion of many successful people, including celebrities. Acting as a person does not mean becoming that person; success in the acting career does not mean being able to be as good as a fish in water in other fields, but it exposes emotional intelligence, financial Shortcomings in business and other aspects eventually led to catastrophe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[查理·芒格的中国“朋友圈”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261665]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;In May 2023, Munger at his home in Los Angeles. Picture from &quot;The Munger Way&quot; &quot;A book by Hong Hai.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/b5db27ea16.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/12/01/b5db27ea16.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260319&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In May 2023, Munger was at his home in Los Angeles. The picture is from the book &quot;The Munger Way&quot;, photographed by Hong Hai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlie Munger was 99 years old. When the news came that he passed away in California, USA on November 28, 2023, people were not particularly surprised, but this will not reduce people’s memory of him. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Warren Buffett commented in the statement, &quot;Without Charlie&#39;s inspiration, wisdom and involvement, Berkshire Hathaway would not be able to reach its current position.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlie Munger is the vice chairman of Berkshire Hathaway and the most important partner of Warren Buffett for half a century. Their investment company has written a wealth myth-from 1965 to 2022, the compound annual rate of return is as high as 19.8%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But his departure will not have much impact on Berkshire Hathaway. Berkshire Hathaway has confirmed that 61-year-old Vice Chairman Greg Abel will succeed Buffett as CEO, and Buffett will become non-executive chairman. Day-to-day operations will be handled by Abel and Vice Chairman Geet Jain. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;When people miss Munger, what exactly are they missing? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since November 28, many tributes to Charlie Munger have appeared on Chinese social media. Many people mentioned each other&#39;s &quot;last face&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Duan Yongping, known as &quot;China&#39;s Buffett&quot;, posted on social media about &quot;the dinner we had at the same table after the shareholders&#39; meeting on April 30 last year.&quot; Ten billion private equity investor Lin Yuan recalled, &quot;I had a communication with Munger in 2018, which lasted about half an hour.&quot; Luo Jiaming, the fund manager of China Europe Fund, said, &quot;I never imagined that the first time I saw Charlie in Omaha this year would be the last time in my life.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actress Tian Pujun posted a photo with Munger for the second time, writing, &quot;Last month, I planned with my friends to go to LA (Los Angeles) to celebrate your 100th birthday in January. Forever.&quot; I miss that beautiful evening half a year ago...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger has always maintained close contacts with the Chinese investment community and is a staunch supporter of China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two months before his death, on October 30, Munger also said when recording the well-known American technology investment podcast &quot;Acquired&quot; that &quot;the prospects of China&#39;s economy in the next 20 years will be greater than that of almost any other large economy.&quot; Everyone needs to be in good health.” Munger is also optimistic about China&#39;s leading companies. Regarding the so-called &quot;China risk theory&quot; from the outside world, he bluntly said that he is &quot;willing to bear it&quot; and &quot;doesn&#39;t mind&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the Chinese companies that Charlie Munger has invested in, BYD is the only company to publicly express its condolences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;BYD&#39;s official Weibo wrote, &quot;We have sadly lost a mentor and friend.&quot; It commented that Munger is one of the greatest investors of our time and has set an immortal benchmark for the investment community. &quot;In 2008, we were fortunate to receive his recognition, and Berkshire Hathaway became an important shareholder of the company. This is the first time that the company has been recognized by a top international investment institution, which has injected strong confidence into our commitment to the new energy vehicle industry. and motivation.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to BYD, another Chinese company Charlie Munger holds is Alibaba. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of the third quarter of this year, Charlie Munger held 300,000 shares of Alibaba through the independently held &quot;Daily Journal&quot; company, with a market value of US$26.022 million, accounting for approximately 16.5% of the investment portfolio. &quot;Daily Journal&quot; holds a total of four stocks, and Alibaba is the only Chinese concept stock. However, Southern Weekend reporters checked Alibaba’s Weibo, WeChat public accounts and official website, and found no mention of Munger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, in February 2023, Munger said frankly, &quot;I think investing in Alibaba was one of the biggest mistakes I have ever made. I was fascinated by its leading position in China&#39;s Internet industry. But not realizing it&#39;s still a retailer, it&#39;s a competitive business...I overestimated Alibaba&#39;s future returns.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Is value investing suitable for A-shares?&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Value investing is the core value of Charlie Munger and Buffett. Munger&#39;s departure has once again sparked a discussion in the investment circle about whether value investing is suitable for A-shares. Many netizens have taken stock of A-share stocks that are known as value investments but have poor performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yuan, managing director of ZhenFund, said on social media, “In China, Munger exists not more as an investor, but as a conceptual thinker. His principles are not applicable to A-shares. It must be applicable, but the universal wisdom of life has inspired many people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Delong, executive general manager of Qianhai Kaiyuan Fund, is a firm supporter of value investment theory. When mourning Munger, he once again expressed his belief in value investment to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;Value investment is a common theory. The investment philosophy of the world is not only suitable for the U.S. stock market, but also for the A-share market.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his view, the current doubts about value investment are &quot;blind men touching the elephant&quot;, and &quot;the elephant must be seen from a distance&quot; Only in this way can we see, and we cannot generalize.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes, “In the past three years, the overall economy has been in decline, and the stock market has also experienced a bear market. If we only take this cross-section, it seems that value investors are also losing money, and they are no different from others. If we take 10 years, On a 20-year scale, the targets of value investment have increased many times.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also admitted that the Chinese market has its own characteristics. &quot;The value investment theory with Chinese characteristics means that we must not only adhere to Buffett&#39;s value investment theory, but also combine the ups and downs of the A-share market to make some appropriate positions.&quot; manage&quot;. When there is a bubble in the stock price, you dare to reduce or even short positions; when the stock price is undervalued, you dare to take advantage of dips. Controlling drawdowns through position management may be more suitable for the A-share market in the long run. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people attribute the failure of value investing in China to insufficient implementation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Zhang Ying, founding managing partner of Matrix Partners, felt, &quot;Looking through the circle of friends at the moment, I feel that 90% of the people are loyal followers of Mr. Munger.&quot; But what most people achieve in their own fields or personal investments is &quot;mediocre performance, and many even fail to achieve a positive cycle, and quite the opposite.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his opinion, the reason is very simple. Most people understand the underlying logic and core principles of Buffett and Munger at most literally. &quot;The possibility of persisting in doing it for a long time is almost zero.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Southern Weekend reporters found that when talking about Munger, more people would forward his philosophy of life and evaluate him as a wise man or a winner in life than when discussing investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As Wang Huan, chairman of Zige Investment, said, he represents the highest standards for investors: &quot;Wisdom, humor, humility, longevity, happiness, children and grandchildren...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dan Bin, a well-known private equity fund manager and chairman of Shenzhen Oriental Harbor Investment Management Co., Ltd., has reposted many condolence articles in WeChat Moments. He borrowed words from &quot;Banshan Collected Works&quot; to describe Munger, &quot;People have to be shocked by prosperity and moved by simplicity. The distance between these two experiences measures the width of a life.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;This is the guy I like&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the late 1970s, Charlie Munger became the number two man at Berkshire Hathaway, and since then Warren Buffett has become his name Fixed collocations before: &quot;Buffett&#39;s business partner&quot;, &quot;Buffett&#39;s closest friend&quot;, &quot;Buffett&#39;s most capable assistant&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the New York Times, Wall Street Journal, Washington Post, Bloomberg, and Reuters, the most influential media in the world, all reported the death of Charlie Munger without exception. Put Buffett in the title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buffett is always the protagonist in the crowd, and &quot;Don&#39;t be jealous&quot; is one of Charlie&#39;s life advices. &quot;Jealousy is a very stupid sin, because it is the only one you can never get from.&quot; The Sin of Having Fun.” Forbes values ​​Munger&#39;s wealth at $2.6 billion, while Buffett&#39;s wealth exceeds $100 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I don’t mind playing second fiddle to Warren at all,” Charlie Munger said in an interview with the New York Times. “Normally, wherever I go, I dominate. But I&#39;m willing to play second fiddle when other people are better. It&#39;s just that I&#39;ve rarely been in that position, except with Warren.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They may be the most memorable in the history of human investing. A golden pair. The seeds of this were laid when Munger was still a child. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Charlie Munger, who was born in 1924, experienced the economic crisis as a child and had to work in Buffett&#39;s grandfather&#39;s grocery store, earning 20 cents an hour. But it wasn&#39;t until 1959 that the two really met, and it can be said that they &quot;hit it off&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buffett later recalled, &quot;He was rolling on the floor laughing, and I thought, &#39;This is the person I like,&#39; and I did the same thing.&quot; The same was true for Munger. His wife once asked him, &quot;You Why are you paying so much attention to him?&quot; Munger replied, &quot;You don&#39;t understand, that&#39;s not an ordinary person.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The friendship between the two continues to this day. The iconic scene of this tacit understanding is that at the shareholders&#39; meeting, Munger always responded with a deadpan expression, &quot;I have nothing to add.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger deliberately gave the stage to Buffett, who is actually very talkative. The Wall Street Journal reported that he would speak for hours at the annual meeting of the Daily Journal, a small media company where he serves as chairman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If he paused to take a sip of water while someone else began to speak, Munger would haughtily raise his index finger to prevent the other speaker from interjecting before he could swallow the water in his mouth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, he is also a famous &quot;master of golden sentences.&quot; Whether on Weibo, Twitter or Facebook, his wise words can be seen everywhere. Buffett never published a book, but Charlie Munger left many writings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Buffett said in 1988, &quot;I was hugely influenced by Charlie. God, I would be a lot poorer if I just listened to Benjamin Graham.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mang Gerard&#39;s biggest influence on Buffett was to stop him from picking up the &quot;butt of cigars.&quot; Both regard Benjamin Graham as a mentor, but the difference is that Buffett will buy any business, even if it is dying, as long as the price is low. Berkshire Hathaway was once a textile factory on the verge of bankruptcy, also known as the legendary &quot;butt of cigars.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Munger spent many years persuading Buffett to focus more on excellent companies with acceptable prices. The income generated by these companies in the future will far exceed the premium paid today. The most famous example is See&#39;s Candies, a business originally sold for $25 million that brought Buffett and Munger nearly $1 billion in after-tax profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 21, 2023, just a week before Munger&#39;s death, Buffett donated approximately US$870 million worth of Berkshire Hathaway shares to four family charities. He also issued a rare letter to shareholders, recommitting that more than 99% of his wealth will be donated to charity, and his children will be the executors of his will. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also stated in the letter, &quot;I am 93 years old and feel very good, but I am fully aware that I am playing overtime.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:25:12 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[雪山脚下的高原第一镇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261653]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/29/no0ytFNX3YjL4Zhy9pNOsJBeiQLmFi30Rl6LgaZ2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/no0ytFNX3YjL4Zhy9pNOsJBeiQLmFi30R l6LgaZ2. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260023&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In the evening, residents of Parry Town came for a walk on the hillside&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It took a day&#39;s bus ride from Shigatse to Yadong County on the border of southern Tibet. The scenery I experienced on the road was ever-changing. It was both Tibet and Inner Mongolia. Finally, like Yunnan, Yadong County is known as &quot;Tibet&#39;s Little Jiangnan&quot;. Yadong County is located at the junction of China, India, and Bhutan. It is located at the southern foot of the middle section of the Himalayas. It is only 2,700 meters above sea level. The air is humid and the vegetation is very lush. The deeper you go, the more you feel like you are in a virgin forest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Yadong&quot; in Tibetan means &quot;whirlpool&quot; or &quot;deep valley of rapids&quot;. As its name suggests, Yadong County is located in a ravine, and the Yadong River surges along the county. As a border county, Yadong used to be a trade channel between China and India. I wanted to visit the border during this trip, and Yadong, with its unique location, became my first choice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“When traveling to Yadong, you must take the government’s tourist bus.” Before departure, the owner of the B&amp;B in Shigatse reminded me this, which made me, who is used to traveling independently, even more curious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/XdzvjF4pyO0UTZkhW2UYQN25VIJedB4W5BVV606I.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/XdzvjF4pyO0UTZkhW2UYQN25VIJedB4W5BVV606I.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260021&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Dromulari Snow Mountain near Pali Town&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Arrived at the local area, the mystery is gradually revealed. In May this year, the local government wanted to develop tourism and opened a tourist line to take tourists to Nathula National Gate and other scenic spots for free. Visitors only need to reserve seats in advance and purchase travel insurance of 1.5 yuan at their own expense. I added the staff on WeChat, sent my ID number and name, made an appointment for the next day’s trip, and purchased insurance at the hotel’s service desk. In Yadong, every hotel will provide government tour buses and purchase insurance information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early the next morning, I set out for the bus boarding point. The county town is very small, and it takes less than half an hour to walk around. All four tourist buses were full, and each bus had a local tour guide. Our tour guide was a young Tibetan man with a cheerful personality. I learned in the subsequent chat that he is a local. He finished college in Lhasa, served as a soldier for two years, and is now back as a tour guide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first stop is Nathu La National Gate located at the junction of China and India. The tourist bus drove for more than half an hour, spiraling along the mountain road and arriving at an altitude of 4,300 meters. Nathu La Port is the highest road trade channel in the world. Currently, only government sightseeing vehicles can drive to the Nathu La National Gate, and private vehicles are prohibited from passing through. Taking pictures is also not allowed. The tour guide took away our mobile phones and ID cards for centralized management. After getting off the bus, tourists lined up in front of the country gate, and the tour guide took photos of everyone with their mobile phones. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/uPXYTeAtbeud0Qnzz4iRYPq9eo48XohRTmniPiBG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/uPXYTeAtbeud0Qnzz4iRYPq9eo48XohRTmniPiBG.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260024&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The old Tibetan man herding cattle introduced me to the history of Pali Town&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;I didn’t want to queue, so I walked into the &quot;International Mail Center&quot; near the country gate. This is an observatory where you can watch India on the opposite side. As I climbed up to the second floor, I saw some tourists who were panting and unable to walk, and some were holding oxygen tanks and breathing oxygen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Standing on the second floor, you can see the Indian National Gate opposite, which is less than 20 meters away. Several Indian soldiers are patrolling, and the surrounding bare mountains are dotted with Chinese and Indian bunkers. The young soldiers stationed in Nathu La told us that in July the mountains here are covered with thick white snow and red azaleas. He also said that tourists from India also come for sightseeing every day. They usually show up around 1 p.m. and stand on the observation deck opposite to watch China. At this time, a wild horse and a wild dog came down from the mountain opposite, causing people to make a noise. &quot;Is this from China or India?&quot; someone asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I would not be able to reach these places by myself without a car. Tibet has huge mountains, and the sightseeing tour ended at 4 pm. The car spent two-thirds of the time traveling through the mountains. In addition to the Nathu La National Gate, we also visited the Kagyu Monastery, the border well-off village, Linhai Waterfall, etc. until we arrived. The end of the border between China, India and Bhutan. Along the way, the Yadong River also followed us, rushing forward along the road, and finally disappeared at the border of the three countries, entering India and Bhutan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the few days I arrived, roads were being built everywhere in Yadong County, and the roadbeds in front and behind the hotel were dug up. I didn’t stay long and decided to go to Pali Town, which is under the jurisdiction of the county. Compared with Yadong County, Pali Town makes me yearn for it more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pali Town is known as the &quot;highest town in the world&quot;, and &quot;Pali&quot; means &quot;rotating mountains&quot; in Tibetan. It was once an important trading town in Tibet. When Yadong County was still a small village, the streets of Pali Town were already filled with caravan merchants and Khampa people from India, Nepal, and Bhutan. Hundreds of years ago, escaped serfs, missionary believers, and traders came to Pali grassland to seek life. Immigration drove the development of Pali. When the Yadong Port was closed in the 1960s (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Editor&#39;s note: it was reopened many years later with the improvement of Sino-Indian relations&lt;/span>;), commercial activities began decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nzbnjAjoWOUn4OY2jnzLV7BM597aPDz2hG7c5y9n.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/29/nzbnjAjoWOUn4OY2jnzLV7BM597aPDz2hG7c5y9n.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260025&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The remaining wall of the old house in Parry Town&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Wei/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pali Town is only an hour&#39;s drive from Yadong County, but it is more than 4,300 meters above sea level and has a completely different climate from Yadong County. Pali Town is located in the vast Pali grassland. Not far away is the beautiful Zhuomulari Snow Mountain, so close that you can reach out and touch it. Around the highway, two-story residential buildings are neatly arranged. During the season when I arrived, golden rapeseed flowers and green grasslands spread out in layers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People who come to Pali Town are usually tourists passing through Yadong County. As soon as I got off the car, I was attracted by this quiet town. Walking through the small alleys, you can appreciate the strong atmosphere of life, Tibetan-style buildings built of stone, neatly placed cow dung on the courtyard walls, and bright window frames painted in red, green and blue. It only takes ten minutes to walk from the town to the grassland, and you will meet almost no people. You can only see a sheep herder and a man drying cow dung in the distance. There are only three hotels in the town, all run by Tibetans. Most of the rooms have no bathrooms. I chose the cheapest single room, and I could directly see the snow-capped mountains from the room window. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, most of the houses in Pali Town are newly built. I only encountered an old dilapidated house on the slope behind the town. The house was overgrown with weeds and half of the wall collapsed. A local old man saw that I was very interested in old houses and showed me old photos on his mobile phone. He also took me to visit several old houses. One of them had &quot;1958&quot; vaguely engraved on the old stone wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“大气”成为评测的关键词？消费者购车不能只看颜值]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261530]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On social media, some people questioned the interior layout design of a certain brand of new car because the platform in front of the co-pilot It is designed as a storage table. However, the concept of vehicle safety has always been that other items cannot be placed on the center console because the airbag is underneath. Sufficient space must be left for the airbag to explode in the event of a traffic accident, otherwise it will cause damage to the vehicle. Secondary injury to personnel inside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, there are many such designs for electric vehicles. For example, car door handles must be highly reliable and can be opened under any circumstances. Mechanical ones are best, but now many cars use built-in door handles, and even electric ones. Once the car enters water, it loses power. , the car door cannot be opened from the outside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This phenomenon of over-innovation, or neglecting safety for the sake of innovation, is to some extent because China’s automobile consumer market is not mature enough. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Car consumption requires certain professional knowledge. Cars are the crystallization of human technology and engineering. Each car has many parts that are precisely integrated together, and its operation involves a lot of professional knowledge. Every system and every component of the car has its specific function and role. The engine outputs power, which determines the power and performance of the car; the chassis is the skeleton of the car, which determines the car&#39;s handling and comfort; and the braking system, fuel system, cooling system, etc. ensure the normal operation of the car. These systems and components are interrelated and cooperate with each other to allow the car to operate normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industrial products have various parameters and technical characteristics. Cars are almost the most parameter-based things that ordinary people have access to. Understanding these parameters and performance can help consumers choose a car that suits them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Parameters such as engine capacity, power, torque, fuel consumption, suspension type, braking performance, tire specifications, etc., all directly affect the driving experience and driving safety. For ordinary consumers, if they want to buy a car that suits them, they need to learn and master certain professional knowledge, such as understanding the difference between three-link and five-link, which one is safer, disc brake or drum brake, electric vehicle There are also differences between lithium iron phosphate and ternary lithium batteries. This requires constant online searching and reading, which is too difficult a task for most people. On the one hand, this requires a certain cultural level to digest this knowledge; on the other hand, it requires a lot of time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are a lot of technical arguments under various car review videos on the Internet, but to some extent this is just an illusion. It is just people who understand technology gather under specific videos. Most people do not know how to do it. Get involved in this debate. They will say that such-and-such car has been reduced in price again, who will buy such a car, but they do not know that most Chinese consumers will not care about this at all. They are a minority among consumers and are not important to manufacturers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When consumers do not understand the technical parameters, manufacturers can attract consumers through things they can understand and guide them to see what to see or ignore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In today&#39;s automobile market, many consumers tend to focus on the appearance, interior and intelligent systems of the car when buying a car, while ignoring the basic functions of the car, that is, the Ride, safety and handling performance. This phenomenon reflects to some extent modern people’s expectations and values ​​for cars, and also reveals certain problems in the automotive industry’s ability to meet consumer needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Consumers are understandably concerned about the exterior and interior of their cars. China has just entered the era of automobile popularization. Cars are still very expensive and still have a strong identity function. Therefore, the appearance and interior design of cars have an important impact on consumers&#39; purchasing decisions. Chinese consumers often like to use the word &quot;daqi&quot; when evaluating cars, so that foreign car designers all know the word &quot;daqi&quot;. Without translation, they can understand a series of connotations it represents: majestic, huge, solemn, Have a face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When consumers like it, manufacturers will naturally make the interior and exterior of the car more luxurious. At the same time, the current development of information technology has indeed continuously improved the information technology content of cars. Automobile manufacturers are also constantly introducing various innovative design elements to meet consumers&#39; needs for freshness and personalization. This kind of innovation even reaches the level of innovation for the sake of innovation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, consumers are often confused by the gorgeous appearance and advanced technology of the vehicle. They pay too much attention to the appearance, interior and intelligent systems of the car, and are attracted by the big sofa and big screen, but ignore it. The core values ​​of a car: performance in driving, safety and handling, which are directly related to consumers’ driving experience and driving safety. The total cost of a car is limited. If the cost is spent on visible places, you will naturally save money on invisible places. Since consumers don&#39;t pay attention to it, manufacturers will save money in this aspect and turn to making their cars more flashy, but in the end they will bury various hidden dangers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, when consumers buy a car, they should learn some professional knowledge and consider more comprehensively the weight between the car&#39;s functions, performance, appearance, and interior. They should not just focus on the appearance, interior, and intelligent systems. aspects and ignore the basic functions of the car. At the same time, automobile manufacturers also have the obligation to guide consumers correctly. While meeting consumer needs, we also guide consumers to choose a car that suits them more rationally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public opinion competition among manufacturers is an important way for consumers to become more professional. Competitors are all professionals and understand the unspoken rules and various shady secrets in the industry. Therefore, supervision from within the industry is often more targeted at the crux of the problem. This kind of industry supervision has spread from the technical level to the communication level, and the most important way to let consumers know is through advertising and marketing. Regardless of the rights and wrongs involved, discussing technical issues in public opinion is itself a process of popularizing science and a way to encourage consumers to learn professional knowledge and gradually distinguish the rights and wrongs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[假身份、假公章、假协议，吴秀波踩入了多深的坑？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261657]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-12-01 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Stills of &quot;The Great Military Advisor Sima Yi&quot;.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/11/30/96f07b79ac.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;691&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/30/96f07b79ac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;260297&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from &quot;Army Division Sima Yi&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 24, 2023, the news that &quot;Wu Xiubo and his company were expropriated for 466 million yuan&quot; became a hot search topic, and actor Wu Xiubo, who had been out of the spotlight for three years, returned to the public eye again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Qichacha shows that Wu Xiubo and his 99%-owned Horgos Fuji Culture Media Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Fuji Company) have previously added a piece of information to be executed, and the execution target is 4.66 More than 100 million yuan, the execution party is the Higher People&#39;s Court of Jiangsu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That night, Wu Xiubo posted two short videos on his personal Weibo, and the next day forwarded a long post on the official Weibo of the TV series &quot;Tiger Roars and Dragons Roar&quot;, detailing the TV series &quot;Army Master Sima Yi&quot; There were disputes during the production process, and it was said that &quot;two scammers with a lot of cases behind them used fake seals and contracts to set up a situation and caused bankruptcy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xiubo, 55, was once a late bloomer in the film and television industry. He once said that he had done many businesses after graduating from the Central Academy of Drama, including opening karaoke bars, restaurants, and making film and television soundtracks. It wasn&#39;t until the TV series &quot;Before Dawn&quot; was aired in 2010 that Wu Xiubo got his first taste of popularity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xiubo is obviously not satisfied with simply being an actor. After becoming famous, he frequently participated in the production and distribution of film and television dramas, and &quot;Army Master Sima Yi&quot; is one of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The drama is divided into two parts. The first part, &quot;Military Advisor Alliance&quot;, was broadcast on Jiangsu Satellite TV, Anhui Satellite TV, and Youku Video in June 2017, and achieved great success. With over 6 billion views and a Douban score of 8.2, it was one of the hottest dramas in 2017 and won the Feitian Award for Outstanding TV Drama that year. &quot;Tiger Roars and Dragon Roar&quot; is the second part. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, due to disputes over the distribution of interests, the three investors of the film launched a series of civil lawsuits against each other and were also involved in a criminal case. Another listed company suffered a decline in performance and was eventually delisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What kind of &quot;confusion&quot; is behind the popular TV series? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Key people hold decision-making positions in three companies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In October 2017, the popularity of the first part of &quot;Army Master Sima Yi&quot; has not subsided. The investor of the film, Jiangsu Huali Culture Media Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Huali Company) took another investor Dongyang Mengjiangwei Film and Television Culture Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Mengjiangwei Company) to court on the grounds that it failed to distribute income as agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The case was heard in public at the Hanjiang People’s Court of Yangzhou, Jiangsu Province on June 11, 2018, and the employer-employee dispute has since surfaced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fuer Company once stated in a statement that in 2013, company shareholder Wu Xiubo suggested the &quot;Sima Yi&quot; theme to Zhang Jian, then deputy general manager of Huali Company, and introduced Mengjiangwei Company Participate in project investment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That year, Wu Xiubo was filming &quot;Ma Xiangyang Goes to the Countryside&quot; directed by Zhang Yongxin. Zhang Yongxin once recalled in an exclusive interview that at that time Wu Xiubo was trying to find a director for the Sima Yi-themed TV series he was planning to shoot. The two were both history buffs. Their similar historical outlook and aesthetic taste made Wu Xiubo throw an &quot;hydrangea ball&quot; to Zhang Yongxin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the referee document, on July 27, 2014, Huali Company and Zhang Yongxin signed a director employment contract, Huali Company affixed the company’s administrative seal, and Zhang Jian signed as the company representative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearly 20 days ago, Huali Company also signed the well-known screenwriter Zheng Wanlong to write the script of &quot;Army Master Sima Yi&quot;. The latter has participated in the scriptwriting of &quot;Iron Teeth and Bronze Teeth Ji Xiaolan&quot; and other dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huali Company is a newbie in the film and television industry, and the boss behind it is mainly engaged in real estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qichacha shows that Jin Hongxing, the actual controller of Huali Company, holds 42.38% of the shares of Jiangsu Huali Real Estate Group Co., Ltd. and once served as the latter’s executive director and general manager. The group was established in 2000 and is a long-established real estate company in Yangzhou. It has many projects in the local area and has won the title of &quot;Outstanding Real Estate Enterprise in Yangzhou City&quot; for five consecutive years from 2006 to 2010. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, another investor brought by Wu Xiubo, Mengjiangwei Company, has rich experience. The latter has participated in the production of popular dramas such as &quot;The New Four&quot; and &quot;Jingzhong Yue Fei&quot;. In April 2014, Mengjiangwei Company was acquired by the listed company Contemporary Oriental (delisted) for 1.1 billion yuan, a premium of 12 times. Contemporary Oriental made a fixed increase of 1.998 billion yuan for this purpose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On December 14, 2015, Huali Company and Mengjiangwei Company signed a joint investment contract, which mainly agreed that the former would be the producer of the series, and the latter would be exclusively responsible for the global distribution of the series, with a total investment of 150 million. Yuan, each party invests 50%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next day, Huali Company signed an agreement with Fuji Company, entrusting the latter to film and produce the play. Huali Company was only responsible for investment, and both parties jointly appointed Zhang Jian as the producer of the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Fuji Company was established less than three months ago. Wu Xiubo, the actual controller, held 99% of the shares, and Zhang Jian served as the legal representative of the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, Zhang Jian plays three roles in this drama project. He is the deputy general manager of the drama&#39;s management, the legal representative of the production company, and the producer of the film and television project. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the increase in cast and crew remuneration, the budget of the play has increased to 220 million yuan. Huali Company and Mengjiangwei Company signed a supplementary agreement a month later, each investing a further 35 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In February 2016, the filming of &quot;Sima Yi&quot;, which had been in preparation for nearly three years, finally started in Hengdian. During the period, the broadcast platforms Jiangsu Radio and Television and Youku were also locked in advance, and Mengjiangwei Company was responsible for distribution matters according to the agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mengjiangwei Company first sold the series to Jiangsu Radio and Television Group for a total price of 200.8 million yuan and broadcast it within the agreed period. Youku also later paid 108 million yuan to Mengjiangwei Company for the online issuance of &quot;Military Division Alliance&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of September 2017, more than two months after &quot;Military Alliance&quot; had finished airing, Huali Company sent a reminder letter to Mengjiangwei Company and its parent company, Contemporary Oriental, demanding proceeds from the issuance. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Forged official seal and mutual non-recognition agreement&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Mengjiangwei Company seems to be confused by Huali Company’s request. The former said that both parties and Fuji Company also signed a &quot;Supplementary Agreement&quot; II&quot; and &quot;Supplementary Agreement III&quot;, renegotiating the revenue sharing method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above two agreements, the budget of the film has been increased to 360 million yuan, and neither Huali Company nor Mengjiangwei Company will make additional investment. Huali Company discounted the cost of its script for 5% of the investment budget, and transferred the remaining 45% of the investment rights and corresponding rights to Fuji Company. At that time, Mengjiangwei Company had received an investment of 100.25 million yuan, so it also transferred the unpaid investment rights and corresponding rights and interests to Fuji Company. Jiangsu Radio and Television&#39;s distribution income goes to Mengjiangwei Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Xiubo also expressed his approval of these two agreements. However, these agreements only bear the contract seals of the three companies. The column for Huali Company’s signature representative is blank. Zhang Jian signed the third supplementary agreement as a representative of Fuji Company. The signing date is only printed. &quot;2016&quot;, the specific month and day are also blank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fuer Company also provided a copy of the agreement between Huali Company and Horgos Premiere Times Film and Television Culture Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Premiere Times), stating that Huali Company will 5% of the investment share was sold to Premiere Times at a price of 20 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the above agreement, Huali Company will no longer have the investment rights and corresponding rights and interests in the film. However, Huali Company not only did not recognize the above-mentioned agreement, but also issued two contracts with contradictory contents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On June 5th and 6th, 2017, Horgos Huali Company, a subsidiary of Huali Company, and Fuji Company signed the &quot;Global Exclusive Agency Distribution Agreement for TV Series&quot; and &quot;TV Series Information Network Dissemination Agreement&quot; &quot;Agency Distribution Agreement&quot; mainly stipulates that all the distribution income of the drama series will go into the account of Fuji Company, and then be divided in half by Fuji Company and Huali Company. The distribution income of the co-investor Mengjiangwei Company will be handled by Fuji Company. Jin Hongxing represented Huali Company, and Zhang Jian signed the contract on behalf of Fuji Company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just a few days ago, on May 31, 2017, Fuji Company just signed a contract with Youku. The former granted the rights to network dissemination of the drama’s information and its sublicensing rights to the latter. The total price was tentatively determined. is 600 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Jin Hongxing also alleged that in the two supplementary agreements proposed by Mengjiangwei Company, the seals of Huali Company were forged by others, which involved another criminal case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One month after Huali Company sued Mengjiangwei Company, on November 8, 2017, the Yili Prefecture Public Security Bureau decided to investigate Zhang Jian on suspicion of official embezzlement and misappropriation of funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jian stated in the interrogation transcript that his appointment as the legal representative of Fuji Company was approved by Jin Hongxing. The two supplementary agreements mentioned above and the agreement with Premiere Times contained the special contract seal of Huali Company. , also carved under the instruction of Jin Hongxing. Jin Hongxing denied this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Jian’s criminal verdict showed that Zhang Jian illegally took 21.768 million yuan of Fuji Company’s property as his own. The amount was huge, constituting the crime of job embezzlement, and he was sentenced to seven years in prison until June 2025. Ending on 2nd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The court also found that although Huali Company signed a memorandum with Zhang Jian in April 2014, stating that it would establish a Beijing branch of Huali Company and hire Zhang Jian as the general manager of the company, Huali Company The Beijing branch has not been registered yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This means that Zhang Jian, who was deeply involved in the entire production process of the show and was regarded by Wu Xiubo and Mengwei Company as the representative of Huali Company, has never actually obtained legal status. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Zhang Jian&#39;s identity, only his criminal verdict states that he was &quot;born in Linkou County, Heilongjiang Province on August 10, 1968.&quot; How he is involved in this huge TV series is still unknown. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the lawsuit brought by Huali Company against Mengjiangwei, the Yangzhou Intermediate People&#39;s Court upheld the original judgment at the second instance and supported Huali Company&#39;s claim for 50% of the issuance income. Since then, Huali Company, Mengjiangwei Company and Wu Xiubo-controlled Fujian Company have launched multiple serial lawsuits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A long post on Weibo forwarded by Wu Xiubo stated that Horgos Huali Company’s case against Fuji Company was brought to the Jiangsu Provincial High Court. The latter lost the case and had to pay 50% of the issuance income to the former. And a liquidated damages of four times the bank interest rate, totaling about 500 million yuan. In November 2023, the Supreme People&#39;s Court made a ruling upholding the Jiangsu High Court&#39;s judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fuer Company has repeatedly raised jurisdictional objections in its related cases with Mengjiangwei Company, Huali Company and Horgos Huali Company, hoping that the cases would be heard by the courts in Beijing , however they failed to achieve success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second half of 2016, before &quot;Sima Yi, the Great Military Advisor&quot; was completed, legal cases began to break out intensively in the two real estate companies held by Jin Hongxing. According to Qichacha, Jiangsu Huali Real Estate Group Co., Ltd. is currently carrying 137 judicial cases, with a total execution amount of approximately 352 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Around 2021, several property market self-media posts in Yangzhou stated that the delivery of the Yangzhou Zhigu Huafu project had been delayed for several years, the owners were unable to apply for real estate certificates, and the Canal Villa project was suspected of being suspended and unfinished. Both properties are developed by Huali Real Estate Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Ali auction information, on November 17, 2020, a 92.72-square-meter residence in Yangzhou Shangri-La Manor was successfully traded for 1.76 million yuan. The owner is Jin Hongxing, the major shareholder of the developer Huali Real Estate Group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qichacha shows that Jin Hongxing is currently &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; restricted from high consumption and is subject to execution. &lt;/span>; The total amount of execution is about 209.6 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Affected listed companies&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;When it acquired Mengjiangwei Company in 2014, Contemporary Oriental not only increased its working capital by 500 million yuan, but also attracted many celebrity investors to participate in the decision-making process. Zeng, Wu Xiubo is one of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Contemporary Oriental’s announcement shows that in the above-mentioned fixed increase, Southern Capital Management Co., Ltd. subscribed for approximately 550 million yuan, including 15 million yuan subscribed by Wu Xiubo. Fashion Starlight (Beijing) Culture Media Co., Ltd., a subsidiary of Fashion Group, and Its then president, Su Mang, subscribed for 10 million yuan and 5 million yuan respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jiaxuan, the actual controller of Mengjiangwei Company at the time, and two shareholders also signed a gambling agreement with Contemporary Oriental, promising that the net profit of Mengjiangwei Company from 2014 to 2016 would not be less than 100 million each. yuan, 135 million yuan and 200 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mengjiangwei Company also delivered the goods as promised. From 2014 to 2016, Mengjiangwei achieved net profits of 109 million yuan, 141 million yuan and 211 million yuan respectively. Mengjiangwei Company is undoubtedly the biggest performance supporter of Contemporary Oriental. As a reference, the net profit attributable to the parent company of Contemporary Oriental in the same period was 177 million yuan, 111 million yuan and -556,200 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After realizing the bet, Xu Jiaxuan left Contemporary Oriental on July 25, 2017, and the company’s performance immediately changed. Contemporary Oriental&#39;s net profit attributable to shareholders decreased by 38.20% year-on-year that year, and by 1559.79% year-on-year in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Contemporary Oriental responded to inquiries from the Shenzhen Stock Exchange in 2019, stating that the departure of core team members led by Xu Jiaxuan had a certain impact on Mengjiangwei’s business, causing its revenue and profits to decline in 2017. On the other hand, affected by the negative public opinion of film and television actors, Mengjiangwei&#39;s performance in 2018 declined sharply and suffered losses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 4, 2022, Contemporary Oriental was delisted by the Shenzhen Stock Exchange and delisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One month ago, Southern Capital liquidated its shares of Contemporary Oriental at a transfer price of 0.27 yuan/share, while the price when Wu Xiubo and others subscribed was 10.8 yuan/share. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The total clearance transfer price of Southern Capital is 25.3633 million yuan. Southern Capital also reduced its holdings of 7.9138 million shares at a price of 6.358 yuan per share in December 2019, cashing out 50.3159 million yuan. In total, Southern Capital recovered only 75.68 million yuan in Contemporary Oriental stocks, a loss of 86%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another listed company affected by &quot;Sima Yi&quot; is Great Wall Film and Television. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2016, Great Wall Film and Television issued a trading suspension announcement regarding the planning of a major asset restructuring, stating that it planned to acquire Beijing Premiere Times Culture Media Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Great Wall Film and Television responded to inquiries from the Shenzhen Stock Exchange that year, it stated that Horgos Premiere Times, a subsidiary of the company it planned to acquire, had signed a contract to receive Huali Company’s 5% investment share in &quot;The Great Military Division Sima Yi&quot;. The investment amount is 20 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Great Wall Film and Television disclosed more details of its agreement with Huali Company in 2018 in response to inquiries from the China Securities Regulatory Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On April 25, 2016, the two parties signed a contract and stipulated that Jiangsu Huali would ensure that Premiere Times’ net return on investment in the play would not be less than 70%, and the excess would be shared by Jiangsu Huali and Premiere Times. Share according to the ratio of 60% and 40%. On May 6, the two parties signed a supplementary agreement to adjust the ratio to 70% and 30%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above announcement shows that the drama was broadcast in June 2017. Due to subsequent differences between the investors during the execution of the contract, due to the principle of caution during the premiere, no actual investment in the TV drama &quot; Military Advisor Alliance&quot; to confirm revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Great Wall Film and Television subsequently terminated its acquisition of Beijing Premiere Times. On May 7, 2021, Great Wall Film and Television was delisted and delisted by the Shenzhen Stock Exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, Wu Xiubo is still the fourth largest circulating shareholder of the listed company Xingfu Blue Ocean (300528.SZ), holding 1.5% of the shares, with a reference market value of 62 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Happiness Blue Ocean is the first state-controlled listed company on the GEM that invests in, produces, and operates the entire film industry chain. Its largest shareholder is Jiangsu Radio and Television Group Co., Ltd., and it was listed on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange in 2016. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2011, Happy Blue Ocean recruited 13 strategic investors, and Wu Xiubo subscribed for 45.0384 million yuan and became one of them. Happy Blue Ocean&#39;s prospectus shows that 15.0384 million yuan of Wu Xiubo&#39;s subscription funds are self-owned funds, and the remaining 30 million yuan are borrowed funds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Happiness Blue Ocean’s third quarter report for 2023 shows that Wu Xiubo’s shareholdings are frozen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Concerning the contract dispute for &quot;The Great Military Advisor Sima Yi&quot;, Wu Xiubo&#39;s agent declined an interview with Southern Weekend reporters. When Southern Weekend reporters called Qichacha, the numbers of Huali Company and several affiliated companies of Jinhongxing were all empty or unanswered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 09:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>