<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[依法查处，数百个非法涉外气象探测站向境外传输数据]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259639]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Since this year, national security agencies, together with meteorological and security departments, have carried out special management of foreign-related meteorological detection nationwide in accordance with the law. , investigated more than 10 overseas meteorological equipment agents, inspected more than 3,000 foreign-related meteorological stations, and found that hundreds of illegal foreign-related meteorological detection stations transmit meteorological data overseas in real time, widely distributed in more than 20 provinces across the country, posing risks to our national security Hidden danger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/e51a5a9b001cc3382bde484cf2fecfe1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;725&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/e51a5a9b001cc3382bde484cf2fecfe1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256145&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Illegal weather detection equipment installed by an overseas company&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/31/f149ab4f4378829dd94d0ce3f794c295.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;775&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm .com/cms/medias/image/23/10/31/f149ab4f4378829dd94d0ce3f794c295.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256146&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Set Illegal meteorological detection equipment in our residential areas&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of these illegal foreign-related meteorological detection sites are directly funded by overseas governments, and some observation points are set up around sensitive places such as military units and military industrial enterprises to conduct altitude measurements. Approval and GPS positioning; some are deployed in China&#39;s main grain-producing areas to correlate the growth of China&#39;s crops and grain yields; some are even transmitted to foreign official meteorological agencies in real-time at long-term, high-frequency, and multiple points to serve foreign homeland security and weather monitoring. The relevant equipment is small in size, easy to install, difficult to find, and can automatically collect and transmit over the network in real time. For relevant foreign-related meteorological detection activities, they failed to apply for an administrative license for foreign-related meteorological detection from our meteorological authorities, failed to submit meteorological data to our meteorological authorities, and transmitted meteorological data overseas without the approval of our meteorological authorities, violating the &quot;Foreign-related Meteorological Observations and Data&quot; &quot;Administrative Measures&quot;, &quot;Data Security Law&quot; and other relevant regulations. National security agencies, in conjunction with meteorological and confidentiality departments, investigate and deal with relevant illegal activities in accordance with the law, and promptly block illegal activities of exporting meteorological data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“没有丢下战友的习惯”：走进“生死在一起连”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259573]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 12:30:19&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The &quot;Life and Death Together Company&quot; of a brigade of the 74th Group Army organized an offensive and defensive drill. Photo by Zhang Yongjin/ &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d8943f6615.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;709&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/d8943f6615.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256010&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The &quot;Life and Death Together Company&quot; of a brigade of the 74th Group Army organized an offensive and defensive drill. Photo by Zhang Yongjin&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In northern Guangdong in September, the hot and humid air after the rain is breathless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the roar of engines, unmanned reconnaissance, firepower raids, impact breakthroughs... According to the company&#39;s &quot;roundabout and outflank&quot; tactics, the Second Company quickly took over Set fire points from multiple directions to complete the mission of seizing control. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is the second company of a brigade of the 74th Group Army of the Army conducting an offensive and defensive drill. In recent years, the officers and soldiers of this company have participated in various types of offensive and defensive warfare drills and competition exercises for many times. The training footprints have been all over the coast of the South China Sea, the Lingnan jungle, the depths of the desert and the Gobi plateau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Second Company was born in the flames of the Anti-Japanese War and grew up in the flames of war. It has the title of &quot;Life and Death Together Company&quot; and &quot;Unite and Grow Together&quot;. , fight together, live and die together”. Entering the period of peace-building, the company has been reformed and moved three times, but it has always inherited the spirit of &quot;life and death together&quot; and worked hard to forge the company into &quot;a hard piece of steel.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Life and Death Together&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Soldier Wu Shanjie will never forget the scene when company commander Zhang Peijin carried him on the plateau competition field. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In July 2022, the heat in Yunnan was unbearable. At that time, the competition between &quot;good warriors&quot; was in full swing: a ten-kilometer run, bunker construction, reconnaissance, bomb dropping... There were many competitions, and they were very physically demanding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At first, Zhang Peijin led six soldiers from his company to participate in the competition and was always far ahead. However, during the last armed three-kilometer run event, Wu Shanjie suddenly suffered from leg cramps and fell to the ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to regulations, one team member is allowed to fall behind in this project without affecting the overall assessment results. Wu Shanjie, who was in unbearable pain, asked the company commander to put him down so as not to affect the final results. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Peijin, who has participated in multiple subject assessments continuously, has already seen his clothes soaked with sweat and his physical strength is close to the limit. Looking at Wu Shanjie who fell to the ground, he gritted his teeth and said, &quot;&#39;Life and Death Company&#39; has no habit of leaving behind its comrades.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; As soon as he finished speaking, Zhang Peijin picked up Wu Shanjie on his back and sprinted towards the finish line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the long journey of the last kilometer, Zhang Peijin got tired, so other comrades took over and took turns carrying Wu Shanjie until the end. The second team, which could have achieved better results, only finished fourth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Of course there will be regrets.&quot; Zhang Peijin confessed to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;But compared with the results, it is more important for the comrades to stand side by side and rush to the finish line. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Never abandoning any teammate is a glorious tradition inherited by the Second Company from the smoke-filled war years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the honor room of the Second Company, a sculpture based on the story of a stretcher silently tells the origin of the company&#39;s name and also interprets the meaning of &quot;life and death together.&quot; &quot;The spiritual connotation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In June 1946, the company was ordered to cover the retreat of the main force. Soldier Zhu Jicai was shot in the leg and injured. Due to the hot weather and lack of medical treatment, his wounds became infected and ulcerated, and he was unable to walk. In order not to drag down the company, Zhu Jicai took the initiative to ask his comrades to put him down and continue marching. But faced with the encircling enemies, his comrades were unwilling to leave him behind. They made a simple stretcher out of branches and vines and carried him while marching and fighting with the red flag. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the critical juncture of life and death, the entire company dealt with dozens of times the enemy for more than 80 days. Not a single soldier was left behind. The mission was successfully completed. After the war, the company was ordered to Awarded the honorary title of &quot;Life and Death Together&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Over the past seventy years, the company has participated in more than 120 battles such as the Benxi Defense War, the Tashan Blockade, and the self-defense counterattack against Vietnam. Entering a new era, it has successively completed major tasks such as adjustment of the organizational structure, relocation of defenses, and cross-regional base-based exercises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The company fought in the north and south, its numbers were adjusted several times, and its location was constantly changed, but the glorious tradition of &quot;living and dying together&quot; has never changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In the war years, my comrades rushed to the battlefield together. They dared to hand their backs to me, and I was willing to take bullets for them. This is the difference between life and death. Let&#39;s &#39;spirit together.&quot; After serving in the army for 11 years, Zi Guangyong has his own views on company spirit. He said that in peaceful times, this spirit is more reflected in daily training and every detail of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He gave an example. On the training ground, if a comrade was feeling unwell, he would help him carry his gun; during the exercise, if the task was difficult, they would complete it together. &quot;It&#39;s like a football match. You can&#39;t win the game just by playing alone.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Officers and soldiers of the &quot;Life and Death Company&quot; review the battle stories of the company&#39;s history. Photo by Zhang Yongjin&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /10/30/41dc7516ed.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/41dc7516ed .jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256011&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The officers and soldiers of the &quot;Life and Death Company&quot; relived the battle stories of the company&#39;s history. Zhang Yongjin/photo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Practice more with brothers&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >; &quot;These five years in the Second Company have taught me what brotherhood is, and also made me regard the army as my second home.&quot; Tibetan young man Zeren Tashi told Southern Weekend reporters. It’s hard to imagine that when he first came to the army, he couldn’t even speak Mandarin well and “didn’t want to chat with others.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2018, Zeren Tashi enlisted in the army from Ganzi, Sichuan. From the snowy plateau to the southeastern coast, Zeren Tashi clearly felt acclimated to the new environment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Worried that others would not understand what he said, and not wanting to worry his family by talking to them, Zeren Tashi, who was already introverted and sensitive, became increasingly withdrawn and depressed. During breaks, he would always go to the basketball court to play alone. When other comrades came over to play, he would quit and give up the court to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Zeren Tashi fell into deep self-doubt, his comrades came. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bing Luojiang came from Guangxi in the same year. He was carefully aware of Zeren Tashi&#39;s emotions and used his own Mandarin as an example, but he was still a &quot;social cow&quot; , encouraging Zeren Tashi. From that time on, the enthusiastic Luo Jiang took Zeren Tashi to chat with his comrades every day to help him actively integrate into collective life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The company also opened &quot;a window&quot; specifically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Whenever I encounter Chinese characters I don&#39;t know during study, my comrades will explain them to me carefully.&quot; Zeren Tashi said, and the company commander also encouraged He must be brave enough to show himself in front of everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, during the subject demonstration activity organized by the Second Company, Zeren Tashi gave a sharing lesson to the company, and his confident behavior won the audience. Applause, &quot;There was a great sense of satisfaction at that time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, the Second Company has more than a dozen ethnic minority soldiers from Tibetan, Zhuang, Li, Mulao and other ethnic groups. Some of them are leaving their hometown for the first time, and some are recent college graduates, with different personalities and physical qualities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;How to make them feel the warmth of home in the company, the company has its own &quot;unique secrets&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Second Company produces a &quot;Knowledge of Soldiers&quot; for each recruit, including various aspects such as physical condition, family situation, interests and hobbies. &quot;In daily life, the backbone of the company cadres will take the initiative to talk to the recruits, understand their actual situation, and help them solve the difficulties in life.&quot; Instructor Wang Gaosheng told Southern Weekend reporters that during the training process, the squad leader will also teach them hand-in-hand. Integrate into the company as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When he first joined the Second Company in 2022, Mulao soldier Qin Guoxing had not had time to get familiar with the company, but reality poured cold water on him. He is a graduate student from 211 College and is regarded as the &quot;proud son of heaven&quot; in the eyes of his parents and friends. However, in Erlian, where there are many experts, his business ability is often only at the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tin Guoxing felt frustrated and often tossed and turned at night and couldn&#39;t sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Comrade Wang Lei saw Tan Guoxing like this and decided to help. Wang Lei is a &quot;veteran&quot; with solid and outstanding abilities and qualities. He took the initiative to play the role of a small instructor, training with Tan Guoxing, and teaching skills step by step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now, Qin Guoxing and Wang Lei have become a &quot;pair&quot; with each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In daily training, Wang Lei led Qin Guoxing to strengthen physical training, while Qin Guoxing helped Wang Lei answer questions in theoretical studies. In helping each other and competing, the two not only improved their performance, but also forged a deep friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Practice more with your brothers and you won&#39;t feel like you are walking alone.&quot; Qin Guoxing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Big things on my mind&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;These are all obtained by our ancestors with blood and sweat. You need to find a way to fill the remaining vacancies. .&quot; On the day of joining the company, the company commander led the recruits to stand in front of the wall of honor, pointing to the wall of honor medals and saying, &quot;If the honor of the company is lost from your hands, it will be a disservice to the revolutionary martyrs of the second company.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;A unit with excellent military training results&quot;, &quot;A top company in basic subject competition training&quot;, &quot;Comprehensive construction of an advanced unit&quot;, &quot;Comprehensive construction of a model company&quot;... Enter the second company In the camp, a &quot;luxurious wall&quot; covered with honorary medals is shocking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Over the past few decades, the Second Company has been rated as an advanced company in comprehensive construction or an advanced unit of the &quot;Four Irons&quot; for 27 consecutive years, and has won the second-class collective merit 7 times, 18 times of collective third-class merit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When Lan Zhihao was still in the first company of the recruits, he had seen this wall through the window. He knew that this must be a heroic and honorary unit, and he was very eager to be assigned to the second company after the recruit training was completed. As a result, his wish came true. He was surprised, happy and full of energy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zeren Tashi&#39;s mood seems a bit complicated. He is proud to be a member of the &quot;benchmark company&quot; of the entire brigade, but also worried about not being able to keep up. The pace of training. In his words, &quot;I feel like I&#39;m done, and I might be choked in training.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Defending the honor of the heroic company has become a major issue that weighs on the minds of every officer and soldier of the second company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But in the main battle unit with so many strong men, such a goal is easy to say, but to achieve it requires extraordinary hard work and sweat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, a major training mission was held in Yunnan, and company commander Zhang Peijin led the entire company to participate. In order to win the victory, the Second Company began to make key preparations from the beginning of the year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;One month before the exercise, we organized soldier training during the day and worked overtime at night to deduce plans and study tactics.&quot; Zhang Peijin recalled, &quot;The backbone of the company also accompanied us. Stay up late with me, just to increase the chance of winning in the final battle.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Despite adequate preparation, the accident still happened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the live-fire shooting session, Zhang Peijin and artillery technician Xiang Jinwen&#39;s company command vehicle suddenly experienced a transmission failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;When changing the target and shooting, I can only hear the sound of the motor inside, but the shell cannot be fired.&quot; Xiang Jinwen made an instant judgment , &quot;It must be a jammed bullet.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Without any hesitation, Xiang Jinwen quickly raised the armored vehicle&#39;s gun, opened the back cover to determine the specific location of the jammed bullet. , and removed the fixing device of the artillery, and took out the shells with bare hands. The entire process, from problem arose to troubleshooting, took just over a minute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the artillery roared and the shells accurately hit the target, Xiang Jinwen&#39;s hanging heart was completely relieved. He said, &quot;This is a super-level performance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the end, the Second Company stood out in the inspection and evaluation and was rated as an &quot;advanced unit against actual troops.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Bite the &quot;hard bones&quot; together&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2015 4 In August, the company made personnel adjustments, and Xiang Jinwen was recommended to the Second Company for development because of his &quot;excellent professional quality.&quot; He feels very lucky because the Second Company is the model unit in the division. From the cadres to the recruits, everyone is proud to be here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To date, Xiang Jinwen has stayed in the Second Company for more than eight years, and he has experienced several important milestones of the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2019, in order to adapt to future combat needs, the second company installed brand-new main battle equipment, which has better maneuverability, stronger firepower, and can achieve rapid Intersperse to achieve the effect of surprising and defeating the enemy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;All kinds of new equipment made the entire company excited. However, the ensuing practical difficulties of &quot;lack of teaching plans, lack of standards, and lack of talents&quot; also plagued the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The equipment is highly informatized and coincides with the retirement of many experienced technical backbones. The new equipment has brought us great challenges.&quot; Xiang Jinwen recalled, &quot;Every time the live-fire shooting results were very unsatisfactory.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Short-stop shooting requires that the armored vehicle must pause briefly and fire while moving. Aiming and shooting puts forward higher cooperation requirements for the cooperation of the driver, communicator and shooter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;From parking to launching to destroy the target and then to the vehicle moving, the whole process only takes six to eight seconds.&quot; Xiang Jinwen said, &quot;If the cooperation is not good, , it is easy for the vehicle to impact again before the shell is fired.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The time for training in the field is very tight, in order to squeeze out time to bond with teammates. Xiang Jinwen had almost no rest during that period and stayed on the training ground with his comrades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The heat in July and August is unbearable. After being exposed to the sun, the temperature inside the armored vehicle can reach more than 50 degrees. If you stay in the vehicle for a long time, it will not last long. Clothes can be squeezed out of water. Xiang Jinwen described that as soon as he got off the armored vehicle, he felt dizzy and &quot;wanted to vomit but couldn&#39;t.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fortunately, Xiang Jinwen and his team performed at a high level every time they fired live ammunition, and also achieved excellent results in the assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obviously, the iterative update of equipment brings not only the problem of equipment adaptation, but also the need for matching tactical means and tactics to promote the company&#39;s preparation for war. Transformation and capability upgrading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In order to form combat effectiveness as soon as possible, the then company commander Wang Xiaolin led the backbone of the company&#39;s cadres to make their own standards and lesson plans, and conduct tactical drills &quot;crossing the river by feeling for the stones.&quot; They stayed at the training ground during the day and in the equipment room at night. They studied hard for more than two months and finally achieved a comprehensive improvement in combat effectiveness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;At that time, I stayed up late to study every night, often until one or two in the morning.&quot; Xiang Jinwen still has a vivid memory of staying up late to train. , I didn’t stay in bed early the next morning and continued to get up early to learn new equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Among the same type of companies, the Second Company was the first to receive inspections and the first to carry out course demonstrations, achieving the brigade&#39;s goal of &quot;forming combat effectiveness that year.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the &quot;model company&quot; in the brigade, there are countless cases where the Second Company worked together to overcome difficulties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The company is responsible for researching multiple subjects and researching tactics on a daily basis. However, these tasks are arduous and complex, and there is no way I can complete them with my own strength. .&quot; Whenever he reaches a bottleneck, his comrades will actively crowd around Zhang Peijin. They will work together on the training ground to optimize tactics and tactics during the day, and work overtime at night to sum up experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhang Peijin said, &quot;I know that I am not fighting alone. I have a group of brothers to help me share the burden.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;In this year&#39;s platoon tactical assessment organized by the brigade, the first platoon of the second company was selected to represent the company in the assessment. After competing with more than a dozen teams on the same stage, the Second Company relied on its advantages in unmanned equipment operation to leave other units far behind and won the first place in the assessment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;In order to prepare for the assessment, we practiced day and night, especially focusing on the use of unmanned equipment at night. Now all main battle equipment operators have mastered the company&#39;s proficiency How to operate and use unmanned equipment.&quot; Platoon leader Liu Chu was very proud, &quot;We have broken down this hard nut together.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >;(Southern Weekend interns Feng Jiayi, Jiang Lai, Lin Xi, and Zhang Xinyi also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[俄防长绍伊古：对话应该以公平对等、互相尊重的原则为基础]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259645]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“地产界胖东来”，藏在河南县城里]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259625]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/30/3yjITVsPZdpbDWKMqUtLmROFxXokwM5Z19pD9tM5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;952&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/3yjITVsPZdpbDWKMqUtLmROF xXokwM5Z19pD9tM5. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256134&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A real estate developed by Yedu. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Wei Lincong/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At a time when leading real estate companies are experiencing explosive growth, small businesses hidden in Henan counties Real estate companies have attracted the attention of the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because there are too many people coming to visit, which even affects the normal operation of the company, Henan Yedu Real Estate Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Yedu) limits the reception time to once a week, and each visitor is 300 Yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This small real estate company rooted in Qingfeng County, Puyang City received more than 300 groups of visitors in 2022. Not only real estate peers, but also various companies such as medical, education, catering, etc. came in droves, calling it &quot;the fattest company in the real estate industry&quot;. Come east&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like the legendary Pang Donglai in the supermarket industry, Yedu also strives to provide products and services that exceed first-tier standards. In the buildings it builds, a gym and a reading room are standard features. The community trash cans are cleaned three times a day, and the sewers in the employee cafeteria are washed twice a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, Yedu only started engaging in real estate development in 2010, and only developed 6 properties in 10 years, all located in Qingfeng County. This county in northeastern Henan has a total population of 750,000. The county’s GDP in 2022 is 23.77 billion yuan, which is only about half of Henan Construction Real Estate’s 2021 revenue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;170 kilometers south of Qingfeng County, Henan Jinsha Real Estate Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Jinsha) in Shangqiu City also received a large number of visitors. At the end of October 2023, a real estate consulting agency in Beijing regarded Sands as a benchmark real estate company and organized more than 40 real estate company executives from 12 provinces to visit and exchange. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The size of Jinsha is not large. The company has developed 40 properties in the past 16 years, distributed in 8 counties and cities in Shangqiu. The GDP of this eastern Henan city in 2022 ranks 7th among the 18 cities in Henan, just exceeding 300 billion yuan, less than 1/4 of Zhengzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in a county where the average price is more than 5,000 yuan, real estate in Jinsha has been sold for more than 10,000 yuan. The community property also provides wedding services, free physical examinations, etc. to the owners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many senior practitioners in the Henan real estate industry told Southern Weekend reporters that in fact, before 2021, the local real estate circle paid little attention to county real estate companies such as Yedu and Jinsha. “At this stage, everyone is thinking that the future development direction of real estate may be to produce products and services.” One of them said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Luxury homes&quot; in the county&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2018, Yedu delivered its second property in Qingfeng County. This property has a light yellow facade and a European-style door that stands out in the county. It was the previous year that Yedu proposed the concept of &quot;refinement&quot; and the company&#39;s headquarters was built next to this building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of October 2023, Yedu will deliver its seventh project. Sun Chaoyang, a company executive who has been with the company for more than ten years, told Southern Weekend reporters that the company spent four months on the facade in order to make it look better. &quot;The colors and lines were adjusted over and over again, which made several paint suppliers lose their temper.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a community that has been delivered, the green trees downstairs were trimmed into a spherical shape. A staff member told the Southern Weekend reporter with a Henan accent that this was improved after the company returned from studying in Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The cleaning staff in the community immediately stopped the broom in their hands when they saw the visitors, smiled and said hello, with makeup still on their young faces. According to work requirements, she has to use a high-pressure water gun to clean every trash can in the community from the inside out three times a day. Yedu&#39;s recruitment requirements for cleaners are under 45 years old, and the monthly salary is more than 5,000 yuan, which is double the county average. According to Anjuke, the average price of properties currently on sale in Yedu is about 5,000 yuan per square meter, which is generally 700 to 800 yuan higher than the price of houses in the same area. Especially in the base camp of Qingfeng County, where the average price of new houses is only about 3,000 yuan, Yedu can be called a &quot;luxury house&quot; in the county. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jinsha said in a recent official WeChat push that &quot;7 rare pine trees&quot; were transplanted at the entrance of one of its properties in Xiayi County, Shangqiu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters consulted in the name of home buyers. Sands Real Estate consultants said that the prices of real estate developed by the company are generally higher than those of regional projects, and the average price of high-end projects can reach 15,000/square meter. According to Anjuke data, this price is 10,000 yuan/square meter higher than the average price of new homes in Shangqiu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The one who shouted the slogan of &quot;refinement&quot; earlier was Yongwei Real Estate Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as Yongwei). Yongwei Real Estate was established in Zhengzhou, Henan in 2005. There was a jingle circulating in the Henan real estate circle: &quot;Yongwei has three treasures: good building materials, landscape and properties.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jinsha directly used Yongwei&#39;s jingle. A person in charge of Yongwei told a Southern Weekend reporter that in order to learn from Yongwei, Sands founder Yang Limin even bought a house in a property developed by Yongwei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Yanqing, president of Rand Consulting Company, has been engaged in real estate consulting and investment for more than 20 years. He explained to Southern Weekend reporters that refinement means controlling quality during the construction process. Assume that there are three seams on the floor, wall, and ceiling. Fine construction must ensure that the three seams are aligned to avoid misaligned seams and damage to the aesthetics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He introduced that as early as 2013, major real estate companies had proposed the concept of refinement. However, the real estate market has developed rapidly, high leverage and high turnover models have become popular, and scale has replaced quality as a more important indicator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yongwei has taken a refined route since 2007, with Zhengzhou as its base camp, and has developed a total of 36 projects. Its high-end projects in Beilong Lake, Zhengzhou, have an average price of more than 60,000 yuan per square meter and are well-known local luxury properties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the beginning, Yongwei also learned from his peers. Zhang Yingqian, who is responsible for brand marketing at Kangqiao Real Estate, a local real estate company in Zhengzhou, told Southern Weekend reporters that Kangqiao relies on quality to build its reputation. The upstart Yongwei once poached a team of dozens of people from Kangqiao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yingqian has been in the industry for more than ten years. She said that at the beginning of development, major real estate companies competed on quality and built benchmark projects at all costs. &quot;From 0 to 1, we mainly rely on products, so we all take the refined route, because we can only obtain the first batch of seed customers through products.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially in the Henan real estate market, because real estate companies With large quantities, competition for quality is even fiercer. Data from the China Real Estate Association shows that the number of real estate companies in Henan will exceed 8,000 in 2022, ranking fourth in the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After rapid development, Zhengzhou real estate companies have passed the primitive accumulation stage, while county real estate companies are experiencing a breakthrough from 0 to 1. The quality competition that once occurred in the Zhengzhou market is now being staged again in the county. Zhang Yingqian revealed that in the past two years, Sands has poached marketing, engineering, design and other managers from Kangqiao Real Estate with high salaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Lessons from High Leverage&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Spurred by the housing reform policy, Henan’s real estate market also began to take off around 2016. According to data from the National Bureau of Statistics, the sales area of ​​commercial housing in Zhengzhou exceeded 30 million square meters in 2016, more than double the previous year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“It’s just like picking up money.” Wang Zhixing, who is responsible for brand planning in Yedu, told Southern Weekend reporters. At that time, he was working as a sales agent for new houses in Anyang City. He often closed the houses as soon as they were launched. Sales were so hot that he didn&#39;t even need a sales department. He just started selling houses with an advertising slogan. The quality of each property is not compared, but location and price are more important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More foreign real estate companies are also entering Henan. Following Evergrande and Country Garden, large-scale real estate companies such as Sunac, Jinke, and Blu-ray successively entered Henan around 2016 to capture land. Local real estate companies are lining up to go public, and CCRE is gradually moving down, covering more than 100 county-level cities in Henan by 2019. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Chaoyang also recalled that the county market was also booming at that time. &quot;As long as you get the land in your hands, you don&#39;t have to pay attention to any products, you can sell it quickly and get money back quickly.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Yedu slowed down its land acquisition. At that time, the company wanted to be &quot;slower and more stable.&quot; , which is related to the setbacks encountered at the beginning of starting a business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yedu first got involved in real estate in 2010. The founder, Cheng Xiaofeng, made his first pot of gold through steel trading. His father worked for Anyang Iron and Steel Group and took him from his hometown of Anyang to Qingfeng County, Puyang next door. a piece of land. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Cheng Xiaofeng, who was born in 1980, entered the society as a teenager. In his early years, he worked as a chef and drove a truck. After attracting attention in Yedu, he rarely appeared in public. He has stayed in the company for a long time and knows almost every employee. He often tells the story of his entrepreneurial days in the company. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, the threshold for investing in real estate in Anyang and Puyang was not high. Wang Zhixing entered the industry in 2011. He remembers that he only had to pay a deposit of 10% of the land price to obtain land. The first project he sold as an agent covered an area of ​​70 acres, and he only paid 2.1 million yuan to start development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Chaoyang said that when developing the first real estate, the company had little own funds and mainly relied on external borrowings from banks and individuals. Due to lack of development experience, the project lost more than 100 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Phoenix Weekly, a private fund-raising collapse occurred in Anyang in 2012. Since the local boom in private lending in 2009, more than 300 high-interest savings companies have been created, and at least more than 20 billion in funds have been involved, flowing into real estate, energy and other fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A local real estate company executive recalled that Anyang’s fundraising had a great impact on the financial environment of the entire region. Banks began to withdraw loans and personal loans were required to be returned in advance. Yedu was also affected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So starting from the second project, Yedu no longer relied on external financing. &quot;I just think I can&#39;t make quick money.&quot; Sun Chaoyang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, under the market conditions at that time, land prices continued to be pushed up. By 2018, one acre of land in Puyang soared to 1.8 million yuan, and Yedu, which only relied on its own funds, had no advantage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another limitation was that Yedu did not have many employees at the time. County companies have difficulty recruiting people, and their personnel reserves are not enough to support company expansion. It was not until 2020 that Yedu had developed for 10 years and the number of employees had increased to about one hundred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like Yedu, Jinsha did not make many moves when the market was booming in the past few years. Practitioners in the Zhengzhou real estate circle know very little about it. One of the senior practitioners concluded that due to capital and personnel constraints, it is difficult for county real estate companies to compete with large real estate companies during their rapid growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Developing against the trend&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is unique about Henan is that the county market still leaves room for survival for local small real estate companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data released by the Henan Provincial Government show that the urbanization rate of Henan&#39;s permanent population in 2022 is 57.07%, which is 8.15 percentage points lower than the national average. Data from the Qingfeng County Bureau of Statistics show that the local urbanization rate in 2022 is only 35.12%&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;National real estate companies also entered the county market during large-scale expansion, which once had an impact on local small real estate companies. Sun Chaoyang introduced that around 2018, Country Garden, Jianye, etc. successively entered Qingfeng County. Under the impact, Yedu’s sales fell by 20%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, with low housing prices and limited profit margins in the county, it is not a key market for large real estate companies. In addition, the company is large and its management radius is difficult to reach the county seat. After several years of development, Country Garden has only developed two properties in Qingfeng County, while Jianye has cooperated with local developers to develop in an asset-light manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For small real estate companies that have taken root in the county, this low-profit market is a place to settle down. Sun Chaoyang believes that the demand for home purchases in the regional market still exists, especially as part of the investment demand has been converted into demand for second home purchases. Through intensive cultivation and improving quality while controlling costs, county real estate companies have made profits from this customer group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2020, under the control of real estate policies such as the &quot;Three Red Lines&quot;, the credit environment has tightened. Coupled with the impact of the COVID-19 epidemic on the economic environment, the high-leverage and high-turnover model has been impacted, and large real estate companies that rely on this model to develop have experienced explosive growth. However, small real estate companies in the county have bucked the trend and developed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Chaoyang introduced that Yedu began to expand out of Qingfeng County in 2020, opening 11 new properties in three years, and increasing its employees by more than 300 people. During this period, the market was sluggish and land prices in the county fell. Yedu seized the opportunity to acquire more than 500 acres of land at once, saving more than 200 million in land costs compared with the high price period in 2018. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ability to buck the trend and acquire land is due to the company’s low debt ratio. Yedu uses its own funds to develop projects and does not use bank loans. The current cash flow is sufficient to ensure the company&#39;s normal operation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The boss’s words are that we can stop doing nothing for half a year.” Wang Zhixing said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sands, which has also developed rapidly after 2020, also announced on its official WeChat account that the company’s debt ratio has remained at 5%-10% all year round. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/u4BoW0srd2cdubOGlD0MGp9PIheyOoeZb7GocKLC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1268&quot; height= &quot;908&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/u4BoW0srd2cdubOGlD0MGp9PIheyOoeZb7GocKLC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256135&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yedu transformed the sales department into a life experience center, and learned that Fat Donglai opened a supermarket next to it. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Wei Lincong/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;How much money can you make selling steamed buns?&quot;&lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在县城站稳脚跟后，扩张的欲望同样出现在小房企身上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年国庆假期后，金沙前往郑州和各大开发商会谈合作，想要进军郑州，在豪宅区北龙湖打造标杆项目。张莹倩参与了会议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种从打造产品到规模扩张的路径让张莹倩感到熟悉。康桥地产在最初靠产品打出名声后，金融机构和咨询公司纷纷上门，劝说老板学习高周转模式，扩大规模。最终在2019年前后在上海建了分部，开始向南方扩张。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但刚走出河南就遭遇行业寒冬，康桥地产扩张受阻。如今，张莹倩又在朋友圈看到，当初劝说自己老板扩大规模的咨询公司，又前往金沙交流了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来找冶都合作的人也多起来，有些有钱，有些有地，开出优惠条件邀请他们去郑州、进北京。 “行情不好的时候（寻求合作）会更多。”孙朝阳说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但冶都并没有答应。公司目前的发展规划依然没有超出濮阳所在的豫北地区。 “谁都想往外走，但更应该认清自己。我们现在没有能力跑到外面。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更大的问题是，高杠杆、高周转模式营造的规模神话已经破灭，房企还能走向哪里？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尽管逆势扩张，但冶都也难免受到市场环境影响。王志兴表示，现在公司在清丰的4个楼盘加起来，月销量才一百多套，以前一个楼盘就能达到这样的水平。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冶都想出的办法是向服务转型。 2021年，程晓锋提出在小区开设面点房，售卖手工馒头。员工们觉得不可思议，“卖馍能挣几个钱？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这个想法还是被执行，并从面点房拓展到超市、干洗、家政等各项服务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年，冶都在总部旁边开了一家500平方米的超市。王志兴介绍，2022年仅为了学习如何开超市，公司就花了一百多万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同在河南的胖东来是重点学习对象。冶都超市配备了和胖东来同款戴森洗手池，斥资两万多元，还提供茶水、婴儿车、免费充电等服务。商品同样和胖东来一样自采自营，馒头、面条和豆芽甚至是自己生产的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;超市工作人员向南方周末记者介绍，公司计划在清丰县人流量大的地方再开三家同等体量的超市，小区里开设规模较小的店。但目前第一家店尚未盈利。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;冶都的想法是做衣食住行全链条的配套服务，未来还要做餐饮、开药店。不仅针对业主，也面向全县百姓。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“公司希望未来把服务作为核心赢利点，地产只是&#39;顺带&#39;。”孙朝阳说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，张莹倩、孙朝阳为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[长相与年龄不符意味着什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259588]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;人的年龄时刻都在增长，但长相却不一定和年龄同步。当长相与年龄不符，明显看起来比实际年龄偏大或者偏小时，不同的人会对此有不同的解释。特别是看起来比实际年龄偏大的情况，往往被解读为过快衰老。事实上，不少科学研究支持这样的推理，即衰老其实有迹可循。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哥本哈根一项长期随访的心脏研究就曾发现，白头发、脸部皱纹以及男性秃顶就是几个明显的衰老标志，可能表明人们有更高的风险患心肌梗死，特别是白头发长得多的人，相比没有白头发的，风险升高的更明显。除了这些具体的外在特征，笼统地感觉到“长相偏老”&amp;nbsp;对评估健康风险而言也有参考意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;受穿着打扮等外在因素干扰，仅凭视觉信息猜一个人的年龄并不容易。2016年，南丹麦大学公共卫生研究所的研究人员在对近两百组同卵双胞胎做对比研究时就发现，即便是有着同样基因和极为相似长相的双胞胎，人们仍然能从他们面部的差别中读到过快衰老的线索。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些双胞胎老人早在2001年时就已年过七旬，研究人员请人通过他们的证件照头像猜测老人的年龄，结果发现，不论是改变面部还是穿着打扮，都会影响人们对老年人年龄的感知。而十多年后的统计还显示，双胞胎中长相看起来更老的人，更早去世的可能性也更大。面部的线索在一定程度上成了生存或者死亡风险的一个预测因素。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然有不少研究都已经发现了藏在面容背后的一些健康秘密，但系统性分析长相情况与衰老关系的研究却不多。为了弄清楚长相与年龄不符究竟意味着什么，2023年3月，荷兰伊拉斯姆斯大学等机构的研究人员通过分析更多的数据，尝试调查了人们所感知到的年龄与一系列衰老相关疾病之间的关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;更显年轻，更健康&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;结果不出所料，与长相偏老的人风险更高对应的是，那些看起来比实际年龄更年轻的人，他们患多种年龄相关疾病的风险都更低，总体上也有更好的认知功能。相关研究发表在《英国皮肤病学杂志》（British Journal of Dermatology），为科学看脸提供了一定参考。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长相与年龄不符的现象在日常生活中很常见。而要想更科学深入地认识这一现象，就要先区分其中三个关于年龄的概念。除了人们仅靠长相就可以评估的感官年龄外，对健康和衰老较具参考价值的还包括实际年龄和生理年龄。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期研究衰老问题的哥伦比亚大学公共卫生学院副教授丹尼尔·贝尔斯基（Daniel W. Belsky）告诉南方周末记者，“实际年龄测量的是出生以来的时间，而生理年龄则是衡量健康的标准。一个生理年龄值可以理解为一个人在这个实际年龄时的典型健康状态。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;也就是说，按照正常衰老速度，一个健康状况良好的人，其生理年龄与实际年龄应该是趋近乃至一致的。但现实中，一些人的生理年龄会比较明显地偏离实际年龄，呈现出非典型的健康状态。其中，生理年龄比实际年龄小的话，说明其总体的健康状况比一般的同龄人更好，而生理年龄大于实际年龄的人，衰老的程度更深。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最新研究中对感官年龄的分析实际上探索了通过视觉这种简单的方式去识别衰老的可能性，而结果表明，长相更年轻的话，对应的多种疾病的风险确实更低。具体来看，长相看起来比实际年龄年轻五岁的话，骨质疏松、慢性阻塞性肺疾病、白内障和听力下降等方面的风险就会显著更低，同时认知表现更好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些结果是基于2600多名欧洲中老年人健康数据的分析，值得注意的是，纳入研究的人年龄分布从五十多岁到八十多岁，正处于年龄相关疾病明显升高的阶段。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;年轻人的身体不一定年轻&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;尽管目前相关研究多关注中老年人，但是并不意味着成熟和衰老的节奏只在进入中年期后才开始突然加快。已有证据表明，二三十岁的年轻人在实际年龄稳定增长的过程中，其生理年龄的差距就已经开始显现。从具体表现看，老得更快的人身体能力更差，还出现认知能力下降和大脑老化的情况。这些人通常自己也能感觉到健康状况变差了，同时长相看起来也更老。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相关研究2015年发表在《美国科学院院刊》（PNAS）。更为残酷的是，这些观测到的衰老差距发生在人们26岁到38岁之间。同样是未到中年的38岁，不同人的生理年龄却差异明显。现为哥伦比亚大学流行病学系及衰老研究中心副教授的丹尼尔·贝尔斯基曾参与这项研究。在近12年的时间段里，研究人员记录了近千名参与者一系列生理指标的变化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“衰老是从生命早期就开始的一个过程。我们可以在健康的年轻人身上看到它的迹象，并且有些人在年轻的时候就已经比其他人衰老得更快。因此，保持健康的生活方式，寻求有干净空气和水的环境，这些才是安全、可靠的，创造机会参与社交也是一个优先事项。”丹尼尔·贝尔斯基告诉南方周末记者，“在某些方面，这都是不言而喻的。但重要的是要认识到，即使在我们倾向于认为坚不可摧的青年时期，我们的生活方式和环境也会影响我们衰老的轨迹，并产生长远影响。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，对衰老的研究并不容易，因为相比小鼠等动物研究中可以快速地观测动物的一生，人类由出生到死亡的时间跨度要长得多。进入中老年后，年龄相关疾病的增多使观察人的衰老变得更容易，相对来看，年轻人衰老的迹象不太容易捕捉。然而对于延缓衰老，年轻人其实有更多时间和机会去做出改变，以改善自身健康。因此，尽早识别出衰老的迹象，了解衰老的规律，在老龄化的背景下对减轻全球公共卫生压力有重要意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;提早感知衰老的迹象&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“我不确定个人是否真的需要测量他们的生理年龄。” 丹尼尔·贝尔斯基解释，流行病学研究中需要对衰老进行测量，一方面是为了识别那些加速或延缓衰老的因素，另外也是为了评估一些延缓衰老的项目、政策、生活干预措施和药物疗法等是否有效。“不过，对于那些确实希望了解更多自己衰老和健康状况的人，市场上其实有一系列的工具可以帮助估计生理年龄，从血样检测到DNA检测都有。这些检测本身并不危险，但结果应该谨慎解释，最好在医疗保健专业人员的帮助下去解读相关的结果。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月，《柳叶刀健康长寿》（The Lancet Healthy Longevity）发表的一项研究报告显示，胸部X光检查这种已经广泛利用的技术有可能用于辅助评估人的衰老。通过训练、开发相关的人工智能模型，研究人员利用胸片来估计当事人的年龄。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而结果显示，对于身体较为健康的人，人工智能通过胸片估计出的年龄与实际年龄有很强的相关性。但对于已患有疾病的人，估算的年龄与实际年龄之间的差异与多项慢性病有关，可以识别出高血压、间质性肺疾病、慢性肾功能衰竭等风险的升高。这意味着胸片这种常见的图片信息有可能成为一种衰老的生物标志物帮助人们评估慢性病的状况甚至预测寿命，同时提升个性化干预治疗的水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与这些借助医学设备的方式相比，直接看脸，靠长相与年龄是否相符来大致评估衰老和相关的健康风险，虽然精准度有限，但显然更为简洁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，需要注意的是，包括看脸来评估感官年龄在内，目前多项相关研究虽然样本数以千计，但来源相对单一，缺乏足够的代表性，而人种差异在感官年龄评估中实际上起着重要的作用，这也是相关研究目前的一个明显的局限。长相与年龄不符的健康启示是否在各类社群中均有效，仍有待更多研究去确认。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;皮肤衰老的对比研究很早就发现，亚洲人和欧洲人皮肤衰老的轨迹很不一样。以中国和法国女性为例，小样本的研究显示，中国女性脸上开始长皱纹的时间比法国女性差不多要晚十年，这个时间差会使得中国女性在此时明显看起来更年轻，但到了四十多岁，中国女性在面部皱纹方面会经历快速衰老，呈现出非线性的态势，而相较来看，法国女性在此方面的衰老是相对稳定的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诸如此类，由于不同人种面部发展上的差异，套用一个群体里的感官经验去推测另一个群体里人们的年龄，准确率会比较受限。外加不同社会里人们穿着打扮方面的文化差异，在跨文化的背景下去认识长相与年龄不符的现象，可能会发现不同的规律。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;延缓衰老的努力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;其实，在看脸方面，长相与年龄是否相符只是一方面。2022年，有生物学研究还发现，长相的吸引力和免疫功能等健康指标之间可能也存在某种联系。在一系列实验和检测后，研究人员发现那些外表更具吸引力的人，他们免疫表现也更好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参与这项研究的得克萨斯基督教大学实验社会心理学研究人员萨默·门格尔科赫（Summer Mengelkoch）告诉南方周末记者，虽然一个人太在意外貌吸引力的话可能会显得自己很肤浅，但他们的研究表明，人们在关注伴侣外貌吸引力的时候，实际上在意的可能不只是长相，而是也有可能籍此挑选出一个健康的伴侣。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最新研究从感官年龄和实际年龄的差距入手，为科学看脸提供了更多的证据。而尽早识别衰老的迹象及风险因素，就可以为延缓衰老采取行动。2023年5月，哈佛大学医学院的研究人员在小鼠和人类研究中发现，生理年龄在压力的影响下会出现双向波动，压力过大时生理年龄会增加，而从压力中恢复之后，生理年龄又会逆转修复。这或可为未来针对衰老的干预提供适合的切入点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“无论是人到中年，还是尚且年轻。要想促进健康的老龄化，我们能做的事情其实是一样的，吃健康的饮食，做大量的体育活动，参与家人、朋友和社区的社交，培养目标感和意义感，避免毒性压力和污染。”丹尼尔·贝尔斯基向南方周末记者强调，“科学界现在正在研发可以减缓生理老化，延长健康生命周期的新药。与此同时，我们已经知道如何通过改变我们的生活环境来促进健康老龄化，那就是要减少污染，确保安全有保障的住房环境，提供负担得起的健康食品。我们也应该在这些方面进行投入。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从魂魄、中阴身到幽灵Vs魔鬼：万圣节话中西之鬼异同]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259582]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;每年万圣节到来前，各种有创意的惊悚化装遍地开花，刷短视频不断能刷到。虽然如今的万圣节，已经和“cosplay节”没有什么区别了。但其原本蕴含的“驱鬼”元素，依然隐隐可见——尽管在现代社会，鬼神早已成为人类扮演调笑的对象。但是各国对“何为鬼”的理解，仍然在沿袭数千年来的传统。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《礼记•祭义》中有一段对“什么是鬼”的精彩讨论和定义：“宰我曰：吾闻鬼神之名，不知其所谓。子曰：气也者，神之盛也。魄也者，鬼之盛也。合鬼与神，教之至也。众生必死，死必归土，此之谓鬼。”宰我不理解何谓鬼神，孔子告诉他：“神就是精气，鬼就是魂魄。一切生灵都必将死亡，死亡之后都必将归于尘土，这就叫鬼”——孔子在这里玩了个谐音梗：鬼就是归，是一切有生命之物的终极归宿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正因如此，在中国最古老的传统中，鬼和神往往也不会分得太清。正所谓“鬼即祖先，祖先亦鬼”，而儒家对鬼神的态度也非常有趣。孔子曾说：“敬鬼神而远之”。又说：“未能事人，焉能事鬼”，以及“子不语怪力乱神”。总之就是尽量回避鬼神问题，甚至某种程度上表现出了不可知论的倾向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而另一方面，儒家又非常强调尊敬祖先，按时祭祀。如果鬼神根本不存在，那又到底是在祭祀什么？对此孔子又打了个补丁：“祭如在，祭神如神在。子曰：吾不与祭，如不祭。”也就是说祭祀祖先时，好像祖先真的在面前；祭神的时候，好像神真的在面前。孔子还说我如果不亲自参加祭祀，祭了就跟没祭一样——从这里可以看出，孔子强调参加祭祀的人，应当在内心有虔诚的情感。在儒家看来，祭祀是一种用来凝聚共同体的道德仪式，而非真用来祈福消灾的宗教仪式。因此行礼只是出于追忆先人的感情，正所谓“圣人以神道设教”。而祭祀也主要是给活人看：“慎终追远，民德归厚矣”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以今天的眼光来看，孔子这种观点很是先进。然而另一方面，既回避鬼神问题，却又要求人虔诚祭祀，似乎也有矛盾。儒家的一生之敌墨家，就曾经抓住这一点大力嘲讽儒家。与儒家相反，墨家力证鬼神真实存在，因此把祭祀看得比儒家还重要。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于道家的态度则比儒家更鲜明，认为死后就回归天地，无所谓鬼神了。所以《庄子》鼓盆而歌，《列子》认为死亡就是永远休息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而墨子在论证“一定要隆重祭祀鬼神时”，却也暴露了自己的真实想法：“虽使鬼神请亡，此犹可以合欢聚众，取亲于乡里”——“就算真没有鬼神，也还可以借着祭祀联欢聚会，联络乡里感情”。这就和儒家殊途同归了，可见墨子本人的信仰也没那么坚定。毕竟你很难想象一神教徒会说“就算真没有神，信仰神也能有如下好处……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;即使是本土学派中最强调鬼神的墨家，对鬼神的存在也是这种态度，这就不难理解为何中国神话中，冥界的早期设定如此单调了。在佛教传入并兴盛之前，中国虽然已有地府的概念，但还非常简略：地府就是灵魂的归宿，由泰山府君掌管，但并无所谓地狱；而投胎的故事虽然出现很早，但并不被视为冥界的固定手续，只是类似后世“夺舍”一般的异闻，因此也就不存在轮回往生的概念。对古人来说，死亡依然意味着永远的分离和宁静，正所谓“死去何所道，托体同山阿”“潜寐黄泉下，千载永不寤”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而死后入黄泉，也是中国最古老的生死观，直到今天还被作为死亡的委婉代称。这里面还有个著名段子，郑庄公掘地见母：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郑庄公平定弟弟的叛乱后，对偏爱弟弟的老妈武姜很生气。就把武姜软禁到了颍地，还发毒誓说：“不及黄泉，无相见也”，意指不到死不相见。结果颍地的官员颍考叔，成功说服郑庄公，唤起了他的亲情和孝心。但庄公还是拿毒誓当借口，颍考叔就说：“这好办，我们可以掘地道，直到挖出黄色泉水，在那里修个地下庭院，你们不就可以见面了吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是庄公母子得以在地道见面，两人抱头痛哭，和好如初。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很多人第一次看这段时都很无语：和好如初，问题是郑庄公和他母亲最初就是互相不喜欢……而且黄泉真就是黄色的泉啊？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;很显然，黄泉观来自土葬，人死后要去地下，可不就黄泉了。大部分学者相信，黄泉的本义就是地下水，因为很多三代古墓都位于水位线以下。等到佛教把轮回带进来，就和黄泉观结合，产生了“地狱”（捺落迦）——印度本土的“捺落迦”，更类似于平行宇宙或者异度空间，人死后将进入这个空间受审；但是中国传统认为，人死后肯定要去地下。所以佛教徒也只好把“捺落迦”搬到了地下，这才有了“地狱”之名。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而佛教的轮回，则是继承自印度教的传统设定。世界各地其实都有类似的理论，比如古希腊哲学家柏拉图，就经常在书中提及轮回。但对大部分文明来说，这种理论只算奇闻趣事，并不是普遍接受的设定。唯独在南亚，轮回往生是一切宗教和哲学的公理基础。甚至就连佛陀之所以出家，也是为了找到脱离轮回之苦的正道。佛教认为，如果众生解脱“轮回”，也就意味着一切“苦”的止息，这就是佛教说的“众生皆苦”。而不在“轮回”之中的众生，也就不再是众生，而是佛了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而佛教的轮回理论，和中国本土的祭祀显然是冲突的。为了解决这一冲突，就有了各种补丁，比如“鬼魂在冥府排队等投胎，摇号期间也要生活”。这种两个轮回两次死亡之间的“摇号”状态，被佛教称为“中阴身”。但这补丁始终不完善——皇帝要祭祀列祖列宗，是祖宗等了几百年还没往生吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;于是道教在吸收了轮回观后，又打了一个补丁：人有三魂七魄，三魂分别为天魂，地魂，命魂。人死后消散的不是魂，而是魄。三魂在人死后，命魂轮回，天魂上天，地魂在祠堂或者坟墓。所以人的命魂在轮回之前，所烧的钱都是给命魂的。命魂投胎了，烧的就是给地魂的。不同的道教流派，还有不同的补丁理论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而到了近现代，基督教把天堂带进来，情况就更乱了：一个人死后既在黄泉享受子孙祭祀，又进入了六道轮回，还可以同时在天国注视着子孙？对此，曾有人试图如此调和：人死后进入冥府受审，判完后有罪者进入轮回或地狱，无罪者原地升天来到天堂，并接受祭祀，完美。其实这些都不重要，因为中国人对生死的态度，骨子里还是来自儒家：一切都是道德仪式而非宗教仪式，一切都是为了安慰生人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于基督宗教对鬼的态度，细究起来也很有趣：我们常说的魔鬼（魔王撒旦）或鬼魔（即跟随魔王的堕落天使），虽然被翻译成“鬼”，但和中国的鬼并不是一回事。中国人说的鬼，更接近欧洲人说的幽灵ghost。根据《圣经》记载，人死后灵魂要和遗体一起休眠，等待末世审判的到来和复活，属基督的人死后到神之国，圣经称为新天新地；不属基督的人死后到阴间受拘禁。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此基督教认为，世界上的鬼怪现象，都是撒旦所做的假象，世界上根本不存在幽灵。而部分基督徒相信鬼魂存在，但反对与他们进行任何形式的交流，原因是《旧约圣经》多次告诫不可以进行交鬼仪式。因此我们可以看到，欧美的鬼片中很少出现幽灵，吸血鬼、狼人、被诅咒的小孩才是常见主角——但即使是这些鬼怪，也同样受到基督教反对。所以每年的万圣节，欧美仍有基督教会倡导抵制，还主张如果有小朋友前来索取糖果，可以给他们送赠圣经或十字架当礼物。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海关总署：11月1日起出入境人员免于填报健康申明卡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259653]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 10:42:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;根据《中华人民共和国国境卫生检疫法》及其实施细则的有关规定，海关总署决定自2023年11月1日零时起，出入境人员免于填报《中华人民共和国出/入境健康申明卡》，但有发热、咳嗽、呼吸困难、呕吐、腹泻、皮疹、不明原因皮下出血等传染病症状，或已经诊断患有传染性疾病的出入境人员须主动向海关进行健康申报，并配合海关做好体温检测、流行病学调查、医学排查、采样检测等卫生检疫工作。如有隐瞒或逃避检疫的，将承担相应法律责任；引起检疫传染病传播或者有传播严重危险的，承担相应刑事责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;特此公告。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;海关总署&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月26日&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访德勤中国副主席吴卫军：  “巩固银行改革成果，需要一张干净的资产负债表”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259629]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;大象起舞，四座皆惊。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《财富》发布的2023年500强企业名单里，中国四大国有银行均在前50名；在英国《银行家》按一级资本发布的2023年全球1000家银行排名中，四家国有大行连续第6年蝉联榜单前四名。仅净利润单项指标，四大国有银行已然超越国际同行：2023年上半年合计超6035亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二十多年前，四大行已陷入“技术性破产”。时值中国“入世”之后，国门洞开，外资银行入华动作频频，自2006年起更享受国民待遇。观察者和业界为此一直高喊“狼来了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2003年，建行和中行被国务院确定为国有独资银行股改试点，并被寄望“用3年左右的时间改造成为具有国际竞争力的现代股份制商业银行”。史无前例的财务重组和引入国际战投之后，建行和中行先后于2005和2006年在港交所和上交所上市。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此举为工行、农行和邮储银行的股改和上市探清了一条可复制之路。正如工行时任董事长姜建清所言，股份制改革是我国国有银行改革的辉煌序章，也是没有退路的背水之战和一场输不起的改革。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;辉煌序章之后，强化公司治理方是重任。层层监督之下，四大行刀刃向内，不断革新。一份全球投资者信赖的、干净的财务报表便是20年修炼的例证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;德勤、普华永道、毕马威、安永，为国际知名的四大会计师事务所（以下简称“四大”），其中德勤中国副主席吴卫军先后担任中国银行和中国邮政储蓄银行股改上市的签字会计师，前者是中国国有银行股改上市试点，后者是中国国有银行股改上市的收官之作。他为金融业称道的是，参与并领导设计了适合中国国情的“银行改革路线图”，在公司治理、财务报告和资本重组三大领域，为推进四大国有商业银行改革提供技术指引。他还被称为最熟悉中国国有银行的会计师，因为他曾先后担任中国银行、中国建设银行、中国农业银行和中国邮政储蓄银行签字会计师。如今，他已连续三年担任中国工商银行年报签字会计师。早在二十多年前，他已担任“四大”会计师事务年合伙人，积极推动落实“四大”会计师事务所的本土化转制方案，并一直致力于通过发挥审计师资本市场“看门人”的价值，做好“资本的眼睛”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为中国银行业改革开放大时代的同行者，时值中国金融改革开放45周年之际，吴卫军接受南方周末专访时一再强调，中国四大国有商业银行的改革是一场排除万难、艰苦卓绝的改革，其成果和历史意义也是显著的。如今，世界面临百年未有之大变局，中国金融业将迎来巨大的历史挑战。在国际和国内金融深化与发展的重大时刻，中国金融企业家的存在，至关重要。他们将引领中国金融企业从外延做大，转向高质量地把内涵做强。他个人则愿意一如既往地以专业服务国家金融业的发展。“我签出来的会计报表能受到国际资本市场和国际监管的认可，那是我专业中最光荣的事情”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴卫军特别强调人才的国际化。“我建议中国企业全面审视现有的国际化人才培养体系，构建先进的国际化人才胜任力模型。如果没有具备国际视野和国际水平的人才，很难巩固45年的改革开放成果，亦很难成为国际资本市场和国际金融业的有效参与者。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/9TrwL1UXbKQdly518gBthsTEVJlaP6YexFRnaiaH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;596&quot; height=&quot;894&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/9TrwL1UXbKQdly518gBthsTEVJlaP6YexFRnaiaH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;吴卫军：德勤中国副主席、“四大”会计师事务所首批中国合伙人。2021年起，担任中国工商银行会计报表审计的签字会计师。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果签出来的会计报表受到国际资本市场认可，是我最光荣的事情”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吴卫军从一位普通农家子弟，在改革开放大潮中快速成长，不仅是“四大”会计师事务所首批中国合伙人，还是1949年之后首位获得英国特许公认会计师资格的中国内地人。30多年的职业生涯中，他的工作地点遍布中国内地、香港、纽约、伦敦和悉尼等地，参与、推动和见证了诸多金融和会计领域历史性变革事件。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早在1993年至1994年，他协助美国专家汤姆∙梅西（Tom Macy）服务中国人民银行金融体系审慎监管改革咨询项目，为商业银行的风险管理引入最基本的风险评价手段——贷款五级分类，并为中国银行业建立国际组织和全球同业能基本理解和接受的会计科目体系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他在评估这两件事的历史价值乃至对如今的影响时称，“这两件事的影响怎么强调都不为过。商业银行会计科目体系和国际接轨，为国际投资者和交易对手方认可我们的银行、巴塞尔银行监管体系接纳我们的银行、为国有商业银行建立会计控制、风险管理和现代公司治理体系等创造了条件。贷款五级分类，不仅为银行提供了基本的风险管理工具，有助于维护资产质量，也为监管机构提供了金融稳定的监管抓手。这是现代金融发展的制度基础。要认识到，我国现代金融业发展的制度建设只有30年的时间，我们还有很多要学习、要提升的地方。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其后，他经历了职业生涯难忘的一段记忆——参与并领导设计“银行改革路线图”。他对此评价称，“中国四大国有商业银行改革是一场排除万难、艰苦卓绝的改革。但其成果和历史意义显著。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;改革何以坚持并能够快速行进？吴卫军称，“支撑这么艰难的银行改革往前行进，是中央高层的决心，还有执行层面领导的专业性和勇气。当时审计队伍的领导团队中只有我一个是在中国内地成长起来的专业人士。我非常想把中国银行业的改革做好，把中国的国有银行带入国际银行业的队列中。如果我签出来的会计报表能受到国际资本市场和国际监管的认可，那是我专业中最光荣的事情。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他还于2010-2012年参与制定并落实“四大”会计师事务所的本土化转制方案。“我看重专业精神的传承。专业精神有两个支撑点，一个是道德操守，一个是专业报国，因为专业主义的前提是爱国主义。专业精神是专业人士的立身之本。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他认为，在金融企业，外部审计师工作有特殊性，即高质量外部审计不仅是保护股东权益的需要，也是满足境内外银行监管合规的需要，更是全球金融和商品交易对手方敞口风险管理的需要。他担任签字会计师的中国工商银行表内总资产规模超过40万亿元。他对团队说，要付出专业努力，协助工商银行提升资产回报率，哪怕是万分之一也好。40万亿元资产的万分之一，就是40亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不仅仅是服务于银行业，在海外重要资本市场上，“四大”成员所服务的上市企业占比一般超过70%。目前中国资本市场已成为世界第二大市场，但截至2023 年10月底，A 股上市公司约5300 家， 其中“四大”中国成员所出具审计报告的企业数量仅约占7%。面对如此差距，吴卫军认为，做好“资本的眼睛”，仍有较大提升空间，主要包括在财务报告链条上，厘清财务信息准备人、审计师和监管者的关系，夯实责任；利用大数据分析等科技手段，提高审计的精准度和有效性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一般认为，包括德勤在内的“四大”会计师事务所签署的审计报告是国际资本市场的通行证。带着它，企业在国际上融资的价格可以保持在较合理的水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;没有国际化人才，很难实现&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;资金链的国际融通”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你说过，专业服务机构刚进入中国时助力吸引外资，后来的服务重点是支持中国企业改革和进军国际资本市场。请问，1990年代吸引外资进入中国最大的难点是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1978年，中国开始实行改革开放政策。1990年代初，中国经济体制改革进入一个新的阶段性变革历程，开始从“计划经济为主，市场调节为辅”向“社会主义市场经济”体制转变。1992年，党的十四大提出要建立社会主义市场经济体制，中国的经济体系开始发生深刻的变革。如何让国际投资者有足够的信心走进中国、认识中国？当时吸引外资最大的难点是如何让国际投资者相信，在计划经济向市场经济转型的过程中，中国政府能够真正拥抱市场经济、遵循国际规则、保护投资者合法权益。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2003年开始的国有银行改革时期，国有商业银行吸引外资投资中国国有银行的难点又是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;2002年，我服务于中银香港重组和股改上市。这个项目让我意识到中国金融体系改革的真正舞台在内地。回到北京后，我服务于中国银行的改革。2005年，中国银行相继引入国际战略投资者——苏格兰皇家银行、淡马锡、瑞银集团、亚洲开发银行。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国有商业银行在21世纪初引进国际战略投资者时，中外双方谈判的主要焦点包括以下方面：第一，是否夯实了资产负债表；第二，是否有能力建立公司治理机制，并按照董事会章程和议事规则运作；第三，风险管理机制是否长久有效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外资进入中国，吸引他们的，除了中国经济的体量及高成长性带来的市场机会，还有勤奋好学的劳动者，以及愿意遵循国际规则、与国际合作的管理者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金融合作的根本在于对手方的“能力”和“意愿”。比如说，你借了别人的钱，借钱给你的人最在意的是你有偿还能力吗？你有意愿偿还吗？因此，我们不能损害和失去已经在国际资本市场上建立起来的商誉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以你接触的外资企业来看，它们现在对中国投资环境有何期待？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;外资进入中国，是因为它们在中国能够赚到钱。赚到钱的基础不是没有风险，而是对风险有认识，回报可预期。只有政府的规则透明，办事有章可循，资本方能更加有效地流动起来。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“四大”在中国的服务重点是支持中国企业改革和进军国际资本市场。与二十多年前相比，中国企业现在出海呈现什么样的新现象？你对有“走出去”战略的企业有什么建议？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们应该讨论的不仅仅是中国企业“走出去”，而应该扩展至中国企业的国际整合和国际融通问题。人才永远是发展战略的根本和核心竞争力的来源。如果没有国际化人才，中国企业很难实现“走出去”，进军国际资本市场，更不用谈供应链的国际整合和资金链的国际融通。我建议中国企业全面审视现有的国际化人才培养体系，构建先进的国际化人才胜任力模型，探索数字经济时代和后疫情时代更加有效的人才培养模式，让国际资本市场更好地看到是什么样的人在管理现在的中国企业。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国银行和中国工商银行在海外五十多个国家和地区开设了经营机构和营业网点，它们为中国企业与世界经济的融合提供金融支持。中国银行和中国工商银行的海外金融牌照和网络资源是中国金融业改革积累的重要资产。在当前的国际地缘政治环境下，中国金融机构几乎不可能再在海外重要金融中心城市获取金融牌照。所以，对中国金融机构的海外牌照资产和网络资源要格外珍惜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我国的金融机构要派最优秀的人才到海外金融中心城市历练，积累与国际监管机构的协作经验，建立沟通渠道，形成国际金融人才梯队。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;要有如履薄冰的态度&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;早在1993年至1994年，你协助美国专家汤姆∙梅西（Tom Macy）服务中国人民银行的金融体系审慎监管改革项目。30年前，中国金融业的监管与国际差距在哪里？&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;30年前，中国金融业的监管与国际同业的差距主要在于监管的专业性不足。直到银监会和保监会成立，也就是到2003年，中国才形成专门的监管机构和监管队伍。1993年，中国金融监管与国际同业的对话没有技术基础，所以，我们协助人民银行设计会计科目体系，引入最基本的风险评价手段——贷款五级分类。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时中国金融业改革的大方向是市场化和国际化，无论是监管者还是被监管者，都有积极学习国外经验的热情和主动性。这是开始国际对话的起点。专业服务机构，比如德勤，主要发挥了中国监管机构、金融企业和国际组织对话沟通的桥梁作用。而中国金融机构改革上市的时候，我们又发挥了“嫁女儿”抬轿子的作用。有差距不可怕，可怕的是在差距的两端没有愿意迈出一步的人。在金融业，我们仍然没有骄傲的资本，我们要有如履薄冰的态度。在金融战场上，打败自己的永远不是竞争对手。这就叫专业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;20年间，金融监管体制发生了多次变化。银监会和保监会脱胎于人行并于2003年同步成立，后于2018年合并为银保监会，直至2023年国家金融监督管理总局挂牌。你认为，与国际监管体制相比，还有变革空间吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对于中国金融业，2023年是极不平凡的一年。中国金融监管体系变革为“一委一行一局一会”。无论机构如何设置，变革的空间只有一个，那就是提升专业性。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在过去20年中国监管水平提升的过程中，我在三个领域提出过自己的专业观点并产生了积极影响。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一个观点是，强化金融监管的“铁三角”关系。这个观点是在2009年我从英国金融监管局结束借调回国后提出来的。在金融监管架构下，“铁三角”关系是指金融监管部门、中央银行和财政部的三方关系。金融危机考验的是一个国家的金融应急和领导能力。提升“铁三角”关系的协调能力，对危机作出快速和有效的反应起着重要作用。解决金融体系的问题，仅靠一家政府机关是不够的。即使在经济运转正常时期，这三家机构也需要协调，为金融体系提供清晰和不重复的指导。在金融体系统一领导方面，这种“铁三角”的协调和执行力还要继续提升，因此，中央金融工作委员会的设立是现代经济、金融管理的需要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二个观点是，建立监管三方会谈机制。这个观点是在2003年3月银监会成立后，我作为会计师事务所的代表，与时任银监会领导交流时提出的。当时，我提出要借鉴国际先进做法，监管当局每年组织受监管金融机构和其外部审计师的三方会议，讨论监管关注的财务和业务风险问题，布置监管工作。有时，甚至可以安排闭门会议，即在受监管机构的管理层不在场的情况下，监管机构和外部审计师针对重要的和重大的问题进行沟通。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三个观点是，对金融机构的股东进行监管。这是在2005年，为中国银行上市做准备，在河北香河召开的一次研讨会上，我认真向参会领导提出来的。银行的资本充足率要求是8%，即银行用的是12.5倍的杠杆率。如果不对股东进行监管，银行可能就会受到股东不良行为的影响。对股东进行监管这一建议的讨论也扩展至汇金公司的管理模式。我坚定地表达支持汇金模式，推动汇金成为专业管理机构。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在回过头来看，我的这些观点都经得起时间的检验。我相信，我今天表达的一些观点也会在30年后被证明是重要的，会出现在我专业报国的成绩单上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，我国金融监管体系的架构已进行了大幅调整与优化。在现有监管架构下，如何提升监管制度和运作机制的有效性？从运行实效上讲，特别要做好下面三篇文章：一是如何吸引和留用最优秀的金融人才加入金融监管队伍；二是如何协调央行、金融监管总局和证监会等监管部门之间的监管协作，如何尊重财政部作为最后拯救者的地位，如何发挥好金融国资委（目前由汇金和财政部金融司承担）的股东监管作用；三是如何开发和应用更为强大的监管科技工具，提升监管质效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你建议吸收和留用最优秀的金融人才加入监管队伍。在公务员序列里，如何实现突破，用市场价格吸引优秀人才？国外金融监管机构有可借鉴之处吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;金融监管和财政管理等机构都要尊重专业性。它们发挥功能，是以专业为基础的。我们一定要信任专家，不要怀疑专业人士拥有的爱国主义精神。技术型的人才在公务员体系中要得到保护和支持。在英美的金融监管体系中，只有高层，比如美联储主席等级别的人士排列在公务员体系里，其他专业人士全按照市场价格给予薪酬待遇。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你之前说过，金融业要强化监管。事实上，金融业一直在加强监管。怎么看强监管和改革创新的关系？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;强监管和改革创新并不矛盾，不可偏废。只有加强监管，才能防范和化解系统性金融风险；只有改革创新，才能提升金融产品、服务的多样性，提升金融市场的广度和深度，更好地满足人民群众和实体经济的金融需求。有智慧的金融企业家认为，支持实体经济，就是支持金融业的未来。实体经济和金融业这两者之间的关联度的强化和黏合需要金融创新来完成。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;强监管和改革创新是“既要”“又要”的关系，关键在于平衡监管和创新的关系，把握监管的力度和边界。简言之，监管既不能不足，亦不能过度。监管过度就会妨碍金融可持续发展的改革和创新。改革和创新当然不能以显著增大系统性金融风险为代价，不能纵容脱离实体经济的金融行为。脱离实体经济外的、金融环节内的“空转”型金融创新，是以金融逐利为目的的“伪创新”，必须制止。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;尊重专业是&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;银行改革&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;临危不惧的胆识保障&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;监管体制不断变革，银行也在不断变革。你曾参与并领导设计了适合中国国情的“银行改革路线图”。当时四大银行因不良资产极其庞大被认为已经“技术性破产”。你们设计“改革路线图”、参与银行改革的勇气从哪里来？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;改革前，中国四大国有商业银行“在技术层面上是破产的”，仅靠隐含的国家财政担保来维持生计。如果不进行股改，四大国有商业银行就会从“技术性破产”走向实际破产。这是当时中国经济制度改革迫切需要解决的问题。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们敢于为“技术性破产”的四大国有商业银行设计改革路线图，是因为我们看到了国家破釜沉舟、排除万难的改革勇气和定力；是因为我们对自身的专业能力有信心，我们有能力对金融机构面对的问题动手术；是因为金融机构的管理层有担当，并且敢于承担责任，能够把我们列出来的任务清单执行下去。2003年，在完成中国银行的审计后，我们提出了五百多条管理建议，中国银行的行领导专门责成内审部成立工作组，监督落实我们提出的建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2003年至2006 年，你担任签字会计师，协助中国银行在香港和上海两地上市。2012 年，你担任签字会计师协助中国邮储银行在香港上市。你对国有大行进一步深化改革有信心吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我对国有大行的改革和发展一直充满信心。这种信心的基础是对金融改革决策者和领导者的认同，包括对他们制定的政策方向的认同。金融机构的领导者意识到不改革便是死路一条，他们利用自己的知识储备，愿意与国内外专家配合，寻找改革的出路，是他们提出来，“我们需要一张路线图”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时的金融改革决策者和领导者，坚持市场化和国际化方向，尊重专业人士，信任并充分发挥国内外专家的力量。国有大行已经完成改革阶段的工作任务，当前面临的挑战是持续提升核心竞争力，更加高效地适应新环境、新变化、新趋势。与我们打过交道的国有大行的领导者是专业的。在任何时代，我们都需要尊重专业，尊重专业是信心的来源，是临危不惧的胆识保障。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了协助中国银行和中国邮储银行股改上市外，你还曾担任或正担任中国建设银行、中国农业银行、中国工商银行的签字会计师。在上市之后，国有银行改革和发展的难点是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对于股改上市之后中国银行业的发展，我想用八个字来概括：成就巨大、任重道远。在股改上市之后，国有控股大型商业银行取得了令人瞩目的成就：财务和风险防控能力增强；资产负债表比较夯实，创造利润的能力增强；建成了以“四会一层”为核心，获得国际资本市场认可的公司治理体系；形成了国际化经营的布局。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但如今，银行改革和发展面临着更加复杂、严峻的挑战。如何建设现代化的商业银行永远是一个难题，是一个复杂而艰巨的工程，涵盖战略管理、风险管理、信息系统和企业文化方方面面。尤为艰难之处是，国有商业银行的领导要明确如何平衡国有银行的政策属性和商业属性，在坚持党的领导前提下，实现经济效益社会责任兼顾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;它们为何有动力自我革命？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;国有大行的自我革命动力主要来自以下三个方面：国家和政府办好银行的决心和领导力；国有大行与国际接轨的治理体系已经建立；金融企业家和职业银行家的成长、成就和积极作为。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以国有大行董事会的有效性为例，我做个说明。国有大行的董事会主要由三组董事组成，一组是代表国有股东的股权董事，他们来自财政部和中央汇金公司；一组是独立董事，他们具备国际经验及风险管理、法律、会计等领域的专业知识；一组是负责经营管理的执行董事，他们是中管干部。这是一支兼具专业性和政治性的、强大的银行战略管理队伍。他们的自我驱动力很强，有崇高的使命感。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;增强“数目字管理能力”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2018年，作为清华大学国家金融研究院金融与发展研究中心客座研究员，你专注深度研究中国银行业及金融体系改革的相关问题，总结改革开放40年在会计发展和银行改革方面累积的经验。请问，在会计领域，你提出的主要问题和总结的经验是什么？会计和金融的关系是什么？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;会计准则体系、审计市场建设和会计人才水平直接影响一个国家的会计能力。回首改革开放的45年，中国会计准则不断优化完善，实现行业覆盖，全国统一，国际接轨；审计市场进行制度性改革，建成适应国家市场体系的多层次会计师事务所；会计人才培养获得重视，建立国家会计学院，开展全国会计领军人才项目，为中国改革与发展培育专业力量。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“经济越发展，会计越重要”。企业会计准则是市场经济的重要规则，注册会计师行业承担着建设社会诚信的重要责任，而会计人才也是国家发展需要的战略人才。会计准则，注册会计师行业和会计人才的水平是会计能力的重要因素。一个国家的会计能力反映了它的经济制度和政府管治软实力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄仁宇教授在《万历十五年》一书中论述了他的大历史观。其中最为重要的一个理论是国家的“数目字管理能力”。他认为，一个稳定的和成熟的商业社会需要具备计算和记录整个社会的资源的能力，只有这样，“资金方便对流，实物经济变为金融经济，可以交换的条件增多，分工进一步合理化，整个国家可以以&#39;数目字管理&#39;”——进而国家可以强盛。简单而言，黄仁宇教授认为，数目字管理能力是国家强盛的基础。我十分认同这个观点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;会计能力是国家治理能力的基础，特别是在数字经济时代，形成和运用数字资产都需要会计这一基本功能的存在。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于会计和金融的关系，我的观点是鲜明的。企业的金融是财务，社会的财务是金融。会计、财务和金融将是“三位一体”的学科。每个人都应老老实实地学点会计知识，因为所有的经济活动最终都要经受“借记”和“贷记”的检验。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;金融企业需从“外延做大”转向“内涵做强”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最新的世界500强名单里，四大行均在前50名；在英国《银行家》杂志的评选中，四大行霸榜前四。你观察，中国银行业在逆周期经营能力和风控能力方面存在哪些挑战？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;国有商业银行的资产负债表不再是简单的商业经营实体的资产负债表，而是由中国经济基本面支撑，它反映了中国社会的金融资产分布。商业银行的资产质量，将高度依赖国有经济和政府财务状况的健康度。这是国有大行资产负债表的主体特殊性。银行要发挥好在经济运行中的风险代理监督作用，及时发现风险，并向国家相关部门呈报经济运行中存在的风险和隐患。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国有商业银行的成绩单必须以“长期主义”为基础，资产负债表的快速扩张更加需要执行严格的风险纪律，特别是严格的信贷纪律。银行家需要更执著地坚持专业主义精神，吸收上一轮去杠杆的教训，提高放贷和购买债券的质量标准，在增量上管好不良资产的入口，同时不断夯实存量资产质量，保持充足的资本和损失吸收缓冲垫，坚持科学的流动性管理方法，坚守一张干净的、健康的、可持续的资产负债表。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;目前看，你认为中国国有银行业还需要深化哪些改革和促进哪些发展？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;金融业的发展始终与时代大局保持高度关联。当今世界面临百年未有之大变局，中国金融业已经迎来巨大的历史挑战。在国际和国内金融深化与发展的重大时刻，中国金融企业家的存在，至关重要。作为世界第二大经济体，今天中国的金融业，比任何时候都更迫切地需要一支强大的金融企业家队伍，需要他们充分发挥领导力，引领中国金融企业从简单地外延做大，转向高质量地内涵做强。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们要爱护中国的金融企业家。金融是承担风险的行业，金融企业家要做的业务决策就是承担风险的决策。如果运用没有边界的问责制度来束缚金融企业家，这肯定会扼杀金融企业家承担风险的主动性，削弱金融对实体经济的支持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金融企业家在社会经济运行中还发挥着一个鲜为人知的功能，他们对社会经济的运行履行着代理监督作用。以银行家为例，他们把贷款借给企业，令他们感到日夜不安的是借款人无法偿还贷款本息的风险。因此，银行家从放贷之日起，就会定期走访企业，要求企业维护健康的财务状况，满足贷款合同要求，这种监督作用提高了中国经济发展的效率；同时，金融机构也累积了有关借款人和行业的知识，为资金有效地流向实体经济把握方向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国创新为何会成功？因为中国的经济体量大，试错成本平摊下来很小。成功之后，创新带来的总体经济效果很大。因此，必须要鼓励这样一个试错机制，更好地吸引资本进入创新市场。这就需要投资银行的参与，我们要鼓励培养一批在中国扎根、支撑中国经济向高质量、高效率发展的投资银行家。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[约瑟夫·奈：中美不会彼此构成威胁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259615]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 07:57:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35970adf3270835011604556288/NaBoGdbWdHEA.mp4&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011604556288&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;成稿555&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35970adf3270835011604556288/NaBoGdbWdHEA.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35970adf3270835011604556288/NaBoGdbWdHEA.mp4&quot;>;&lt;/source>;成稿555&lt;/video>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日常用语的“职业密码”丨人在职场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259566]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 23:02:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My friend is a senior lawyer. One day he received a call from an old classmate asking him if he had any acquaintances in the hospital. Illness requires immediate hospitalization. While socializing, the lawyer asked urgently: &quot;What crime is your father suspected of?&quot; As soon as he said it, everyone laughed, and he was stunned: He hadn&#39;t drank too much, why did his words get messed up? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years ago, this same lawyer also went to a restaurant for dinner. A late brother called him and asked him which private room he was in. He replied confidently: The third court! ——Look, how much career information a person hides in his slips of the tongue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every person who speaks has an accent of varying degrees, and you can roughly &quot;hear&quot; the place where he was born or grew up. Those who seem to be born to speak standard Mandarin are actually just his accent. In daily communication, people often use words, sentences, and quotations from scriptures, which often bear the imprint of their profession, or it may just be the inertia of their language. There is a saying that one should never leave one&#39;s profession in three words. Sometimes, a single word or sentence may reveal the professional information of the person concerned, which can be regarded as a kind of &quot;intentional&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three hundred and sixty lines, each line contains jargon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A colleague from a provincial TV station is as clumsy as I am, and he usually talks about his country of origin and &quot;doesn&#39;t understand the language&quot;. He specializes in supervisory reporting, and I am a little worried about whether his undercover investigation will go smoothly. A colleague who &quot;doesn&#39;t know the language&quot; proudly revealed to me: Because of his strong accent, when he went to the dialect areas of his hometown for secret visits and open checks, it was even more confusing, and he was treated as a native of his hometown. Once &quot;crossing districts&quot;, chickens and ducks often have to break out in a hurry, not knowing what song the other party is &quot;singing&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the TV colleague has repeatedly encountered embarrassment in his dialect &quot;comfort zone&quot;. When tracking and investigating a people&#39;s livelihood complaint, he personally experienced the procedures as a local citizen. The reception staff at the Government Affairs Center had seen countless people and were quite experienced. He discovered a &quot;flaw&quot; on the spot: You, you are... a reporter, right? Asking questions about this and that, and turning over and over again. We ordinary people are very direct when it comes to doing things, not like you! With one word to reveal the secret interviewer, the colleague pretended to smile bitterly, and had no choice but to admit that he was unlucky and go for another secret visit at another time. This time, recite silently three times: Get rid of routines, get rid of routines, get rid of routines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“What did you think at the time?” “What do you think about this?” “What are the solutions to this problem?”… Reporters’ clichés have sneaked into our daily lives. The most recent time I returned to the provincial capital from my hometown, I heard a ride-hailing call on my phone. The driver picked me up half an hour early and then went in the opposite direction to pick up the next two passengers. During the chat, my reporter&#39;s professional habit kicked in. I first asked him about his passenger status, then about his passenger background, then about his experience and feelings in the industry, and then about the competition situation in the industry. I wanted to know whether he had a ride or not, and wanted to know more about the current tailwind. The bitterness and joy of car owners. When I was resting in the service area on the way, the driver took the initiative to approach me: Boss, you are so kind. You are so polite when chatting with us and treat us as your own. Unlike some bosses who urge us to drive as fast as possible after getting in the car. No delay at all... ...I smiled and prepared to explain to him that the chat just now was just a &quot;mobile interview&quot; and he was just another of my &quot;interview subjects.&quot; As the words came to my lips, I decided to call myself the &quot;boss&quot; and respond to his gratitude: the big bosses all have people driving, and the little bosses only ride along. Favorable wind, not necessarily smooth road. If you want to go along the way, have it all to yourself without carpooling. We are all part-time workers, so we understand how difficult it is for you. ——A response that seems to reveal one’s professional identity unconsciously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Three sentences are indispensable to one&#39;s profession&quot; reveals the habits of the brain behind people&#39;s expression habits - habits of thinking. In the workplace, when people communicate and process information, they often have special terminology or specific expressions. They are used frequently day after day, which can easily form a fixed mindset (expression). When the real scene continues to change, people often It is difficult to transition and switch in place instantly. The longer a person stays in a certain position (position), the greater the corresponding expression inertia. &quot;Three sentences are inseparable from one&#39;s own profession&quot; also highlights people&#39;s &quot;path dependence&quot; in thinking and expression. People have different lives, growth, and professional backgrounds. Familiar words give people a sense of security and even a sense of superiority: when officials with computer majors were in charge, they emphasized &quot;systematic thinking&quot;; officials who had been engaged in vocational education for a long time strongly advocated &quot;suitable thinking&quot; after transferring to basic education. &quot;Education&quot;... How can yesterday&#39;s &quot;butt&quot; command today&#39;s &quot;head&quot;? Maybe it&#39;s also a kind of &quot;muscle memory&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a Jiangsu media person)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;span>; Voices from the workplace, complaints about workplace experiences, breaking stereotypes, and revealing industry rules. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《完蛋！我被美女包围了！》热销：戳中男性痛点，顺利开辟生态位]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 22:25:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, &quot;It&#39;s over!&quot; I&#39;m surrounded by beautiful women! &quot;&quot; became the number one best-selling game on Steam in China after only one day of being online. Discussions about this game have also become hot searches on social media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This phenomenon deserves concern and analysis. The plot line setting of the game is very simple. You transform into the male protagonist Gu Yi and use the first-person perspective to immersively meet, interact and socialize with six beauties with different ages, looks, personalities and family backgrounds. You can choose one of them. Develop the character deeply and make it your other half: the charming witch who loves to go to nightclubs, the intellectual sister who loves literature and art, the innocent school girl who is not materialistic, the unruly rich lady, the sexy mother who raises her children alone, and the girl who wants to be a little girl at heart. The cool CEO, the choice is yours, which one you will end up with, you can do whatever you want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, this is a male-oriented love clearance game. The target audience is men. There is no harem or side effects. It is just pure love and satisfying men&#39;s various fantasies about their significant other. There are relatively few games in this category on the market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The public has the impression that young people, especially young men, love to play games, which is true. The hunting and war that our ancestors engaged in in the tribal era were the first priority for survival. This has become the pursuit of power and victory engraved in genes. The mainstream favorites of men are action, combat, war, civilized hegemony and strategy. The game involves a battle of wits and courage. In this type of game, most of the male players are male. Love is either absent or is just an add-on or embellishment. There is a high probability that the game producer has established such a mental position: every man’s dream is to conquer the world. , falling in love is also about capturing a woman’s heart by conquering the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The design idea of ​​this game is very different. It just allows a very ordinary man without any cheats to fall in love with a beautiful woman. Although the game has 12 hidden endings and hundreds of route choices , &quot;Every choice you make will trigger unexpected hidden stories.&quot; However, compared with the mainstream male-oriented games on the market, it is not really complicated, nor can it be said that the workmanship is exquisite, so it must be so popular. Particularly successful is that it hits the pain points of young men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A major feature of the game is &quot;real-person interactive images&quot;: six beauties with different styles are all played and photographed by real people. In the era of general artificial intelligence (AGI) led by GPT-4, it is not difficult to use AI to design stunning beauties that are more perfect than real people, and the cost is lower. This approach has already had a negative impact on the profit model of &quot;welfare girls&quot; who sell personal photos. The impact. The producers of this game went in the opposite direction, using real people to act on camera, and pre-filmed various plot lines like genuine film and television works, allowing players to choose the objects and plots they want to develop in depth, allowing players to become film and television male protagonists. , the power to control and promote the development of the plot on your own, and it can also approach the experience of interacting with real people in real life, which can be said to be thoughtful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sexual version of this game is the so-called otome game. Otome is a girl. Women choose to fall in love with men, whether they are domineering CEOs, rich second generation, celebrities, or race car drivers. In short, it is to satisfy women&#39;s perfect imagination of their significant other. In terms of proportion, there are several orders of magnitude more otome games than male-oriented romance games. In this sense, &quot;Done!&quot; I&#39;m surrounded by beautiful women! &quot;The reason why it is so popular may be because there are too few such games. Game producers ignore and underestimate men&#39;s emotional needs. In addition, &quot;live-person interactive images&quot; fill the gap, so it suddenly opens up. an ecological niche. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The popularity of this game is enough to show that the male world is not all about killing and working to make money. Men also have emotional needs. Our traditional culture does not encourage men to open up and express themselves. &quot;A man cannot shed tears easily.&quot; Men must appear strong and carry everything without being weak or shrinking. However, everyone has moments of weakness and emotions. There are times when I cannot bear the need to express myself and my emotions break down. Men are human beings too, and their spiritual world should also be cared for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, men’s voices have been absent from public opinion. In the statements of some merchants, there is even a saying that &quot;men&#39;s consumption power is not as good as that of dogs.&quot; However, this situation is changing. The values ​​and consumption concepts of the new generation of young men are very different from their parents. They care more about themselves and invest more in their own image and spiritual world. For example, in recent years, the consumption and consumption of male cosmetics have increased annually. Significantly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to iiMedia Consulting data, among Chinese users who choose to shop through online live streaming channels, 58% are men and 42% are women. Among them, those born in the 1980s and 1990s are the main force in shopping, accounting for 42%. The total exceeds 80%; live streaming e-commerce shopping users are mainly distributed in first- and second-tier cities, with second-tier cities leading the way with 42%. This is very different from the impression some people have. The consumption power of young men is rising and blowing out, which is a trend worthy of attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When men convert their productivity into consumption power, they also win the hospitality of businesses. This is the rule of the game in the consumer society. &quot;It&#39;s over!&quot; I&#39;m surrounded by beautiful women! 》The fire is another footnote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, since it is a romance game, it will inevitably lead some people to discuss the relationship between games and reality. Some people worry that the quality of opposite-sex partners in romance games is much higher than in real life, which will cause players to invisibly raise their inner expectations and standards for mate selection, and lose interest in the available partners in reality. There should be a real social investigation on whether this effect exists and how big it is, and it is meaningless to talk about it in the air. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a person who has to earn money to support his family and career during working hours, but only occasionally spends some time playing games during off work hours or weekends to satisfy his dreams and fantasies that cannot be realized in real life, should not be punished. Even if you are harsh, you won’t lose your sense of reality just by playing a few games, because the gravity of the real world is strong enough to pull you back to the ground. Occasionally falling into fantasy, even if it is a fantasy that cannot be realized, will make a person&#39;s heart shine, or make the soul gain a sense of relaxation and transcendence, which is necessary for a person&#39;s mental health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if you are completely immersed and lost in fantasy due to the lack of anchors in the real world, and never want to get out of the virtual world, or use the perfect objects in the virtual world to ask for optional objects in the real world, then of course It is a pathology and not desirable. A sane adult should never go to this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>