<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[高速服务区外来师傅修车受阻：背后是“独家经营权”带来的垄断收益丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258660]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;If the vehicle breaks down in the highway service area, can it only be repaired by the repair shop in the service area? The employees of the maintenance shop in the service area threatened to stop the maintenance technicians hired from outside to repair the car. Is this &quot;reasonable and legal&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Jimu News, a truck transporting fruit broke down and failed to start while resting in the Jiangxi Fengcheng service area of ​​the Shanghai-Kunming Expressway. After the auto repair shop in the service area said it could not repair the vehicle, the driver himself invited a technician from a nearby designated repair shop of the truck manufacturer to come to the service area to prepare for repairs. Unexpectedly, he was blocked and intimidated by the staff of the repair shop in the service area. The maintenance technician who was invited had no choice but to leave. The truck driver contacted several local repair shops, but they did not dare to arrange for personnel to go to the service area to repair the vehicle. There was no choice but for the driver to drag the car off the highway to repair it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not uncommon for car repairs to conflict with repair shops in expressway service areas. More than a month ago, a similar incident occurred in the Jiqing service area in Hunan. A truck driver was stopped by repairmen in the service area when he was inspecting his truck. After being told that the driver made the repairs himself, he uttered wild words. On social networks, similar complaints involving car repairs and tow truck conflicts on the highway are not the same. Some service area repair shop staff even use violence or threaten violence against drivers who repair their own cars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the highway, can only repair shops in the service area repair cars? In an interview with the media, the person in charge of the Fengcheng service area said that the practices of the repair shop in the service area are &quot;reasonable and legal and have laws to follow.&quot; The law the person in charge refers to refers to the provisions of the Highway Law, Highway Safety Protection Regulations and other relevant regulations that &quot;prohibit the establishment of stalls within the scope of highways and highway land.&quot; This is obviously a misinterpretation. The so-called &quot;setting up stalls&quot; refers to setting up relatively fixed stalls for a long time and waiting for customers to come to your door. The purpose of prohibiting it is to avoid &quot;damaging, polluting the highway and affecting the smooth flow of the highway.&quot; After receiving the invitation from the customer, he temporarily went on the road to repair the car, precisely to repair the vehicle as soon as possible to avoid parking on the road for a long time and to ensure the smooth flow of the road. Regardless of the definition of &quot;setting up a stall&quot; or the legislative purpose of the regulations, it is completely legal for drivers to repair their cars by themselves or to invite repairmen to temporarily repair their cars on the road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the conflict at the Jiqing service area in Hunan mentioned above, the maintenance personnel in the service area claimed that the Provincial Department of Transportation has a document that stipulates that &quot;people below&quot; (referring to repair shops other than highways) cannot go to the highway for repairs. car, but ultimately failed to produce relevant documents. Do the traffic management departments in some places really have such regulations? If such a document does exist, it should be made public and reviewed for legality. If the government department does not have such regulations, is this an internal regulation of the highway management department, or is the service area repair shop lying? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In vehicle maintenance services, drivers and car owners are consumers, and of course they have the right to freely choose repair service providers. Auto repair shops in service areas prevent drivers from repairing their cars by themselves or other repairmen, and force drivers to go to their repair shops to repair their cars. This is a &quot;forced transaction&quot; behavior that is expressly prohibited by the Consumer Rights Protection Act. The Criminal Law also stipulates that using violence or threats to forcefully buy or sell goods, force others to provide services or force others to receive services, if the circumstances are serious, constitutes the crime of forced transaction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why are obviously illegal behaviors so common? The root of the problem lies in the word &quot;profit&quot;. As the person in charge of the Fengcheng service area said, off-road vehicle maintenance personnel going to the service area to repair cars &quot;harms the interests of the service area repair shops.&quot; The interests of service area repair shops are actually the interests of service area and highway managers. Expressway service areas, as part of expressway service facilities, are constructed and operated by expressway managers. If a repair shop opens in a service area, it must pay space rent to the highway administrator. These rents are generally higher than those for sites outside highways, because this is not only site rent, but also implies a premium for &quot;exclusive operating rights.&quot; Precisely because highway managers also benefit from the &quot;exclusive operating rights&quot; of repair shops, they will naturally try their best to protect the interests of repair shops. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;exclusivity&quot; premium is very common in closed establishments. Food prices in airport terminals and highway service areas are generally much more expensive than in urban areas. Even canteens in primary and secondary schools can be auctioned for sky-high prices. This is all due to the monopoly benefits brought by the &quot;exclusive operating rights.&quot; More importantly, these premium benefits are not obtained through market competition, but rely on franchise rights granted by administrative power. For these infrastructure operators with administrative monopolies, the common practice in various countries is to strictly limit their profit margins to maintain a balance between attracting social investment and avoiding huge profits to maintain public welfare. To this end, they must be strictly supervised to prevent them from relying on their monopoly status to harm the public interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, there was an incident in a highway service area in Guangdong where a driver repaired his own car and was threatened by a repair shop employee. Due to public opinion and the intervention of relevant departments, the auto repair shop in the service area was shut down for rectification. The same incident occurred in Fengcheng, Jiangxi this time. The public expects local market supervision and other departments to take timely action to investigate and deal with forced buying and selling, and forced transactions to safeguard the interests of consumers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[身份证、退伍证、婚姻信息、家庭住址……当一个明星被“开盒”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258670]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 12, Chen Muchi, who plays the role of Prince Yin Jiao in the movie &quot;Fengshen Part 1&quot;, He posted a statement on Weibo, responding that he &quot;did have a marriage.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a4e19d459cf53705edb203836a30d784.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;413&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a4e19d459cf53705edb203836a30d784.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why suddenly Admit that you have been married? It turned out that before Chen Muchi released his statement, a screenshot purporting to be his marriage registration information had been quickly circulated on the Internet. The screenshot contains very detailed information, including not only the registration certificate number, registration institution, registrar’s name and registration date, but also personal information such as the ID number and household registration location of both men and women. Some netizens even circulated an unmosaic version. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the melon-eaters discussed with enthusiasm was nothing more than: getting married and divorced at a young age? There was no response to rumors about a relationship on the Internet before, so why did you come out to respond when it was revealed that you were married? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some netizens pointed out that Chen Muchi had to respond because he was &quot;opened&quot;. Because not only his marriage registration information is spread on the Internet, but also his ID card photo, veteran information and personal contact number. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/e216e7cb88a5f40d47751c7ce1ddfeef.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;854&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/e216e7cb88a5f40d47751c7ce1ddfeef.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot; Open the box”? &quot;Unboxing&quot; is not essentially different from &quot;human flesh&quot;. It is an act of publicly exposing the privacy of others on the Internet with the purpose of &quot;breaking the other party&#39;s hypocrisy&quot;. It is actually an act of cyber violence that infringes on personal privacy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, celebrities, like ordinary people, have the right to marry and love freely, and they can choose to do so publicly or not. Although celebrities, as public figures, will be exposed to the public eye and accept comments from the outside world, can their personal privacy be exposed at will and involuntarily? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem of personal privacy leakage reflected in this incident is more serious than many people imagine. Nowadays, any ordinary person will receive sales calls from different banks, credit, and real estate companies every day, and the leakage of personal contact information has become a common occurrence. For celebrities, their ID numbers are almost an open secret. Taking airport pick-up and drop-off as an example, how do fans learn about a celebrity’s travel itinerary? Most of them have the ID numbers and itinerary information of celebrities, and this information usually comes from illegal &quot;scalpers&quot; selling it for a few yuan to dozens of yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/18a2b1484d42333596d077e3559bf7b8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height= &quot;735&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/18a2b1484d42333596d077e3559bf7b8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/208f5fa16d95e7cd3c26e368dbbbbe9a.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;505&quot; height=&quot;404&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/208f5fa16d95e7cd3c26e368dbbbbe9a.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this information, they can not only grasp the star&#39;s schedule, They can also book air tickets and steal their mileage at will. Artists such as Li Chen, Wu Lei, and Jiang Yingrong have all experienced situations where their airplane seats were changed and their mileage was stolen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the desire for voyeurism is infinitely magnified, some people will even use public power to satisfy such dark desires. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Chen Muchi&#39;s marriage registration information was exposed, many netizens questioned the source of the screenshots - from which channel did such detailed personal privacy information leak out? Was it the work of staff from the civil affairs system? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coincidentally, on January 31, 2023, Hu Ge announced that he was getting married and had a daughter. However, because his wife was not a public figure, Hu Ge did not disclose her identity. Someone also exposed Hu Ge&#39;s marriage registration information, allowing netizens to discover that Hu Ge&#39;s wife is a staff member close to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/ae1f0a396113d36fa7ceeb8745b50d52.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;630&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/ae1f0a396113d36fa7ceeb8745b50d52.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254117&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you have a lawyer Popular Science: In real life, no matter lawyers, courts, public security, or procuratorates, they cannot access citizens’ information at will. Citizens’ private information must not be accessed or leaked for non-public needs. Any access will leave traces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/26785e53c02b4b9149ebd6f7b7a5f1bc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;791&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/26785e53c02b4b9149ebd6f7b7a5f1bc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to respond to a Celebrities are &quot;hunting&quot; for privacy, and abusing their power, ignoring the law, and wantonly spreading personal privacy is the most terrifying part of the whole thing. The act of spreading other people&#39;s privacy based on the mentality of taking advantage of others will not only cause secondary harm to the victim, but is actually illegal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 1032, paragraph 1, of the Civil Code stipulates: &quot;Natural persons enjoy the right to privacy. No organization or individual may infringe on the privacy rights of others by means of spying, intrusion, disclosure, disclosure, etc.&quot; The right to privacy protects the privacy of natural persons. It can be seen from the word privacy itself that it has two characteristics: one is &quot;hidden&quot;, that is, it is not a public state. If it has been disclosed by a natural person on his own or legally disclosed, it is not private; the second is &quot;private&quot;, That is, private matters have nothing to do with other people&#39;s rights and interests, public interests, etc. It is from these two aspects that Article 1032, Paragraph 2 of the Civil Code defines privacy as: &quot;A natural person&#39;s private life is peaceful and he does not want others to know about his private space, private activities, and private information.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Article 1033 of the Civil Code stipulates that, unless otherwise provided by law or with the explicit consent of the right holder, no organization or individual may commit the following acts:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;( 1) Intruding on the private life and peace of others through phone calls, text messages, instant messaging tools, emails, leaflets, etc.;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(2) Entering, photographing, and peeping into other people&#39;s homes, hotel rooms, and other private spaces;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;(3) Photographing, peeping, eavesdropping, and disclosing the private activities of others;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(4) Photographing, peeping at the private parts of others’ bodies;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(5) Process other people&#39;s private information;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;(6) Infringe on the privacy rights of others in other ways. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No matter whether you love or hate a person, you should not use the &quot;open box&quot; method to make other people&#39;s legally protected privacy and personal information public, and you must never do anything illegal. Blind tolerance and helplessness will only encourage the voyeurs&#39; desire for control and arrogance, allowing them to hide in dark corners and continue to do whatever they want. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether you are a celebrity or an ordinary person, your right to privacy is protected by law. Legal experts also emphasized that when the legitimate rights and interests enjoyed are illegally infringed, one should immediately call the police and use legal weapons to protect one&#39;s own rights and interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国足协换届选举产生新一届主席、副主席]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258674]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 10:13:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;On October 16, the 12th Member Congress of the Chinese Football Association was held in Beijing to elect new members. A term of executive committee and chairman and vice-chairman. Song Kai was elected as the new Chairman of the Chinese Football Association, and Sun Wen, Yuan Yongqing, Yang Xu, and Xu Jiren were elected as the Vice Chairman of the Chinese Football Association. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“两弹一星”元勋钱学森｜那年今日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258622]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“灵神星”探测器升空：星际采矿还是建立基地？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258664]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;October 13, 2023, 10:19 U.S. Eastern Time (22:19 Beijing time on the same day), carrying NASA The SpaceX &quot;Falcon Heavy&quot; launch vehicle of the &quot;Psyche&quot; probe was successfully launched from the 39A launch pad of the Cape Canaveral Space Launch Base. The probe successfully entered orbit. The two first stages of the launch vehicle All thrusters were recovered and the launch mission was a complete success. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the whole mission has just begun. According to NASA: The probe will have to fly 2.2 billion miles (nearly 3.6 billion kilometers) to reach &quot;16 Psyche&quot; in the main asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter in 2029, and orbit the asteroid for 26 months. scientific investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The magnetometer on board the probe will search for evidence of the asteroid&#39;s ancient magnetic field to prove the theory that it is the remnant of a fragmented planet&#39;s core. Gamma-ray and neutron spectrometers will help scientists determine the chemical elements that make up asteroids. A multispectral imager will provide information about its mineral composition and its topography. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This exploration mission includes many first-of-its-kind scientific and technological innovations: This is the first time a human spacecraft has used Hall-effect thrusters (electromagnetic propulsion) in deep space beyond the lunar orbit. vehicle), driven almost entirely by solar energy, flew to the junction of the inner solar system and the outer solar system; it was also the first time for humans to explore the first M-type asteroid metallic body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA emphasized: This project is the result of comprehensive cooperation between the American scientific community and industry. The main research team is led by Lindy Elkins-Tanton of Arizona State University, and more than a dozen other universities and research institutions participate. The Jet Propulsion Laboratory and Caltech in Southern California assist NASA with scientific management, systems engineering, integration and testing, and mission operations. Maxar Technologies&#39; team in California is responsible for the solar power system and the &quot;Hall electric pusher&quot;. SpaceX&#39;s Falcon Heavy launch vehicle is responsible for the probe launch mission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to NASA&#39;s scientific expedition mission, this project is of great significance to the future development of mankind. It can be said to be the first step in the exploration journey of &quot;interstellar mining&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;16 Psyche&quot; is located in the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter. It was discovered by the Italian astronomer Gasparis on March 17, 1852. It was named after &quot;Greek mythology&quot; by humans. Named after Psyche, the wife of the soul and Eros, the god of love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The long axis of its ellipsoidal body is 225 kilometers, and it is almost entirely made of metal. Its mass is astonishingly large, about 272 million tons, accounting for about 0.6% of the total mass of celestial bodies in the &quot;asteroid belt&quot;. The metal proportion of this asteroid reaches 82.5%, and its main components are iron, nickel, and precious metals such as gold, platinum, and copper. &quot;Forbes&quot; and others value it at between US$1 billion and US$100 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Scientists are curious: Why is the metal content of this asteroid so high? One theory is that it is the remnant core of an early planet in the early stages of the formation of the solar system. During the growth process of a planet, it was hit by other celestial bodies, and its outer crust and mantle were shattered into countless fragments, leaving only bare metal material. The original planetary core. The reason for this speculation is that the small &quot;Psyche&quot; actually has two large impact craters, and there is no sign of water or hydrated minerals on its surface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, human research on the planet’s core is still extremely limited. We have not even drilled through 1/3 of the thin crust, the outermost layer of the Earth’s structure. Research on the mantle and core can only be done. Make inferences based on seismic waves. If &quot;Spirit Star&quot; is indeed proven to be a rocky planetary core, then this cooled planetary core will allow humans to intuitively understand the structure of the planet&#39;s core and gain a deeper understanding of the planet&#39;s origin, evolution, and development. This will further promote the rapid development of geophysical research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NASA’s launch of a probe to the “Spirit Star” is undoubtedly paving the way for the commercialization of space resources in the future. This kind of investment in technology and capital is very long-term. Just like Prince Enrique in the early days of the &quot;Great Navigation&quot;, he continued to invest in the ocean for decades, but it took several generations for the Portuguese royal family to get feedback from the ocean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With human aerospace technology, the cost of mining from extraterrestrials and transporting it back to earth will be so high that 1 kilogram of pig iron is more expensive than the same weight of top-quality diamonds. So, why do NASA and Musk conduct such research and exploration? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author believes that their idea is not to smelt iron on the &quot;Ling Shen&quot; and then send it back to the earth, but to &quot;colonize Mars&quot;. &quot;Ling Shen&quot; is extremely far away from the earth, but relatively close to Mars. &quot;Mars colonization&quot; requires a large amount of building materials. If iron, nickel and other metals from &quot;Spirit Star&quot; are used, it will be much cheaper than transporting materials from the earth to Mars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Iron and nickel are the basic materials for making stainless steel. Using solar energy, space metallurgy is directly performed in a vacuum space environment. The production process is completely different from that on the earth, and no carbon-based energy and catalysts are needed. Musk insists on exploring the application of stainless steel in his &quot;Starship&quot; research and development, rather than the carbon fiber aerospace materials used by other countries. This can be explained logically: they have considered the selection of materials for large-scale infrastructure and manufacturing on extraterrestrial planets. question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Musk has also invested in Solar City to develop solar energy. This can be explained by NASA taking great technical risks to use solar-powered &quot;Hall thrusters&quot; in the &quot;Psyche&quot; mission. pass. In the asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter, solar radiation is already weak, so why choose a less efficient solar drive? It seems that NASA is exploring technology to improve the efficiency of its use under the conditions of low solar energy in deep space. This is the exploratory spirit of &quot;knowing that there are tigers in the mountains, and prefer to travel to the tiger mountains&quot;, which shows his great determination, firm will and actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was young, I played the video game &quot;StarCraft&quot;, and &quot;interstellar mining&quot; was the first step in building a base. Unexpectedly, before reaching old age, human beings have already begun to try to realize their dreams. It can be said that thousands of sails are racing against each other and hundreds of teams are competing against each other. The vision of humanity becoming a space-faring species is getting closer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 09:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“飞越”按摩店：两位盲人的择业折返跑]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258668]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Blind masseur Sun Jingrui is massaging a customer. Photo by Wang Xinyi&quot; src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/34b826dd72.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/15/34b826dd72.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254113&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Blind masseur Sun Jingrui is massaging a customer. Photo by Wang Xinyi&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Wenfeng&#39;s 15-year career as a blind masseur can be divided into two periods: in the first period he struggled with &quot;what can a blind person do&quot;, and in the latter period was he answering &quot;what can I do&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The interval was a two-year escape - in 2019, he decided to escape from the blind employment paradigm and worked as a barista and telephone recruiter in Guangzhou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At about the same time, another blind masseur, Sun Jingrui, also chose to run away. After they briefly crossed paths in Guangzhou, the two lifelines bifurcated again, but they ended up reaching the same destination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the age of 31, Ren Wenfeng returned to his hometown of Huanggang, Hubei Province and reopened a massage parlor in the small county town. He and his wife manage the small shop, which is about 40 square meters, and entertain three or four customers every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;34-year-old Sun Jingrui also returned to the massage parlor, but he chose to work in the metropolis Guangzhou. His store is also closer to the consumption perception of modern urbanites: warm yellow lighting, the fragrance of essential oils, supplemented by Mindfulness meditation. When there are not many customers, Jingrui will write plans or go out to connect resources, like an entrepreneur, thinking about how to build more chain stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to data from the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation, as of 2020, there are 17,300 blind health massage institutions in China. In the common discussion of &quot;What can blind people do without massages?&quot; Ren Wenfeng and Sun Jingrui may have many answers to this question, but one thing is for sure, although returning to a massage parlor may not seem to fit the mainstream narrative, it is Doesn&#39;t mean &quot;failed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Falling into Darkness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Ren Wenfeng and Sun Jingrui are both acquired blind people, which means that they need one more layer of psychological construction than congenitally blind people. They want to eliminate all their once-visible selves, as well as their past thoughts, and learn to live in darkness from scratch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was 8 years old, a wooden stick flew in while playing and changed the direction of Ren Wenfeng’s life. The surgery failed to save his vision, and retinal detachment was a gradual farewell, which was more painful than a sudden plunge into darkness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He began to worry about his future life: Will he have to rely on his parents for the rest of his life? How will I support myself in the future? These questions all point to the same thing: What can a blind person do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day during the summer vacation, he listened to a radio program that introduced summer training classes to people. He called and asked: &quot;What can blind people do?&quot; The other party told him that he should contact the local Disabled Persons&#39; Federation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, the process of Sun Jingrui&#39;s blindness is like a person struggling in the water. When he was in junior high school, he was diagnosed with retinal detachment. Because it is discovered late, surgery is difficult to reverse the damage, which is almost equivalent to being declared blind. The doctor suggested that he go to a school for the blind to adapt to his future outcome in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Sun Jingrui decided to race against his eyesight. He wanted to get into a good university before he lost his sight, so that he could &quot;choose a major that is not too hard on the eyes and continue to live a normal life.&quot; Before suffering from eye disease, Sun Jingrui’s dream was to major in mechanical engineering at South China University of Technology. This was a place where he could realize his dream of becoming an engineer. But in his sophomore year of high school, the fog in front of his eyes became thicker and thicker. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2006 was the year of Sun Jingrui&#39;s college entrance examination. The girl he had a crush on would call him and ask him &quot;When will he come back to class?&quot; She had sorted out the class content and was waiting for him. Sun Jingrui said vaguely &quot;next month.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui could not wait until the day he returned to the classroom. With the disappearance of the last bit of light, he became completely blind. He no longer dares to go out for fear that others will notice the strangeness of his eyeballs. Occasionally, once he goes out every few months, he will outline the surrounding environment in his mind and turn his head frequently, trying to act like he was before he lost his sight. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For discerning people, career planning is a process of continuous focus: &quot;study-weigh-choose&quot;, and finally choose the track you are best at. But for blind people, massage parlors are one of the most common secular choices and one of the few stable careers for this special group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Blind massage parlors are like blind paths in the city, existing but not noticeable. They are scattered throughout the city, set up at street intersections, on the first floor of residential buildings, or between barber shops and grocery stores. Most stores are simply furnished, with a few lamps, a few beds, and one or two chairs placed in fixed locations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ren Wenfeng’s first massage parlor job was in Wuhan, and he was contacted by the Disabled Persons’ Federation in his hometown. The massage shop is located on the second floor of a residential area. Four beds and two sofas are squeezed into the 20-square-meter house. At night, he called his mother and complained: &quot;It&#39;s too shabby. I want to turn around and leave.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But he persisted in the end: &quot;As long as there is a job that a blind person can do, anything can be done.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;In 2011, Ren Wenfeng came to Shanghai from Wuhan. When customers at the massage parlor talked about urban life, Ren Wenfeng stood aside with envy. In his world, the busiest moment in Shanghai is the store celebration in June. The heat wave carries the crowds, sending the noise and footsteps into the store. The masseurs are busy amidst the waves of people&#39;s voices and the sounds of watches. . After the store celebration, the crowd dispersed, leaving the masseur in the dark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the time is monotonous: working from 8 a.m. to 11 p.m., food and accommodation are included in the store, and most of the time is spent waiting. Time just slipped between the thick and deformed fingers. In the view of Ren Wenfeng at the time, &quot;This is a job with no future, or even a present.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ren Wenfeng first worked, his slender and soft hands with clear joints were evaluated as &quot;a pair of hands that can be used to play the piano&quot;; now, after more than ten years in the massage industry, Ren Wenfeng&#39;s His fingers became as thick as a rolling pin. &quot;A hand that specializes in massage,&quot; someone praised him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Sun Jingrui has also noticed changes in his body. The muscles on the back of the hand are broad and thick, and the top of the thumb nail is slightly buckled due to years of exertion. The skin connected to the nail has shed its skin and is slightly white. In Guangzhou, he relieves the pressure on the shoulders and necks of many white-collar workers who sit in offices for a long time, but his own cervical vertebrae are tingling due to long-term fixed posture massage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui is unwilling to live in a traditional massage shop. Pictures of the lives of discerning people in the past remind him from time to time. If he cannot return to the world of discerning people, he must at least make achievements in the massage industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sun Jingrui&#39;s thumb tip is peeling. Photo by Wang Xinyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/537b790619 .png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;877&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/537b790619.png&quot; data-key =&quot;254114&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Jingrui’s thumb tip is peeling. Photo by Wang Xinyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Beyond Making a Living&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The Internet is one of the common channels for visually impaired people to contact the outside world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2018, Ren Wenfeng learned about the &quot;Coffee in the Palm&quot; project of Hemu Innovation Center, a non-profit organization in Guangzhou, through an online forum. This is an activity to train visually impaired people to learn hand-brewed coffee skills and become baristas. As the road was being built in front of the store and business was not booming, Ren Wenfeng closed the massage parlor operating in Wuhan and went to Guangzhou to study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Yingzhang, the head of Hemu Innovation Center, was deeply impressed by him: &quot;I resigned from Wuhan and occasionally do some part-time jobs to supplement my income.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Sun Jingrui also used the Internet to The community gained access to the &quot;Dialogue Academy&quot; project organized by &quot;Dialogue in the Dark&quot;, a Hong Kong social enterprise. He sold the massage parlor he was running and went to Hong Kong alone for training as one of the six members who passed the interview. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unlike Ren Wenfeng who started his career with massage, Sun Jingrui had the consciousness of entering the &quot;mainstream workplace&quot; when he just lost his eyesight. With good English, he once sought opportunities to work as an interpreter through a hotline program on a radio station. This experience ended in failure, which shattered his illusions about employment for the visually impaired. Returning to the field of massage, he also considered entering a hospital. But &quot;total blindness&quot; once again prevented him from getting a stable and decent job. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The problem goes far beyond that. Finding a position that accepts visually impaired people is the first step. After entering the workplace, the challenge really begins. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After becoming blind, more than ten years of experience in massage parlors affected Ren Wenfeng&#39;s character. Sensitivity and low self-esteem were the biggest challenges he faced in the &quot;mainstream workplace&quot;. When he was a barista, some customers would initiate conversations, but he could only respond with silence. In Ren Wenfeng&#39;s narration, his perception of the &quot;mainstream world&quot; is contradictory: like a mirror: on the polished surface facing outward, he wants to be recognized and prove that he &quot;can also accomplish many things&quot;; on the coated surface It is his timidity, he is afraid that others will notice his &quot;difference&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Hong Kong, in order to adapt to the teacher&#39;s rhythm and language environment, Sun Jingrui needs to listen to class recordings repeatedly. &quot;Going to bed at two or three in the morning, and getting up again at six or seven in the morning, because class starts at eight.&quot; During the course, he was deeply touched by two parts. The first part is &quot;self-advocacy&quot;, where visually impaired students learn how to seek help in the workplace; the second part is skills training, including holding regular meetings, taking notes, organizing activities, etc. These ordinary people&#39;s daily work content is very new in Sun Jingrui&#39;s eyes. &quot;There is no such thing in a massage parlor.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When visually impaired people choose other jobs, they always subconsciously compare them with the massage industry. They use the massage industry as a frame of reference to view the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the practical part of the course in Hong Kong, Sun Jingrui needed to design workshops and course content alone in a social enterprise. With the help of his instructor, he gradually grew from an initial &quot;facilitator&quot; to an &quot;implementer&quot; of the project. By&quot;. He gradually discovered: &quot;I can actually do a lot of things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from Sun Jingrui&#39;s discovery of &quot;what he can do&quot; in the workplace, Ren Wenfeng&#39;s experience as a barista made him discover &quot;what he cannot or cannot do&quot; What do you like to do?&quot; Looking back now, Ren Wenfeng feels that knowing &quot;what not to do&quot; is the beginning of career planning - in this sense, although he failed to become an excellent barista, this experience is not a failure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the limited income of a barista, Ren Wenfeng wanted to do something else. His second job is telephone recruitment: 30 phone calls a day that last for more than 30 seconds, corresponding to a basic salary of more than 1,000 yuan; if the other party is willing to submit a resume and successfully joins the job, he will receive a commission. According to Ren Wenfeng&#39;s rough statistics, the call answering rate is about 50%, which means that at least 60 calls need to be made every day. What is more difficult to control is that most of the answerers will hang up the phone in about 10 seconds. Rejection is normal, and what makes Ren Wenfeng even more unbearable are those unfriendly words. After a few months, Ren Wenfeng&#39;s performance was at the bottom of the group because he was not good at speaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Sun Jingrui also experienced telephone recruitment work. He summarized the job as &quot;repetitive&quot; and &quot;boring&quot;: &quot;I keep saying repetitive words every day, and even get scolded.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;In the view of Guo Siyuan, a teacher at the School of Humanities and Social Sciences of the Zhongkai College of Agricultural Engineering: &quot;The uneven quality of education for blind people is the pain point that restricts the employment of people with disabilities.&quot; Ren Wenfeng also described the problems encountered in the &quot;mainstream workplace&quot; The embarrassment is attributed to the lack of education. Blind people only need to learn the skills of living. As for spiritual nourishment and interpersonal communication skills such as literature, history and philosophy, it seems not so important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sun Jingrui&#39;s &quot;Healing Time&quot; store uses warm yellow as the main color. Photo by Wang Xinyi&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/15/da8b8d691c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/da8b8d691c. png&quot; data-key=&quot;254115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Sun Jingrui&#39;s &quot;Healing Time&quot; store uses warm yellow as the main color. Photo by Wang Xinyi&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Seeing” myself&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2021, after returning to Huanggang from Guangzhou, Ren Wenfeng started a family. Now the massage parlor he runs is facing the road, with a small yard behind it. Although it cannot be seen, he bought green plants and table lamps and carefully arranged this imaginary space. In his free time, he would make himself a cup of coffee with the sound of wind chimes and sunshine, waiting for customers and learning something new at the same time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I returned to the massage parlor because I didn’t feel safe enough.” Ren Wenfeng said, “Many jobs are not only unstable, but may also have no income at all.” The stable income brought by massage parlors means that he Be able to feel more confident in front of parents, loved ones and neighbors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Take what you have learned back and open a store. This may be Wenfeng&#39;s most practical choice.&quot; Liu Yingzhang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the rush of big cities, small cities are more casual. The guests communicated with Ren Wenfeng about the details of the massage in their hometown dialect. Sometimes Ren Wenfeng would take the initiative to ask the guests &quot;does it hurt?&quot; He was no longer content to be a silent backdrop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jingrui’s store in Guangzhou opened in 2022. The store staff are partners who met during charity activities, and are supported by startup resources from the Hemu Innovation Center. The concept of the store is to use mindfulness to guide customers to observe their bodies, highlighting the masseurs Masseurs gain recognition through their professional skills and techniques, and no longer rely on selling essential oils and other peripheral products to gain value. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the view of colleague Zhang Jinlan, Sun Jingrui&#39;s attempt to break through traditional massage parlors is &quot;very meaningful.&quot; Many customers will give gifts to the visually impaired masseuses in return, and will also hold their hands and show them the gifts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;White-collar workers like to call Jing Rui by his English name Ray, and some customers call him &quot;dolphin&quot;. He said he likes this nickname: when humans are drowning, dolphins will lift humans to the surface of the water. In daily life, Jingrui is willing to enlighten his visually impaired friends and lift them out of the &quot;ocean&quot; of emotions.每当张金兰在工作上遇到难点时，孙静睿就会罗列出要点，逐条和她讲道理，“他是一个可以并肩作战的伙伴”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙静睿希望帮助更多的视障人士到外面看看，但单枪匹马的“托举”往往有些无力。他不太好意思直接劝，有时会采取“迂回战术”，比如，故作轻松和朋友说：“明天有一个演讲俱乐部，谁有空一起过去玩一下？”朋友们会觉得很新奇，但是一到真的要上台表演的时候，他们又觉得“太害羞了，不行的”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙静睿也曾面临这样的困境。在刘颖璋看来，孙静睿算是这一群体的“精英”。第一次来到该中心参加活动时，孙静睿戴着墨镜，用一口流利的英语和大家打招呼，这种“大哥”气质当时就给刘颖璋留下了很深的印象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在工作中，孙静睿最初也有“依靠明眼人管理者”的思维惯性。目前，合木创新中心的“手心咖啡”和“愈时间”按摩店项目都由视障人士担任管理者，独立带领视障与非视障的员工，共同参与市场竞争，这和以往由非视障人士领导的模式有本质不同。他们希望这种模式能够打破视障者只能在职场中扮演从属者的偏见，有一天，只需稍加引导，他们能主动探索世界。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;孙静睿在网络上广为流传的个人照。网络图片&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/bd761597be.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1264&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/bd761597be.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254116&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;孙静睿在网络上广为流传的个人照。网络图片&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在网络上流传较广的一张照片中，孙静睿身着白衬衫、牛仔裤，戴着墨镜，一只手托着下巴，露出标志性露齿笑。但他记忆中自己的形象，却停留在18岁之前，静睿的梦想是未来有一天，他的视力恢复了，能够亲眼看看身边伙伴的模样，也能看看自己穿上职业装是什么样子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（陈鑫、刘颖璋和深度训练营对本文亦有贡献）&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我们该以什么姿态面对“牺牲者”丨记者手记]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258658]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/z03yFnCJiTOLmMoGQ3hWWPydrAH9HG48GZcsUjV2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1063&quot; height=&quot;681&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/z03yFnCJiTOLmMoGQ3hWWPydrAH9HG48GZcsUjV2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254109&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;年轻时的何协（左）与朋友。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，我去了内蒙古根河市郊的敖鲁古雅鄂温克自治乡采访，使鹿鄂温克人已经搬迁到那儿整20年了。这场搬迁，对鄂温克人来说，最大的变化就是禁枪。这意味着他们传统游猎生活的终结。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我在乡里闲晃，和人谈起枪的事，边上的看客马上给我指路：这得找何老大啊，还有谁能比他更清楚？语气里隐约带有些揶揄的味道——在当时，我并不清楚这里头有什么故事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;找到何老大也不难，大多数时候，他都和妻子卓耶在家门口的长凳上安静地坐着。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何老大的本名叫何协，“中国最后一位女酋长”玛力亚索的大儿子，鄂温克人里最后一代猎民。一到他家门前，他就招呼我坐下，还给我开了瓶海拉尔啤酒，这是他的待客之道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来我才知道，枪在去年刚给何协惹来麻烦。2003年前后收枪时，他私藏了把小口径枪，2022年卖给了别人。被人举报后，法院以倒卖枪支罪判刑。何协搞不清判决书是怎么写的，就记得“判二缓三”，退休金也没了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;好在，何协也没那么在乎钱，够用就行了嘛。两口子靠卓耶每月四千多的退休金过活，是“月光族”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何协的一位朋友和我讲起不久前发生的事。前段时间，何协向他借了500块，说是要拿去还钱。结果，何协还了一百多块的账，剩下的钱全买了卤牛肉和啤酒。三百多买的肉，两口子没吃几筷子，全拿去喂了乡里的狗。“这不是糟蹋钱吗？”提起这事，这位朋友多少还有些生气。他也拿何协没辙，“这家伙，倒是什么也不操心！”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何协的一些举动也的确让人无可奈何。采访期间，我和何协等人一起回了趟搬迁前的老敖乡，当晚在附近民宿住宿。即便民宿大堂醒目地贴着请勿吸烟的告示，何协还是旁若无人地抽起烟来。同行者劝他出去抽，他又犟上了：抽根烟怎么了？现代社会的规矩在他那儿基本是失效的。民宿老板只得再三叮嘱我们，一定要看住何协，房间里可绝对不能抽烟。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在敖乡，他成了“没进步”的一类人。内蒙古社科院民族研究所研究员白兰关注鄂温克人已有三十多年，和何协一家成了老友。她和我讲起，2023年7月，她去敖乡参加一场旅游论坛。碰到何协时，他已经喝到差不多了。乡长赶紧让工作人员把他送回了家，“那么多领导来，（担心）何协搁那儿丢人”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;离开敖乡前，我打算去和何协告个别。一进门，他正躺在屋里闷着头睡觉呢。卓耶告诉我，何协已经在床上躺了一整天，前两天有客人来，高兴，又喝猛了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回到北京后，我读了纪录片导演顾桃写的《敖鲁古雅·敖鲁古雅》，这是他拍摄“鄂温克三部曲”时的日记合集。书里描写的何协同我见到的完全是两副模样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在顾桃的书里，他是山上猎民点神气的“点儿长”。“锯鹿茸时，何协总要对着喷血的茸喝上几口，眼睛眯成缝，卷卷的头发，脸上还溅着血滴，别人看了会吓一跳，他却很享受。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在猎民点，何协的气场能镇住那些偷酒喝的人。“维佳和毛谢（二人都是鄂温克猎民）没有去找鹿，而是搭上顺风车去阿龙山找酒了。中午毛谢和维佳醉醺醺地回来，看到何老大，都悄悄躲回自己家的帐篷睡去了”。“只要何协在点上，玛力亚索就不会担心”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;我忍不住想，要是他们还有枪，还能上山打猎，何协会不会和现在的状态不一样？当然，这只是个无效的假设。只有一两百人的使鹿鄂温克人，融入现代化进程中，是早晚都会发生的事情。而其中总有一两代人，会成为这一进程中的牺牲者。他们上一代，完整地享受了山林中的生活，而下一代，没那么多包袱，又探索出了新的活法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有学者认为，从国家治理的层面上看，这是必须要做出的牺牲。理性的态度是，记住牺牲的那部分人，给予他们及后代一定的补偿，“这才是现实”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;白兰说，她一直在思考，怎么让鄂温克人在发展过程中，有更多自主选择权，让传统得以延续。不过，她到现在，还是没有结论。“作为研究者，有时候我感觉自己是失败的。”听到白兰说出这句话，我心里咯噔一下。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为记者，我能做的，只能是记录下“牺牲者”如今的生活状态，抵抗遗忘。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/CoPO3sir3sJ83J1WYSZA9THj2LsdK3ILWHYsS49V.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1073&quot; height=&quot;771&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/CoPO3sir3sJ83J1WYSZA9THj2LsdK3ILWHYsS49V.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254108&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年7月23日傍晚，何协坐在定居点的马路牙子上喝酒。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者韩谦/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[民政部：去年办理结婚登记683.5万对，比上年下降10.6％]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258666]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/07130c1404f69430cfe64d18eafb5200.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;597&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/07130c1404f69430cfe64d18eafb5200.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254111&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;日前，民政部发布2022年民政事业发展统计公报。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;统计公报显示，2022年，全国婚姻登记机构和场所共计4310个，其中婚姻登记机构1103个，全年依法办理结婚登记683.5万对，比上年下降10.6％。结婚率为4.8‰，比上年下降0.6 个千分点。依法办理离婚手续287.9万对，比上年增长1.4%，其中：民政部门登记离婚210.0万对，法院判决、调解离婚77.9万对。离婚率为2.0‰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a638596c90088e4bd210897dc1617082.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;371&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/a638596c90088e4bd210897dc1617082.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254110&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/f2f977d08aa0a8ce648a89a5e59f8330.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/15/f2f977d08aa0a8ce648a89a5e59f8330.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254112&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[关于幸福这件事：与“哈佛最受欢迎讲师”沙哈尔谈反脆弱和东方哲学]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258577]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/CMxvsLqwcXUy58dsdIxC7UQoClDSXwLnJuFcG6zF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/CMxvsLqwcXUy58dsdIxC7UQoClDSXwLnJuFcG6zF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253690&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（沈煜/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2002年，年轻、拘谨的心理学博士泰勒·本-沙哈尔站在哈佛大学的课堂上，首次开讲“积极心理学“。当时，仅有8名学生选修了他的课，中途又有两人退出。他坚持了下来。在空荡荡的教室里，他每周一次和6个学生探讨一个人生终极之问——如何让自己和别人变得更幸福。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到第二学年，选修的人数激增至380人，有超过20%的学生反馈这门课改善了他们的个人生活；该学年第二学期，有855名哈佛学子选修了这门课。不到一年，沙哈尔的积极心理学成为哈佛最受欢迎的课程，他的另一门课“领导心理学”也是该校最热门的课程之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位刚站上讲台不久的青年学者因此成为哈佛史上最受欢迎的导师之一。在共享精神的推动下，自2006年起，他所讲授的“积极心理学“（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;又被称为幸福课&lt;/span>;）被拍摄、制作成公开课，向互联网免费开放，其影响力迅速溢出哈佛校园，在全球范围内被无数人收看、下载、分享。沙哈尔和主讲“公正”课的哈佛政治学教授迈克尓·桑德尔一道，成了有世界知名度的学者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现年53岁的沙哈尔在以色列出生、长大。他的祖辈是生活在欧洲的犹太商人，在上个世纪的犹太复国运动中，他们携家带口回到上帝恩赐的“应许之地”。在沙哈尔的童年记忆中，身为生意人的祖父每天都会花几小时钻研《希伯来圣经》和《塔木德》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了正统犹太文化的熏陶，他的童年也笼罩在巴以冲突的流血暴力和恐怖事件阴云下。 “每天早上醒来，我们都会担心去学校乘坐的巴士上会有炸弹；去餐厅吃饭，会担心餐厅被炸。”他平静地回忆。对于战争的第一记忆，来自他不满3岁时窗外拉响的警报声。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿时记忆和父祖辈们的坚韧，给沙哈尔留下了难以磨灭的印象。在美国求学并获得学术成功后，他辞去了哈佛教职，回到家乡以色列，创办“幸福研究学院”以推广积极心理学。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在哈佛读书时，他曾跟随著名华裔学者杜维明学习中国哲学。儒家人文主义和道家思想让他既觉得亲切，又有被智慧“点亮“之感。在推广、发展积极心理学的过程中，他也从《道德经》《论语》《大学》这些中国传统经典中汲取理论和实践智慧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新冠疫情暴发前，沙哈尔平均每年两次来中国讲课，他所创办的“幸福研究学院”在中国有四百多名学员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时隔四年，他于2023年9月底再次拜访中国。在上海一家充满1990年代奇特风情元素的酒店内，就创伤、反脆弱、儒道之学，以及如何战胜PTSD（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“创伤后应激障碍”&lt;/span>;）并获得成长等话题，他接受了我——一个对“幸福科学”和工具方法论持部分怀疑立场的中国记者——的采访。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/w7Y894iV4LPPLjmkqLk3Qpe60cvMnPnWW9i6SQ6P.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/w7Y894iV4LPPLjmkqLk3Qpe60cvMnPnWW9i6SQ6P.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253681&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2020年3月27日，受新冠疫情影响，训练馆不开放，一位母亲陪着孩子在小区里进行训练&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;没有人是孤岛——如何应对创伤和无助&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;与四年前比，这次和你的学员、合作者以及学界同行见面交流，你是否觉察到中国人的精神、心理面貌有一些变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我感受到了一些。但是，我在中国所经历观察到的，并非中国独有的。过去三年对人们充满挑战，他们变得比过去更焦虑、更悲伤、更忧心忡忡。我们所面对的挑战，不只是如何克服焦虑、悲伤或者担忧，也是如何在经历这一切后有可能变得更强韧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这正是幸福科学在今天为何如此重要，因为它向我们提供了工具、技巧和建议，帮助我们在经历艰难困苦后有可能变得更强韧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这四年中，你有留意过来自中国的社会心理调查报告，或者和中国的心理学界同行有相关问题的交流吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;2021年，也就是疫情时期，我和清华大学的彭凯平教授有过一场对谈。我们发现：文化差异当然存在，但从全球范围看，人们的相似之处多过不同之处，中国人和美国人、巴西人、德国人、澳大利亚人一样，都比过去有了更多的不安全感和焦虑感。全球大流行病影响到世界各个角落的人。所以，这就是为什么心理学家、政治领袖们需要合作，找到解决问题的办法。这就是为什么我这么期待再次与彭教授对话。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你们那次聊了疫情下哪些社会心理问题？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们谈到纽约大学教授纳西姆·尼古拉斯·塔勒布提出的一个新概念——“反脆弱”，是关于我们在经历艰难、困苦或创伤之后如何有可能获得成长。修复只是恢复到过去的状态，我们还应该从经历中获得成长，不是PTSD，而是PTG（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“创伤后成长”&lt;/span>;）。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，大多数人经历创伤后并没有得到成长，他们要么患上了PTSD，要么有其他形式的心理问题，譬如焦虑、失去安全感、悲伤，甚至抑郁。所以，真正的问题是：我们的学校、机构、家庭能做些什么来帮助大家提升获得PTG的可能性，我们能做些什么来提升反脆弱的能力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有位知名心理学家提出过一个洞察，他说：在中国，社会心理学和文化心理学现在是、未来也继续是心理学研究的主流，因为中国人的精神状态，几乎是被他所处的时代所决定的；而在美国，临床心理学是主流，因为美国人总是想找医生解决他/她的个体精神危机，譬如为什么就是感到不快乐。在这两个精神人格画像如此不同的国度，处于“非主流”的积极心理学能起什么作用？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;确实如此。我想从儒家经典《大学》里找到的一个章节来回答这个问题。孔子的弟子曾子在《礼记·大学》里说：“古之欲明明德于天下者，先治其国；欲治其国者，先齐其家；欲齐其家者，先修其身；欲修其身者，先正其心；欲正其心者，先诚其意；欲诚其意者，先致其知，致知在格物。物格而后知至，知至而后意诚，意诚而后心正，心正而后身修，身修而后家齐，家齐而后国治，国治而后天下平。”儒家认为：一个人如果想在天下倡导美好的道德，应该从自身做起，然后上升到治理好你的家庭，然后到治理好你所在的国，再到天下。你知道杜维明吗？他是我在哈佛时的老师，我跟着他学习儒家人文主义。他讲到孔子是如何从“天下”的大圈子，到国，到家，再到自身，从修身开始。对我而言，中国哲学非常善于把个体的人和社会结合起来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孔子是正确的，如果我们想建立一个更好的社会，我们不能只盯着社会层面的事务，当然也不能只是盯着临床性的（治疗方案）。我们需要从整体性看，从个体、家庭、国家、天下等各个层面分析、理解、行动。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9PlvUXlLLBpC3SxCC6bBVMWoIhmtHCr06tElGUJ7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/9PlvUXlLLBpC3SxCC6bBVMWoIhmtHCr06tElGUJ7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253682&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2020年6月12日，武汉，通往大路的铁门还在封闭中，老巷居民晚餐后自发在家门口跳舞健身&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;能具体讲讲怎么行动？譬如中国的年轻人现在面临就业困难，很多人去考公、考编、考研，竞争也因此变得异常激烈。如果在就业、考公、考研中反复失败，就会导致心理学上说的“习得性无助”。像这种有一定代表性的特定群体心理状态，积极心理学如何发挥作用呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对付“习得性无助”最显而易见的办法，是继续行动。因为“习得性无助”的典型特征，是不再行动，只是放弃、退缩，再次尝试成为一种巨大的挑战。所以，即使你失败了，还是要去尝试，如果失败了五次，就尝试第六次。成功人士，譬如成功的企业家，最重要的特质之一是能做到屡败屡战。这是针对一般情况。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更具体地说，“习得性无助”的解药之一是去帮助他人。我来解释一下：多年来，美国针对高风险人群有过大量社会调查研究。这里所说的“高风险人群”指贫困社区的居民，那里犯罪率通常很高，孩子们在学校里表现糟糕。研究者们最初来到这些贫困区，向那里的居民提供食物、钱等等，为他们提供各种资助项目，结果发现他们中处境得到改变的很罕见。最后，研究者发现：改变他们处境最有效的途径，是让他们起来、去帮助其他人。当他们开始这么做时，就能摆脱“习得性无助”，变成有能力帮助他人的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;用当下中国人的话来讲，这很正能量。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;它确实有效。所以，让我们更幸福的最好办法之一，是思考如何能让他人更幸福，而不是总让自己处于无助状态。就像孔子教导的，把自己和社会、和社区连接起来。此外，它也是一种让人的自我感觉变得更好的方式，这通常是临床心理学所关注的。我们需要开始思考影响社会现实、我们周遭的现实，因为帮助身边的人其实也是在帮助我们自己。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为没有人是孤岛，我们都是整体的一部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/P80kOVKz761jkiIMtGUA8hmR7dKfGgakxO3jtsAn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/P80kOVKz761jkiIMtGUA8hmR7dKfGgakxO3jtsAn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253680&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年1月11日，以色列耶路撒冷，医护人员为民众做核酸检测&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;有灵性的生活&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;作为一名积极心理学家，你在疫情期间、特别是封锁隔离期是如何度过的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;首先，我不时会感到挣扎。生活确实变得艰难了。你知道我很渴望到中国来，我也渴望拥抱我的朋友们。我大概有一年多没法见到父母。我们住在美国的新泽西，而我父母都在以色列，他们年纪都很大了，我们很担心他们会感染新冠，但又没办法旅行。我非常想念他们，这很有挑战性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也没法和朋友们去餐厅吃饭。我们家经常有朋友来拜访，门总是开着的，很多人进进出出，我和妻子的朋友、孩子们的朋友。突然间，疫情来了，房子里只有我们和孩子。我们当然要为已有的一切感恩，但是没法看到我们所爱的人，不能和他们在一起，总是艰难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，我主要的工作内容是上课、做讲座，所以经济层面也面临挑战。所以，在很多方面，我的感受都很挣扎。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了面对这些挑战，我回到了积极心理学最基本的方法：譬如，我知道健身对良好生活来说很重要，我过去每周运动三次，疫情期间就增加到五次；我过去每天都做正念训练，现在增加更多训练，有时做瑜伽，有时是太极，有时是气功，有时冥想；我也尽可能和家人有更多时间在一起，每天全家人都在一起吃晚饭，交谈，有时也会哭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也继续保持工作，继续写作，继续阅读。最重要的是，允许自己经历所有这些情绪，不要和悲伤情绪决斗，不要想着消灭焦虑，接受它们的存在，允许这些情绪、感受像水一样流过我的心灵，那是老子所运用的比喻，不要试图“拉黑”或是阻止、打断它们。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;封锁时，你有过情绪失控的时刻，譬如对孩子大喊大叫？毕竟，和3个十来岁的孩子整天待在一个房子里，这也很有挑战性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是很有挑战性。我一般不会朝孩子大喊大叫，但有时确实被他们搞得很火大。即使现在可以自由外出了，我有时依然会被他们搞得很火大。我认为很重要的是，父母爱孩子的同时，还要为他们设立界限。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，疫情期间，当我的一个孩子没有做学校布置的功课时，我非常生气，我告诉他必须做出改变，因为老师已经投诉了。人们认为你是个教授幸福学的教授，你的家里就一定一直充满快乐、和谐的气氛。但实际不是这么回事。你必须理解这一点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;想问一个很私人的话题，你有宗教信仰吗？个人感觉，积极心理学是一门强调价值中立的社会科学。但是，相比一套工具、方法，一个人能够长期保持积极、健康的心理状态，价值、信念甚至宗教会不会更为重要呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我有宗教信仰。但在我的课上，我强调的一个重点是——我们每个人都能够过一种富有灵性的生活，无论是否皈依某种宗教。因为当我们找到了自己做事的意义，我们就拥有了灵性生活。我可以是一名教师，可以是一名机构管理者，我在我的工作里找到意义感，因此感受到灵性。我可以从养家中找到意义，也有了灵性体验。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，与其是说我是宗教性的人，不如说我是灵性的。在我的个人生活和职业里，我都感受到意义和目标。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;看来，我们似乎都认同一点——在积极心理学的冰山之下，必须有更为基础性的东西，如价值、信念、信仰或者宗教等等。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;的确如此。这些东西会让我们拥有人生的目的，在生活里找到目的。我再一次强调，我们可以在不同领域找到它，有些人在信仰里找到，有些人在工作里找到，有些人在家庭里找到，或是在其他地方找到。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总之，去做一些你相信的、对你来说重要的、意义重大的事。那就是关键所在。如果你想做得很好，并且能长期坚持下去，你也需要找到你天赋所在的地方。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你来自以色列，有犹太文化背景。从你自己的家族、族群的生命故事中，可曾总结过一些经验或智慧？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很多人问我，为什么你来中国的次数比到其他国家更多，为什么你会有这么多中国学生。我回答说我第一次来中国大概是20年前，感觉很像回到了自己的家乡。这是真的。因为犹太传统和中国传统有很多相似的价值观，譬如重视家庭、家族，家的观念在我们的历史里很重要。我感觉自己和中国有很强的连接，包括和中国的历史、中国的哲学。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于你问我从我的先祖和族群史上学到了什么？首先，我们能够克服长久以来的苦难，是依靠与力量之源的连接，包括自然和社群。这是两个非常关键的因素。我所说的自然，既指外部世界，也包括我们作为人类的天性。所以，老子谈到向自然学习的重要性。道家说“道法自然”，地之道，天之道，即“道”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我想和你分享《道德经》上的一段话：“人法地，地法天，天法道，道法自然。”当我们和自然连接，就能从中获取力量。这是力量的第一源头，然后是第二源头。儒家谈到最多的是社群，并大量地谈到了社群在一起时的种种仪式。在犹太教中，当家族成员在一起时，我们也有很多仪式。我去中国朋友家做客时，经常会和他们的父母、有时是和祖父母们坐在一起。他们通常都说中文，我听不懂他们在说什么，但是我能理解这种连接，因为在以色列也能看到相同场景。那就是我们犹太人的力量之源——自然、社群，也包括家庭。就像儒家所教导的：从自身到家庭，再到更大的群体——国、天下。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我想问一个更富个人经验的问题。记得我童年时，每天几乎都能从电视上看到关于巴以冲突的国际新闻，包括自杀式袭击，当时觉得十分可怕。你的童年、青少年在以色列度过，这种来自外部世界的暴力信息甚至经历，对你和你的小伙伴们有困扰吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;你知道我是在以色列长大的。每天早上醒来，我们都会担心去学校乘坐的巴士上会有炸弹；去餐厅吃饭，会担心餐厅有炸弹。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我对战争的第一记忆来自我不满3岁时，当时街上响起了警报声，我们不得不冲到地下避难所躲起来，因为担心会被炸伤或者炸死。所以，你理解了我是在怎样的环境里长大的，我经历了这些东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;不满3岁啊，作为一个孩子，怎么面对这种每天和死神擦肩而过的恐惧？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;沙哈尔：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;就像你应对所有其他的创伤、困难和艰难一样。你身边有社群支撑你。你谈论它，把它写下来。同时，坚持锻炼，找到对你来说有意义的事，找到你可以表示感谢的事。当我们面对创伤性经历时，这些办法总是有用的，不管遇到的是新冠疫情、失业，还是失去了所爱之人。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些都是幸福科学所教给我们的工具和技巧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[游客擅自穿越被四姑娘山终身禁入：户外探险应合法合规且风险自担丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258650]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，四川阿坝州四姑娘山景区管理局通报，2名游客违反规定私自在景区内进行徒步穿越，对其实行终身禁入。近年来，此类私自组织的徒步穿越活动很多，发生险情的也不在少数。对于这些违规户外活动，一方面要加大处罚力度，另一方面，也要让公众的探险热情有出口，可以开发一些穿越路线，让探险者去冒险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据四姑娘山景区管理局日前通报，王某、采某两名游客购买门票进入景区，随后无视景区内的标牌提示和工作人员劝阻，在景区内开展徒步穿越。但因为当晚下了雪，两人报警求助，被救援下山。通报称，两人违反了景区的禁止规定，给景区的保护、管理造成一定的危害和恶劣影响，因此决定禁止二人终身再次进入四姑娘山景区进行观光等一切形式的旅游。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于景区管理局这一决定，很多网友表示赞同。四姑娘山并非普通风景区，它是世界自然遗产、国家级自然保护区。景区管理局是事业单位，根据阿坝州政府授权对景区进行管理。这两名游客虽然是购买门票合法进入景区，但随后私自进行徒步穿越，违反了景区的禁止性规定，管理局有权禁止他们再次进入景区。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;禁入成为不少景区对严重违规的游客采取的选项。 2023年以来，因为向大熊猫吐水、拍打大熊猫兽舍玻璃等不文明行为，有多名游客被成都熊猫基地宣布1年内禁入、5年内禁入、终身禁入。 2021年，3名游客在长城城墙上刻字，被北京延庆文旅部门列入不文明旅游“黑名单”，当地12家景区联合禁入。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，不少网友认为，单纯禁入都算不上处罚，对擅自穿越等严重违规行为应该加重处罚，并要求其承担救援费用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加重处罚也是有法可依的。根据国务院制定的“自然保护区条例”，未经批准进入自然保护区或者在自然保护区内不服从管理机构管理的，可以根据不同情节处以100元以上5000元以下的罚款。 2019年，7名驴友擅自在四川卧龙国家级自然保护区进行徒步穿越，结果1人遇难。另外6人就被保护区管理局处以每人5000元罚款，并要求他们承担医疗费用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;越野、穿越等户外探险活动近来受到越来越多人追捧。但此类活动有不少涉及官方已经明确禁止的线路，而且往往由于后勤保障不足、避险意识不够等原因，发生遇险事故。如2021年五一假期，秦岭山区发生多起“驴友”非法穿越中失联或遇难的事件。驴友们热衷穿越的“鳌太线”，早已被陕西太白山国家级自然保护区管理局、陕西省森林公安局等部门明令禁止穿越。但这些穿越活动仍屡禁不绝，且屡屡发生驴友遇险事件，需要各方进行救援。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些救援往往要投入极大的人力物力。比如2022年2月驴友在西藏冒雪转山遇险，当地出动100多名公安民辅警、基层干部和农牧民，20多台救援车辆，9匹马，在冰天雪地、狂风暴雪中冒险搜救20多个小时。 2021年5月，上海男驴友在秦岭穿越途中失联，事发后，共有10多支专业救援队200多人携带无人机等设备进山开展地毯式搜救。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样大规模的搜救行动，成本是非常高的。这些救援费用该由谁出？随着此类事件越来越多，官方救援机构不堪重负。不少地方开始施行有偿救援。 2018年7月开始生效的安徽黄山有偿救援办法规定，对违反景区规定，擅自进入未开发、未开放区域而遇险的游客实行有偿救援，要求违规游客承担救援过程中产生的劳务、院前救治、交通、意外保险、后勤保障、引入第三方救援力量等费用。 2018年8月，四川甘孜亚丁景区也宣布将对违规游客实行有偿搜救制度，搜救费用按不同区域，分别为1.5万元和2万元起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，有偿搜救不是先给钱再救人。有人遇险求救，救援机构还是要第一时间出动救援，毕竟人命关天。但是在救援结束后，应该对救援费用进行结算，由被救援者承担。如果拒不支付，可以通过法院诉讼等方式强制执行。如果被救援者遇难，则从他的遗产中支付。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，探险也是人类的天性。探险活动可以激发人们挑战极限的勇气。真正的探险家往往也会受到大众的敬仰。一味禁止也不能完全杜绝驴友们去穿越。堵不如疏。可以考虑适当开放一些热门穿越路线，并在沿途设置一定的应急设施，降低穿越的难度。同时要明确，户外探险是高风险的活动，即使准备充分，也可能出现意外情况。知名潜水探险家韩颋日前在广西九顿天窗进行洞穴潜水时就遭遇意外不幸身亡。户外活动参与者要充分了解风险，做好后勤保障准备，并自行承担可能出现的风险。如果需要救援，也要自费。承担不了这些风险的话，那最好还是不要去玩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[高端家教与留守儿童，时髦机车与过期月饼丨人在职场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258648]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-15 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;两年前，在我的哈佛实习心理学导师逝世后，我有些悲伤，打算短暂地把视野从实验室文献转向生活中的心理学案例。恰好，一名“高端家教”机构老师找到我，我对此颇感兴趣，在2021年7月至2023年4月期间，我短暂地窥探了一下这个圈子。2023年5月之后，我又接触了本地留守儿童公益补习班的圈子。两个圈子有着不同的用语、生活方式、情感模式、家庭架构，颇值得玩味。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在匹配高端家庭之前，大概的流程是要准备中英文简历，罗列自己相关的家教经历以及一分钟的英文自我介绍视频。然后，由中介机构进行双向的匹配，有驾照、教师资格证、幼教证书可以加分，画画、钢琴、跳舞等特长也在众多家长的要求范围之内。一般来说，家长都颇为挑剔，而随着英美本科、研究生学历的毕业生积极涌入这一行业，这个目标月收入在一万五到三五万元的工作岗位，应聘难度也水涨船高，一般要面试8-10个家庭才可能有回音。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我面试的近10个家庭中，需求普遍聚集在北上广深杭五大城市，其余零星分布的家庭也在这些城市周围。这些家庭大多数住在别墅或者300平以上的大平层，配备保姆、司机、管家，大多由母亲单独面试（只有一个家庭由父亲出席，母亲上班赚钱），父亲不在家中。母亲的需求大多数是需要老师制定作息时间表和学习计划，并监督执行，接送孩子上下学和完成课外作业，小部分的家长有竞赛需求。更懂心理学和教育的家庭，会提出开发孩子智力和抓住语言发展黄金期的要求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;举某一特大城市家长的例子来说，父母双方均为香港硕士，家中有三个小孩，居住在比较偏僻的别墅群，家中有外公外婆同住，母亲全职陪伴小孩，父亲每天往返两个城市，基本没有时间照看孩子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在我接手陪伴两个小朋友的时候，小朋友英文水平很高，在民办学校读书，兴趣爱好广泛。4岁男孩A是这个家庭的第二个孩子，喜欢时髦的小汽车，妈妈会买一整墙壁时髦的小汽车和相关的汽车绘本，见到我会说：“Hi, teacher, I hope you like this motorcycle!”7岁女孩B是姐姐，喜欢绘画和芭蕾，在地下室有自己专属的练舞房和画室，在附近地区的大型赛事中均取得过名次。每周除了上课，老师需要周末陪他们参加足球班、游泳课、芭蕾舞班以及数学竞赛班。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这位母亲打算未来利用孩子的香港身份证，让孩子通过联考进入内地顶尖高校，或者DSE进入香港名校读本科。若未来移民，就留美读书，可进可退。因此，孩子在民办学校读书并不用功，始终觉得自己和普通小孩不一样，有优越感。很明显的是，三个孩子情绪健康，活泼积极，爱跟人打招呼，毫不怯场，也不畏难，每天过着无忧无虑的生活，在快乐之中健康平安地长大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可是，小学的孩子每天还需要保姆帮忙刷牙洗脸换鞋，孩子母亲也期待家庭教师亲力亲为帮孩子整理内务，从心理学的角度，我觉得这么做多多少少会妨碍孩子的自主性发展。5月，我辞去了这份家庭陪伴师的工作，短暂在家休息。一个亲戚找上我：你有没有兴趣利用业余时间给留守儿童补课呢？不需要全天，每天三个小时就好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;得知孩子们的基本情况后，我欣然应允。我的工资在三五千元不等，可以说是大缩水。对留守儿童这一群体来说，需要很多帮助，并且要从最基础的做起。打个比方，最初我买了一本小升初的数学补习资料给初一女孩C，帮助她过渡衔接初中知识。但是她不会算分数，1/5+1/5，她算下来等于1/10。小测下来，只有20分左右。究其原因，老师说是小学贪玩，缺乏基础。在我看来，很有可能是过去几年都没有开发数学智力，现在13岁才开始正儿八经地学习数学知识，很可能需要手把手的数学启蒙。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我跟留守儿童相互陪伴了一段时间。从英语方面来说，由于乡镇小学缺少英语老师，他们没学过英语，高端家庭的小孩A和B完全可以胜任他们的家庭小老师；数学，很差劲；语文，没读过课外书。由于经济水平的限制，也没有用过电脑和产生网瘾。因为父母长期不在家，睡眠不足，饮食不好，常常无精打采，也不知道如何好好地利用补习时间跟老师互动，主动提问和谈论自己的困扰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与女孩C的母亲谈及未来，孩子想转学到她附近的学校，可是那所学校很差劲，附近也没有补习班。“老师，你看我的孩子是读书这块料吗？”妈妈表示感激我送《你当像鸟飞往你的山》这样的励志书籍给孩子，鼓励她多自学。女孩的父母均高中毕业，很好说话，对女儿的情况很关心，每天都会微信发消息给我聊几句，态度很好。而女孩自己，没有兴趣爱好，不爱说话，有一只跟母亲打电话用的智能小手表，用着破旧的书包。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中秋刚过，本地机构的老师送来一盒月饼，仔细一看，第二天过期。本来想分享几个给小朋友，但是算了。无论是时髦的机车，还是快过期的月饼，每一种生活，都有它本身的滋味。而在这两种互不交叉的社会阶层背后，是值得我在未来科研生活和应用实践中重新锚定的新方向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（文中家庭隐私信息已模糊处理，如有雷同，纯属巧合。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者系香港城市大学本科毕业生）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目之“人在职场”，欢迎来信分享职场心声、吐槽职场经历、打破刻板印象、揭秘行业规则。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>