<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“雅思组合”蝉联亚运金牌，剑指巴黎奥运欲补遗憾]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258242]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/08/VZnJEmGbnPVkkQZsVnhsghW5cspqXy32xlLgoLs1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/VZnJEmGbnPVkkQZsVnhsghW5cspqXy3 2xlLgoLs1. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253363&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, the champion Chinese combination Zheng Siwei and Huang Yaqiong (right) Group photo at the award ceremony&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Which event is the most stable for the Chinese badminton team? The list includes men’s singles before Lin Dan retired, Ge Fei/Gu Jun, Gao Ling/Huang Sui, Yang Wei/Zhang Jiewen, Du Jing/Yu Yang, Zhao Yunlei/Tian Qing, Chen Qingchen/Jia Yifan’s women’s doubles, Zhang Ning , the women&#39;s singles during the Xie Xingfang period...and the Chinese mixed doubles before the 2018 to 2021 Tokyo Olympics and the 2022 to 2023 World Championships: a pair of Chinese pairs once dominated the world and became the absolute king among many mixed doubles pairs. The Badminton World Federation ranking points have exceeded an unprecedented 110,000. They are Zheng Siwei/Huang Yaqiong, known as the &quot;IELTS combination&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2017, the Chinese badminton team made adjustments and split the top two mixed doubles players Zheng Siwei/Chen Qingchen and Lu Kai/Huang Yaqiong into a new combination of Zheng Siwei/Huang Yaqiong. The two formed a team to compete in November 2017. In the first half of 2018, they broke into the top ten in the world and reached the top of the world in August of the same year. In the 2018 season, he won 9 mixed doubles championships, broke 4 world records in 5 months, and ranked first in the world with a huge points advantage. In 67 games in 2019, they were 59-8. In the past two years, the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; has won the World Championships championship, successively won the All England Open, Asian Games championship, year-end finals and other championships. With an undefeated record, it helped the Chinese team win the International Badminton Team Championship Su Diman Cup, becoming the most dominant mixed doubles combination in the Tokyo Olympic cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F6yZl3IJeDDwpo94ZHEu1ys8uyvjJt2DVCOE9x5C.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F6yZl3IJeDDwpo94ZHEu1ys8uyvjJt2DVCOE9x5C.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253360&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, in the badminton mixed doubles final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese combination Zheng Siwei (top) and Huang Yaqiong (bottom) defeated the Japanese combination Watanabe 2-0 Yongda and Higashino Arisa won the championship &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first half of 2022, Zheng Siwei and Huang Yaqiong will be paired up After regrouping, they won 7 consecutive season championships within 5 months, including the third world championship. After that, they won three championships in the second half of the year, including the Badminton World Tour Finals, and were awarded the &quot;Best Group of 2022&quot; award by the Badminton World Federation. The two set a record of 38 consecutive unbeaten games, with a winning rate of 96%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from the 2023 season, the old rivals of the &quot;IELTS combination&quot;, the Korean combination Seo Chenjae/Cai Yujing, have made rapid progress. When the two sides meet, it usually takes three games to determine the winner. In the last two matches (the 2023 World Badminton Championship final on August 27 and the 8-4 match at the China Badminton Open on September 8), they defeated the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; consecutively and became the latter&#39;s current extremely important opponent. In the badminton mixed doubles semi-finals of the 2023 Hangzhou Asian Games, the two pairs met again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past month, the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; encountered some controversy due to two consecutive losses. In the comments on the game video, you can often see fans questioning the two&#39;s decline in form. For the third time in two months, the result was particularly important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/eWEd6kb9faaQQU0jefLEgF8vUaSf4TvVJUn37bK6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/eWEd6kb9faaQQU0jefLEgF8vUaSf4TvVJUn37bK6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253365&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, the badminton mixed doubles final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the champion Chinese combination Zheng Siwei (first from left) and Huang Yaqiong (second from right) and the runner-up Japanese combination Yuta Watanabe (Second from left) and Arisa Higashino (first from right) shake hands and greet each other after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in 2021 From 2022 to 2022, the IELTS combination has experienced a more severe &quot;dark moment&quot;. The period before and after the Tokyo Olympics is also considered by the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; to be the most difficult stage in their mixed doubles career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year, Zheng Siwei is 24 years old and Huang Yaqiong is 27 years old. For athletes, their bodies are at their peak. During the Tokyo Olympics cycle, they won the championship in almost all mixed doubles competitions except the Olympic Games. They were high-spirited and pointed at the championship podium in Musashino Forest. However, it backfired as they lost to teammates Huang Dongping/Wang Yilu in the Olympic final and won the silver medal. After returning to China, they lost to the opponent again in the National Games final. The two took a break in the next Sudirman Cup, but after getting ready, they ushered in the second round of the 2021 World Championships (a first-round bye) and lost to the little-known Hong Kong combination Zhang Dezheng/Ng Yongrong, and were upset. For a while, the fans were talking a lot, unable to accept such a gap. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Yaqiong said that she felt two different pressures before and after the Tokyo Olympics: before the game, she was anxious about not being able to train normally due to injuries to her partner, but she wanted to get good results in the Olympics; after the game, It&#39;s the loss of the game that leads to a sluggish state, and the confusion of not knowing where to start. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After research, the national team coaching staff decided to split the &quot;IELTS&quot; first. Huang Yaqiong recalled that before the split, her coach had a long talk with her and asked her to think carefully, &quot;You will be 30 years old in the next Olympics. Do you have the courage to persist until then?&quot; She replied firmly: &quot;I think Fight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F7DnixpOVw6WJSVIW2BjNTTIdlJPz5rWfZTojIrR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/F7DnixpOVw6WJSVIW2BjNTTIdlJPz5rWfZTojIrR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253364&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, in the badminton mixed doubles semi-finals of the Hangzhou Asian Games, South Korean combination Seo Seung-jae and Chae Yoo-jung (right) competed&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two entered winter training with Zhang Shuxian and Ou Xuanyi respectively. Before the start of the new season, Zheng Siwei/Zhang Shuxian won the first place in the team&#39;s round-robin competition, but they were eliminated in the first round of the German Open. Huang Yaqiong and Ou Xuanyi, who performed averagely in the round-robin competition, entered the finals and finished second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the low ranking of the new combination and the ineligibility to register for high-level tours, the IELTS combination was briefly reorganized at the All England Open in March 2022. Facing the not-so-strong French player in the first round, the two fought hard for three games and won. After the game, Yaqiong said to Si Si: &quot;Why is the game a bit tight?&quot; Si Si answered frankly: &quot;I feel a little lack of confidence.&quot; After several efforts, they broke into the semi-finals and reunited with Wang Yilu/Huang Dongping, but Still failed to achieve a breakthrough, lost 1:2 and missed the finals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Yaqiong believes that she can clearly feel that her old partner is always short of breath and has no confidence. &quot;It&#39;s rare to see his mind in this state on the court. He used to be positive and dominate the game on the court. In the first game, I noticed that he was not as determined as before, and he couldn&#39;t handle the ball easily. No. Like his usual style.&quot; Zheng Siwei felt the change in Huang Yaqiong: &quot;My confidence was very low at the time, but Yaqiong was very different from before. She took the initiative to encourage me and was able to completely stabilize the situation on the court.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;After the All England Championships, Zheng Siwei&#39;s injury relapsed and it was difficult to walk. &quot;My style of play is very taxing on the body and ability. Now that my legs are not good, how can I still play? If I want to continue playing, I must improve (condition), maintain (strength), and practice more. However, practicing more will conflict with injuries. , it felt like the sky was falling.&quot; He recalled the dilemma he faced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The coach asked them for their opinions on registration for the Asian Championship pairing. Zheng Siwei said: &quot;I still choose Yaqiong. From that time, we have already confirmed the pairing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After that, it was the familiar 30-game winning streak script. Before the 2022 World Championships, the two were worried about whether they would waste all their good luck in the previous open competitions, fearing that they would be worse in the big competition. Because I had been on a &quot;round trip&quot; before, I felt a little bit confused. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They had a bye in the first round of the World Championships. When they debuted, they encountered a fierce blockage from the young Thai combination Supac/Supisara and lost the second game 19-21. The decisive game was once trailing 13-17. Huang Yaqiong said in an interview after the game: &quot;When we were behind 13-17, we got a point and caught up to 14-17. It was my turn to serve and I felt that my heart had settled down. After the game, my thinking also told me, That&#39;s when he felt very stable and we had no problem.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the end, they made it all the way and won their third World Championship title. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/q6ClwTmtLd2PPYA47BtYXXFOGeavF1GnEL6mJtwP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;596&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/q6ClwTmtLd2PPYA47BtYXXFOGeavF1GnEL6mJtwP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253362&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 6, 2023, in the badminton mixed doubles semifinals of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese combination Zheng Siwei (left) and Huang Yaqiong (right) defeated the South Korean combination Seo Seungjae 2-1 , Cai Youjing, advanced to the finals &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the eyes of coach Yang Ming, the reorganized &quot;IELTS&quot; has reached another level : &quot;It was a good thing for them to be separated for a while. The two of them joined forces again and both have grown more than before.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Huang Yaqiong recalled that the two would argue endlessly when they had differences before, but in the end there was no result. Now Zheng Siwei will listen to her opinions and try together to see whose method is more effective. Zheng Siwei believes that Huang Yaqiong is &quot;better able to handle it.&quot; &quot;The main feature and score of our combination lies in me. In the past, she would be affected by my poor condition, make mistakes together, and have a series of negative reactions. But now, no matter what I do, Yaqiong can handle it. I&#39;m good, She is better; I am worse, she can stand up... Maybe it is because since we cooperated, we have always been better in good times than in bad times, and we have not had much deliberation on how to solve problems in adversity. If we had not separated in those three months, we would still have been together. Continuing to hold it together and work together may have negative effects. It seems that we can&#39;t solve this kind of thing together. Once we get over this emotion in a new environment and new partners, we may not need to solve it in particular when we come back.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With such a process from the bottom to the top, fans still have full confidence in them despite their anxiety about the two losing streak. Therefore, whether Seo Seung Jae/Chae Yoo Jung will win or lose in the semifinals of this Asian Games has become an important battle for whether the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; can overcome the psychological barrier. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the game, the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; failed to find a rhythm and had no effective scoring methods, and lost the first game 13-21. In the second game, &quot;Yasi&quot; actively adjusted and entered the defense by taking the initiative to pick the ball, looking for counterattack opportunities in the multi-shot stalemate, and regained the game 21-15. In the deciding game, &quot;IELTS&quot; fell behind 2-6 at first, but took the lead before 11 points. After that, &quot;Yasi&quot; played more resolutely and put all the pressure on his opponent. The opponent became tighter and tighter, making consecutive mistakes such as serving the ball and hitting the ball out of bounds. 21-16, they finally got what they wanted. After scoring the winning point, Zheng Siwei couldn&#39;t help but roar. During the game, Zheng Siwei no longer just attacked hard, but added changes in offense; Huang Yaqiong improved her marking and follow-up speed in front of the net. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/LarRnS4uOvigimfHN9fARGiV4ZuiLQH93xCCTZlp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/LarRnS4uOvigimfHN9fARGiV4ZuiLQH93xCCTZlp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253361&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 30, 2021, in the 2020 Tokyo Olympics badminton mixed doubles final, the Chinese combination Wang Yilu and Huang Dongping defeated their teammates Zheng Siwei and Huang Yaqiong 2-1&lt;span style=&quot;color : #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the game, Zheng Siwei said: &quot;We just shouldered them, played multiple shots with them, and took the initiative to play offense and defense with them. , In fact, the probability that our opponent will attack us is not very high.&quot; During the game, every time a point was scored, &quot;YELTS&quot; would be shouted three times. Zheng Siwei said that the fight to the end was no longer a purely technical and tactical contest, but more of a psychological contest. If you only shout once every time you score a point, your opponent will not feel the pressure and have to shout twice more. &quot;In the end, they will indeed be frightened and the serve will go into the net.&quot; Huang Yaqiong said: &quot;Actually, I There were times when I was not determined. After the 11-minute interval in the deciding game, my energy dropped a little, but my thinking kept encouraging me, and I also mobilized myself by shouting.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With this victory, IELTS The combination is as powerful as a rainbow. In the Asian Games badminton mixed doubles final on October 7, 2023, they defeated Japanese combination Higashino Arisa/Watanabe Yuta 2:0 (21-15/21-14) and retained the Asian Games mixed doubles championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the fight continues, my goal is the Olympics and Paris.&quot; Huang Yaqiong said after that conversation. Now, this goal is less than 10 months away. Can the &quot;IELTS combination&quot; that has returned to the top make up for the regrets of the Tokyo Olympics? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新的中东战争爆发？以色列的猝不及防和犹太社区的自发秩序]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258248]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 6:30 in the morning on October 7, 2023, the 50th anniversary of the &quot;Fourth Middle East War&quot; , Hamas launched a surprise attack on Israel. The Israeli intelligence system, which was once considered the most sophisticated, was completely unaware of the opponent&#39;s large-scale war preparations; the Israel Defense Forces, known for its elite, was completely unprepared and was caught off guard; and the once effective social &quot;militia&quot; The &quot;system&quot; (employing troops among the people) also failed to give full play to the rapid response effect in the previous &quot;Middle East wars&quot;, resulting in a large number of civilian casualties. Throughout the day, the two sides fought inextricably, and another powder keg started to smoke. Human society is really in trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During dinner, I received a message from a friend in Canada: Due to this conflict, his Jewish community will raise more than 13.6 million Canadian dollars to aid Jewish compatriots, and his family will spread it to Nearly 550,000 Canadian dollars (approximately equivalent to 2.9 million yuan). very scary! Why do you want so much money? After some communication, I learned some little secrets of today’s Jewish community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This friend married a Jewish woman, gave birth to three children, was accepted as a Jew, and moved into a Jewish community in Canada consisting of 98 Jewish households. Jewish social rules are very special: they are based on matrilineal descent, and children born from the marriage of a foreign man to a Jewish woman are accepted as Jews. Children born from marriage between foreign women and Jewish men are not considered Jews, but only foreigners with Jewish genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New families entering the Jewish community, including foreign men who marry them, can enjoy the benefits of the community and must also assume the community&#39;s covenant obligations, including: infrastructure maintenance, cleaning, night shift duty, and security Services, school children&#39;s education, scholarships, religious services, psychological help, poverty relief, etc. A friend said: His children receive tens of thousands of Canadian dollars in scholarships and various benefits from the community every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the wool comes from the sheep. These benefits are not provided by the Canadian government, but are raised by their small Jewish community. Specifically: each family in the community has to pay a share of 165,000 Canadian dollars (approximately equivalent to 875,000 yuan) per year, and 1,600 per year. More than 10,000 Canadian dollars are the community&#39;s common fund to provide community survival operations, repairs and updates, security services, and mutual assistance. Equivalent to owner-operated properties, cleaning, security, social security, churches, teaching assistants and many other institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This community mutual fund is managed and paid by the rabbi. All accounts are open to all families and every member of the community. Decisions are made at community meetings, so there is no corruption or waste. This is a tradition and skill developed by the Jewish people who are good at financial management for thousands of years. Only by shrewdly watching their own money and not being misappropriated by power can each individual ensure that the wealth of the entire group and society is protected from theft and corruption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jewish Community Mutual Fund also has a high-value internal resource: teaching assistants. It is not a supplementary lesson, but a thinking course outside of school teaching. There are Jewish &quot;wise men&quot; who preside over the cultivation of children&#39;s values, ways of thinking, and methodology training... among which &quot;Tanach&quot; and &quot;Talmud&quot; are very important. The result is that Jewish children have great advantages in academics and business, Indians are good at being professional managers, and Jewish young people are better at cutting-edge high-tech, financial elites and startup company bosses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jewish households in this community all have high incomes and live in single-family houses with large yards and swimming pools. But even so, not every household can pay the full amount of 165,000 Canadian dollars every year. The community&#39;s approach is: those with money contribute money, those with power contribute, and those with talents contribute people, which is converted into a certain workload to undertake the above-mentioned community services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That friend’s father-in-law and brother-in-law are expanding a new Jewish community in Perth, Western Australia. In this emergency, there was no contribution or help, so friends contributed three contributions of about 550,000 Canadian dollars. From now on, how they settle their own accounts is their family matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to cultural genes and historical reasons, Jews advocate autonomy based on identification with Jewish religious and cultural traditions. Therefore, this small community with only 98 households and less than 500 people actually has its own self-defense force. Most young people in their teens to early twenties like to dance with guns and sticks. In Canada, where gun control is lax, they are equipped with real guns and live ammunition. In addition to the guns provided by each household, part of the community&#39;s common fund has a security fund every year that is used to purchase long guns and ammunition. In the photos my friend showed me, there is even a 12.7mm &quot;Barrett&quot; heavy weapon. spy. The community organizes military training for young people every year, but these powerful spears are usually locked in the arsenal to prevent accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This small Jewish community has less than 500 people, but it has more than 400 guns, short guns, long guns, shotguns... nearly every person has one, and the number is increasing every year. They joked: Who can use it again? Dare to slaughter the Jews? Come and try? Having said that, my friend said that at community meetings, the most controversial topic is still the cost of security. Many families think that some self-defense capabilities are enough. After all, this is not a war period, and Canada is not a war zone. There is no need for every household to pay for it every year. It&#39;s a waste of money to allow dozens of stupid boys and crazy girls to fire tens of thousands of bullets every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, these spontaneous martial arts training among civilians are not completely useless. After the early morning raid on October 7, many young people from Jewish communities in the United States, Canada, Australia and other places took flights to Israel that night to prepare to join the war. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jews are a very small ethnic group, with only 25 million people including those of mixed race, accounting for only 3‰ of the global population today. Due to their cultural and traditional characteristics, they like the financial industry and academic industry. This ethnic group is too rich, and it is not that they are &quot;rich no more than three generations&quot;. Instead, the generations of children they have raised have been too successful in academics and business, occupying the There are too many high-level jobs, high salaries, and high profits, and such a small population cannot build a large empire or form a million-strong army to protect itself. Therefore, the survival wisdom and organizational order that the Jewish community today has explored, which is what Hayek calls &quot;spontaneous order&quot;, are the adaptive choices of groups and individuals in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[决赛直落三局，中国女排击败日本队第九次登上亚运冠军领奖台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258263]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 18:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team captain Yuan Xinyue hit the ball during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/f23a79e4e4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/f23a79e4e4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253420&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Yuan Xinyue, captain of the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team, hit the ball during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 7, 2023, the Hangzhou Asian Games women&#39;s volleyball final was held at the gymnasium of the Cangqian Campus of Hangzhou Normal University. The Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team swept the Japanese women&#39;s volleyball team in three straight games, winning all six games during the entire Asian Games. Lost one game and successfully defended the women&#39;s volleyball championship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, Wang Yuanyuan hit the ball in the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/08/1ba8b9a86e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/08/1ba8b9a86e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253421&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Wang Yuanyuan competed Hit the ball. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the beginning of the first game of the final, the Japanese team led by 3 points, but then the Chinese team scored 10 points in a row and relied on effective blocking and high speed in the second half. The high-quality serve reversed the situation on the court and won the first game at 25:15 through consecutive points. In the second game, the Japanese team adjusted their status and clenched the score, once narrowing the point difference to 2 points. The rhythm of the game was intense and fierce. The Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team has been Maintaining the lead in the score and securing the victory at 25:21; in the third game, the Japanese team strengthened their blocking and played extremely tenaciously. The two teams fought all the way to 9:9. In the end, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball player Wu Mengjie won the third game Locked in at 25:21, the game ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team members blocked the ball during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/08/6ec690b66f.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/08/6ec690b66f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253422&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023, Chinese Women&#39;s Volleyball Team Players block during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball players hit the ball during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/b1a9e64b5b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/08/b1a9e64b5b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253423&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023, China Women&#39;s volleyball players hit the ball during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball players celebrated scoring during the game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/904e72284c.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/10/08/904e72284c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023, China Women&#39;s volleyball players celebrate scoring during the game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since its first participation in 1974, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team has occupied an absolute dominance in the Asian Games. The team has won a total of 9 gold medals and 3 silver medals in the 13 Asian Games. 1 bronze, the team with the most championships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball girls celebrated winning the final.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/08/7e28335163.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/10/08/7e28335163.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023, Chinese Women&#39;s Volleyball Team The girls celebrate winning the final. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On October 7, 2023, after the final, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team waved to the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/43e8525457.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/10/08/43e8525457.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;October 7, 2023 On the same day, after the final, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team waved to the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Cai Bin, the head coach of the Chinese team, believes that the efforts of the players have been rewarded: &quot;From the first game to the last game of this Asian Games, the players&#39; hard work has paid off.&quot; The ups and downs of mentality are actually very small. Keep your mentality calmer and do every process well, and the result will be natural.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023 On October 7, 2020, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball players displayed the five-star red flag and gold medal on the medal podium.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/64aadb1356.jpg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/64aadb1356.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253427&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese women&#39;s volleyball players displayed the five-star red flag and gold medal on the medal podium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 18:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[女排横扫日本队成功卫冕，队长袁心玥渐入佳境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258252]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/08/BLywMWeLWuvv0jb5ynmTl7P9CVr6ielltPKqn680.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;558&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/BLywMWeLWuvv0jb5ynmTl7P9CVr6ielltPKqn6 80. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253378&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese team players took a group photo at the award ceremony&lt;span style =&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of October 7, in the women&#39;s volleyball final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the girls of the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team won 3-0 The Japanese team once again won the Asian Games. In this Asian Games, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team won all 6 games and successfully won the 9th Asian Games gold medal in team history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Throughout the game, captain Yuan Xinyue had a very high offensive success rate and was at her peak. She scored 18 points with 17 of 22 dunks and 1 block. When the score was tight and the situation was tense on the court, she took on the offensive responsibility and won two match points. She worked with teammates Li Yingying, Diao Linyu, Gong Xiangyu, Wang Yuanyuan and others to win the gold medal in one fell swoop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Asian Games is the first major competition for the women&#39;s volleyball girls after their failure in the Olympic qualifying rounds. After the game, Yuan Xinyue said in an interview: &quot;We have been adjusting our state and mentality after the Olympic preliminaries. In training, we focus more on encouraging each other. I need to do my best first, and then work with the team. Discuss and solve the problems encountered.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/SIbZ6wm7hqpZTFQELnM3zUR9xe7oDEAHY5kwtUK2.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;668&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/SIbZ6wm7hqpZTFQELnM3zUR9xe7oDEAHY5kwtUK2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253374&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese team player Yuan Xinyue (top right) blocked the ball during the game&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having served as captain for more than a year, Yuan Xinyue has become more and more familiar with this identity and its responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In May 2022, the Chinese Women&#39;s Volleyball Team announced that Yuan Xinyue would serve as the captain. At that time, after nearly four months of selection, preparation and running-in, a new women&#39;s volleyball team had just been formed. Since Zhu Ting is still recuperating from her injury, the newly appointed head coach Cai Bin decided to hand over the captain&#39;s armband to Yuan Xinyue. &quot;From the perspective of the time he joined the national team, his experience in competitions and his performance in this training camp, Yuan Xinyue is very qualified to be the captain.&quot; A role.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is indeed the case. Among the 16-man roster announced at that time, Ding Xia, Jin Ye, Wang Weiyi, Wang Yunou, Diao Linyu and other players were all older than Yuan Xinyue. However, in terms of the time when she was selected for the national team and the experience of participating with the team, no one could match the latter. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 is Yuan Xinyue’s 10th year joining the national team. “I think the biggest difference (this year) from the past is that there are more new players around me, and there are also several teammates who have fought together before.” In the past 10 years, she has witnessed the changes in women&#39;s volleyball teammates and the ups and downs of performance. Now as the captain, the goal she has set for herself is: &quot;I hope that I can play the role of a veteran player in the team and make greater contributions to the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;27-year-old Yuan Xinyue She practiced volleyball with her mother who was a women&#39;s volleyball coach on the school team since she was a child. Due to her good natural conditions, her parents sent her to the August 1st women&#39;s volleyball training camp and went to Beijing alone. In 2013, Yuan Xinyue, who was under 17 years old and nearly two meters tall, was selected by the then women&#39;s volleyball head coach Lang Ping and jumped into the national team. In the same year, her Chinese girls&#39; volleyball team defeated the United States team in the U18 World Championship finals and won the championship. She won the &quot;Most Valuable Player Award (MVP)&quot; for her outstanding performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/A3EePMPbGSsHlwjMPllgOZyVOjNKJyRsXFPkswN3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/A3EePMPbGSsHlwjMPllgOZyVOjNKJyRsXFPkswN3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253379&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese team head coach Cai Bin (second from right) directed during the game&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2014, at the Women&#39;s Volleyball World Championships in Italy, due to an accidental injury to veteran Xu Yunli, fledgling Yuan Xinyue replaced her. In that game, she scored 7 points in 8 attacks. With her outstanding performance, she became an important force in the team&#39;s promotion. This is her first time to participate in the world&#39;s top competition. &quot;I am very excited. The team schedule is very tight and there is no time to think about it. Whenever I am free, Sister Li will immediately give me extra lessons. So that the night before the semi-finals, I dreamed It&#39;s all a competition.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/C3iY5niN71dtcadh64c59MWkgCI2MYJl4aD0ZXds.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width= &quot;960&quot; height=&quot;660&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/C3iY5niN71dtcadh64c59MWkgCI2MYJl4aD0ZXds.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253377&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, Chinese team player Yuan Xinyue (top) attacked during the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Xinhua News Agency /Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CCTV commentator Tian Zongqi was deeply impressed by Yuan Xinyue’s outstanding performance at the time, and compared her with Hou Yuzhu (the 1984 Los Angeles Olympics women’s volleyball gold medalist), “As a 17-year-old As a young player, she awakened her teammates from a state of collective sleepwalking.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the following years, Yuan Xinyue could be seen by the audience in international competitions such as the women&#39;s volleyball team. Fans who are familiar with her also recognized Yuan Xinyue because of her immatureness. He called her &quot;Little Apple&quot; because of her cheeks. The &quot;Little Apple&quot; with extraordinary performance has jumped from a young player of the national team to a backbone player of the women&#39;s volleyball team known as the &quot;Zhu Yuan Zhang&quot; together with Zhu Ting and Zhang Changning, and experienced the 2016 Rio Olympics with his teammates. The glorious moment when the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team returns to its peak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But she often feels that she is not good enough. “Because of Zhu Ting, Zhang Changning, and (Li) Yingying, they can support several points of offense and defense, help me share and involve the opponent in blocking. People&#39;s energy. When I don&#39;t have them, how should I play by myself? I think this ability should be improved a bit.&quot; Yuan Xinyue has been the main secondary attacker in the team, and blocking is one of the primary responsibilities of the secondary attacker. For a while, she was criticized for her poor blocking ability. &quot;I think blocking is quite difficult, because it is not only a passive way to be beaten, but also an event that requires you to actively find rhythm and timing.&quot; She realized that blocking was her shortcoming. Later, Yuan Xinyue made up her mind to improve her blocking skills through hard training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 2019 Women&#39;s Volleyball World Cup, when the Chinese Women&#39;s Volleyball Team faced off against the Brazilian Women&#39;s Volleyball Team, deputy attacker Yuan Xinyue scored 26 points and scored 7 points in personal blocking. Together with Zhu Ting, she became the leading scorer in the match. She set the record for the highest points scored by a Chinese women&#39;s volleyball attacker in a single game in a World Series in the more than 20 years since the implementation of the per-goal scoring system in volleyball matches in January 1999. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/CeQQzOmeOjYPatJMASWqi3dK8K47549kdSWwI0Gn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;705&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/CeQQzOmeOjYPatJMASWqi3dK8K47549kdSWwI0Gn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253375&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On October 7, 2023, in the women&#39;s volleyball final of the Hangzhou Asian Games, the Chinese team defeated the Japanese team 3-0. Chinese team players Wang Yuanyuan, Gao Yi, and Yuan Xinyue (from left to Right) Celebrating the victory after the game &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Xinhua News Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since re-coaching the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team in 2013, Lang Ping has led the women&#39;s volleyball girls They won the 2015 Women&#39;s Volleyball World Cup, the 2016 Rio Olympics and the 2019 Women&#39;s Volleyball World Cup, and Yuan Xinyue participated in all of them and made considerable contributions. Although the women&#39;s volleyball girls later missed the Tokyo Olympics, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team&#39;s several ups and downs in the past 40 years perfectly interpreted the spirit of the women&#39;s volleyball team.正如郎平所说：“女排精神不是赢得冠军，而是有时候知道不能赢，也会竭尽全力。哪怕一路走来摇摇晃晃，但站起来抖抖身上的尘土，依旧眼神坚定，只要你打不死我，我就和你拼到底。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年上映的电影《夺冠》记录了郎平重新执教国家队、女排时隔12年重返奥运巅峰的坎坷历程。影片完整还原了女排姑娘们在里约赛场夺冠的一幕，袁心玥也参与了电影的制作。她记得，在拍摄重头戏中巴对决时，导演担心效果出不来想用些辣椒水，被她拒绝了，“一会就能哭起来。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/hn9usGsqAEfBocw5yB1tF7OEz8ZTOS7qU1BYKqMQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/hn9usGsqAEfBocw5yB1tF7OEz8ZTOS7qU1BYKqMQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253376&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月7日，中国队球员袁心玥在比赛中&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亚运会前几个月，女排姑娘们刚走过奥运预选赛三连败的曲折历程。 “队长的身份会让我在困难的时候，告诉自己更应该站出来。”袁心玥做到了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;回顾中国女排2023年的比赛历程，虽然无缘直通巴黎奥运会让人颇为遗憾，但在杭州亚运会上卫冕成功以及在世界女排联赛中力克一众强手拿到亚军，都让球迷看到了这支处于新老交替期的中国女排队伍的进步和成长。我们相信在不久的将来，那支战无不胜、攻无不克的中国女排一定会重回世界之巅。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（参考资料：新华网、澎湃新闻、新京报等。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[枪击案后，赴泰旅游会否再陷困境？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258250]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/Iscf507cfHf8z9z7Oc7csxC72ETxATEcO5Qk2ZDA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/Iscf507cfHf8z9z7Oc7csxC72ETxATEcO5Qk2ZDA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253366&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年10月7日，一名遇难者的母亲在泰国农磨兰普府发生枪击事件的保育中心外哭泣。当地一所保育中心6日发生枪击事件，造成至少36人死亡&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间2023年10月3日下午16时20分左右，泰国曼谷市暹罗百丽宫购物中心发出多声枪响。14岁的嫌犯用一把改造过且装有实弹的训练用空弹枪射击，导致2人死亡5人受伤。受害者中有两位中国公民，其中一位不幸罹难，另一位受伤，仍在重症监护室接受救治。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就在9月25日，泰国内阁为中国游客提供的为期5个月的免签政策，才正式开始生效。新冠疫情前，中国是泰国国际旅游的第一大客源国。据泰国官方统计，2023年前8个月，泰国的中国游客总数为210万，不足2019年中国赴泰游客总数的五分之一。推出免签政策，旨在刺激泰国旅游业恢复活力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;泰国旅行社协会名誉秘书长阿迪估计，这一政策将会为泰国在2023年最后一个季度多吸引50万—70万中国游客。泰国政府发言人乃猜表示，免签政策生效后的两天内，就有超过2.2万中国游客进入泰国。携程数据显示，截至9月12日，今年黄金周假期携程平台上的泰国旅游预订量同比增长5706%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事态似乎正向着好的方向发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，百丽宫的枪击事件，为中国游客重燃的赴泰热情浇上一盆冷水。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/xmr5dhNn1X0xBRW6Hzg61gaQAuYIm15QW1Q2cLHp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;698&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/xmr5dhNn1X0xBRW6Hzg61gaQAuYIm15QW1Q2cLHp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253367&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月25日，泰国总理赛塔·他威信（前排右）在曼谷素万那普国际机场迎接中国游客。自25日起，泰国对中国游客实施为期约5个月的免签政策&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;旅行变得惴惴不安&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;枪击事件发生后，在一些自由行旅客的心中，曼谷从行程表上的重头戏变为不可久留之地。“再也不会来泰国了。”这是无奈踏上泰国土地的Kark的想法。和许多游客一样，Kark被泰国新近的免签政策带来的便利所吸引，将其选为国庆假期的目的地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kark原计划10月3日从香港飞到曼谷，住在离案发现场不到两公里的酒店，下午去百丽宫购物。只因在香港临时和朋友聚餐而把行程推后一天，Kark躲过一劫。“之前准备3号下午在百丽宫买包，后来看媒体报道，凶手就是在那家店旁边的厕所开了第一枪。这是老天的信号，告诉我这个国家不要去了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看到新闻时，逗留香港的Kark陷入焦虑和恐惧：危险离自己也许只有一个巧合的距离。当他向旅行平台申请退票时，被航空公司以“非不可抗力影响”为由拒绝。为了不让三千多元的往返机票打水漂，Kark采取折中方案：4号落地曼谷后，立马转飞普吉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kark坦言，旅行变得让人惴惴不安。枪击案发生之前，Kark还能保持冷静：舆论夸大了泰国诈骗犯罪事件的概率，父母的极力反对也不能阻止他游览泰国的脚步。现在，身处人流稀落的素万那普国际机场，他感到危险如影随形。身体在泰国，心灵却渴望逃离。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;类似的烦恼也出现在李平身上，同样是在申请机票退订碰壁后，他取消了在曼谷停留两天的计划，5日到达曼谷机场后径直前往芭提雅。在这个以热闹夜市闻名的度假胜地，李平晚上6点后就一直待在酒店，“想去玩但担心人身安全，不敢去。”白天出门，听到周围有很多人讲中国话时，他才感到安心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/KXTm6Ii5XcR5YJlHn8S7HbnjGqU0PgDsABqQf3My.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/KXTm6Ii5XcR5YJlHn8S7HbnjGqU0PgDsABqQf3My.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253370&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月5日，泰国曼谷，警方突击搜查了一处住宅，一名法医正在查看陈列的枪支零件&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;失控的枪&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;出境旅行的安全问题，成为许多赴泰游客心中超越性价比的重要考量。百丽宫的枪击事件，暴露了泰国在枪支管制方面的漏洞。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《曼谷邮报》报道，当地警方透露，14岁的嫌犯所用的武器，是一把经过改造的空弹枪——原本多用作体育竞赛的发令枪，被改造为装有子弹的真枪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;警方发现，嫌犯通过网络联系到非法出售枪支弹药的商家，花费17000泰铢（约合3259人民币）从对方那里直接购买空弹枪和9毫米真弹。尽管空弹枪和BB枪可以通过更换枪管被改造为致命武器，但由于它们被当作“仿真枪”，按照泰国法律规定，持有这类枪支不必像持有真枪一样需要申请注册。由于缺少监管，仿真枪流通比真枪更为便利，很容易就能从网上买到。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/kM2XN3crvGbSAomd8X24a49CuuXiQcBSGDbkpmQT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;598&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/kM2XN3crvGbSAomd8X24a49CuuXiQcBSGDbkpmQT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253368&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，警察在泰国曼谷逮捕一名枪击事件嫌疑人。曼谷市中心知名商场暹罗百丽宫当天发生一起枪击事件，一名中国公民不幸遇难，另有一名中国公民受伤&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据泰国国家网报道，泰国警察总署署长多萨透露，近年来泰国进口了大量空弹枪，其中大多数被改造后用于犯罪。在7月的一次清缴行动中，警方缴获了2000个空弹枪管、超过10万发弹药。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，泰国也是枪支持有大国。据研究报告指出，泰国有超过1030万支枪，平民的拥枪率为平均每100人10.5支，这一比例在亚洲国家中排名第二。2019年泰国涉枪死亡人数为2804人，枪支凶杀率为10万分之3.91，这一数据也排在东盟国的第二位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;泰国颁布的《火器、弹药、爆炸物、烟花和仿真枪法》对非法持枪行为设置了较为严厉的惩罚：最高达10年的监禁、2万泰铢（约合人民币3930元）的罚款。但是，法律落实的力度有限。在泰国所有的枪支中，仍有40%的枪支属于非法持有，没有注册登记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在《纽约时报》的采访中，曼谷风险评估公司PQA联会的首席执行官夸利亚表示，泰国的枪支管制就像“不存在”一样，“注册枪支根本不需要费什么力气。泰国的问题在于枪支泛滥。无论合法还是非法的，枪支都可以畅通接触，容易获得。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;枪支泛滥和监管不力的现状，对泰国社会的公共安全构成威胁，百丽宫枪击案悲剧发生后，加强枪支管制已成为泰国官方、民众、游客的共同呼声。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月5日，经过多日商讨，泰国内政部公布了收紧枪支持有、交易、进口的13项计划。其中，短期计划包括：禁止批准新的仿真枪进口许可证、新增针对仿制枪持有的登记要求、停止颁发新的枪支经营许可证等。长期计划包括：强制要求持枪申请人提供精神状况的健康证明、将空弹枪和BB枪等排除在仿制枪类别之外、要求持枪人对子弹信息进行登记等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/QDHytCZBdmWPy9xG360HZwJ3qRPzYKTylg88R6Do.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/QDHytCZBdmWPy9xG360HZwJ3qRPzYKTylg88R6Do.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253369&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月3日，警察在泰国曼谷商场暹罗百丽宫的案发现场发现一支手枪&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（新华社/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;旅游业冲击&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;枪击事件发生后，泰国总理塞塔向中国驻泰大使道歉、探望中国伤员，泰国王室也慰问帮助，其官方积极安抚中国游客的努力不可谓不诚恳。但泰国方面似乎也意识到，此次袭击或许会对后疫情时代刚复苏的泰国旅游业造成无法避免的冲击。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据泰国星暹传媒报道，泰国旅游营销协会主席基蒂指出，考虑到枪袭案对中国游客的心理影响，10月将会有一半以上的中国客源流失，原本预计的70万游泰华人，或将减少到30万。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相较于泰国方面对旅游业的担忧，针对此次枪击案是否严重挫伤泰国游业务的问题，中国国内旅行社、线上旅游平台有更乐观的看法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;众信旅游市场部某负责人指出，枪击案和自然灾害、罢工等事件一样，会让游客因更警惕目的地安全问题而做出权衡，但疫情后出境旅游市场恢复的更大影响因素是签证和交通。从中国到泰国的航班数量，与疫情前相比仍存在较大差距，泰国旅游业务的恢复，是一个更长期的过程。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;携程负责组团社业务的工作人员透露，截至10月5日，她收到因发生枪击案而要求退订泰国游的申请并不多，“大概10个里面会有一人提出这种诉求。”据她估计，11、12月到泰国的游客量会出现一定降幅，但这之后，这种影响会逐渐消散。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此，中国旅游研究院国际研究所所长杨劲松解释，此次枪击案属于偶发性事件，“它并不像大规模暴动、战争、疫情等系统性风险一样，大家会立刻做出反应，采取措施应对。枪击案的影响有滞后性，就像“噶腰子”传闻，逐渐累积，让泰国留下负面印象。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杨劲松认为，泰国要改善在中国游客心中的形象，一方面需要向游客提供更多切实的安全保障，例如加强建设公共场所的安检系统、推动两国警方的联合执法工作；另一方面，要做好安保方面的宣传工作，主动向游客告知本国的避难场所、求助设施、警力配备，减少他们心中的不确定性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中Kark、李平均为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 17:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[财政部党组书记调整：蓝佛安系“财政老兵”，刘昆推动央地财政关系改革]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258258]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 16:10:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;财政部官网公告，2023年9月28日下午，中央组织部有关负责同志出席财政部领导干部会议，宣布中央决定：蓝佛安同志任财政部党组书记，免去刘昆同志的财政部党组书记职务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;接任财政部党组书记前，蓝佛安担任山西省委书记、省人大常委会主任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/rEGJKiwYT330dBdFQmqiHE6OuiyOp6Rm2cdvSBSL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;639&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/rEGJKiwYT330dBdFQmqiHE6OuiyOp6Rm2cdvSBSL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253389&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月10日，蓝佛安在太原市看望慰问教师。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（山西省政府官网/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;蓝佛安重回财政系统&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;新任财政部党组书记蓝佛安，是财政系统“老兵”，从事财政工作近20年，又在审计部门有过8年任职经历。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国政府网显示，蓝佛安出生于1962年，是广东惠州人，毕业于湖北财经学院（现为中南财经政法大学）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大学毕业后，蓝佛安在财政部预算司工作了三年。1988年，蓝佛安回到家乡广东，在广东省财政厅预算处以及办公室工作了11年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1999年，蓝佛安短暂离开财政系统，前往地方任职，出任东莞市副市长。两年后，蓝佛安回到广东省财政厅担任副厅长一职，直至2007年。同一时期，刘昆是广东省财政厅党组书记、厅长（2002年-2010年）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2007年，蓝佛安调任广东省审计厅，出任党组书记一职。一年后，又接任审计厅厅长。2011年，蓝佛安曾发表论文，介绍审计在政府治理过程中的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蓝佛安表示，审计作为保障经济社会健康发展的“免疫系统”，在保障经济社会健康运行中要发挥“预防、揭露、抵御”功能。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在广东省审计厅工作八年后，蓝佛安再度前往地方任职，出任韶关市委书记。2016年1月，蓝佛安升任广东省副省长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2017年3月，蓝佛安转岗海南，担任海南省委常委、省纪委书记、省监察委员会主任。2021年，蓝佛安又调任山西，出任山西省委副书记。同年，接任山西省省长一职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据山西广播电视台报道，蓝佛安调任山西工作时，时任省委书记楼阳生在省委常委会扩大会议上表示，“蓝佛安同志政治坚定，思路清晰，熟悉党务和经济工作，勤奋敬业，敢于担当，推动工作力度大，公道正派，处事严谨，自我要求严格”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年12月，出任山西省省长一年多时间的蓝佛安，升任山西省委书记。十个月后，蓝佛安进京，担任财政部党组书记。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;刘昆任党组书记五年有余&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;根据财政部官网资料，1956年12月出生的刘昆，已年满66周岁。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年3月，时任财政部部长肖捷转岗至国务院工作，升任国务委员兼国务院秘书长，刘昆接棒财政部党组书记、部长。接任前，刘昆担任全国人大常委会机关党组成员、全国人大常委会预算工作委员会主任、第十二届全国人大财经委员会副主任委员。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直至2023年9月，刘昆已担任财政部党组书记五年零七个月。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年3月13日，十四届全国人大一次会议举行第五次全体会议，大会经投票表决决定任命刘昆为财政部长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新中国成立以来，刘昆是第一位广东籍的财政部部长。综合财政部官网、人民网资料，1978年-1982年，刘昆在厦门大学经济系财政金融专业就读。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毕业后，刘昆长期在广东省政府办公厅工作。2002年，担任广东省政府副秘书长的刘昆，出任广东省财政厅党组书记、厅长一职，长达八年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2010年，刘昆升任广东省副省长。根据广东省政府官网，担任副省长的三年间，刘昆分管过社会保障、编制、监察、民政、农口、供销社等多个领域工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年，刘昆再度回到财政条线工作，进京担任财政部党组成员、副部长一职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据人民网报道，刘昆分管国库司（国库支付中心）、经济建设司、监督检查局和财政部驻各地财政监察专员办事处、投资评审中心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年12月，在财政部工作三年后，刘昆转岗至全国人大常委会，担任全国人大常委会预算工作委员会主任等职务。中国人大网显示，全国人大常委会预算工作委员会为正部级单位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;直至2018年3月，刘昆接替肖捷出任财政部党组书记、部长。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/qKbY29D5QNEPrR0nypQ3VWjLpFQJBYIIPP9Qgfsm.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;731&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/qKbY29D5QNEPrR0nypQ3VWjLpFQJBYIIPP9Qgfsm.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253388&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月7日，财政部部长刘昆与世界银行行长彭安杰举行会谈。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（财政部官网/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;推动央地财政关系改革&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2018年3月底，新任财政部部长刘昆，出席了国务院发展研究中心主办的一场论坛活动，谈及央地财政关系改革。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘昆在演讲时谈到，在保持中央和地方财力格局总体稳定的前提下，科学确定共享税、中央和地方分享方式和比例，适当增加地方税种，继续优化转移支付制度，扩大一般性转移支付规模。建立健全专项转移支付定期评估和退出机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与此同时，还要健全地方税体系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“结合实施中央和地方收入划分改革，研究调整部分消费税品目征收环节和收入的归属，积极稳妥推进健全地方税体系改革。调整税制结构，培育地方税源，加强地方税权，理顺税费关系，逐步建立稳定、可持续的地方税体系。”刘昆表示。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;央地财政关系改革，贯穿了刘昆担任财政部党组书记、部长的五年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，国务院印发《实施更大规模减税降费后调整中央与地方收入划分改革推进方案》，旨在进一步理顺央地财政关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;方案提出，调动中央与地方两个积极性，稳定分税制改革以来形成的中央与地方收入划分总体格局，巩固增值税“五五分享”等收入划分改革成果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;调整完善增值税留抵退税分担机制，建立增值税留抵退税长效机制，结合财政收入形势确定退税规模，并保持中央与地方“五五”分担比例不变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，将部分在生产（进口）环节征收的现行消费税品目，逐步后移至批发或零售环节征收，拓展地方收入来源，引导地方改善消费环境。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年，刘昆还向十三届全国人大常委会作了题为《我国的中央和地方财政关系》的讲座，详细阐述了当前我国央地财政关系现状及未来改革方向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘昆表示，进一步理顺央地财政关系，要从健全地方税、直接税体系，完善以共享税为主体的收入划分模式，以及完善共同财政事权体系，强化中央财政事权和支出责任等方向努力。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年2月，刘昆在《求是》杂志刊登的文章中写道，财税改革向纵深推进，进一步改革预算管理制度，深入推进中央与地方财政事权和支出责任划分改革，实施具有中国特色的共同财政事权转移支付。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;严控地方债务规模&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;刘昆担任财政部党组书记、部长的五年间，面临的一大压力，便是地方财政收支矛盾加剧，债务风险不断增加。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年3月，刘昆以及财政部两位副部长围绕“财税改革和财政工作”主题，回答中外记者提问，其间谈到地方债问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“当然我也不回避，个别地方政府在法定限额外，通过融资平台公司违法违规或变相举借债务，就是所谓的政府的隐性债务。”刘昆强调，“我们采取严格措施，不允许发生新的隐性债务，同时要求稳妥化解存量债务。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谈到如何化解存量债务时，刘昆表示，将坚持中央不救助，谁举债谁负责，做到“谁家的孩子谁家抱”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年下半年，财政部开始建立地方隐性债务监测系统，动态监控各地区债务规模。2019年开始，又设立地方政府债务风险等级评定机制，将地方债务风险划分为红、橙、黄、绿四个等级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“平衡好促发展和防风险的关系，合理安排赤字、债务及支出政策，抓实化解地方政府隐性债务风险工作。”2021年年初，刘昆在接受新华社采访时谈到，当前我国地方政府债务风险总体可控，但有的地区仍在新增隐性债务，个别地区偿债风险有所上升。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘昆表示，给地方政府债务戴上“紧箍”，经济社会发展就多一道“安全阀”。接下来，财政部门将积极采取“开前门”和“堵后门”并行、保障和规范并举等措施，进一步完善管理、强化监管，推进地方政府债务“阳光化”，切实把债务风险关进笼子里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年6月，十四届全国人大常委会第三次会议在人民大会堂举行第一次全体会议，刘昆作了关于2022年中央决算的报告。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他指出，下一步将重点做好六项工作：加力提效实施积极的财政政策、加强重点领域支出保障、兜牢基层“三保”底线、有效防范化解地方政府债务风险、加大财会监督力度、扎实做好审计整改“下半篇文章”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7月，中共中央政治局召开会议，分析研究当前经济形势，部署下半年经济工作。会议指出，要有效防范化解地方债务风险，制定实施一揽子化债方案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月28日，刘昆向全国人大常委会报告今年以来预算执行情况时强调，“中央财政积极支持地方做好隐性债务风险化解工作，妥善化解存量隐性债务，坚决查处新增隐性债务行为，防止一边化债一边新增。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中国队无悬念领跑，创历史最佳战绩。杭州亚运会奖牌榜回顾丨有数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258244]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 14:52:17&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[唐慧、唐世科寻衅滋事案公开宣判]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258246]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 14:48:05&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;8日，湖南省道县人民法院依法公开宣判唐慧、唐世科寻衅滋事案，被告人唐慧犯寻衅滋事罪，判处有期徒刑四年。被告人唐世科犯寻衅滋事罪，判处有期徒刑三年六个月。对被告人唐慧、唐世科的违法所得人民币6万元予以追缴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经审理查明，2010年至2012年期间，被告人唐慧、唐世科以永州市第四人民医院没有查出唐慧宫外孕导致其右侧输卵管被切除为由，通过恶意举报，多次辱骂、威胁医院工作人员等方式向医院施压索要赔偿（永州市医学会鉴定不构成医疗事故），永州市第四人民医院被迫支付6万元给唐慧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年，因树障引起永州市零陵区富家桥镇晓里塘村大面积、频繁停电现象，严重影响居民正常生产生活，国网湖南省电力有限公司永州市零陵区供电分公司根据上级通知组织清障施工时，将该村二组马家巷山上的14棵野生幼年樟树及其他林木采伐。唐慧、唐世科以“唐世科自留山中的野生樟树被非法采伐”为由向零陵区供电分公司索赔，赔偿金额从3万元渐次提高到50万元。后因害怕背上敲诈勒索的嫌疑，唐慧、唐世科向永州市零陵区人民法院起诉要求赔偿359.6万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为达到通过司法程序获取赔偿款的目的，二人恶意举报，多次追逐、拦截、辱骂办案人员，在公共场所起哄闹事，在网络上散布虚假信息，严重影响他人的工作生活，造成公共场所秩序严重混乱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;法院认为，被告人唐慧、唐世科借故生非，多次追逐、拦截、纠缠、辱骂他人，严重影响他人工作和生活，情节恶劣；强拿硬要财物6万元，情节严重；在医院等公共场所起哄闹事，造成公共场所秩序严重混乱，其行为均已构成寻衅滋事罪。道县人民法院根据被告人唐慧、唐世科犯罪事实、性质、情节和社会危害程度，依法作出上述判决。两名被告人当庭表示上诉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 14:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[西安某大学女生被63页PPT控诉出轨：如此公之于众侵犯隐私吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258240]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 13:50:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，西安外国语大学一女生被男友以63页PPT控诉出轨一事，成为社交网络热点。抛开八卦的成分，这件事在社会和法律的层面，也值得辨析。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;发布控诉PPT的男子自称在上海某会计师事务所工作，而被控诉女生则是西安外国语大学大四学生，他们从2022年底开始谈恋爱，但在近一年的时间里，这名女生与两名前男友有出轨行为。男子认为女友的“出轨”严重伤害了自己的感情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事件在网上大量传播，也引起了不少网友争议。有人认为，女生劈腿，给男友戴绿帽子，是严重的错误；也有人称，两人只是男女朋友关系，并非夫妻，女生做的事并不违法，而制作PPT在网络上散布，却是侵犯个人隐私权的违法行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;社交网络上，“劈腿”“出轨”等桃色事件天然容易引起极大关注。但是不同的情况在法律层面确实有着不同的性质。从法律上来说，民法典只规定夫妻之间有相互忠诚的义务（这包括感情、性等方面的专一），情侣之间则没有法定的忠诚义务。因此，领了结婚证的夫妻，如果一方出轨，是明确违反了法律规定。情侣之间没有成文法意义上的忠诚义务，自然更谈不上什么不忠诚的后果。恋爱、感情，也不属于民法规范的“民事法律行为”范畴，不受民法“诚实信用”原则的约束。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，规范公众社会行为的，除了成文法，还有习惯法，包括公序良俗、道德评价等等。对确定了恋爱关系的情侣，习惯法同样有相互忠诚的要求。如果任意一方有背叛行为，都应该受到道德批判，并须返还礼金等。被背叛的一方，也有权利通过公开事实，借助道德力量对背叛的一方进行惩戒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，过去这种道德批判一般限于熟人或者社区、村落、单位等比较小的圈子之内。而今，社交网络的发达，可能让此类事件迅速传遍整个网络。被批判者，不仅在小圈子里名誉扫地，更可能在全网络范围内“社会性死亡”，而且网络上的道德批判可能比熟人圈子更加猛烈，更加直接，甚至可能引发舆论风暴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，被“出轨”后将对方信息发到网络上，是不是涉嫌泄露个人信息，侵犯隐私权呢？类似的情况并不是没有先例。 2021年，“女网红遭CEO男友65页PPT控诉”事件同样成为网络热点，最后，男子被警方认定“散布他人隐私”违反治安管理处罚法，行政拘留6日。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而在最新的这份控诉PPT中，涉事女生不仅被指名道姓，点名身份，还有该女生的学生证、她和“出轨对象”的照片，以及女生与他们聊天记录的截图。这些信息都可能会被认定为个人隐私。不少法律从业者提醒，这种“揭私”式指控可能触犯法律。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时还有一个细节，这名控诉大学生女友出轨的男子后来发布声明称，他只把制作的PPT发给了女友的室友和同事，希望她们能对其进行劝说和教育。他没有将文件发到公开网络上，也不希望事件继续传播。若果真如此，涉事几方都可以报警，要求警方调查清楚，到底是谁把文件发到了公开的网络上，引起了巨大的传播。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外值得注意的是，类似的网络控诉出轨事件不只一例，有男友控诉女友出轨的，也有女友控诉男友出轨的。对此类问题的讨论和评判，不能因为实施者性别不同就区别对待。女性的隐私是隐私，男性的隐私也是隐私。男性发PPT控诉女友出轨是侵犯隐私，要受处罚，女性公开控诉男友出轨，同样是侵犯隐私，也应该受到处罚。对类似事件，有关部门理应一视同仁，要么都处罚，要么都不处罚，而不能因为性别不同而选择性执法。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《坚如磐石》，癫狂张艺谋]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258192]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;在谈论《坚如磐石》时，我们绕不开的话题是，张艺谋。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为一位国民级的导演，他获奖无数，也争议缠身。在毁誉之间，观众能达成的共识是：他是非常风格化的导演。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;厚重历史叙事下的小人物，权力与欲望交缠的国民性，浓烈到冒险的色彩运用，符号化的主角和群体操式的群演，不节制的大场面带来的奇观视觉……所有的信号，都很容易让观众看出，这是打上张艺谋烙印的电影。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/525ef413691a4e03e0afdaee4db01e50.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;668&quot; height=&quot;276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/525ef413691a4e03e0afdaee4db01e50.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这种风格贯穿张艺谋的导演生涯，在不同时代会有不同的进化，但底色是一致的。这种持续输出，让张艺谋和他的作品，就像一个坚固的建筑，好的坏的，持之不变。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;时间长了，观众也容易腻了。就好比今年春节档的《满江红》，连批评都变得乏味。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;但事有例外，张艺谋一旦拍现实题材，就容易“先锋”起来。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;早在1989年的《代号美洲豹》，他就在探索商业动作片的拍法，在那个时代超前得很；&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;1997年的《有话好好说》，大面积的手持摄影配合奔放怪诞的故事，甚至有些意识流的展示；&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;而2000年的《幸福时光》，喜剧的面子下，裹着悲剧的里子。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在稳固和探索的交缠下，《坚如磐石》显得有些特别。这部2019年就拍完的电影，跨过了疫情三年，才姗姗来迟。从题材到尺度，它都有点太过锋利。这在预告片“绿油油”的色调里，也能看出苗头，似乎是老导演“老夫聊发少年狂”，要在&lt;span>;不熟悉的类型里摸索摸索。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/125b2f0b75d2d3087d490aa6cab3a7a9.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;404&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/125b2f0b75d2d3087d490aa6cab3a7a9.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253172&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;电影有一群演技派坐镇，且片中演员是完全不化妆的。这为营销提供了噱头，但是回归电影本身，更是主题的需要，大&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;面积阴冷的蓝绿色调，比演&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;员更抢戏。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;它不自然，也不寻常，埋藏着爆炸的情绪。&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在现实世界里，绿色代表着健康、环保、生机等等，是个很正面的颜色。但是在类型电影里，大面积的冷绿则是“禁忌”，大多用在特定的场景里。熟稔类型电影的观众，很容易想起恐怖片的段落里，那些阴森森的绿光，又或者想起那些毒药、腐烂、囚禁的道具或场面。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f3a012e0f370e3e2a835f7b41b0c0ce8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;407&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/f3a012e0f370e3e2a835f7b41b0c0ce8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253171&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在《坚如磐石》那个不存在的金江市，充斥着阴冷的绿。张艺谋似乎仍不满足，在整部电影里，你甚至找不出几段令人有安全感的打光。即便是正反打的交谈戏，镜头都要保持轻微的晃动，这是个激进到冒&lt;/span>;险的做法，很难用轻飘飘的“风格化”来解释。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不寻常的“绿”，即是《坚如磐石》的题眼。它代表着阴谋、暴力、腐败等等，在架空的城市，体面的身份背后，隐藏着许多肮脏交易。这为人物的复杂性和突如其&lt;span>;来的暴力，提供了感官上的刺激。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在整个观影过程中，我都能感到一种不安全感。观众不是被讨好的、被保护的，冲突和暴力来得猝不及防，尺度拉到极大。你甚至能感受到主创那种压抑不住的激烈情绪，在每一个剧情的关键节点，绝不手软，给你一下子。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/dc907405800990169839ba1fc44896d3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/dc907405800990169839ba1fc44896d3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253168&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在扫黑题材里，糟糕的做法是脸谱化。正的一方没头脑，就是天然正确；邪的一方不高兴，就是死心塌地搞破坏。一部大制作的电影，难的不是找到一群优秀的演员，而是让每个人物不管戏份大小，都能立&lt;/span>;得住，成为故事网的结实节点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;编剧陈宇的做法，是将人物从正邪两极出发，编织出一个错综复杂的关系网。举个例子，扮演副市长爱人的陈&lt;span>;冲，戏份并不重，但这样一个次要角色，与雷佳音、张国立、于和伟的角色们，都有清楚的关系。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;印象深刻的一段，是于和伟扮演的黎志田上门威胁。陈冲出于利益的立场，语含机锋，寸步不让。但在知晓丈夫怀念旧情的背叛后，陈冲一瞬间从悲伤到愤怒，再到果决，直到交锋结束，门一关，眼泪流出，整个人就垮掉了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/942a89a62ae35ca160f9a98a68147270.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;401&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/942a89a62ae35ca160f9a98a68147270.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253170&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这样一个人物，有作为黑暗利益链的一面，也有作为爱人的感性一面，人物的复杂不需要铺陈篇幅，全靠演员精湛的表演。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但这是一部群像戏，并不只是一个角色写得好，或者一个演员表演优秀就够了。在群像戏里，人物交缠相互作用，才能形成一个结构复杂却线路清楚的网。而每个&lt;span>;人物都要在节点上发力，才能产生共振的合力，让整个故事有宿命感，好像每个人走向终局，路上极为精彩，结果早就注定。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/353cabfdbb000381dc01ffa4e1263e39.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;407&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/07/353cabfdbb000381dc01ffa4e1263e39.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253169&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在这部演员平均水准很高的电影里，于和伟提供了颠覆式的表演。假如把整个故事看作一场风暴，黎志田当然是风暴眼。在与权力一方的交易里，他是摆在台前的棋子；在与正义一方的交锋里，他是从容应对的老狐狸；而在女儿面前，他是一秒切换的溺爱慈父。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;张艺谋用若干个名场面，去堆积他的复杂性，他的出身和奋斗，霸权和狠戾，暴力和残忍，细致和温柔……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;令我印象最深的戏，是在面临死亡的前一刻，他压低声线不想惊扰熟睡的女儿。导演并没有放大，在暴力和混乱中，这位一贯谈笑自如的枭雄，&lt;/span>;只能无力地哀求。恰恰就是这个无力的要求，容易被忽略的要求，是这个人物的两面：看起来尽在掌握，实际上狼狈不堪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总体来看，《坚如磐石》不是宏大的、振奋的、讨好观众的，反而充斥着偏激的色彩运用，动荡的镜头语言&lt;span>;，复杂又黑暗的剧情。它是张艺谋的另一面，不令人愉悦，但足够震撼。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[地方城投为何弃美元债，发日元债？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258234]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-08 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/w1sXZW7OyMDxPsetTQcXnApMd5ld6UzE1Wb1raow.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height=&quot;950&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/08/w1sXZW7OyMDxPsetTQcXnApMd5ld6UzE1Wb1raow.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253300&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;江苏连云港市赣榆区，该地城投首发日元债。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;地方城投找到了一条新的境外融资通道——日元债。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“本债券是首单地方国企日元债券。”2023年4月，中诚信绿金国际有限公司（下称中诚信绿金）官网刊文表示，连云港市赣榆城市建设发展集团有限公司发行日元债券，规模为58亿日元（约合2.8亿元人民币），债券期限为3年，票面利率1.8%。中诚信绿金为此次债券发行提供了评估意见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此之前，地方城投主要发行的境外债券是美元债。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对中资企业来说，日元债是指境内企业及其控制的境外企业或分支机构，向境外举借的、以日元计价的债券。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据南方周末记者统计，2023年以来，截至2023年10月6日，全国7家城投公司共发行了7只日元债，规模共计664亿日元（约合32亿元人民币），息票率在1.4%至2.3%之间。发行日元债的城投企业，分布在江苏、山东、四川三地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，江苏瀚瑞投资控股有限公司（下称瀚瑞投资）于8月发行的日元债规模最大，达167.2亿日元（约合8亿元人民币），息票率为1.7%。瀚瑞投资由镇江市国资委100%持股。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;实际发行成本远高于息票率&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;7只日元债的发行材料显示，4家公司属于市级城投平台，3家为县区级城投平台。债券发行均为固定利率，发行期限都是三年，且拥有银行出具的SBLC（备用信用证）作为增信方式。但7只日元债券均未显示债券评级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一般来说，备用信用证是指银行应申请人要求向受益人开立的、保证在申请人未能按双方协议履行其责任或义务时，银行作为担保方，代其履行一定金额、一定期限范围内的支付责任或经济赔偿责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈工所在的城投公司，2023年便发行了一笔日元债，他曾参与发行事宜。陈工向南方周末记者介绍，为了能够让银行出具备用信用证，公司向银行进行了实物抵押，抵押物的价值要比融资金额高一些。此外，公司还会向银行支付两个点，作为备证费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1.4%-2.3%的息票率，意味着买方的利润空间有限。最新的五年期LPR为4.2%。此外，江苏、山东等地的城投平台，普遍债务压力重，又存在偿债风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，是谁在购买城投公司的日元债？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“和美元债一样，买方主要是境内的金融机构。”陈工进一步介绍，公司的日元债就是一家国内银行在买，发行前已经和该银行谈好了购买事项，就是走个日元债的通道，“因为利率低，在票面利率的基础上，公司私底下又给买方补了两个点的利息”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，发行债券还要加上3‰左右的交易手续费。算上备证费等，日元债的实际发行成本远高于息票率。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据债券发行材料，上述7家城投公司发行日元债的用途，主要是补充运营资本、项目融资以及离岸债券的再融资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈工解释，境内融资受限，发行日元债的直接目的是缓解资金压力。此外，也能够完成当地的招商引资任务，“虽是境内机构在买，但走了境外通道，就成了境外资金”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中资美元债发行量创新低&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;长期以来，包括城投公司在内的中资企业，主要发行的境外债券是美元债。然而过去一段时间，中资美元债发行量不断萎缩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;联合资信报告显示，2023年二季度，受美联储加息推高发行成本，以及信用风险事件影响，中资美元债发行大幅缩量。4-6月，共发行了656只中资美元债，发行规模仅为92.21亿美元，创近十年新低。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从发行主体行业分布看，金融板块是单季发行规模最大领域，发行规模占季度发行总额的比重为59%。城投公司发行规模为19.78%，房地产板块发行规模占比压缩至20%以下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;香港仁和投资总裁徐翔宇从事高收益债投资多年，熟悉中资美元债市场。他向南方周末记者介绍，城投公司转向日元债，主要原因是美元债发行成本过高。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“如果公司发美元债，实际成本在12%左右。”陈工透露。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其它国家也正积极发行日元债。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年7月，《日本经济新闻》报道，2023年二季度，日元债券发行金额约为8500亿日元（约合409亿元人民币），达到4年来的单季最高水平。日本央行表示，将继续实施大规模宽松政策，利率趋于稳定，发债变得容易。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此前4月，股神沃伦·巴菲特旗下的伯克希尔—哈撒韦公司发行5只日元债券，共筹集1644亿日元（约合79亿元人民币）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，陈工为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>