<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[网红民工吴桂春重返东莞：“要千方百计看两本书”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260786]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[研究发现鲨鱼可以跟人类一样品尝出苦味]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260788]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A new study recently published in the US magazine &quot;Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences&quot; stated that sharks and other cartilaginous fish have the same Genes that detect bitter tastes like humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;a>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity : 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;677&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/3bb8a8b58b482a95b5d8522d0903e6d0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258594&quot; >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;The picture shows a photo of a shark provided by the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity. Published by Xinhua News Agency (Photo courtesy of the Australian Center for Marine Biodiversity/Photo by Andrew Fox)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many animals and plants secrete toxic compounds as a defense, a chemical that enables humans to perceive their taste The bitter taste receptor type 2 (T2R) gene helps humans recognize these compounds and avoid poisoning. Many bony vertebrates also have this bitter taste receptor gene, but researchers have never found it in cartilaginous vertebrates before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this study, researchers from the University of Cologne in Germany and other institutions used the latest gene sequencing technology to sequence the genes of 17 species of cartilaginous fish (including sharks and rays) and found that 12 species of cartilaginous fish All carry a taste receptor gene similar to T2R, which they named T2R1. The researchers then implanted the T2R1 genes from two of the shark species into human kidney cells in the laboratory, and then exposed them to 94 bitter substances that humans can perceive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results showed that 7 bitter substances activated the bitter taste receptors of two species of sharks, and the other 4 substances only activated the bitter taste receptors of one shark, which means that these sharks can also taste human food. Perceived bitter substances such as colchicine or bile acids. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The discovery suggests the ability to perceive bitter tastes may be older than previously thought, possibly before cartilaginous fishes and bony vertebrates diverged from a common ancestor nearly 500 million years ago, the researchers said. has evolved. Teleost vertebrates continue to evolve a variety of bitter taste receptor genes. Although the researchers detected only one T2R1 gene in these cartilaginous fish genomes, this means it may be the original form of the bitter taste receptor gene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[台湾观众可能没有我们这么了解侯孝贤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260763]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeKnCcAnsCEY3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;260&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/07/06/rKWMbSoWwfVL8BpgZ8crjMyz3wQqeK nCcAnsCEY3. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;240307&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Single episode introduction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hello everyone, welcome to A Little Culture. I am Yu Yaqin, the anchor of this issue. Recently, the famous director Hou Hsiao-hsien has to bid farewell to the film industry due to health reasons. For this reason, today I invited Teacher Wang Yinjie from the China Academy of Art and my colleague Teacher Li Heng to talk about this great fan of Chinese films. A very important film master. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Excerpts of golden verses&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He lives in southern Taiwan, which is very different from Taipei in our impression. It has more rural character. This rural character is also the way Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at the world. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Some actors have said that he doesn’t even have a script. He is not a person who particularly likes to coordinate actors. A director who is very standard in the film industry, very sophisticated and precise. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;He provides a very valuable preservation of personal experience and personal memory for the narration of film history. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1700&quot; height=&quot;1132&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8T0VpH1YT2tgR3YXsfcAgwBzxaIxG8QjdktiwGEO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258472&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot; color: #993300;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;[Guests in this issue]&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Yaqin, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Heng, Southern Weekend Cultural Supplement Department Reporter&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yinjie, Associate Professor, School of Film, China Academy of Art&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #993300;&quot;>;[Listening Tips]&lt;/span>;&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:58 Director Hou Hsiao-hsien’s life and works&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 04:17 Countryside is Hou Hsiao-hsien’s way of looking at the world&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 05:22&amp;nbsp;《 &quot;Son&#39;s Big Doll&quot; established many of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s aesthetic styles&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 09:23&amp;nbsp;After 2000, Hou Hsiao-hsien moved towards more international cooperation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 11:08&amp;nbsp;Jia Zhangke is I came into contact with Hou Hsiao-hsien from &quot;City of Sadness&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 14:33 Hou Hsiao-hsien is not a standardized director in the film industry&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 17:52 Hou Hsiao-hsien has always been photographing individuals with a faint light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 19:57 Taiwanese audiences may not know Hou Hsiao-hsien as well as we do&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 23:14&amp;nbsp;Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films have many long shots and do not pursue a lot of drama&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;► 26:19 The emotions of the characters in Hou’s films are like hearing thunder in silence&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 32:47 Hou Hsiao-hsien holds a very important position in the hearts of a generation of movie fans&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 37: 15 A kind of misalignment: The life needs of young people in Taiwan do not come from directors such as Hou Hsiao-hsien&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 41:11 We need to trust the interpretation of the world by creators of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s generation&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 43:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien looks at everyone around him in a level-headed manner&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 45:06 The use of dialect is a characteristic of Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 47:05 Recommended by Wang Yinjie Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Sad City&quot; and &quot;Flowers of Shanghai&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 53:49 Three movies recommended by Yu Yaqin: &quot;Once Upon a Childhood&quot;, &quot;Love in the Wind&quot; and &quot;The Assassin Nie Yinniang&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;► 55:53 Three movies recommended by Li Heng: &quot;Once Upon a Time in Childhood&quot;, &quot;Goodbye South Country, South Country&quot; and &quot;Dream Life&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 58:16 Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s masterpiece is so dazzling that it... The light of urban youth-themed works overshadowed&lt;br>;► 01:01:52 Director Hou’s films strive for a certain authenticity of the atmosphere of that era&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:06:30 When there are many things that cannot be said Whenever possible, we use literature as a metaphor and movies to present it&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:08:25 Hou Hsiao-hsien provides a way to retain personal experience and memory in telling film history&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:11 :14 Use Southern aesthetics to summarize Hou Hsiao-hsien’s films&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 01:16:09 Hou Hsiao-hsien influenced young directors from Taiwan, mainland China’s sixth-generation directors, Hirokazu Kore-eda, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;Audio Clip/Shao Ruier&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : #999999;&quot;>;Operation Promotion/Shao Ruier, Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这部罪案片，悬疑为壳，人性为核]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260769]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The dramatization of crime films often has two levels . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first level is to explore the truth of the murder. Under the sensory stimulation of extreme violence, the protagonist takes the audience&#39;s perspective to reveal the truth bit by bit. The plot has twists and turns and even reversals, providing plot excitement. The other layer is to explore the theme of human nature. The protagonist often has some kind of commonality with the victim and murderer of the case. The story of the detective story is also the protagonist&#39;s growth of exploring himself and &quot;finding himself&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the case was finally solved, the protagonist found the truth of the case and the answer to the confusion in life. They point to an ending in the interweaving, and the audience sees two stories and gets a double plot impact. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those character arcs in drama theory are actually not complicated. Excellent stories not only reveal the truth about the character&#39;s personality, but more importantly, tell the arc or change of the character&#39;s inner nature during the course of the story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Knowing this, it is easy to understand the director&#39;s intention. In crime films, these two layers are often intertwined, but with different emphasis. For example, &quot;The Mistake on the River&quot; currently in theaters focuses on the latter layer. The director was afraid of being misunderstood, so he directly wrote &quot;No Answer&quot; on the poster. It just reminds the audience that the main purpose of this movie is to explore the human nature related to the case. The investigation itself is not important. There is no need to worry about who the murderer is. There is no answer at all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, the new film &quot;Pursuit&quot; directed by Zeng Yingting and starring Junning Chang and Ethan Ruan is not so literary and extreme. Although this movie has some fresh topics, it does not challenge the audience&#39;s entertainment interests too much and is a very regular crime film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/65d82de147164b79f0bb63f091c3cc89.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1531&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/65d82de147164b79f0bb63f091c3cc89.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258558&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Female worker accident He died tragically and was involved in a series of female murders. Finger-cutting, heart-breaking, imprisonment...bizarre cases, cruel murderers, and sensory-stimulating gimmicks are all cut into the trailer. Seasoned genre film viewers are very familiar with this method of publicity, and of course they know that a gimmick is just a gimmick, and its scale will only be safe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that &quot;The Hunt&quot; is a movie dominated by female characters, and you can even consider it a female movie (although it is very genre). In the crime genre, very few women lead the investigation. We might as well try to recall the positioning of female characters in crime films. They are often victims or perpetrators (which appears as a reversal card at this time). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this crime movie, the protagonist is the detective Wu Jie played by Junning Chang. She is the leader and the soul of the drama. If you put aside your female identity, Zhang Junning&#39;s role is not special. This is a decadent Matthew Scudder-like character who looks like a professional, capable, and tough detective on the outside, but is broken on the inside. We have seen countless similar male characters. The decadent man finds himself and his original intention through handling cases, which is very cliché. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Pursuit&quot;, we cannot ignore the gender issue, it is the theme of this movie. The audience is first put into a female perspective. Wu Jie, who has experienced pain in the film, is facing the difficulty of how to survive. She tried to commit suicide in the car. This is the starting point of the character&#39;s story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Jie encountered the case of an unknown female corpse. Objectively, the instinct of the criminal police prevented the idea of ​​​​suicide. When she starts to handle the case, the story becomes logical and has two layers: one is that Wu Jie is solving the case of the unknown female corpse and wants to find the murderer; the other is that Wu Jie is also facing her spiritual death and trying to find a way to survive. The answer to go down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/55ac85fe659166239979062a3d35d39b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/55ac85fe659166239979062a3d35d39b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258556&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from &quot;Pursuit&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the movie, detective Wu Jie has a dialogue: &quot;We always say that the corpse will choose someone to handle the case, and she chose me.&quot; Of course the dead would not choose. The fact is that Wu Jie chose this case. She wanted to seek justice for the dead, and her motivation was not only her professional status, but also her responsibility as a woman and her need to heal herself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, female identity shows special significance. On the surface of the story, a female detective is investigating murder cases against women. Inside, there is a woman who empathizes with women who have been hurt—both physically and emotionally—and ultimately healed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of empathy is not uncommon, but it is difficult to become the main line. There is a scene in &quot;Silence of the Lambs&quot; where a group of male detectives are drinking coffee and talking during an indoor scene involving a woman&#39;s autopsy. Jodie Foster, who was inside, felt uncomfortable and helpless when she saw the naked female corpse. Finally, she mustered up the courage to clear the men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To be honest, the story itself of &quot;Pursuit&quot; did not give me much new ideas and was very routine. However, the empathy between the female detective Wu Jie and the female victims always reminds me of the scene in &quot;Silence of the Lambs&quot;. The female perspective runs throughout, and this amplified empathy transcends the limitations of the screen, which is beyond the expectations of ordinary crime films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/039ed79c018630d1e3a528e179f0fb4d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;552&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/039ed79c018630d1e3a528e179f0fb4d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258555&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ; As a category. They are all movies with female protagonists, and women are the protagonists in an absolute sense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is easy for the audience to take a certain unconscious stance, not because of the performance of the two actors, but because of the female protagonist&#39;s genre film, which not only brings freshness, but also brings strangeness. Feeling unwell. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9c3085713ee0bf1bd85bcd6b68ee6ac7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;858&quot; height= &quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/9c3085713ee0bf1bd85bcd6b68ee6ac7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258557&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Type films and There is no need for extraordinary acting skills, it is very craftsmanship, it should be performed, it cannot be missing or wrong. In my eyes, the &quot;craftsmanship&quot; of performances in genre films is a compliment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is Zhang Junning or Zhang Xiaofei, they provide a fresh sense of crime themes. Although the story still has loopholes and problems of one kind or another, more and more complete and different types of female protagonists appear in On the screen, this is a good phenomenon that deserves applause. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人机连接走到哪一步了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260684]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Neuralink, a brain-computer interface company owned by Musk, officially began recruiting volunteers for its first clinical trial. Ideal volunteer candidates are quadriplegic adults under the age of 40. The trial will see most of the volunteers&#39; skulls removed and implanted with a brain-computer implant, a processing, communication and charging system. The device, which is a chip and wires, has more than a thousand electrodes to receive brain data. By comparison, implants from other rival companies have only about 16 electrodes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The thunder that has been ringing has finally turned into raindrops, and the brain-computer interface or human-computer connection will enter the human trial stage. However, implanting a chip in the brain is an invasive procedure that could cause harm to a person if not careful. However, the significance of this research is very important. It can not only decipher the thinking of the human brain, but also make it possible for people to obtain more powerful capabilities with the help of computers and shape the so-called human-machine complex. To this end, we must find a balance between harm and benefits to minimize harm to people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such a balance is the content of medical ethics intervention. In May 2023, Neuralink said that its first human clinical trial was approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA); on September 19, Neuralink announced that the company had received approval from an independent review committee and would conduct the trial this year. Conducting the first human trial of a brain-computer interface. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This shows that Neuralink has done enough homework in terms of ethical review and approval. Before doing this kind of homework, we also followed the procedures of medical clinical trials from animals to humans. Before applying for human clinical trials, Neuralink has conducted relevant tests on pigs and monkeys respectively, and achieved certain results. In particular, the tests on monkeys have proven that it can be applied to humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In April 2021, Neuralink released a video showing a macaque implanted with its device playing video games through telepathy, indicating a major breakthrough in chip implantation in brain control research. The macaque in the video is named Pug, and has a brain-computer interface implanted in his brain. Initially, the research team taught Pug to play games using a game joystick and rewarded him with banana milkshakes through metal straws. At this stage, the brain-computer device records which neurons are activated, models the relationship between Pug&#39;s neural activity and the expected direction of movement, and achieves &quot;brain-computer connection.&quot; Judging from the macaque&#39;s brain thoughts controlling the joystick to play games, the implanted chip shows the preliminary goal of monkey-computer integration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After these results were obtained, Neuralink applied for human trials. Moreover, current human trials also follow the principle that they are only conducted on patients, not healthy subjects. For patients, trials are about balancing benefits and harms. Experiments on patients are to treat their diseases. Even if the process is full of risks, compared with the benefits of giving patients a new life, if the latter is greater or far greater than the former, it is feasible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This trial is targeting paralyzed patients and visually impaired people. Through the brain-computer interface, the brain consciousness of paralyzed patients can be obtained, and this consciousness can be received through an external computer, and then the computer can decipher and issue instructions to the corresponding mechanical devices to help patients with cerebral palsy move, at least to take care of themselves. Such as eating, drinking and going to the bathroom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the visually impaired, implanted visual chips can help them improve and restore their vision, such as helping patients with retinal dystrophy improve their vision. If successful, it could help more patients. There are currently about 1.3 million blind people and 2.9 million people with low vision in the United States. These two numbers are likely to grow to 2.2 million and 5 million by 2030. If the brain-computer interface can treat visual impairment, this group will also benefit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, if an accident occurs in a brain-computer interface experiment or if the damage exceeds the benefits, the principle of putting life and health first will need to be stopped immediately. However, such experiments may also yield unexpected results and new discoveries, helping to reveal more secrets of the human brain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, research on brain-computer interfaces in animals has achieved more results. A research team from the Howard Hughes Medical Institute in the United States has developed a new system that combines virtual reality (VR) and brain-computer interface (BMI) to try to detect the thoughts or thoughts in the minds of rats. As in humans, when rodents experience places and events, the hippocampus, an area of ​​the brain responsible for spatial memory, activates specific patterns of neural activity that allow thoughts to wander back in time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hippocampus is an important area of ​​the brain responsible for memory and imagination. It possesses a model of the environment called a cognitive map. Therefore, the hippocampus contains a spatial map-like representation of the previously explored environment. to facilitate subsequent recall or simulation. At the same time, the representation of each environment consists of specific place cells, and when the animal passes a specific location in that environment, these neurons fire selectively, recalling past scenes. This situation is similar to people&#39;s memory of the environment and cognition of environmental patterns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the test, the rats were placed in a specially designed VR system. The brain-computer interface system translated the rat&#39;s brain activity into movement on a virtual reality screen. Rats need to control their hippocampus activity to imagine specific scenes in order to receive rewards, and this thinking process is very similar to humans. When people are asked to go to a certain theater, they may imagine leaving home and going to the theater. Routes and neighborhoods that will be traveled. Afterwards, the rats were asked to move the virtual object from one location to another by imagining it, that is, the rats needed to move the object to the target location in the virtual space by controlling their hippocampus activity. The researchers then changed the location of the target, inducing the rats to produce activity patterns associated with the new location. The process is like the person sitting in the seat imagining picking up the cup next to the water dispenser and filling it with water. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that rats can control their hippocampal activity with the precision and flexibility of humans, holding their thoughts in a given position for several seconds, similar to how humans relive past events. event or imagine a new scenario. Moreover, as brain-computer interface systems are increasingly used in prosthetics, the results of this research can be used to design new prosthetic devices to serve people with disabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This study on rats once again shows that brain-computer interfaces can know a person&#39;s thoughts and thoughts, just like mind reading. This also means that future brain-computer interfaces can be used for in-depth research on human brain consciousness and thinking, but if they are to be used for healthy people and other purposes, more and stricter ethical and legal supervision is required. Therefore, it is easier to gain consensus by limiting human-machine interfaces to the diagnosis and treatment of diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[在上海住了18年，这位来自迈阿密的“洋盘”还没打算离开]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260759]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/utyNcEWO8MEI850PChVe8Y1LL53sWqYf3c0BPhHY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;607&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/utyNcEWO8MEI850PChVe8Y1LL53sWqY f3c0BPhHY. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He pointed to a residential building across the street and told the story of his friend who had moved to Singapore; in the next street, the locksmith Master Ji saved him; and further on was He often goes to the small shop where clothes are repaired, and greets him every time he passes by. “If I don’t see them, I might forget them.” He is afraid of losing these living records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Combining the life experience of his great-great-grandfather provided him with a new perspective, &quot;Our difficulties are simply incommensurable.&quot; Different from the missionary mission of his ancestors more than a hundred years ago, he has a new perspective on his own mission. The mission becomes clearer, &quot;There is a lot of valuable knowledge here, and I hope it can be seen by more people in the world. I have a visa, can travel, understand the different wisdom of Eastern and Western cultures, and I can do something.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ZXiLAp78GODTtXwpuqbDHbUpLpTPsSWW7MmmmbCi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ZXiLAp78GODTtXwpuqbDHbUpLpTPsSWW7MmmmbCi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258513&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999 ; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2015, Chris measured Shanghai Xiaolongbao&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt; strong>;Where are you in the bubble? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;American Chris has a serious Chinese name - Shen Kaiwei. He said the origin of the name was somewhat boring. When he was working in a hotel in Shanghai more than ten years ago, a colleague in the human resources department named him Shen Jiawei, which he rarely used. When his new book &quot;Yangpan&quot; was published in October 2023, he changed the middle character to &quot;kai&quot;, which happened to have a similar pronunciation to his English name Christopher St. Cavish. Friends who know him well tend to call him Chris. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Foreign Deal&quot; records Chris&#39;s life in Shanghai over the past 18 years, including the whole story of his coming to Shanghai by chance, his ups and downs of riding a motorcycle around northwest China, and his unusual Family stories told to others. In Shanghai dialect, &quot;foreign plate&quot; refers to outsiders who don&#39;t know much about local customs. The English title &quot;outsider&quot; may be more straightforward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“To some foreigners, I am too Chinese; to many Chinese, I am too foreigner. I am not building a bubble (for expats in China)” &quot;Comfort Zone&quot;) came to China, but when I drifted out and blended in outside the circle, I would miss it. I came for China, but I can&#39;t live in China full time.&quot; Chris in &quot;Foreign Dishes&quot; wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/JcFNp61FAenMuqeRmELyriB9rxwHELEQjnPuioYR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1059&quot; height= &quot;1500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/JcFNp61FAenMuqeRmELyriB9rxwHELEQjnPuioYR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Foreign Deals-Flat Cover&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Foreign Deals&quot; is Chris&#39;s first book. Earlier, he applied a quantitative framework to the Xiao Long Bao in Shanghai, collecting the weight of the Xiao Long Bao, the weight of the soup, the quality of the fillings, and the thickness of the skin, calculating the structural and technological quality of the Xiao Long Bao, and wrote &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot;, &quot;if that counts as a book.&quot; Before writing, he worked as a professional chef in Miami and New York for 10 years. Tired of the static life in his hometown of Miami, he decided to seek opportunities in Asia and then travel around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The initial destination I wanted was Hong Kong. At the beginning of the 21st century, he traveled through Southeast Asia as a backpacker and went to Hong Kong to visit his sister. He loves Hong Kong very much. &quot;It is neither a completely Western culture nor a completely Chinese culture.&quot; In the plan, he would go directly to the kitchen of the Peninsula Hotel and offer to work for free. But The Peninsula doesn’t need a young American who doesn’t speak Cantonese in its kitchen. After repeatedly hitting the wall and going through different referrals, he finally found a job as a chef in Shanghai. That’s how I came to Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, Chris came to Shanghai for the first time at the age of 24, planning to stay for only one year. What he didn&#39;t expect was that he would still be living here 18 years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After working in Shanghai for a year, he quit his job as a chef and traveled around the northwest on a modified motorcycle. The journey is thrilling. The motorcycle was always breaking down and he was always looking for a repair shop along the way. One time the brake pads broke, but no shop had vintage brake parts made in Germany during the war (yes, in the 1930s). He later rode a motorcycle with broken brakes through Tianshui, Gansu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Without any danger, he ended his month-long trip. &quot;I was still in Lanzhou in the morning, and arrived in Xining in the afternoon. Everything went too fast. I am used to life on a motorcycle. If I do it again, I might go to Xinjiang. It may not be safe, but...&quot; In short, he later sat down After a 36-hour train ride back to Shanghai, he flew back to Miami the next day. “At that time, I was not sure whether I wanted to come back, so I rented out the house.” Three months later, he returned to Shanghai. Just one more year, he thought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many foreigners in China think so too. Wandering and living with the mentality of “just one more year”, only thinking about 12 months at a time. When my passport was filled with visa papers issued once a year, I suddenly realized that I had been living in this country for more than ten years. Chris calls this &quot;tomorrow syndrome&quot; - &quot;Tomorrow never comes. That year will never end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Chris first came to Shanghai in 2005, there were 100,000 foreign residents in Shanghai. Ten years later, that number had doubled, and has decreased in recent years. &quot;Immigration and foreigners will automatically create their own bubble circle - a barbaric one-size-fits-all approach based on the wealth and poverty of your home country. See foreign doctors when you are sick, and spend a lot of money on imported ingredients when cooking.&quot; Although he is very fond of bubbles. The circle ridicules you in every possible way, but in fact you are also a member of the circle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/hzcXUoCTYzN6J3xgbfOiIuiREbwP3lMCzHTylElr.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height= &quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/hzcXUoCTYzN6J3xgbfOiIuiREbwP3lMCzHTylElr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258512&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2023, Chris was filming the story of a famous hairy crab dumpling restaurant in Shanghai. This hotel will close in the spring of 2023 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Sheila Zhao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most common greeting in the bubble circle is: Are you coming to China? How long? Can you speak Chinese? People judge who is the boss in this circle based on the answers. “A foreigner who has lived in China for six years will look down on a foreigner who has lived in China for six months, and by analogy, a foreigner who has lived in China for six months will look down on a foreigner who has lived in China for six weeks. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparisons like these apply to work, too, with expats teaching English at the bottom of that hierarchical chain of contempt and businessmen at the top. Chris knows several of the latter, &quot;They complain endlessly about the aunties, the Western food, and their Chinese employees.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They also complain about the changes. Expats who have been here for a long time often lament how beautiful Shanghai was in the past, but the implication is that it is not as good as it used to be. Chris doesn’t think so. “Shanghai teaches people to accept changes. This can be good or bad. If you find a good restaurant, you should go there today, because it may not be open tomorrow. If you don’t like Shanghai now, it doesn’t matter. Just wait. , it will be completely different in a year.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After staying in the bubble circle for too long, Chris sometimes wants to go out. The Shanghai Xiaolongbao evaluation completed in collaboration with friends is an attempt. After that, he was often in a half-and-half situation—“one foot in the bubble, one foot outside.” “It was like my identity. Sometimes I wake up in the morning and just want to be in the bubble, so I eat sandwiches for breakfast, pizza for dinner, and stay in my room watching YouTube all day. Sometimes I want to go out and chat with my neighbors and friends. I want to really live in Shanghai.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Zaske81bGCt7il1Z5Du763IZ2PcIn6N6uv8kGAIS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src =&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Zaske81bGCt7il1Z5Du763IZ2PcIn6N6uv8kGAIS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text- align: center;&quot;>;In 2016, Chris learned the ramen making process at a ramen school in Lanzhou. This experience was also recorded in &quot;Foreign Dishes&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Writing in a Foreign Country&lt;/span>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After quitting being a chef, Chris switched jobs to work for an English magazine, writing food reports for foreigners in China. It took him several years to switch perspectives from chef to food writer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;What you want as a diner is completely different from what you want as a chef.&quot; At the end of October 2023, we made an appointment to meet in a Western restaurant. Chris gave the example of cinnamon rolls on the table, &quot; As a chef, I don&#39;t want them (walnuts and icing) to spill, and the edges to be neatly folded. But that doesn&#39;t affect the taste. As a diner, what I think about is does it taste good? Did I enjoy the meal? It Is the price right?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, food is just a medium for him to care about people, helping him to answer more curious questions: &quot;What is their life like? In what ways are we the same and in what ways are we different? ? What is their happiness? What about their sadness?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Writing seems to give me a license to ask people questions that would be excessive or embarrassing in normal interactions.&quot; Some The interview went deeper. For example, when he chatted with Master Tao, a handmade pottery maker in Hongkou, the other party naturally revealed to him the difficulties and struggles in the past. Others are not so lucky. For example, he started visiting the Cen brothers, who were both potters with Master Tao, in 2006. More than ten years later, they still &quot;never said hello&quot; as if they didn&#39;t know him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Chris and his friends released the &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot;. They abandoned personal subjective opinions and measured hundreds of Xiao Long Bao in 52 stores from a purely physical perspective. &quot; Writing about food is bound to be subjective, and you have to understand what other people are obsessed with, but everyone insists on their own opinions (including myself), which makes me feel very tired. I want to change it, and let others or other Use things to make judgments.&quot; He confided in &quot;Foreign Dishes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/63YOykirN9t6Q71aphczyDPfvNrfx43WSxM7Djga.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/63YOykirN9t6Q71aphczyDPfvNrfx43WSxM7Djga.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2012, Chris was DJing in a nightclub&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot; unexpectedly gained him a lot of attention. He has been dubbed a &quot;foreigner obsessed with Xiao Long Bao&quot; and appears in many people&#39;s circles of friends and in interviews with the media. A company that specializes in making xiao long bao even invited him to be a consultant for cheese xiao long bao. He refused. The person in charge of the Shanghai Catering Association said in an interview that they would support Chris if he conducts follow-up research. After seeing the news, he walked to the bathroom and cried in the hallway. In his 10th year in Shanghai, he felt accepted by the city for the first time. Although when he later called the Shanghai Catering Association to talk, the other party had completely forgotten about it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot;, Chris realized that his writing should have more interaction with China. &quot;This is the first step to get out of the bubble circle.&quot; In his circle of friends Gradually more and more Chinese people appeared. Xu Junqian met Chris after the release of &quot;Shanghai Xiao Long Bao Index&quot;. At that time, the latter was recruiting a researcher, and she sent an email to recommend herself. However, the two were slow to warm up, and they did not meet until the following year after exchanging emails. As a test, Chris gave her a name and asked her if she could contact him. Later, the two set off smoothly and went to Yunnan to interview a chef. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of her cooperation with Chris, Xu Junqian went to Altay to interview people who make camel milk, and also went to Shanxi to interview people who make pasta. If it weren&#39;t for work, she probably wouldn&#39;t have taken the initiative to set foot in these places. &quot;Chris speaks Chinese very well, but some dialects are still a bit difficult for him.&quot; When the two collaborate, Xu Junqian is often the interviewer, while Chris listens silently and only adds questions at the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Through Chris’s perspective, Xu Junqian has seen a lot, and “his skin has become thicker.” In her eyes, Chris is a pure person who “does not pursue eye-catching content or deliberately sensationalize. .&quot; In the spring and summer of 2023, they and the photographer went to Qinghai to interview Han Lu, an old man who makes Lanzhou Ramen. The old man cried when the conversation got emotional. This moment was also recorded by their camera, but Chris later did not use this part of the material. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Cr1eWUzQ0tv0kOeBkhoA4MDssuwQmxxlGdt62phU.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/Cr1eWUzQ0tv0kOeBkhoA4MDssuwQmxxlGdt62phU.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to her part-time job, Xu Junqian works in a family Work for foreign companies. She likes to compare the two jobs, &quot;They are like the two poles of the spectrum. Foreign-funded companies pursue returns when doing things, and they would like to arrange ABCD solutions for everything. But often, the more cautious they are, the less they dare to be creative.&quot; As for Chris, &quot;He keeps an open mind and always has unexpected gains.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years or so, Chris has worked for several media outlets and experienced marriage, divorce, moving, and depression again. . After resigning from an online media in 2020, he opened a consulting company to provide services for hotels and restaurants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the company&#39;s business is in a mess. &quot;It performed pretty well in 2021, but it was completely dead last year.&quot; The survival problems that writers often face are increasingly bothering him. The trip to Qinghai with Xu Junqian was paid for with his credit card and he paid it back recently. So he would &quot;take some editorial jobs, or do odd jobs for some schools. I had no choice.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also thought about moving away from Shanghai to Suzhou or Dali, but neither was feasible. On the one hand, he cannot do without Shanghai&#39;s convenient medical system to prevent depression from recurring. On the other hand, &quot;I have many memories here.&quot; He pointed to a residential building across the street and told the story of his friend who had moved to Singapore; in the next street, the locksmith Master Ji saved him; and further on, He often goes to the small shop where clothes are repaired, and greets him every time he passes by. “If I don’t see them, I might forget them.” He is afraid of losing these living records. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The other dilemma is more secret, which was told to me by Xu Junqian. In the past two years, when she helped Chris find interviewees, she would always conceal the latter&#39;s nationality and only introduce him as a foreign author who writes about food. During the same trip to Qinghai, they also interviewed another Lanzhou ramen practitioner. The other person’s attitude was neither salty nor bland. He only asked the waiter to serve a few bowls of ramen. “It felt like he wanted us to leave as soon as we finished the noodles.” .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Are people less friendly?&quot; Chris also asked himself. &quot;I don&#39;t think so. Even if they hate the United States, at least they are polite to me. If you go to the United States in the past two years, the situation may be worse, and the hatred against Asians has become more and more intense.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/fI19RQMpK82UXKtvYnQsUBZlaQujmJNTCJQrW0ML.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/fI19RQMpK82UXKtvYnQsUBZlaQujmJNTCJQrW0ML.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center; &quot;>;The second time I met Chris, we walked together in a neighborhood he was familiar with. He once lived in an apartment on Huashan Road for four or five years, and he knew almost everything about the changes in the nearby shops&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Wang Jiawei/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;&lt;strong>;Should I stay? Do I want to leave? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In 2006, when his parents and sister traveled to China, Chris heard the family story for the first time:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In 1867, 24-year-old Hiram Harrison Lowry and his wife left New York after graduating from Christian School and were sent to Fuzhou, China as a missionary. Two years later, they were ordered to Beijing to establish the first Methodist mission in North China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Lori has been in China for more than fifty years and has experienced war, disease, intense xenophobia, the collapse of the Qing government, and personal life difficulties. They could have returned to the United States, but they chose to stay. They built schools, churches and hospitals for the poor Chinese at that time, and also served as deans of Huiwen Academy (after a complex evolution, this academy was incorporated into Yenching University and then into the famous Peking University today). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The remains of my ancestors are buried somewhere in Beijing, to the west of the old city wall . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——&quot;Foreign Dishes&quot;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he first heard about his great-great-grandfather’s mysterious connection with China, Chris felt it was strange. When the family was walking in the alley near Tiananmen Square looking for the Asili Church (a legacy left by my great-great-grandfather, now the Christian Church Chongwenmen Church), Chris&#39;s mother started counting in broken Chinese. Chris and his sister were stunned, &quot;Can mom speak Chinese?&quot; He vaguely knew that his grandfather, who spoke fluent Mandarin, &quot;had a weird connection with China.&quot; However, his grandfather had a cold relationship with his family and believed in the philosophy of American men in the 1950s. He believes that women should take care of children and never talks too much about themselves with their children. When Chris&#39; mother was 21, her grandfather committed suicide. The clues are interrupted. Later, Chris asked other relatives in the family. They tried to contact Asili Tang, &quot;Maybe it was the language barrier, but they gave up in the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This matter was put on hold for 16 years. Until the spring of 2022, Chris was determined to salvage this piece of history. He saw it as some kind of family duty. The process of collecting information was like a detective challenge. Many diaries were lost or damaged. He spent a lot of energy - &quot;often working 12 hours a day&quot; - to track down Lowry&#39;s life. Finally, in &quot;Foreign Deal&quot;, he used two chapters to reconstruct the life experience of the Lowry couple more than a hundred years ago through detailed historical materials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/KIafELmP4N0SEMAmRv2A4MlyOWW8ecTYemMV5WlV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1059&quot; height= &quot;1500&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/KIafELmP4N0SEMAmRv2A4MlyOWW8ecTYemMV5WlV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Foreign Dishes - Three-dimensional Cover&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After writing &quot;Foreign Dishes&quot;, he couldn&#39;t stop I kept asking myself, &quot;Do I stay? Do I leave?&quot; There was no answer. In fact, he asks this question every year, when he goes to renew his visa at the turn of the new and old years of the lunar calendar. The long Spring Festival holiday is often wasted in anxiety. He is worried that &quot;the visa officer feels that he has paid too little tax due to his responsibilities, or that he dislikes the company&#39;s office being too small.&quot; The anxiety is getting worse every year, and he wants to keep his home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to the COVID-19 epidemic, many of Chris’s friends have left China in recent years. Visas are becoming more and more difficult to obtain, and the number of flights back to China is not the same. He feels that now is the lowest number of foreigners in China in recent years. “The ones who remain are people who take China more seriously. They may have already Get married and have children here, or run a company.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This past summer, he did not have a good time. Depression and the bleak financial situation tortured him physically and mentally, so he borrowed money to return to Miami. After returning to his hometown after four years, he is no longer familiar with many things, such as how much tip should be given, and there are also some issues that he does not understand well and the context behind them, such as transgender. He was embarrassed to find that flying to Qinghai to interview an old man who makes Lanzhou Ramen was more attractive and comfortable than driving 10 minutes to a Colombian restaurant near his home to interview locals. &quot;In Qinghai, people assume that you are an outsider.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;He felt that he should stay in China. Sorting out the life experience of his great-great-grandfather provided him with a new perspective, &quot;Our difficulties are simply incommensurable.&quot; Different from the missionary mission of his ancestors more than a hundred years ago, he became increasingly clear about his mission, &quot;Here There is a lot of valuable knowledge, and I hope it can be seen by more people in the world. I have a visa, can travel, understand the different wisdom of Eastern and Western cultures, and I can do something.&quot; He is currently planning a video account, and is also Prepare a book about noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Back in 2006. After returning to Miami after a motorcycle trip around the northwest, Chris thought to himself, &quot;One year is not enough for China.&quot; More than ten years later, he said with a smile, &quot;Now I feel that 18 years is not enough.&quot; It’s not enough, I don’t know what is enough.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 09:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D真实还原早产儿出生后的六重难关丨国际早产儿日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260775]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-17 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[永聚煤业火灾遇难26人：事发早晚交班时，起火二楼存大量工作服]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260782]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 23:50:08&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Post-disaster situation of Yongju Coal Industry Joint Construction Building. CCTV+ Visual China Map&quot; src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/3bfb49f2de.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/3bfb49f2de.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258572&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; The post-disaster situation of the Yongju Coal Industry Joint Construction Building. CCTV+ Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At 6:51 on November 16, 2023, a fire broke out in the ground joint building of Yongju Coal Industry Co., Ltd. in Lishi District, Luliang City, Shanxi Province, killing 26 people and injuring 38 others. The patient is being treated with all his strength. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Information Office of the Luliang Municipal People’s Government, the fire broke out in the employee bathhouse of the Lianjian Building. Luliang City’s fire protection, public security, health, emergency and other departments rushed to the scene for rescue. The open flames were extinguished at about 8:35, and the rescue was completed at 13:45. The cause of the fire is under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant staff of the Comprehensive Guidance Section of the Luliang City Fire Rescue Detachment told Southern Weekend reporters that the detachment immediately dispatched the police after receiving the call from passers-by. The fire occurred in a building on a local mine, but the specific purpose was unclear. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to official information, a total of 18 fire trucks, more than 30 ambulances, more than 90 medical staff, and more than 150 rescue workers were deployed at the scene for emergency rescue. Relevant staff from Luliang First People&#39;s Hospital told Southern Weekend reporters that the hospital is doing its best to treat the injured. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Run away blindly”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Miner Yang Xu (pseudonym) felt scared after escaping from the fire. In an interview with a Southern Weekend reporter, Yang Xu said frankly: “I’m scared. I choked to death inside, it was on the fourth floor, and I didn’t dare to jump.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the incident occurred, he was holding a pre-shift meeting on the fourth floor of the joint building. If there hadn&#39;t been this fire, after the meeting, he would go to the second floor to change clothes in the well, and then go down to the well on the first floor. Another miner who also works at Yongju Coal Mining told Southern Weekend reporters that the company arranges &quot;three shifts&quot; for underground employees. The morning shift is from 6 a.m. to 2 p.m., and the middle shift is from 2 p.m. to 10 p.m. pm, and the evening shift is from 10 pm to 6 pm the next day. The time when the fire broke out was the handover time between the night shift leaving the well and the morning shift entering the well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the day of the fire, Yang Xu worked the morning shift. He had a meeting at 6:30 and went down to the mine around 7:00. &quot;(The pre-shift meeting) lasted until about 6:50. I heard someone outside shouting, &#39;Come out, it&#39;s on fire.&#39; I was sitting by the window and saw it. Forty or fifty people in our team ran down the stairs. The fire was too big and the smoke was too strong. I turned on the light on my mobile phone and couldn&#39;t see anything. I took the stairs every day and ran down blindly. When I got to the first floor, the front door was on fire and I couldn&#39;t walk. I opened the back door. Escape. I almost choked to death when I escaped. The black smoke from (burning) plastic.&quot; Yang Xu recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xu is 34 years old and started digging coal at the age of 18. He is a local in Luliang and his home is only more than ten minutes away from Yongju Coal Industry. After escaping from the fire scene, Yang Xu took a video of the scene. In the video, before daybreak, bright flames burst out from two windows on the second floor. Along with the sound of explosions, thick black smoke shot straight up along the outer wall. In another video, miners wearing work clothes were seen holding on to the drainage pipe on the outer wall to escape. Some people on the third and fourth floors also lowered ropes to save themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xu has worked at Yongju Coal for more than two years. He estimates that there are two to three thousand miners working in the coal mine, mostly in their 40s and 50s, some local and some from other places. When the shift changes around 7 a.m. every day, there are about six to seven hundred people in the building. Yang Xu said that the building where the fire broke out has four floors. The first floor leads directly to the bottom of the well and is also the lamp room, which is a place where lights are placed and charged from underground. The second floor is a place for bathing and changing clothes, and the third and fourth floors are where workers hold meetings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The brother-in-law of a local woman interviewed is also a miner at Yongju Coal Mining. He had just been transferred from the morning shift to the middle shift the day before the incident. &quot;Fortunately, it was staggered.&quot; The woman told Southern Weekend reporters that her brother-in-law said that the Lianjian Building usually functions as an office building. Except for safety education meetings and showers before starting work, underground workers will not stay in the Lianjian Building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The blackened area on the left exterior wall is the scene of the fire. CCTV+ Visual China Map&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/f2e157cf98.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f2e157cf98. png&quot; data-key=&quot;258573&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The blackened area on the left exterior wall is the scene of the fire. CCTV+ Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Those who had the accident were all on the morning shift before the start of the meeting”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to CCTV news, the fire started on the second floor. Yang Xu said that when going down the well, one has to wear work clothes, and when going up the well, one has to take a shower and change into his own clothes. &quot;On the second floor, there are about two to three thousand people&#39;s underground clothes. Many of them are cotton clothes. They are placed in hanging baskets. The hanging baskets have two layers, one for clean clothes and one for dirty clothes. Every worker has a hanging basket. Usually The hanging baskets are hung from the ceiling. When changing clothes, you swipe your card and the hanging basket will be lowered by the rope.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A hanging basket installation master who has been in the industry for decades told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;Many coal mines, Large enterprises such as steel plants, cement plants, and power plants all install this kind of (bathroom hanging basket). Our manufacturer is also very puzzled about the accident in Shanxi.&quot; He explained that if the fire is caused by wiring problems, the lifting basket is used The best is nylon rope, which will burn automatically and the basket will fall down without burning into pieces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Our products have not caught fire yet. The wires we use are 2.5 square meters copper-core flame-retardant wires with a 30-watt motor. The wire joints are all soldered with solder. It is wrapped with flame-retardant waterproof tape. Our plastic hanging basket is also flame-retardant, that is, if you keep putting it on the fire, it will catch fire, and as soon as it is out of the fire, it will go out immediately.&quot; The hanging basket master analyzed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Those who worked the night shift were fine this time. Those who had the accident were all those who worked the morning shift before starting their shift. They were all on the third and fourth floors. They couldn&#39;t get out when they wanted to.&quot; Yang Xu said, for He had seen all the 26 people killed underground. &quot;They were probably from one team or two teams. All the 40 or 50 people in our team escaped.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yang Xu said that each shift in the mine costs 200 yuan, or 6,000 yuan a month. Although it is not low in the local area, it is &quot;half-tired to death and risking one&#39;s life to make money.&quot; Yang Xu didn&#39;t know what to do next. The mine stopped working after the accident, and he still had two children at home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that Yongju Coal is a private enterprise affiliated to Luliang Dongtai Group, with an approved production capacity of 1.5 million tons per year and a total of 837 employees. The mine was approved to start construction on November 4, 2020, and the merger, reorganization and integration project passed completion acceptance on June 1, 2021. On October 12, 2021, the Shanxi Provincial Department of Emergency Management approved the mine as a Level 2 mine in the safety production standardized management system. The joint building where the fire broke out is a reinforced concrete frame structure building with a total construction area of ​​6,920 square meters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Qichacha’s information, 33.3% of the 78 judicial cases involved in the company were labor disputes. In 2022, it received two environmental penalties, including construction before approval and excessive sewage discharge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of November 16, the Lishi District Emergency Management Bureau of Luliang City, Shanxi Province revealed that currently, various mining enterprises in Lishi District have suspended production for rectification, and are conducting investigation and rectification of fire hazards throughout the district. Work. According to the Beijing News, many persons responsible for the fire accident have been arrested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[摸清观众口味，老IP也能回春]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260771]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Every classic horror film series, away from Don&#39;t open a murderer who is terrifying, such as Freddy in the &quot;A Nightmare on Elm Street&quot; series, Michael Myers in the &quot;Moonlight&quot; series, Leatherface in &quot;The Texas Chainsaw Massacre&quot;, &quot; Hannibal in the &quot;Hannibal&quot; series, Pennywise in the &quot;Return of the Clown&quot; series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These super villains are synonymous with &quot;horror&quot; and have brought countless nightmares to movie fans. At the same time, their existence also constitutes the core attraction of the movie. Just like the MacGuffin in the movie, it makes people uneasy and worried about when they will show up and what kind of killing they will cause after they show up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/3f399188e77f9505d96543dcd3a96ceb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/3f399188e77f9505d96543dcd3a96ceb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258563&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Step into the Thousand After the Jubilee Year, although horror films declined, a director named James Wan showed his talents and created a series of impressive horror images. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The place where his dream began was &quot;Saw&quot; released in 2004. The then unknown James Wan and his friend Leigh Whannell had a sudden idea and used a cost of 1.2 million US dollars and 18 days of shooting time to create the low-cost horror film &quot;Saw&quot;. After the film was released, it grossed US$103 million at the global box office, making James Wan famous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/43be6fc791d4d4bf8d8601b789acc251.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;770&quot; height= &quot;345&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/43be6fc791d4d4bf8d8601b789acc251.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258560&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first work A huge success, opening up a bright road for the future. For the next six years, the series continued to be output at the rate of one movie per year, allowing the audience to experience various imaginative torture and murder mechanisms. So far, the &quot;Saw&quot; series has grossed more than 1 billion U.S. dollars (approximately 7 billion yuan) at the global box office, and has been certified by Guinness as &quot;the most successful series of horror films in history.&quot; Its influence is evident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the 8th and 9th installments, which were restarted after several years, caused the entire series to fall into the abyss of collapse. Especially &quot;Chainsaw 9: Vortex&quot;, released in 2021, suffered a terrible reputation and became the worst in the series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/5a261e8c8d8d72b0db440a2f03dddd75.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;770&quot; height= &quot;345&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/5a261e8c8d8d72b0db440a2f03dddd75.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258559&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Just in Movie Fans People all regretted that the masterpiece was not guaranteed in the late season, and the producer Lionsgate Pictures changed its direction and released &quot;Saw 10&quot;. Unexpectedly, this adjustment had an immediate effect, making this IP burst out with vigorous vitality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It no longer simply shows blood and torture, but instead introduces the analysis of human nature from the perspective of the old murderer Jigsaw. European and American film critics unanimously believe that &quot;Saw 10&quot; is more like a movie than other films in the series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/a5f4dfacd6b3d97ff5e192053afa52cb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1350&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/a5f4dfacd6b3d97ff5e192053afa52cb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258562&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Familiar with &quot;Electronic Audiences of the &quot;Saw&quot; series know that this series has two main characteristics: first, it always tells stories from the perspective of victims or police, throwing extreme dangers and moral dilemmas to the audience; second, it creates Jigsaw, the terrifying jigsaw killer, casts a huge shadow over his victims. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Saw 10&quot;, the perspective is changed, and the main perspective of the villain Jigsaw is used to advance the movie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4630740adca06fc8b01df8a0777e8256.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;583&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4630740adca06fc8b01df8a0777e8256.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258561&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jigsaw&#39;s real name John Kramer, although known as a perverted murderer, never kills anyone himself. Most of the time, he just acts as a judge. He is a terminally ill engineer who likes to tinker with various exquisite torture instruments to make victims choose between pain and death. In his view, this choice is &quot;not punishment, but redemption&quot;, giving those guilty a chance to reform and allowing them to understand the value of life in pain. This kind of &quot;good intentions&quot; constitutes the fatal and terrifying attraction of this character. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Jigsaw only lived for three episodes in this series and died at the end of &quot;Saw 3&quot;. Next, he &quot;lived&quot; for five more episodes through memories, videos, etc. His followers inherited his will and continued to set challenges for others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8bcc0ec65647f883c8df9c7fe6434c8a.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/8bcc0ec65647f883c8df9c7fe6434c8a.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258564&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Caught Jigsaw is a character who captures the soul of the series. Due to Jigsaw&#39;s absence from &quot;Saw 9&quot;, the film&#39;s reputation immediately collapsed. Audiences generally believed that without Jigsaw&#39;s iconic voice and thought-provoking lines, the series seemed to have been hollowed out and lost its creepy feel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, the filmmakers cleverly made &quot;Saw 10&quot; a prequel, with the timeline set between the first and second parts, so that Jigsaw is still alive. At that time, Jigsaw was suffering from cancer. By chance, he learned from his patients that there was an underground medical organization in Mexico that could effectively cure cancer. After getting a rough understanding of the organization, Jigsaw headed to Mexico alone with his last glimmer of hope. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ad85b2d10fce5915bcc1d7952ea9d6ab.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;584&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ad85b2d10fce5915bcc1d7952ea9d6ab.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258566&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In With the help of doctor Cecilia, Jigsaw underwent what is called an &quot;awake craniotomy.&quot; After the operation, the doctor told him that everything was going well and he should rest and recuperate. A few days later, when Jigsaw returned to the agency and wanted to express his gratitude, he found that the place was empty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The craniotomy video he saw during the operation was just a teaching video recorded in advance. It turned out that what he encountered was a fraud group that specializes in scamming cancer patients: the hospital was fake, the doctor was fake, the surgery was fake, and his disease was not cured at all. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f4d7a40ca514959917e38f18dfb5e61e.gif&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;339&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f4d7a40ca514959917e38f18dfb5e61e.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;258568&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In order to take revenge and punish this fraud group, Jigsaw started another round of killings. He arrested all members of the fraud chain, from drivers to nurses, anesthetists, and doctors. Along with them came the familiar jigsaw torture: scraping bones and flesh to defuse bombs, breaking legs to extract bone marrow, opening skulls to remove brain tissue...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to these bloody tortures, &quot;Saw 10&quot; &quot;The most outstanding contribution is that it fleshes out the character of Jigsaw to the greatest extent, magnifies his weakness, and makes him look more like a &quot;person&quot; - a terminally ill old man who seeks medical treatment urgently, and this Old people will also cry for the rest of their lives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this kind of fullness also has its regrets, that is, it can easily make the character &quot;intellectual&quot;. Jigsaw has always been a mysterious, cruel and highly intelligent villain, and he is a symbol of evil. The &quot;in-depth interpretation&quot; of &quot;Saw 10&quot; undermined the coldness and mastery of his symbolic period. People can&#39;t help but wonder, such a clumsy fraud technique can actually deceive the famous Jigsaw? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/e962fca1bdb9a682032b0406e409ffe0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;584&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/e962fca1bdb9a682032b0406e409ffe0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258567&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, from Jigsaw&#39;s perspective cut also greatly weakened the film&#39;s reversal and suspense. Although Jigsaw sets up a reverse climax in the film by taking personal risks in order to find out the mastermind behind the scenes, it pales in comparison to the ultimate reversal in the &quot;Saw&quot; series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, the series was approached from the perspective of the victim and the police, and the setting of suspense points was often very layered: the first level was the victim’s level-breaking mode, either solo, or cooperatively, or in trials. The process is full of all kinds of uncertainties; the second level is the detective&#39;s perseverance in the case and the battle of wits and courage with Jigsaw and his followers. The audience can&#39;t help but sweat for the detective and wonder what he can do. Can they successfully arrest the murderer and save their lives? &quot;Chainsaw 10&quot; only retains the first layer of suspense and completely abandons the second layer of suspense, greatly reducing its suspense. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/b8fd0f4e9f37091626ad3cb526d3cc9b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;581&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/b8fd0f4e9f37091626ad3cb526d3cc9b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258565&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, in order Catering to the trend of anti-elitism in Hollywood, &quot;Saw 10&quot; also increased the &quot;heroic temperament&quot; of Jigsaw. Because Jigsaw faces a female doctor who is only interested in profit and disregards human life, the film emphasizes the justice of his lynching more than any previous film. He has transformed from a morally ambiguous villain into a civilian hero who stands up for patients. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, in a sense, the revival of &quot;Saw 10&quot; is speculative and clever, and it is also the vane of current Hollywood sequels: as long as we hold on to the soul of the story, grasp the trend of the times, and feel By clarifying the audience&#39;s taste, old IP can find a new outlet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[缅北果敢电信网络诈骗犯罪集团首犯明学昌畏罪自杀]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260780]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 23:07:47&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 12, the public security organs in Wenzhou, Zhejiang Province arrested Mingxue, an important leader of the Kokang Telecom Internet Fraud Criminal Group in northern Myanmar, in accordance with the law. Chang, Ming Guoping, Ming Julan and Ming Zhenzhen are wanted for arrest. On November 16, with the strong cooperation of all parties in Myanmar, Ming Guoping, Ming Julan, and Ming Zhenzhen were successfully captured and handed over to our public security organs. On the same day, the Myanmar Consulate General in Kunming received a notification that the Myanmar side organized the arrest of Ming Xuechang on the night of November 15, during which Ming Xuechang committed suicide due to fear of crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the public security agency stated that they will continue to crack down on telecommunications network fraud crimes involving China in northern Myanmar, resolutely eradicate the criminal soil, severely punish criminal suspects in accordance with the law, and resolutely safeguard the safety of people&#39;s lives, property and legitimate rights and interests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[程羽黑读《巢云楼诗钞》丨当代人如何写好旧体诗？ ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260651]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/15/UJWg9H3lGJ0s3HTg5qvJvCMrytfNlXDIR8Z4DsoE.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;690&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/UJWg9H3lGJ0s3HTg5qvJvCMrytfN lXDIR8Z4DsoE. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258347&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Professor Wang Yonghao from the Chinese Department of Fudan University and his &quot;Chaoyunlou Poetry Notes&quot; (Unity Press, 2023). &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Contemporary people&#39;s attitudes towards old-style poetry often gravitate towards two extremes. Some people think too highly of old-style poetry, while others take old-style poetry too lightly. Let’s talk about the former first. Old-style poetry is indeed the jewel in the crown of Chinese literature, but that is only in terms of its excellent works, not that its technology is difficult to master. Li Bai and Du Fu wrote in the old style, and I also wrote in the old style. This can only mean that we use the same style. I have a friend who went to the same elementary school as Yao Ming, but he never thought of himself as Yao Ming - I think this is common sense. Unfortunately, in the world of poetry, not everyone has this common sense. Some people regard being able to write old-style poems as a status symbol. They hold some basic rules as a secret that is not passed down. They say it horizontally and vertically and are proud of it all their lives. It always reminds me of using the tires of the crashed plane as a sacred offering. Aborigines who rose up. In fact, as a skill, the threshold for old-style poetry is not high, and basic rules such as equivalence and antithesis can be mastered in two days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Focus on the latter. I have seen many professors who study classical literature who like to write old-style poetry and are quite proud of their ability to write poetry. However, after reading the works of most of them, one feels deeply regretful. where is the problem? Although many people now accuse the academic community of being low-level, it is fair to say that these professors are not bad at learning. They have studied a large amount of literature, written many good papers, and are familiar with the techniques of classical literature. Some of them are even very good at writing. I remember one of them. His academic prose was brilliant and full of wonderful ideas, which made me unable to stop reading until he showed off his limericks in a serious and triumphant manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason for this situation is probably aesthetic. Aesthetics is &quot;tacit&quot; and cannot be accumulated with knowledge. As far as poetry is concerned, the only way to cultivate aesthetics is to see the best works and experience the beauty in them - to use an outdated buzzword, it is to &quot;open the taste buds&quot; . Having aesthetic ability does not necessarily mean that you can write good poetry - art always requires talent - but at least it can make people aware of themselves. For them, if the poem is poor, it will not be published, and the works that can be shown to others are naturally above the standard. In recent years, I have seen some comments that overestimate old-style literature and believe that the study of classical literature in the modern academic system is meaningless. Only those who can write poetry and classical prose are valuable. I think this is a biased view. A qualified essay requires no less skill and effort than writing a qualified poem. In my opinion, the former is also more valuable. So I often feel sorry for the professors mentioned above - they can obviously write such good papers and monographs, but they can&#39;t write a qualified poem, just like the Mayans in the American jungle who can create magnificent Pyramid, revised amazing calendar, but cannot make the most basic wheel. This is a problem of the shortboard being too short, not a problem of the longboard not being long enough. But some people misunderstand the crux of the matter. Recently, I have also seen some erudite people diligently searching for literature, trying to find a way to write poetry by solving problems such as &quot;How does Qian Zhongshu read poetry&quot;, but the results are often disappointing. In my opinion, they are trying to lengthen the strengths of the literature while ignoring the shortcomings of aesthetics. They are primary school students pretending to be doctoral students to talk about advanced issues, regardless of the fact that the 1+1 foundation is not well laid. For them, it is more urgent to read &quot;Three Hundred Tang Poems&quot; than to explore unpopular literature that sounds noble--if their purpose is to write good poems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mr. Wang Yonghao&#39;s &quot;Chaoyunlou Poetry Notes&quot; provides an excellent example for contemporary people to write old-style poems. This collection of poems contains 1,402 poems, and I spent a week reading them. What impressed me most about this note was the author&#39;s excellent aesthetics, which may be related to the fact that he studied painting when he was young. Painting is an intuitive art, with a higher threshold than poetry and less room for ambiguity. The edification of painting itself is a good aesthetic training. I think Chaoyunlou&#39;s poems have three characteristics, which are especially worthy of reference by contemporary aspiring poets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, the elegance of words. The poems in Chaoyunlou all use elegant words, and there are absolutely no vulgar words. From the perspective of literary history, there is no absolute superiority or inferiority between elegance and vulgarity. There are many common sayings of the time in Du&#39;s poems. Zhang Jie of the Song Dynasty said in &quot;Suihantang Poetry Talk&quot;: &quot;The worldly disciples see how vulgar Zi&#39;s beautiful poems are, but they don&#39;t know that vulgar language is the most difficult in poetry. It is not vulgar, but the most ancient. Yes.&quot; This statement is too flattering. I think Mr. Zhou Yukai said it best: &quot;When these common sayings invade the elegant and exquisite poetic word system, they immediately bring a fresh stimulation in their non-poetic form. A little bit of it can cure the &quot;vulgarity&quot; that is full of statements in traditional poetry.&quot; It can be seen that vulgarity can cure the kind of &quot;vulgarity&quot; that is &quot;elegant but so vulgar&quot;. In modern times, Nie Gannu&#39;s poems are very popular, and he also &quot;takes vulgarity as elegance&quot;, and various common sayings make people laugh (famous lines such as &quot;It is easy to write nonsense words, but it is difficult to be honest in thoughts&quot;). But nowadays, people generally lack classical cultivation. &quot;Elegance&quot; is much rarer than &quot;vulgarity&quot;. Few people can write elegant and upright poetry and ancient prose. Moreover, using &quot;vulgar&quot; is more difficult than using &quot;elegant&quot;. &quot;Vulgar&quot; can only be valuable if it is as interesting as Nie Gannu. Once it is vulgar and boring, it tastes like cold French fries. From my reading experience, contemporary poetry writing suffers from &quot;vulgarity&quot;. A few years ago, a professor used a very vulgar dialect in a poem and triggered a wave of parody. This shows the value of Chao Yunlou&#39;s use of elegant words. . Let&#39;s take &quot;Italian Dolomites&quot; as an example:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is so magnificent that the flood is overthrown and the beginning is the beginning. The golden energy spreads across the horizon, and the surrounding area is covered with frost. The wind is blowing in the wilderness, and there is no starlight in the sky. He entered the room in the morning with his jade in his hand, and took his armor with him to shine on the bed at night. Watch the clouds fall and their shadows disperse, let the crane spend its time dreaming. Jiazhao can be met sincerely, but it is difficult to read all the books. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chaoyunlou uses the wild brushstrokes of poets from the Wei, Jin, Southern and Northern Dynasties to depict the magnificent autumn scenery of the Italian Dolomites, including &quot;flood over&quot;, &quot;juechu&quot;, &quot;opening&quot;, &quot;gazing&quot; and &quot;surrounding view&quot;. Words such as &quot;Jia Zhao&quot; and &quot;Chi Shu&quot; are full of ancient meanings, and &quot;holding jade into the room in the morning and wearing armor to look at the bed at night&quot; can especially be used to express an exotic situation like Chinese classical music, which is extremely elegant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is the richness of life. Chao Yunlou has traveled extensively throughout Europe and Asia, and has a deep understanding of humanities, art and natural landscapes. Chinese tradition values ​​a poet&#39;s experience. Su Dongpo criticized Meng Haoran&#39;s poems as &quot;like making a wine hand without materials&quot;, which means that although he has talent, he lacks experience. Shen Zengzhi believed that opening up a poetic realm was &quot;the ability of an explorer to find new worlds and open ports.&quot; Kang Youwei said in his poem that &quot;the new world is full of strange and wonderful places, and he also searched Europe and Asia to create new sounds.&quot; They both realized the &quot;new world&quot; and &quot;new poetry&quot;. &quot;environment&quot; relationship. Speaking of practitioners among modern people, the first thing that comes to mind is Mr. Jao Tsung-i&#39;s collections of &quot;Buddha Country&quot;, &quot;Western Sea&quot;, &quot;White Mountain&quot; and &quot;Black Lake&quot;, which record the mountains, rivers and customs he saw during his overseas travels. &quot;The self-expectation in the preface is to &quot;point the way forward for the poetry world and open up new eyes and ears to the world.&quot; I think the best one is &quot;Napoleon&#39;s Tomb&quot; in &quot;The Collection of the West Sea&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A hundred battles come to an end If you betray him, he will stroke the bronze camel from under the palace. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The water in the deep palace pool is still sobbing, and the wind and smoke on the island are passing by. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The long days are tired and the short days are sad, and the monument stands abruptly opposite the river. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I have no regrets about the abundant return of my soul, and my last words really make me cry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is tragic, generous and moving, making people sing and sigh. Rao Gong&#39;s nature is calm and peaceful, so it is rare to see such heartfelt works, which often leave people with the feeling that there is still something to be said. This regret was made up for after opening &quot;Chao Yunlou Poetry Notes&quot; - Chao Yunlou&#39;s poems have loud sounds and strong emotions, which is my favorite style. Let’s take “Reflections on the Parthenon on the Acropolis” as an example:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The wind and smoke outside the depression grass are passing by. There is a sacrificial field in Zhenwu. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Several carved pillars are damaged by singing, and one is hanging from the rafters facing the moon. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The Jade Hall was destroyed by fire and empty, and the lonely soul of the Golden Hall was stagnant. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Thousands of dendrobiums are leisurely and sorrowful day and night, and I look alone at Liuhe and place my wine cup on the string. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The materials used in the poem are all Chinese classical, but the imagery is exotic. As a reader with a global perspective, it is easy to appreciate the wonderful idea of ​​blending China and the West, such as &quot;several places of pressing songs to damage the carved pillars&quot;. &quot;Pressing songs&quot; is a Chinese classic, but when juxtaposed with &quot;carved pillars&quot;, it makes people think The harp in ancient Greece, and the &quot;column&quot; also refers to the famous marble columns of the Parthenon. It&#39;s a pun, and it&#39;s very ingenious. The last couplet implicitly uses Xie Tiao&#39;s &quot;The river flows day and night, and the guests&#39; hearts are still sad&quot;, which expresses the meaning of rejoicing in time, which is very similar to Li Bai&#39;s &quot;Wu song and Chu dance are not over yet, the green mountains want to hold half of the sun. Silver arrows and golden pots leak a lot of water, &quot;Looking at the autumn moon falling on the river waves&quot;, Du Fu &quot;I don&#39;t know where the royal palace is, but the ruins are under the cliff... The beauty is made of loess, but the condition is pink and white. At that time, I served on the golden carriage, and the old thing was a stone horse. When I came to borrow straw, I sat down and sang loudly with tears. During the journey, who is the elder?&quot; The vast sadness without the slightest frivolity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is the sincerity of emotion. The poems in Chaoyunlou are all sincere and serious. Many people like to write poems in a glib or eccentric tone, or even be mean and mean, in order to show off their talents. Their targets were great talents like Su Dongpo and Qian Zhongshu. Little did they know that Su Dongpo&#39;s humor came from his broad-mindedness in adversity, while Qian Zhongshu&#39;s humor came from his insight into the world. Both of them had very noble personalities and were very kind to others. They were by no means less intelligent than those today. One&#39;s imitator. Chao Yunlou&#39;s poetry is the opposite of this vulgar poetry style. It is simple, majestic, and full of gentle and honest emotions of classic literature. Let&#39;s take &quot;Visiting the Old House in Montpellier to Compose a Long Song to an Old Friend&quot; as an example:&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Recalling the past, I saw the beauty across the flowers, and vowed to miss her dearly with my delicate hands. Occasionally, the sound in front of the lamp is lingering, but after saying goodbye, it is still difficult to hold on. Look at the bright moonlight like water, and look at the jagged shadows of the trees in the courtyard. I avoid people late at night and come to tell my secrets, and I go to share my secrets with the birds in the morning. There are many high-profile guests holding cups in the hall. Who is sitting there waving his bows and reciting poems? The timidity is dripping in the jade, and the courage to face the stubbornness is still a waste of words. Thinking of his long-lasting desolation at the end of the world, why is it so foolish to sing wildly in Yan City? There should be a high door that can hold the foot, but the rafters cannot be repaired. Gu Zi is frivolous and passes down the household, and his pearls and shoes reach the sunset. Fang Qing turned his back on the lamp and sighed that the night would last forever. Then he turned to face the wall and felt sad. The swallows circled the carvings and mistakenly painted the building, and the rain overflowed the eaves and damaged the old foundation. The old path is covered with stones and grass, and the moss and brocade are covered with snow in the cold dew. Because I feel that every morning the flute is noisy, and in the evening the shengpa is singing and the music is missing. There is no need to blame God for the depression, there is no deception in the mighty years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenery is beautiful and the heart is full of twists and turns. &quot;There is no need to blame fortune for the depression, there is no deception in the mighty years&quot;, which especially shows the clarity of the poet&#39;s heart. The structure of this long poem is reminiscent of the famous &quot;hanging poem&quot; by the ancient Arab poet Ummrull al-Qais. It is also inspired by the old residence, recalling the joy and love with old friends, looking back on the present and the past, and feeling deeply moved. It can be seen that poets from different civilizations have similarities in their poetic minds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After reading &quot;Chao Yunlou Poetry Notes&quot;, I have a strong impression: the author is a &quot;Renaissance man&quot;, versatile, with surging creative talent and desire. The author has a high reputation in the academic world, but he will never be complacent about it. Try reading &quot;The main church is the place where the Portuguese navigator Prince Henry was born and baptized. From its north-facing balcony, you can still see the scenery of the old city winding to the Douro Valley. Human affairs and metabolism have passed through the past and present, and humankind&#39;s ambitions and long-term aspirations have never been extinguished, and we cannot help but be vigilant, vigilant, and diligent to achieve love.&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;老I am afraid of being alone in the storm, and I cherish my broken body because of my wife. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I admire him for hanging on the mat and kissing the birds, and I have found the quiet place and cried on the journey. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is difficult to recruit Haijia easily when facing the water, and I regret my mistake in cursive writing. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The body is often spared from returning to the fish belly, but the mind is trapped in the moon pot&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Prince Henry (I used to call him &quot;Enrique&quot; to distinguish him from many mediocre people with the same name) was a great figure who created the Age of Discovery. Chao Yunlou looked at the old man from the balcony of the church where he was baptized. City, when I think of mankind&#39;s great ambitions, I can&#39;t help but feel vigilant and excited. Chao Yunlou prides himself on being a &quot;confucian scholar&quot; and admires Prince Henry&#39;s sailing career of &quot;hanging on the mat and flying birds in the air&quot;, which shows his ambition to reach thousands of miles. I think people today are not necessarily inferior to the ancients on one point - Enrique had never been to the open sea at that time, and in terms of extensive travels, Chaoyunlou has far surpassed Enrique. Enrique organized an expedition fleet and opened up a new route. &quot;Chaoyunlou Poetry Notes&quot; demonstrated a way for contemporary people to write old-style poems. As readers, we certainly hope that more poets will follow the route opened by Chaoyun Tower and reach the new world of poetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>