<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[当幼儿园的儿子变得“社会”时，父亲在想什么丨养儿育女]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257882]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My son, who is in the third grade of kindergarten, came back from school one night and told me in a low mood: Dad, I can’t do it tomorrow. Because I was talking to my classmates today, the primary teacher who was supposed to be on duty tomorrow was assigned to another classmate by the teacher. I said it didn&#39;t matter, there would be another chance in the future, and then I pulled him with a smile to get ready to play. Unexpectedly, my son scolded me for my passive and careless attitude. He said no, so he would do it one less time. He would not be able to talk nonsense to his classmates next time. I was stunned for a moment. It was really I wonder why he is so interested in being a little teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under my gentle questioning, my son told the truth that he wanted to be a primary school teacher: because this way he could control other children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The answer surprised me. It was clearly a sign of a desire for power. I heard that this is a kind of power given by teachers to children who perform well in order to facilitate daily management. Children who serve as primary school teachers can help the teacher supervise other children, mainly in that they can criticize children with irregular behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wanted to indoctrinate my son and tell him that this idea was wrong. As soon as I said one sentence, I was already lacking in confidence and knew that my dogmatic words would be contradicted by him. I changed my way of saying this: When you are a primary school teacher, you should serve the children. When you find a child making a mistake, don’t scold him loudly, otherwise the other person will be sad. You should speak in a gentle tone. The son said very maturely, I understand. It seems that he has become accustomed to the rules of this little teacher&#39;s game, which I did not expect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that being a primary school teacher is sometimes difficult. Once, he and a classmate were both primary school teachers. His good friend was called out by the classmate when he was speaking. He wanted to be accommodating, but was rejected by the classmate. This made him very distressed and didn&#39;t know what to do. Another time, he criticized a classmate when he was a primary school teacher. A few days later, the classmate deliberately called his name when he was a primary school teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was stunned when I heard these stories. I was at a loss and felt very familiar at the same time. Isn’t this the epitome of the workplace for us adults, and it is too “social”. My son didn’t understand what I meant by “society”. I told him that what the other person did was wrong and you can’t do that. I asked a few friends who have children and they reported similar situations. The only comfort I can find is that such a mechanism can restrain children from some irregular behaviors in class, but it may not be effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe children don’t want to become too “social”. Sometimes they have no choice like us adults, or they are trapped in it without knowing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mother of her son’s classmate told me something: Once, my son told her that one day her child was punished by the teacher at school to stand in the back of the classroom and talk to other children. She asked my son, how did you know, and he said without hesitation that the teacher made us stand while we were talking together. After listening to it, we burst out laughing. We were thinking about saying goodbye to others, but we suddenly exposed ourselves. Perhaps this is a contrast between &quot;society&quot; and innocence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times, children’s world is becoming adult, and children experience the rules and confusion of adult society prematurely. When we face our own problems, we usually appear powerless or messed up. When our children encounter the same situation, how can we expect them to be perfect? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I went to pick up my son from school one day, he happily said that today he was on duty as a student. I thought to myself, what&#39;s so good about being a duty student? Isn&#39;t it just voluntary labor? But he told me that being a student on duty was to help the teacher sweep the floor and arrange chairs. It was a task assigned to him by the teacher, and it was a supreme honor. Thinking about children&#39;s &quot;society&quot;, there may be a gratifying point, that is, the threshold for happiness is very low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently I watched a movie online called &quot;Goodbye, Our Kindergarten&quot;. In the movie, the kindergarten children sang a song at the graduation ceremony, &quot;We have spent countless days here. Every night, we laughed many times, cried many times, caught cold many times, we played here with so many dear friends, we ran here, fell here, fought here, goodbye to our Kindergarten, this is our playground.” The singing and lyrics moved me very much. Kindergarten should be a pure and happy playground, with less social fetters and worries. I recommended this movie to my son. He refused at first, but when I told him that it was about a few children going on an adventure to visit a good friend who was seriously ill, he expressed great interest. That weekend afternoon, because there was no Mandarin dubbing, I read all the lines to him with great emotion. After the movie ended, he said he was going to cry. I knew that he must have the same empathy for other people&#39;s sadness and happiness as the children in the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a worker in the cultural industry)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; •&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(&quot;Raising Children&quot; in the &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of the Southern Weekend App, welcome Write a letter to share the scenery and principles you have learned as a parent and teacher on the way your children grow up. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 22:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打工人为什么越来越反感团建？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257819]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/IZMnXlFgOEJEXwna8gI3vyBrOXpfwcN464su8Xku.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;920&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/IZMnXlFgOEJEXwna8gI3vyBrOXpfwcN464 su8Xku. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252394&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Absurd Show&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;18 faces are on the ground, 18 hands are stretched out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18 employees in black team uniforms lay flat on the stage of a hotel conference hall, pointing in a worshiping posture to the judges&#39; seat where the team&#39;s appearance is scored - the seat of the training instructor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high scores given by the judges were like a black hole, sucking eight teams composed of employees into endless rehearsals and competitions. It seems that after being assigned the team names of &quot;War Wolf&quot;, &quot;Electric Wolf&quot; and &quot;Wild Wolf&quot;, people&#39;s wolf nature can be stimulated. The salesperson who doesn&#39;t like to exercise stacked up four layers of arhats without safety protection; the girl who usually speaks slowly and quietly yells &quot;Hello everyone&quot; while kicking in goose steps to compete for the glory of the team; to express her love for the company Out of gratitude, a team simply knelt down collectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The door to the conference hall was pushed open by the diligently practicing team members before 8 o&#39;clock in the morning, and was reluctantly closed until 1 o&#39;clock in the morning. Rehearsing exhaustingly, just so that one of the teams can show the most unique posture, the neatest steps, and the loudest slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The team building organized by the company made Li Yang a performer of spectacle. Before, he couldn&#39;t believe that he would show his style as &quot;falling headfirst&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yang is a salesperson at a private lighting company. When he sees videos displayed by other teams on Douyin, he always sneers at those exaggerated actions. Unexpectedly, the person in the video now is himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On an ordinary weekend in August 2023, in Changzhou, Jiangsu, under the threat of salary deduction from the personnel department, Li Yang and more than 200 other colleagues boarded the team-building bus angrily. In the hotel where the team was built, they devoted themselves to all activities day and night, without any fear of leaving behind hoarse voices, bruised limbs, and colds, as if everything was done willingly from the beginning. The anger of being forced to &quot;work overtime&quot; and the 100 yuan of self-funded team building fees seem to be just small hurdles that need to be overcome in the process of &quot;soul sublimation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sublimation of training activities is to let employees learn to be &quot;thankful&quot;, which is the appeal of the company boss. Li Yang recalled that this team building did sometimes touch the soft hearts of some employees. Listening to the training instructor&#39;s exaggeration, an employee who had left his hometown had an epiphany with tears in his eyes: he should regard the company as his &quot;home&quot;; the boss carried two employees on his back and ran panting around the venue to simulate the &quot;hardship of starting a business.&quot; Li Yang will also feel compassion when he sees it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, reason reminded him that these sensational points are more like the fog lingering on the abnormal logic: &quot;The mentor said that the boss runs on the back of his employees, just like when he started a business, he carried the burden for his employees. Why do I think it&#39;s the other way around? It&#39;s obviously the employees who are carrying the boss&#39;s weight forward. The instructor just wants us to feel guilty and work hard.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yang does feel guilty, but This has nothing to do with the company&#39;s favor, but more to do with one&#39;s own actions against one&#39;s will. He confessed that he did not understand the value of these games, but he became the component that maintained their operation; he knew the mentor&#39;s &quot;lies&quot;, but accepted his every instruction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After leaving his previous company, this is Li Yang’s first year at this company and he has not yet established himself. He didn&#39;t dare to stand up and refute anything, &quot;I can&#39;t be the kind of person who dares to be the first in the world.&quot; Seeing a group of &quot;post-00&quot; colleagues sneak away in the night after experiencing the first day of training, Li Yang&#39;s feet were still nailed In place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who stayed behind, like Li Yang, carried out their &quot;behave&quot; to the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Life and Death Grid&quot; with &quot;team collaboration&quot; as the training purpose: nearly 300 people pass through the same net hole one after another. If someone touches the net, everything will be cleared and restarted. The whole process lasted for more than 4 hours, with the supervisor interrupting again and again and the team members numbly repeating the devastating actions. Meditation designed to teach people self-reflection: While everyone was meditating in soothing music, a dozen training assistants suddenly rushed out of the darkness and cursed at the employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yang doesn’t have many complaints about his boss, the initiator of team building. What he dislikes the most is &quot;Brother Guo Shi&quot;, the training instructor who issues orders and designs courses - a man in his forties with unknown educational background and qualifications, who calls himself &quot;the master&quot;. &quot;He likes to ask us closed-ended questions, and his catchphrase is &#39;understand the applause&#39;, just like a pyramid scheme.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/27/lHBup7JvgoG3V87TLGXrNJ1Y9JzN0VMY92m0mYQl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /27/lHBup7JvgoG3V87TLGXrNJ1Y9JzN0VMY92m0mYQl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Employees of Li Yang’s company conducted a team presentation&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Brother Guo Shi appeared with his head held high among a group of &quot;teaching assistants&quot; who were kneeling. On the podium, he emphasized that as long as Obey, don&#39;t argue, he has the power to eliminate anyone. A female employee in her fifties fell to the ground from exhaustion while being punished in a game (doing hundreds of push-ups). Instructor Guo yelled at those who came to help and urged the punished to complete it alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Instructor Guo is just one of the symbols of this closed venue. Along with him, suppressing the free movement of participants, there are banners hanging on the four walls: &quot;To love him is to strictly demand him&quot;, &quot;There is no you and me, only us&quot; &quot;If you don&#39;t provide results, the boss will bear the consequences&quot;; There is a game mechanism with bonuses for the top three, more than 200 uniform black T-shirts, and a queue shouting louder than the other. Li Yang explained, &quot;Although it seems absurd, in that environment, everyone did it, and you had no choice but to follow it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/27/WtiOFFAbblHFrnkf54zAo7rXxfnwuRJW8TuW6aFV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;664&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/27/WtiOFFAbblHFrnkf54zAo7rXxfnwuRJW8TuW6aFV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252393&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Today&#39;s team building is not training&quot;, “Team building is biased towards entertainment and has even been demonized”, “bad money drives out good money”, this is the evaluation of the current team building market by Xia Hui, general manager of the experiential training institution Renzhongren in South China&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The loneliness of experiential training&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;No matter whether the experience is good or bad, &quot;team building&quot; is something that most migrant workers avoid today. I am afraid of the shackles of the workplace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is nothing new to rely on rationality to undergo certain magic operations in team building like Li Yang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A steady stream of companies send their employees on team-building tours that are infuriating and humiliating. On the Internet, every once in a while, there will be hot searches such as &quot;slapping each other&#39;s face team building&quot;, &quot;kowtow to the leader team building&quot; and &quot;cruel survival team building&quot;. What was once shocking news is now commonplace. They seem to form a part of our country&#39;s workplace culture, to an extreme degree and in a stable state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Today’s team building is not training”, “Team building is biased towards entertainment and has even been demonized”, “Bad money drives out good money”, this is Xia Xia, General Manager of South China Region of Renzhongren, an experiential training institution. Wei’s evaluation of today’s team building market. Rather than “team building”, people in the industry prefer to use “experiential training” to refer to these corporate team trainings designed to challenge oneself, build a team, and improve performance. Xia Hui said that &quot;team building&quot; was originally just the name of a course in experiential training. Because it is designed with low difficulty, broad goals, and high demand, it has gradually become the most popular type among peers. Among them, games and activities are the easiest to imitate, so &quot;team building&quot; has become synonymous with various activities of corporate teams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market is filled with all kinds of experiential trainers. Some, like &quot;Instructor Guo&quot;, specialize in corporate courses and are good at using chicken soup stories and game commands to establish themselves as authorities; some have switched careers from military training instructors and continue to enjoy the unique field control of this job in outdoor projects. more often, they act as &quot;tour guides&quot; in relaxed team-building trips. They rarely make guidance summaries, and their faces are vague in the minds of employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, there is currently no unified and official professional qualification certificate for experiential trainers to enter the industry. Training institutions set entry thresholds for trainers, and they all do so in their own way. Xia Hui said that perhaps we will see many &quot;team building alliances&quot; that have introduced some trainer assessment standards, but those are all &quot;private certifications.&quot; Renzhongren&#39;s trainers will undergo half a year of training courses and half a year of internal assessment before officially taking up their posts. Mr. Hu from Shaanxi relied on his previous experience as a military training instructor and self-study online to expand his training knowledge. He was able to work directly in a company he knew well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Wei, general manager of Shanghai Zhongji Development, feels dismayed by the uneven qualifications of trainers. &quot;Some colleagues distort experiential training into military training and devil training. It is not like this. It should be relatively mild.&quot; What he deplores even more is the loneliness of the golden age of experiential training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When experiential training was introduced from Europe and the United States to mainland China via Hong Kong 28 years ago, it was not as notorious as it is today. At that time, it was a niche, professional, high-level industry that was easily recognized by customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To find a true etymology for experiential training, it is Outward Bound. “Outdoor Development” and “Outward Bound” were both its translation names. Overseas, its identity is not a business-oriented service, but an education model. Its predecessor was the Seamen’s School of the same name founded by German-Jewish educator Kurt Hahn in Wales during World War II. Hann believes that the one-month wilderness survival training can allow trainees to break through themselves, hone their will and form a close team bond through &quot;personal experience&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first company in China to try something new is Renzhongren. In 1995, Renzhongren introduced Outward Bound to China, turned it into a corporate training business, promoted it in China, and registered the trademark &quot;Outward Bound&quot; for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders call the most prosperous decade of the experiential training industry at the beginning of the 21st century the &quot;Expansion Training Era.&quot; In 2004, when Lin Wei first entered the industry, experiential trainer was a profession with a halo. Most of those who came to participate in the first round of interviews with Lin Wei had a master&#39;s degree or above, including many with Ph.D.s and even university teachers who worked part-time during the winter and summer vacations. Undergraduate students with a background in education or psychology may also be selected, but it is best to have more than three years of work experience. After the first round of careful selection, the remaining 12 candidates will go to the base to receive a one-month training course. While attending class, he was eliminated. In the end, only five people were left in formal positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What attracted Lin Wei to join the industry was the high salary and dignity that this career brought. In 2004, the average monthly salary of a white-collar worker was around 5,000 yuan, but a Shanghai trainer who gave 15 classes a month could earn a salary of more than 20,000 yuan. A course lasts for 1-2 days, and one trainer is responsible for leading more than ten students. Whether they are ordinary employees or wealthy entrepreneurs, they all respect trainers as &quot;teachers&quot; - not through preaching, but through guidance and encouragement, allowing students to transcend previously unreachable limits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the classic project of high-altitude broken bridge, students need to climb an 8-meter-high shelf, walk on a broken narrow board, and jump from one end to the other. Of course, this is while wearing a fall arrester. Whenever students tremble at the take-off point due to fear of heights, Lin Wei would say soothing words on the edge of the bridge, teach them to take a deep breath, lower their posture, and tell them &quot;it can be done.&quot; During the review session, Lin Wei will summarize the students&#39; performance and explain the psychological mechanism behind the game, &quot;By breaking through situational pressure and expected pressure, people can get out of their comfort zone and grow.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Students and training The trainers were reluctant to leave when they left. They even cheered and threw the trainer high into the air. Lin Wei believes that &quot;obtaining such great recognition from people in such a short period of time is unmatched by other professions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Lin Wei can no longer see the reverence he once had in the eyes of his students. and admiration, &quot;They no longer call trainers teachers, but &#39;coaches&#39; instead. However, this is not a position for training people&#39;s skills.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Kanzhun.com, currently, experiential training in Shanghai The average salary of a teacher is around 13,000 yuan. Lin Wei told Southern People Weekly that most of the original batch of high-quality trainers have now switched to in-house training (a type of corporate consulting that focuses on the right medicine and focuses on theoretical explanations). What left with them was Lin Wei&#39;s enthusiasm, a passion that &quot;sees that the peers around me are all excellent and I can learn a lot from them.&quot; He doesn’t understand why fitness coaches can also be trainers. “Physical fitness is not the focus. Improving mental understanding through experience is the purpose.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experiential training has low investment threshold, high income, and market demand. Large, various activity courses are also easy to copy. The sinking of &quot;high-end industries&quot; has led to the industry attracting many profit-seekers, but there is a lack of internal regulatory constraints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Customers favor fun activities and do not care about the &quot;training value&quot; behind them. To adapt to this, the proportion of business expansion training courses that require carefully designed outlines and emphasis on educational content is decreasing; the proportion of simple entertainment team building (such as simple games, fun sports, themed activities) is increasing. Entertainment team building accounts for 50% of Renzhongren’s business and as high as 70% for Zhongji. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Wei pointed out that current team building is like letting participants simply watch a movie. While watching, their emotions fluctuated greatly; after leaving the theater, what happened in the dark had no impact on their future lives. &quot;Actually, the sharing session after the movie is the most valuable. The previous training was to guide the students to talk about these &#39;movie-viewing experiences&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/EsBEbeEWTuyWxB7uIFakKT3iBXPjaMjNLP8a3lAZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/27/EsBEbeEWTuyWxB7uIFakKT3iBXPjaMjNLP8a3lAZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On a personal level, Kang Ying The team building she participated in was regarded as &quot;the cleansing of the soul.&quot; However, she firmly believes that team building cannot bring the relationship between employees and the company closer &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Team building is not that Important&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Kang Ying, who returned from the United States six years ago, was full of child-like desire to explore when she first came into contact with team building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from college in 1999, Kang Ying has been working in the United States. He returned to China in 2017 and worked as a director in two domestic pharmaceutical companies. In recent years, she has unlocked team building, a unique domestic employee collective activity. &quot;I think it is very fresh and fun, so I am more involved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, Kang Ying is still grateful for the desert hike two years ago. The spiritual wealth that team building brought to her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day, 15 kilometers, Dunhuang Gobi. For Kang Ying, who doesn&#39;t usually exercise much, this is an astronomical figure. After learning about the team building content, she almost had the idea of ​​resigning. At that time, she was pulled into a WeChat group by the service provider, which was designed to prepare for the subsequent hike. The trainer requires employees in the group to clock in and start running one kilometer every day. Mileage gradually increases until 8 kilometers per day. Colleagues check in together and encourage each other. Kang Ying gritted her teeth and persisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This activity even helped her develop an exercise habit. &quot;It&#39;s hard to imagine that without this group, I would be able to run 8 kilometers alone. After that, I successfully lost 20 pounds and my whole body has reversed growth. It seems that I have really developed some perseverance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The long journey in the desert exhausted Kang Ying’s physical strength gained through running, and also allowed her to experience friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hiking activity starts at 7 a.m. and plans to cover 15 kilometers along the &quot;Xuan Zang Westbound&quot; route in 8 hours. After only 3 hours, Kang Ying could no longer move her legs. In her 46 years of life, she felt the despair of being physically exhausted for the first time. Looking up at the huge sandy slope, she paused in a daze. Suddenly a colleague&#39;s voice came from beside him: &quot;Don&#39;t think too much, step on this sand nest with your left foot, step on that one with your right foot, and climb up step by step.&quot; The other colleagues were not in a hurry and stopped to tell them Her knack for climbing. The trainer encouraged her while handing her water. The slope was finally over. The mutual-help friendship forged under difficult circumstances continues to this day. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I thought about it afterwards, and it&#39;s the same at work. As a superior, when I need my team&#39;s subordinates to overcome difficulties, I shouldn&#39;t threaten them: If they can&#39;t do it, come see me with your head raised. . You should stand in their shoes and give more specific guidance. Even if it is as simple as &#39;step your left foot first and then your right foot&#39;.&quot; Kang Ying concluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a personal level, Kang Ying regards the team building she participates in as &quot;the cleansing of the soul.&quot; However, she firmly believes that team building cannot bring employees and the company closer. Effects such as &quot;strengthening employees&#39; sense of belonging to the company&quot; and &quot;deepening their recognition of corporate culture&quot;, in Kang Ying&#39;s view, are all illusions created by team-building advertisements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the desert team building helped the company accumulate some goodwill in Kang Ying&#39;s heart, then this goodwill has been completely lost in the lazy working environment and workplace factional struggles. Kang Ying believes that the CEO&#39;s behavior is the factor that actually affects a company&#39;s corporate culture the most. If the CEO notices that his subordinates are blaming others, but fails to stop them, blaming behavior will continue to occur in the company. Kang Ying&#39;s direct boss in the company is the general manager, but she once received a message from the human resources department: the group CEO wanted her to be his eyes and ears - to report all the general manager&#39;s activities at any time, including his private life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she thought that the leaders might be burying spies and scheming, but the company was always happy to organize team building and create a scene of concerted efforts, Kang Ying began to question the meaning of team building itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also two years ago, the company failed in financing and carried out large-scale layoffs. Kang Ying lost her job. The mountains I climbed, the speeches I heard, the games I fought, and the philosophies I learned were like a dream, leaving nothing behind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kang Ying said that it is too reluctant to expect to gain a &quot;sense of belonging&quot; in the company through team building. If she can work in a company for more than ten years, she will naturally feel &quot;home&quot; about it. But in the past two years, she didn&#39;t know if the company would one day abandon her. A team building session cannot resolve this sense of crisis. Kang Ying believes that if employees show emotional dependence on the company, it is most likely a performance to &quot;show compliance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes, team building is not only a performance by employees to their superiors, but also a performance by the company to the outside world. A staff member of Renzhongren revealed that when many customers book experiential training services, it is more for promotional purposes. With an excellent video team, multi-camera shooting, high-end equipment, and skilled editing, team-building activities are recorded as blockbusters and become advertisements for recruiting new members. The actual feelings of the actors are not important, and it is not important whether the training purpose is achieved. What is important is to show to the outside world that &quot;this is an exciting and accomplished collective activity.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wearing a mask may be a survival rule for some people. Some people are also trying to take off their masks. In August 2023, a company in Hunan was worried that group travel would cause discomfort to some employees, so it changed the payment to 3,500 yuan per person, which can be freely disposed of; the personnel of a company in Chengdu discovered that when the boss arranged a weekend team building, no one After signing up, a full vote was initiated and the event was scheduled for Friday afternoon. They don&#39;t know yet what they will lose, but they seem to have regained a little bit of the fun they had been deprived of before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Li Yang, Teacher Hu, Kang Ying, and Bobo are all pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[许家印被采取强制措施！可能涉嫌多项罪名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257888]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 20:46:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Various rumors about the current situation of Xu Jiayin, the actual controller of Evergrande Group, have finally come to light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 28, 2023, China Evergrande issued an announcement on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange stating, &quot;The company has received notice from relevant departments that Xu Jiayin, the company&#39;s executive director and chairman of the board of directors, has been detained in accordance with the law for suspected illegal crimes. Take compulsory measures. Trading of the company’s shares on the Stock Exchange will be suspended from 9:00 a.m. on September 28, 2023, and will continue to be suspended until further notice.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A criminal law expert told 21 A reporter from Century Business Herald said that the content of Evergrande Group’s announcement was very clear. According to Evergrande Group&#39;s announcement, the company should have received a definite notice, and the notice characterized Xu Jiayin as &quot;suspected of illegal crimes&quot; and compulsory measures were taken. It is common sense to guess that when there is notification from relevant departments, the coercive measures taken are likely to be different from the &quot;residential surveillance&quot; that has been misreported by overseas media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned criminal law experts said that in the context of the early stage of the China Securities Regulatory Commission’s investigation into Evergrande Real Estate and the public security departments taking criminal coercive measures against suspected criminals such as Du Mou of Evergrande Fortune, Xu Jiayin was suspected of illegal crimes. The results should not surprise many people. Public opinion has previously focused more on “when” to take action. Judging from the current public information, the issues he is involved in are likely to be related to multiple crimes. They are very complicated and may take quite some time to clarify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior observer in the field of corporate governance told the 21st Century Business Herald reporter that Xu Jiayin had previously publicly declared high-profile slogans such as &quot;No one is allowed to lie flat&quot; and &quot;I can have nothing&quot; in 2021, but comprehensively considering all aspects, Judging from the information and reports, in fact, Xu Jiayin and his company said one thing and did another, tried to &quot;sit down&quot; at every turn, and threw the burden of resolving various problems and contradictions on society, leaving a mess that is difficult to clean up. From this perspective, it is no exaggeration to say that public opinion criticized him verbally and writingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned observers pointed out that at this cusp of great pressure from all parties, Xu Jiayin was shouting slogans to deceive creditors, but at the same time he had a &quot;silent technical divorce&quot; with Ding Yumei. Due to the agreement of Evergrande Group to be listed in Hong Kong through the &quot;small red chip&quot; structure, among the more than 90 billion Evergrande Group has previously distributed in accumulated dividends, the British Virgin Islands and Cayman Islands are 100% controlled by Xu Jiayin and Ding Yumei respectively. The offshore company received most of the dividends through China Evergrande (03333.HK), and transferred them overseas before and after the accident. Through the &quot;technical divorce&quot; operation, it eventually fell into the pocket of &quot;overseas ex-wife&quot; Ding Yumei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior partner of an accounting firm who is familiar with cross-border restructuring pointed out to the 21st Century Business Herald reporter that at present, Evergrande Group’s overseas debt restructuring may be due to Xu Jiayin and some senior executives being suspected of illegal crimes. The situation faces major changes. But whether it is domestic or overseas, whether the reorganization is successful or liquidated, I believe there are sufficient legal channels for domestic and foreign creditors to safeguard their rights and interests and pursue the responsibilities of Xu Jiayin and others. At the same time, the regulatory authorities are also likely to investigate Xu Jiayin and other executives&#39; illegal violations. The crime and subsequent investigation will be investigated and held accountable in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 20:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刑事自诉小慧君诽谤立案：孙灏羽的“好运”可以复制吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257796]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;There is new progress in the &quot;Xiao Huijun&quot; rumor-mongering sexual assault incident. Chidu Company founder Sun Haoyu recently posted on social media that the procedural issues in his criminal private prosecution case against Xiao Huijun for defamation have been resolved and will be heard soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2020, the well-known cross-dressing blogger &quot;Sien Xiaohuijun&quot; publicly accused her former boss Sun Haoyu of sexually harassing her online. Fortunately, Sun Haoyu later obtained evidence to prove that the so-called sexual harassment was just a rumor created by Xiao Huijun in order to terminate the contract with the company at a low cost. Including Xiao Huijun and several other contract anchors under Chidu premeditated and planned this rumor and slander incident in a group. After obtaining the evidence, Sun Haoyu filed a civil lawsuit against Xiao Huijun and others, which was supported by the court. The court clearly stated in the civil judgment that the evidence proved that the alleged sexual harassment was fiction, and ordered Xiao Huijun and others to apologize and compensate for losses to Chidu Company and Sun Haoyu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Sun Haoyu filed a criminal private prosecution with the court, requesting that Xiao Huijun be held criminally responsible for spreading rumors and defamation. Initially, the court in Xiao Huijun&#39;s place of residence believed that it had no jurisdiction and ruled to dismiss Sun Haoyu&#39;s lawsuit. The higher court ruling published by Sun Haoyu this time determined that the court at Xiao Huijun&#39;s place of residence had jurisdiction and ordered the court to open the case and accept it. At this point, there is no obstacle to filing a criminal case against Xiao Huijun for defamation, and the next step will be to enter the formal trial process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From being rumored to be sexually assaulted, to winning the civil lawsuit and the court confirming that &quot;Xiao Huijun&quot; spread the rumor, to finally filing a criminal private prosecution case, the journey has been difficult. In view of the frequent occurrence of similar rumors on the Internet, many netizens hope that Xiao Huijun&#39;s case will deter those who try to follow suit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, there have been constant incidents of accusing others of sexual harassment or even sexual assault through online essays. However, many of them are difficult to distinguish between true and false, and some have been deemed by judicial authorities as lacking evidence or even being slanderous. For example, a female employee of a well-known large factory alleged that she was raped by a male leader, but police investigation showed that there was no rape. Recently, another host was also accused of rape, and police investigations revealed that the woman suffered from schizophrenia and experienced hallucinations and delusions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For these online essays alleging sexual assault, many netizens often choose to believe the parties involved for the first time. The reason is often that &quot;women will not use their innocence to slander others.&quot; However, many facts prove that in the face of interests, nothing is impossible. For example, Xiao Huijun did not hesitate to sacrifice her &quot;innocence&quot; in order to terminate the contract with Chidu Company at a low cost. There are also some people whose motives for slander are difficult for ordinary people to understand, and they may simply have mental problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Xiao Huijun accused Sun Haoyu of sexual harassment, many netizens believed it to be true. Sun Haoyu and Chidu Company were bullied online and threatened offline. The company&#39;s door and front desk were smashed many times, and people were everywhere when Sun Haoyu went out. Followed by taking pictures and cursing. An MCN organization that was originally at the top of the industry has almost come to a standstill and is now unknown in the industry. A well-known host was at the peak of his career, but after being accused of sexual harassment, he was put into hiding, and his career and reputation were ruined. Although they won the lawsuit, their careers struggled to recover. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is extremely difficult for these men who have been falsely accused to defend their reputations. In civil litigation, it is difficult to obtain evidence recognized by the court. Sun Haoyu was lucky. Someone in Xiao Huijun&#39;s &quot;Blood Battle Chidu&quot; small group found his way back and provided the chat records Sun Haoyu needed. Zhang Heng, another well-known online article author who was falsely accused of raping an underage female fan more than ten years ago, has been unable to obtain the identity of the false accuser through legal channels, let alone prosecute. The accuser just wanted to make a famous person look bad, but he &quot;hidden his fame and achievements&quot; and didn&#39;t even reveal his true identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if the civil lawsuit is won, the compensation received is very little. The defendant&#39;s apology is often light and perfunctory, and the amount of communication of the apology is also very different from that of the false accusation. , it is difficult to clarify the facts and restore reputation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To deter rumors and defamation, the rumor makers must pay a greater price, such as criminal liability. However, the criminal law stipulates that spreading rumors and defamation is generally a private prosecution crime, and the victim needs to collect evidence and file a lawsuit. It is even difficult for victims to collect evidence for civil lawsuits, and it is even more difficult for criminal evidence that requires stricter requirements than civil lawsuits. Sun Haoyu was just lucky. He got the evidence and the verdict of winning the civil lawsuit, and he had more confidence to file a criminal private prosecution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Sun Haoyu’s good luck is difficult to replicate.要让诬告陷害者得到惩罚，需要降低诬告陷害转为公诉的门槛，只要被害人提出诉求，就应该转为公诉，由警方对案件进行调查取证。如此，才能加大对造谣诽谤的打击，维护被害人利益，维护网络秩序。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会：赛场内外，同样精彩]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257834]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;截至2023年9月27日17时，中国代表团在杭州亚运会奖牌榜上遥遥领先，奖牌总数124块，其中69块金牌、39块银牌、16块铜牌。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月24日，获得女子1500米自由泳决赛冠军的李冰洁在展示奖牌。&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252480&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月24日，获得女子1500米自由泳决赛冠军的李冰洁在展示奖牌。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杭州第19届亚运会于2023年9月23日至10月8日举行，共有15个比赛日。 The competition events of this Asian Games include 40 major events, 61 sub-events, and 481 minor events. It is the Asian Games with the largest number of events.值得注意的是，非奥项目作为亚运区别于奥运会的标识，大多起源于民间传统体育活动，具有深&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[政府办马拉松，摊主开新店：淄博烧烤国庆“再拼一把”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257832]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月13日，第四届中国国际文化旅游博览会在济南举行，展区内展出淄博烧烤模型。视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/2a6b600519.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/2a6b600519.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252360&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月13日，第四届中国国际文化旅游博览会在济南举行，展区内展出淄博烧烤模型。 （视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个过去的“五一”，一个临近的“十一”，淄博市中医医院急诊科的孙大夫，连着两个长假出了两趟任务。 In order to protect people from all over the country who came to Zi for barbecue, as a member of the city&#39;s medical security team, he stayed on duty at the makeshift barbecue city for several days during the May Day holiday. The constant flow of people made him, an &quot;Old Zibo&quot;, feel unreal. The outside world kept saying that it was going to be cold, but it was always crowded every time he passed by the popular barbecue spot Ba Daji when he went out. Just like that, half a year passed in a blink of an eye. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过完这个暑假，大街上确实有所恢复平静，不过一场马拉松下来，又是一片人声鼎沸。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“&#39;十一&#39;肯定还会有一波流量。在这个时候办马拉松，就是这个意思。”9月24日，国庆长假前的最后一个周末，这座网红城市举办首届马拉松比赛。 Just after the game ended that day, Dr. Sun gave his prediction for the passenger flow during the National Day holiday. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因为在淄博举行，这场马拉松又被跑友们戏称为“烧烤马拉松”。 “As soon as I heard it was the Zibo Marathon, I rushed (to sign up).” After getting off the high-speed train at noon on September 23, Feng Yanhua made an appointment with fellow runners to have a meal. They queued for an hour and a half, and many people in front of the store were carrying Marathon on their backs. The pre-game package looked like a contestant who stopped by for the tooth festival. &quot;Zibo people are very welcoming, and the barbecue is very affordable and delicious.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上演了几个月的“狂飙”剧情，淄博烧烤经历了从爆火，到疯狂扩张，再到归于短暂平静的激烈演进。 Many interviewees said that after the summer vacation, the market showed obvious signs of calming down. However, whether it will return to its original shape before the epidemic or maintain an average value of warm but not cool, people are still waiting and watching, and it is difficult to tell. Conclusion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，受访者一致认为，至少这个“十一”黄金周，淄博仍会迎来游客高峰。 For this reason, businesses and citizens are eager to try to seize this possible &quot;last wave of traffic.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;烧烤店主：“十一”再拼一把&lt;/h4>;&lt;p>;明显的“转折点”发生在暑假结束之后，八大局街上“一眼就能望到头了”，红火了半年的淄博烧烤热度降了下来。 &quot;It was still very busy in July and August, but after September, it subsided a bit quickly.&quot; Standing at the fork in the traffic flow, whether to advance or retreat, the owner of a barbecue restaurant in Zhangdian District, Zibo City was a little undecided. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;单老板的店上过纪录片《人生一串》，叠加“进淄赶烤”的超级热度，生意着实火爆了很久。 “当时都有点崩溃了，人太多了，全店连轴转。”他对南方周末记者说，扩招了不少服务员，工资也从两千八涨到三千，再从三千涨到三千五，&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[病儿为何大额捐赠自家？儿慈会明星项目“冲配捐”调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257829]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/928a05c694.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/928a05c694.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251850&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;为唤起全民参与公益的热情，99公益日的组织者们引入了配捐。（视觉中国/图）&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;作为一家筹款能力超强的慈善组织，中华少年儿童慈善救助基金会（简称儿慈会）近期陷入配捐风波之中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年9月，柯某孝被指利用儿慈会“9958儿童紧急救助”项目（以下简称9958）骗取大病患儿家庭近千万救命钱，被警方拘押。儿慈会公开声明称，柯某孝并非其工作人员，仅在9958项目河北廊坊团队合作机构中当过志愿者。但争议尚未平息。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;多位受骗患儿家长讲述，他们参与了柯某孝发起的“配捐”，将资金打给柯某孝，预期在一段时间后获得高于本金的回款，高出部分为企业配捐。因为这种“配捐”在公益界是一种常态化的操作模式，大病患儿家庭习以为常，所以没有对柯某孝发起项目的真实性产生怀疑。（详见南方周末报道《&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/256685?source=131&quot;>;中华儿慈会志愿者疑卷走近千万救助款，大病家庭再陷配捐骗局&lt;/a>;》）&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;然而，患儿家长们习以为常的“配捐”，是不是处于灰色地带的套捐？根据相关法律政策，慈善组织诱导患儿家长自筹款项参与配捐、自捐自用，属于违规行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;如此“配捐”，儿慈会是否知情？南方周末记者发现，慈善组织管理与运作的缺陷，为配捐异化提供了温床。筹款越多，配捐越多——在一致的目标下，最需要用钱的人们掏出兜里的钱，垫高了慈善组织的筹款数字。&lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;“钱拿不回谁敢做”&lt;/h4>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;又到了每年9月的99公益日，广西人李山（化名）想为罹患白血病的女儿多筹点救命钱。他决定参与“配捐”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;99公益日是由互联网公司联合数百家公益机构、企业、名人共同发起的全民公益活动，2015年9月9日是中国首个互联网公益日。为唤起全民参与公益的热情，组织者们引入了一种国外流行的玩法——配捐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;配捐即配比捐赠，当一个捐赠者向公益机构捐赠一笔钱之后，另一个捐赠者（通常是企业）会随机或按照一定比例向同一个公益机构再捐赠一笔钱。配捐模式的初衷是鼓励公众参与捐赠，按照其本意，包括企业配比在内的捐赠额不应用于捐赠者本人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;慈善法也明确规定，捐赠人与慈善组织约定捐赠财产的用途和受益人时，不得指定捐赠人的利害关系人作为受益人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但李山没听说过上述规定。2023年99公益日前夕，李山在儿慈会发起的“向阳花守护西部儿童”“困境女童保障计划”“援助困境儿童上学梦”三个公益配捐项目里，各开设了一个“一起捐”筹款链接，并以自己身患白血病女儿的名字给链接命名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“一起捐”是腾讯公益平台推出的一种公益玩法。用户在公益项目主页点击对应按钮，填写目标金额和发起人信息，便可生成链接。捐赠人打开链接，输入金额即可进行捐赠。随后，这条捐赠信息和对应的配捐会记录在发起人的“一起捐”里，可公开查询。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据项目公开的信息和执行计划，“向阳花守护西部儿童”的受助者为18岁以下西部省份的困境儿童，“困境女童保障计划”将长期帮扶全国范围内的困境女童，“援助困境儿童上学梦”的目标则是让困境儿童安心上学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“我这还真不懂。”2023年9月17日，李山听南方周末记者介绍上述三个项目后说，他既不清楚这些项目的援助对象，也不了解自己的行为算不算捐赠。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但此前，9月7日至9日三天时间里，李山通过“一起捐”给这三个项目筹到超过21万元，其中不乏数笔金额3000元、4000元的“捐赠”。按规则，腾讯为此配捐超过2.2万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;李山向南方周末记者解释，这些“捐赠”都是他自己的钱。“往里&#39;捐钱&#39;的是一些亲戚朋友，我先把这个钱给他们，再让他们捐到项目里。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;李山坦言，对于“捐”的这二十多万元，他并没有用于援助西部儿童或困境女童的意思，“我们本身都缺钱”。他相信，“捐”出去的和企业配捐的钱，最终都会回到他手里，“（钱）拿不回那谁敢做啊”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者发现，在9月7日-9日三天时间里，一共有1.2万人次以“一起捐”的形式参与了上述三个项目，他们总共“捐”了886万余元，平均每条“一起捐”筹得4.59万元，单笔最大的“捐赠”为1万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9658c1749b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9658c1749b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251851&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;一位大病患儿家长为“援助困境儿童上学梦”项目发起的“一起捐”链接。（网络截图/图）&lt;/p>;&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;自筹、自捐、自用&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;通过“配捐”，“捐”出去的钱可以“连本带利”拿回来，李山形成这样的认知始于2022年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当时他正带着女儿在东莞住院。为了给还没上小学的女儿寻医治病，他自称两年里花费至少70万元。他记得那天，身边的病友拿出两千元，让他替自己“捐”进已经开好的链接，同时答题助&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[病儿为何大额捐赠自家？儿慈会明星项目“冲配捐”调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257801]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电竞加入亚运会，意味着什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257864]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;那些幸运抽中9月26日王者荣耀亚运会决赛门票的观众，正在向杭州电竞中心涌来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电竞项目，是亚运会唯一一项需要以抽签购票的竞技项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比赛开始前一个小时，电竞中心门口的等候者们开始入场。两位年轻的coser（角色扮演爱好者）尽管未抽中门票，仍然决定留在电竞中心门口，通过观看电视转播度过难忘之夜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/oupRK0i3RNd0s4DHvrfOBnDXXiOnYwvQj7Qvj2sZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/oupRK0i3RNd0s4DHvrfOBnDXXiOnYwvQj7Qvj2sZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月26日，杭州电竞中心举行的王者荣耀亚运会决赛现场。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（南方周末记者张锐/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月25日，杭州亚运会电子竞技项目王者荣耀亚运版半决赛，央视体育和CCTV5+频道对比赛进行转播，这是央视首次转播亚运会电子竞技项目比赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;coser亦枫同时是一名同人画手，她选择这份工作就源自对电竞的兴趣。“自从（电竞）入亚，我就开始一直解释（电竞）。”亦枫对南方周末记者说，三天前，她和父亲一起观看了亚运会开幕式，当电竞选手入场，她还兴奋地指给父亲看。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王者荣耀的比赛由红、蓝两队参与，每队5人，两队在王者峡谷地图展开团队合作和竞技对抗。coser陆知安聊起，在她身边，包括参加青训的男性朋友，对女性玩家的竞技实力存在偏见，这令她产生了“证明”自己的想法。通过观看职业选手的电竞赛事，她学到一些比赛战略和技术，由此提升了段位。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位80后男性观众2006年因为《DOTA》开始关注电竞赛事，《DOTA2》是杭州亚运会电竞项目之一。他也是足球迷，向南方周末记者谈起两者相似的团队性和竞技性，尤其是在比赛决胜时刻绝地翻盘带来的悸动。进场时，他对比赛结果充满信心。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月26日晚，杭州亚运会电子竞技王者荣耀亚运版本决赛，中国队2比0战胜马来西亚队，拿到亚运会历史上首枚电子竞技项目金牌，并计入中国奖牌榜。本次参赛的31位中国选手，平均年龄24岁左右，累计比赛场次超过11000场，已经拿过六十多项各类赛事的冠军奖杯。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这几乎是一场没有悬念的比赛。现场的欢呼声在中国选手出场时达到顶峰，他们来自比对手更职业化的联赛和俱乐部。加油的声浪伴随着比赛中的每一次“进攻”。决赛第二局，中国队甚至更换选手，并且更加干净迅速地推平了对面的“基地”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/Wn5XEdjfBQOfaV0ZIS9ZBKA5CRLQ7yBofH6lKUdb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/Wn5XEdjfBQOfaV0ZIS9ZBKA5CRLQ7yBofH6lKUdb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252655&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月26日晚，杭州，中国队队员赢得亚运会首枚电子竞技项目金牌后，登台向观众致意。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是亚运会电竞的第一个决赛夜，分出胜负之际，杭州电竞中心场馆内的热情似乎还没来得及充分释放。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;数字时代的体育运动&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;电子竞技有至少四十年历史。1980年，美国纽约举办的“国际&#39;太空侵略者&#39;”大赛，被认为是世界上第一个正规的电子竞技比赛，当时的冠军得主后来成为一名电子游戏程序员。千禧年后WCG（世界电子竞技大赛）的开办，使得Esports，或者说“电子竞技”，开始成为国际化赛事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州体育学院休闲体育与管理学院院长、博士生导师王晓东告诉南方周末记者，原始社会，人们已经发明跑步、游泳等体育活动；农业社会，人们有了骑马、弓箭等活动；工业社会，人们开始骑自行车、赛车等；“数字时代一定会以数字作为工具，出现新的体育运动”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年2月16日，在广州图书馆举行的“亚运TALK·广州站”活动中，杭州亚组委宣传部部长、杭州市委宣传部副部长许德清曾回应南方周末记者关于电竞的问题。许德清认为电竞是一种年轻、团队、创新的文化，“电竞和游戏是不同的，电竞被定义为智力的较量，和象棋、围棋一样是智力的比赛”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在杭州亚运会的四十个竞赛项目中，与桥牌、国际象棋、围棋和象棋一起，电子竞技被归为“智力项目”。“世界脑力竞技联盟”曾将“脑力竞技”定义为“一种体育或游戏，关联着参与者的心智能力，而非他们的身体优势”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京大学体育教研部副教授、硕士生导师亓昕回忆起二十年前的一幕。2003年，国家体育总局将“电子竞技”列为我国第99个正式体育项目。当时，电竞还是新鲜事物，她和学生们在课堂上去探讨“电竞到底是不是体育”。反对者占了绝大多数，实际上，不只是电竞，包括棋类项目，这些项目缺乏身体的运动，在当时也不太能被接受为“体育”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最近十年，亓昕明显感觉到外界对体育和电竞的认知发生了比较大的变化。北京大学有学生组织的电竞协会，参与的学生越来越多。据亓昕观察，这些学生的个人能力均得到发展，如思维能力、反应能力、大局观、意志力以及团队精神等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;几年前，她在一次活动中认识了一位前电竞职业选手，听选手聊起比赛和训练，对电竞的印象逐渐改观。“除了天赋之外，还要进行后天的艰苦训练。”亓昕说，当选手在比赛的那一刻，与传统体育运动员是一样的，眼前别无他物，只有赛事，哪怕遇到身体、精神上的困境，那一刻也会全力争胜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人们逐渐意识到，竞技性也是电子竞技的核心内容。”亓昕对南方周末记者列举，“一场比赛中，身体和心理哪些会提升，会有哪些负面的东西出现？如何在电竞比赛中激发团队热情、创造力，培养不服输、不气馁、顽强拼搏的体育精神？这些都是重要的研究课题。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亓昕认为，如果电竞选手能够像其他体育领域知名运动员那样取得一定社会知名度和认可度，他们未来甚至也可以参与高校教学工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不同于国内传统体育项目，电竞项目赛事一直由游戏厂商、电竞俱乐部等自下而上推动：电竞游戏出现，俱乐部入场，直播平台兴起，赛事逐步完善，最终走入亚运。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当初电竞入亚的消息传来，王国基感觉“有点儿突然，但并不意外”。王国基是中国文化管理协会电子竞技工作委员会会长，他解释，尽管电子竞技从网络游戏发展而来，但与游戏有较大差别：“网络游戏和电子竞技、爱好和职业化，要清醒地有所认识，而且要明确区分开来。不是说今天杭州举办亚运会，7个电竞项目成了正式比赛项目，就把网络游戏全面背书了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“我们在做一件严肃的事情”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;行业人士认为，此次电竞入亚，将把电竞行业带入更为规范化的方向。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亓昕告诉南方周末记者，“打电竞”和“打游戏”的区别，在于“体育规则”。电竞需要遵守严格的体育规范，这些规范被亓昕称为“边缘和界限”，用来保证电竞的有序和可控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;参与亚运会电竞项目的工作人员孙竞介绍，电竞项目正在逐渐变得“严肃”，比赛形式和规则构建均向传统、正规体育项目靠拢，“这对于很多厂商的赛事团队来讲，是很大的挑战”。为了适应亚运会的赛事规则，一些电竞项目赛程发生转变。比如，原来决定胜利的五场比赛缩减为三场。至少提前三个月，电竞选手就要开始封闭性训练并执行饮食计划，以确保通过兴奋剂检查。而这些在联赛中还是难以想象的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;规则确实更细致了。孙竞介绍，2006年，电竞管理规则一共约五千字；到了现在，最新的一版规则，已有大约12万字。“比赛的流程、各种犯规的情况、各个项目的细则都拆得很细了，”他对南方周末记者说，“距离足球篮球规则还有很远的距离，但是和一些传统项目的规则已经比较接近了。”比如比赛时间开始的确认，“规则里写比赛开始5分钟之内，如果触发了不可修复的bug要重赛”，行业内就此讨论了很长时间，才确定从哪一刻算“比赛开始”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相较一些传统体育项目对运动员年龄的宽松要求，比如本届亚运会，13岁小将崔宸曦夺得滑板女子街式决赛冠军，行业对电竞运动员的年龄要求更高。例如，浙江省电竞协会要求，要满足注册电子竞技运动员条件，必须年满18周岁、完成九年义务教育并获得全日制初中及以上毕业证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者探访杭州LGD电竞俱乐部，俱乐部经理马赛介绍，他们不会考虑未成年人成为选手。电竞选手的职业年龄在18岁-25岁，这意味着成为职业选手的机会稍纵即逝。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;俱乐部专业测试往往会劝退许多怀有电竞想法的年轻人。该测试通过电脑端和器械端，考验人的反应、瞬时记忆和手眼脑协调等能力。多轮测试中，悉数通过的只有六人，但是进入青训队伍后，依然难关重重。从青训到二队的淘汰率为67%，二队到一队淘汰50%。一些青训选手半年内无法证明自己可以参与更高级别的赛事，就会离开俱乐部另寻去处。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;LGD电竞俱乐部CEO潘婕介绍，人才选拔有非常详细的评估体系，不仅仅考察线上的实操表现，还有线下面试，评估其现实的心理状况等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙竞告诉南方周末记者，一些电竞项目与传统体育如出一辙。比如FPS（第一人称射击）游戏，他注意到，选手需要完成一定量的传统体育锻炼，训练肌肉反应速度，其中还引入了“热身”的概念。一些高强度比赛从早打到晚，如果没有这方面基础，很容易出现体力不支的情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;应舜洁是上海市电竞教育培训工委会副主任，从事电竞教育多年。他告诉南方周末记者，电竞行业一直关注传统体育行业，包括赛训体系、管理都在向传统体育学习，“关注选手的心理健康、伤病管理、作息日常、身体机能等，这些都是传统电竞没有的东西”。他提到，过去“网吧式”的模式显然是不健康的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;潘婕说，电竞比赛能够得到大的发展正是借鉴NBA等成熟体育联赛的赛事规则、转会规则、工资帽等。但是在借鉴过程中，传统体育规则总有“水土不服”的情况，尤其是服务于线下的规则如何适应线上，“最开始所有的规则都是纯竞技的，后期包括一些商业条款的规则也逐渐纳入俱乐部体系之内”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们为什么要有这么多人组织，有媒体运行中心、运动员村、媒体村、场地的竞赛团队、裁判团队，因为我们在做一件严肃的事情。”孙竞说。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;高强度身体运动，电竞的未来？&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年9月6日，国际奥委会宣布成立国际奥委会电子竞技委员会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我们相信虚拟体育有助于推广卓越、友谊和尊重等奥林匹克运动核心价值观，”国际奥委会主席巴赫表示，“它们可以激发全球年轻人参与体育活动，拥有积极健康的生活方式。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;值得一提的是，巴赫将电竞分为三类：第一类是虚拟现实体育运动，其中有身体运动，参与者的身体面临（高强度）运动和挑战；第二类涉及按照国际单项体育联合会规则进行的电子竞技比赛；第三类则是更广泛的电子竞技。国际奥委会优先考虑的是第一类入奥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;广州体育学院是中国最早开办电竞专业的公办本科高校。王晓东认为，电子竞技分为有身体运动的竞技和非身体运动的竞技，虚拟体育指的是前者。他以模拟赛车举例，使用赛车模拟器的运动强度跟实际赛车并无太大区别。他们曾经举办关于模拟赛车的比赛，参加比赛的孩子个个“精气十足”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王晓东提倡巴赫所说的虚拟体育，他向南方周末记者介绍，学校的电竞课程首先要学体育，并且生源也是传统的体育生。他同时提到这些项目的困难度，目前来看，虚拟体育的市场竞争接受度不算太高，青少年基础相对较弱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相对于虚拟体育，《FIFA Online4》《王者荣耀》《英雄联盟》等非身体运动的电子竞技赛事，显然在市场上有更高的接受度。杭州亚运会的电竞项目，实际上容纳了两个方向，其中既有前者这样的虚拟体育项目，也有后者这样的热门电竞项目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者了解到，目前国内俱乐部的投入仍然在后者，而非传统的虚拟体育项目。潘婕分析，一个俱乐部的投入项目需要考虑用户基数、市场情况、联赛体系、赛事的观赏性等，目前来看，虚拟体育的发展相对受限。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王国基2023年6月参加了在新加坡举办的奥林匹克电竞周，他有一个很深的感受。在新加坡举办的比赛里，其中9项是虚拟体育项目，例如需要肢体参与的射击、跆拳道、舞蹈游戏等。“电子设备不断进步以后，人类在现有环境下，电子竞技，特别是虚拟体育成为一种新的运动形式，这个是非常积极健康的，也是未来有很广阔的发展前景的。”王国基认为，人类进入数字时代，会有一些新的运动形式诞生，而且可能远远超过传统的体育运动形式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长期以来，人们认为非身体运动的竞技存在一些问题，比如缺乏锻炼的久坐不符合健康精神，同时带来的沉迷隐患也加剧了外界的担忧。不同于传统体育项目，电竞项目很可能受到游戏版权商的影响，这也增加了人们对公平性的怀疑。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;亓昕告诉南方周末记者，如果电竞未来只是在原来游戏的基础上去做一个休闲娱乐活动的话，走向会很受限制：“如果未来我们的电竞还只是一种智力的挑战，我觉得可能会越走越窄。电竞未来选择的方向，是向体育方面发展，而不仅仅基于游戏。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;产业的尽头是文化&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在十八年的相关从业经历中，潘婕认为，电竞行业的发展始终是一个“循序渐进”的过程。其繁荣离不开庞大的用户基础，尤其是年轻人的热情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与过去的“正名”不同，电竞职业化后，“劝退”反而成了重要的事情。“很多孩子是拿电竞当打游戏的借口，实际上他们既缺乏天赋，又不够努力”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年，电子竞技入选雅加达亚运会表演赛，中国代表队取得了两金一银的成绩。2019年4月1日，人力资源和社会保障部、市场监管总局、统计局正式向社会发布了13个新职业信息，其中与电竞行业相关的新职业有电子竞技运营师、电子竞技员两项。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时候，应舜洁能感受到2018年雅加达亚运会和一系列国际赛事对电竞行业带来的改变。2018年上半年招聘从业人员，“大多数过来的人都不知道电竞是干什么的，水平也参差不齐”。应舜洁询问他们关于电竞的认识，得到的答案往往就是与游戏挂钩。下半年开始，应舜洁收到了更多的简历，包括一些传统体育从业者也开始加入。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;应舜洁说，电竞人才缺口巨大，“要求从业者既了解电竞的行业规则，又具备良好的职业技能素养，这在2018年之前是很困难的一件事”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雅加达亚运会四年后，《2022年中国电子竞技产业报告》显示，2022年中国电竞产业收入1445.03亿元，电竞人口规模约4.88亿，全年举办电竞赛事108项。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;杭州亚组委执行秘书长、杭州市副市长陈卫强在接受媒体专访时坦言，电竞“入亚”更加长远的考量在于产业——通过电竞“入亚”，带动杭州及整个中国电竞产业的发展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“从游戏的策划、开发到运动员的训练、赛事的组织，还有直转播解说评论，以及大数据的统计，整个电竞产业链非常长，内容非常多。”王国基对南方周末记者说，除了标准化、职业化、国际化，产业化也是非常重要的。受国家人社部委托，电竞委员会制定了电子竞技员国家职业技能标准，编写的相关教材也即将出版。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;潘婕所在的俱乐部曾与法甲足球俱乐部巴黎圣日尔曼合作，她对南方周末记者说，当她来到圣日尔曼主场，发现人们不一定去看足球赛事，但是一定会去俱乐部周边参观，这几乎成为一种城市文化，这给了她很大触动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中央电视台体育频道2004年的一档电视栏目《电子竞技世界》中，有一期，栏目组编了一个情景剧。剧中，主持人前往葡萄牙报道欧洲杯，临行前做了一个奇怪的梦：一些FIFA足球和实况足球的游戏玩家，竟然成了欧洲杯16个国家队的主教练……&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是一个来自二十年前的“预言”。2023年杭州亚运会，包括《FIFA Online 4》在内的八个电竞项目已经是亚运会正式竞赛项目，9月24日至10月2日,杭州亚运会电竞比赛共将产生7枚金牌。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（亦枫、陆知安、孙竞为化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[实力悬殊，亚运中国女篮101比46大比分胜蒙古国队]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257842]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 27, 2023, Pan Zhenqi broke through the opponent&#39;s blockade, and the Chinese women&#39;s basketball players met He has an obvious height advantage over the Mongolian national team.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/f03d1994fe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/f03d1994fe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252644&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, Pan Zhenqi broke through the opponent&#39;s blockade. The Chinese women&#39;s basketball players have a clear height advantage over the Mongolian national team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hangzhou Asian Games women’s basketball competition will kick off on September 27, 2023. The previous champion Chinese women’s basketball team will make its debut at the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Gymnasium. In the Group A preliminaries, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team easily defeated the Mongolian team 101-46, getting a &quot;good start&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 27, 2023, after the game, the Chinese women&#39;s basketball team and the Mongolian women&#39;s basketball team high-fived.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/28/b3cb9ee133.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /28/b3cb9ee133.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252645&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, after the game, the Chinese women’s basketball team High five with the Mongolian women&#39;s basketball team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facing the Mongolian women&#39;s basketball team, which was at a disadvantage in terms of overall height, the Chinese team took the initiative from the very beginning, with Han Xu succeeding under the basket many times to establish a lead. Throughout the game, the Chinese team firmly held the initiative, with 24 more rebounds than its opponents and 32 more assists than its opponents. In the end, it defeated its opponents with an absolute advantage of 55 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 27, 2023, Han Xu was making a layup. Han Xu scored 15 points and 5 rebounds in this game.&quot; src=&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/43ca91481b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/43ca91481b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252646&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; On September 27, 2023, Han Xu was making a layup. Han Xu scored 15 points and 5 rebounds in this game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 27, 2023, Li Meng was passing the ball. Li Meng scored 10 points in this game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/28/a1f210bc4a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/28/a1f210bc4a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252647&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, Li Meng passed the ball . Li Meng scored 10 points in this game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 27, 2023, Li Yueru was making a layup. Li Yueru scored 18 points and 10 rebounds in this game.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/28/011fdfd233.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/28/011fdfd233.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252648&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, Li Yueru was making a layup. Li Yueru scored 18 points and 10 rebounds in this game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chinese women’s basketball team’s 12-member roster for the Hangzhou Asian Games is: Li Yuan, Jin Weina, Yang Liwei, Wang Siyu, Li Meng, Zhang Ru, Pan Zhenqi, Luo Xinqi, Li Yueru, Huang Sijing, Tang Yu, Han Xu. After defeating their opponents in the first game, the women&#39;s basketball girls did not talk too much about their goal of winning the championship, but unanimously stated that they must start from every game. Coach Zheng Wei said that he hopes to adjust the players&#39; status and improve overall coordination through the group stage: &quot;It takes a process for players to recover and adapt, but the progress is relatively fast. The three games in the group stage are very valuable to us.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 27, 2023, Zhang Ru interacted with the audience.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/ 4bcd204b91.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/4bcd204b91.jpg&quot; data- key=&quot;252649&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, Zhang Ru interacted with the audience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 27, 2023, the audience showed off conspicuous basketball shirts.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /28/0ccaa880ef.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/0ccaa880ef.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;252650&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, the audience displayed eye-catching basketball shirts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 12 participating women’s basketball teams in the Hangzhou Asian Games are divided into three groups. The Chinese women’s basketball team is in Group A with the Mongolian, Indonesian and Indian women’s basketball teams. The top two teams in each group and the two best third-placed teams will advance to the knockout stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 27, 2023, at the competition site, an audience member dressed in classical Chinese makeup.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/28/ff7b485bc5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 28/ff7b485bc5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252651&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 27, 2023, at the competition site, a dresser Audience with Chinese classical makeup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 29, the Chinese women’s basketball team will face the Indonesian team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[紫光集团原董事长赵伟国贪污、为亲友非法牟利、背信损害上市公司利益案一审开庭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257862]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 17:12:46&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 28, 2023, the Jilin Intermediate People’s Court of Jilin Province held a public hearing of the first instance against the former chairman of Ziguang Group Zhao Weiguo’s case of corruption, illegal profit-making for relatives and friends, and breach of trust to harm the interests of listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/b648e7213f78650dfba6a2a151229b7e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;5456&quot; height= &quot;3637&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/b648e7213f78650dfba6a2a151229b7e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252692&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Jilin City People&#39;s Procuratorate charged: From 2018 to 2021, the defendant Zhao Weiguo took advantage of his position as chairman of Ziguang Group to conspire with Li Luyuan, a person with a specific relationship, by The company actually controlled by Li Luyuan purchased the Tongzhou Business Park project property that was originally supposed to be purchased by Ziguang Group at a low price, obtained real estate premium benefits, and illegally occupied more than 470 million yuan in state-owned assets. From 2014 to 2021, Zhao Weiguo took advantage of his position as chairman of Ziguang Group to hand over the profit-making business of his unit to Li Luyuan and other specific related parties for management, or to purchase agency management from companies managed by Li Luyuan at prices significantly higher than the market price. services, causing direct economic losses to the country of more than 890 million yuan. In 2019, Zhao Weiguo also instructed directors of the listed companies he actually controlled to lease company projects to companies actually operated by Li Luyuan at prices significantly lower than the market price, causing the listed company to suffer a loss of more than 46.45 million yuan. The procuratorate requested that Zhao Weiguo be held criminally responsible for corruption, illegal profit-making for relatives and friends, and breach of trust and harming the interests of listed companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/f4e45066f58e5ff6bc00985e21a47f96.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;4602&quot; height= &quot;3068&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/f4e45066f58e5ff6bc00985e21a47f96.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252693&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the trial, the procuratorate presented relevant evidence, and the defendant Zhao Weiguo and his defender conducted cross-examination. Both the prosecution and the defense fully expressed their opinions under the auspices of the court. Zhao Weiguo conducted He made his final statement and expressed his guilt and repentance in court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the trial, the court adjourned and announced the verdict at a later date. More than 20 people representing people from all walks of life attended the trial. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>