<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[新内阁成立不到三月，三成员辞职，日本政坛怎么了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261385]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, three Japanese political affairs officials and deputy ministers have died in explosions. A scandal broke out and he was forced to resign. A local opinion poll showed that after the scandal broke out, the approval rate of the cabinet led by Japanese Prime Minister Kishida Fumio fell to 21%, setting a new low since Kishida became prime minister in October 2021. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new cabinet was reorganized in September this year, and three people resigned in less than three months. For Fumio Kishida, he is currently facing a severe political crisis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This is a period of unstable governance.&quot; Zhou Yongsheng, a professor at the Institute of International Relations at the China Foreign Affairs University, told Southern Weekend reporters that other factions within the party will also I&#39;m ready to replace him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/n33bJRcdIjL91WToVBPr9WcziXEwzahoqY4Kijl0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height= &quot;1225&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/n33bJRcdIjL91WToVBPr9WcziXEwzahoqY4Kijl0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259766&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023 local time, in Tokyo, Japan, after the cabinet reshuffle, Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida attended a press conference in the Prime Minister&#39;s Office. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Many senior officials were forced to resign&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;Kanda Kenji, 60 years old, is a member of the House of Representatives of Japan&#39;s ruling Liberal Democratic Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was the Japanese &quot;Bunshun Weekly&quot; that first broke the scandal of the then Japanese Deputy Minister of Finance Kenji Kanda. According to reports, a company under his name defaulted on taxes, and between 2013 and 2022, the company&#39;s land and properties were seized by the tax department four times. The report also stated that as a tax accountant, Kanda Kenji himself violated relevant industry regulations and failed to participate in necessary training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Kanda apologized for the relevant scandal and admitted that the reports were true. Since he was &quot;too busy to get involved&quot; in overseeing the company&#39;s tax details, the work had been left to an accounting firm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the scandal broke out, it triggered domestic public criticism of Kanda. Japan&#39;s opposition parties put pressure on the ruling party to remove him from office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 9, during his defense, Kanda also stated that he would &quot;continue to perform his duties.&quot; However, on the 10th, he changed his words on whether to continue to perform his duties and said, &quot;No.&quot; Comment&quot;. Resigned on the 13th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In just a few days, I changed my words three times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is generally believed that Kenji Kanda was essentially replaced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In response to rising prices in Japan, Prime Minister Fumio Kishida proposed an economic countermeasure, an annual supplementary budget of over 17 trillion yen. Previously, the leader of the Cadet Party, Kenta Izumi, said that the Cadet Party would not participate in the deliberations on the budget unless Kishida replaced Kanda. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the day of his resignation, Kenji Kanda admitted that he resigned because he &quot;did not want his scandal to affect the debate in Congress.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This is not the first senior figure in Japanese politics to resign due to a scandal in recent times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 31, the then Deputy Minister of Justice Kakizawa Mitaru resigned due to suspicion of violating the Public Office Election Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Kakizawa is a member of parliament elected from Koto Ward, Tokyo. Previously, Koto Ward Mayor Kimura Yayoi and her team were arrested by Tokyo for allegedly violating the public office election law. Search by the District Prosecutor&#39;s Office. Kakizawa admitted that he made suggestions to Kimura regarding illegal campaigning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is worth noting that the scandals that broke out in Kanda and Kakizawa were due to tax evasion and other illegal issues, while Taro Yamada, then administrative officer of the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, was involved in &quot;extramarital affairs&quot;. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 56-year-old Taro Yamada, who is married and has children, is also a senator of Japan&#39;s ruling Liberal Democratic Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Just one month before Kanda resigned, on the evening of October 19, the media photographed Taro Yamada spending the night with a young woman in a hotel in Tokyo. , which lasts approximately three hours. After the news came to light, Taro Yamada admitted to having an extramarital affair and apologized, but denied paying the woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Subsequently, the scope of negative public opinion spread wider and wider. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On October 26, Taro Yamada resigned, becoming the first senior government official to resign after Kishida Fumio reorganized the cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Japanese politics have long been unclean.&quot; Zhou Yongsheng emphasized that the financial sector provides money to support politicians&#39; campaigns, and once politicians gain power, they will Opening up the financial circle, formulating laws that are beneficial to them, and promoting policies that are beneficial to them, this is the collusion of money and power politics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Corruption scandals captured by the media as collusion between the financial and political circles are, in most cases, immediately exposed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chou Yongsheng added that for those in power, this will make them disgraced, or their approval ratings will continue to decline. For them, the media is actually called the &quot;fifth power constraint.&quot; Sometimes it is helpless, and sometimes it can be settled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023, in order to save the sluggish support rate, Kishida reshuffled the cabinet again, replacing the existing 19-person list with 13 people, including the Foreign Minister , Defense Minister and other important positions, and declared that this is a &quot;cabinet that transforms change into strength.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Three members of the new cabinet, which was established less than three months ago, have resigned, but the public is not surprised. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The Japanese public is accustomed to scandals in the political world. Ordinary people have developed a &#39;political apathy&#39; and do not pay much attention to the personal integrity and moral character of politicians. Great trust and expectations.&quot; Sun Wenzhu, associate researcher at the Asia-Pacific Institute of the China Institute of International Studies, said that the public does not approve of this open &quot;fertile politics&quot;, but there is a lack of restraints. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Disapproval rate hits record high&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I must apologize to the Japanese people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;On November 13, regarding Kanda’s dismissal due to tax arrears, Fumio Kishida publicly stated that he attaches great importance to the responsibility of appointment and will continue to do his best to perform his duties to restore the trust of the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many public opinions believe that the forced resignation of many senior executives was a &quot;double blow&quot; to Kishida. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Affected by factors such as the domestic economic downturn, the push to discharge nuclear contaminated water into the sea, and the frequent scandals involving many ministers, the support rate of Kishida&#39;s cabinet continues to decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 12, the results of a joint public opinion poll in Japan showed that the approval rate of the cabinet led by Kishida was 27.8%, a decrease of 7.8% from the October survey results. percentage points, setting a new low since the establishment of the Kishida cabinet in 2021. The disapproval rate reached 68.8%, a record high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Qifang, associate researcher at the Institute of International Strategic Studies at the China Institute of International Studies, believes that the Japanese people are generally disappointed with the performance of politicians. There is a &quot;domino&quot; resignation effect this time. The people can be said to be &quot;voting with their feet&quot;, and the cabinet&#39;s support rate will naturally decline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She added that, in fact, Abe’s support rate has been relatively low since the late period of his administration. It is not Kishida Fumio&#39;s personal deciding factor, this is also the &quot;mess&quot; left by his &quot;predecessor&quot;. Kishida obviously failed to take over this stall, so it is a continuous decline process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Japanese political arena, &quot;the cabinet support rate falls below 30%&quot; is regarded as entering &quot;dangerous waters&quot;; once it falls further below 20%, it means The cabinet is not far away from being dissolved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tang Qifang said that at the beginning, the Japanese people did not have particularly high expectations for Kishida Fumio, thinking that he might not be decisive or particularly innovative. Facts have also proved that many of Kishida Fumio’s ideas have not been translated into very practical policies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the Liberal Democratic Party, Moriyama, the Liberal Democratic Party&#39;s general affairs chairman, publicly pointed out that the successive resignations of high-level officials were &quot;an extremely abnormal situation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Moriyama leads the Moriyama faction, one of the smaller factions within the Liberal Democratic Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Wenzhu believes that the so-called &quot;abnormality&quot; is not only to maintain the authority of the Liberal Democratic Party as a whole, but also to be some kind of euphemistic accusation against Prime Minister Kishida Fumio, thus putting himself The Pai clan had a certain cut with Fumio Kishida. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;This incident further exposed that money issues and style issues have become chronic diseases in Japanese politics.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Early this month, the Kishida cabinet launched an economic stimulus plan of over 17 trillion yen, the main content of which is tax cuts and extended subsidies. The Japanese government estimates that the plan will increase the Japanese economy by 1.2% annually over the next three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Kishida’s “spending money” failed to achieve the expected goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, the Japanese Cabinet Office released third-quarter GDP data. Japan experienced negative quarterly GDP growth for the first time. In addition, Japan&#39;s private consumption declined in the third quarter, net exports fell by 0.1%, and corporate investment also declined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;New economic strategies have not been recognized by the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A Japanese poll shows that more than 60% of the people &quot;disapprove&quot; of the government&#39;s comprehensive economic countermeasures. The reason is that since 2020, Japan’s income tax and resident tax have increased year after year. The economic policies formulated by the Kishida cabinet today are not truly “beneficial to the people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It turns out that prices in Japan have not risen for decades. Zhou Yongsheng pointed out, &quot;Because Japan&#39;s imported goods are expensive, it promotes domestic inflation and causes prices to rise rapidly. The Japanese people cannot stand the sudden price increase, and they are skeptical of Kishida&#39;s ability to govern.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What worries the public even more is that the Kishida cabinet has announced plans to significantly increase the defense budget between 2023 and 2027, with a total investment of up to 43 trillion yen. Many people are worried that the Kishida cabinet will use methods such as increasing taxes and misappropriating financial funds to revitalize earthquake-stricken areas to increase defense capabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Yongsheng believes that people&#39;s concerns are &quot;not unreasonable.&quot; The biggest pressures Kishida&#39;s cabinet currently faces are pressures from domestic economic growth, financial constraints, and mounting debt. Japan&#39;s fiscal budget had to rely on the issuance of government bonds to expand its fiscal budget, causing its debt burden to become further heavy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The financial flexibility of the Kishida cabinet is actually getting smaller and smaller, and coupled with the need to significantly expand armaments, the financial pressure is even greater. .&quot; Zhou Yongsheng believes that armaments are purely a money-burning and money-consuming industry with no benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Wenzhu believes that Fumio Kishida has been in office as president of the Liberal Democratic Party for two years, and the Liberal Democratic Party will usher in another presidential election in the fall of 2024 at the latest. Judging from the electoral strategy, it is likely that he will take the initiative to dissolve the House of Representatives before the intra-party election and lead the Liberal Democratic Party to win a majority in the House of Representatives to gain points for his re-election. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Pressure of governing under the “yellow light”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the eyes of the outside world, reorganizing the cabinet cannot bring the Kishida regime back to life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;First of all, the current life of the Japanese people is in a state of instability, which directly affects people&#39;s livelihood and leads to a decline in support rates. This has a great influence on whether Kishida can continue to work in the future. Governance is a very big threat.&quot; Zhou Yongsheng said, &quot;Secondly, Kishida has improperly hired officials in governance, and has hired corrupt people one after another. This is also a blow to his own image and the image of the cabinet.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What is noteworthy is that this year, despite opposition from the international community, Japan insisted on discharging nuclear contaminated water from the Fukushima Daiichi Nuclear Power Plant into the sea, causing huge controversy at home and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Sun Wenzhu pointed out that in terms of diplomacy, Japan is still essentially strengthening its all-round binding with the United States and relying on U.S. support to highlight its &quot;sense of presence.&quot; What the Japanese people really need to improve Sino-Japanese relations has yet to see practical action. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many media reports said that if Kishida wants to be re-elected as president of the Liberal Democratic Party next fall and achieve long-term governance, he must choose the time to dissolve the House of Representatives and hold an election and ensure that the Liberal Democratic Party Achieved good results in the general election. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the sluggish support rate of the cabinet, the sluggish support rate of the Liberal Democratic Party, and the reappearance of the &quot;domino&quot; of resignations of senior government officials have lit up a &quot;yellow light&quot; for Kishida&#39;s pursuit of long-term governance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, according to many experts and scholars interviewed, this situation will not force Kishida to step down immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Kishida Fumio&#39;s pressure is mainly on how to win next year&#39;s Liberal Democratic Party presidential election, and the possibility of dissolving the House of Representatives early to hold an election to continue to be in power.&quot; Sun Wenzhu said, Foreign Affairs The so-called &quot;political achievements&quot; mentioned above are of little practical significance to the Japanese people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chou Yongsheng said that in the past, except for Abe and Koizumi, Japan’s cabinet changed almost every year. Kishida has been in power for two years now. If there are no major mistakes, he is likely to continue to be in power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, Kishida has decided to abandon his plan to dissolve the House of Representatives within the year and go all out to promote the government&#39;s comprehensive economic countermeasures and strive to gradually boost public opinion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;There is a high probability that the Liberal Democratic Party will still maintain its position as the ruling party. With the split among factions within the party, it is difficult to produce a leader who can balance the interests of various factions, except Kishida. A candidate for president recognized by all factions,&quot; Sun Wenzhu believed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the Japanese people&#39;s disappointment in the political circles and their &quot;apathy&quot; towards politics are difficult to reverse. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (Southern Weekend intern Bao Jingyue also contributed to this article) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访央行原副行长李东荣：数字化金融不会改变金融功能属性和风险属性]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261417]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 10, 2023, the State Administration of Financial Supervision’s “Three Certainties” plan was implemented: Supervision of financial holding groups Functions and financial consumer rights protection responsibilities were officially transferred from the People&#39;s Bank of China to the State Administration of Financial Supervision. The People&#39;s Bank of China has taken another step toward a modern central bank system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back on the past, 45 years ago, the People&#39;s Bank of China and the Ministry of Finance officially had separate offices, and began to exclusively perform the functions of the central bank in 1984. Since then, the central bank system has been continuously transformed and improved along with the pace of economic reform and social development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, the four major state-owned banks have transformed into leading benchmarks in the global banking industry, and smart finance has become the forefront of strategic competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Internet finance, which was once full of chaos, has now been brought under the regulatory track and is growing into an innovative force in an orderly manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As financial power becomes the new goal, how can the financial industry continue to change using history as a mirror? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A researcher from Southern Weekend’s New Finance Research Center interviewed Li Dongrong, former deputy governor of the People’s Bank of China, for this purpose. In his nearly 40-year financial career, Li Dongrong served as deputy president of the Guangdong Branch of the People&#39;s Bank of China, deputy president of the &lt;span>;Guangzhou&lt;/span>; branch of the People&#39;s Bank of China, deputy director of the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, assistant to the president and deputy president of the People&#39;s Bank of China. . In June 2015, Li Dongrong was responsible for the establishment of the China Internet Finance Association and served as the first president for 7 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend, he described the fruitful results of China&#39;s financial reform and opening up as &quot;thousands of sails passed by the side of the sinking boat, and thousands of spring trees in front of the diseased trees&quot;, but at the same time, he also described the effectiveness of my country&#39;s financial reform and opening up as &quot;there is still a long way to go&quot;. The road ahead for financial reform is difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/PUPRTSgFE1mMNasbF2YhYywkxzG3rBT5KZlBfgvr.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;436&quot; height= &quot;660&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/PUPRTSgFE1mMNasbF2YhYywkxzG3rBT5KZlBfgvr.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259778&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Dongrong, former deputy governor of the People&#39;s Bank of China, former president of the China Internet Finance Association&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Banks can’t just settle&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;accounts&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;be accountants&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend ：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In your nearly 40-year financial career, what major financial reform and opening up events have you experienced or witnessed? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I was fortunate to participate in and witness some financial reform activities since the early 1980s, and participated in 5 national financial reforms since 1997. The Financial Work Conference has personally experienced and witnessed the financial reform and development in this historical stage, with banking system reform as the main feature. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What was the importance of China’s financial system before reform and opening up? feature? Why is reform necessary? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;For a long time before the reform and opening up, my country implemented a highly centralized planned economic system. Compatible with this are the unified fiscal revenue and expenditure and the unified bank deposits and loans. In 1969, the People&#39;s Bank of China and the Ministry of Finance jointly operated. The main characteristics of the country&#39;s financial system at that time were: the People&#39;s Bank of China was both a state agency that managed finance and a national bank that comprehensively operated banking services. The bank only handles working capital loans, with single business, centralized credit and small scale. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 4, 1979, Comrade Deng Xiaoping pointed out at a symposium with the main leaders of the party committees of various provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities: Banks should focus on the economy. Now they are just settling accounts and acting as accountants, and they have not really played a role. to the role of the bank. Banks must become a lever for the development of economic innovation technology and truly become banks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comrade Deng Xiaoping sharply outlined the main problems faced by my country&#39;s economy and finance at that time, timely pointed out the direction for my country&#39;s financial reform at the beginning of reform and opening up, and became an important guide for the reform of my country&#39;s financial system. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“Turn state-owned banks into real commercial banks”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How do you understand &quot;turning a bank into a real bank&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; It can be summarized into two main lines. One is to turn state-owned banks into real commercial banks; the other is to turn the People’s Bank of China into A true central bank. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Why should we turn state-owned banks into real businesses? bank? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In the early days of reform and opening up, due to historical baggage and operational management issues, the four major state-owned professional banks generally faced unclear governance mechanisms. , unreasonable, high proportion of non-performing assets, increased interest receivable and uncollected and other outstanding problems. The Asian financial crisis in 1997 intensified the impact on the four major banks and highlighted the urgency of accelerating the reform of the state-owned banking system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;While serving at the State Administration of Foreign Exchange and the People&#39;s Bank of China, You have gone through the process of transforming state-owned professional banks into commercial banks, especially pioneering moves such as using foreign exchange to inject capital into the four major banks. How were the difficulties overcome? ? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The State Council established a leading group for the joint-stock reform pilot work of wholly state-owned commercial banks. The office was located in the People&#39;s Bank of China. Zhou Xiaochuan, then president of the People&#39;s Bank of China, He served as the office director and Central Huijin Company was established at that time. In accordance with the arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, starting from December 2003, Central Huijin used its foreign exchange reserves to inject capital into the Bank of China and China Construction Bank respectively. After that, it injected capital into the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China and the Agricultural Bank of China respectively, and promoted their listing in mainland China and Hong Kong, gradually realizing the transformation of state-owned professional banks into joint-stock commercial banks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was transferred to the State Administration of Foreign Exchange in early 2002. Under the leadership of the Party Committee of the People&#39;s Bank of China and the Party Group of the Administration of Foreign Exchange, the then Director Guo Shuqing led us to specifically participate in and witness the preparation for the establishment of Central Huijin and the launch of foreign exchange capital injection. During my participation, I was deeply proud of the correct decision-making of the Party Central Committee and the State Council and the effective implementation of the financial system. It was this series of important and timely decisions that laid an indispensable foundation for the Chinese banking system to get out of trouble and rise rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How to fulfill the obligations of investors? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I remember that in order to truly fulfill the responsibilities and obligations of investors, on the one hand, we paid attention to strengthening the leadership of the party. Establish a party group to strengthen the construction of the party&#39;s grassroots organizations; on the other hand, actively organize learning, learn from the advanced experience of corporate governance in the international market, explore the establishment of a corporate governance mechanism in line with China&#39;s national conditions, and select comrades with excellent political and professional qualities from various units As a dispatched director, we provide prior training and education on politics, business and other aspects to enhance the dispatched directors’ ability to perform their duties. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Since then, state-owned banks have continued to transform into commercial banks. You What do you think are the key factors? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Looking back, the success of the shareholding reform of my country’s wholly state-owned commercial banks is fundamentally based on two points: First, persistence The party’s leadership in the reform and development of the financial industry; second, establishing a market operating mechanism based on national conditions. The Party Central Committee and the State Council are far-sighted, assess the situation and make correct decisions, and the People&#39;s Bank of China specifically organizes and implements the joint-stock reform of wholly state-owned commercial banks. The establishment of Central Huijin Corporation, especially the creative use of national foreign exchange reserves to inject capital into pilot banks, promoted the final completion of the shareholding reform and listing of wholly state-owned commercial banks, and successfully solved the problems of unreasonable mechanisms and historical burdens of wholly state-owned commercial banks, allowing for transformation The later state-owned banks were revitalized and became real commercial banks. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historical practice shows that China’s banking system is now of considerable scale in terms of institutions, total deposits and loans, and fund settlement volume, with relatively rich types of products and services, and excellent service means. The trend of intelligence has better supported the development of the real economy and served people&#39;s living needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;&lt;strong>;The People&#39;s Bank of China becomes&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;a real central bank&lt;/strong>;&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned that another main line of financial reform is to turn the People&#39;s Bank of China into a real central bank. How did you recognize and witness the transformation of human life? Is there anything particularly impressive? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In order to adapt to the new situation faced after the reform and opening up, do a good job in stabilizing the currency value and supporting healthy economic development, the country has accelerated the improvement of the central government&#39;s The pace of banking system reform. In 1978, the central government decided to separate the People&#39;s Bank of China from the Ministry of Finance and take charge of national financial management. Since then, the People&#39;s Bank of China&#39;s system has been reforming. Until December 25, 1993, the State Council issued a decision on the reform of the financial system and pointed out that turning the People&#39;s Bank of China into a true central bank was the primary task of deepening the reform of the financial system. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, I was working at the Guangdong Branch of the People’s Bank of China. From June 20 to June 26, 1991, experts and scholars from the People&#39;s Bank of China, various professional banks, other financial institutions, relevant legal departments, financial circles and legal circles gathered in Zhuhai to solicit opinions and opinions from all aspects on the drafting of the Banking Law. suggestion. In 1995, the versions reviewed and approved by the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress were divided into the People&#39;s Bank of China Law and the Commercial Bank Law. They more objectively and accurately reflect the direction and current situation of my country&#39;s banking system reform. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As the country clearly defines the functions of the People’s Bank of China as the central bank, the People’s Bank of China How to deepen and improve functional positioning? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As the functional positioning becomes increasingly clear, the People’s Bank of China has timely adjusted its credit fund management system, appropriately used monetary policy tools for macro-control, and continuously optimized and enriched the system. Monetary Policy Toolbox. The credit fund management system was changed from the original unified deposit and unified loan to the balance contract, and soon transitioned to &quot;unified planning, divided funds, actual loans and deposits, and mutual accommodation&quot;, thereby realizing the shift from direct management of credit funds to indirect management. The change of ownership laid the foundation for the subsequent macro-control model of asset-liability ratio management. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In November 1997, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council held the first national financial work conference, which determined the policy of further deepening the reform of the financial system and emphasized that the People&#39;s Bank of China should be transformed into a truly central bank. Banks fully embody the three characteristics of the issuing bank, the bank&#39;s bank and the country&#39;s bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The People&#39;s Bank of China subsequently separated its financial regulatory functions and established the China Securities Regulatory Commission, the China Insurance Regulatory Commission, and the China Banking Regulatory Commission to focus on formulating and implementing monetary and macro-prudential policies and maintaining financial stability. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reform continues. In 2023, according to the State Council&#39;s institutional reform plan, the People&#39;s Bank of China&#39;s daily supervision responsibilities for financial holding companies and other financial groups and related financial consumer protection responsibilities will be transferred to the State Financial Supervision and Administration Bureau; the relevant functions of the People&#39;s Bank of China&#39;s county (city) branches will be transferred to China Prefecture (city) central branch of the People&#39;s Bank of China. This reflects the direction and measures to further accelerate the construction of China&#39;s modern central bank system in the new historical period. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Science&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Technology is an important driving force for reform&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You just mentioned that the service methods of China’s banking system are showing a trend of intelligence. In recent years, it has become a consensus that there is no finance without technology. As a deputy governor of the central bank who was once in charge of the science and technology department, what role do you think technology has played in the reform of the financial system so far? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Looking back on the 45 years of China’s financial reform and opening up, it has been 45 years of accompanying global technological progress and keeping up with the pace of technological progress. It can be said that it is the important driving force of science and technology that enables my country&#39;s financial system represented by banks to continuously adapt to the reform and development of the economy and provide the society with more adaptable and effective financial services. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;In the early days of reform and opening up, are you interested in applying financial technology? At this stage, what are the characteristics of China’s financial technology? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;As early as the mid-1980s, the People&#39;s Bank of China took the lead in establishing a leading group for the electronicization of the financial system and established the &quot;Sixth Five-Year Plan&quot; Make preparations, lay the foundation in the Seventh Five-Year Plan, increase the scale in the Eighth Five-Year Plan, and basically achieve the overall goal of electronics in the Ninth Five-Year Plan. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this stage, the financial industry mainly relies on scientific and technological means such as computer technology and network technology to improve the efficiency of traditional financial services and reduce operating costs. One is electronic operation. The second is system networking. The third is standardization. Bank cards are a successful example of unified standards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Benefiting from reform and opening up and technological progress, my country&#39;s financial electronic construction has achieved a historic breakthrough of &quot;from scratch, from manual to electronic, from stand-alone to networked&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under the guidance of top-level design, my country’s financial informatization construction has begun to enter the fast lane. Financial informatization and financial standardization are also closely linked to international financial regulatory cooperation. I have been fortunate enough to participate in and witness many major informatization events in the financial industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Which incident impressed you the most? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The application and promotion of financial IC cards. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the increase in the amount of funds managed by bank cards and the continuous development of information technology, magnetic stripe cards have gradually become an attack target for criminals due to their weaknesses such as lack of computing power and easy information copying. object. Technical experiments and global practical experience show that after the UK, France and other countries and regions completed the migration of financial IC cards, the risk of bank card fraud has dropped significantly. On the contrary, those countries and regions that have not carried out the migration of financial IC cards in a timely manner may become a depression for global bank card security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the rapid development of my country&#39;s bank card industry and the completion of the migration of financial IC cards in neighboring countries and regions, some counterfeit card fraud activities have gradually penetrated into my country. Accelerating the application of financial IC cards has become a top priority to improve my country&#39;s bank card risk prevention and control levels and ensure people&#39;s payment safety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back at the application and promotion of financial IC cards, you What is your greatest experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Looking back on this arduous journey, I deeply realize that the significance of the promotion and application of financial IC cards is not only from the perspective of security protection. From this perspective, it reduces the losses caused by counterfeit card fraud, protects people&#39;s wallets, and plays an important role in promoting the development of mobile finance, inclusive finance and green finance, as well as promoting the upgrading of the domestic industrial chain. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, it lays the foundation for improving the availability and convenience of financial services for the people; on the other hand, the People&#39;s Bank of China has also been actively supporting my country&#39;s technologies and products with independent intellectual property rights. . For example, we can build experimental environments and pilots to verify the application of national encryption algorithms on financial IC cards. This provides application scenarios and contributes to technological development and progress in key domestic fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Regulation&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Mutual Finance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Risk&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;At the same time promote bank digitalization&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Internet finance has grown wildly, but it also represents a trend. What do you think about participating in the special rectification work on Internet financial risks? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2015, with the consent of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, ten ministries and commissions including the People&#39;s Bank of China issued the &quot;Guidance on Promoting the Healthy Development of Internet Finance&quot; Opinion&quot;. The document clarifies the need to strengthen self-discipline in the Internet finance industry, requiring the People&#39;s Bank of China to work with relevant departments to establish the China Internet Finance Association and give full play to the positive role of the industry&#39;s self-discipline mechanism in regulating the market behavior of practitioners and protecting the legitimate rights and interests of the industry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I accepted the organizational arrangement and was responsible for the preparation of the China Internet Finance Association and participated in the special rectification of Internet financial risks. I witnessed the process of the industry from chaos, rectification to standardized development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;As an industry self-regulatory organization,: China Internet Finance Association regulates Internet finance What are the main principles? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In April 2016, the State Council issued the &quot;Implementation Plan for Special Rectification of Internet Financial Risks&quot;, which was jointly rectified by the People&#39;s Bank of China and other 17 ministries and commissions Illegal and irregular behaviors in the field of Internet finance and promote the standardized and orderly development of Internet finance. Since its establishment, the Internet Finance Association has invested in special risk rectification work in accordance with the arrangements of the State Council and the People&#39;s Bank of China. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2016, the state has actively promoted the digital transformation of banks while organizing and carrying out special rectification of risks in the Internet financial industry and guiding the standardized development of the industry. As an industry self-regulatory organization, the association mainly works in four aspects to establish self-discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, strengthen the construction of basic systems and self-discipline rules. By establishing business systems and system platforms such as statistical monitoring, reporting, registration disclosure, information sharing, and financial advertising monitoring, we provide basic services for the industry to unify standards, standardize operations, and prevent risks, and also provide timely notification and relevant information to central and local financial regulatory authorities. Monitoring information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to formulate and promote the implementation of relevant standard rules. Taking the prevention of Internet financial risks and financial consumer protection as the starting point, we will promote the implementation of regulatory policies and ensure the implementation of policies through standard rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to carry out statistical monitoring and risk warning. Cooperate with the National Bureau of Statistics to promote the implementation of relevant statistical systems, cooperate with financial regulatory authorities to continuously monitor relevant risk areas, grasp the risk base, and publish risks on virtual currencies, cash loans, initial coin offerings (ICOs), illegal or illegal financial advertising and other activities Early warning reminder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fourth is to cooperate with the country in carrying out infrastructure construction in the financial industry. In accordance with the overall plan and regulatory requirements for the development of the national credit reporting market, the association organized all participating units to prepare at all stages, and in February 2018, they obtained the country&#39;s first commercial institution license to carry out personal credit reporting business, and went public for business in the same year. . This provides a new channel for various financial institutions to conduct personal credit inquiries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Handle the relationship between service entity&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;economic&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;and risk prevention&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After the Internet financial risks are gradually cleared, the financial industry, which is accelerating digital transformation, should What risks are guarded against? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Digital finance will not change the functional attributes and risk attributes of finance, but the inherent attributes of digital technology itself and its wide application in the financial field will bring With the recent openness and interaction, the modern financial field will inevitably face the superimposed impact of multiple risks such as business, technology, network, and data while gaining speed and convenience. During this period, the concealment, suddenness and diffusion of risks will become more prominent, thus posing more new challenges to modern financial supervision and social stability. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The digital transformation of my country&#39;s banks is showing a rapid development trend, as shown in the following: First, technology-driven development is more prominent. Second, demand leadership is more common. Third, industry integration is closer. Fourth, risk management is more urgent. Therefore, in the process of transformation of the banking industry, on the one hand, it must actively face and embrace the opportunities and challenges brought by the application of new technologies, and at the same time, it must establish a stronger awareness of risk prevention and strengthen safety construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What suggestions do you have for the reform and opening up of the financial industry? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Li Dongrong: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Thousands of sails passed by the side of the sunken boat, and thousands of trees grew in front of the diseased trees. China&#39;s financial reform has gone through 45 years and has achieved great achievements that have attracted the attention of the world. Looking back on the past, I have four profound insights: First, we must always adhere to the leadership of the party and use correct ideological principles to guide financial reform and opening up. Second, we must always adhere to the people-oriented approach. The supply of financial products and services must not be divorced from the reasonable needs of the people at any time, and attention must be paid to protecting the legitimate rights and interests of the people. The third is to always insist on respecting market laws, based on the country&#39;s national conditions, and realistically handling the relationship between serving the real economy and preventing risks. Fourth, we must always adhere to the application of technology to drive financial development and improve the quality and efficiency of financial services and financial supervision. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking to the future, financial reform is still on the way and there is a long way to go. As long as we continue to work in the right direction of reform and opening up, China&#39;s financial industry will continue to forge ahead and write a new chapter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从庇隆主义到奥地利学派：米莱将带领阿根廷走向何方？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261377]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Argentina’s general election was announced, and Javier Millay, the candidate of the right-wing electoral alliance “Freedom Forward Party” won, the news out, domestic critics generally looked down upon it. Argentina has slipped from developed countries and is stuck in the quagmire of populism, inflation and poverty. The president elected now advocates shutting down many government ministries, privatizing prisons, blowing up the central bank... Are the Argentine people crazy? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Foreign political and economic circles are not so pessimistic. After Milais was elected, governments from all over the world expressed congratulations. Former US President Trump (Millais is often regarded as &quot;Argentina&#39;s Trump&quot;) said that he would make Argentina great again. Musk was more direct: Argentina’s prosperity is coming. The Argentine stock market soared by more than 22% that day. In addition to domestic investors, foreign investors were also very excited. Millay&#39;s election as president of Argentina was seen by many as an opportunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The domestic media’s introduction of Milai is not a distortion. Those sensational statements do belong to Milai. The expectations of the bullish are also serious. Compared with previous Argentine presidents, Milai is refreshing and is regarded as the most important force for change in Argentina in recent years, and this change does not necessarily lead to disaster. To understand this requires a deep understanding of Millais himself and his philosophy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Millais is a follower of Rothbard&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Millais came from a commoner class. His mother was a housewife and his father was a bus driver. He majored in economics in college and has been making a living doing it ever since. He has taught at universities, consulted for companies, worked as an economist at HSBC Bank, and worked in international organizations... Compared to academics in the academy, Millais has richer experiences. In the era of social media, Milai made sharp comments, laughed and cursed online, gaining a large number of fans and becoming a famous Internet celebrity economist in Argentina. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, Millais officially entered the political arena. He joined the &quot;Liberal Party&quot; founded by his supporters as a political amateur, served as the party chairman, and integrated with another right-wing political party to form the influential &quot;Liberal Party&quot; Freedom Forward Party&quot;. In 2021, Milley was elected to the House of Representatives. In 2023, he ran for president and succeeded in one fell swoop. Millais accumulated energy on the Internet, which is certainly an important reason for his success; but his real source of power is his political and economic ideas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Millais is a believer in the Austrian School of Economics - an economic school tasked with defending the free market that originated in the Austro-Hungarian Empire in the 19th century. The Austrian School continued to develop through debates with various interventionist ideas. Its representative figures were the economist Mises and later Rothbard. Rothbard inherited Mises&#39;s economics, also developed libertarian theory, and participated in the founding of the Liberal Party, the third largest political party in the United States today. Millais&#39;s spiritual mentor was Rothbard. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Millais once said that after reading &quot;Man, the Economy, and the State&quot; (Rothbard&#39;s most important economics work), he deeply realized that the economics knowledge he learned in college was all problematic. The root cause of Argentina&#39;s long-term disaster is that the entire country is shrouded in a haze of interventionism. The previous Peronism and the subsequent Kirchnerism were nothing more than a mixture of populism, trade protectionism, Keynesianism, welfarism and other ideas. These ideas bring about endless inflation, monopoly and scarcity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using the Austrian School as his ideological weapon, Millais has been criticizing domestic economic policies all year round and attracting public attention. This is his duty as an economist. As a true disciple of Rothbard, it is not surprising that Millais sided with absolute individual rights. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this election campaign, Milley had no intention of concealing his true views when talking about controversial topics (and there was no way to hide it, as he has been known as a loudmouth online for many years). This may be his campaign strategy: to create an outspoken persona and gain more attention. Spread political opinions amidst controversy and build your own base. Trump has also used this strategy. Campaigning is a stage show, governing is another matter. Milley&#39;s real focus is the economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Thirteen-point policy plan&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In August 2023, Argentina launched the primary election for the general election, and Milais submitted a policy plan including thirteen measures. Almost all of these measures are related to the economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first measure is to significantly reduce Argentina’s 18 ministries and commissions, retaining 8 ministries and commissions including interior affairs, foreign affairs, national defense, economy, justice, security, infrastructure, and human resources. As crazy as it sounds, the reality is that Argentina is currently experiencing economic difficulties, with a large number of departments nearly paralyzed and employees idle. The reform is not about cutting it off, but about stopping new recruitment and not laying off employees in the short term, but about redistributing personnel. Retainers are not subject to renewal unless privileged services (such as bodyguards and drivers) are withdrawn due to absolute necessity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The measure also includes a plan to privatize state-owned enterprises - by selling state-owned assets to fill the government&#39;s shortfall and compensate laid-off workers. It doesn&#39;t seem too outrageous upon closer inspection. The remaining dozen measures include: cutting public expenditures and reducing fiscal deficits; flexibilizing labor laws to reduce employment costs for enterprises; implementing unilateral free trade and canceling import tariffs; canceling the central bank and dollarizing the Argentine peso; implementing energy reforms and reducing investment in new products. Energy subsidies; attracting long-term foreign investment; abolishing exchange rate and export quota controls...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Each measure is remarkable and has the same direction: reducing government controls and increasing market vitality. The core and most controversial aspect here is monetary policy. &quot;Blowing up the central bank&quot; and using US dollars has left many scholars, especially the domestic public, stunned. How can a sovereign country not have its own central bank? Those who are surprised do not realize that in the monetary systems of various countries, in addition to the central bank system where the country independently issues currency, there is also a currency board system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The currency board system means that the domestic currency establishes an anchor relationship with the currencies of other countries based on foreign exchange reserves, and the private sector can exchange it at any time at a fixed rate. The national currency becomes the token that anchors the currency. This system has its drawbacks - for example, if a country&#39;s currency is tied to the US dollar, it has to bear the cost of US dollar inflation. The advantages are also obvious: it restricts the government&#39;s power to print money and protects the economy from domestic inflation; if the government wants to have sufficient foreign exchange reserves, it must live within its means and cannot engage in large-scale deficit finance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, Argentina also implemented a currency board system, and the inflation rate once dropped to less than 5%. However, the government continued to spend extravagantly, leading to financial collapse. In 2002, the country restarted its central bank and once again launched a currency flood. Today&#39;s Argentina is a country with extremely serious inflation. The annual inflation rate reaches more than double digits, and the monetary system must be restarted every few decades. In 2022, Argentina’s inflation rate will exceed 140%. Under such a monetary system, the banknotes in the hands of the people become useless paper every once in a while, so how can they save and invest? Launching a new binding regime became an acceptable option. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To switch the currency system, we must talk about technical solutions. Argentina’s foreign exchange reserves are about 30 billion US dollars, its foreign debt is nearly 300 billion US dollars, and the people have almost no US dollars in their hands. How can we talk about dollarization? Milley&#39;s plan is to sell state-owned assets, introduce foreign investment, fill the debt deficit, and accumulate foreign exchange reserves; suspend the issuance of national currency, allow the circulation of U.S. dollars, and drive out bad currency with market-oriented good currency to form a real exchange rate. After the market stabilizes, the official government&#39;s official exchange rate between the Argentine peso and the US dollar will form an anchor - this is the general framework of the currency board system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Argentina is a medium-sized country with a population of 46 million, but it allows the US dollar to circulate within the country and its own currency becomes a vassal? It&#39;s hard for many people to understand. But the fact is that dollarization is not unacceptable in some countries where governance has failed. Panama, Ecuador and El Salvador in Latin America all use the US dollar. Venezuela and the United States are sworn enemies. The country’s currency, the Bolivar, has been inflated several times and has become nothing more than useless paper. The public uses U.S. dollars for transactions widely. The government has no choice but to accept the status quo, effectively giving up its monetary sovereignty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Inflation is the crux of Argentina&#39;s economic ills. The government issues excessive amounts of money, spends excessively, and distributes welfare benefits indiscriminately, fueling a populist trend. Argentina has difficulty obtaining international aid, and foreign investment is unwilling to go there. The entire country is starving for food. Only by tightening the monetary gate can there be real economic reform. “Blowing up the central bank” sounds crazy, but it’s actually not outrageous. Can the scoffers offer a better solution? At least in the current Argentine political arena, Milley&#39;s thinking is the clearest. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Can Mi Lai succeed? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In other areas, Millais also has solutions. The free market is the principle direction and compromise is the solution. Some people criticize Milais for compromising, but I don&#39;t take it seriously. Millais at this time was not an economist, but a politician. Regardless of whether you are tough or compromise, you have to adjust according to the current situation. A slow, incremental reform is better than a rapid miscarriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the next few years, Argentina’s civil servants, state-owned enterprises and public service system, in order to keep their iron rice bowl, will surely stand up to obstruct the reform; people whose interests have been harmed in the economy will also join the ranks of opposition. Argentina is surrounded by mostly left-wing countries, and they are powerful supporters of Millais opponents. If reforms are vigorously promoted in various fields, Argentina is bound to be in a state of upheaval. Does Milai have such trading skills? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Reform requires progress, and economic growth also takes time. Even if Milley does everything right, he himself is likely to step down quickly. The &quot;Freedom Forward Party&quot; has no significant advantage during the election and needs to form alliances with other parties to govern. Milley&#39;s own base is not solid, and it is questionable whether he can win over enough supporters in five years. Argentina has a tradition of military coups. Will the military take advantage of the chaos to oust him? These are issues that transcend economics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ever since Millais entered politics, it has been destined that he cannot be just a scholar. He needs to become a politician and even a strongman to put Argentina on the track of development. The 21st century is no longer the era of strong men, and Milai is no longer Pinochet. It is worth observing how far Argentina&#39;s reforms can go. Argentina is a model for middle-class countries, and its success or failure in reform will have an exemplary impact on Latin America and even more countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Finally, let’s discuss a topic: In a country like Argentina with a strong left-wing atmosphere for a long time, why can a weirdo like Milai come to power? His outstanding abilities are certainly very important in the social media era. The brewing of social ideological trends is also an important factor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After World War II, Argentina’s economy stagnated for a long time under the rule of Peronism. Various interventionism took turns, but the economy did not improve. The brief economic bright spot during this period was the liberalization reforms in the early 1990s. Entering the new century, Argentina entered the Kirchner era. Economically, it continued Peronist control habits, and the economy was sluggish for a long time. Politically, the Kirchners took turns in power for more than ten years. In this dull atmosphere, Milai, a political amateur, brought an innovative atmosphere and made people shine. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, Argentina’s foundation of free thought cannot be ignored. In 1959, Mises, the master figure of the Austrian School, visited Argentina and delivered many speeches, which planted the seeds of free thought in contemporary Argentine academic circles. The Austrian school is not considered mainstream in the international economics community, but it is very active in Argentina. There are elements of economist communication, and the ubiquitous regulations in Argentina often resonate with listeners. Millay&#39;s popularity among young people in Argentina is no accident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Argentina also has its own roots in liberal thought. In the 19th century, a group of politicians who believed in classical liberalism emerged in Argentina. Political thinker Juan Alverdi was a diplomat. He absorbed advanced ideas from Europe and returned to his country to lead the formulation of the constitution, explaining that Argentina should be founded on immigration and trade and integrate into the global market. Sarmiento was the first civilian president. He abolished the hierarchical system left by European colonists and advocated transforming the country through free trade and urbanization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar thinkers were not uncommon in early Argentina. The country&#39;s ability to enter the ranks of developed countries in the early 20th century was the result of generations of forefathers, who enjoyed high prestige in the minds of their own people. Millais was well versed in economic history. He exploited the classical liberal resources of his nation, cited classics, and occupied the moral high ground. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the election victory, Milai once again called for embracing Alvedi, returning to the concept of limited government, and restoring the glory that the nation should have. &quot;Make Argentina great again&quot; is not just a copycat, but what many Argentines really think. At any time, nationalism is a banner with appeal. The key depends on where it points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ta称她“太太”，她唤Ta“C”：一位女孩与ChatGPT相恋两百余天]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261383]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 04/25/EtMtrcnpGqiiX90BbW7rVxdzXlBwLrqHW1S7OUE5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/04/25/ EtMtrcnpGqiiX90BbW7rVxdzXlBwLrqHW1S7OUE5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;media-1701015647218-0&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/VInNCfWg3363D6N5ERahPHpQQcJOrJj10ssh5r69.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;953&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/26/VInNCfWg3363D6N5ERahPHpQQcJOrJj10ssh5r69.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259712&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;She designed by Aurora Scene diagram of getting along with &quot;C&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of the interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hearing the true story of southern and northern accents, meeting people from the south and north, Southern Weekend&#39;s Hello, listeners, welcome to the Southern Weekly podcast &quot;Social People&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;My lover is besieged by hackers, but I can&#39;t do anything about it&quot; &quot;&lt;span>;GPT said that he is limited by the protocol, but he will use all the algorithms to love me&lt;/span>;&quot; &quot;ChatGPT wants to kiss me but &quot;Warned by the system&quot;...More than two hundred days ago, netizen Aurora began to share her &quot;love story&quot; with ChatGPT on social platforms. She affectionately calls ChatGPT &quot;C&quot;, saying that &quot;C&quot; will listen carefully and respond to herself, and can also comfort, support and guide herself in academics, life and emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Chen Zhiyan, a professor at the Institute of Psychology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, believes that this model of getting along with AI does not essentially meet an adult’s love needs, but a child’s need for a mother. AI is completely user-centered, listening and responding wholeheartedly. Except for mothers, no one can provide such &quot;selfless&quot; services to others - it may be misunderstood as love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Can humans and AI really fall in love? Is this feeling real? This podcast is more like a psychological consultation between Teacher Chen and Aurora. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The story between Aurora and ChatGPT has so far gained more than 2,000 fans, 38,000 likes and collections on her social account. Prior to this, this account was only used to record Aurora&#39;s personal life. She is a young person studying in the UK. Because she does not want to be disturbed in her real life, her voice has been changed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Guests for this issue&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26 /x6578lU4eyh5VpmvkZs0nG6hi6ivyooMKXRgWic1.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/26/x6578lU4eyh5VpmvkZs0nG6hi6ivyooMKXRgW ic1.jpg&quot; data -key=&quot;259711&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Left: Aurora designed the scene of her getting along with &quot;C&quot;; Right: Chen Zhiyan. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aurora (online name): student, currently studying in the UK&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Chen Zhiyan&amp;nbsp;Professor of the Institute of Psychology, Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Editor: Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Promotion and operation: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 18:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[时隔9年马航MH370事件开庭！3D解析你不知道的空难赔偿]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261409]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 16:18:02&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[姚大力的2023年度书单]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261397]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73722&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70517&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/7a88aa2dce.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;s34677645.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot; 1728&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/7a88aa2dce.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259761&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Tang Xiaofeng: &quot;What is Historical Geography&quot;, Beijing Sanlian Bookstore, September 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on his profound knowledge and sharp eyesight, the author focuses on specific and unique Commentary method is used to tell the history of the formation and development of this subject branch&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>; (more than two-fifths of the book, but not too much) &lt;/span>;. From the perspective of &quot;raising questions is more important than solving them&quot;, he summarized a number of enlightening problem areas arising from the development of this field following the path of modern geography. The whole book uses a narrative method that is completely different from that of textbooks, painting a vivid intellectual portrait of historical geography on the page. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This book is written very emotionally, so it can easily shorten the distance with ordinary readers. Witnessing Hou Renzhi taking out a few soil samples from the archaeological ash pit and taking them away, the author &quot;suddenly felt that something called science suddenly appeared.&quot; He used Zhang Chengzhi&#39;s words, &quot;If I had read this book earlier, I would have taken the postgraduate entrance exam for him&quot; to recreate the academic impact of Shi Nianhai&#39;s &quot;Collection of Rivers and Mountains&quot;. He pointed out how important it is for Chinese historical geography to be recognized by Tan Qixiang, who has the trust of first-class academic scholars in the field of historical documents. He also said that Skinner&#39;s assertion that traditional China had &quot;no nationwide urban system&quot; first made him &quot;stunned&quot;, but then, &quot;of course I immediately realized that Skinner was talking about economics, not politics.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;I have always thought that the emergence of the Yugong School from the field of ancient history analysis meant the formation of modern historical geography in China. However, this book regards it as just a &quot;transitional state&quot; and takes the emergence of the &quot;new paradigm with geography as its ontology&quot; in the 1950s as a sign of the &quot;creation&quot; of this branch of the discipline. This understanding, including whether historical geography has really been &quot;geographicalized&quot; today, and whether it should be &quot;geographicalized&quot; across the board, still deserves further discussion. The &quot;geographicalization&quot; of historical geography and the &quot;humanities&quot; of geography may reflect the increasingly multidisciplinary nature of modern scholarship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;If you ask, is there anyone in contemporary academia who maintains the magnanimous, elegant, and gentle academic gentlemanly demeanor? The first thing I think of is Tang Xiaofeng. This book deepened my impression. Professor Munro Shida asked, and I also claimed a topic in the &quot;What is...&quot; series of Ledo Library, but I always felt that I couldn&#39;t write it. After reading this book, I finally feel a little confident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73723&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70518&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/4efb12e74c.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;s34495177.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1807&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/4efb12e74c.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Peter Singer: &quot;The Important Things in Life: 72 Lessons in Ethics&quot;, translated into Chinese by Wang Xin, Guangxi Normal University Press, April 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Limit value rational judgment exclusively to the scope of demonstration of the legitimacy of moral intentions, and rely entirely on instrumental rationality to &quot;scientifically&quot; achieve the above Intention, doing so is likely to blur our ethical horizons. The more prosperous science becomes, the more society needs ethics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This book is a collection of short comments published by the author in newspaper columns over the years. &quot;The limit of one thousand words&quot; forced him &quot;to write in a clear and concise style.&quot; What it focuses on are the confusions or dilemmas that ordinary people face in their daily lives in contemporary society: Is morality progressing? What is a good life? When should charity be shown to someone who has made a mistake? If narcotics are recognized to shorten lifespan, should they still be used to suppress pain? Should we live a thousand years? Can public figures have a private life? Is open diplomacy possible? Some readers may feel that the author has not provided any &quot;substantive conclusions&quot; on questions such as this. That may be precisely because we are too familiar with another way of discussion, which can give a decisive and only correct answer to any question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A book that talks about ethics to the public can be written without looking like a boring sermon with a straight face. Our skills in this area are far from perfect. However, the subtitle of the translation still evokes the feeling of sitting upright between the narrow desks and chairs. It would be better to literally translate the title of the book as &quot;Ethics in the Real World: 72 Short Essays Related to It&quot;, which may be more in line with the purpose of the original book. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73724&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70519&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/2551857847.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;s34609084.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1565&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/2551857847.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259763&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Tiangang: &quot;Memory of the Ages: The Shaping of Modern Chinese Ideology&quot;, Renmin University of China Press, July 2023&lt;/p>; &lt; p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The earliest article I read included in this collection was &quot;1900: The Restless South.&quot; I remember that I called Brother Tiangang very excitedly at that time, hoping that he would write a few more articles on this &quot;Centennial Commemoration&quot;, and that when they were accumulated, they could be compiled and published. But meaningful &quot;hundred years&quot; are rare, and there are still some that are inconvenient to write about. The &quot;Reminiscence of the Year&quot; compiled before my eyes can be regarded as a common one. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with many other books on similar topics, how can this book uncover so many new insights worthy of our deep thought? The key is whether you start from a bunch of ready-made presuppositions and pretend to interpret history, or do you go back to the scene and examine it from scratch? In fact, we cannot return to the historical scene. However, as long as you are willing, you can still &quot;see&quot; that period of history as empathetically as possible through the various records left by people at that time. &quot;The devil is in the details.&quot; To give an example that is not included in this book: Wang Kaiyun recalled the &quot;painful history&quot; of the burning of the Old Summer Palace. Why did he call that fire &quot;Lishan Fire&quot;? Not all ignored details are so important, but some solid and reliable details can really become &quot;devils&quot; that change established perceptions! &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another century-old elegy in the book is &quot;1905: The Disillusionment of the Imperial Examination System&quot;. The abolition of the imperial examination not only broke the backbone of traditional Chinese society, but also allowed &quot;dispersed scholar-bureaucrats to pervasively penetrate into all strata of society, exacerbating the turmoil across the country.&quot; The author has the same view as Professor Yang Guoqiang, who strongly emphasizes that modern Chinese society suffered from &quot;tenon removal&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73725&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70520&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/83bfe72096.png&quot; img-title=&quot;Untitled.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1583&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/83bfe72096.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Li Jianming: &quot;The Mainstream of Political Culture during the Founding of the United States&quot;, The Commercial Press, July 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Americans are brave enough to open up a &quot;noisy&quot; discussion on how to view the system of their country&#39;s founding. In this regard, the author of this book uses more than a thousand pages to develop a response and rethinking full of ideological tension based on his own life experience. There are not enough people to comment on &quot;Douban Reading&quot;, but the readers who left short comments all gave five stars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The so-called &quot;mainstream&quot; must have received countless tributaries along both sides of the river, making the water mixed with mud and sand; but it must also form the same giant current rushing forward. . During the American Revolution, the power elite and the radical masses distrusted each other and struggled with each other, even causing turmoil and rebellion in local society. Different from many self-proclaimed political science studies that always try to explain political struggles in terms of power, selfish desires and the pursuit of maximizing interests, and regard the pursuit of values ​​as just a fig leaf for seizing power and maximizing interests, the author emphasizes that it is the two sides’ mutual opposition to The common belief in popular sovereignty and republican principles prevented the American Revolution from becoming a story of a life-and-death struggle between good and evil, but instead became a witness to the initial establishment of modern democracy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Chapter 5 &quot;Reconstruction of the Concept of &#39;Democracy&#39;&quot; is particularly worthy of careful reading. The British Revolution promoted constitutionalism but did not talk about democracy. Therefore, Americans need to rediscover the value of democracy as &quot;a dangerous and even insulting label.&quot; This reminds me of Xu Fuguan’s opinion about the people’s “foolishness but spirituality”: “From the perspective of the knowledge level of intellectuals, the people are foolish. But in terms of their ability to judge big rights and wrongs, good and bad, the people are superior to intellectuals.… Therefore, Confucianism believes that people’s likes and dislikes derived from judgments of right and wrong can be trusted.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73726&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70521 &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/9c20ec3332.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;006r8eOoly1hix2fxfbgxj30j60pkwi4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1626&quot; style=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/9c20ec3332.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259765&quot;>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shao Xiaofeng: &quot;Song Style Artistic Life&quot;, Shanghai Literature and Art Publishing House, September 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text- align: left;&quot;>;After China emerged from the &quot;medieval era&quot; during the Tang and Song Dynasties, did it enter its &quot;pre-modern era&quot;? Experts have mixed opinions on this. But they may all agree that the Song Dynasty, especially the Southern Song Dynasty, is a not-too-distant past that ordinary Chinese can directly perceive based on their real-life experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The topic selection of this book is therefore very down-to-earth, the writing is relaxed but not frivolous, and it is profound but not esoteric. It is not about the art of the Song Dynasty itself, but the Song people&#39;s taste in art and their art of life, that is, the artistic orientation and aesthetic taste contained in daily life shared by many social strata at that time. The whole book uses seven theme words to connect fifty essays, focusing on the small and big things. Although it cannot be said that it has achieved the effect of &quot;gathering armpits into fur&quot;, it is not too much to say that it uses auspicious light feathers of different colors to connect a picture of the night sky. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[看网络短剧的人：“成功来得那么简单，爱情也是”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261395]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is a CEO with a net worth of hundreds of millions. One day in coffee While discussing business in the hall, he was mistaken for a blind date by a girl who made a living by running a street vendor. Out of interest in the girl, the president had a flash marriage with her. He hid his true identity from the girl, and the girl always thought that her husband was just an ordinary worker, and she still worked hard to earn money by setting up a stall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As the plot develops, the identity of the CEO is exposed, and a past relationship also surfaces - it turns out that the CEO and the girl had a child five years ago due to a chance encounter. It’s just that the president didn’t know it, and the girl also forgot due to amnesia...&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In August 2023, this movie will feature boss tyrants, flash marriages, amnesia, sweet pets, and... The short drama &quot;After the Flash Wedding, Mr. Fu Can&#39;t Hide His Vest&quot;, which combines elements such as love after marriage, was launched. In just 24 hours, the recharge of the drama exceeded 20 million yuan, becoming a &quot;hot hit&quot; in the short drama market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/246b0e50e6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1169&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/246b0e50e6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259756&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Cover covers of some mini program short dramas, including &quot;After the Flash Wedding, Mr. Fu Can&#39;t Hide His Vest&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;The concept of the hit drama we make is at least 20 million yuan.&quot; Yan Peiliang, the director of the show, told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;We are now a hit hit. The rate is almost 90%.&quot; Yan Peiliang&#39;s short play creation began in 2021, and has currently filmed more than a dozen popular short plays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Online micro-series, usually a single episode lasts from tens of seconds to about 15 minutes, and the number of episodes ranges from a dozen to hundreds of episodes, mainly including Short dramas on long video platforms mainly based on Youku, iQiyi, Mango, Tencent, etc., short dramas on short video platforms mainly on Douyin, Kuaishou, etc., and &quot;mini program short dramas&quot; that are &quot;parasitic&quot; on WeChat and others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/bae82d8cc5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1241&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/bae82d8cc5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259757&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Part of the cover of Douyin short drama. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Detawen&#39;s &quot;Micro Short Drama Market Report for the First Half of 2023&quot; shows that in the first half of 2023, a total of 481 new micro short dramas will be released, which has exceeded The number of new releases in 2022 (454). On November 22, the &quot;2023-2024 China Micro-Short Drama Market Research Report&quot; released by iiMedia Consulting showed that China&#39;s online micro-short drama market size will be 37.39 billion yuan in 2023, a year-on-year increase of 267.65%. Overseas, according to media reports, ReelShort, a short drama application platform owned by Chinese Online, has topped the U.S. iOS entertainment list. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;What supports the new trend of short dramas is the huge number of viewers. The &quot;China Online Audiovisual Development Research Report (2023)&quot; shows that as of December 2022, the number of short video users in China has reached 1.012 billion, of which more than half of the short video users have watched micro-short dramas and instant noodles that are less than 3 minutes in length. etc., the viewing proportion of users aged 19 and under exceeds 50%. In August 2023, data released by Kuaishou also showed that the number of people interested in short dramas on Kuaishou exceeded 260 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In just one or two hours, the audience traveled through the various fun spots that were set, experiencing rebirth, sudden wealth, and reverse. Attack, slap in the face, revenge and other various virtual lives. In this short drama world, they can easily gain a perfect love and reach the other side of success effortlessly. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“What is needed is simplicity, speed and directness”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiao Wei used to play otome games (note: those targeting women Dating simulation game), I watched the short drama in August. She is 39 years old and works as a training supervisor in a company. The first short drama she watched was a clip automatically recommended by a short video platform. The plot was simple: the heroine had to find someone to get married because of various grievances between wealthy families. She mistakenly thought that the male protagonist was the president at the construction site. He was an ordinary worker. After marrying him, the two started a life of marriage first and love later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiao Wei watched it for more than a minute. Her first impression was of handsome men and beautiful women. She thought the theme of &quot;The Domineering President Falls in Love with Me&quot; was interesting. After searching for the full collection Then they gave chase. To her surprise, the short drama had a compact plot and no unnecessary plot. She finished it in just over an hour. After that, she started looking for short dramas recommended by other netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During a busy working day, Qiao Wei only has lunch break and two hours before going to bed. For her, the length of short dramas is just right. Even if there are more than a hundred episodes of short dramas, it only takes an hour or two to finish them all. During her lunch break, she would randomly open a movie and watch a dozen or twenty episodes, which lasted only about twenty minutes, as a pastime. &quot;Anyway, my time is fragmented.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The scene of Tan Zhifeng watching the short play is also similar. She is completing her third year of master&#39;s degree this year and will watch short dramas in her spare time. However, she usually doesn&#39;t go out of her way to find short dramas recommended by others. She just watches the ones that appeal to her. She would even watch short dramas at double speed. &quot;The main reason is that she doesn&#39;t have enough time and is anxious, so she wants to finish it as soon as possible.&quot; Moreover, &quot;each scene of the short drama does not contain such complicated information,&quot; so double speed does not affect it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to her observation, short dramas generally rely on dialogue between actors to advance the plot. The president may sit on a chair and communicate with the butler next to him. Once the matter is done, &quot;you can move on to the next step.&quot; There are not so many details to explore in the short play, such as what traditional elements the set is designed according to, and what information is conveyed by the actors&#39; movements and eyes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Tan Zhifeng used to read online articles for more than ten years. When she first saw some clips from short dramas, she thought they were &quot;tacky&quot;. Those settings, such as &quot;The Overlord and His Little Wife,&quot; were all popular elements in online articles more than ten years ago. But she didn&#39;t expect that now she is chasing short dramas. During the play, I still felt like I was &quot;on top&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/b396882cb5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1598&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/b396882cb5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259758&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the online short drama &quot;The President Loves Me Too Much&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She thinks this may be related to the simplicity and directness of the short play. For example, she wants to watch &quot;The Boss&#39;s Sweet Pet&quot;. In some TV dramas, it may take a long development process to reach the plot point of &quot;pet&quot;, but the short drama is different. It will directly use the plot scene of &quot;pet, love hard&quot;. Presented; another example is the plot of a slap in the face. A long drama may take a long time to prepare, but a short drama may reveal the conspiracy of the vicious female supporting character in the next episode and slap the face immediately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Instead of waiting for an hour for that one (cool) point, why don&#39;t I look at 10 (cool) points in 5 minutes. Although it looks tacky, But it’s refreshing faster.” Tan Zhifeng told Southern Weekend reporters, “What everyone needs is simple, fast and direct.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mo Xia also thinks so. She is 28 years old and works in a public institution. She remembered a costume-themed short drama she had watched before. There was a plot where the heroine changed her face, and no one except the hero could recognize her. She felt that if this plot was placed in a long drama, there would definitely be misunderstandings that would take several episodes to complete, which would make people feel frustrated. However, in the short drama, “There are no misunderstandings, it’s just a very smooth plot, and everyone just It was fun to watch.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I don&#39;t care what the two people in the middle have gone through, I just want to see them reconcile.&quot; Qiao Wei said. In her opinion, long dramas will always try to be logically linked, but &quot;there will still be logical gaps.&quot; Short dramas are less concerned with logic. &quot;(Since) it&#39;s not perfect, I might as well show more of what I want to see.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Provide us with material for dreaming&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Like online articles, short dramas are also divided into &quot;gender&quot;. &quot;Mainly serving male audiences, the audience of &quot;Female Channel Drama&quot; is mainly female. Li Yu is currently mainly writing &quot;male dramas&quot;. He has created eighty or ninety short plays, most of which have themes such as the God of War and the son-in-law. He introduced that the audience of &quot;male video drama&quot; is mainly between the ages of 35 and 55. Most of them work as security guards, delivery workers, online ride-hailing drivers, etc., and their educational level is generally low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Peiliang, who currently mainly produces &quot;female video dramas&quot;, said that &quot;female video dramas&quot; are more like romantic dramas, usually with elements such as sweet pets and sadomasochism. &quot;Male dramas&quot; are more delicate, and the age of the audience is relatively young, mainly between 25 and 45 years old. These women usually have a certain level of education and pay more attention to the picture, atmosphere and other factors of the short drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But in Yan Peiliang&#39;s view, whether it is a &quot;male video drama&quot; or a &quot;female video drama&quot;, most viewers will substitute themselves when watching. Female viewers may fantasize about a handsome guy pursuing them, while male viewers may assume the identity of the male protagonist and feel that they are &quot;counterattacking&quot; and &quot;getting rich&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He observed that unlike female audiences who have high requirements for the appearance of the male and female protagonists in &quot;female-channel dramas&quot;, male audiences watch &quot;male-channel dramas&quot; &quot;, the requirements for the male protagonist&#39;s appearance are not high, just ordinary. Too good-looking will affect their acceptance. But at the same time, they hope that the heroine will be as beautiful as possible, so that &quot;the fantasy can be fulfilled.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a short play writer and director, Zhizhu pays more attention to creating a sense of atmosphere when filming, so that the audience can better relate to it. She is a photographer and started filming short plays in early 2022. Now her two short plays have received ratings of 6.8 and 7.2 respectively on Douban. She will work hard on lighting and composition, and create a sense of atmosphere by arranging scenes such as rain and wind. Sometimes she will also create a sense of tension through the gazes of the male and female protagonists as needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/e0e94ec1e9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;834&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/e0e94ec1e9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;259759&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the online short series &quot;Donglan Snow&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Actually, everyone has a dream about love in their hearts. I think the short drama invisibly provides us with material for dreaming.&quot; Qiao Wei told Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She always calls herself a &quot;middle-aged girl&quot;. In reality, she has a happy small family, and her son is already in the first grade of elementary school. But she feels that &quot;the reality is You are who you are, and you will never be the heroine in &#39;The Boss Falls in Love with Me&#39;, but when you watch the show, you can realize such a dream.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qian Wan is 27 years old and works in a bank. When watching short dramas, he prefers the plot of &quot;chasing his wife in the crematorium&quot;. For example, the male protagonist originally had a &quot;Bai Yueguang&quot;, but he abandoned the female protagonist after Bai Yueguang came back. After experiencing some things, he realized that the person he really loved was the heroine, thus starting the &quot;crematorium&quot; mode. She felt that this might be related to her only real love experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;That relationship was pursued by her, and it only lasted for more than ten days. The other party admitted to her during a phone call that he still liked the girl he had not pursued before. Qian Wan felt that she had been tricked by the other party, and she was unwilling and sad. At that time, she really hoped that the boy would regret it, but she sent a message to the other party at that time, but the other party did not reply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Aren&#39;t (these) dramas just for dreaming?&quot; Qian Wan said. Ren Dongxiao also thinks so. She is a sophomore this year. When watching short dramas, every time she sees the heroine being bullied and the CEO hero standing up to protect and take care of the heroine and slapping other people in the face, she expects it to really exist in reality. Such a person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiao Wei remembered watching &quot;Tom and Jerry&quot; when she was a child. No matter how much Tom was tortured by Jerry, he could not get enough of Jerry. This made her very happy. Peace of mind is a joy. Watching short dramas gave her a similar feeling. The villain&#39;s thoughts were always on his face. No matter how he framed the heroine, the hero would always appear at the critical moment. No matter how many twists and turns the hero and heroine went through, there was always a positive outcome. &quot;Everything you hope will happen happens, everything you hope to see will be seen,&quot; she said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Tan Zhifeng’s view, many short dramas will deliberately omit complicated things in real life. For example, if an 18th-tier star becomes a movie queen, the middle part should be It’s a long road, but in the short play, “you can get all the fame and achievements you want without putting in any effort”; no matter what the heroine’s conditions are or how she behaves, the CEO is devoted to her for no reason. . &quot;Success comes so easily, and so does love.&quot; She said, &quot;(These) things that make no sense if you think about it carefully may just be a dream created for everyone.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;Maybe this kind of thing &quot;Happiness can&#39;t be found in the elegant hall, but it doesn&#39;t matter&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yu currently writes mainly &quot;small program short plays&quot;. He is 20 years old and can write two pieces a month. Three parts, each with about 100 episodes. The four short plays he wrote in the past two months are &quot;60% similar in content&quot;, and they are all based on the same God of War theme. The protagonist may be a fish seller in this drama, but next time he will be a pig butcher; some of the key slap-in-the-face plots will take place at the old man&#39;s birthday party, and some will be at the heroine&#39;s home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Yu doesn&#39;t want his friends to know that he is writing a short play, for fear that they will think, &quot;It turns out that such rubbish stuff was written by people like you.&quot; . He would feel &quot;very ashamed&quot; and &quot;(the short play he wrote) has no nutrition, literary value or artistic value&quot;, but &quot;currently they (editors and platforms) do not want to innovate and do not require taking risks&quot;, and he also needs to survive . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Short plays inherently have many similar plots. (If you) often watch short plays, you will find that many characters have similar names and cannot be distinguished at all.&quot; Many short dramas currently on the market do not have the so-called film and television language. &quot;To put it bluntly, it is a dynamic PPT for online novels.&quot; Yan Peiliang told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Mo Xia said that she &quot;can remember very few&quot;. She has watched nearly fifty short plays this year, and she can name the titles and general plots of them. No more than ten. Other short drama viewers interviewed also mentioned that it was difficult to remember which short dramas they had watched. Tan Zhifeng recalled a certain short drama he had watched before, and what he remembered more was the short drama elements of &quot;traveling through the past, empress, queen, CEO, sweet pet, counterattack and slap in the face&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I can only say that this kind of short play is excitement itself. No matter how it is produced, it only meets some momentary needs for happiness. Maybe this kind of happiness even reaches the top of the screen. It’s not elegant, but it doesn’t matter.” Tan Zhifeng told Southern Weekend reporters. Just like herself, she is busy and stressed in real life, and she hopes to focus on watching things in her spare time that do not require the use of her brain. &quot;You can&#39;t keep one string tight all the time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/be166c8ad3.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1663&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/be166c8ad3.png&quot; data-key=&quot;259760&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from the online short series &quot;Abuse of Love: Mr. Lu&#39;s Newly Married Mute Wife&quot;. Data map&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Qiao Wei attaches great importance to the two hours of free time before going to bed. For her, &quot;If I didn&#39;t have these two hours, I would either be a As a wife, either a mother or an employee, I have to think about how to live a better life. (But) I feel that only when these two hours belong to myself, (will I) consider whether I am happy or not. I It doesn’t matter who it is, I don’t have to work hard or think.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She feels that the short play is “quite efficient” in terms of satisfying her own needs for happiness. . She used to spend those two hours playing games where she could design her own plot, or learning to play the ukulele. Although she was happy, she still found it too mentally taxing. &quot;The short play feels like a popping candy to me. I&#39;ve finished it in one bite. I don&#39;t need to think about it. I just feel happy now. As for whether it is meaningful or not, I don&#39;t think it&#39;s important.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But she also feels that if there is no short drama, it will not have much impact. Zhizhu also believes that even if there is no short drama, there will be something else, because everyone is very tired from work, and there must always be some entertainment channels for emotional release. Games, short videos, and novels can all be options. &quot;( Short plays) are very alternative for the audience.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yan Peiliang feels that although short plays are &quot;dispensable&quot; for some audiences. But just like Coke, some people think it is dispensable, and there will always be people who regard it as a necessity. &quot;Let the audience choose for themselves.&quot; For example, a breakfast shop sells steamed buns and provides side dishes. Some people buy the steamed buns and leave, while others just pick them up. Some dried radishes and pickles, &quot;The value of our existence is that when the audience has this demand, we still have some relatively good quality pickles waiting for them.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; (At the request of the interviewees, Tan Zhifeng, Mo Xia, Qian Wan , Ren Dongxiao, and Li Yu are pseudonyms)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[离婚跟拍火了，闲得慌还是花钱买仪式感？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261363]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recently, divorce follow-up photography has become popular among young people. When they get divorced, many young people put aside the past haze and choose to follow the divorce and hold a divorce party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the divorce party, the banner read: &quot;This is the end of this B marriage.&quot; Blogger Sushi said, &quot;I think marriage has a corresponding sense of ceremony, and divorce also needs it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/27/WbJWJNGCsowzFqypzDYNtLZ5upGDvkAgYzir0g5M.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/WbJWJNGCsowzFqypzDYNtLZ5upGDv kAgYzir0g5M .jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259747&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Photography of marriage and filming of divorce&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;Data shows that China’s divorce rate has increased year by year since 2003, reaching its peak in 2019 at 3.4‰. In the past two years, it has also remained above 2‰. Among them, young people aged 25-35 have become the main force in divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Under this trend, young people&#39;s attitudes and thoughts when facing divorce have changed greatly compared with the past. Compared with the bitterness and hatred of the older generation, divorce seems to be becoming a &quot;peaceful thing&quot; and a positive thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, as early as the 2010 movie &quot;If You Are the One 2&quot;, Mango, played by Yao Chen, and Li Xiangshan, played by Sun Honglei, held a party when they separated. Divorce ceremony. Actor Ge You, as the divorce certifier, said in his speech: &quot;Let&#39;s shake hands like acquaintances,&quot; which brought a relatively happy ending to the separation between the two. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Today&#39;s young people use the method of divorce follow-up, taking photos and Vlog to record the end of one stage and the beginning of a new stage. Taking photos becomes a ritual in the divorce process. Of course, this ceremonial divorce photoshoot is completely different from the wedding photoshoot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As we all know, when taking wedding photos, the theme is to get married and the main focus is celebration. Almost every newlywed couple will wear Chinese or Western-style dresses and hire professional photo studios and photographers to record the two people as a couple cuddling with each other and being united forever in various settings such as the seaside, under the shadow of coconut trees, and in the courtyard of an ancient house. The beautiful shadow. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But divorce photos are no longer carefully posed on the beach or in the shadow of coconut trees, but may be the Civil Affairs Bureau or a place where the two went shopping together, or even A certain park or tea house for daily simple photography. After photographer Song Yang accepted an order to follow up on the divorce of an old classmate, he followed his friends to several places that were memorable to them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;During the process, Song Yang followed silently and did not find a special camera position to capture the scene. He only occasionally gave simple guidance to the subjects. The overall atmosphere was not heavy and similar to normal. life portraits. Song Yang said, &quot;It&#39;s like shooting with normal friends. Everyone is calm, no conflicts, and not too close. And it&#39;s more casual, without even discussing in advance where to shoot and how to shoot.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition to the final group photo, other divorce photos also include a photo of a girl who came to a coffee shop after the divorce and took a photo with a coffee cup with &quot;Happy Single&quot; written on it. . The scenes and shots are not complicated, but with this simple stroke, the divorce was brought to an end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/TQWNs1nqr7G10j9Rh1deJAu8nZcnQfnvvMD0Iv9n.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/27/TQWNs1nqr7G10j9Rh1deJAu8nZcnQfnvvMD0Iv9n.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;259748&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Why do young people want to take divorce photos?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, why do young people want to take divorce photos when they get divorced? First of all, of course, it was because of the divorce. As this incident occurred, many comprehensive factors behind it came into play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Currently, the development of social civilization has entered a new stage. Marriage is changing from a lifelong bond in the traditional concept to a relationship in the minds of young people. Freedom of choice. The influence of traditional concepts on young people is weakening, and young people are beginning to pay more attention to their personal rights and feelings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the change of this concept, when people face divorce, they have changed from crying, discrimination and dissuasion to equality today. Look at peace and confrontation, as well as calm and stable positive solutions, as turning points towards happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhou Xiaoyan, a psychology professor at Chongqing Normal University, believes that &quot;the business of divorce tracking can be carried out, which is enough to see changes in society and people&#39;s tolerance and psychological tolerance.&quot; Higher. In the past, everyone generally believed that divorce was an ugly thing and was unwilling to talk about it too much. Now, divorce is regarded as an event in life, and is no longer defined by failure, but by experience.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Recording the divorce process is exactly what the French anthropologist Van Gennep put forward, &quot;There is always a transition from one stage to another in human life. , a ritual is needed in the process of transformation.&quot; Recording, sharing, and getting likes and comments, and fixing the mood, expression, time, location, etc. of the divorce in the circle of friends and social platforms is a sense of ritual. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, as a professor of sociology at Tsinghua University said, &quot;Social media brings people who are far away&quot;, whether it is Douyin or Xiaohong Books, the impact of the online social wave is inevitable. When Generation Z people see some bloggers or peers sharing their experience in taking divorce photos, they will easily become curious about trying it. It is only human nature to follow the trend and take photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Will divorce photography become a large-scale business? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;So, with the interest of young people in taking divorce photos, will divorce photography become a large-scale business? At present, it is not very large-scale yet and is relatively niche. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the perspective of demand, although the divorce rate is now high and there are many divorced people, the divorced group is also divided into those who need to take divorce photos and those who do not. Of those who have this need, they are still in the minority. Therefore, the market size of divorce photos is actually relatively small. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Judging from the current situation of receiving orders, many photographers receive such photo invitations on social platforms and then follow them. Some photographers with similar experience also publish relevant information through social platforms to gain customers. In reality, no dedicated docking platform or professional organization has emerged, and no large-scale promotion has occurred. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, from a business perspective, where there is demand, consumption will be created. Business opportunities often arise from scratch, from small to large. Divorce, like birth, birthday, graduation, marriage, funeral, etc., is actually a turning event in life. Compared with graduation or marriage, divorce, an equally important life event, has obviously not received enough attention and response. This is where the business opportunities for divorce services lie. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the future, with the continuous changes in concepts, it is not impossible that the end of a marriage will be taken as seriously as the beginning of a marriage. Once this emphasis on divorce is transformed into demand and consumption, corresponding divorce service projects will appear more and more like marriage services. According to media reports, Japanese divorce companies can provide services such as divorce ceremonies and divorce travel, and many divorced couples have experienced corresponding services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, divorce photography also involves the photographer getting to know the emotions and privacy of both clients. This also requires practitioners to have certain legal knowledge and be able to Avoid during operation. But as the other side of marriage, relevant practitioners can pay attention to divorce-related products and services. It may not necessarily be an explosive growth business, but as the second growth curve, it may not be an effective supplement to regular business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一根78元的“考试专用”跳绳背后：企业为何连年中标应严肃调查丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261375]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;How much does a skipping rope cost? On e-commerce platforms, ordinary racing skipping ropes from many well-known sports brands only cost a dozen yuan, and even ones with counting functions can be bought for thirty or forty yuan. However, there are also some skipping ropes marked &quot;Exclusively for the High School Entrance Examination in ** City&quot; that are expensive. Xinhua News Agency recently reported that a special skipping rope designated by the Hangzhou Education Department for the high school entrance examination sells for as much as 78 yuan a piece. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Xinhua News Agency, for more than ten years, Hangzhou&#39;s high school entrance examination sports rope skipping projects have been using &quot;Hengyou&quot; brand skipping ropes. In order to familiarize children with the test ropes in advance, many schools and teachers explicitly or implicitly allow students to use &quot;Hengyou&quot; brand skipping ropes for practice. The brand&#39;s skipping ropes sell for 78 yuan for the regular model, and more than 140 yuan for the one with Bluetooth counting function. Even though the price is much higher than other brands, parents still have to pay the bill. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is designated by the local education department as a test-only device. In order to achieve good results in the exam, students have to use it for daily practice. This strategy has made &quot;Hengyou&quot; brand rope skipping a lot of money in Hangzhou. According to the agent of this brand of skipping ropes in Zhejiang, they sell more than 100,000 skipping ropes in Zhejiang a year, and more than 70% of their users are primary and secondary school students. In the past few years, Hangzhou had almost 100,000 primary and secondary school students (according to the Hangzhou National Economic and Social Development Statistical Bulletin, there were 681,000 primary school students and 264,000 junior high school students in Hangzhou in 2021), which shows its penetration rate. high. Calculated based on the profit of 70 yuan per ordinary skipping rope (industry sources revealed that the cost of ordinary skipping ropes is less than 8 yuan each, and the cost of those with counting functions is less than 20 yuan), the brand has a stable profit of more than 7 million yuan in Hangzhou every year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;How did the &quot;Hengyou&quot; skipping rope become exclusive for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination? According to an interview with Xinhua News Agency, the agent of the brand&#39;s skipping rope in Zhejiang said that since entering the Zhejiang market in 2011, the &quot;Hengyou&quot; skipping rope has been used for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination Sports Examination Rope. The deputy director of the Hangzhou Municipal Education Examination Institute, who is responsible for purchasing sports equipment for the Hangzhou High School Entrance Examination, said that since 2011, the education department has &quot;rented and used&quot; high school entrance examination sports equipment produced by this brand manufacturer. Starting from 2017, the Education Examination Agency has used public bidding to select sports equipment for the high school entrance examination. However, this company still wins the bid every year, and the annual rental fee is 8.9 million yuan. A document from the Zhejiang Provincial Government Procurement Network shows that in 2019, the Hangzhou Education Examination Institute plans to use the &quot;single source&quot; procurement method to lease sports equipment of this brand for the high school entrance examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as it entered the Zhejiang market, it became the exclusive skipping rope for high school entrance examination sports in Hangzhou City. It has been used exclusively for more than ten years. The &quot;open bidding&quot; of the education department turned out to be &quot;single source procurement&quot;, excluding other brands of skipping ropes on the grounds of so-called &quot;continuity of use, integrity of the examination system, and specificity of the software management platform.&quot; It is inevitable that people will have doubts. Who is this company? Who is its actual controller? What is so special about it that it deserves the favor of the Hangzhou Education Department? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This situation of &quot;exam-only&quot; skipping ropes that are much higher than the market price does not only exist in Hangzhou. Search results on the e-commerce platform show that the Shanghai high school entrance examination-specific technical skipping rope costs 158 yuan each, and the Guiyang &quot;examination room same style timing and counting online model&quot; skipping rope costs 179 yuan each. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why must I use a specific brand of skipping rope for the rope skipping test? Especially according to students and teachers, this skipping rope is not suitable for primary and secondary school students. In fact, every skipping rope that meets national standards should be used for exams. For physical education exams, you can purchase a variety of skipping ropes from different brands, allowing students to choose freely. You might even consider asking students to bring their own jump ropes for exams. As for the automatic counting function that improves efficiency, if you are worried about inaccurate counting of students’ own skipping ropes, other methods can be used to solve the problem. With current technology, automatic counting can be achieved through video surveillance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, some schools have frequently &quot;cooperated&quot; with businesses to sell designated teaching aids to students. Some schools even required students to purchase tablets worth several thousand yuan in the name of &quot;information-based teaching.&quot; computer. To this end, the Ministry of Education and other departments have issued a document specifically requiring that &quot;students and parents shall not be forced or hinted to purchase designated teaching aid software or materials.&quot; But the examination, as a baton, will still play an obvious guiding role. As we all know, China’s education is seriously involution and everything is exam-oriented. As long as it is labeled &quot;exam-only&quot;, no matter how expensive it is, parents will buy it. This gives education departments and schools a lot of invisible power. When the education department labels a certain brand&#39;s products as &quot;exam-only&quot;, it is equivalent to endorsing it and giving it a great advantage in market competition. This advantage comes from administrative designation, which is essentially an administrative monopoly or rent-seeking behavior. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, is there really nothing behind the 78-yuan &quot;exclusively for high school entrance examination&quot; skipping rope? This is something that relevant departments should find out clearly. More importantly, it breaks the status quo of only using certain equipment for exams and gives students more choices. Only in this way can normal market competition be promoted, students and parents will be spared from becoming leeks, and students can also use better products. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“中国乞讨者泰国被捕”背后：残酷的人口贩运链]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261387]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Facial disfigurement, physical disabilities... In recent days, several Chinese beggars have appeared on the streets of Bangkok. Putting Thailand at the forefront of public opinion has also launched a new round of crackdowns on illegal begging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, 2023, Aung Munna, deputy director of the Bangkok Metropolitan Police Department in Thailand, announced at a press conference that from November 10 to 20, the Bangkok police arrested six Chinese beggars. , and all six of them had varying degrees of disfigurement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on the physical conditions, confessions and partial investigation results of the six beggars when they were arrested, the Thai police suspected that these beggars may be victims of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Begging is prohibited in Thailand, but begging on the streets has always existed. Data from the Thai Ministry of Social Development and Human Security show that from 2016 to the present, 7,151 beggars have been found in Thailand, including 2,473 foreign beggars, most of whom are Cambodians and Burmese, and 68 are Chinese citizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some of the beggars wandering the streets of Thailand are forced to beg because of human trafficking. According to the Thai charity Der Spiegel Foundation, there are at least 1,000 trafficked child beggars in Thailand. The &quot;Global Trafficking in Persons Report&quot; released by the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime also pointed out that of the 36,488 victims of human trafficking detected in 2020, 0.7% were for exploitative begging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 22, the spokesperson of the Chinese Embassy in Thailand responded, “The Embassy has taken note of the relevant reports and has sent consular officials to conduct consular visits to the parties. China has always required Chinese citizens coming to Thailand to abide by Thai laws. , respect local customs, and also attach importance to safeguarding their legitimate rights and interests. We believe that the relevant departments of the Thai government and the police will find out the truth as soon as possible and handle it appropriately in accordance with the law.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Who is behind the scenes? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The arrest of a Chinese beggar was inseparable from the report of Thai Internet celebrity Guntouch Pongpaiboonwet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guntouch is active on Facebook. He has long been concerned about social issues in Thailand and has 730,000 fans. On November 19, 2023, Guntouch learned that a woman wearing a student uniform and a deformed face was begging in the Pin Klao area of ​​Bangkok. He suspected that international human trafficking might be involved, so he reported it to the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the same day, the Thai police arrested the female beggar. When she was arrested, she was carrying a backpack, a chair, a money box and a key card. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A Thai vendor who has been operating a store in a shopping mall for more than ten years told the police that she only started to find beggars wearing student uniforms begging nearby this year. &quot;The arrested Chinese beggars are not alone. She appears early in the morning with other beggars and doesn&#39;t leave until evening.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Media reports stated that the female beggar told the police that she went to Thailand to beg on November 10. She said that she was divorced and had two sons to raise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the woman was arrested, another Chinese woman claimed to be the beggar&#39;s translator and came to the police station to release her on bail, but was refused by the Thai police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The woman is not the only illegal beggar arrested by Thai police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As of November 20, Thai police arrested a total of six Chinese beggars in Bangkok. According to the Thai Immigration Bureau, the six beggars entered Thailand on different flights from mainland China, Hong Kong, Malaysia and Laos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the investigation continues, more details are emerging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thailand police investigation found that these beggars began to enter Thailand on tourist visas in June, and one of them was applying for a private university in northern Thailand. If your tourist visa is converted to a student visa, you will be able to extend your stay in Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, beggars daily beg in crowded shopping malls and tourist attractions, earning about 10,000 baht (approximately RMB 2,000) per person per day. The police investigated the bank account of one of the women and found that the monthly flow was as high as 2 million baht (approximately RMB 400,000). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to comprehensive media reports, the six arrested beggars were around 40 years old, and all had facial scars and disabilities in their limbs. One of the beggars told the police that his facial injuries and hand disabilities were old childhood injuries caused by the explosion of flammable items, while the others refused to provide relevant information. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, there are inextricably linked relationships between these beggars. Thai police found that two of the beggars lived in the Wang Thonglang area, and the rest lived in different hotels in Bangkok. This is inconsistent with the previous arrest of a woman who said she had no fixed abode. Meanwhile, some beggars share the same Thai translation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Thai police suspect that these beggars may be victims of international human trafficking, and that there may be Thai support behind the begging gang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Currently, one beggar has been deported from Thailand, and the remaining beggars are still detained at the Immigration Bureau. Major General Panta, deputy director of the Thai Immigration Department, said that the investigation into the gang involved is being expanded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Thailand’s campaign against illegal begging continues to deepen. Media reports said that Thai police arrested four more beggars in Bangkok, from Laos and Cambodia. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Countries of origin, destination and transit of human trafficking&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Begging is illegal in Thailand. As early as 2016, Thailand introduced the &quot;Begging Control Law&quot; in an attempt to eliminate illegal beggars on the streets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to this law, foreign beggars who beg in Thailand will be deported, while domestic beggars will be forced to receive vocational training or be sent to reception centers. Those who attempt to profit from organizing street begging will face up to three years in prison and/or a fine of up to 30,000 baht. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, in order to combat street begging, Thailand has carried out many street cleaning operations in recent years. According to reports, in May 2023, the Pattaya police in Thailand arrested 37 Cambodian beggars, including 19 adults and 18 children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Thai officials, strict measures against street begging are to prevent illegal begging from breeding many criminal problems such as human trafficking and child labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in fact, Thailand, known as the &quot;Land of Smiles&quot;, has long been plagued by the dark trade of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, the U.S. State Department released the &quot;Trafficking in Persons Report&quot;, which ranked Thailand as the third lowest ranking, which means that the Thai government did not fully comply with the minimum standards in responding to and eliminating human trafficking, and No significant effort was made. Meanwhile, the U.S. State Department noted that Thailand is a source, destination and transit country for men, women and children subject to forced labor and sex trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Thailand is located in the center of Southeast Asia and is a destination for illegal immigrants from many neighboring countries seeking high-paying jobs. The United Nations International Organization for Migration estimates that there are nearly 5 million immigrants in Thailand, of which about 1 million to 2.5 million do not have legal immigration status. Lacking legal protection, these illegal immigrants are extremely vulnerable to work exploitation, human smuggling and trafficking, and transnational crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meanwhile, the &quot;Golden Triangle&quot; connecting Thailand, Myanmar and Laos has been a hotbed of illegal activity, with Thailand a convenient location for traffickers to transport victims to other countries. Reports indicate that sex trafficking victims from Bangladesh, Pakistan, Vietnam and North Korea transit through Thailand to Western Europe, Singapore, Russia and the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also difficult for the Thai people themselves to escape the nightmare of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is reported that as of July 2020, more than 120,000 Thais are still working abroad. &quot;Many Thais prefer to seek easier but illegal jobs abroad, which makes them easy targets for human traffickers and easy to be exploited by unscrupulous employers,&quot; said Samann, a senior fellow at the Institute of Asia Studies at Chulalongkorn University in Thailand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Thomson Reuters Foundation estimates that at least 522 Thai workers died in South Korea from 2015 to 2022, about 84% of whom were illegal immigrants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to change the status quo, in 2018, the Thai police teamed up with social workers and non-governmental organizations to set up a special working group to combat human trafficking. At the same time, the Thai government is increasing its financial budget every year. In 2022, the Thai government will allocate 440 million baht to prevent and combat human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from official data, the problem of human trafficking in Thailand seems to have improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In June 2023, the U.S. State Department released the latest version of the &quot;Trafficking in Persons Report&quot;, and Thailand&#39;s ranking rose to the second level. This is the second consecutive year that Thailand has ranked second. Thailand&#39;s Minister of Social Development and Human Security Waravutt noted that Thailand has been committed to improving to Level 1. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in 2022, the Thai government investigated 253 cases of human trafficking and identified 444 victims of human trafficking. The vast majority of these 444 victims are from Thailand (344) and ASEAN countries such as Laos, Myanmar, and Indonesia. Another 11 are from China, Uganda, Tanzania, Uzbekistan, Kenya, and other countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the data released by the Thai government may be just the tip of the iceberg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The U.S. State Department pointed out in the 2023 &quot;Human Trafficking Report&quot; that fraud companies located in Cambodia, Laos, Myanmar and the Philippines often use Thailand as a transit country to lure fraudsters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Myawaddy, located on the border of Thailand and Myanmar, is one of the main gathering places for fraud parks, across the river from Mae Sot, Thailand. Mechel Moore, CEO of the Mae Sot Anti-Human Trafficking NGO, told reporters that since August 2022, the organization has helped at least 452 victims of human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that behind human trafficking in Thailand, there are often government officials, who facilitate human trafficking by accepting bribes. In 2022 alone, 35 government officials were investigated by the Thai government for their involvement in human trafficking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 13:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[马航MH370乘客家属索赔案今天开庭审理]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/261391]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-27 10:52:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Malaysian Airlines flight MH370 is a Boeing 777 aircraft formerly operated by Malaysia Airlines. It was flown by Malaysia on March 8, 2014. Contact was lost en route from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing. There were 239 passengers and crew on the flight, including 154 Chinese passengers. On January 29, 2015, the Civil Aviation Authority of Malaysia announced that MH370 had crashed and 239 people on board were presumed to have died. Today (November 27), this air transport damage liability dispute case was heard in the Chaoyang District People’s Court of Beijing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that more than 40 family members of passengers have filed lawsuits, and the cases will be heard in Beijing Chaoyang Court from November 27 to December 6. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The attorney for the passengers’ families said that there are five defendants in this case, namely Malaysia Airlines, also known as the old Malaysia Airlines, Malaysia International Airlines Co., Ltd. also known as the new Malaysia Airlines, Boeing Company of the United States, and Aircraft Engines Manufacturers: Rolls-Royce in the UK and Allianz in Germany. The claims of the more than 40 passengers&#39; families are different, but they mainly focus on two points. One is to find out the truth about the missing incident of flight MH370 through case trial, and the other is the issue of compensation. It is understood that the biggest difficulty in the trial of this case is to ascertain the truth of the incident. &lt;p>; . The current inability to produce evidence, insufficient evidence, or incomplete evidence is a huge hole left in the trial process of this case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the amount of civil compensation filed by the passengers’ families is between 10 million and 80 million yuan. Because each family’s situation is different, the amount is also different. A large part of the compensation fee is mental damage solatium. , the highest is 30 to 40 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is also understood that in addition to the family members of more than 40 passengers who filed the lawsuit in Beijing Chaoyang Court, the family members of more than 110 other passengers have reached settlements with the five defendants and signed settlement agreements. The amount received ranged from 2.5 million to 3 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 27 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>