<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[此情可待成追忆：本师吴金华先生逝世十年祭]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260212]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/xJaaVqlw63PvYAuRlUUy4wQFy4drzzlOu07pkyhn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;864&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/xJaaVqlw63PvYAuRlUUy4wQFy4drzz lOu07pkyhn. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257543&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mr. Wu Jinhua, Distinguished Professor of Fudan University and Researcher of the Institute of Ancient Books (1943-2013) 2007 Photos taken during his visit to the United States in December. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1997, nine years had passed since I graduated from Nanjing Normal University with an undergraduate degree in ancient literature. One spring afternoon, I went up to the fourth floor with my four-year-old daughter in my arms. When I took out the key and opened the door, I woke up from my own heavy breathing. Because I was unwilling to let my life go down, I decided to go back to college to start another kind of growth. At that moment, I thought of you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, after graduating from college, I stopped thinking about you for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I saw you in college, you had a bald head like a European monk, energetic eyes behind big glasses, and thick lips that were always smiling. Except in summer, he seems to always wear a blue or black tunic suit with one or two pens in the top pocket. A classmate from the previous class said that they saw you wiping the blackboard with the sleeves of your Mao suit while you were engaged in class. We didn’t take your class very often, so we never saw you do this in class, but I did see you darken your face after class. The corners, cuffs, pockets, etc. of the tunic suit looked like they were stained with chalk dust. I was admitted to Nanjing Normal University in 1984. The various inexplicable and severe restrictions I had suffered before led to strong rebellion in the tolerant university. During those four years, I couldn’t see anything, including you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As graduation approaches, my view of you has changed a lot. I went to your home to receive guidance on my graduation thesis. That was the only individual communication in the past four years. The house was very crowded and there was no desk, so you invited me to sit down at a small round dining table filled with books and started talking about my thesis. During this period, I have been attracted by a copy of &quot;The Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; spread out in the middle of the table. The blank space on the opened page is filled with long and short school slogans written in different pens. When you talk about it later, you forget why, as if you are looking for an example to illustrate, you start to flip through the book. Then I saw clearly that every page of the book was filled with colorful words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AvnX5ym43zUn0CFTMDMl2eAOkOZRhgh5Toicl6Pv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1045&quot; height= &quot;780&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/AvnX5ym43zUn0CFTMDMl2eAOkOZRhgh5Toicl6Pv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257546&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; annotated by Mr. Wu Jinhua. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am very ashamed. What you talked to me about academics that day was quickly forgotten. Only the appearance of this book still comes to mind from time to time. After graduating from Nanjing Normal University, I returned to my hometown of Changshu. After only a year or two, my arrogance naturally turned into decadence. In the next few years, I rarely read. When the weather is bad, I wander aimlessly by Shang Lake at the foot of Yushan Mountain, letting the rain and snow fall from my head. Try to persuade yourself and try to play cards day and night with all kinds of people from all walks of life. Smoking more and more aggressively, especially when alone. I often drank, got drunk late at night, and sat alone in the darkness on the side of the road, crying silently. It wasn&#39;t until this spring afternoon that everything came to an abrupt end. I decided to start over and do something seriously for a long time. What came to mind again at that time was the &quot;Anthology of the Three Kingdoms&quot; filled with words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So I wrote to you. I didn’t even know that you left Suiyuan two years ago (Editor’s note: the former site of Yuan Mei Suiyuan, the old campus of Nanjing Normal University). Your reply from Shanghai said that it was a pleasure to know that you wanted to come to study. Professionally, as long as we don&#39;t completely abandon what we have learned and review it, not many people can compete. What you have to do is to concentrate on preparing foreign languages. In the winter of that year, in the last two months before the postgraduate entrance examination, it seemed to be raining all the time. I locked myself in a room, lowered the curtains, put away the clock, and read, recited, and dictated, day and night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first time I came to your home after being admitted to Fudan University, you came out of the study. Because you still retained the memories from ten years ago, you looked much older and had less hair, but your eyes Still energetic. I said, I came too late, I should have come ten years ago. You immediately said with a smile on your face, it&#39;s not too late, I just started at your age. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first year, you asked me to translate the papers of Japanese scholars in conjunction with foreign language learning. Before submitting the completed translation, you asked me to write a translator&#39;s note. For those few hundred words of notes, you revised it four or five times. Through repeated frustrations, I began to slowly understand what &quot;negative rhetoric&quot; is. When you finally changed the schedule, you smiled and said gently that it seemed that you had been away from school for too long and you were no longer in the mood. But it doesn’t matter, just start slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of the first school year, you asked me to go to the library to borrow different versions of &quot;Jiankang Records&quot; and use my summer vacation time to do the revision. After school started, I reported the findings of the review to you, and you seemed very happy. I remember when my wife came over to pour us water, you turned around and said to your wife seriously, &quot;Ji Zhongping is very attentive. I have read this book so many times, but I didn&#39;t see many of the problems he found.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/TwzgBI2zDO3U2Oc4bzNaQFJrUsHg4ccOFXYQFWid.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;843&quot; height= &quot;723&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/TwzgBI2zDO3U2Oc4bzNaQFJrUsHg4ccOFXYQFWid.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257544&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Qing Yi Xun Tang published &quot;Jiankang Record&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I came to Fudan again to study for a Ph.D., it was the first time I talked about choosing a doctoral thesis topic. You introduced what you discovered. A category of words created using classic sentences. I blurted out that the use of such words should be to make the rhetoric more elegant. After hearing this, you patted your thigh with an exaggerated movement that was completely beyond my expectation and said, Great, this understanding is great, this is your invention. Well, let&#39;s call this type of words Yayan words, and you can do this topic. The next day, I went to class in the liberal arts building and saw my senior who had just finished class and said to me, the teacher said in class that you have an important invention. A few days later, I met a friend from East China Normal University and told me that Teacher Wu went to their school for a meeting and said at the meeting that I had an amazing invention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In those years when I was studying at Fudan, after having long conversations with you, on the way back to school late at night, I would always stand up and pedal my bike hard, eager to sit down at my desk the next second. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was a teenager, I read books such as &quot;The Detectives of Sherlock Holmes&quot; and &quot;Three Heroes and Five Righteousnesses&quot;. I imagined that when I grew up, I could become a detective who pursues the truth and an impartial judge. However, I realized that this was unrealistic when I became an adult. . You taught me how to do collation and exegesis, and how to make reliable inferences through thorough investigation and meticulous analysis. I will pursue the truth relentlessly and base myself on the facts without any compromise. Everything depends on me. Discovering a typo is like exposing a villain; restoring an original word is like clearing up an unjust case. Sitting at my desk late at night, I felt like Sherlock Holmes sitting in a carriage on his way to investigate a case, or like Bao Zheng sitting in the lobby of the Kaifeng government office. I don’t have any great talents to gain wealth in the world, nor do I have any ambition to achieve greatness in the world. When I come to this world, I have to live in a certain way. If I can live my life with this feeling besides being harmless to humans and animals. I have been content for the rest of my life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I remember one time, when I said goodbye to you and said I was leaving because a friend had an appointment to play football, you asked me, does football really fascinate you so much? At the time I just said yes. I didn&#39;t tell you that day why I never tire of football, because it was the only relatively fair game I could participate in. On our court, there are only simple and clear rules, relying only on one&#39;s own skills and efforts, everything is under the sun, and all power and influence are meaningless. I don&#39;t know any skills other than poetry, I just like to participate in this kind of game with my own ability and enthusiasm. Only this kind of game can allow me to truly feel the joy of life, even though no one cheers, there is no income, and there is even the risk of breaking my muscles and bones at any time. I am very superficial, and my understanding of knowledge is no different from playing football. Although I still play football twice a week to this day, I know very well that in my lifetime, my strength and speed will gradually fade away. One day, I will no longer be able to run as much as I want on the court. However, even then, , I can still continue to experience the same fun on my desk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I first met you, I brought you some tea. You told me seriously that this would never happen again. We don’t need this when we get along. If you can write an article and show it to me, that would be better than giving me anything. From then on, all I can think of in return is to write something to you. In the days I spent with you, I don’t remember saying any words of gratitude in front of you in a serious manner. You passed away suddenly in June 2013. I rushed back to Shanghai from Kyoto. I came down from your house alone late that night and sat in the small garden next to the building. I regretted that I had not had time to say many things to you in person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t know if we can meet again in another world in the future. If not, then we will never have the chance to say those words in person, so I have no choice but to write the above words. Although It&#39;s just a very small part of it. If you have a soul, you will surely understand what I mean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/308zXIMnik3dYv81fwpnBsMOKS9TN8ELyu6dHtcC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1242&quot; height= &quot;847&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/308zXIMnik3dYv81fwpnBsMOKS9TN8ELyu6dHtcC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Jinhua and Mr. Jao Tsung-I (left), taken in 1993. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by He Lingxia)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to gratitude, there is also an apology. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although my lifestyle has changed completely since I came to Fudan to study, some of the beliefs I formed since I was a student at Nanjing Normal University have not changed. Those beliefs may just be a joke in the eyes of others today, but I am willing to stick to them for life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was studying for a master&#39;s degree at Fudan University, the Institute of Ancient Books Collation held a meeting for students to evaluate scholarships. The meeting had a section that was equivalent to self-declaration. The students who spoke in front talked about what they had done and what they had published, and they talked very enthusiastically. Although I have done some research and published papers in journals, I cannot speak like they did. Seeing that it was almost my turn, I stood up quickly, picked up the blank form that was given to me, handed it to the teacher who was hosting the meeting, and said that I was ashamed and felt that I could not compare with them, so I quit first. The next day, you called my dormitory and told me seriously that as long as you applied, you would have won at least the second prize. This is very important, don’t do this next time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, I still don’t think this is important. My idea is very simple, because I didn’t win this award, I got through with it. What kind of honor can there be for an award that requires application only? After the doctoral thesis was written, you told me twice that after the defense, we would go to the Academy of Social Sciences to apply for the Lu Shuxiang Award, or go to Peking University to apply for the Wang Li Award. The first time I pretended not to hear, but the second time I told you clearly that I would not apply. When I was studying for a PhD at Fudan University, I won the highest award in liberal arts, but I never thought about applying. You applied privately on my behalf. You suddenly called me after 11 o&#39;clock the next night and told me that you had applied for me, and now you only need me to go to the award meeting the next day to make an introduction. I hesitated for a while and reluctantly agreed. Of course I know this is all your hard work, and I really can&#39;t bear to disobey you late at night. The next day I only used half of the allotted time and ended my uncomfortable self-cutting hastily. When I left the venue, I felt relaxed all over. I didn&#39;t care whether I won an award or not. I just felt that I had gone through this process, which was more or less an explanation to you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although I like football very much, I rarely take the initiative to ask people to play football. Because I don&#39;t like others to accompany me reluctantly because of my invitation. I don’t like the state of being in my heart but not in my heart, and I certainly don’t want my friends to be like this. The games we play are just a bunch of ragtag games, but everyone is united physically and mentally. It is a game without any dirty things other than football. Although my technical level is limited, I thought I was enjoying the real joy of gaming. Any association with anything other than football would probably make me feel uncomfortable. It makes me feel a little sad to think that one day we all in this world will inevitably end in clouds and rain. However, I am not depressed at all when I think that all the hard work I have done will eventually be wiped out. Every run, every pass, every shot, while doing your best, the fun is in it. The moment I came off the field, I had finished enjoying football. In the days to come, if you tell me how I was in that game, I actually feel nothing. I rarely remember what kind of goals I have scored, even if they were just played yesterday. What I never forget every day is just where to start the next game. I have little knowledge and cannot give any lofty meaning to my profession. I just hope that the research I engage in can be as pure as football. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VRZYDxiw00rhnLfbpNMeNxJZTtpKlMrnQUwItYFq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;531&quot; height= &quot;742&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/VRZYDxiw00rhnLfbpNMeNxJZTtpKlMrnQUwItYFq.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Jinhua graduated from the Chinese Department of Nanjing Normal University in 1966. In 1968, he was assigned to teach in a middle school in Ganyu County, Xuzhou area. In 1978, he returned to his alma mater and studied the history of Chinese under the tutelage of Mr. Xu Fu. After graduating in 1981, he stayed at the school to teach. In 1986, he won the second prize of the Young Linguist Award of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences. In 1991, he was promoted to professor. In 1995, he was transferred to Fudan University. Institute of Collation of Ancient Books, author of &quot;Exegesis of the Chronicles of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, &quot;Research and Interpretation of Shishuoxinyu&quot;, &quot;A Series of Research on Ancient Documents&quot;, &quot;A Series of Research on the Chronicles of the Three Kingdoms&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I quit my original job when I came to study for a Ph.D. During the holiday in early October of the first semester, you asked me to go to your house for dinner. During this period, you asked me if I have any requirements for my workplace after graduation. I said it didn&#39;t matter to me, as long as I had a bite to eat. You said, then see if you are willing to stay. I said of course that&#39;s good, so I can always be by your side. Then you said that you believed that I would have no problems with my business, but you hoped that I could do some things outside of business to ensure that I could stay. I told you on the spot that I didn&#39;t want to. I just wanted to make a living based on my own ability. You mentioned it twice after that, and I explicitly rejected it both times. The last time, I even said that if I had to do that to stay, then I would go somewhere else. If I have to do academic work that way, then I would rather live on the streets pulling a cart and carrying bags. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I know that&#39;s arrogant and rude to say. In fact, I have never seen and can&#39;t imagine anyone talking to you like that. Of course I fully understand that you have my life in mind, but if I do what you say, I will have trouble sleeping at night. These beliefs have been rooted in my heart since I was a teacher in Nanjing. They are the promises I made to myself. Even when I was dissolute, I never violated them at all. Perhaps, for others, there shouldn&#39;t be any doubts about doing something like that, because everyone does it, but I am me, and in my opinion, no matter how many people do it, it is impossible to change this kind of thing. nature, I cannot deceive myself, so I am willing to accept the life I choose. I think if the research we did is credible, it must be the only judgment made based on real materials and strict logic. The beliefs I adhere to are the same kind of non-dual judgment. It is impossible for me to change because of the intervention of anyone other than facts and logic, not even you. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You are very strict with students. My wife once told me privately that even several older doctoral students were scolded by you until they cried in front of them. I don’t know why you are so tolerant to me. You have never spoken harshly, so that I have the confidence to speak freely in front of you again and again, especially for those beliefs that are ridiculous in the eyes of others, but you always smile gently and make some remarks. Advice, and ultimately make it clear that you respect my choice. I admit that if you were still alive, I still would not apologize to you for things like the above. Because although I am stubborn, during the time when I was studying with you, I regarded you as the judge of this world to a certain extent. I need to state the facts clearly to you, and then get a fair ruling from you. . It&#39;s not that I don&#39;t respect you, but I&#39;m afraid that my apology will change your original decision. In my opinion, such a change of judgment, even if it is beneficial to me, no longer has the meaning of a ruling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It has been ten years since you went to another world, and I no longer need you to make any judgments. Therefore, please accept my apology now. I apologize to you for all my past arrogance. Apologize. Forgive me, more than 20 years ago, I just wanted to go back to the peach blossom land I once had. I didn’t know it at that time. Things have changed, and the place I yearned for has already kept pace with the times. But I have always been like that warrior who is searching for a sword, stubbornly guarding that place. mark. Forgive me, I don’t want to live just for food, that’s no different than a dolphin or a dog. I want a life with wine. The gentle smile you show in the face of those unbridled smiles is a great comfort to an inappropriately lonely student. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People often say that once you are a teacher, you will always be a father. This is just a matter of etiquette, because how much emotion can be created in a day&#39;s interaction. Deep feelings are the accumulation of emotions generated after long-term mutual understanding. I know there are teachers who are different from you, but for more than ten years, you are the only one to me. To this day, I still feel lucky that on that spring afternoon twenty-six years ago, when I said goodbye to comfort and wanted to start another kind of growth, you adopted me, just like a father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[药品集采12小时：“割肉”也不想丢标]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260396]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2bf7fc80a8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2bf7fc80a8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257839&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;This collective purchase 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased, and the prices of the selected drugs were reduced by an average of 58%, the second largest price reduction in history. Visual China | Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;If the company&#39;s market share in the next four years was determined within 12 hours, how would you choose? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the morning of Monday, November 6, 2023, the temperature in Shanghai dropped sharply, but there were crowds of people outside the Fengxian District Conference Center and the discussion was lively. The ninth batch of centralized bulk procurement of state-organized drugs is underway here, and representatives of various pharmaceutical companies carrying sealed quotation information materials are waiting anxiously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;We have ten manufacturers bidding together for our drug varieties, and the competition is fierce, (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai , STKaiti;&quot;>;Long procurement cycle&lt;/span>;) is both a temptation and a challenge. I personally think it will prompt companies to further lower their quotations.&quot; A representative of a pharmaceutical company from Shangqiu, Henan told a reporter from Southern Weekend that the company is It was my first time to participate in the national centralized drug procurement, and I started preparing for this round of application since passing the consistency evaluation half a year ago. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Starting at eight o&#39;clock, business representatives poured into the first floor of the conference center. Within 12 hours, a total of 382 products from 262 companies participated in the bidding. The staff of the notary office will unseal, announce and read out the product specifications and quotations of each pharmaceutical company one by one, and then release the list of proposed winners; the proposed pharmaceutical companies will then Transfer to another hotel conference center to wait - enter into groups according to the order of drugs, and select and confirm the supply area in the next four-year procurement cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed that there were pharmaceutical distribution, local state-owned enterprises and other related enterprises inside and outside the site eagerly waiting for the event. Although these companies themselves are not participating in this collective purchase, they are also looking forward to the results of the ninth batch of collective purchases, especially if they can collide with some cooperation opportunities with the selected pharmaceutical companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At about 19:00 on November 6, the National Medical Insurance Administration announced that 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased in this centralized purchase, and the average price of the selected drugs was reduced by 58%. It can save 18.2 billion yuan in drug costs every year - the second largest price reduction in history, second only to the previous record high of the first national procurement after the 4+7 pilot (59%). &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Once the bid is lost, it will be &quot;sidelined&quot; for the next four years&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;The ninth batch of centralized procurement It covers medications for common and chronic diseases such as infections, tumors, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, gastrointestinal diseases, and mental illnesses, as well as key drugs such as emergency drugs and shortage drugs. At present, during the period of high incidence of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection, the much-anticipated azithromycin oral suspension is also on the list of this centralized purchase. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;What is different from the first eight batches of centralized procurement is that once selected, the procurement cycle will be extended from two years to four years, that is, from the implementation date to December 2027 March 31st. This is more attractive to pharmaceutical companies than in previous years. On the morning of November 6, many business representatives kept discussing the topic of extending the procurement cycle while waiting for declarations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;While waiting, a representative of a Jiangxi pharmaceutical company looked embarrassed while holding a thick stack of written documents. &quot;During the eighth batch of collective purchases, we did not win the selection for an exclusive product with a high market share, and most of the volume on the market was &#39;divided up&#39; by several successful bidders. Therefore, we participated in this collective purchase, even if we &#39;cut the meat&#39; We don’t want to lose the bid, we have to keep the production line.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Liu Hengwei, deputy general manager of the marketing center of Zhonghuan Pharmaceutical Group Co., Ltd., introduced to Southern Weekend reporters that the three projects they applied for Two products are planned to be selected. “Both are new products that have just been introduced into the Chinese market, and are also recommended drugs in the diagnosis and treatment guidelines. Although the current market sales are not large, it is expected to have a large growth in the next four years. Taking into account the patient Drug accessibility and hospitals will give priority to the centralized procurement of drugs from the winning bidders, and we have shown the greatest sincerity for this centralized procurement.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Jiang Changsong, assistant to the dean of the National Medical Insurance Research Institute of Capital Medical University and director of the price procurement office, said that the procurement cycle of centralized procurement has been extended to four years for the first time, further ensuring The stability of drug use in medical institutions also means that if pharmaceutical companies &quot;lose their bids&quot;, they will have to watch their huge market share &quot;sideline&quot; in the next four years. &quot;National centralized drug procurement means large and stable quantities, and the supply cycle To ensure long-term growth, companies must exchange prices for volume and ensure supply.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to a report from the National Medical Insurance Administration, among the pharmaceutical companies participating in this centralized procurement, 266 products from 205 companies have been qualified for selection, including 200 domestic companies. 260 products from pharmaceutical companies and 6 products from 5 international pharmaceutical companies (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family : KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Including 1 original research drug and 5 imported generic drugs&lt;/span>;), the proportion of bidding companies planning to be selected is about 78%, with an average of 6.5 companies planning to be selected for each variety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Amiodarone injection to treat arrhythmia, dopamine injection to rescue shock, oxytocin injection to induce labor, etc. 5 kinds of shortage medicines and emergency rescue For pharmaceuticals, we use the &quot;volume-driven&quot; procurement method to stabilize corporate expectations and achieve a balance between multiple goals of ensuring supply and reasonably reducing prices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/065d42ac9d. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/065d42ac9d.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257840&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the morning of November 6, 2023, representatives of pharmaceutical companies submitted application materials on the first floor of the Fengxian District Conference Center in Shanghai. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Fierce battle: The battle for pharmaceutical companies’ supply areas&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;November On the morning of the 6th, after the acceptance of application materials and the disclosure of application information ended, the companies to be selected could not relax their nerves because they would face another &quot;fierce battle&quot; that afternoon - the selection and confirmation of supply areas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;According to the &quot;National Drug Centralized Procurement Document&quot; released by the National Drug Joint Procurement Office on October 13, 2023, the companies to be selected must first determine their main suppliers. Region, the first-ranked company will give priority to selecting one region among the supply regions. All companies to be selected will confirm the remaining regions in order. Each company will select one region at a time. Repeat the above process until all region selections are confirmed. The selection process for the reserve area is similar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;At the same time, the purchase quantities of all drugs in different specifications in various provinces and regions are also announced, which can be used by applying companies to formulate constituency strategies accordingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;On the afternoon of November 6, two large conference rooms were prepared at the constituency site, one for business representatives to wait, and the other for confirming supply area information . The organizer calls the numbers one by one according to the drug types, and after checking the ID cards and authorization letters, the companies enter the selection areas in groups. This process starts around 14:00 that day and continues until the evening. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Tian Yong, executive deputy general manager of Qilu Pharmaceutical Group Sales Corporation, told Southern Weekend reporters that there are multiple considerations for corporate constituencies. “First look at the donor district hospital report. How big the volume is? Secondly, it depends on the market capacity of the province. Thirdly, it depends on the importance that enterprises attach to different regions. For example, enterprises tend to choose Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou to enhance brand awareness. For example, our Shandong enterprises certainly want to choose the area at their doorstep, but they also Maybe he wasn’t selected and was picked by a company with a higher ranking.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Some business representatives also mentioned that some western provinces may not be popular in the electoral process due to low reporting volume and high distribution costs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters noticed at the scene that after the first round of companies entered the conference hall to select areas, it took more than an hour for people to come out one after another. Representatives of pharmaceutical companies should adjust their constituency plans in a timely manner based on the conditions of their competitors. Someone not only recorded his own district selection, but also made notes on the district selection of other companies. The filled-in notes attracted onlookers. People competed to take photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Determining the main drug supply and supply areas is largely to avoid situations where the centralized procurement of drugs cannot be supplied in sufficient quantity in time or the selected company is disqualified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Starting from this year (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Collection of medicines to ensure supply&lt;/span >;) Judging from the situation, it is much better than before.&quot; Gao Xiaoyan, deputy director of Shanghai No. 7 People&#39;s Hospital, told Southern Weekend reporters. Zhang Lan, director of the Pharmacy Department of Xuanwu Hospital of Capital Medical University (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;hereinafter referred to as Xuanwu Hospital&lt;/span>;), also said that hospitals all hope to collect drugs collectively Achieving quality and quantity supply requires the guarantee of a long-term mechanism, including the supervision and evaluation of winning bidders by relevant departments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/fc7500b81f. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/fc7500b81f.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;257841&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;From the afternoon to the evening of November 6, 2023, the companies to be selected will enter the venue in groups according to drug types and select supply areas. Photo by Southern Weekend reporter Huang Sizhuo&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Scientific and rational use of drugs attract attention&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;National Drugs From the beginning, centralized purchasing focused on large varieties, and now it has progressed to include all varieties that are clinically deemed necessary. In the implementation of each batch, Ruijin Hospital covers a relatively large number of varieties. So far, it has The procurement cycle of the first five batches of centralized medicines has been completed, and the sixth batch is in progress.&quot; Ruijin Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 毷体, 毷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;The following Bian Xiaolan, director of the Pharmacy Department of Ruijin Hospital, said that medical institutions are now very concerned about how to use drugs more scientifically and rationally in the next step. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Since 2018, the National Medical Insurance Administration has organized nine batches of national drug procurement, including a total of 374 kinds of drugs, with an average reduction of more than 50%. Zhang Lan, director of the Pharmacy Department of Xuanwu Hospital, said that centralized purchasing has been carried out on a regular basis, and clinicians have been observing the efficacy of centralized purchasing of generic drugs for some time. On the basis of respecting the patient&#39;s wishes, doctors will combine the diagnosis and treatment guidelines and the patient&#39;s condition to provide patients with Choose the right medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;In response to some voices saying that generic drugs selected through centralized purchasing may not be as effective as original drugs, Xuanwu Hospital has led a number of hospitals with strong research capabilities to conduct centralized purchasing and selection in batches. Real-world research on generic drugs. A recently published study covering 29 medical institutions in 16 provinces across the country and about 140,000 real cases showed that the clinical efficacy and safety of generic drugs selected through centralized procurement are equivalent to those of the original drugs (see Southern Weekend’s October 22 report for details&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/content/259061&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;140,000 cases, 2-year PK, centralized purchasing of generic drugs What is the efficacy and safety?》&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&quot;Currently, (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;generic drugs and Original drugs&lt;/span>;) differences are within controllable range. Moreover, the drug configuration of different hospitals will be slightly different according to the actual situation. Our hospital tends to be equipped with both centralized drugs and original drugs, with the patient as the center and combining their needs. The medication plan will be comprehensively considered based on disease progression, past medication, etc.,&quot; Bian Xiaolan told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Ruijin Hospital selected endocrine metabolism-related drugs and cardiovascular and cerebrovascular drugs based on clinical characteristics, and participated in the second and third batches of national centralized procurement led by Xuanwu Hospital. Real-world studies of generic pharmaceuticals. Bian Xiaolan said that there are now more and more evaluation systems and tools. For example, Shanghai is developing a comprehensive drug clinical evaluation management system, and relevant research will be announced in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;Zhang Lan introduced that real-world research on the fourth and fifth batches of generic drugs selected by the national centralized procurement has been launched, and the original data collection and reporting process will be more perfect in the future. Provide evidence-based support for clinical medication. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[危险的快递驿站：一场不该发生的意外]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260347]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh20BlLq.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;589&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N5YkULYLq9jNkIX0wTWMi96cfPWbob8frh2 0BlLq. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257425&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;The doctor asked us to prepare for the worst&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At noon on August 25, 2023, Zhang Xiang, who was on a business trip, received When I got the call that my wife was injured and rushed back to Taiyuan, Shanxi Province, it was already past two o&#39;clock in the afternoon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The son was sitting on an iron chair in the waiting area, keeping his mother&#39;s mobile phone, myopia glasses, and the pair of white sandals that he had thrown off when he fell from the second floor. Lin Mei was lying on the hospital bed with her eyes open and her face pale. She was soon sent to the intensive care unit (ICU). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At noon that day, Lin Mei had cut the vegetables. The message pushed by the Tmall APP on her mobile phone showed that the plasticine purchased online for her son had arrived at the Cainiao Station near the community. She put down the kitchen knife, casually wore a pair of jeans and a pair of white sandals, and took her son out to pick up the express delivery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If everything goes well, she will pick up the express delivery and return home in 10 minutes and prepare lunch. They had just moved into this new house. The developer called them and asked them to apply for the real estate certificate together. Unfortunately, the housing management center was off work at that time, so they agreed to do it as soon as they got back from a business trip.她和丈夫是高中同学，相识20年，结婚十几年，一起打拼到现在终于有了车、房和一个10岁的儿子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/XDoKyf0VCRkVxzDMXS5GOeXxesJwNDsQkEqXLNLT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257424&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;该驿站一楼为便利店，二楼为菜鸟驿站&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从后来的监控视频可以看到，取件时，林梅一边看着手机上的取件码，一边在货架上找快递，根本没有注意到，脚下还有一个敞开的洞，她侧身寻找快递时不幸掉入脚下的洞中。洞口是老板平时用来上下货的，从二楼洞口到一楼地面高度为2.8米，洞口通常应该关闭，但事发时没有及时关上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这家菜鸟驿站用钢架和钢板结构把一个商铺的空间隔为两层，一楼是便利店卖水果蔬菜，二楼取快递，通常需要自己到二楼找件，自助扫码取件。快递驿站和便利店是同一个老板。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据驿站老板描述，他也曾从洞口掉下去过，当时不小心闪了一下摔下去，只是腿受伤休养了一段时间。 “他是有心理防备的，但是我老婆没有任何心理防备，她掉下去的时候完全懵了，根本不知道发生了什么。”张象说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/kfdZphizaHPVMJWTrk5cPH6efEvZRCli8mSXPNIH.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257427&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在病床上的林梅&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在ICU门外，张象写了几行关于“勿念”的纸条让护士送进去，又在纸上空白处补充“每天下午五点可以探视”，画上两个笑脸，附带一支笔让林梅可以写点什么。后来纸条送出来的时候，纸是湿的，没有字。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;生命体征稳定以后，陆续做了三场手术，出现各种并发症，肺炎、泌尿系统感染、压疮、血栓，“四大并发症占全了，每天都有新的挑战。”张象在一个多月的时间里瘦了十多斤，“太痛苦了！”他描述，治疗血栓的过滤器，做的时候从大腿植入到血管，取的时候从脖子上取出来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一次大手术，是颈椎手术，张象印象深刻。他记得林梅从手术室出来的时候，她躺着，但表情放松，面带笑容，“因为觉得手术终于做完了，觉得可能很有希望，可能很快就能好了。”后来，这样的笑容越来越少。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山西医科大学第二医院康复医学科主治医生张昱告诉《南方人物周刊》，林梅在摔落的过程中，头撞到侧边的墙壁上，颈椎骨折造成的颈部脊髓损伤，导致四肢瘫痪。下肢完全不能活动，上肢活动很差。双腿的感觉和运动都处于丧失状态。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/JVTErMkRdKzy4ydSv204lcLnYPl29jUPLU2h6P5Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257428&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;林梅在ICU时，张象写的纸条&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他解释，颈脊髓是大脑脑干往躯体椎管内延续的一部分脑组织，受到损伤之后，不受大脑脑干支配，所以会出现瘫痪症状。脊髓损伤造成向大脑传输感觉的功能缺失，导致下级神经元会产生异常。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“医生让我们做好最坏的打算。”张象说，“太痛苦了，如果癌症是判了死刑，脊髓损伤就相当于凌迟。”林梅无法自主翻身，甚至不能动动脚趾，只有病理性的抽搐，神经无法自主控制，没有出汗功能，感知不到冷和热。她会突然之间颤抖，但不觉得冷。有时候又觉得特别冷，像在冰天雪地里一样，实际上被子盖得好好的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上肢力量小，拿不住碗筷，只能喂饭吃。张象在医院附近租了一个房子，给爱人做饭，平时家属和护工轮换照顾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张昱表示，完全性脊髓损伤恢复希望非常小，几乎是没有希望恢复。 “林梅目前来看是完全性损伤的状态，双腿恢复的难度非常大，但是在时间上还不能下定论。我们医院一般是3个月左右，如果3个月后还是这样的体征症状的话，就可以下定论了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，林梅累计治疗费用已超18万元，未来还将有很多开支。而在多次沟通下，截至目前菜鸟方面仅支付了2万元，菜鸟驿站店主支付了3.5万元。事发之后一个多月内，这家菜鸟驿站还在正常营业，甚至那个洞还在使用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一场不该发生的意外，彻底改变了一个家庭的命运和一位37岁女性的人生，儿子刚上小学五年级，而她的下半生都有可能将在病床上度过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;意外背后暴露出快递驿站模式存在的诸多隐患。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;危险的发生：菜鸟驿站是如何运营的？ &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;某县城菜鸟驿站老板告诉《南方人物周刊》，自己的这家店于两年前开设，店内另有两位亲属帮忙，“正常驿站两三个人就够了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据他描述，菜鸟不收取加盟费，开一家菜鸟驿站的前期投入并不算高：需要到菜鸟官方购置扫描枪、工作台、云监控、货架等设备，成本约为1万元左右；再加上保证金3000元、门面租金、水电费，基本上开一家菜鸟驿站的成本在3万元左右。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在店铺审核上，“需要在看好地方和房子之后，在网上提交申请，店铺的要求不严格，申请好了之后他们会过来看。之后直接去跟快递员或者快递公司片区负责人谈好价格就可以。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;驿站的收入来源，主要是跟快递公司合作，由快递公司支付给驿站老板派送费及寄件收入。菜鸟驿站官方网站显示，每件快递的派送费为0.5-1元，寄件收入为3-5元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;驿站模式之所以覆盖迅速，也与快递行业愈演愈烈的价格战相关。快递公司用价格换规模，必然影响利润，导致网点派送费降低，利润空间进一步被压缩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为节约“最后一公里”的末端配送成本，快递驿站可谓应运而生。中国物流协会调查数据显示，末端配送成本占物流行业总成本的30%以上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈君曾是某电商平台旗下自营快递的网点经营者，负责“最后一公里”的末端配送，“公司确实下了不少本。”她提到，快递公司负责租房费用和电费水费，并免费配备电脑设备、安装摄像头，需要发该网点3个人的基本工资，之外还需要付每个快件的派送费，经营者只需要交一笔保证金。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她和亲戚经营该网点约6年时间，派送费从最早的4元，逐渐减少到1.5元、1元。在该店内，两个人负责送快递，一个人守店，负责分件、寄快递、处理退货等工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个客户他们都会送货上门，挨个打电话。凌晨4点多，需要起床去高速路口接快递，然后回来卸货、扫码分件。每天的件必须当天派送完，直接面对消费者，会碰到各种不同的情况，想做好这份工作，必须要有很强的服务意识。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，这家电商平台因物流成本高而关停了旗下的自营快递公司，陈君便也不再经营。 “相比我们以前做的那些，现在这种快递驿站模式确实给快递公司省了不少成本，节省了快递员的精力，但对用户来说没以前方便了。”末端配送从快递公司全盘负责，变成了驿站老板自负盈亏。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;行业竞争激烈，快递驿站的品牌越来越多，极兔速递驿站、圆通妈妈驿站、中通兔喜生活……甚至一个社区会出现多个快递驿站，有网友以自身经历吐槽：“因为小区比较大，取6个快递，竟然在6个不同的驿站。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;派送费也在持续下跌，《南方人物周刊》采访的两位菜鸟驿站的老板表示，在他们所在区域，派送费分别只有每单0.3元、0.5元，均比几年前的价格有所下跌。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我家小区菜鸟驿站两年都换了七八个老板了。”一位网友表示，这种驿站的转让费一般并不低，亦出现驿站老板靠转让费“割一波韭菜”的情况——靠经营驿站赚的钱还没有转让费赚得多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此时，经营副业便成了一个能够增加收入来源的选择。根据菜鸟驿站官网，其在介绍“菜鸟驿站是怎么赚钱的？”中提到：除了稳定的派费收入之外，依靠驿站带来的固定人流量，可以经营副业、售卖生活用品快销品等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但问题也在于，作为高频的生活场景，快递服务关键的“最后一公里”，店主若不能投入足够的精力，便难以保证服务质量。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;林梅出事的菜鸟驿站便是如此。在这家店里，驿站成了副业，主业是蔬果超市。 “大家既然都要来，这是一个天然的引流渠道，所以他们把蔬菜水果放到一层，取快递在二层，且是自助的。”张象提到。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUUOJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/08/N3z3pDzDqzSqcLFYMT3B9xY3ASxWwAn28ViUUOJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257426&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在钢架结构私自开“洞”，存在安全隐患。事发时“洞”为敞开状态，林梅从中掉落&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;被诟病的加盟模式以及法律风险&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;国家邮政局的数据显示，2010年至2022年，我国快递业务量规模增长了47.3倍，电商的快速发展给快递业带来了巨量的需求增长，快递驿站模式应运而生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;京东从2007年开始自建物流，凭借自有物流的优质服务赢得了客户的口碑。阿里深知自建物流所要耗费的成本高昂，为了提升平台的快递服务质量，它于2013年联合零售、地产、物流等企业打造菜鸟网络，其模式较轻，定位是物流体系中的“数据中枢”，即物流平台，采用加盟模式，菜鸟公司不承担驿站具体的运营成本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时，马云还曾表态“绝对不做物流”，这对于发展淘宝、天猫和拉拢物流公司起到了作用，得以进一步掌握物流环节的话语权。菜鸟既有阿里电商提供的流量，又具备稳定的物流配送网络。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据阿里2023财年年报，菜鸟集团成为阿里巴巴集团内增长速度最高的业务，收入为556.81亿元，同比增长21%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年9月26日，菜鸟智慧物流网络有限公司正式向港交所提交上市申请，成为阿里“1+6+N”组织变革以来首个正式开启IPO进程的业务集团。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8年前，菜鸟在安徽芜湖推出首个提供快递代收服务的“菜鸟驿站”。招股书显示，菜鸟如今在全球已有380多个物流分拨中心和17万个驿站，运营着全球最大的菜鸟驿站网络，日均处理包裹超8000万个。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种加盟模式也引来争议，其本意是为消费者提供多元化的最后一公里服务，提高配送效率，但也极易出现相互推卸责任的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毕竟，快递公司只负责到驿站这一环，而驿站直接赚的是快递公司的钱，而不是赚消费者的钱，菜鸟和消费者之间不存在直接的交易关系。菜鸟具有品牌影响力，但难以对每家加盟驿站严格监管，因此就难以让客户获得较好的服务体验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;快递驿站模式本身也存在一定的法律风险。国务院2018年发布的《快递暂行条例》第二十五条规定，从事快递业务的企业应当将快递投递到约定的地址、收件人或者收件人指定的收件人，并告知收件人或者收件人当面验收。收件人或代理人有权当面验收。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，在驿站模式下，很难做到送货上门。上述县城菜鸟驿站老板表示，的确有不少送货上门的诉求，“都可以送，现在如果说驿站不送的话，可能就落到快递公司上面了。快递公司让快递员给他派送，后续投诉驿站的话会有罚款。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在社交平台，有用户表示“投诉也没用，会被驿站拉黑名单，以后就不给你入库了，每次都从驿站返到快递网点，你的快递总会比别人的慢，目前来说没有什么有效的方法。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;京衡律师事务所合伙人钱颖刚告诉《南方人物周刊》，未经消费者同意，快递公司无权将消费者购买的商品放入快递驿站。消费者通过网络签订的电子商务合同，约定以包邮或支付邮费的方式将购买的商品运送至指定的地址，“快递公司如果未经消费者同意擅自更改送达地点或送达方式构成违约，应当承担继续履行合同或其他补救方式，并承担违约责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对驿站监管不力带来的安全隐患，后果则更为严重。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在菜鸟驿站官网，提到驿站店铺的具体要求为：位于一楼（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;与马路平行&lt;/span>;），写字楼、商业体不限楼层。但林梅出事的驿站并未遵守此要求，私自搭建钢架结构，且在经营时间内未受到菜鸟公司的监管和整改。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“消费者完全不知道，总公司跟网点之间是什么关系，只知道菜鸟是个大公司，去取件，完全是天猫后台给我们推送的信息，这里是公共经营场所，但完全没有安全保障可言，导致了悲剧的发生。”张象说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钱颖刚表示，在林梅事件中，“在加盟情况下，从保护消费者角度考虑，按特许经营来理解，特许人和加盟店应当对外承担连带责任。驿站老板因为自身的疏忽、过失，在服务过程中导致损害他人后果的，赔偿责任一般来说不能免除。在未经消费者同意的情况下，快递公司也应当承担共同侵权责任。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;坠落之后&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;每天一觉醒来是张象最痛苦的时刻，会觉得这是真的吗？如果是一个梦该多好。可现实如此残酷且真实。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但他需要振作精神，在爱人抑郁、崩溃大哭的时候给她安慰。他在床边给林梅读苏东坡的诗词，读史铁生的文章，告诉她一个人的命运不可能是完美的，总会有一些坎坷曲折。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两个多月以来，林梅大部分时间都在病房躺着，偶尔可以看到窗户外面的云，“你看外面的云越来越多。”她望着云，对张象说。这让他想起过去的某个普通的日子，两个人一起散步时，林梅会说：“你看天上的云，其实我们一起在外面走一走，看看天上的云，吹吹大自然的风就很幸福了。”张象说，“现在想来那个时候是最幸福的，但那时候我还不以为然。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在张象眼里，林梅是一个特别简单、很会操持家务的人，只有她知道家里所有物品的摆放位置。出事之后刚开始一段时间，张象回家住过一晚，但“完全睡不着，每天晚上都很难受，看到家里所有的地方都是她的痕迹，都是她的影子，我完全没办法睡觉。在出租屋里，陌生的地方反而好一些”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;自从在一起以来，每年过生日的时候，林梅都会亲自给张象包饺子吃。不久前，张象生日，林梅对他说，“今天不能给你包饺子了。”“后来我妈包饺子，我回家取来，她也没吃多少，只吃了五六个。”张象回忆。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出差之前，张象去超市买了条鲫鱼，做了一道林梅最喜欢吃的鲫鱼豆腐汤。他记得那天林梅特别开心地吃完了，把他的皮鞋拿出来擦，黑皮鞋的白边擦得雪白，“像新买的一样。”张象叹口气，“等我赶回来以后，看到这双鞋边还是白的，但是人已不是以前了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张昱提到，在医院，黄金康复期是3-6个月。如果长期瘫痪，难以避免的并发症是心肺功能的降低，如果没有经济上的压力，可以做一些康复训练，用可动肢体去代偿失控肢体在生活工作上的一些训练，使身体的其他机能维持在一定的水平。后续护理、家庭康复阶段对照顾者的要求较高，家人和陪护人员需要付出很大的辛苦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我曾经承诺带她去一些地方，本来计划今年要去的，不管以后恢复成什么样，哪怕是坐轮椅也要带她去，当然坐轮椅会很不方便，所以就想一定要把她尽量治好，要实现我对她的承诺。”张象说他会继续“讨个公道”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;身为青年作家的张象，8月份有一本新书出版，林梅出事后出版社给他快递样书，他发现自己还只能去菜鸟驿站取，“感觉我一辈子都不想再去那个地方，但是没有办法，必须去拿我的书，因为没有选择。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应采访对象要求，文中林梅、陈君化名。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[直男最爱的迪卡侬，靠卖一条裙子赚了几十亿？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;最近，在社交媒体上火了一款运动裙裤，让人意外的是，这条“神仙裙子”既不是中产必备的Lululemon，也不是耐克安德玛等知名品牌，而是广大直男的老朋友——迪卡侬。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一直以平价天堂和直男最爱著称的迪卡侬，这次为什么靠女性出圈了呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;数据显示，2022年至今，小红书上有关迪卡侬的笔记就已高达10w+，随着流量的激增，也带动了旗下女士产品的销量，据其淘宝官方旗舰店销量top5显示，排名最低的女性瑜伽裤都有高达3w+的销售量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年，迪卡侬年销售额达到140亿欧元，中国成为最大的海外市场之一，其中女性需求最为耀眼，在迪卡侬官方店中，女士产品数量约占半数。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这跟中国户外经济的发展有着密切的关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2020年中国户外用品市场规模达3150亿元，2025年预计达到5990亿元，与欧美国家相比，我国户外经济市场规模仍有较大发展空间。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;有调查显示，国内参与户外运动的群体主要为一线及新一线的青年女性，花得多、买得多、省得多成为当代女性旅游消费的三大特点，逐渐掀起小众运动之风。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所以，迪卡侬看到了“女性消费者+小众运动”的发展潜力，今天，“知道”带你探索迪卡侬的转型秘诀。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73293&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70108&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;封面.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/e8559b5769.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256944&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73287&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70102&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P2 .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2d7b8c0985.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256945&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73288&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70103&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1438&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/d50d46318f.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256946&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73289&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70104&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/01f97bd44a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256947&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73290&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70105&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/5b881cd6b2.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256948&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73291&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70106&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P6-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/8cfe4b8417.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256949&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73292&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70107&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;P7-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1440&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/2348f3fefa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256950&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[广东省卫健委党组书记、主任朱宏接受审查调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260404]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:55:20&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision: Zhu Hong, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission, is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law. He voluntarily surrendered and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and supervisory investigation by the Guangdong Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Zhu Hong’s resume&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Hong, male, Han nationality, born in September 1966, with an on-the-job postgraduate degree, started working in September 1982, and started working in March 1986. Joined the Chinese Communist Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He has successively served as member of the Party Committee and Vice President of Nanfang Hospital of Southern Medical University, director of the Guangdong Provincial Medical Academic Exchange Center, secretary of the Party Committee of Nanfang Hospital of Southern Medical University, and secretary and director of the Party Leadership Group of the Guangdong Provincial Health Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[探索宇宙中相互竞争的隐秘力量：欧几里得望远镜发布首批照片]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260406]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 09:14:03&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 7, 2023, Beijing time, the European Space Agency released the Euclid Telescope (Euclid) The first 5 full-color pictures taken. These images are the result of scientists&#39; preliminary processing of the first batch of data obtained by the Euclid Telescope, but they have already demonstrated the powerful observation capabilities of the telescope - no telescope has ever obtained such clear images across such a large area of ​​the sky before. image. They believe that this telescope is ready to create the largest three-dimensional map of the universe in history, helping us gain insights into the nature of dark matter and dark energy in the &quot;dark&quot; universe, thereby revealing the hidden secrets of the universe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Euclid is a famous ancient Greek mathematician and is known as the &quot;Father of Geometry&quot;. His &quot;Elements of Geometry&quot; has been passed down to the world and laid the foundation for the development of geometry for more than two thousand years. Foundation. Scientists now realize that the density of matter and energy is closely related to the geometry of the universe and determines its future. Therefore, the European Space Agency (ESA) decided to name the telescope that explores the structure and evolution of the universe after Euclid to commemorate the pioneer of geometry. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Five&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Key Questions&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the current mainstream cosmological theory, only 5% of the visible ordinary matter in the universe is , the remaining 95% includes 25% dark matter and 70% dark energy. Therefore, understanding the nature of dark matter and dark energy has become one of the most important issues in science today. The Euclid telescope is expected to play an important role in research in this area over the next decade and beyond. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With a range of up to 10 billion light-years, Euclid will observe billions of galaxies in more than 1/3 of the sky, creating a picture of the large-scale structure of the universe. picture. Scientists hope to study five key issues in cosmology by exploring the composition and evolution of the &quot;dark&quot; universe: the structure and evolutionary history of the cosmic web (matter in the universe is arranged in a huge network), what dark matter is, and the nature of the universe. How expansion changes over time, what the nature of dark energy is, and whether we really fully understand gravity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2007, researchers proposed two research plans in response to the European Space Agency&#39;s space exploration plan from 2015 to 2025, namely the &quot;Dark Universe Explorer&quot; (Dark Universe Explorer). DUNE) and the Spectroscopic All Sky Cosmic Explorer (SPACE). Both proposals propose complementary techniques to detect dark energy. After a period of evaluation and demonstration, the two plans were merged, and this became the later Euclid Telescope. In October 2011, the European Space Agency&#39;s Science Mission Committee selected the Euclid Telescope; in June 2012, the telescope project was officially established. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After more than ten years of demonstration, design, construction and testing, the Euclid Telescope is finally ready for use. On July 1, 2023, the Euclid Telescope was successfully launched from the Cape Canaveral Space Launch Site in Florida, USA, on board the Falcon 9 rocket of the US Space Exploration Company (SpaceX). At the end of July, the telescope flew near the Sun-Earth&#39;s second Lagrange point, about 1.5 million kilometers away from the Earth, and successfully entered its working orbit. The European Space Agency&#39;s Gaia telescope and NASA&#39;s James Webb Space Telescope are also in orbit around this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/JW8CkTtukg7yZWUPLmJPaITk0vHwhPz8wsvoPcng.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257868&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Artistic illustration of the workings of the Euclidean telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Euclid Telescope is about 4.7 meters high and 3.7 meters in diameter. It consists of a service module and a load module composition. Among them, the payload module that performs the detection function includes a 1.2-meter-diameter telescope and two scientific instruments: the visible light band camera (VIS) and the near-infrared band camera (NISP); the service module mainly includes power generation and distribution, attitude control, data Devices for handling, propulsion, thermal control, remote control and telemetry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The European Space Agency has high hopes for the Euclid telescope. &quot;Dark matter pulls galaxies together, causing them to spin faster than visible matter itself can explain; dark energy is driving the accelerating expansion of the universe. For the first time, the Euclid Telescope will allow cosmologists to study these competing forces simultaneously Dark mysteries,&quot; European Space Agency science director Carole Mundell said on the European Space Agency&#39;s official website. &quot;The Euclid Telescope will help us make leaps in understanding the entire universe, and these beautiful images show that , the mission is poised to help answer one of the biggest mysteries of modern physics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Five&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Amazing Images&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; The first five images released by the Euclid Telescope are the Perseus Cluster of galaxies, the spiral galaxy IC 342, the irregular dwarf galaxy NGC 6822, the globular star cluster NGC 6397 and the Horsehead Nebula. Picture of (The Horsehead Nebula). The field of view of the telescope for observation is very large, reaching 0.5 square degrees, which exceeds the sky area occupied by the full moon. It took less than a day to shoot the five images released this time. From bright stars to faint galaxies, the Euclid Telescope relies on its powerful observation capabilities to create exceptionally clear visible and infrared images. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perseus is one of the largest known structures in the universe, located 240 million light-years from Earth. This image of the Perseus Galaxy Cluster shows the 1,000 galaxies that are part of the cluster, along with more than 100,000 more distant galaxies in the background. This is the first time astronomers have been able to capture so many of the Perseus Galaxy at such a high level of detail in such a large image. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/snRL44n411PcaY3LYohiSopcZhMN2ISGKrfrplsS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257866&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Perseus Galaxy Cluster photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(ESA/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many of these faint galaxies have not been observed by astronomers before because some of them are very They are so far away that it took 10 billion years for their light to reach us. Astronomers have shown that galaxy clusters like Perseus could only form if dark matter was present in the universe. They will observe many galaxy clusters like Perseus through the Euclid telescope and map the distribution and shape of the galaxies in them to learn more about how dark matter binds these galaxies together to form galaxy clusters and shapes us The universe as seen today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;While in orbit, the Euclid Telescope will image billions of galaxies, revealing the invisible effects of dark matter and dark energy on them. Among the first galaxies observed by Euclid, one was nicknamed the &quot;Hidden Galaxy&quot;. This spiral galaxy similar in shape to the Milky Way was officially numbered IC 342 and was also known as Caldway. Er number 5. Thanks to the infrared capabilities of the Euclid Telescope, astronomers have discovered key information about the stars in this galaxy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/e2hilsHZlMsOyyGLA3ZHSQY5ByNJnxBP2444xn3e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257867&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The spiral galaxy IC 342 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(ESA/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the early universe, most galaxies did not look like the typical spiral shape of the Milky Way. Not only are they irregular in appearance, they are also small and form the building blocks of larger galaxies like the Milky Way. We can still find some such galaxies in the relatively nearby universe. Among the images released by the Euclid Telescope, there is an irregular dwarf galaxy numbered NGC 6822, 1.6 million light-years away from the Earth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/46Kgy0wxPbXdRogTr1PFnp76rZtiMgAcUliWWHII.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257869&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Irregular dwarf galaxy NGC 6822 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Euclid Telescope also photographed the globular star cluster NGC 6397, which is the second closest to Earth globular star cluster, about 7,800 light-years from Earth. Globular star clusters are collections of hundreds of thousands of stars held together by gravity. Currently, no other telescope other than Euclid can see an entire globular cluster in a single observation and identify so many stars in the cluster at the same time. These faint stars can tell us about the history of the Milky Way and the location of dark matter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/YtwMWpHhBpdTUm6apwOxqcqRlVFynVaPiQPCQJCF.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257865&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Globular star cluster NGC 6397 photographed by the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the celestial objects for which the Euclid Telescope released images this time, the Horsehead Nebula is the closest One, also known as Barnard 33, is part of the constellation Orion and is about 1,500 light-years away from Earth. In this image of the Horsehead Nebula, we can see not only the spectacular panorama, but also the fine details. In new Euclid observations of the stellar cradle, scientists expect to find many faint, never-before-seen Jupiter-mass planets in their early stages of formation, as well as young brown dwarfs and baby stars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/11/Kt1Udxfzy63x6VuRqHte9ajlJRMWu1oCAnxmOotV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257864&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Horsehead Nebula taken with the Euclid Telescope. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(European Space Agency/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Six years&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;continuous observation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;Although only 5 pictures were released in the first batch, these pictures already reflect the tremendous efforts of the scientists and engineers behind the development of the telescope to create these masterpieces. Euclid project manager Giuseppe Racca said on the European Space Agency&#39;s official website: &quot;Our high standards for this telescope have paid off. There is so much detail in these images, thanks to Special optical design, perfect manufacturing and assembly of the telescope and instruments and extremely precise pointing and temperature control.&quot; said René Laureijs, Euclid project scientist Comment: &quot;We have never seen astronomical images like this before, with so much detail. They are more beautiful and clearer than we could have hoped for, showing us much that has never been seen before in the known regions of the nearby universe. Characteristics. Now we are ready to observe billions of galaxies and study their evolution throughout the history of the universe.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The debut of the Euclid Telescope has inspired the astronomical community, and many people insist that Have the same opinion as Rene Laures. The images demonstrate the extraordinary capabilities of the Euclid Telescope&#39;s various instruments, which allow astronomers to study the distribution of matter in the universe and its evolution on the largest scales. Based on a large number of high-quality observations covering large areas of the sky, they will show us dark and hidden parts of the universe. And beyond the realms of dark matter and dark energy, these images show how Euclid can help astronomers create a treasure trove of information about the physics of individual stars and galaxies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Euclidean Union director Yannick Mellier said: &quot;Over the next few months, Euclid Union scientists will analyze these images and develop A series of scientific papers are published in the journal &lt;em>;Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics&lt;/em>;, as well as papers on the scientific objectives and instrument performance of the Euclid mission.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;In the months since the Euclid Telescope was launched, scientists and engineers have been testing and calibrating the telescope&#39;s science equipment. The team is currently making final fine-tuning in order to begin regular observations in early 2024. As the mission progresses, data obtained by the telescope will be released annually and open to researchers around the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan, the Euclid telescope will carry out observations for six years, after which the possibility of extending the mission will be evaluated based on the remaining amount of cryogenic gas used for propulsion. In the next six years, we can expect that the Euclid Telescope will continue to bring us new surprises and use more wonderful pictures to show us the hidden charm of the universe. The analysis of observational data will last longer, and astronomers will carefully search for clues to unravel the mysteries of dark matter and dark energy in these data. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[万亿特殊再融资债券：云南、内蒙古、辽宁超千亿，北上广未发行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260402]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73412&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70221&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; img-title=&quot;VCG211250367208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yunnan and Inner Mongolia both issued 107.6 billion yuan , ranking first in the country. Visual China/Picture&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 10/7781706ea4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257853&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yunnan and Inner Mongolia both issued 107.6 billion yuan, Ranked first in the country. Visual China/Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;All creditors have been notified to settle their arrears.&quot; A grassroots official from a western province told a Southern Weekend reporter that the funds for the special refinancing bonds issued this time have been received and are being paid. Complete government debt. &lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In early October 2023, various regions began to issue special refinancing bonds on a large scale. According to statistics from Southern Weekend reporters, as of November 5, 25 provinces (municipalities and autonomous regions) have issued a total of 1.13 trillion yuan, equivalent to Gansu&#39;s GDP in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Special refinancing bonds are issued by provincial governments. For municipal and county governments, they are equivalent to an extra amount of low-interest debt repayment funds, which can replace high-interest debts and lengthen the repayment cycle. Compared with refinancing bonds issued in ordinary times, special refinancing bonds do not list specific bond information for repayment. According to past issuance history, it is mainly used to repay implicit debts in various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A number of local financial system officials revealed to Southern Weekend reporters that this special refinancing bond has two main investment purposes, one is to replace high-interest non-standard debt, and the other is to repay the debt owed by government departments to enterprises. accounts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before the issuance of this round of special refinancing bonds, the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting on July 24, emphasizing the need to effectively prevent and resolve local debt risks and formulate and implement a package of debt reduction plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 7, Zhang Qingsong, deputy governor of the People&#39;s Bank of China, said at the International Financial Leaders Investment Summit that &quot;a few provinces may face debt repayment pressure, and most of the debts of the relevant provinces are backed by real assets. Add A package of market-oriented plans has been formulated, and I believe that with the implementation of targeted policies, some local government debt risks will gradually be reduced.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Yunnan, Inner Mongolia, and Liaoning issued over 100 billion yuan&lt;/p>; h4>; &lt;p>;According to the issuance information of this special refinancing bond, as of November 5, the top three provinces by issuance amount are: Yunnan (107.6 billion yuan), Inner Mongolia (106.7 billion yuan), Liaoning (100.6 billion yuan) . The region with the least issuance is Shanxi, with only 2.8 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the debt ratio is calculated as (government debt/GDP)*100%, in 2022, the debt ratios of the above three places will rank first among the 31 provincial-level administrative regions (excluding Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan). Nine, tenth, twelfth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This time, only six regions including Beijing, Guangdong, Shanghai, Zhejiang, Hainan and Tibet did not issue special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, Guangdong, Zhejiang, Shanghai, and Beijing have low debt ratios and developed economies. The government debt of Hainan and Tibet is not large. In 2022, Tibet&#39;s government debt balance is only 56.8 billion yuan, ranking last among the 31 provincial-level administrative regions. Hainan’s debt balance is 348.7 billion yuan, ranking fourth from the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of issuance structure, as of November 5, among the special refinancing bonds issued, the scale of general bonds was 759.4 billion yuan, accounting for 67.3%; the scale of special bonds was 368.6 billion yuan, accounting for 67.3%. 32.7%. General bonds have a wide range of uses for funds, while special bonds have limited investment options. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During this round of special refinancing bond issuance, no department has yet explained the quotas for each region. However, judging from the issuance situation, funds still flow more to the central and western provinces with relatively low fiscal self-sufficiency rates, as well as regions with larger debt scales and higher debt ratios. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The province requires us to deal with high-interest non-standard debt first.” A financial system official in a northern province told Southern Weekend reporters that after issuing special refinancing bonds, his prefecture-level city obtained With more than 10 billion yuan in funds, arrangements are currently being made to redeem non-standard products. Since the beginning of this year, there have been many non-standard defaults in the local area, which has put great pressure on repaying principal and interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to debt replacement, another important purpose is to pay off the government&#39;s debts to enterprises. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 26, the bond issuance information disclosed by Inner Mongolia showed that it plans to issue 66.32 billion yuan of refinancing general bonds, and the funds raised will be used to repay the arrears of corporate accounts that the government is responsible for repaying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 6, the above-mentioned bond issuance materials were updated, and the purpose of the funds was adjusted to repay existing debt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Audit Work Report on the Budget Implementation and Other Financial Revenues and Expenditures of the Autonomous Region in 2022&quot; previously released by Inner Mongolia showed that the policy of clearing up the accounts of small and medium-sized enterprises owed to private enterprises has not been implemented, and 62 companies are owed 111 million yuan. . In addition, at the end of 2021, Inner Mongolia&#39;s temporary payment balance was as high as 47.055 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 20, Premier Li Qiang chaired an executive meeting of the State Council. The meeting pointed out that the provincial government should take overall responsibility for the settlement of arrears in the region, promptly solve the problem of government arrears on corporate accounts, and untie the &quot;chain&quot; of mutual arrears between enterprises, and central and state-owned enterprises should take the lead in repayment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Every creditor is now required to complete the procedures first.” The grassroots official in the western province mentioned above said that for example, in the past when building a road, the company had to complete a complete set of procedures for completion acceptance and submit it to the province for review and approval before releasing the loan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, some regions have begun to offer discounts to repay accounts owed to companies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On October 26, Wuxi Delinhai Environmental Protection Technology Co., Ltd. (688069.SH) issued an announcement stating that the company, Yuxi Water Conservancy Bureau and Dali Erhai Protection Investment and Construction Co., Ltd. had receivables for some projects. The accounts receivable reached a debt restructuring plan, and the above-mentioned accounts receivable totaled 160 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the announcement, Delinhai agreed to give the debtor a certain discount and is expected to recover 120 million yuan through this debt restructuring. Industrial and commercial information shows that Erhai Investment Company is a state-owned enterprise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The announcement explains that there are two backgrounds for this debt restructuring. First, the above-mentioned National Standing Committee requires that the problem of corporate account arrears be solved; second, the Yunnan Provincial Government strives to resolve the existing hidden debts and implement hidden debts. The policy of clearing sexual debts was implemented and the implementation of a number of debt reduction measures was implemented. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The issuance of special refinancing bonds is undoubtedly an important part of the debt reduction measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img img-id=&quot;73413&quot; group-id=&quot;0&quot; asset-id=&quot;70222&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; img-title=&quot;WechatIMG1515.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;2266&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/10/3f00d582ab.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257854&quot; style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Faster and higher than the previous two rounds&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In the past few years, there have been two peak issuance periods of special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Public information shows that from December 2020 to September 2021, a total of 627.8 billion yuan of special refinancing bonds were issued, mainly used for the pilot program of implicit debt resolution in incorporated counties. Immediately afterwards, from October 2021 to June 2022, a total of 504.18 billion yuan was issued, mainly for the pilot program without hidden debt in the entire region, concentrated in Beijing, Shanghai, and Guangdong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Luo Zhiheng, president of the Guangdong Securities Research Institute, the proportion of local government bond renewals from 2018 to 2022 were 81.3%, 87.3%, 87.2%, 86.3% and 86.1% respectively, all at the The higher level is mainly to repay bonds issued in 2015-2017. From January to August 2023, the renewal ratio will increase to 90.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maturity renewal ratio = (refinancing bonds - special refinancing bonds) / maturity size. Generally speaking, after local government bonds mature, in addition to issuing refinancing bonds, fiscal funds, etc. will also be arranged for repayment. In other words, as the tight financial balance of local governments intensifies, they rely more on issuing bonds to renew maturing debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the previous two rounds of special refinancing bonds issued, this issuance is faster. In just over a month, the issuance amount exceeded one trillion yuan. The amount of this issuance is also close to the sum of the previous two rounds, and it has not yet ended. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth noting that after refinancing bonds replace implicit debt, it will increase the government debt balance. According to current regulations, local government debt (general debt and special debt) is subject to limit control. The difference between the debt limit and the debt balance is the maximum issuance amount of local special refinancing bonds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Take the main issuance of general bonds as an example. As of November 5, seven regions including Inner Mongolia, Tianjin, and Guizhou have exceeded the local maximum issuance quota, that is, the debt ceiling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wen Laicheng, a professor at the Central University of Finance and Economics, told Southern Weekend reporters that the issuance of special refinancing bonds in some places may exceed local debt limits. To this end, the Ministry of Finance will make overall adjustments and increase the debt limits of some regions on the basis of the local debt limits approved by the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the &quot;Report on the 2022 Municipal Budget Adjustment Plan (Draft)&quot; released by Chongqing City in September 2022 mentioned that the Ministry of Finance requires that the balance limit of special debt should be approximately 70%. It is retained by each province (autonomous region and municipality) and recovered by the central government at a proportion of approximately 30% for overall deployment among provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as a special means, special refinancing bonds can only relieve local government debt pressure in the short term, and the issuance amount is limited, which cannot completely solve the hidden debts of various places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An executive of a county-level urban investment company in the north told Southern Weekend reporters that his province issued tens of billions of special refinancing bonds this time because the company had successively experienced non-standard overdue incidents this year. Due to heavy debt pressure, he reported to higher-level government departments to apply for bond funding support, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, after the issuance of trillions of special refinancing bonds, the financing demand of local urban investment platforms remains strong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A staff member of a financial leasing platform in Shanghai told Southern Weekend reporters that several provinces he is responsible for have issued special refinancing bonds, but it has not affected business development. Several urban investment platforms he has recently contacted, Liquidity is still urgently needed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[花都华侨农场访问记：海外中国人筚路蓝缕，在国内也同样熠熠发光]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260343]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 22:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On a recent weekend, I took my son to wander around Ersha Island in Guangzhou and accidentally stumbled into the Guangdong Overseas Chinese Museum. , the overseas Chinese farm in one of the exhibition halls aroused my strong interest. As a teacher engaged in sociology, I came up with the idea of ​​visiting the overseas Chinese farm. I searched online and found out that there is an overseas Chinese farm on the outskirts of my city. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There were no classes on November 6, so early in the morning, I made an appointment with a colleague to go to the destination - the overseas Chinese farm located in Huadong Town, Huadu District, Guangzhou City. Huadu Overseas Chinese Farm has an area of ​​14.55 square kilometers and a registered population of more than 5,200, including residents from 13 countries and regions including Indonesia, Vietnam, Malaysia, Thailand, Japan, Singapore, Cambodia, India, Laos, New Zealand, Madagascar, Hong Kong, and Macau. There are more than 4,800 returned overseas Chinese and their family members. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The past and present life of Overseas Chinese Farm&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;After an hour&#39;s drive, we arrived at the &quot;Overseas Chinese Farm&quot; bus station. After briefly consulting an aunt at the canteen, we went to Qiao Xingyuan Community across the road. She said that many returned overseas Chinese live here. The community is not small, with nearly 30 houses together. Half of the houses have an elevated first floor, and there are some privately built houses scattered on the mountain behind. On the empty platform on the first floor of a house, we met two aunties who were busy packing mobile phone cases. They were returned overseas Chinese from Vietnam. My colleagues and I chatted with them while helping to install mobile phone cases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They returned to China in 1978, when they were only 10 and 8 years old respectively, and were placed here together. At that time, the management of the farm separated men and women, and they lived in collective dormitories. Even if they are a family, they must be spread out and cannot live together. The dormitory at that time was made of mud bricks, with rows of bunk beds inside. Due to the large number of people, the space was very small. Later, because too many returned overseas Chinese were accepted, the dormitories were not enough, so they had to live in ancestral halls in nearby villages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of agricultural production and livelihood, the farm is similar to the surrounding villages. They are also divided into several production teams. In addition to planting rice, vegetables, peanuts, fruits, oranges, lychees, and mangoes, they also cultivate On the hillside, tea plantations are planted. It is reported that as early as the late 1970s, the Overseas Chinese Farm was the most important tea production base in Huadu. The tea industry was once prosperous, and the tea produced was well-known throughout the province and sold at home and abroad. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scene of planting tea in the mountains is still vivid in my mind. An aunt said that everyone used axes and hoes to open up the densely forested hills and turned them into tea planting bases. Without machinery, they carried small tea seedlings to the mountains with bare hands to plant them, and then carried buckets of water for watering. Gradually, a lush green tea mountain was formed in the Qifengtian and Wan Gongtang areas, covering an area of ​​several hundred hectares. At that time, we had to work on time every day. We usually got up at 7 o&#39;clock in the morning to pick tea, because the dew was thick at that time, which was the best time to pick tea. Although the conditions are difficult, everyone is very motivated. During the lunch break, everyone will gather together and listen to one of them reading the day&#39;s newspaper aloud, and sometimes someone will take the lead in singing...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difference is , all returned overseas Chinese who settle on farms can enjoy the same benefits and treatment as urban residents, including food stamps, cloth stamps, meat stamps and other material supplies. Now, after they have retired for many years, they can also enjoy retirement salary benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, the aunt told us that rural people in eight villages within ten miles are proud to marry their daughters to the farm, because the daughter will immediately become an &quot;employee&quot; who can &quot;enjoy benefits&quot;, and her personal destiny will be A major turnaround could occur. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2007, the local government decided to implement a housing renovation project for Huaqiao Farm, investing 130 million yuan, with a total construction area of ​​more than 70,000 square meters, and built new buildings such as Qiaonan Garden, Qiaogang Garden, and Qiaoxing Garden. In residential areas, employees only need to pay a small amount of money to live in spacious and bright houses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Aren&#39;t the surrounding villagers envious of you?&quot; I asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;That was true at the time, but it&#39;s different now. We envy them very much.&quot; said an aunt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The government of Huadong Town, where the overseas Chinese farm was originally located, has taken advantage of its proximity to Baiyun International Airport in recent years and is committed to building an aviation logistics industry cluster, an aviation maintenance industry cluster, an e-commerce industry cluster and a temporary logistics cluster. It is an empty advanced manufacturing agglomeration area and carries out high-intensity development of overseas Chinese farms and nearby villages. Because overseas Chinese farms themselves are state-owned land, they are land development and utilization activities within the government that do not involve property rights replacement, and provide visible benefits to farm employees. However, the situation in nearby villages is different. Many villagers have received considerable compensation for their land expropriation. Some even only need to pay an additional tens of thousands of yuan to live in various comprehensive and complete buildings. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aunts can earn 80-100 yuan a day by doing odd jobs packaging mobile phone cases. Anyway, when they are free at home, they just look at their mobile phones and do something, which makes them comfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The original words of an aunt were, &quot;When I was very young, my mother taught me to be hardworking. Now that I am retired, but my body is still strong, I just find something to do, and I feel at ease.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Some people know how to play cards and check their mobile phones after retirement, but I don&#39;t like it. I feel bad when I lose money playing cards; it hurts my eyes because I look at my mobile phone all the time. I feel uncomfortable, so I might as well do something.&quot; Another person An aunt said this. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The role of returned overseas Chinese&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;At nearly 12 noon, the aunts will go home for dinner. After saying goodbye to them, we went to Qiao Nan Garden across the road to find food. In a restaurant, we met a family of returned Indonesians having dinner. We simply said hello to them and explained our purpose, but they were so enthusiastic that they invited us to eat with them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the chat during the dinner, I learned that my aunt’s surname was Wen, and she was the fourth eldest child in the family. She had an older brother, two older sisters, and a younger sister. She returned to China in 1960, when she was 6 years old. Today, the old mother is 98 years old, her mind is still clear and her spirit is still strong. Aunt Wen said that her grandfather went to Indonesia in his early years and was one of the first batch of people to &quot;go to Southeast Asia&quot;. They raised pigs, made tofu, got married and settled down locally. Her parents also inherited their ancestors&#39; business and made a living mainly by making and selling tofu in small cities or towns in southwestern Indonesia. Obviously, they have no choice to settle or make a living in capitals or big cities where competition is fiercer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Diligence, frugality, running a small business, and moving forward in hardship and adversity cannot be underestimated. These traits have laid the foundation for Aunt Wen’s generation to be smart and understand business since childhood. After returning to China, Aunt Wen and her family successively ran a bean product factory, a garment factory, a wood processing factory and a restaurant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It should be noted that these so-called &quot;small and micro enterprises&quot; are not privately owned, but are owned by the farm. The products produced must be handed over to the farm for unified sales or other disposal by the farm. Compared with the nearby villagers who have been farming all day long, Aunt Wen&#39;s family and others like Aunt Wen who have worked abroad for a long time are obviously better in thinking and ideas. They have largely promoted the comprehensive transformation and upgrading of the farm, and have contributed to the farm&#39;s development. Industrial diversification has blazed a trail. Relying on their foresight and example, the farm has begun industrialization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a larger scale, Aunt Wen and a group of people took the lead in promoting the rural industrialization process in the Huadu area. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as Aunt Wen is concerned, she is bold, outgoing and sociable. She obtained a Class A driver&#39;s license at the age of 18 and became the only female driver in the farm driver class in the 1980s. She often drove long trailers Traveling all over the country, I naturally have a lot of knowledge and quick thinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aunt Wen is also an authentic food maker. Every festival, whether it is a Chinese festival or an Indonesian festival, or when someone in the neighborhood gets married, has a baby, or has a child going to school or joining the military. During the banquet, she would prepare various ingredients a week in advance, sometimes even making a special trip to Hong Kong to buy them, and make all kinds of exquisite snacks with Indonesian characteristics, such as thousand-layer cakes, manjian cakes, pagoda rice, Padang dishes, fermented soybean cubes, Gadot-Gadot, etc., for relatives, friends and neighbors to taste. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;毫无疑问，归侨身份让各国特色美食在华侨农场得以传承与光大，乡邻们在品尝各国美食过程中进行着跨文化交流，这样的朝夕共处与频繁交流，无疑营造了一个多样丰富文化的社区氛围，对于化解社区矛盾与争端、构建社区发展共同体、提升社区自组织能力、增进社区治理效能产生积极作用。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;归侨身份亦对后代的发展产生垂范作用。席间还有温姨的侄子，他饭后便欲启程去香港，继而转机去印尼。原来，他父母很早就定居香港，他小学及中学是在香港念的，大学及研究生在美国完成，目前在印尼巴厘岛一家地产公司上班。不难看出，祖辈或长辈们的跨国经历，对后代的受教育水平及人生际遇产生深远影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;温姨告诉我，农场有数量不少的第三代跨国移民，多少得益于或受益于祖辈们构建起来的跨国联系网络。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;我的感想&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;下午3时许，我们请温姨带我们去她曾经“战斗”过的一些地方走走、看看，她欣然应许，我们相继去了五队、六队和九队。一路上，我们发现从前的临时农场管理办公室、茶厂、制衣厂等早已改头换面，原址上已建起了很多涉及新能源与高科技等领域的新型企业。道理至简，华侨农场属国营单位，管理方式较大程度沿袭计划经济体制，很多传统产业难以跟上新的发展形势，不少企业纷纷破产，取而代之的是新项目纷纷上马，新企业纷纷进驻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看到曾经劳作的地方，只有少数厂牌孤独地伫立在那里，温姨露出了遗憾与无奈的表情。时代在改变，华侨农场也在转型，这是无法阻止的客观规律。未来，华侨农场将继续深度融入都市化与现代化。在这一过程中，我以为有关方面可以尝试开展下面几件事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其一，应该鼓励大学老师、相关研究人员或学生群体开展针对归侨及其后代的口述史研究，做好各年龄层次人口的采访与调查，成为花东镇乃至花都区地方志的重要组成部分。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其二，通过政府与民间合作的方式，成立华侨农村博物馆或展览馆，让华侨文化与华侨精神发扬光大，将其打造为花都旅游中的特色与亮点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其三，积极申报建设省级或市级国际化社区，华侨农场是实实在在与真真切切的国际化社区，有关部门在升级改造与后续规划过程中不能或不宜一味地“去农场化”，华侨农场作为一种地方性特质早已成为花东镇或花都区地方性知识的重要组分，有关方面需要充分尊重地方，尊重地方原真性，让上述地方在新时期国际化社区营建过程中得以体现与绽放，这无疑很大程度助力地方营销（place marketing），进而成为招商引资的重要社会资本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者系广州大学社会学系教授）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 22:55:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[弄虚作假？二次污染？85亿元苏钢“毒地”疑云]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260398]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 20:53:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/23ba7d78ba.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/23ba7d78ba.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257847&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年3月18日，公益组织“北京草原之盟”技术顾问及志愿者前往苏州雷丁国际学校调研，大门有红色警报。多家公益组织对此事发起了公益诉讼。受访者供图&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;花85亿抢拍到的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;地块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;竟然&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;含&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“毒&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;”，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;开发建设后不能投入运营&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，上市公司&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;上海陆家嘴金融贸易区开发股份有限公司（以下简称陆家嘴）&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;要求&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;对簿公堂&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2023年11月4日，陆家嘴发布公告，因土壤污染问题向江苏苏钢集团有限公司&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;以下&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;简称&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏钢&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;集团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;及多家苏州政府机构、事业单位发起诉讼，并向苏钢集团索赔100.44亿元。目前江苏省高级人民法院已立案，尚未开庭审理。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;7&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;前&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，陆家嘴高价拍下&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏钢集团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;厂区旧址&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;17块地，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;总建筑面积超100万平方米&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;陆家嘴在&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;023年9月29日发布的公告中称，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;02&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;年，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;其中2号地块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;已&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;建成学校&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;在&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;申请&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;办学许可证&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;过程&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆续发现包括&amp;nbsp;2&amp;nbsp;号地块在内的诸多地块存在污染&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;023&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;以来&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;多次&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;发布公告，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;调查得知共有14块土地污染，污染面积和程度远超挂牌出让时披露的情况。2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;022年，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;相关&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;地块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;被中央环保督察点名，当地政府委托第三方调查也发现污染超标。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;陆家嘴在公告中表示，这块土地的“调规变性及出让过程中，各被告存在一系列违法违规、弄虚作假、不依法履职的侵权行为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;发布&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;公告6&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;天&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;后，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;023年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;1月10日，苏钢集团发布情况说明，称&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;正在积极应诉，把确保群众身体健康和购房者合法权益放在首位。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;一方&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;在2019年已&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;知悉2号地块不符合环保要求&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;但&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;未依法完成土壤污染调查和修复治理&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;就&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;启动了该地块项目建设&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;且&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;在开发建设期间&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;存在&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;施工作业不规范造成二次污染&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;等&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;情况&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者采访发现，苏钢&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;集团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;地块是典型的工业用地再开发案例，土壤调查评估、修复和土地转让开发利用跨越了&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;七&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，其间我国土壤污染防治的法律法规、技术规范和标准从少到多、不断完善。前后评估结果不同，可能由于土壤污染评估标准一再变更、不断加严，且江南水系丰富，污染容易迁移。此种&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;情况下，污染修复由谁负责，也是法律难题。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;高价买下“毒土地”？&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2016年，苏钢集团将全资子公司&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸房地产开发有限公司&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（以下简称&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;）95%股权挂牌出售，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;的核心资&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;产是17块国有土地。地块位于苏州市高新区浒墅关镇苏通路北、苏钢路东，原是苏钢集团的生产厂区。经过222轮激烈的报价竞争，陆家嘴以85.25亿元成为拿下土地的赢家。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2ff5ec2cee.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;574&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/2ff5ec2cee.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257848&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;苏州钢铁历史。苏钢集团官网/图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;公告中披露了&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏钢集团2016年8月挂牌时的信息，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;名下地块中，非焦化区域的土壤和地下水基本未受到污染，可再开发利用；焦化区域的污染主要集中在4号地块局部区域。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;在2022年4月14日发布的公告中称，“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;基于对公开市场股权挂牌信息的信任，以及对政府部门行政行为的合理信赖&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;竞得&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;股权。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏钢&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;集团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;情况说明&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;透露&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;在2016年转让股权时，我司已如实披露了第三方专业机构关于苏州绿岸名下土地存在部分污染的调查结果及报告全文，并在资产评估报告中明确提示了该范围中部分地块原为钢铁焦化生产区域，可能存在土壤污染风险。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴与苏钢集团签署的《股权交易事宜备忘录》显示，双方约定“关于部分地块存在土壤污染事宜，根据经苏州市环境保护局备案的相关调查评估报告，该等土壤环境治理不存在技术上的障碍，治理完成后将符合国家和地方性环境质量标准，可根据现有规划文件的要求进行开发建设。苏钢集团将就环境治理事宜为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;绿岸公司&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;提供协调及支持”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;根据规划，陆家嘴将在此建设苏州高新区首个百万方城市区域综合体项目，项目于2017年5月启动，开发周期计划为8年。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;除了打造商业体和“锦绣澜山”住宅，陆家嘴还引进了由苏州伦华教育集团与英国雷丁学校共同打造的九年一贯制国际化学校——苏州雷丁学校，选址定在了项目的2号地块。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;没想到&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;学校建成了，却不能顺利招生。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;据上游新闻报道，2021年，苏州雷丁学校校方在办理办学许可证过程中，根据苏州高新区环保局要求，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;陆家嘴委托第三方机构&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;调查学校所在地块的土壤污染状况，发现存在严重污染，无法通过环评投入使用。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;苏钢集团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;在情况说明中提到：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2019&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;年，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;陆家嘴一&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;方&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;知悉&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;号地块不符合环保要求，且未依法完成&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;号地块土壤污染调查和修复治理，即启动了该地块项目建设。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2021&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;年，因无法通过环评验收而未能启用。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴公告还显示，苏州市资规局将&amp;nbsp;2&amp;nbsp;号地块恢复为工业&amp;nbsp;(研发)用地，雷丁学校项目客观上无法完成综合验收。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/58fb238dfb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/58fb238dfb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257849&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;2023年3月，公益组织“北京草原之盟”技术顾问及志愿者前往苏州雷丁国际学校调研。多家公益组织对此事发起了公益诉讼。受访者供图&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;一年后，“毒地”遭中央环保督察组点名。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2022年4月，江苏省公布的《中央第二生态环境保护督察组向我省移交的第六批信访事项办理情况》中提到，第三方检测机构检测结果显示，苏州绿岸项目多处地块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土壤中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苯并[a]芘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;、萘严重超标，不符合用地标准。在苏州高新区管委会的要求下，陆家嘴已暂停&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;相关开发、建设、销售工作，并对上述污染地块实施了严格管理。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;督察&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;通报&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;显示，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州高新区管委会高度重视，成立了工作专班&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者获得的调查报告显示，2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;年8月，苏州高新区浒墅关镇人民政府委托生态环境部南京环境科学研究所进行详细&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;调查，发现7个地块超标。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;苏钢&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;集团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;情况说明提到了&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;此7个地块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2022&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;年，陆家嘴一方与苏钢一致同意委托的第三方专业机构南京环科所对地块污染情况进行了详细调查。焦化区&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;3&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;4&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;5&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;6&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;号和非焦化区&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;10&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;号地块（其中仅&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;号地块已开发建设），经治理修复后可安全利用。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;已有居民入住的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;14&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;15&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;号地块、已开发建设的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;8&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;9&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;12&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;13&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;16&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;号地块和未开发建设的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;7&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;11&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;, serif&quot;>;17&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;仿宋_GB2312&quot;>;号地块，属可安全利用地块。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/5f4f9ff746.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;794&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/5f4f9ff746.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257850&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;地块规划示意图。陆家嘴公告/图（编辑注：因图有倾斜，地块编号和地块位置未完全对齐。）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;根据陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;发布的公告&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;污染地块数目不止7块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;20&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;22年以来，陆家嘴及各方环境调查机构确定&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;名下&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;14&amp;nbsp;块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土地存在污染。陆家嘴一纸诉状将苏钢集团及其委托检测的苏州市环境科学研究所、苏州市苏城环境科技有限责任公司以及相关方苏州国家高新技术产业开发区管理委员会、苏州市自然资源和规划局告上法庭&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;作为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;案件第三人。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者致电案件原告方及第三人，多名工作人员表示有关案件事宜需询问陆家嘴集团董秘办，11月9日，董秘办回复，“集团统一口径，不接受采访”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;根据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;两份&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;环评公示，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者尝试联系&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏钢集团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州市环境科学研究所和环评&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;承担&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;方&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州科技大学的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;相关人员&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;均未取得联系或&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;拒绝采访。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;参考标准不同，检测结果不同&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;污染场地的开发利用，需要经过严格的环境监测、评估、修复等&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;流程&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，为何房子都造好了，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;才&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;向&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;外界说有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;污染&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;中央环保督察提到了两种超标污染物：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苯并[a]芘和萘。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;比对&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;这两个污染物在2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014-2022年的多份&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;报告中的数值可以发现，苏钢地块“毒地”的后知后觉，有可能是污染的确存在，而评估时依据的标准不同，导致&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;结果不同&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏钢&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;将地块分为非焦化区和焦化区&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（污染较重），&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;委托第三方环境公司分别进行土壤调查。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;环保组织&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;广州绿网环境保护服务中心&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;向苏州市生态环境局申请公开，获得了《江苏苏钢集团老区（除未关停区域）土壤初步调查报告》《江苏苏钢集团有限公司老区焦化区域场地污染初步调查报告》&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;《江苏苏钢集团有限公司老区焦化区域场地污染&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;详细&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;调查报告》和《江苏苏钢集团有限公司老区焦化区域&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土壤和地下水人体健康评估报告&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;》&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;四份报告调查范围涵盖了&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;非焦化区和焦化区。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苯并[a]芘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;是一类致癌物，烧烤时也会产生，属于半挥发性有机物&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;；&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;萘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;介于挥发性有机物和半挥发性有机物之间。非焦化区在2014年1月进行了土壤调查，在35个采样点中，均未测苯并[a]芘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;大部分样点（34个）未检测萘。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;彼时，调查&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;依据的标准是《展览会用地土壤环境质量评价标准》（HJ350-2007）（下称“展览会用地标准”），是原环境保护部制定的行业标准，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;没有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;明确这两种污染物需强制检测&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;而在后续的其他的报告中，如&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;022年4月中央环保督察组通报、陆家嘴发布的公告、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2022年8月苏州高新区委托生态环境部南京环境科学研究所的调查均显示，非焦化区部分点位也存在苯并[a]芘、萘超标。此时，参考的标准是2018年8月1日实施的国家标准《土壤环境质量&amp;nbsp;建设用地土壤污染风险管控标准（试行）》（GB36600-2018）（下称“建设用地标准”），此前不是必测的苯并[a]芘和萘已要求必测。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;“苯并[a]芘和萘在非焦化区的污染可能一直存在，只是因为之前没有检测所以未发现。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;绿网&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;工作人员&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊猜测。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;而焦化区发现的部分&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;污染物，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;各&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;阶段报告中有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;检测&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，但&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;可能由于&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;新标准中限值加严，导致之前达标，之后超标。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;萘就是这样。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014年、2015年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;焦化区&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;土壤&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;调查结果显示，仅有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;污水处理区和粗苯车间&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;（也就是前文提到的4号地块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;的部分区域&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;受到污染，其他区域萘未超标。此时参考的是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“展览会用地标准”的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;B级标准，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;萘的限值为530mg/kg。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;而在后续的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;检测&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;报告中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;不只是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;4号地块，有&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;多&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;地块&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;萘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;等污染物&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;超标。后续&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;报告参考的萘&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;限值加严了，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;分别&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;25mg/kg(&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;第一类用地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;和&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;70mg/kg(&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;第二类用地)&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，均远低于&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;此前标准的&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;530mg/kg。“此前标准限制得过于宽泛，现有标准基于人体健康等因素&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;更科学&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;评价，比较严格。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;说。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/be70b96a1e.PNG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;493&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/be70b96a1e.PNG&quot; data-key=&quot;257851&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;苏钢“毒地”各报告、通报中关键污染物检测结果汇总。南方周末记者林方舟黄思琪&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;南方周末实习生习丽杰整理&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;检测中的“保守性原则”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;虽然2014年的土壤污染检测要求中没有强制检测名录，但业内有一项“保守&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;性&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;原则”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2014年2月，原环境保护部发布的《场地环境调查技术导则》（HJ25.1-2014）提到了“检测项目应根据保守性原则”：一般工业场地可选择的检测项目包括半挥发性有机物。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;也就意味着苯并[a]芘这样的半挥发性有机物按照保守性原则，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;建议&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;检测。但郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;指出&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，苏钢委托的第三方环境公司并未&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;采纳，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;非焦化区没有检测&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;介绍，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;半挥发性有机物是钢铁厂地块土壤中的常见污染物，它们在焦化、燃煤过程中的热解和不完全燃烧过程中释放，排放到大气中，又沉降到附近的地面，进而污染土壤，“不只非焦化区，甚至厂区外的土壤也可能会超标”。其他&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;钢铁厂&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;也曾&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;发生过类似情况&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;“苏钢地块是典型的工业用地再开发的案例，它的土壤调查、土地转让和开发跨越了我们国家土壤污染防治领域的法律法规、技术规范和标准从无到有、从少到多的过程。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;郭磊&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;说。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;在2014年苏钢地块开展土壤调查的时段&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，我国土壤污染防治的相关法律法规、标准、技术规范&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;建设&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;也才&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;刚刚起步&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;直至2014年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;上述技术导则才诞生&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;；直至2017年7月1日，污染地块土壤环境管理办法才施行；2019年1月1日，土壤污染防治法才施行。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;在此之前，仅有原环保部等部门出台的几项部门通知，并不具备较高的法律效力。一位&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土壤修复行业人士向南方周末记者回忆，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;014年左右，行业非常混乱。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;重庆市生态环境局、规划和自然资源局于2021年发布《关于进一步加强建设用地土壤污染分类分级管理工作的通知》曾表述&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“早期土壤污染状况调查的认识不到位，相关技术导则规范不健全，调查技术手段受限等原因，导致部分重污染行业建设用地地块调查结果失真，修复不到位……部分建设用地土壤污染调查、风险评估、风险管控及修复效果评估报告编制质量不高、专家评审把关不严，对从业企业、评审专家缺乏约束管理。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“且不论弄虚作假等，光上述因素就会造成土壤调查精度不高，导致调查结果跟实际情况间可能有较大差距。”郭磊称。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;二次污染？&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;南方周末记者发现，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;焦化区域的污染主要集中在4号地块，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴一方在交易时即知晓，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;也曾编制修复方案和治理。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;2018年9月，《苏钢地块老区焦化区域污染场地修复工程环境影响评价报告表及专项评价》公示，建设&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;单位为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;苏州绿岸，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;内容&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;为土壤原&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;位和异位修复。公示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;原网页环评报告链接已经失效，但网传有一份&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;97&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;页的同名称环评报告（以下简称环评报告）。南方周末记者联系环评承担方&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;苏州科技大学&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;技术&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;人员确认，未获得&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;回应&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;微软雅黑&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;环评报告提到了苏钢老区焦化场地，自2015年启动初步调查、详细调查、修复方案等历时三年多，每一环节均经过专家评审，符合当时的环保要求，但是土壤修复中萘的修复目标值不符合新标准要求，修改后符合&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“建设用地标准”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;（&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;GB36600-2018）&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;。评价适用标准中，修复后规划为商业用地，土壤参考也是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“建设用地标准”第二类&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;用地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;，萘的标准为70mg/kg。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/126c7a8461.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;908&quot; data-catchresult=&quot;img_catchSuccess&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/10/126c7a8461.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257852&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: justify;&quot;>;红色为曾进行土壤修复的大概位置。黄色为2022年新发现的4块污染地块。绿网公众号截图。&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;default&quot;>;环评报告显示，4号地块将进行土壤修复。但2022年后的多份检测报告显示，4号地块仍然有污染。有土壤修复业内人士向南方周末记者提醒，“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;焦化厂污染是疑难杂症，非常难治理。在江南地区的水文地质条件下，还需要特别注意污染迁移”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;雷丁学校所在的2号地块也被多次报告污染，地图显示，2号地块和4号地块相连。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;苏钢的情况说明提到：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;等线&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;方在开发建设苏州绿岸地块期间，没有按照有关要求建设地下水阻隔墙及采取其他防护措施，存在扰动地下水、搬运土壤造成部分环境交叉污染的行为和施工作业不规范造成二次污染的行为。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;对此&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，陆家嘴还未有回应。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;2022年7月&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;被苏州生态环境局处罚1.88万，原因是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;违反土壤生态环境管理制度&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;违法&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;事实对应&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;土壤污染防治法第四十二条第三款&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;：&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;风险管控、修复活动完成后，需要实施后期管理的，土壤污染责任人应当按照要求实施后期管理&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;陆家嘴&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;在&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;2&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;023年1月10日发布&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;公告表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，苏州生态环境局作出该项处罚的原因是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸在之前依据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏钢集&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;团&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;披露的污染区域对&amp;nbsp;4&amp;nbsp;号地块土壤修复后未按要求实施后期管理&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;等线&amp;quot;&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;汇业律师事务所合伙人、&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;环境资源与能源专委会执行主任张秀秀&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;向南方周末&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;记者&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，如果&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;施工作业导致污染扩散，应对生态环境损害的扩大部分承担责任。但不能&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;排除苏钢集团是否需要对&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;4&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;号地块的污染负责，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;其中&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;可能涉及多因一果的共同侵权，依据&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;民法典&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;第1231条的规定，在责任大小认定上需要结合污染范围、程度，以及行为对损害后果所起作用等因素确定&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;”。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;毒地修复责任归谁&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;张秀秀认为&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;根据已有材料，目前难以断定苏钢集团在交易时是否有所隐瞒、场地调查过程中是否存在不规范行为。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;土地&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;出让了，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;标准更迭加严，应该由谁来承担土地污染修复责任？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;张秀秀告诉南方周末记者，评价交易双方的土地污染修复责任，关键看土地交易交割时期的标准，尤其是强制性标准。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;如果交易前，场地调查已有明确的国家标准，出让方不存在未披露风险情形，在企业存续期间也做到了合法合规达标排放，即使倒查，也无法追究其历史上生态环境损害赔偿责任，交易后的土壤污染风险&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;也&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;应由继受人承担。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;如果土地交易时&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;缺乏&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;明确的标准，双方也没有遵循保守性原则严格排查，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;那么&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;现有土地使用权人&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;就&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;具有土壤污染风险管控和修复的义务&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;，在本案中，也就是&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;。&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;这在一定程度上归因于受让方在交易前缺乏独立严谨的环境调&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;查。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;“&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;苏州绿岸&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;作为现有建设用地使用权人，具有对土壤污染的风险管控和评估义务，应承担土地污染修复责任。至于修复费用的追偿问题，有两种途径，一是行政途径，通过土地污染责任认定程序&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;；&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;二是通过民事诉讼途径，&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;基于&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;投资并购交易合同。”&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;张秀秀&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;&amp;quot;宋体&amp;quot;&quot;>;介绍。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Calibri&quot;>;2021&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;年&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;Calibri&quot;>;1&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;月，生态环境部会同自然资源部制定了《建设用地土壤污染责任人认定暂行办法》，规定建设用地使用权人可以向有管辖权的生态环境主管部门提出土壤污染责任人认定申请。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;不过，张秀秀认为陆家嘴与苏钢集团的责任认定存在较大难题。主要原因是目前国内土壤污染责任人认定办法出台时间短、实践案例少，推行阻力较大。“很多地方的主管部门对于受理申请、启动认定程序非常犹豫，因为可资借鉴的案例很少。如果不被受理，使用权人只能通过交易合同关系&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;去&lt;/span>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;追究历史的污染责任人。但一般的合同关系里，如果双方对于土壤污染的约定不明确，受让了污染场地的一方就会比较吃亏。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;南方周末记者查询发现，陆家嘴目前的公开披露信息中，未明确提及是否启动土地污染责任认定程序。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;张秀秀表示，该起环境污染责任纠纷案件的启示意义在于，土地交易中买受人应注重环境法律风险的排查。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;span data-font-family=&quot;宋体&quot;>;首先，买受人要深度了解土壤污染状况和历史用途，如果地块历史用途或周边涉及污染，应重点关注土壤污染的风险。其次，买受人应对地块的调查保持一定的独立性，对于既有的专业报告、评审结论保持警惕性，不可轻信结论，如有必要，可以聘请第三方开展更详细的土壤调查。最后，基于投资的通盘考虑，愿意承担一定环境法律风险的交易，应对土壤污染治理成本进行评估，就土壤污染状况、风险转移及可追溯的相关法律责任，在交易合同予以明确。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[国家金监总局三定方案： 健全金融消保者保护制度]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260400]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 21:18:12&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;国家金融监督管理总局职能配置、内设机构和人员编制规定&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第一条&lt;/strong>; 为了规范国家金融监督管理总局的职能配置、内设机构和人员编制，推进机构、职能、权限、程序、责任法定化，根据党的二十届二中全会审议通过的《党和国家机构改革方案》、第十四届全国人民代表大会第一次会议审议批准的《国务院机构改革方案》和《中国共产党机构编制工作条例》以及党中央对金融工作的有关要求，制定本规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第二条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局是国务院直属机构，为正部级。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第三条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局在中国银行保险监督管理委员会基础上组建，将中国人民银行对金融控股公司等金融集团的日常监管职责、有关金融消费者保护职责，中国证券监督管理委员会的投资者保护职责划入国家金融监督管理总局。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第四条&lt;/strong>; 本规定确定的主要职责、机构设置、人员编制等，是国家金融监督管理总局机构职责权限、人员配备和工作运行的基本依据。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第五条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局负责贯彻落实党中央关于金融工作的方针政策和决策部署，把坚持和加强党中央对金融工作的集中统一领导落实到履行职责过程中。主要职责是：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）依法对除证券业之外的金融业实行统一监督管理，强化机构监管、行为监管、功能监管、穿透式监管、持续监管，维护金融业合法、稳健运行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）对金融业改革开放和监管有效性相关问题开展系统性研究，参与拟订金融业改革发展战略规划。拟订银行业、保险业、金融控股公司等有关法律法规草案，提出制定和修改建议。制定银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等有关监管制度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）统筹金融消费者权益保护工作。制定金融消费者权益保护发展规划，建立健全金融消费者权益保护制度，研究金融消费者权益保护重大问题，开展金融消费者教育工作，构建金融消费者投诉处理机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（四）依法对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行准入管理，对其公司治理、风险管理、内部控制、资本充足状况、偿付能力、经营行为、信息披露等实施监管。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（五）依法对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行现场检查与非现场监管，开展风险与合规评估，查处违法违规行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（六）统一编制银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的监管数据报表，按照国家有关规定予以发布，履行金融业综合统计相关工作职责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（七）负责银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的科技监管，建立科技监管体系，制定科技监管政策，构建监管大数据平台，开展风险监测、分析、评价、预警，充分利用科技手段加强监管、防范风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（八）对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等实行穿透式监管，制定股权监管制度，依法审查批准股东、实际控制人及股权变更，依法对股东、实际控制人以及一致行动人、最终受益人等开展调查，对违法违规行为采取相关措施或进行处罚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（九）建立除货币、支付、征信、反洗钱、外汇和证券期货等领域之外的金融稽查体系，建立行政执法与刑事司法衔接机制，依法对违法违规金融活动相关主体进行调查、取证、处理，涉嫌犯罪的，移送司法机关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十）建立银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的恢复和处置制度，会同相关部门研究提出有关金融机构恢复和处置意见建议并组织实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十一）牵头打击非法金融活动，组织建立非法金融活动监测预警体系，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作。对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，研究提出相关工作建议，按要求组织实施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十二）按照建立以中央金融管理部门地方派出机构为主的地方金融监管体制要求，指导和监督地方金融监管相关业务工作，指导协调地方政府履行相关金融风险处置属地责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十三）负责对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等与信息技术服务机构等中介机构的信息科技外包等合作行为进行监管，依法对违法违规行为开展调查，并对金融机构采取相关措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十四）参加金融业相关国际组织与国际监管规则制定，开展对外交流与国际合作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十五）完成党中央、国务院交办的其他任务。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第六条&lt;/strong>; 职能转变。加强和完善现代金融监管，转变监管理念和监管方式，坚持既管合法又管非法，持续提升监管的前瞻性、精准性、有效性，强化中央和地方监管协同，消除监管空白和盲区，加强金融消费者权益保护，加大对违法违规行为的查处力度，牢牢守住不发生系统性金融风险的底线。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加强金融监管内部治理，强化对权力运行的有效制衡，规范政策制定、市场准入、稽查执法、行政处罚、风险处置等工作流程，强化对重点岗位和关键环节的监督制约，打造一支政治过硬、专业精湛、清正廉洁的监管铁军。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第七条&lt;/strong>; 与其他部门的职责分工：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）打击非法金融活动职责分工。1.国家金融监督管理总局牵头建立打击非法金融活动工作协调机制，组织建立非法金融活动监测预警体系，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作。2.国家金融监督管理总局、中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会、国家外汇管理局依据各自职责对相关非法设立金融机构、从事特许金融活动等组织调查认定，采取相关措施或予以取缔。3.教育、养老、房地产、商贸服务等行业主管部门在职责范围内开展本行业本领域非法集资等非法金融活动的防范和配合处置工作。4.互联网信息内容管理部门、电信主管部门、市场监督管理部门等相关职能部门在职责范围内开展非法金融活动防范和配合处置工作。5.地方政府负责辖内非法集资等非法金融活动防范和处置工作，开展风险排查、案件查处、善后处置和维护稳定等工作。6.对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，国家金融监督管理总局负责提出相关工作建议，按程序报批后组织实施，并及时采取应急措施。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）金融消费者权益保护工作职责分工。1.国家金融监督管理总局统筹负责金融消费者权益保护，牵头建立金融消费者保护工作协调机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。2.国家金融监督管理总局统筹制定金融消费者权益保护发展规划、建立健全金融消费者权益保护制度、开展金融消费者教育等工作，中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会予以支持配合。3.国家金融监督管理总局牵头建立统一的金融消费者投诉举报流程和标准体系。国家金融监督管理总局、中国人民银行、中国证券监督管理委员会按分工落实或督促相关机构落实投诉举报处理主体责任，依法查处侵害金融消费者合法权益的行为。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）行政执法与刑事司法衔接机制。1.国家金融监督管理总局与公安部、最高人民检察院建立行政执法与刑事司法衔接工作机制，实现案件信息共享、协同办理。2.国家金融监督管理总局发现违法行为涉嫌犯罪的，按照有关规定移送公安部，同时抄送最高人民检察院。公安机关经调查发现依法需要由国家金融监督管理总局作出行政处罚的，由公安部向国家金融监督管理总局提出建议。3.检察机关决定不起诉的案件，需要由国家金融监督管理总局作出行政处罚的，由最高人民检察院向国家金融监督管理总局提出检察意见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第八条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局根据本规定第五条所明确的主要职责，编制权责清单，逐项明确权责名称、权责类型、设定依据、履责方式、追责情形等。在此基础上，制定办事指南、运行流程图等，进一步优化行政程序，规范权力运行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第九条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局设下列正司局级内设机构：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（一）办公厅（党委办公室）。负责机关日常运转，承担信息、安全、保密、信访、政务公开、新闻宣传等工作。承担国家金融监督管理总局党委办公室日常工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二）政策研究司。承担金融业相关改革开放政策研究与组织实施具体工作。对国内外经济金融形势、国际金融监管改革及发展趋势、监管方法和运行机制等开展系统性研究，提出相关监管政策建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（三）法规司。起草相关法律法规草案。拟订相关监管制度。承担合法性审查、法律咨询服务、行政复议、行政应诉等工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（四）统计与风险监测司。拟订监管统计制度。承担监管报表编制、信息披露、数据共享以及行业风险监测分析预警等工作。统筹非现场监管工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（五）科技监管司。拟订相关信息科技发展规划和信息科技风险监管制度并组织实施。按分工承担网络安全、数据安全、关键信息基础设施监管等工作，推动数字化信息化建设。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（六）公司治理监管司。拟订公司治理监管制度。开展股权管理和公司治理监管等工作，承担金融控股公司、保险集团等机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（七）普惠金融司。督促金融机构落实普惠金融政策要求，拟订监督管理的规章制度并组织实施，指导金融机构开展对小微企业、“三农”和特殊群体的金融服务工作，规范普惠金融秩序。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（八）金融机构准入司。拟订银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等的准入制度，研究结构布局，对机构及其业务范围实行准入管理，审查董事、高级管理人员等任职资格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（九）大型银行监管司。承担政策性银行、开发性银行和国有控股大型商业银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十）股份制和城市商业银行监管司。承担全国性股份制商业银行、城市商业银行、民营银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十一）农村中小银行监管司。承担农村中小银行机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十二）财产保险监管司（再保险监管司）。承担财产保险机构、再保险机构、保险中介机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十三）人身保险监管司。承担人身保险机构的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十四）资管机构监管司。承担信托公司、理财公司、保险资产管理公司的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十五）非银机构监管司。承担金融资产管理公司、企业集团财务公司、金融租赁公司、汽车金融公司、消费金融公司、货币经纪公司的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十六）银行机构检查局。拟订银行机构现场检查计划并组织实施。承担现场检查立项、实施和后评价等工作。提出现场检查意见，采取监管措施，提出行政处罚建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十七）保险和非银机构检查局。拟订保险业机构、金融控股公司及其他非银行机构的现场检查计划并组织实施。承担现场检查立项、实施和后评价等工作。提出现场检查意见，采取监管措施，提出行政处罚建议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十八）机构恢复与处置司。拟订相关高风险机构风险处置制度、标准、程序，对出现严重风险、难以持续经营的机构开展风险处置等工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（十九）金融消费者权益保护局。拟订金融消费者权益保护发展规划和制度，开展金融消费者教育工作，承担相关金融产品合规性、适当性管理工作，组织调查处理侵害金融消费者合法权益案件，构建金融消费者投诉处理机制和金融消费纠纷多元化解机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十）打击非法金融活动局。建立非法金融活动监测预警体系和公开举报渠道，组织协调、指导督促有关部门和地方政府依法开展非法金融活动防范和处置工作，开展相关宣传教育、政策解释和业务指导等工作。对涉及跨部门跨地区和新业态新产品等非法金融活动，研究提出相关工作建议。拟订小额贷款公司、融资性担保公司、典当行、融资租赁公司、商业保理公司、地方资产管理公司等地方金融组织监管制度，指导和监督地方金融监管部门相关业务工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十一）稽查局。拟订稽查工作制度。组织对违法违规金融活动相关主体进行调查、取证，提出处理意见；涉嫌犯罪的，提出移送司法机关的建议。指导、检查金融机构安全保卫工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十二）行政处罚局。承担行政处罚案件审理等工作，提出审理意见，组织听证和集体讨论，送达行政处罚决定并执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十三）内审司（党委巡视工作领导小组办公室）。拟订系统内审和巡视工作制度、办法，监督检查系统贯彻落实有关重大决策部署情况，组织开展系统内审和巡视工作，对发现的问题及责任人提出处理建议，指导、监督、检查系统内审和巡察工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十四）国际合作司（港澳台办公室）。承担外事管理、国际合作和涉港澳台地区相关事务。承担外资银行的非现场监测、风险分析和监管评价等工作，根据风险监管需要开展现场调查，采取监管措施，开展个案风险处置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十五）人事教育司（党委组织部）。承担机关、派出机构和直属单位等的干部人事、机构编制、劳动工资、教育培训和离退休干部管理工作。指导行业人才队伍建设工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十六）财务会计司。承担财务管理工作，负责编报系统年度财务预决算。依法强化对银行业机构、保险业机构、金融控股公司等财会监督工作的督促指导。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;（二十七）党建工作局（党委宣传部）。承担国家金融监督管理总局党委落实全面从严治党主体责任相关工作。承担系统党的建设工作，指导系统基层党组织建设、党员队伍建设、党风廉政建设和反腐败工作。负责系统党的宣传工作。领导系统统战、群团组织工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;机关党委。负责机关及在京直属单位党的建设和纪检工作，领导机关群团组织的工作。机关党委设立机关纪委，承担机关及在京直属单位纪检、党风廉政建设有关工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局机关行政编制910名。设局长1名，副局长4名；司局级领导职数114名（含首席风险官、首席检查官、首席律师、首席会计师各1名，机关党委专职副书记1名，机关纪委书记1名）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十一条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局设立稽查总队，作为直属行政机构，正司级，负责相关案件的调查、取证，提出处理意见等。稽查总队的编制和领导职数另行规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十二条&lt;/strong>; 国家金融监督管理总局对派出机构实行垂直管理。国家金融监督管理总局地方派出机构、所属事业单位的设置、职责和编制事项另行规定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十三条&lt;/strong>; 本规定由中央机构编制委员会办公室负责解释，其调整由中央机构编制委员会办公室按规定程序办理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据机构编制管理权限，由国家金融监督管理总局党委决定、报中央机构编制委员会办公室备案的机构编制事项，按照有关规定执行。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第十四条&lt;/strong>; 本规定自2023年10月29日起施行&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《漫长的季节》文学策划考编上岸：反思“铁饭碗”的人为何拥抱“铁饭碗”？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260345]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-10 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，一则“作家考编”的新闻引发关注。2023年武汉市文联所属事业单位芳草杂志社公布了专项招聘名单，青年作家班宇、陈春成、王苏辛、淡豹（刘雪婷）在列。此事再次引发网友“宇宙的尽头是考编”的感叹。公示名单显示，班宇、陈春成与王苏辛“成功上岸”，淡豹则不幸名落孙山。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这则新闻的话题热度虽逊于去年的“明星考编”事件，但也提出了一些值得深入探讨的议题。此次“作家考编”之所以引发热议，还是因为在人设与选择上出了问题，让外界产生了强烈的违和感，这一点值得特别加以辨析。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;班宇曾被称为“东北文艺复兴三杰”之一，著有小说集《冬泳》，也是悬疑剧《漫长的季节》的文学策划。这部以上世纪末东北下岗潮为背景的热播剧，一大主旨就是对“铁饭碗”的反思，尤其是展现了其对人的束缚与异化。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;淡豹拥有社会学与人类学学习背景，她的文学作品关注性别、阶层议题，也专长于非虚构写作，长期以来以“关注现实”的面目示人，怎么看都与“编制”扯不上关系。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无怪乎有网友评论道，看到这则“作家考编”新闻，颇有一种“孙悟空考上天宫编制”“《冬泳》终于上岸”的感觉，其中淡豹还喜提了“申公豹”的网络绰号。原因无他，只因作家之前的作品与“人设”，与考编的行为出现较大反差，让读者产生违和感。对比淡豹曾在访谈中“一个人怎么写，他就怎么活着”的说法，“作家考编”的短短四个字已经让“怎么写”与“怎么活着”互相矛盾了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果说作家本人完全隐身于作品之外，并不希望读者“像吃了鸡蛋还要认识老母鸡”一样了解自己，那么“作家考编”就不会引发多么大的争议，比如那些深居简出、极少抛头露面也不搞营销的作家。问题在于，如今的文化界已经高度市场化，青年作家对外出售的除了文学作品，还有各种线上线下的访谈、演讲、见面会、分享会构筑的“人设”，也将这种鲜明的“个人IP”作为一种文化商品出售。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次考编的青年作家里，或多或少都在经营着市场化的人设，这种人设也帮助他们取得了作品的成功，甚至还有作品之外的成功，花钱买书的读者购买的就不止是作家的作品，也包括他们营销包装的“人设”，以及蕴藏其中的价值观与生活方式。读者期待他们实践人设，并对未能言行一致表示失望，这种失望也恰如其分。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平心而论，没有任何一条法律法规禁止这几名青年作家考编，自由开放的现代社会当然也允许一个人实践他的价值观与生活方式，但他们这种“华丽转身”也未免有些“突如其来”，自然难逃外界乃至追随者的疑问：他们为什么要去考取编制？编制又能给这些已经取得不小成功的青年作家带来什么？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公开资料显示，武汉市文学艺术理论研究所（芳草杂志社）是武汉市文联所属二级事业单位，业务范围主要是各项文学学术研究、编辑出版发行《芳草》文学期刊。官网公示的招考条件显示，报考者除了年龄要在40周岁以下之外，还需要满足“三项条件其中一项”：作品获得省级期刊文学奖项，在中文核心期刊或是省级以上出版社发表过30万字以上作品，作品入围过几个特定的文学排行榜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这次编制考试的招考条件可谓相当之高，三项条件恐怕就刷掉了绝大多数“普通做题家”。而从公示的成绩表与录取名单显示，此次“入编考试”分为专业能力评审、面试成绩两大类，最后依照综合成绩排名，并没有笔试环节，可见有别于普通的“考公考编”，称得上是为“青年作家”这个群体量身定做。试问，一家文学期刊为何拥有如此之高的招考要求，又为何可以吸引多名青年作家报考？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这些青年作家本已在市场取得了成功，也没有逃避竞争去“吃皇粮”的迫切需要，在体制内期刊从事文学理论或是编辑工作多少有些大材小用的味道。因此比较合理的推断是，编制带来的好处不是明面上的“铁饭碗”，而是可以为这些市场化作家提供更好的社会地位，或者说某种身份标记，青年作家之所以要求得一官半职的傍身，大约是可以把两头的好处都占了，这自然符合“理性经济人”的决策。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“学院憎恨天才，犹如修道院憎恨圣徒”早就是业界的共识。文学作品本就应该交给市场判断、交给读者选择，而不是一定要作家博得某个“盖章认证”，或是有一官半职傍身，其作品才能通行于世。几名青年作家遭遇的群嘲，也说明了这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>