<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[“永恒”的敌人：未了案横跨八十年，谁的“王洛宾”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260885]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 11, 2023, Zhuozhou, Hebei, Wang Haicheng&#39;s &quot;In That Faraway Land&quot; &quot;Place&quot; manuscript. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/1c70971ed9.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/1c70971ed9.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258759&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 11, 2023, Zhuozhou, Hebei Province, Wang Haicheng&#39;s manuscript of &quot;In That Distant Place&quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;A stage play&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312 , SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Only a few people realize that everything they enjoy at the moment is facing unprecedented challenges. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A quarter of an hour before 7:30, outside the West Second Ring Road in Beijing, a group of children and parents gathered in front of the Erqi Theater. It was a cool evening in early September, and the new version of the red children&#39;s drama &quot;The Ballad of Soybean&quot; began its national tour here. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some Chinese people are familiar with this story. In 1940, the Gansu Provincial Working Committee of the Communist Party of China was destroyed. Luo Lili, who was 8 months old, was arrested at the same time as his parents. After several twists and turns, he was imprisoned in Lanzhou Dashagou Prison, where he spent 6 years. Wang Luobin, who was also in prison, asked Luo Lili what the most delicious food in the world was. Luo Lili, who had never been exposed to the outside world, thought it was broad beans that he had eaten by chance. Wang Luobin composed the song &quot;Soybean Ballad&quot; from this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A while after leaving the venue, the crowd suddenly surrounded an old man. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The old man has appeared on CCTV 13 times. On TV, he is smart, wise, and tall. He is proud that he &quot;didn&#39;t make a single mistake&quot; when talking. &quot;, and sometimes, I even have to play and sing &quot;In That Distant Place&quot; on the stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But the old man in front of him has droopy eye bags and a lot of white hair on his sparse head. He kept taking out performance tickets from the small shoulder bag on his chest, a total of 40 tickets, which belonged to &quot;old friends&quot; he had met through cooperation in the name of his father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Most of these &quot;old friends&quot; reached the peak of their careers in the 1990s. They had their own programs in top media and were able to open solo concerts in the most central concert hall in Beijing. Concert, organize a commemorative concert for Wang Luobin in the most famous building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also officials from Zhuozhou, Hebei. This county-level city with a population of 650,000 has a 30-square-meter former residence of Wang Luobin and a Wang Luobin Chorus. The director of Zhuozhou Culture and Tourism Bureau and the director of the cultural center drove 60 kilometers to come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He is the youngest son of Wang Luobin, the &quot;King of Western Singers&quot;. Wang Luobin&#39;s ancestral home is in Zhuozhou, and a new Wang Luobin Music Memorial Hall is about to be renovated in an old factory in the north of the city as a local cultural landmark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin, who will appear on the stage in a quarter of an hour, is a &quot;prisoner&quot; who has to go through several political movements before he can be called the King of Singers in the future. , Prison Years, and Social Change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin&#39;s 83-year ups and downs often give playwrights a headache. He once participated in the Northwest Anti-Japanese War Theater Troupe with Xiao Jun, Seke and others. He was also highly appreciated by the warlord Ma Bufang and formed a children&#39;s theater troupe in Qinghai. During China&#39;s darkest period, he captured a hint of romanticism, and some of the songs he was most proud of in his life were born here, including &quot;In That Distant Place&quot; and &quot;Youth Dance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At half past seven, &quot;Soybean Ballad&quot; started. I got a chance to film Wang Haicheng, a documentary director who has been following him for more than ten years. The film is called &quot;Looking for Wang Luobin&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the &quot;old friends&quot; in the audience, some people want to promote this drama to a bigger stage, and some people want to make a movie related to Wang Luobin. , two people respectively proposed to build a music school named after the king of singers in Hebei and Hainan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They all need to obtain authorization from Wang Haicheng. Only a few people realize that everything the son of the King of Songs enjoys at the moment is facing unprecedented challenges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 11, 2023, in Zhuozhou, Hebei, Wang Haicheng showed his published biography of Wang Luobin and audio and video products. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ae52930ca3.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/19/ae52930ca3.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258760&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;September 11, 2023 On the same day, in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province, Wang Haicheng displayed his published biography of Wang Luobin and audio-visual products. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;SON OF THE SINGER&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Family has never been a place where the singer is willing to devote his attention&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng has spent half his life defending his father&#39;s honor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin has two marriages, three sons and several loves. Among the three sons, the eldest went to Australia in the 1980s. The second child was a truck driver and died of illness. After surviving a period of history, the four fathers and sons now only have the third child left. Therefore, interviews, authorizations, rights protection, concerts, commemorations, and publications all fell on Wang Haicheng. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, for a long time, the identity of &quot;Wang Luobin&#39;s son&quot; made Wang Haicheng breathless. When he was 8 months old, Wang Luobin was arrested, followed by a search of his home. A month later, his mother passed away in the hospital bed. Relatives in Beijing did not dare to have contact with the Wang family. After hearing about it, the fifth uncle in Zhuozhou drove a carriage all day and night from Beijing in the early winter in the north to bring the body back from Beijing and bury it in a wheat field. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A few years ago, Wang Haicheng tried to find his mother&#39;s tomb, but he could no longer find it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Studying stopped in the second grade of junior high school. When it was time to go to the mountains and countryside, Wang Haicheng stayed on the farm for nine years because of Wang Luobin. When groups of educated young people returned to the city one after another, he also got a nickname: &quot;Cushionzi&quot;. This dialect refers to the last puppy out of a litter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Family is never a place where the singer is willing to devote his attention. Wang Haicheng wrote that the union between his father and his mother was due to the breakup of his father&#39;s previous relationship, so he wanted to take revenge on his life. Wang Luobin was born free. He went to the grassland, to the market, and even in prison, collecting folk songs. A producer who visited the singer&#39;s deeds mentioned a detail. In his later years, Wang Luobin rode a bicycle everywhere. When it got dark, he would lie on the road and fall asleep, and then go home the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin passed away in 1996. Wang Haicheng immediately joined the China Music Copyright Association and registered 207 musical works recorded, organized and created by Wang Luobin with the association. He became increasingly aware that his father had left a shining legacy. Since 2000, Wang Haicheng has successively published two biographies of Wang Luobin, a song sheet of Wang Luobin, invested in TV films, and a long narrative poem. Four exhibition halls have been created in Turpan, Xinjiang, Haibei, Qinghai, Baishui Ancient Town, Dabancheng, Xinjiang, and Liupan Mountain, Ningxia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is difficult to say how father&#39;s love plays a subtle role in Wang Haicheng&#39;s life. In order to guard this heritage, he was like an ascetic, stationed in the Grape Valley of the Flame Mountain for 16 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the first few years of the 21st century, the Turpan Wang Luobin Music and Art Museum in Grape Valley was the only temple to commemorate the king of singers. This building has an Ottoman-style white circular dome and 80 panels displaying the singer&#39;s life. Visitors came in the 40℃ high temperature. When they opened the door, they saw the sweaty son of the singer wearing a shirt with Wang Luobin&#39;s logo in front of him. There were biographies, song collections, tapes and records on the counter. When the operation of the art museum was most difficult, Wang Haicheng went to bring in strange stones from the Gobi Desert that looked like pork belly and English letters. This is the most popular commodity in Xinjiang’s tourism market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He also set up an incense burner in front of his father&#39;s portrait - Wang Luobin converted to Buddhism in his later years. There was once a man who claimed to be a physicist and kowtowed three times directly to the portrait. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng honed his speaking skills, pondered the details of his father&#39;s life, paid attention to his image, and never refused any opportunity to appear in the national media. The comment that moved him most came from an old man from Shandong: &quot;Wang Haicheng, you are the biggest filial son in China.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On July 24, 2022, Wang Luobin Music was located in Putaogou, Turpan, Xinjiang Art Museum. (Visual China/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dc0cd8871e.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height =&quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dc0cd8871e.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258761&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 24, 2022, Wang Luobin Music Art Museum is located in Grape Valley, Turpan, Xinjiang. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Salvage and Debate&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;Changing one note, two notes, or a chorus counts as &quot;adaptation&quot;? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the 1990s, a modern storm swept through Urumqi: the most cutting-edge local popular music came from further west. Ethnic minorities hold weekly house music gatherings. Seven days and nights after the song &quot;Forgetting Love Water&quot; reached Urumqi, the shops in the Grand Bazaar would use rough-sounding speakers to play versions in other languages. The bars all over the street are full of singing bands. On the radio, the male host can talk endlessly about the Beatles, Tchaikovsky and Rachmaninoff. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yibo, the director of &quot;Looking for Wang Luobin&quot;, was the popular host of the Urumqi Economic Radio program &quot;Music Leisure Island&quot; at the time. After more than 20 years, she believes that Urumqi at that time showed tolerance for all kinds of music and was the &quot;center of Asian music.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But there is no local singer&#39;s name in popular music. His limelight comes from outside Urumqi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin was rediscovered in the context of an era where order was brought to order. In May 1981, on an afternoon when the temperature suddenly soared to 33°C and the snow suddenly melted, in a five- to six-square-meter concierge at the Qianjin Theater, Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhao Quanzhang met Wang Luobin, who had just been released from prison. In Zhao Quanzhang&#39;s reminiscence article, this person who looked like Quasimodo in &quot;The Hunchback of Notre Dame&quot; was unemployed, had no household registration, and did not even have &quot;food and oil connections.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Zhao Quanzhang wrote the internal reference for Wang Luobin, and soon received instructions from Song Renqiong, then head of the Organization Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. Zhao Quanzhang once recalled that the work of bringing order to the country was not completely smooth at that time. The resolution of Wang Luobin&#39;s problem had an impact on Xinjiang and the whole country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Openness was the theme of the 1980s. And for a musician who has experienced the war of resistance, prison, and rehabilitation, is there any symbol more suitable to glimpse a country&#39;s path of exploration? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the autumn of 1988, &quot;Eight Thousand Miles to the Clouds and the Moon&quot; hosted by Taiwanese artist Ling Feng went to Xinjiang to interview Wang Luobin. This was the first program from the other side to introduce China. TV programs about mainland China’s customs and customs. Then, Xia Jie, a female writer from Hong Kong, China, also came to visit and wrote three articles. Soon, Singapore, Australia, North America, and overseas Chinese had someone to pay attention to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The media calls him the King of Western Singers and enjoys special government subsidies. China Record Corporation awarded him the Golden Record Special Creation Award, and UNESCO awarded him the &quot;Promote &quot;Special Contribution Award for Cultural Exchange between East and West&quot;. But all the medals are inferior to the gifts given by the people. In the era when the word &quot;fan&quot; only refers to fans, Wang Luobin&#39;s most proud example is, &quot;Chinese friends said that at least half of the two million Chinese in the United States can sing. &quot;In that distant place&quot;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A more well-known story is that Sanmao, a female writer from Taiwan, China, moved directly into the home of the singer, and scandals abounded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Trouble is coming quietly. One day in 1993, Luo Dayou&#39;s agent called. Not long ago, Rolling Stone Records released the tape &quot;Love Song Anniversary - Luo Dayou and Wang Luobin&#39;s Great Collaboration of the Century&quot; without Wang Luobin&#39;s consent. The King of Songs was very angry and took Luo Dayou to court for infringement of his copyright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Greater controversy ensued. Someone revealed that Ling Feng paid 20,000 yuan to buy out ten of Wang Luobin&#39;s songs, including &quot;In That Faraway Place&quot;, &quot;The Girl from Dabancheng&quot;, &quot;Mayila&quot; and &quot;Youth Dance&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The music issue soon turned into a political issue. Someone asked, can Wang Luobin sell folk songs that belong to the people? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A major discussion that lasted for more than a year began. In June 1994, &quot;People&#39;s Music&quot; magazine began to discuss the copyright issue of Wang Luobin&#39;s folk songs. Dai Penghai, an associate researcher at the Shanghai Conservatory of Music, published two articles criticizing the news media for hyping up Wang Luobin, and also accused Wang Luobin of &quot;selling out the people&#39;s sovereignty and interests in national music culture.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;There are also people who support Wang Luobin. Liu Zaisheng, a professor at the Music Department of Shandong Normal University, pointed out that “collecting brotherly ethnic songs in different languages ​​is a more complex and difficult task, and the translation and dubbing of lyrics often plays a key role in success or failure.” And “if we combine the When the lyrics are analyzed together, it is not difficult to find that they have formed Wang Luobin&#39;s unique creative style that is lyrical, colloquial, and popular.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another background to the great discussion is that during China&#39;s &quot;resumption of customs&quot; negotiations, the Copyright Law was promulgated in 1991, which stipulates that &quot;adaptation, translation, The copyright of works resulting from the annotation and arrangement of existing works shall be enjoyed by the person who adapted, translated, annotated and arranged them.&quot; In other words, if Wang Luobin &quot;adapts, translates, annotates, and organizes&quot; folk songs, the copyright of the new songs belongs to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But, does changing one note, two notes, or a chorus count as &quot;adaptation&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On August 5 of that year, a symposium attended by more than thirty people was held in Beijing, including musicologists, composers, and legal professionals. people and journalists. The person presiding over the meeting was Qiao Jianzhong, then director of the Music Research Institute of the China Academy of Arts. He later recalled in an article that this symposium was actually an &quot;absent criticism&quot; against Wang Luobin, which was very explosive. However, the meeting finally reached a consensus that Wang Luobin had worked hard in recording, translating, editing, and adapting folk songs, but the rights he enjoyed needed to be quantitatively analyzed before the rights could be determined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The eighty-year-old singer was very hurt and left the stage to participate in the debate in person several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the death of Wang Luobin in 1996, the big discussion did not continue. But this discussion could have clarified some fundamental issues, such as the quantitative standards for adaptation and the copyright of folk songs. In that era, Wang Luobin was not the only one who encountered similar problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Shanghai, a young man who was writing &quot;The Complete Works of Xian Xinghai&quot; was also troubled by this problem. In the process of sorting out Xian Xinghai&#39;s works, Wu Yuebei, a top student in the composition department of the Shanghai Conservatory of Music, checked and filled in the original scores. Some melodies that he thought were not harmonious even needed to be changed. When Xian Xinghai&#39;s descendants heard about Wang Luobin&#39;s dispute, they worriedly asked, if the original score was adjusted, would the copyright belong to him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After consulting the leaders of the Ministry of Culture at the time, &quot;The Complete Works of Xian Xinghai&quot; was finally processed as follows: the works with major changes were also included in the revised original works. version, as well as a more substantial adapted version. For revised or revised editions, the name of the reviser will be marked as a footnote at the end of the work, but no copyright will be generated. The edited version will have a copyright page marked with the name of the organizer, who owns the rights to the content compiled by him in the new version, but not the rights to the original work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This young man majoring in composition has no way of knowing that after more than 20 years, he may end the discussion about the copyright of the singer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wang Luobin and Luo Dayou. Reproduced from the photo album saved by Wang Haicheng on September 11, 2023. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/19/449cb5c56b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image /23/11/19/449cb5c56b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258762&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Luobin and Luo Dayou. Reproduced from the photo album saved by Wang Haicheng on September 11, 2023. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Carpet rights protection&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;His opponents include video city vendors, publishing houses, university professors, as well as Li Yuchun, Tan Weiwei and Wang Sulong. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The new century is coming, and the law has become a modern weapon to protect rights and interests. Wang Haicheng suddenly discovered that everything his father left behind could be easily taken away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, China was in the midst of a heat wave to achieve modernization through a market economy. The &quot;resumption of customs&quot; turned into &quot;joining the WTO&quot;, a stable and international The integrated legal system is gradually improving. Intellectual property rights are a focus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2002, Wang Luobin&#39;s adaptation of &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; was sued by the family of a deceased musician for copyright infringement. The family members believe that &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; is not a folk song, but a song composed by the late musician, originally titled &quot;How Beautiful My Garden is.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The family did not sue Wang Haicheng directly, but first sued an audio-visual company in Guangzhou. The CD published by the company labeled &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; as a folk song. The court found that the song was composed by the late musician. Afterwards, the family took this judgment and sued Wang Haicheng, claiming 230,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng said that &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; was written by his father in 1969 while serving a sentence. At that time, a young man was unjustly imprisoned, and his new wife died. The young man stopped cutting his hair and shaving. Wang Luobin felt inspired and adapted &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; based on an Ili folk song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A friend in Yili told Wang Haicheng that the original version of this ancient folk song can be found in the local archives. But before he was about to leave, the friend said that the information was missing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In August 2004, the court of first instance sentenced Wang Haicheng to pay compensation of 237,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the appeal, Wang Haicheng and his lawyer began to think about how to collect evidence. In October 2005, he and his lawyer pretended to be collectors from Beijing and spent 4,600 yuan to buy a small video camera. After arriving in Yili, they arranged to grab mutton and invited local music teachers and old people who could sing folk songs for interviews. At first, they did not reveal their interest in &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; and started talking about Ili folk songs. The cameras are always working. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the conversation was almost over, Wang Haicheng turned to &quot;Tall White Poplar&quot; and asked if there was an original folk song version of this song. Everyone said yes, and everyone hummed a line. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But when they reveal their identities, very few people are willing to testify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After hitting a wall one after another, they finally found three old people willing to testify. I also met an &quot;Avanti&quot; (meaning &quot;teacher&quot;) named Ishamuddin, who said that the original song had probably been circulated for two hundred years, and he also knew that a lawsuit was ongoing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, Wang Haicheng thought that if he lost the lawsuit, &quot;things would develop like dominoes.&quot; Dozens of publishers had published this song Society will also be in crisis. Even if he travels to Hainan, he will pray with Mazu, hoping that Mazu can help him, the son of the king of singers, who is in trouble. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On May 8, 2006, the Xinjiang High Court made a judgment that the two songs each enjoyed property rights in copyright. In Wang Haicheng&#39;s words, &quot;Both songs come from folk songs, and they are in a parallel relationship.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At almost the same time, Wang Haicheng launched a blanket rights protection campaign that lasted for several years. For the sake of copyright, he fought against pirated CDs, KTV bosses, and singers who randomly covered his father&#39;s works. His opponents include audio-visual city vendors, publishers, university professors, as well as Li Yuchun, Tan Weiwei and Wang Sulong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It was in 2004 when he was ordered to pay 237,000 yuan in compensation that Wang Haicheng received an unfamiliar phone call. The other party introduced himself like this: Ju Yonghe, a native of Jiangsu, a lawyer in Beijing, and a loyal fan of Wang Luobin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When they finally met a year later, Wang Haicheng was deeply impressed by his &quot;uprightness and non-joking&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;He said that he was concerned that there were many publications infringing Wang Luobin&#39;s rights on the market, and he especially wanted to help protect his rights.&quot; Wang Haicheng was &quot;a little nervous financially at the time, and he was also weighing Should I file a lawsuit?&quot; Lawyer Ju dispelled his concerns: He would bear the cost of the lawsuit. If he lost the lawsuit, he would not ask Wang Haicheng for money. If he won, he would pay half of it after deducting travel expenses. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This may be a more subtle way, and it also uses legal weapons to confirm again and again that Wang Luobin owns the copyright to a certain song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2005, Lawyer Ju has continued to make efforts. He went to the audio and video market and Xinhua Bookstore, walked around, saw the allegedly infringing publications, bought them, issued invoices, and sued. &quot;All those audio and video publishers came to me to ask for authorization. They can also use high-definition pictures of Wang Luobin on the covers of their publications. I also provided the introduction of Wang Luobin on the inside pages. It is more accurate and the text is smoother.&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin became an inviolable icon. Around 2010, Lawyer Ju moved to KTV. In the words of the time, it was a &quot;mopping up&quot; operation. KTV&#39;s infringement made Wang Haicheng even more intolerable. The scenes in &quot;In That Distant Place&quot; were of Hainan beaches and bikini beauties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Based on the Yangtze River Delta, Lawyer Ju gradually expanded the scope of his operations. In his eyes, &quot;the judicial environment in the Yangtze River Delta was relatively good at the time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Victory is like a snowball getting bigger and bigger. In the eyes of some people in the music industry, even what didn&#39;t belong to him before, now belongs to him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to Wang Haicheng, the economic benefits in this round were not as much as people imagined. The compensation involved in the case that he received was &quot;about 120,000 yuan.&quot; &quot;. But he is very happy and feels that this battle is going smoothly and &quot;the pirated KTVs have been beaten into silence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In this battle, he gave himself an indestructible meaning: to maintain his father&#39;s eternal status in the history of Chinese music. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But this blanket rights protection came to an abrupt end in 2013, and Wang Haicheng was put in a tight ring. After mediation by the Supreme People&#39;s Court, Wang Luobin&#39;s descendants reached an agreement: some of the previous lawsuits should be withdrawn. &quot;If the lawsuit cannot be withdrawn, the accepting authority should proactively notify the accepting agency to add Wang Haiyan (eldest brother) and Wang Haixing (second brother) as co-litigants. Everything involving Mr. Wang Luobin&#39;s intellectual property rights All litigation actions should be jointly made by three persons (Wang Haiyan, Wang Haixing and Wang Haicheng) to make substantive decisions.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It will be 6 years before Lawyer Ju appears again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 10, 2023, Wang Haicheng came to an old factory in Zhuozhou, Hebei, where the Wang Luobin Music Memorial Hall is being planned. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Photo)&quot; src=&quot;http: //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7f942b41f0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm. com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7f942b41f0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258763&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023 On September 10, Wang Haicheng came to an old factory in Zhuozhou, Hebei Province, where the Wang Luobin Music Memorial Hall is being planned. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Xunge&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, SimKai , STKaiti;&quot;>;On nights like this in the 1970s, Wang Haicheng asked his silent father again and again: I heard that there is a song that is also yours? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin left behind a world of lush water and grass, where there were young birds, rivers, long-braided Dabancheng girls, and most of all, It is important to praise the courage of love at all times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the world left behind by his father, Wang Haicheng spent more than twenty years marking the birth and origin of each symbol, the youthful bird and the long-braided Da. Bancheng Girl was born in 1938, while Alam Khan did not appear until May 1944. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​reason is that Wang Luobin rarely signs his name. He compiled a book called &quot;Song of the Northwest&quot; related to the Anti-Japanese War. The back cover said &quot;Compiled and printed by the Gansu People&#39;s Anti-Enemy Support Association.&quot; Wang Luobin said in his autobiography, &quot;I think this work is a citizen&#39;s duty.&quot; In this special era, many of his songs were not signed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Hai wrote three biographies of his father, a large part of which is about tracing his father&#39;s creative story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But it was 1974 when he first heard his father talk about his creative motivations. One day, the father and son went to a friend&#39;s house to celebrate their child&#39;s full moon. With the wine mixed with alcohol, everyone booed and asked Wang Haicheng to sing. He took over the guitar, finished singing &quot;Manli&quot;, and vividly talked about the origin of the song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;There was a pair of lovers on the Mongolian grasslands. During the Anti-Japanese War, the man signed up to join the army to fight. The woman heard from the rear that the man had died. She was very sad and died of illness. &quot;The man came back from the war and heard that his fiancée was dead, so he ran to the cemetery and sang this song in front of her grave. Suddenly, this woman stood up from behind the grave again.&quot; Wang Haicheng recalled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin, who was no longer very talkative, took a sip of wine and said: &quot;Today is so interesting. My son sang a song by Lao Tzu. I didn&#39;t know that the song was from Lao Tzu.&quot; &quot;Written.&quot; It was a pornographic song, and criticism of it reached its peak in the 1950s. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;More stories were collected during the period when I temporarily lived with my father at my second brother’s house. Father and son sleep in a small room together, with two beds on the left and right and a window in the middle. During the day, Wang Luobin opened the bed and used the bed board as a table to copy music scores. &quot;He did not forget to revise the songs while copying them, and he sang them while writing.&quot; At night, the mosquitoes kept the two awake. On nights like this in the 1970s, Wang Haicheng asked his silent father again and again: I heard that there is a song that is also yours? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But this experience will not be helpful until Wang Haicheng writes his father&#39;s biography 30 years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After his father passed away, it became more difficult to find songs. The problem of songs was sometimes a legal issue, and sometimes even a political issue. There is only one song whose origin does not need to be searched by Wang Haicheng, and that is &quot;In That Distant Place&quot;, the &quot;Crown Pearl&quot; of the King of Western Songs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1939, Wang Luobin followed director Zheng Junli to Qinghai to shoot the movie &quot;Long Live the Nation&quot;. Dolma, the daughter of a Tibetan head of thousands of households, was chosen to be the shepherdess. Wang Luobin Become a helper. While driving the sheep, Wang Luobin accidentally whipped his horse&#39;s buttocks. Dolma on the horse swung the whip and hit Wang Luobin gently. Thus, there is the plot in the lyrics: &quot;I would like to be a little lamb/follow her side/I would like her to hold a whip/keep hitting me gently every day.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The singer himself has told this story to the media too many times. But maybe it’s just that there are so many stories that one day in the future, people with a heart will begin to compare the time, place and characters of each story, and discover flaws that are difficult to correct. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Luobin also told actor Ma Yue. The actor won the second prize in bel canto singing in the amateur group of the Youth Singing Competition in his early years. Once he held a solo concert at the Beijing Opera House. After singing &quot;In That Far Place&quot;, an old man with a goatee came to him and said, &quot;Ma Yue, you look a lot like me when I was young.&quot; Second. The sentence is, &quot;You sang my song inaccurately.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;That was 1994 when the big discussion was launched. The singer pointed out two of his mistakes, one of which was that the tune was wrong, &quot;I was in prison, and you were singing my songs outside. Now I sing the song back to its original form, and everyone says I sang it wrong. I You can&#39;t change it back.&quot; - Many people don&#39;t know that the widely sung &quot;In That Faraway Place&quot; is indeed not the version written by Wang Luobin. His version and the score are now engraved on his tombstone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Afterwards, the two met twice, and the singer added about the spread of the song. He said, &quot;Among the frontline anti-Japanese officers and soldiers, there are many people who sing. Why? Because there is a good girl in the heart of every anti-Japanese soldier.&quot; This young man, whose career was on the rise, realized that &quot;all of Wang Luobin&#39;s works grew out of the soil of the nation.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wang Haicheng and his father Wang Luobin (right). (Interviewee/picture)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /19/32f0379936.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1516&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/32f0379936.jpg &quot; data-key=&quot;258764&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wang Haicheng and his father Wang Luobin (right). (Interviewee/picture)&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Okay, let’s fight to the end”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics , Italics_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;The courier in the community delivers express delivery to the court every day. I am very confused, what on earth did this family commit? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The day after the performance of &quot;Soybean Ballad&quot;, one of Wang Luobin&#39;s students entertained Wang Haicheng for a banquet. When the food was over, she asked seriously if she needed help. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Old friends are worried for a reason. The second round of rights protection launched by Wang Haicheng in 2019 has just suffered a defeat. In June 2023, the Beijing Intellectual Property Court&#39;s final judgment determined that Wang Luobin and his descendants no longer enjoyed the copyright of &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;, &quot;Four Seasons Tune&quot; and &quot;Under the Silver Moonlight&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9 months ago, the Intermediate Court of Yangzhou City, Jiangsu Province identified Wang Luobin as the copyright holder of &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Different from the rights protection that came to an abrupt end ten years ago, the defendants this time are mostly professionals in the music industry and publishing houses. Among the list are Gong Yaonian, a national first-class composer, Hu Tingjiang, deputy director of the Composition Department of the China Conservatory of Music, and the People&#39;s Music Publishing House. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The dispute mainly focuses on whether the music presented in these composers&#39; publications is plagiarized or adapted from Wang Luobin&#39;s version. &lt;p>; Arrangement&quot;. This aroused Wang Haicheng&#39;s dissatisfaction. In his opinion, 9 films including &quot;In That Distant Place&quot; belong to Wang Luobin. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Using an inappropriate metaphor proposed by the other party, it is the relationship between grandfather and grandson. We believe that grandfather must be a folk work, which is relatively stable. &quot;Li Ye, deputy director of the editorial office of People&#39;s Music Publishing House, said, &quot;But to use the other party&#39;s words in court, &#39;Wang Luobin is the grandfather, and the rest of you are all grandchildren.&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;The defendants also raised questions based on this, believing that some of Wang Luobin&#39;s songs were not &quot;adapted&quot; at all, and were even directly &quot;copied&quot; from other people&#39;s creations. The family members of one of the defendants also discovered that the authenticity of those stories written by Wang Haicheng and the song king&#39;s creation is open to question. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This defendant&#39;s family member is Wu Yuebei, the young man who participated in the compilation of &quot;The Complete Works of Xian Xinghai&quot; more than 20 years ago. He is now a professor at the Central Conservatory of Music and a doctoral supervisor in composition. The defendant Gong Yaonian is his father-in-law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The second round of rights are turbulent. At the beginning, the defendants each fought. Hu Tingjiang, the earliest prosecution, adapted a &quot;Marrayam&quot;. In just this song, the lawyer of the residence sued him nearly a hundred times in many courts across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Hu Tingjiang recalled that he had been prosecuted, and there were still many puzzles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Around 2017, Wang Haicheng suddenly added Hu Tingjiang WeChat to inform him of the adaptation of &quot;May&quot; from Wang Luobin&#39;s &quot;May&quot;, and he needs to get his own. Authorization. Hu Tingjiang replied to respect Mr. Wang Luobin, but &quot;Marra&quot; was not created by Wang Luobin, but a well -known Kazakh folk song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Once, Wang Haicheng sent a message and praised Hu Tingjiang&#39;s adaptation very successful. He hoped that he would continue to work hard and adapt a few more Wang Luobin&#39;s works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In June 2017, Wang Haicheng sent another solo concert list of Changji College, which was printed with the words &quot;Young Dance&quot; Hu Tingjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It didn&#39;t take long for him to be prosecuted. The subpoena was sent from all over the country, and Hu Tingjiang remembered that the courier in the community was sent to the court courier every day, and he was very puzzled, &quot;What did this family commit?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Until a trial live broadcast, Hu Tingjiang, who was fighting alone, learned that Gong Yaonian was also prosecuted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Soon, these prosecution professors, musicians, and publishers formed an alliance of interoperability information. There are 43 people in the &quot;Wang Luobin Copywriter Case, and there are more than a dozen publishing houses in the&quot; Music Publishing Unite &quot;. Different from those KTV and audiovisual companies that have been sued by the son of the king of the song, the people in the &quot;alliance&quot; uphold such beliefs: even if they are only claimed with 10,000 yuan, they must make the reason clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On the afternoon of April 20, 2023, 29 years after the discussion was launched, another symposium was held at the People&#39;s Music Publishing House called &quot;National Folk Music Work Protection -Wang Luobin&#39;s descendants of the Western Folk Song Copyright Dispute Case &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On this day, Li Yan once doubted that some publishers far away from Shanghai and Hunan would send representatives to this meeting with only half a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On that day, she was surprised to find that more than thirty publishing houses, many of them were present in person. At the meeting, some people admitted that they did hesitate to the court&#39;s subpoena before: (Wang Haicheng) It costs 10,000 yuan a song to bargain with him, and 5,000 can be reconciled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Someone later proposed that it was not money. Finally, everyone formed a consistent opinion, okay, let&#39;s go to the end.&quot; Li Yan said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another consensus reached by the conference is that &quot;the legislative level should be introduced as soon as possible&quot; to &quot;realize the law can be rely on, avoid the same case in the judicial practice, &quot;Different judgment&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In fact, the original provisions of the copyright law introduced in 1991 that &quot;the copyright protection measures of folk literature and art works are separately stipulated by the State Council.&quot; But there is no following. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The most active Hu Tingjiang, northern Wu Yue, etc., turned the libraries of the Central Conservatory of Music, the Chinese Academy of Music and the China Institute of Music, and even Also find original information from the Moscow Library of Kazakhstan and the Moscow Library in Russia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; After more than three years of searching and research, Wu Yue north now believes that he can complete the tasks that the teachers have not completed many years ago and put Wang Luobin down the altar . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At the end of September 2023, I met Wu Yue in a community near Wanshou Park, Beijing. He has a majestic national face, and he has a tired elegance when he walks. Beside a piano, he prepared a chair and a laptop for me, which contained evidence he collected. Earlier, he had to bring two things, a Bluetooth speaker, and a luggage full of physical evidence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This composer made me stare at the computer screen carefully. Then, he closed his eyes and repeated everything he had investigated in the past 4 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;September 15, 2023, Beijing, Wu Yue north shows the evidence he collected in the computer. Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/c8081ce523.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com// CMS/MEDIAS/Image/23/11/19/C8081ce523.jpg &quot;Data-key =&quot; 258765 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; text-align: center; &quot;>; September 2023 On the 15th, Beijing, Wu Yue north showed the evidence he collected in the computer. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; &quot;Pearl on the Crown&quot; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body style _GB2312, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Speaking of&quot; In the Far Place &quot;, the person they think of is Chen Tianhe. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; On March 31, 1946, a student society named Shan Ge Club was announced at the National Music Institute of Qingmuguan in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Shange is the product of the student movement. Earlier, the authorities planned to cancel the subsidies of the student&#39;s consumption of coal and were opposed by the students. After the &quot;Coal Incident&quot;, students began to seek autonomy in a school in the subtropical canyon. At the same time, they couldn&#39;t wait to find some deeper things from the soil of folk songs from the soil of folk songs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At that time, the situation was unknown, but this group of music students began to worry more eternal issues. In the first series of &quot;Chinese Folk Songs&quot; they printed, there is such a wish: &quot;After analyzing these folk songs, the problems that have not been paid attention to in Western composition can be produced. . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; There was no way to pick the style at the time. According to a memories article by Xie Gongcheng, the first series of&quot; Chinese Folk Song &quot;was from&quot; New Music &quot; Magazine, Yan&#39;an&#39;s small singing book, Wang Luobin&#39;s &quot;Northwest Folk Song Collection&quot; and private relationships, more than a hundred national songs collected. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This &quot;Northwest Folk Song Collection&quot; was published in Chongqing in 1942. At the end of 1939, Wang Luobin gave the manuscript to the reporter Zhang Xiluo, a reporter from Chongqing in Xining to publish it, and Zhang Xiluo found the opportunity until he opened the Dagong Bookstore. The collection of the Capital Library shows that the song collection contains 17 songs, and there is no &quot;in the distant place&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; During the collection of &quot;Chinese Folk Songs&quot;, the students of the piano group were responsible for the accompaniment, and the vocal group was responsible for the singing. There are two teachers joining, namely the professor of the composer and the director of the teaching affairs, Chen Tianhe, and the professor and director of the composition department, Jiang Dingxian. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; History has a bifurcation here. Although Volkswagen regards Wang Luobin as the benchmark of the western folk songs, the college faction has also paid attention to Wang Luobin, but in the music education of professional colleges, the history of the folk song system has begun to start with the &quot;folk song movement&quot; of the Shan Song Club. When it comes to &quot;Alamu Khan&quot;, they will think of Xie Gongcheng&#39;s four chorus adapted in 1945; when it comes to &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;, he will think of Jiang Dingxian; and when it comes to the &quot;Pearl on the Crown&quot; of the Song King, The person they think of is Chen Tianhe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; There is only one reason. The accompaniment of this song popular version is equipped with Chen Tianhe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wu Yuebei looks for clues from Wang Luobin&#39;s own words. &quot;People&#39;s Music&quot; magazine published an article &quot;History is fair&quot; written by Wang Luobin in 1994, which mentioned that &quot;in the distant place&quot; can allow his colleagues, a lady named Ug Huiying to testify as a testimony. &quot;It can not only prove that this song was written by me, but also proved that this song should have copyright.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Ugly Huiying at the time was the chairman of the Taipei Music Copyright Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wu Yuebei found the &quot;Northwest Folk Song Collection&quot; compiled by Ugly Huiying in 1967. A total of 88 songs, 84 of which are edited by Ugly Huiying, and &quot;in the distant place&quot; is marked as Chen Tianhe arranged. Interestingly, the version of Chen Tianhe is currently a small version, and it is engraved with the tombstone of Wang Luobin, which is a big version. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1994, Ugly Huiying presented a &quot;Selection of the Chinese National Ballad&quot; by her in 1982 by her in 1982. Nothing was marked with her name. As for &quot;In the Far&quot;, only &quot;Qinghai Folk Songs&quot; are written. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; These two versions seem to contradict each other. From the north of Wu Yue, two key issues are explained. First of all, there is no version of Wang Luobin published by Ug Huiying. Secondly, according to the analysis of Wu Yuebei, the reason why the second version has the names of ugly Huiying and Chen Tianhe, it is that the version of the &quot;removed &#39;part&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; This is actually an old topic in the 1990s discussion. What exactly is the difference between &quot;adaptation, sorting&quot; and &quot;notes&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the north of Wu Yue, the arrangement is on the basis of the original work. It simplifies the complicated works by increasing or decreased and deleted. The work, plus his own play, becomes a readable vernacular work. The adaptation must be incremental, for example, a folk song is changed to a symphony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; And, folk songs have its particularity. The folk song is a song created by the public. The words and songs have been continuously polished and deformed by countless people. According to different times and place, different versions will be generated. Wu Yuebei also gives an example, &quot;You change the&quot; In front of the bed, the moonlight &quot;to the&quot; In front of the window, the moonlight &quot;, are you going to replace Li Bai?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He found a &quot;Selection of Chinese People&#39;s Songs&quot; published by Shan Ge Society in 1946, which selected a small version of &quot;In the Far Far&quot;, which stated that &quot;Chen Tianhe is accompanied by accompaniment&quot;. According to the survey of Wu Yue, a female student in Qinghai sang to Chen Tianhe in 1945, and the latter spent the piano song for this. Wang Luobin&#39;s version was officially published in 1983 &quot;Selection of Luobin Songs&quot;. Wang Luobin knew that the existence of a small version was also attached to the book, but he explained that this was the result of the female student who went to school in Chongqing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In some circulating statements, the female student was Ugly Huiying, who graduated from Chongqing National Music Institute in 1947. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The memoir called &quot;Walking through the Memory Star&quot; also inadvertently mentioned Ugly Huiying and Wang Luobin. This book was written by Luo Wenzhi, the vice president of the former Ningxia Huangpu Military Academy Association, and wrote his son Luo Jiyuan in 2010. It is mentioned that in August 1993, Luo Wenzhi met with Tang Ying Ugly Huiying in Beijing. During the chat, Ug Huiying said that in 1993, Wang Luobin reunited with her in Taipei, and learned that she had spread her &quot;The Far Far&quot;, &quot;Youth Dance&quot; and &quot;Daban City Girl in Dazya City&quot; in Qinghai for many years. Folk songs are very emotional. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Pearl on the crown&quot;. According to Liang Maochun, a professor at the Central Conservatory of Music, in 1940, a musical named &quot;Flower of the Desert&quot; was staged in Xining. The &quot;New Music&quot; magazine published in November 1942 reported the matter. The &quot;Songlin&quot; magazine published in December of the following year records the complete script and music of the play. In the preface of &quot;The Song of Desert&quot;, Wang Luobin mentioned that the episodes used in the play are all Kazakh people&#39;s songs, with new words. &quot;I Want to Be a Shepherd&quot;, which is the predecessor of &quot;The Far Far&quot;, appeared in the first act. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; History meets the narrow road here, but as the parties leave the world one by one, some statements have been difficult to verify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 2023, the opinion of the lawyer is that the signature on any or several &quot;earliest publications&quot; cannot prove that the signature is 80 80 Author of a certain song a year ago. He also made an example: &quot;A watch on a person&#39;s wrist, and life experience tells us that the person wearing a watch is the owner of the watch, and the person who does not need to wear a watch provides any other evidence to prove it. And their descendants have claimed their rights, exercise their rights, and defend their rights for songs such as &quot;Kangding Love Song&quot;, &quot;Four Seasons&quot;, &quot;Mayera&quot;. No one else has proposed rights proposal in the past 40 years. Anti-evidence. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; north of Wu Yue, why did the students of the music department that year become the main force of the altar of the king of La Ge more than 20 years later? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The reason is that his understanding of Wang Luobin has begun since the 1980s. In the 1990s, many friends and teachers, including Dai Penghai and Xie Gong, had participated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; One more important reason may be that Wu Yuebei is responsible for a national folk song inheritance project. Wang Haicheng&#39;s prosecution will make him unusual difficult. Do you want to include folk songs related to Wang Luobin? Will there be legal risks after inclusion? What should I do if similar people come out? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Not long ago, some editors asked Li Yan and wanted to use western folk songs to deal with it? &quot;I suggest him that the case has not been finalized yet, so you don&#39;t need it.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt = &quot;The 1947&quot; Chinese Song Selected &quot;by Hu Tingjiang, of which&quot; Kangding Love Song &quot;signed&quot; Jiang Dingxian &quot;(Jiang Dingxian&quot;. Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/34df94a31a.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/34df94a31a.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 258766 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot; color: #999999; Text-Align: Center; &quot;>; The 1947 version of&quot; Selected Chinese Songs &quot;found by Hu Tingjiang, of which&quot; Kangding Love Song &quot;signed&quot; Jiang Dingxian &quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Smoke disappear &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Simkai, Stkaiti; &quot;>; Initially, it was their fall, and then the fans were old. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; At least one thing, Wu Yuebei and Wang Haicheng have a rare consensus. They all found that society pays attention to new series of lawsuits. Not high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Until today, there are still Wang Luobin&#39;s memorials in Pakistan, Hubei, Baishui Ancient Town, and Urumqi. Member of the CPPCC also hopes that all children in Puzhou will sing Wang Luobin&#39;s song. In early September 2023, at a lecture at the Three Gorges University, Wu Yuebei mentioned this protracted copyright dispute, but the audience at the scene did not know who Wang Luobin was except the teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Today, the person who knows the western song king most lives in a 26-storey commercial house in the north of Lazhou. This is a residence purchased after Wang Haicheng was moved by the enthusiasm of Lizhou officials. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Most of the time, Wang Haicheng is a long-awaited and strictly restricted old man. Once, he took me to the old factory in Puzhou to check the construction progress of the Wang Luobin Music Art Museum. He indirectly reached a call, and the other party wanted to buy Wang Luobin&#39;s manuscript. He was full of &quot;good&quot;, hung up the phone, and made a look at me. &quot;I asked others to know that Wang Luobin&#39;s son sells manuscripts, which is incredible.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He is easy to be excited, especially when it comes to these difficult and from the academic opponent, he will doubt the motivation of the opponent and admire their cunning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is difficult to confirm whether Wang Haicheng understands these complaints from the professional music circle. In this commercial house, he continued to move out of his published Wang Luobin&#39;s work and several thick Xinjiang folk songs, and repeatedly emphasized that the change of a note and a word is the result of his father&#39;s exhaustion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;Uyghur is a multi-syllable, Chinese is a single syllable, and the Han people say that good is &#39;good&#39;, Uyghur said that a good one is&quot; To sing the Chinese folk songs in Chinese, it must be a big surgery for it. &quot;Wang Haicheng can also give more examples. For example,&quot; Alamu Khan &quot;is adapted to the Children&#39;s Troupe of Qinghai, so it has been added for half a rest, which is convenient for convenience Children breathe when singing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The 72-year-old man still needs to answer the &quot;love&quot; between his father and Sanmao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;I have seen it, eating at my house, my wife gave Sanmao noodles, eaten two meals, and told me to talk to me when I have come, I have been here for several days. Today this day is the most comfortable &#39;. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>;&quot; I understand her, there is a kind of &quot; Feeling, she wants to integrate into her home, and she wants to live with my father. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Once valid. His &quot;My Father Wang Luobin&quot; Douban score is 7.9, and many people have burst into tears. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In the Library of Laizhou, the photos of Sanmao were placed on a desk that was used by Wang Luobin, which was moved from Xinjiang. Wrapped wrapped, Wang Haicheng said that all of this was arranged according to Wang Luobin&#39;s life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But in the photos of Wang Luobin and desk he showed afterwards, there were no three-hairy photo on the table. He also explained that the photo was actually placed on the cabinet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Now, some stories are invalid. The Tianjin High Court determined that the &quot;Mayera&quot; adapted from Hu Tingjiang was not infringed; during the trial of Hu Tingjiang&#39;s version of &quot;Youth Dance&quot; case, the Hubei High Court directly stated in a 34 -page judgment: If Wang Haicheng and others have the demands of rights, then then It is tantamount to &quot;belonging to the right of primitive folk songs.&quot; The Hubei High Court also ordered a series of &quot;risks&quot; after litigation: Once supported rights protection, Wang Haicheng and others can be based on Wang Luobin&#39;s first work, and arbitrarily initiate lawsuits in other homologous works in the subsequent subsequent. This is undoubtedly &quot;harmful to the right to the original folk song.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Another reason is that the world left by his father, Wang Haicheng spent half a lifetime and continued to construct. Those who accused Wang Luobin of no copyright may disappear all this smoke. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; He is the child who has won Wang Luobin from the three brothers. So far, he will play the piano every day and play with the guitar. If anyone says he and Wang Luobin are very Like, he will show a sincere smile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin did have a dream to let his songs sing for 500 years. So far, the longest Chinese songs are said to be &quot;Jasmine&quot;, which has been circulating for nearly 400 years. In 1794, I finally met the Macanloni Mission of the Emperor Qianlong, ready to return to Britain from Guangzhou. Here, the group secretary John Baro heard the Guangzhou dialect version of &quot;Jasmine&quot;. He was in &quot;China Travel&quot; The song was recorded with Roman Pinyin and translated lyrics, becoming the earliest record in Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; So, who is pushing the eternal universe of the western song king and let it slide into the abyss of forgotten? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Perhaps, all this has nothing to do with the law. All cultural idols will disappear in time. At first, it was their fall, and then the fans were old. Idols may be mentioned briefly at a certain moment and a certain period -but this is only accidental. In the end, they will sink into the long fog again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; How many people remember, this year is the 80th anniversary of the birthday of Sanmao? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;September 10, 2023, Hebei Library Library, Sanmao&#39;s photos are placed on the right desk, Wang Haicheng is playing&quot; Youth Dance &quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/ Figure) &quot;src =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dbb29400.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/dbb29400.jpg&quot; data- key = &quot;258767&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style: #999999; text- Align: Center; &quot;>; September 10, 2023, Hebei Library Library, Sanmao&#39;s photos are placed on the right desk, Wang Haicheng is playing&quot; Youth Dance &quot;. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;H4>; What is it if it is not a folk song? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, SIMKAI, stkaiti;&quot;>; After many inquiries, he finally found &quot;Dada and He The author of Maria and &quot;Marray&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; A sunny and kind Beijing autumn afternoon in the afternoon, I saw Du Yaxiong, who edited 1983 &quot;Selection of Luobin Songs&quot;. He is now Chinese music. Professor of the Department of Music of the College. He just discharged from the hospital, his face was rosy, his hair was silver, and he often made a strong laughter. In the afternoon of the same day, a male tweeter came to visit and heard about Wang Luobin. He talked: &quot;Wang Luobin&#39;s songs dare not touch, and we (units) have also defended.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left ; &quot;>; In the summer of 1982, Du Yaxiong was still a young man. He lived in Wang Luobin&#39;s house to help him organize the score. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Recalling the summer of forty years ago, Du Yaxiong has a feeling of vagueness. Wang Luobin did not understand the origin of his song. &quot;After all, he is not engaged in us. This major (ethnic music), we know whether a song belongs to a folk song or a song, which is very clear. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; National music began in 1959. Dutch musicians, who have been dispatched by Java for 15 years, renamed the 3rd edition of his book &quot;Music&quot; to &quot;National Music Science&quot;, which created this discipline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Wang Luobin told Du Yaxiong that the song &quot;Dadal and Maria&quot; was sang by a Kazakh old lady in Xining, Qinghai around 1940. Including &quot;Maura&quot;, Wang Luobin believes that these are folk songs, but Du Yaxiong does not agree. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;People who have studied Kazakhson folk songs can be seen that these are not folk songs. Why? Kazakh folk songs have specific rhythm, a song divides the main song and chorus song In the two parts, the lyrics of the main song must be 11 syllables, their combinations can be 344, 443, 434. Each combination is a sound step. &quot;Du Yaxiong said,&quot; There is still a rule, that is, the combination The lyrics and songs are consistent, and a phrase of the Kazakh folk song has ended, but the word has not been sang, and the last voice of the first sentence should be placed in the second music. The first sound of the last lyrics in the last music festival. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; Du Yaxiong speculates that this way of presenting this music is likely to come from the daily life of the Kazakh people. Life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &quot;There is a swap mechanism for nomadic peoples. Young people will not stay in the tent and go sheep. , Riding the horse, 200 meters away from the tent, first &#39;ah 呺 —&#39; shouting, someone in the tent, he will come out to tie the dog, and use &quot;Ah 呺 —&quot; to respond to you. &quot;This Scholars who studied the history of music have added a naughty supplement, &quot;but I am not necessarily right.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; What if it is not a folk song? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Du Yaxiong understands Kazakh. After inquiring from many parties, he finally found the author of &quot;Da Dar and Maria&quot; and &quot;May&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The author of the first song is Mary Jagel (1887-1950), born in Acko Mora, Kazakhstan, is Kazakhstan. Stan people artist. Du Yaxiong inferred that she created the song around 1903. This song has been widely circulated in Kazakhstan, once the theme of many music works. Judging from Wang Luobin&#39;s record, at the latest in the early 1930s, this song was introduced to China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The author of the second song is Marrara Shammustinovova (1890-1927), Professor Ah Hedi, Aramutu Conservatory of Music McDIS Jubanov introduced this person in the book &quot;The Nightingale of the Times&quot; and said that the song was the author&#39;s &quot;self -portrait&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Du Yaxiong also verified &quot;Girl in Daban City&quot;. Cut the rhythm. He was curious why Wang Luobin&#39;s version was not like this. Wang Luobin&#39;s saying was that the driver he heard was singing -not Wang Haicheng said, but the active version of the version suitable for the Han people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Regarding &quot;Youth Dance&quot;, Wang Luobin told Du Yaxiong: &quot;It was recorded in Jiuquan Dongguan in 1939. The lyrics were original, not me. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; As for the&quot; pearl on the crown &quot;, Du Yaxiong does not think that the popular version is the result of&quot; tuning &quot;, but a version of the male cavity, using&quot; Anti -tuning &quot;method creates a female cavity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Therefore, in the 1983 &quot;Selection of Luobin Songs&quot;, Du Yaxiong divided the songs into two parts, the first part was the folk song, the second part was Wang Luobin&#39;s of Creation, and these songs are in the first part. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; However, Du Yaxiong also affirmed the contribution of Wang Luobin&#39;s translation of ethnic minorities. Translated into Chinese, it is too difficult, translation is to see Yada. Of course, some things are not right with the original, he is a half -compiled and half translation. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In fact, Wang Haicheng still won part of the victory in the final judgment of the Beijing Intellectual Property Court. The court determined that Wang Luobin and his descendants continued to enjoy the copyright of &quot;Daban City Girl&quot;, &quot;Da Dar and Maria&quot;, &quot;Mayra&quot;, and &quot;in that distant place&quot;; for &quot;Youth Dance&quot;, he enjoys lyrics copyright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; But Wang Haicheng still determined that someone is accelerating the disappearance. Not long ago, when Beijing Normal University produced the musical &quot;The Ballad of the Past&quot;, some people proposed that &quot;in the distant place&quot; may be controversial. The school conveyed was reported by a lawyer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; The lawyer&#39;s name is Dong Xiaoyue, the granddaughter of Chen Tianhe. She also has a persistent life. When holding a chorus competition in high school, some students mentioned that &quot;in the distant place&quot; belongs to Wang Luobin, and she will scratch others. Chen Tianhe died in 1955. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Dong Xiaoyue after the 80s became a reporter and book editor, but from time to time, she held her. Around 2010, she began to find the &quot;Selection of Chinese Songs&quot; from the major libraries in Beijing. The earliest version of this book has only two volumes in China. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; It is like the result of a period of life, Dong Xiaoyue became a lawyer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Someone once asked her to charge the copyright fee. She replied in a letter: &quot;It should not be entangled in the copyright dispute, let everything follow the wind. The problem of music does not need to be given to the law. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p style =&quot; text-align: left; &quot;>; The young Wang Luobin more than 80 years ago would not expect that the copyright and origin of a song will be far away. It will become so important in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; In 1935, at the age of 22, he worked as a music teacher at a middle school outside Beijing&#39;s Xizhimen. There is a river nearby. At noon in the summer, he ran to the river to swim, and there were many college students who moved after the fall of the Northeast. One day, the naked and mud people listened to their classmates to read &quot;August Village&quot;. This novel describes the story of the Northeast military and civilians fighting with the Japanese invaders after the &quot;September 18th&quot; incident. When I read a poem called &quot;I want to fall in love, I also want the freedom of the motherland&quot;, Wang Luobin, full of passion, wore clothes, copied the poem down, and went home to compose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; Later, a young man found it and said that his songs were well written or sang well, but do you know who the novel author is. Wang Luobin was embarrassed and did not know. The young man laughed and said, &quot;The author is Xiao Jun, I am Xiao Jun.&quot; Wang Luobin recalled: &quot;I was shocked, so the two of us hugged, laughed, and became friends.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font- FAMILY: Kaita, Kai Trioons_GB2312, Stkaiti; &quot;>; (Southern Weekend Intern Huang Xiaoying also contributed to this article) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;IMG Alt =&quot; September 10, 2023, Lizhou, Hebei, Hebei, Hebei, Wang Luobin&#39;s former residence memorial. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &quot;SRC =&quot; http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/fcb1a38e23.jpg &quot;border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/fcb1a38e23.jpg &quot;data- key =&quot; 258768 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p STYLE = &quot;COLOR: #999999; Text-Align: Center;&quot;>; September 10, 2023, Hebei, Hebei, Wang Luobin&#39;s former residence Memorial Hall. (Southern Weekend reporter Su Youpeng/Picture) &lt;/p>; &lt;h5>; Wang Luobin Chronicle &lt;/h5>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, Stkaiti &quot;>; 1913, born in Beijing. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1931, entered the National Peiping Normal University Music Department to study. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In 1937, the Anti-Japanese War broke out and went to Shanxi to participate in the Eighth Route Army&#39;s Northwest Warfield Service Troupe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1940, served as music education in Xining, Qinghai, and was responsible for the establishment of Qinghai Children&#39;s Anti-Japanese War Theater. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1949, participated in the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1952-1976, he was imprisoned many times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; In 1981, he recovered his reputation and military status and served as art consultant of the Xinjiang Military Region Cultural and Art Troupe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1991, enjoy special government allowances. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;FonT-FAMILY: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, Stkaiti;&quot;>; 1994, a special contribution award for Eastern and Western cultural exchanges by UNESCO. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_GB2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; 1996, died at the age of 83 due to the invalidation of gallbladder adenocarcinoma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“4个月挣250元”，去横店当“童漂”值得吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260937]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-20 12:25:46 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/23/ 11/20/26999ccfccca7220487e539964EB758DE.JPEG &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 427 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/medias/image/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/23/ 11/20/26999ccfccca7220487E539964EB758DE. JPEG &quot;Data-Key =&quot; 258849 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to media reports, many parents now take their children to be&quot; children&#39;s drift &quot;in Hengdian to find the opportunity to appear in film and television dramas. The life of &quot;Tong Diao&quot; is also very bitter. &quot;100 people grab a seat&quot;, &quot;Earn 250 yuan in 4 months&quot; and &quot;paying a lot of money with the capital&quot; are the norm of many &quot;children&#39;s drifts&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are media statistics, in 2022, in the film, online dramas, TV dramas and other film and television cultural works filmed in Hengdian, 230 minors participated in the performance of minor entertainers, with more than 6,000 people. This number is not small, and it is the reason why &quot;Tong Diao&quot; exists -Hengdian does provide an opportunity to act in acting and famous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, with the influx of children and their families, &quot;Children&#39;s Drifting&quot; quickly became inside. It is difficult for the &quot;Tongfu&quot; industry to say that it is a pure dream chasing story, but has evolved into a strange capital game. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;In 2,000 years, at least 3 plays can be guaranteed in one year, and you can appear in special actors. In 53 years, at least 8 dramas in 3 years, you can be able to play special actors and characters.&quot; This is the charging model of several children&#39;s brokerage companies in the media report. According to the &quot;members&quot; of various levels, it is equipped with corresponding resources according to the amount paid. Obviously, for families who lack an economic foundation, &quot;Tong Diao&quot; is very cruel and the return rate is extremely low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Another problem of &quot;children&#39;s drift&quot; is that the main body of dreaming is children. If they are in a kind of irregular situation, what should I do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The compulsory education law stipulates that children, parents of adolescents, or other legal guardians shall ensure that they are accepted on time and complete compulsory education in accordance with the law. If the parents let the child leave the school early for a child star dream, they are suspected of illegal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Even if the child completes compulsory education, the basic education is too weak. This impact may be lifelong. The cost of &quot;children&#39;s drift&quot; is too huge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Therefore, for the risk of &quot;children&#39;s drift&quot;, parents should have more rational and comprehensive assessment. &quot;Being a wrist and becoming a horns&quot;, after all, has huge uncertainties. Family gambling everything to fight a very low probability of probability. Is this wise? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且儿童还不具备完全民事行为能力，他们对自身行为的性质其实还没有完整清晰的认知。很多孩子确实喜欢演戏，但他们对“沉没成本”是缺乏认知的——一旦演艺道路受阻，孩子该如何回归常规的成长路径？孩子对此茫然无知，而家长如果也缺乏审慎，无疑是一种不负责任。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，舆论也没必要对“童漂”及其家庭做陈义过高的批判。网上一些常见的批评诸如“把孩子当挣钱工具”“家长有个发财梦”云云，也未见得准确。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从采访中可以看到，很多家长不过是因为孩子想演戏，想奋力一搏帮孩子圆梦罢了。他们未必是利欲熏心的父母，这本质上和要孩子“读名校”没有区别，都是选择了一条十分内卷且前景不明朗的道路。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在规劝家长保持审慎的同时，社会也应当有所干预。比如那些演艺经纪公司是否正规，其实就应当引发相关部门的关注。有家长反映，“带资进组”疑似遭遇诈骗，交了钱不仅无戏可演还被当事人“拉黑”了。对于这些，市场监管部门应当顺着相关线索，去排查其中有无违法违规问题存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一根不容模糊的红线是：无论家庭给孩子选择怎样的成长路径，但受教育必须得到强制性的贯彻。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论如何，横店“童漂”的辛酸，终究是一种令人难言滋味的内卷。追梦之旅当然是充满艰辛的，但这条道路似乎又不那么符合一种朴素的儿童成长叙事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鉴于此，“童漂”是否适合自身的家庭状况，还是需要家长再三地审慎考虑；而社会显然也应当努力扫除其中存在的风险隐患，保障未成年人权利，至少让“童漂”这条路上少一些坑。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[假如我变成了“熊孩子”丨世界儿童日]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260935]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[涉罪的“豆芽”：网售体彩242亿元被控非法经营]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260927]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2022年8月3日，呼和浩特，乘客在中国体育彩票“幸运专列”主题列车上留影。（人民视觉/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d59a5b48fe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/d59a5b48fe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258819&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年8月3日，呼和浩特，乘客在中国体育彩票“幸运专列”主题列车上留影。 （人民视觉/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“线上平台不能用了？”2023年11月15日，浙江省长兴县某体育彩票店店主吴勇的微信里又弹出熟客的询问。 He can receive similar information almost every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;吴勇在县内经营5家体彩店，曾是国家体育总局体彩管理中心评选出的全国优秀竞彩网点业主。 But now, he is planning to transfer the three stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年2月16日，因涉嫌非法经营罪，吴勇被江西省吉水县公安局拘留，“退赃”120万元后被取保候审。吉水县检察院认定，2019年至2023年，吴勇通过“豆芽”App销售体彩1.27亿元，非法获利810万余元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“豆芽”App的运营模式是，彩民线上下单，店主收到通知后，在线下彩票实体店出票。 APP operators are profitable by charging a 1%handling fee from the owner of the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据起诉书，在“豆芽”注册的彩票代销店近1.4万家，彩民271万余人。 From 2019 to 2023, a total of about 24.2 billion yuan of lottery tickets sold through &quot;bean sprouts&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从时间上看，吴勇等人被指控的行为主要发生在2015年国家对网售彩票清理整顿之后，8年来，财政部没再开放对网售彩票的授权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在刑法中，构成非法经营罪的一个条件是违反“国家规定”。 However, the &quot;Lottery Management Regulations&quot; formulated by the State Council in 2009 did not stipulate the sales of lottery tickets through the Internet. The relevant regulations were formulated by the Ministry of Finance and other relevant ministries and commissions. During the trial of this case, the focus of the dispute between the two parties was that Wu Yong and others sold lottery tickets through the Internet violated the &quot;national regulations&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“禁令”带来红利&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;吴勇的彩票店生意始于十年前。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2013年，巴西世界杯举办的前一年，身为球迷的吴勇在长兴县城商业区租下一个门面，经营的第一家体彩店Open. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;彼时，多家互联网头部公司都在各自平台开通了网络售彩业务，线下彩票店生意并不景气。 According to Wu Yong, the online lottery service attracted a large number of young people. Before the World Cup began, the business of the lottery store &quot;basically only back to the book&quot;. Most of the customers were acquaintances with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;查阅相关公开信息，财政部未公开披露过互联网彩票市场的规模。一个可供参考的数据是，长期跟踪彩票市场的机构彩通咨询发布的《2014年互联网彩票市场分析报告》显示，那一年，中国互联网彩票销售规模达850亿，较2013年销售规模翻番，市场份额首次超过20%。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过，火热的互联网彩票市场很快被政策降温。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2015年1月15日，财政部、民政部和国家体育总局联合下发《关于开展擅自利用互联网销售彩票行为自查自纠工作有关问题的通知》。 2月底，阿里、腾讯、网易、新浪、人民网等多个互联网平台宣布停售彩票。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;既料到又没有料到的是，吴勇享受到了“禁令”带来的多重红利。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那些原本被互联网平台吸引的彩民开始光顾他的彩票店。不时还有人问他，线下购彩太麻烦，还有没有线上购彩的渠道？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;和同行交流时，吴勇知道了“87彩店”（“豆芽”前身）这个应用。他在网上找到公司电话，打过去询问。之后，公司销售人员同他联系，要求他提供店铺照片、代销证、银行卡、身份证等核验资质。通过审批后，吴勇的线上彩票业务开始了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;彩民通过吴勇分享的彩票店推广码下载App后，购买的彩票只能从吴勇的店铺出票。 2015年开始，线上销售额就能占吴勇店铺销售总量的近一半。此后暴发的新冠疫情，进一步加速了吴勇线上生意的发展，“通过App销售的彩票，差不多能占七八成。”他估算。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2021年是吴勇业绩最好的一年，线上彩票销售额达到四千多万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;足球赛事大多集中在晚上，彩民的购票热潮是在开赛前半个小时。一家线下体彩门店一般只有一台终端出票机，生意火爆时，出票速度跟不上。从2018年开始，吴勇又以店员或亲戚的身份陆续申请了4家体彩代销店，以消化更多订单。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;使用“豆芽”期间，吴勇就留意到有店主因为使用这款应用，被地方体彩管理中心通报，暂停门店销售权限。他的门店里，还贴着县里体彩中心下发的禁止网售彩票的宣传海报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但他“没太当回事”。毕竟，靠实体店里零散的客人，甚至都难以回本，“要生存下去，不可能不用线上渠道”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者从接近案件的人士处了解到，目前至少有62位使用过“豆芽”的彩票店店主被吉水县公安局调查。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除两名店主已被检察机关诉至法院，南方周末记者同另6位涉案店主确认，他们在2023年2月至6月间陆续因涉嫌非法经营罪被吉水县公安局取保候审，目前仍处于公安机关侦查阶段。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这6人向南方周末记者表达了相似的想法，“大家都这么干，你不干不就亏了？”一位店主说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;波动的政策&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;和吴勇一同被检察院起诉的，还有另一名彩票店店主，以及“豆芽”的运营公司北京春新芽科技有限公司实际控制人王岭峰和6名员工。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;王岭峰在2014年年底入局互联网彩票业。按照他对南方周末记者的说法，自己是在华东某省体彩管理中心领导的建议下进入这个行业，此后也曾受多地体彩中心邀请给店主们做培训，“怎么用&#39;互联网+&#39;的思维卖彩票&#39;”。不过，南方周末记者未能向他所述体彩机构核实到这一点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2016年，王岭峰在接受《新浪彩通》采访时提到，2015年初禁售互联网彩票的政策出台前，公司已开始和多地体彩中心谈合作，中心认可他们的模式，并愿意推给店主。禁令下发后，洽谈全部停止。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;出乎他意料的是，很多彩票店主却主动找到公司，“当时真觉得都快完了，居然活了过来”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;那次采访中，王岭峰谈到，创业中面临的最大困难，“还是政策”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;互联网彩票制度经历了从收紧到放宽再到收紧的过程。在中国境内，合法彩票只有国务院特许发行的体育彩票和福利彩票。民政部、国家体育总局分别负责全国福彩、体彩的管理，财政部则负责彩票的监督管理。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2007年12月，财政部、民政部、国家体育总局联合下发《关于彩票机构利用互联网销售彩票有关问题的通知》，提到要一律停止利用互联网销售彩票。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;但到了2010年，财政部又发布《互联网销售彩票管理暂行办法》（以下简称“暂行办法”），指出要抓紧选择具备暂行办法规定条件、管理基础好的单位，报财政部批准后开展试点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;暂行办法中还强调，未经批准，任何单位不得利用互联网销售彩票。不过，这份文件仍被业内解读为一个积极信号，意味着此前处于灰色地带的网售彩票模式有望合法化。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在无一机构获财政部批准的情况下，互联网彩票业迅速发展。新浪、网易等门户网站和淘宝、京东、当当等电子商务平台都推出了彩票业务。彩通咨询统计，2011年，中国互联网彩票销量突破百亿元大关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2012年9月，网售彩票试点落地。财政部同意国家体育总局体彩管理中心委托中国竞彩网和500彩票网开展网售体彩业务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;到了2015年，政策又逐渐收紧，相关部门发布了前述针对网售彩票的禁令。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2016年4月28日，财政部、公安部、原国家工商总局、民政部、国家体育总局联合发文，指出自2015年以来对网售彩票清理整顿取得阶段性成效，但个别地区还是存在有令不行、有禁不止的现象。文件再次强调，严禁彩票发行销售机构及其代销者擅自网售彩票。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过，央视在2018年4月发布的调查显示，仍有超过三百多家彩票网站在运行，每年售彩金额不低于1000 billion.当年俄罗斯世界杯开赛期间，多个彩票App出现在手机应用商城的下载排行榜前列。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;4个月后，2018年8月21日，财政部、民政部、国家体育总局联合国家发改委、工信部、公安部等12个部委发布公告，坚决禁止擅自网售彩票行为，并指出财政部尚未批准任何彩票机构开通这项业务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;13天后，财政部、民政部、国家体育总局又发布关于修改《彩票管理条例实施细则》的决定，“擅自利用互联网销售的福利彩票、体育彩票”被列入“非法彩票”之列。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年9月3日，北京服贸会体育服务展区的体彩展。（人民视觉/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/774ebd3c4a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/774ebd3c4a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258820&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月3日，北京服贸会体育服务展区的体彩展。 （人民视觉/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“国家规定”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2015年政策收紧后，财政部便没再开放对互联网销售彩票的授权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前，财政部、民政部、国家体育总局只能监管到各省市彩票发行中心和代销者。中国彩票行业沙龙创始人苏国京认为，如果允许网上销售彩票，非彩票机构的网络平台一旦出现“吃票”和各类争议问题，如何监管、谁去监管就成了大问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;所谓“吃票”，即彩民在网上购买了彩票，平台或代销者并没有实际出单，而是直接私吞票款。如果彩民中了小奖，可以直接兑付，要是彩民中了大奖，平台或代销者无法支付这笔费用，就可能出现关站、跑路的状况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;《检察日报》报道过“吃票”案例，上海一彩票店店主孙某在2019年2月至4月间利用互联网销售彩票508万元，实际出票443万元，吃票六十多万元。 2020年，上海青浦区法院以非法经营罪判处孙某有期徒刑6年6个月，并处罚金人民币60万元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在“豆芽”上，每隔几个月，吴勇会被客服要求抽查实际出票情况。客服随机抽选10个订单，吴勇需要把对应实体票找出，拍照发给客服审核。吴勇表示，对彩民的线上下单，自己全部都在线下真实出票。起诉书也未提及他存在“吃票”行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不过，平台上还是会出现“漏网之鱼”。和吴勇一同被吉水县检察院起诉的一名湖南体彩店店主就被控“吃票”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;根据起诉书，2019年1月至2021年年底期间，他利用“云彩店”App（亦为“豆芽”前身）销售彩票1.48亿元，“吃票”金额6400万余元，非法获利327万余元。该店主在接受南方周末采访时表示，自己的确存在“吃票”行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;与“吃票”者不同，吴勇等彩票店店主通过App销售彩票，但在线下出票，是否也涉嫌非法经营？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2022年1月，江西修水县法院对一个类似案件作出判决（以下称“修水案”）。南方周末记者从该案一名被告人的辩护律师处获悉，此案中，售彩App与彩票店店主都不存在截留票款不出票、“吃票”的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;修水县法院最终认定，售彩App相关负责人和App合作的数名彩票店店主均构成非法经营罪。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;法院判决的依据为，《彩票管理条例实施细则》规定，擅自利用互联网销售的彩票属于非法彩票的范畴。此外，App还设置具有赌博性质的跟单、合买程序等，改变了彩票销售、兑奖规则，“销售数额特别巨大，情节特别严重，扰乱了彩票市场秩序”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刑法第225条对非法经营罪的定义是，违反国家规定，未经许可经营法律、法规规定的专营专卖物品或其他扰乱市场秩序的非法经营行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;被告人提起上诉后，二审法院维持原判。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;修水案律师告诉南方周末记者，开庭过程中，控辩交锋的一个重点在于，什么是“国家规定”？以及未经批准禁止网售彩票的相关文件，是否属于“国家规定”？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月9日、10日，王岭峰、吴勇等9人涉嫌非法经营一案在江西吉水县法院一审开庭，上述问题也是庭审中的焦点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;刑法第96 条对“违反国家规定”的解释是，违反全国人民代表大会及其常务委员会制定的法律和决定，国务院制定的行政法规、规定的行政措施、发布的决定和命令。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;吴勇的辩护律师、对外经贸大学副教授郑海平在法庭上指出，《彩票管理条例》由国务院制定，属于“国家规定”的范畴。但该《条例》只是禁止“擅自发行、销售彩票”，并未明确禁止利用互联网销售彩票的行为。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对于利用互联网销售彩票的禁止性规定，主要出现在《彩票管理条例实施细则》及《互联网彩票管理暂行办法》中。但前者由财政部、民政部、国家体育总局制定，后者则是由财政部发布。从法律位阶上来说，它们只是部门规章，不得认定为“违反国家规定”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;目前，吉水县法院尚未作出一审判决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;分配格局可能被打破&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“豆芽案”中尚未被起诉的另6名店主也在等待判决结果。他们分别在福建、山东、江苏等地开设线下彩票店，均称没有“吃票”，在缴纳数十万到上百万不等的“非法所得”后，被取保候审。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;代理了修水县法院审理的非法经营案后，前述代理修水案的律师又陆续接到了近十件类似案件当事人的咨询，“八成以上都由江西省的公安机关立案侦查”。这意味着，使用网络方式销售的彩票店店主都面临着刑事犯罪风险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;尽管有风险，但通过线上渠道销售彩票的店并不少见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年11月13日，南方周末记者随机拨打北京10家体彩门店电话，以彩民身份询问是否可以线上购买彩票。 8家彩票店表示可以添加微信后线上购买，其中两家发送了可以网购体彩的App下载链接。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;就监管部门的态度而言，对通过App购买彩票，与通过微信让店主代购彩票的定性也不同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;南方周末记者从北京、浙江、湖南等地体彩管理中心处了解，App购买彩票被明确禁止，而通过添加店主微信的方式购彩是否违规，目前还没有明确的界定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;吴勇所在的浙江湖州市体彩中心认为，微信购彩属于网络购彩行为，“没有违法那么严重，但我们不提倡”。长沙市体彩中心则表示，如果有彩票店店主被查到通过微信渠道售彩，“可能会受到撤机的处罚”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;网售彩票为何迟迟难以松动？苏国京告诉南方周末记者，在中国，彩票更被强调公益性，而弱化其博彩属性。互联网平台提供了比线下购买更为便捷的销售渠道和支付手段，但有可能造成彩民的沉迷，也让管控未成年人购彩更为困难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;北京师范大学心理学院副教授、中国彩票事业研究中心原副主任陈海平则表示，互联网售彩还会带来的问题是，原有公益金分配格局被打破。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;彩票资金被分为奖金、发行费和公益金三部分。按照财政部规定，各省彩票公益金一半上缴中央财政，一半留在省级财政。而互联网销售彩票则打破了地域限制，互联网经济发达的省份，销售额会上涨，留在地方财政的公益金增多。以线下销售为主导的省份，也必然带来公益金减少。这容易造成各省之间彩票销售的不良竞争，不仅打破原有的公益金筹集和分配格局，形成新的贫富不均，而且会出现各种市场乱象。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在苏国京看来，如果彩票行业不出台更高位阶的法律，“不把互联网销售中的责权利厘清，就没法彻底解决问题&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[去扬州看东坡：到心仪之地，施仁爱之方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260929]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;平山堂里思忆多&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; Yangzhou once stayed in the generations of Junjie densely. Its lapse of the column and flowers, layers of golden powder and golden sand. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/iuFLzQrv52hE6WWvWJOAgg0YjIcLVwDAGdPa20BS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/iuFLzQrv52hE6WWvWJOAgg0YjIcLVwDAGdPa20BS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;从大明寺栖灵塔俯瞰瘦西湖&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢向前/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出瘦西湖北门，道路对面就是大明寺。 Entering the scenic ramp, the &quot;Qi Ling Site&quot; archway appears in front of it, four pillars and three, and heavy eaves.它东侧院墙上嵌着石匾，“淮东第一观”几个红色大字很醒目，来自秦观的《次韵子由题平山堂》：“游人若论登临美，须作淮东第一观。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过大明寺的天王殿，西侧有一个八角型门洞，穿过去就是平山堂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平山堂正前方是一列木质花廊，栽于两侧的老紫藤盘旋缠绕，茂密的枝叶与盛放的藤花，洒落一地清凉。我突然想起“堂前垂柳”，就先退出花廊。周边植着腊梅、琼花、黄杨、紫薇等，玉兰的叶片繁茂润泽，树高达七八米，盛放时应该很华美。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前庭南侧的草地上有块乳白石头，上方写着绿色大字“欧公柳”，它果然在呢。下方是欧阳修的《朝中措》：“平山阑槛倚晴空，山色有无中。手种堂前垂柳，别来几度春风……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仁宗嘉祐元年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1056年）&lt;/span>;，朋友刘敞将赴任扬州知州，欧阳修为之饯行，赠以此词。 It has been a few years since he has been transferred to Yangzhou, and he still loves Pingshan Hall, where he once wandered.词里隐含一丝时光易逝的惆怅，但声调旷达明朗，并无衰颓之气。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;四处张望，却不见柳树踪影，有点奇怪，继续搜寻。结果它就在石头旁边，低矮，年轻，倾斜得似要躺下，是一株柽柳。树叶短促倔强，毫无袅娜之态。想象中欧公手植的垂柳，应是纤柔细长的那一款。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/5EZGfpAtygCizPHpjt6EyLPDL9oWXNb27K5sAAUz.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;924&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/5EZGfpAtygCizPHpjt6EyLPDL9oWXNb27K5sAAUz.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258828&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;平山堂&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢向前/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平山堂内十分拥挤，旅行团熙来攘往。 “平山堂”匾下方的楹联，将浩渺时空、无边风月，兼收并蓄，景物中还有知情识趣的雅士：“晓起凭栏，六代青山都到眼；晚来对酒，二分明月正当头。”匾额的东西两侧，高悬“坐花载月”“风流宛在”匾，后者为清末两江总督刘坤一所题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平山堂东、西厢的橱窗里，放置了四库全书的《六一诗话》《欧阳文粹》《文忠集》等；四幅木质诗牌占据了半堵墙，录着苏辙等吟平山堂的诗。 Mei Yaochen&#39;s &quot;Thousands of Mountain Flying Crossing the River&quot;, Su Zhe&#39;s &quot;Halling on the Mountains on the Mountains in the Hall&quot; has a small weather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仁宗庆历八年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1048年）&lt;/span>;，欧阳修由滁州徙知扬州时，仍处于“庆历新政”失败后的政治低潮期。 He pays attention to the people&#39;s livelihood, and is not relaxed for politics. The people in Luzhou and Yangzhou feel their moral politics, and they have built a temple for Ou Gong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公务之余，欧公诗酒流连，在大明寺西南方构筑平山堂，既能呼朋唤侣，登高望远，也可独享清幽。他写给前任知州韩琦的信里，很是欢愉：“独平山堂占胜蜀冈，江南诸山，一目千里。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看欧阳修他们的描写，还以为平山堂所在的蜀冈雄伟高峻。今天站在堂外，柽柳正南方的石栏杆下面，有一片喜兴、美艳的红叶。试图再遥望远方，视线却被树木遮挡。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来乘电梯登上大明寺70米高的栖灵塔，那才真是利于极目远眺。平川广野，一望无垠，没看到什么山峰，远方的灰色楼群小巧得好似积木。脚下的瘦西湖像一轴风景长卷，水岸弯曲萦绕，仿佛随意镶嵌在或浓或淡的绿树中，少量亭台散落其间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f50omRqfzEpUrZGqTAUZNwAPhOL3tL38LXovRKZD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;834&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/f50omRqfzEpUrZGqTAUZNwAPhOL3tL38LXovRKZD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258830&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;大明寺栖灵塔（右）与弘佛亭&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢向前/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平山堂与欧阳祠陈列的众多石刻里，东坡的《西江月》、欧阳修的《醉翁亭记》，惹人驻足。后者是东坡在颍州书写的，沉雄矫捷的正楷，一向被书家喜爱。 《西江月》词则作于平山堂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏轼对欧公的感情，不同寻常。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧阳修一向举贤好士，他隆重奖掖苏轼，更是天下尽知。当时流行的太学体文风追求迂曲深奥、艰涩怪僻，欧阳修等有心匡正。仁宗嘉祐二年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1057年）&lt;/span>;春，欧公作为礼部省试的主考官，将“词语甚朴，无所藻饰”的苏轼擢为“论”试的第二名。本届进士中名人辈出，嘉祐贡举被视为“千年科举第一榜”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一些志在必得的知名考生落榜后，愤懑不满，有人恶作剧写下祭文投往欧公家。还有浮薄士子围堵欧阳修，在他的马前喧哗鼓噪，“群嘲而聚骂者，动满千百”，巡逻的士卒难以制止。不过从此以后，病态的文风渐渐被扭转了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧阳修对三苏评价都高，苏轼丰美畅达的文字，更是令他拍案叫绝。给梅尧臣的信里，他乐滋滋地说：“读轼书，不觉汗出，快哉，快哉！老夫当避路，放他出一头地也。可喜，可喜！”这是文坛前辈发现优异后生的喜不自禁，更是天才对天才的惺惺相惜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧公的提携之恩、期许之情，令东坡终身感念，他说自己“受知最深”。元丰七年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1084年）&lt;/span>;东坡由黄州赴汝州，十月经过扬州时，再次踏入平山Hall.他“每到平山忆醉翁”，这回也不例外。壁上墨迹依旧，恩师却已仙逝，距离最后一次见面已经十余年。东坡以一阕《西江月》深挚怀念欧公，也感慨光阴似箭、世事虚幻：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;em>;三过平山堂下，半生弹指声中&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;。 &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;十年不见老仙翁，壁上龙蛇飞动。 &lt;/em>;&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;em>;欲吊文章太守，仍歌杨柳春风。休言万事转头空，未转头时&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;皆&lt;/em>;&lt;em>;梦。 &lt;/em>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧、苏两位文忠公，两代文坛盟主，均以道德文章垂范天下。他俩的任期都短，却令扬州人怀想，也让平山堂充满磁力。来参拜的后人络绎不绝，留下诸多诗文，续写了一脉风流。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王士祯的《花草蒙拾》说：平山堂地势不高，环境普通，“然以欧、苏词，遂令地重。”楼台亭榭一旦沾染贤人君子的光泽，或被丽辞鸿篇加持，就备添神韵。即使廊柱檐角已被时光磨蚀，依然不朽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平山堂几废几兴，现存建筑为同治年间重建，后来屡次大修。它让逸兴雅怀有所附丽，也凝集了一段动人的师生情谊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;半年能够做什么&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;待到东坡也以知州身份来到扬州，已是平山堂建成40多年后。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;哲宗元祐七年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1092年）&lt;/span>;二月，东坡在颍州接到任命，移知扬州，他非常乐意。三月到任，在扬州不足半年，这么点时间很难有所作为吧，他却以善政令百姓感怀。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东坡爱花，栽花赏花赠花簪花叹花，跟花朵各种互动。他笔下的梅兰菊荷、牡丹、海棠、山茶、杜鹃，或秾丽或幽洁，或一枝独秀，或满树争妍。他也很能领略芍药的妩媚，题画诗《赵昌芍药》云：“扬州近日红千叶，自是风流时世妆。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东坡到任后，却做了一个大煞风景的决定：停办万花会。他写信告诉好友王巩：万花会已成为扬州大害，停办“虽煞风景，免造业也。”其《以乐害民》一文说：扬州芍药为天下之冠，万花会用花十余万枝，既破坏各家花园，胥吏也借此扰民损民，扬州人非常不满，“予始至，问民疾苦，遂首罢之。”他认为万花会是“以一笑乐，为穷民之害”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北宋文人张邦基的《墨庄漫录》记载：万花会始于蔡京知扬州时，此后年年延续。停办花会，“人皆鼓舞欣悦”。张邦基点评道：苏公为政基本上都是这样，让百姓受惠，所以被他们称颂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从颍州赴任扬州途中，东坡目睹了百姓艰难求生、流离失所的惨状：沿途城邑都有许多流民，因无力偿付积欠&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（欠官府税赋）&lt;/span>;，不敢归乡。行至乡间，东坡经常屏去吏卒，走访村落。父老皆满面忧戚地哭诉：今年虽然夏麦成熟，但丰年催缴积欠更严苛，“胥徒在门，枷棒在身，则人户求死不得。”东坡也忍不住流泪。他两次上奏章：臣曾经知杭州、颍州，现在又到扬州，“亲见两浙、京西、淮南三路之民，皆为积欠所压”，日益困厄，流亡、死亡者过半。淮、浙积欠最多，又连年遭灾，吏卒在上级驱督下催收，对平民日日威逼鞭挞。百姓如何安生？朝廷的仁政又如何体现？东坡“昧死一言”，请求朝廷暂停一年催缴，“使久困之民，稍知一饱之乐”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;依苏轼所请，朝廷六月一日下诏，淮南东西路、两浙路的积欠暂停一年催理。他喜不自禁：“诏书宽积欠，父老颜色好。再拜贺吾君，获此不贪宝。颓然笑阮籍，醉几书谢表。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东坡经过调研，对税务、仓法、漕运等也提出改良意见，兴利除弊。门生李廌的《师友谈记》等记载：以往官府准许纲运的船夫私载货物，用以补贴收入。他们往往视官船为家，随时修葺，行船速度也快。近年严禁私载，结果舟坏人贫，漕米等比从前损耗数倍，公私皆亏；有的船工因饥寒偷盗货物，拆卖车船。扬州、楚州、泗州等州，众多船工遭鞭笞、发配，还有的沦为乞丐盗贼。东坡上奏折建议恢复旧例，得到朝廷准许。弊端消除，公私皆受益，也无人因此受刑。李廌引用《左传》的话感慨：“仁人之言，其利博哉”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;平山堂之北的谷林堂是东坡所建，现存建筑为清末重建。它与平山堂之间，由红色梁柱的走廊连接。跟谷林堂东侧一墙之隔，即大明寺的大雄宝殿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;堂额“谷林堂”三字，集自东坡的法帖。楹联“深谷下窈窕；高林合扶疏”则来自他的诗《谷林堂》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谷林堂的整体感觉，比平山堂似乎少一丝隆重意味，从礼仪的角度看，合乎长幼之序。当然，布置得也很丰满，大堂与东、西厢的墙上，有欧阳修、梅尧臣、苏氏兄弟的画像与《嘉祐贡举图》《赤壁夜游图》等，书法则有东坡临颜真卿《争座位帖》与他的《获见帖》《一夜帖》等。橱窗里陈列着黄色封面的《宋刻东坡集》和四库全书的《东坡书传》等。墙上整齐排列“苏门四学士”的诗牌，其中晁补之的七律《招缙云守关彦远、教授曾彦和集平山堂》，写于他邀约曾彦和等在平山堂聚会时：“蜀冈势与蜀山通，龙虎盘挐上紫空……少师杨柳无遗迹”，从后一句看来，晁写诗时欧公柳已经不存。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/hvHZ8TiSIHMCy64YvGQVhxo5HpGDHZ66XctremeD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/hvHZ8TiSIHMCy64YvGQVhxo5HpGDHZ66XctremeD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258826&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;谷林堂墙上的《嘉祐贡举图》&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢向前/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;晁补之元祐五年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1090年）&lt;/span>;出任扬州通判。东坡知扬州，他做副手，师生相得。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;元祐七年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1092年）&lt;/span>;八月东坡得到诏命，担任兵部尚书兼南郊郊祀卤簿使。朝廷屡次催促，东坡九月抵京。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;晁补之是兵部侍郎杜纯的女婿，东坡履新，恰好是杜纯的顶头上司。考虑到岳父与老师以前不曾近距离相处，担心他俩不那么投缘，晁补之向东坡介绍了杜纯立身处世的风格，以及当官任职恩及万物的优点。后来岳父来信称，与东坡共事得还不错，不过觉得他“尚气好辩”。晁补之回了一封长信，详述苏公为人为政的高风亮节：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;补之于苏公为门下士，无所复赞。然刚洁寡欲，奉已至俭菲，而以身任官责，嫉邪爱物，知无不为，尤是不忽细务，其有所不得尽，视去官职如土芥。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;晁补之直言不讳地反驳岳父——并不觉得苏公有此毛病：“来书犹怪其尚气好辩，此非补之所能知。”还提醒岳父：人非圣贤，各有短长。他举西汉名臣汲黯与郑当时的例子：两人性情各异，有不同的光芒与瑕疵，但司马迁并称其贤能。所以“君子以同而异，若是可也。”晁补之认为，各位贤者在朝堂和睦，则地方的好尚也跟朝廷一致，那就没有什么事是做不成的。这位女婿跟岳父辩理，维护师尊，还真是较真。晁补之在苏门四学士中受知最早，他对苏公的敬慕，可见一斑。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;走到谷林堂北侧的小园，这一角比较安静。一组假山，几株老桂，桂花横斜的枝丫掩映青瓦屋脊，高挑的枫杨、竹子在风中摇曳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/nDQX5lQW91ibVFGxj7x2nuGqLXrSXsTQnNm6K4di.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/nDQX5lQW91ibVFGxj7x2nuGqLXrSXsTQnNm6K4di.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;谷林堂北侧小园&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢向前/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;东坡到扬州后身体欠佳，很少会客。得到毛正仲赠的茶叶后，他在端午那天组了一个饭局，以丰盛的菜肴、应节气的粽子待客，特别用蜀井的清冽之水烹茶。东坡表白道：“报君不虚授，知我非轻啜。”毛君的好茶没有送错人，这下您知道我喝得多么郑重其事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谷林堂建成后，东坡也在堂边的树林里喝过茶吧？ &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;写诗差点又惹祸&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;与瘦西湖的喧嚣迥然不同，竹西公园人迹稀疏，一派清幽。它位于古运河畔，1989年在竹西寺遗址一带兴建。里面景致不错，似乎像扬州人自家的后花园，没有太多外人打扰，悄无声息地漂亮着。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;雨后空气清凉湿润，成片的银杏、桂花、松、竹、红枫等，愈发明洁清新。茶花开得正旺，海桐繁密细碎的米白色花朵，沁出清淡的香味。浅山、草亭、石桥、盆景，以及几处故址旧迹，各有可观。竹西精舍的左侧，立着吴道子画像、李白题赞、颜真卿书写的三绝碑复制件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s8EobfkUrvx87kxWMu6kjkKEKLnaGzQ7AJfUxfeY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s8EobfkUrvx87kxWMu6kjkKEKLnaGzQ7AJfUxfeY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258827&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;竹西公园“三绝碑“&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢向前/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竹西公园水域不小，有溪有湖，水是从运河引进的。月明桥的半圆型桥洞，与水中倒影衔接，恰如一轮满月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公园深处的水塘后方，有两道垂直分布的碑刻长廊，陈列着杜牧、王安石、秦观、姜夔等咏扬州的诗词。东坡诗碑《次韵苏伯固游蜀冈，送李孝博奉使岭表》，曾是竹西寺一宝。后来诗碑不存，王士祯到寺里仔细寻访，居然找到残碑。他拂拭蛛丝灰尘，“摩娑三叹，如与公晤言、酬唱于当日。”随后次韵写下《上方寺访东坡先生石刻诗》，“缅思峨嵋人，文采真神仙。”碑廊内陈列的是摹本。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/YOFvVaMjeCCuq5k4a8sO9dhQhYxjiAmvK3CaYvJI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;790&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/YOFvVaMjeCCuq5k4a8sO9dhQhYxjiAmvK3CaYvJI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258829&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;竹西公园碑廊&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢向前/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;苏东坡《归宜兴，留题竹西寺三首》诗碑的前方，有一大蓬玫红色的杜鹃，花簇锦攒，流光溢彩，跟他欢快喜悦的诗句十分搭调。其三写道：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;此生已觉都无事，今岁仍逢大有年。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;山寺归来闻好语，野花啼鸟亦欣然。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;元丰八年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1085年）&lt;/span>;春，东坡得到神宗遗诏，获准在常州居住。他从南都&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（今河南商丘）&lt;/span>;欣然南返，四月下旬抵达扬州。田园梦想实现了，心情不错。五月初一与友人同游竹西寺，受到款待，所见所闻皆愉悦，忍不住写诗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/n46RDz21F4KrmOO7hXbatDGdZ6DQnW2X928ovIio.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/n46RDz21F4KrmOO7hXbatDGdZ6DQnW2X928ovIio.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;竹西寺苏东坡诗碑&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢向前/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;公园里被竹枝、冬青掩映的一角，有一眼老井。小巧的灰色石井壁高出地面一尺多，内侧有好几道被井绳长年累月勒出的深痕。旁边约一米高的石碑上刻着“蜀井”二字，由秦观的后裔秦子卿教授题写。蜀井又名“第一泉”，是竹西寺八景之一，前人都说井水味道甘冽。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竹西寺位于蜀岗之尾，冈势至此趋于平缓。相传蜀冈的地脉与蜀地相通，泉脉也跟蜀江相连，所以东坡将竹西寺的水称为乡味，他要把含有故乡味道的井水携往江南的新家。真是惬意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没想到，后来他差点再次以诗罹祸。元祐六年&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（1091年）&lt;/span>;东坡任翰林学士、知制诰时，政敌为罗织罪名，居然翻检陈年旧事，说元丰八年三月神宗皇帝驾崩，苏轼写诗竟将此视为“好语”，乐不可支。东坡赶紧上奏札申辩，说自己三月上旬在南都哀悼先帝之后，返回常州。五月初去竹西寺，“见百姓父老十数人，相与道旁语笑。其间一人以两手加额云：&#39;见说好个少年官家&#39;。”臣喜闻百姓讴歌少年天子，出于至诚；加之请求归耕常州得到批准；路过淮、浙，又看见丰收在望，因此作诗，还题于寺庙墙壁上。假如我有任何不善之意，怎敢公然示人？而且那时离先帝仙逝已经两个月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总算有惊无险。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2AJvSxYhhCzzu7cHQHHFiYe4YGT1ujJQenAXUU4h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2AJvSxYhhCzzu7cHQHHFiYe4YGT1ujJQenAXUU4h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;竹西公园十分清幽&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（卢向前/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竹西公园位于竹西路，周边还有以禅智、上方等命名的街道。出公园南门往东，走到十字路口，朝北拐入江都北路。路右侧那片小高层住宅叫中海世玺，感觉小区的品质不错。居民从自家阳台俯瞰公园的花圃芳径，想必赏心悦目。前行三四百米即禅智路，一条稍微窄点的支路。道路一侧为建筑工地，被米褐色墙面围护着，上面写着“扬州是我家，用心呵护它”等标语。沿着江都北路继续北行，下一个路口即上方寺路。车流较少，道路通畅，偶尔有三两个行人悠闲走过。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;竹西寺又名禅智寺、上方寺，最早是隋炀帝行宫，后来成为名寺，接待过众多帝王、名臣、文豪，1853年毁于兵火。 From the palace garden of Emperor Xingle, the famous monk&#39;s famous brake, the victory of the poet, the park, community, and streets of the citizens&#39; pacing ... The soil in this corner, I do n’t know how much the fluttering and melting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;由唐至清，吟咏竹西寺的诗词不计其数，文学史上的璀璨人物，好些在此留下履迹墨痕。风流欲绝，惹人遐想。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;假如用胶片再现他们的身影，应是这般模样：杜牧在秋雨后踏着蝉声而来，周边青苔满阶，桂花飘萧；张祜游罢繁华的十里长街，前往竹西寺，伫立月明桥上，痴看美人游弋，叹一声要死就该死在扬州；东坡的动作特别多，进了寺院先饮鸡苏水，后喝莺粟汤，又借来藤床瓦枕，躺平了享受竹风清凉，临走还不忘汲一罐井水，再蘸墨在墙上题诗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他的“影像”素材最丰满、活络。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[抢课大战后，年轻人在夜校找到了生活的盼头]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260905]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;倒计时归零后，系统崩掉了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了准备这场抢课大战，90后女生吉姆特地制作了一张表格，志愿按照优先级排列，分别是非洲鼓课、手碟课、银饰制作课和扎染工艺课. The plan couldn&#39;t keep up with the change. On August 11, the system collapsed as soon as it opened.她幸运抢到了一个非洲鼓课的名额，“跟抢演唱会门票一样，”她说，“要有信念感，我一定要抢到。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;500元，12节课，每节课一个半小时。 2023年秋天，一项颇具年代感的群众生活——夜校突然在社交平台上受到追捧。 According to data from Meituan and Public Comment, the search volume of &quot;Night School&quot; on the platform increased by 980%year -on -year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上海市民夜校的“资深学员”任轶切身体会到此前从未有过的火热。 2018年前后，她偶然得知了市民夜校的存在，她的母亲原本想学手机摄影，去夜校报名才发现年龄限制在18-55岁之间，超过55岁的老年人有专门的“老年大学&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任轶自此“入坑”，五年间，她把皮具班、钩针班、盘扣班挨个尝试了一遍。她说，那时的市民夜校不似如今这般火热，“基本守着（开放名额）的点就可以抢到”。 At that time, most of the night school courses were common projects such as calligraphy, painting, yoga, and vocal music.五年后，报名页面显得乱花迷眼，列表中不乏“宠物友好社交课程”“海派调饮茶”“十二月花神系列课程”等光看名字就能挑起兴趣的课程。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;年轻人加入夜校的目的很轻松，一位女生向南方周末记者解释意图：“社交，认识更多志同道合的人，或者你只是想新学一门技能，或者随便去看看，能学就学，不学就算了。都可以。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;火热的形势之下，任轶遭遇抢课滑铁卢，但最终交上了好运。在随时有人退课的动态系统中，她捡漏了一门盘扣课。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;涌入夜校“学艺”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;任轶偏爱手作类课程，此前在夜校上过皮具课和钩针班。皮具班上，他们以一块完整的植鞣革作为起点，经历裁剪、打孔、走针后，学习缝制卡包、钥匙包或口金包。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年秋天的这节盘扣班，她手上拨弄的新对象，换成了盘扣——一种在传统服饰中固定衣襟的扣钮。课程在一个工作日的晚七点开始，历时一个半小时。她将长长的软扣条，盘成葫芦状、燕子状等各式各样的扣子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时间一晃而过。 “每次到最后可能还做不完，但是人家打扫卫生的阿姨都急得要下班了，就赶我们。”任轶自认在班上属于手比较笨的学员，“但是我就是乐此不疲”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s0wHEYsHW8aVjkdSRXynltS6wqLVnaKeTXMte0wY.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;675&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/s0wHEYsHW8aVjkdSRXynltS6wqLVnaKeTXMte0wY.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258774&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;在盘扣课上，学员们学习制作这种在传统服饰中固定衣襟的扣钮。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卢尔煜是一名自由插画师，日常作息“凌晨睡，中午起”，每晚七点的夜校刚好卡在她一天中相对清醒的时刻。她报了茶艺课、花艺课和越剧班，分别在每周三、四、五的晚上七到八点半上课。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卢尔煜说，茶艺课和花艺课显得“闲情逸致”，如果在外面花几千元去学，有点不太值当，不如拿这笔钱去学语言这样看上去更实用的知识。而夜校价格低廉，降低了她接触这类兴趣爱好的门槛。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/03eGV06UVYLt2pKNdY7VIfLPfX5r98BOaa2tR8VL.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/03eGV06UVYLt2pKNdY7VIfLPfX5r98BOaa2tR8VL.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258775&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;卢尔煜的茶艺课笔记。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前想学这类课程，只能在网上搜索，搜索之后，也未必能鉴别出老师的水准高低，“可能会被骗”。报名前，卢尔煜留意过茶艺课老师的背景，“茶艺一级技师”“宋代点茶沿袭人”，资质可靠。市民夜校的老师经过了筛选，课程介绍清清楚楚地列明，省下了太多麻烦，“你可能会有想学的东西，但是一想到有繁琐的东西要去了解，不停地咨询这家那家，可能咨询下来后热情已经消磨完了”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她很喜欢茶艺课的氛围，十多个人，四五人一组。一帮人听老师讲茶的起源、红茶的冲泡方法。老师传授记住六类茶的口诀，“&#39;红绿灯（红茶、绿茶、黄茶）&#39;，再加&#39;黑白青&#39;”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/D62e0AYt7n8glJp50gV7sbZSWe51VFLHbahlhKQw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1702&quot; height=&quot;1276&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/D62e0AYt7n8glJp50gV7sbZSWe51VFLHbahlhKQw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258772&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;夜校的茶艺课相比市面上的培训课程价格更低廉，老师资质经过了专门筛选，对年轻人来说方便可靠。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;茶艺课上，老师带来不同品牌的矿泉水或纯净水，倒在透明杯子里，让大家蒙眼品尝不同水泡茶时的口感。检测pH值的用具能测出“有些水是7.37，有些8.08，还有一些6.26”。卢尔煜观察，水的pH值通常对口感影响不大，而水的硬度和矿物质含量则会带来两极评价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在任轶上过的手作课上，最后一堂课通常是成果汇报，大家把一学期的成果摆出来展示。 “整个教室的长桌上都摆满了大家各种各样的作品，如果今天有一个夜市，我们整个班都可以拉出来练摊”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/tEhLHAOeGTtWR5hfmDhLLEzSBguexVra0BZxRBac.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/tEhLHAOeGTtWR5hfmDhLLEzSBguexVra0BZxRBac.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258776&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;手作课的各项成果。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;不是需要坚持的事&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“我报夜校无非出于几点考虑。第一，它很经济，同等质量、同等内容的课程，可能在市面上需要两三倍的价格。第二，它很有保障，风险比较低。它是上海市群众艺术馆办的项目，不像外面很多兴趣培训机构那样，受经济下行的影响就干不下去了，课程都没上完中间就跑路了，我的钱就打水漂了。”吉姆对南方周末记者说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她正式工作还没几年，在机关单位里上班，职业要求她保持“严肃、严谨的形象”，无论职业形象，还是自身行为，都有一定标准。但在非洲鼓课上，她不必那么紧绷。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每天，吉姆骑自行车通勤，身后背着装有非洲鼓的背包，远看像背包客。实木的非洲鼓，重达五六斤。同事问她是不是准备出去玩，她从不解释，“我说我就是出去玩了”。下班后，她脱下职业装，换好便服，骑20分钟车到夜校，结束后再骑半小时车回家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;教非洲鼓课的老师会多种乐器，比如尤克里里、中阮、吉他、键盘。 12节课程，前半程从基本的四分音符、八分音符学起，中间穿插节奏型的教学。如今课程过半，她正在为最新的作业头疼——老师要求大家自己编一首曲子。她观察，非洲鼓老师很注重培养她们的编曲能力，学成后能通过乐器传达生活感悟，而非仅仅照着谱子打出一段别人写的旋律。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“（非洲鼓）不是需要坚持的事，我没有觉得它很负担，是我上完班后放松的事。”吉姆说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;权衡了上课地点的远近、时间成本以及学习的迫切程度后，孙依然最终挑选了桥牌课。这是一种颇费脑力的棋牌类游戏，她一边听老师讲，一边在笔记本上记下牌型和规则。桥牌班的上课点离她家只有一站地铁。 “等于我去夜校就是早一站下地铁去上课，上完课再坐同一班地铁，一站到家”。同是夜校班的同学，有人住在浦东，下了班赶到离家更远的夜校上课，仅仅是因为感兴趣。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙依然觉得，一周一次的夜校，不会给自己带来太大的压力，“真有其他更重要的事，也完全有其他的时间处理”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她平时从事数据分析工作，按她的说法，就是将信息整理、分析、输出为“任谁看都是这样的”事实。 “工作不是一个纯理性状态，桥牌有完整的规则，明显的逻辑，其实都可以算出来的，你可以完全做一个AI机器人，可以算概率，对方可能出什么牌。”孙依然说，“我的工作虽然听起来像整理分析，但不是纯理性的，有很多人为因素参与决定，工作中我会觉得有些受束缚，但是桥牌没有。”她说，桥牌能带给她的乐趣正在于此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一项多人参与的棋牌游戏，观察桥牌桌上玩家的不同风格也能带来乐趣。孙依然观察到，有人脑子灵光，上了牌场对各类牌型应对自如，但“胜负心很强”；有的人和她一样，对阵时需要不断翻看笔记，因此将牌局拉得很长；还有仅仅把对局当作一次游戏，倾向于让对手直接把牌说出来，大家一起想想怎么做。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7mHrDYb4en1fFAVYlAQsX7bt7b8LYpiqGJ9uoXbe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;540&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/7mHrDYb4en1fFAVYlAQsX7bt7b8LYpiqGJ9uoXbe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258773&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;桥牌课笔记。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孙依然形容上夜校之前的工作日晚上，无聊、消磨时间。 “吃晚饭、健身、看看综艺也就过去了。看综艺或电影是没有头的，有时间就可以一直看，永远看不完。但如果我有别的事，也不会因为少看了两小时综艺而难过。”孙依然说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;夜校有出勤率考核，超过三次缺勤，就会失去下一季夜校的报名资格。 Many interviewees said that the night school courses are now more than half, and most of them have persisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“现在年轻人的工作压力比以前大，需要更多的释放，找一些乐子。每个人找乐子的方式不一样。”孙依然说，“因为网络发达，大家更习惯于线上交流，线下的交流反而少了，多出来自己的时间变多了，所以大家可能就更想要出去玩，其中包括上夜校。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“每个礼拜都很有盼头”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;将上夜校纳入每周日程后，这些年轻人也感受到看似无用的业余生活给日常生活带来的改变。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据MBTI人格测试的结果，卢尔煜是一个“I人”。在“解放天性”的越剧班，大家要站起来演唱，还要压腿、跑圈。班上的同学两两配对，一个唱花旦，一个唱小生。越剧班里都是女孩，年龄不拘，70后到90后都有。前几节课，她们学《天上掉下个林妹妹》，卢尔煜选择扮“可以内向”一些的花旦。 “贾宝玉有些眼神戏，他说天上掉下个林妹妹，要表现出&#39;哇，这么漂亮&#39;，看到花旦很吃惊的感觉。有的同学会表现出特别浮夸的表情，老师也会被逗笑，你在这个环境里面也会被感染到。”她说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;放在过去，自认“宅女”的卢尔煜除了下楼扔垃圾，可以二十多天不出门。她说，“夜校其实相当于给自己强制一个出门时间，不要跟社会彻底脱节。因为不上班，又不去线下这些（社交活动），跟人群越来越远了，所以也是有点强制自己这三天出门的感觉。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;和同学们一起拍击非洲鼓，给吉姆留下一次难忘的体验。打鼓时，由于不熟悉曲谱，担心赶不上节奏，往往节奏会越来越快，这时只要有一个人意识到问题，可以慢下来，就会有越来越多人发现节奏快了，齐心拉回正常的轨道，“可能整体的节奏就会被拉回来”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;吉姆说，这和现在大家热衷谈论的“内卷”相反。 “内卷”有一个经典的具象比喻：在电影院里，前排有一个人站了起来，遮住后排的视线，于是越来越多人站起来，最终所有人只能站着看电影。而非洲鼓中的放慢步调则恰恰相反，“当时一瞬间发现还能这样，觉得很奇妙”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再次回到教室，孙依然觉得夜校的氛围比起大学或中学时代好很多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“高中以前基本上都是被逼着，只能学这些，不管你喜不喜欢。大学虽然是自己选的专业，但基本上每一堂课都有很大比例的人其实根本不想听。”她观察到，夜校的桥牌课堂里，很少有鸦雀无声的情形出现，老师的问题总能得到学生热情的回应。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，随着桥牌知识的深入，抱着学习新东西的心态来上课的孙依然，也感受到知识积累的压力。 “现在感觉到了一个临界点，做这件事情给我带来的快乐，和我为了把它做好要付出的努力差不多持平了。”她担心随着难度增加，桥牌也会变得有些压力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“这个名额是比较难抢的，你报了名，付出了金钱和时间，你又不好好实践，你还不如不去。”孙依然说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;报了皮具班的王一衣偶尔也感到焦虑。有一次，因为出差，皮具课要落下一节。 “我就觉得落一节课，会不会比别人少学点什么？”老师反过来劝慰她，回来会帮她把这节课补上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，王一衣总体上还是觉得，“每个礼拜都很有盼头”。 “能让你脱离工作，找一个新的寄托，每天白天已经被工作所累，晚上如果有一个新的内容，可以调剂一下生活。就会让你生活的重心不是一直在工作上，可以分一点心思给其他的东西。”她说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（除任轶、卢尔煜外，其余受访者皆为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[近十年来最具话题度的日本动画完结，如何盖棺定论？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260933]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-20 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 4, 2023, &quot;Attack on Titan Final Season Finale Part 2&quot; will be broadcast. The name of this name reads the ten -year -old &quot;Attack on the Giant&quot; animation is complete. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now that everything has settled, we can fully evaluate &quot;Attack on Titan&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;), the most popular and topical Japanese animation work in the past decade. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/EAtAXg52wGhYOn1Rm5NNB1ZyHtWjuUIZa3PD9LtB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height= &quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/EAtAXg52wGhYOn1Rm5NNB1ZyHtWjuUIZa3PD9LtB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258823&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The classic scene of the giant staring in &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Why is &quot;Giant&quot; so popular? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;To evaluate the work &quot;Giant&quot;, the first question that must be answered is: Why is &quot;Giant&quot; so popular and discussed globally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ypYjeefyRY4CiYEcGnOjEDEECvEE7Ztn1J09SPeZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;342&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/ypYjeefyRY4CiYEcGnOjEDEECvEE7Ztn1J09SPeZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258821&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The classic gesture of the protagonist of &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Japan, television is still the main broadcast channel for animation. The vast majority of Japanese animations in the Chinese context are classified as late-night programs. They usually air after midnight. This broadcast schedule shows that these animations were not considered to be produced for the public from the beginning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is because Japanese cultural products have formed an industry with extremely mature market segmentation. Almost every work that appears in such a market is specialized for its main audience group, and the same is true for Japanese animation as a late-night TV show. Popular works during the same period when the first season of &quot;Giant&quot; was aired included &quot;There&#39;s Something Really Wrong with My Youth Love Story&quot;, &quot;How Can My Sister Be So Cute&quot;, &quot;Date A Live&quot;, &quot;The Perverted Prince and the Laughing Cat&quot;, &quot;Let&#39;s Work&quot; ! &quot;Demon Lord&quot;, &quot;A Certain Scientific Railgun S&quot;, etc. These animations, from background settings, characters, to story directions, are all customized for Japanese animation lovers in the traditional sense and can appeal to these core target groups. Good, but it also limits the dissemination of these works to a wider public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Correspondingly, the conventional production concept of Japanese animation has always been low cost and small output. In the Japanese animation industry, which has long relied on DVD and Blu-ray discs as its main profit channels, an animation can be considered a best-seller if it can sell 10,000 discs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Giant&quot; is an &quot;alien&quot; in Japanese animation. The average sales volume of the nine-volume animated disc of &quot;Giant&quot; in the first season was 52,067 copies, and as of August 2016, the total sales volume was 468,603 copies. It was also the number one selling TV animation in Japan in 2013. In mainland China, iQiyi, which exclusively introduced the copyright, received a total of 320 million online views by the end of the first season. In North America, the work has sold 200,000 copies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the Japanese animation works, the production level of &quot;Giant&quot; is far higher than the industry average (regardless of the graphics, actions, and soundtrack). This is the production company of the previous seasons of &quot;Giant&quot; Wit Studio has earned the nickname &quot;Hegemonic Society&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The production cycle of the &quot;Giant&quot; animation is also different - such a popular work did not continue to work while the iron was hot. The second animated season of &quot;Giant&quot; airs, four years after the first season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This long pause comes from the decision of &quot;Hegemony Society&quot;. The company believes that the success of &quot;Giant&quot; is mainly due to its own production level, and thinks that instead of producing &quot;Giant&quot; animation whose copyright does not belong to itself, To earn some hard-earned money, it is better to use production resources like &quot;Giant&quot; to produce your own original animation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This animation is &quot;Kabaneri of the Iron Fortress&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;The Iron Fortress&quot;), and Wit Studio has devoted considerable resources to it. Judging only from the animation quality outside of the plot, &quot;Iron Castle&quot; is better than the first season of &quot;Giant&quot;. However, &quot;Iron Castle&quot; is far from meeting Wit Studio&#39;s expectations in terms of reputation and popularity. The shortcoming lies in the story of &quot;Iron Castle&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This &quot;detour&quot; of Wit Studio just provides a control group, allowing us to clearly see the root cause of the popularity of &quot;Giant&quot; through the control variable method-its own story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from those stories with &quot;otaku&quot; attributes that are generally targeted at two-dimensional enthusiasts in the Japanese industry, &quot;Giant&quot; is an extremely rare work that is truly created according to the model of popular works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0IMa5Hcv5KLsY818h8abDian5L1jDBT82RpJW9Vp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0IMa5Hcv5KLsY818h8abDian5L1jDBT82RpJW9Vp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258822&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In &quot;Attack on Titan&quot;, humans and titans fight. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information picture/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The popular pop culture works have some very basic characteristics, that is, they do a good job of showing the world view, On the basis of suspense creation, rhythm control, characterization, etc., use good production level to tell a story well. The original comic book &quot;Giant&quot; followed this rule until the final ending - good-looking stories are liked by people. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;How to evaluate &quot;Giant&quot;? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Since the popularity of &quot;Giant&quot; mainly comes from the original comic, the evaluation of &quot;Giant&quot; should also be based on the original comic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding the &quot;Giant&quot; comic, readers at the time had this to say: When the final chapter of the &quot;Giant&quot; comic was released, the fans of &quot;Fullmetal Alchemist&quot; were the happiest because there would be more comics in the new century. The status of the ceiling is preserved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It seems almost a joke, but it is actually fair. Before the end, the &quot;Giant&quot; comic was expected to become the strongest shounen comic since 2000, but in the end it failed to reach the top due to problems with the ending. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The qualifiers such as &quot;new century&quot;, &quot;monthly updates&quot; and &quot;shounen comics&quot; are not like the increasingly subdivided statistics in sports competitions. &quot;As long as you add enough qualifiers, everyone can win.&quot; It is possible to become the first in history in some aspects.&quot; It&#39;s because, in a place like Japan that emphasizes market segmentation, there are great differences between different types of Japanese comics. Not only youth comics, shounen comics, and girls&#39; comics have completely different creative models and concepts. Even if they are both shounen comics, monthly comics and weekly comics are almost two completely different ecologies due to the difference in publication frequency and length of each issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, trying to simply and crudely bring together works from different creation eras in &quot;Guan Gong vs. Qin Qiong&quot; will not lead to valuable conclusions. Japanese comics, which are highly commercialized, are largely driven by readers’ preferences. Therefore, the story direction and themes expressed in a comic largely reflect the acceptance of the mainstream audience at that period, and are not solely determined by the author. Moreover, the comics created later are more likely to be more perfect in terms of plot and plot than the previous works. Putting aside these talks about the degree of completion and the level of narration, it is unavoidable that the book &quot;focuses on the present and ignores the past&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the most important indicators to measure the success of a commercial work - popularity and sales - cannot be used as a basis for comparing the quality of works across eras. The current Internet environment, coupled with the increasingly saturated marketing of producers, and the continuous development of markets outside Japan, have resulted in current works generally having higher popularity and sales than in the past. For example, when &quot;Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba the Movie: Mugen Train&quot; was released, it broke the Japanese movie box office record of &quot;Spirited Away&quot; which had been held for more than 20 years, and now ranks first in the box office history of Japanese movies. But I&#39;m afraid not many people would think that the quality of &quot;Demon Slayer&quot; really surpasses &quot;Spirited Away&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, how do you evaluate what kind of work &quot;Giant&quot; is in the history of Japanese comics? You might as well change your thinking and think about this question: When will the next highly topical Japanese comic work like &quot;Giant&quot; appear, and can it avoid the unfinished ending of &quot;Giant&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For current and future Japanese comics, works like &quot;Giant&quot; with a complete world structure and description of social organization are rare. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The world constructed in comic works actually comes from the author&#39;s own worldview and values. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking back at the history of Japanese comics, you will find that the eras in which cartoonists in previous periods provided them with rich life experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The earliest cartoonists, such as Osamu Tezuka and Fujiko F. Fujio, personally experienced World War II and the reconstruction of postwar Japan. In their works, they can well grasp the grand propositions of war and human destiny. For example, Osamu Tezuka&#39;s &quot;Firebird&quot; is a grand work on the theme of the universe and life that cannot be surpassed in the history of Japanese comics. Fujiko Fujio&#39;s &quot;Doraemon&quot;, even though it is a funny comic for children, does not forget to make Doraemon and Nobi Nobita laugh and cheer in the work: &quot;Japan is defeated!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The subsequent generation of Japanese cartoonists personally experienced the Japanese left-wing movement in the 1960s and 1970s, which affected the depth and value of exploring social propositions in their works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Next, as Japan’s economy took off in the 1980s, cartoonists who grew up in this era had an international vision that surpassed their predecessors. Their works also began to really focus on the real world outside Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today’s young manga authors are living in Japan during the “lost thirty years” after the economic bubble burst. Corresponding to the economic stagnation is the slow development of Japanese society and the isolation of popular culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comic writers who grew up in this environment not only have difficulty understanding the real relationship between countries, but also have difficulty understanding the logic of social operations. This has led to a large number of Japanese comics now. When they were still within the scope of campus in the early stage, the plots and characters looked pretty good. Once the plot develops beyond the scope of the school in the later period, various flaws will appear in the character logic and world setting, eventually leading to a bad ending. The same is true for popular works in recent years, such as &quot;Kaguya-sama Wants Me to Confess ~ Geniuses&#39; Battle of Love Minds ~&quot;, &quot;The Promised Neverland&quot;, and &quot;BEASTARS&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this perspective, works like &quot;Giant&quot; are rare in the current Japanese comic industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The difficulty of world building is only one aspect. &quot;Giant&quot; has the current popularity mainly because of its control of the story rhythm before the end. Before Chapter 90, the &quot;Giant&quot; comic achieved the charm that &quot;information asymmetry&quot; should have. Various hidden clues are revealed bit by bit, gradually piecing together a complete world. In this process, the foreshadowing and echoes before and after the comics can be said to be like a gray line and a thousand miles of hidden connections. This joy of exploration is the most attractive part of &quot;Giant&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, what if we don’t demand the authenticity of the world view, but instead ask, &quot;Can there be another Japanese comic with a story as exciting as &quot;Giant&quot; that is not unfinished at the same time?&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It doesn’t seem easy either. This is because, for a comic published in serial form, the fascinating previous plot and the bad ending are actually highly positively correlated. This form of serialization determines that Japanese comics are a matter of &quot;killing the king and taking the road&quot;. If you want to catch the attention of readers in the highly involved Japanese comics industry, you must make various abnormal plots in the early stages of comics that are &quot;not shocking but endless&quot;. The more these plots violate the logic of daily behavior, the easier it is to arouse readers&#39; interest. However, in order for the story to proceed normally, the author must give a reasonable explanation to these abnormal passages in the subsequent plot. This in itself is an almost impossible task. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Almost all Japanese comics have this problem. For example, one of the flaws of &quot;One Piece&quot;: the ceiling of the entire comic&#39;s combat power, why the red-haired one of the four emperors had his arm bitten off by a sea monster at the beginning of the comic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What makes this situation worse is the high update frequency of Japanese comics. As a weekly Japanese comic, comics authors are generally required to update more than ten pages of content every week, while monthly magazines generally require thirty to forty pages of content per issue. During this period, the author has to complete story and line conception and storyboard design, as well as comic drawing from draft to final product. Although most cartoonists hire more than one assistant, the work intensity of cartoonists is still far beyond what most people imagine. Under such a continuous and high-intensity working state, it is difficult to expect comic writers to maintain the exquisite conception of the story. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In contrast, &quot;Giant&quot;&#39;s clever handling of various early foreshadowings and clues seems so unusual among Japanese comics. It is also the continuous increase of previous characters and story lines that increases the difficulty of ending the entire story and also raises readers&#39; expectations. All this has become an unsolvable problem before the author Isayama Hajime. In the end, he chose an ending that puzzled most readers. This kind of regret is unavoidable when you think about it carefully. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 20 Nov 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[第十一届茅盾文学奖颁奖，专访茅奖新晋得主]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260851]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;On the evening of November 19, the 11th Mao Dun Literature Award Awards Ceremony was held in Tongxiang, Zhejiang Province, the hometown of Mr. Mao Dun. Five novels won awards: Yang Zhijun&#39;s &quot;Snow Mountain Land&quot;, Qiao Ye&#39;s &quot;Bao Shui&quot;, Liu Liangcheng&#39;s &quot;Bemba&quot;, Sun Ganlu&#39;s &quot;A Thousand Miles of Rivers and Mountains&quot;, and Dongxi&#39;s &quot;Echo&quot;.</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 23:25:06 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[支原体肺炎不只小孩得，大人也要当心]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260909]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 22:05:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;Mycoplasma pneumonia is not limited to children, adults should also be careful. Recently, a 30-year-old Ms. Zhu from Guangzhou developed fever, chills, weakness in her limbs, and coughed up yellow sputum. She originally thought it was a common cold, but she didn&#39;t get better. After a bronchoscopy, it was discovered that it was &quot;mycoplasma pneumonia.&quot; After targeted anti-infection He was discharged after improvement after treatment. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;She has an inexplicable high fever that persists and cannot be relieved by ordinary treatments&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;30-year-old Ms. Zhu is usually in good health, but she suddenly developed a fever recently. The maximum body temperature was 39.8°C, accompanied by chills, chills, and weakness in the limbs. She went to the hospital for treatment. After the doctor gave her ibuprofen to reduce fever and cephalosporins to fight infections, her symptoms were not significantly relieved. She then coughed up yellow and white sticky sputum that was difficult to cough up, especially at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, Ms. Zhu came to the outpatient department of the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine of the Second Provincial Hospital to seek treatment. Dr. He Yaowei discovered through chest CT examination that she had an infectious lesion in the lower lobe of her right lung, so she was admitted to the hospital to further improve the examination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The doctor found through bronchoscopy that there was a large amount of yellow-white sticky sputum in Ms. Zhu&#39;s right lower lung bronchus. Through rapid etiology testing, &quot;Mycoplasma pneumoniae&quot; was discovered. In other words, Ms. Zhu suffered from the recently popular &quot;Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In view of her situation, the doctor gave her levofloxacin for targeted anti-infection and symptomatic support treatment such as cough and phlegm reduction. Ms. Zhu quickly improved and was discharged. &lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0c6bbfe3c842916de7086c6ad38f2062.jpeg&quot; border=&quot; 0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;366&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/0c6bbfe3c842916de7086c6ad38f2062.jpeg&quot; data -key=&quot;258779&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Chest CT before treatment: Multiple small flakes and patchy increased density can be seen in the lower lobe of the right lung , the density is uneven, the boundary is blurred, patchy consolidation shadows can be seen, and air bronchial shadows can be seen within them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2a7c361a222986c53f627af6426d6189.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;376&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/19/2a7c361a222986c53f627af6426d6189.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258778&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Thorax CT after treatment: Multiple small flakes and patches of increased density in the lower lobe of the original right lung were significantly less dense than before. light. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Mycoplasma pneumoniae is also an important causative agent of adult pneumonia&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Sun Ruilin, director and chief physician of the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine of the Second Provincial Hospital, explained that mycoplasma pneumonia is Acute pulmonary infection mainly caused by interstitial lesions caused by Mycoplasma pneumoniae is significantly different from pneumonia caused by common bacteria such as Streptococcus pneumoniae in clinical manifestations. Therefore, it is clinically distinguished from Legionella pneumophila, Chlamydia pneumoniae and acute pneumonia. Pneumonia caused by other atypical pathogens such as grammaticis is collectively referred to as &quot;primary atypical pneumonia&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current epidemiological survey results of multiple adult community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) in China show that Mycoplasma pneumoniae and Streptococcus pneumoniae are important pathogens of adult CAP in my country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, the incubation period of mycoplasma pneumonia is 1 to 3 weeks, and the onset is diverse. Most patients only have low fever and fatigue, and some patients may have sudden high fever accompanied by obvious headache and myalgia. and nausea and other systemic symptoms of poisoning. The most prominent respiratory symptoms are dry cough, which often lasts for more than 4 weeks, is often accompanied by obvious sore throat, occasionally chest pain, and blood in sputum. In a few severe cases, respiratory failure may occur, manifesting as respiratory distress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the non-respiratory symptoms, earache, measles-like or scarlet fever-like rash are more common, and a few patients may be accompanied by gastroenteritis, pericarditis, myocarditis, meningoencephalitis, myelitis, and hemolysis. anemia, disseminated intravascular coagulation, arthritis and hepatitis, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having few positive signs in the lungs and obvious imaging manifestations are important features of mycoplasma pneumonia. The lesions are mostly cloud-like patchy infiltrates with blurred edges and low density, radiating from the hilum to the peripheral lung fields. When the lung parenchyma is involved, large consolidation shadows may also appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Quinols and tetracyclines are the drugs of choice for adults with mycoplasma pneumonia&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to reports, commonly used drugs for the treatment of mycoplasma pneumonia include macrolides, fluoroquinolones and Tetracyclines and macrolide antibiotics (such as azithromycin and clarithromycin) are currently the drugs of choice for the treatment of mycoplasma pneumonia in children. Quinolones and tetracyclines are the drugs of choice for adults with mycoplasma pneumonia. However, there are also mycoplasma pneumoniae and macrolide antibiotics. Lactone antibiotics are resistant, so the clinical selection should be based on the individual situation of the patient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Will mycoplasma pneumonia cause &quot;white lung&quot;? A small number of mycoplasma pneumonias invade a wide range of lesions or have poor mucus drainage, involving the bronchi, alveoli, and interstitium of the lungs, causing &quot;atelectasis&quot; and even &quot;white lungs&quot; on imaging. Through effective anti-infection, expectoration, and shooting, Back and bronchoscopy treatment and other methods can cure the disease in a short time, and most patients have a good prognosis. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Doctors remind that Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can occur throughout the year, especially in late summer, autumn and winter, when the incidence is high. The main sources of infection are patients and carriers, which are mainly spread through air droplets, such as coughing and sneezing. Preschool and school-age children and adolescents over 5 years old are at high risk. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The preventive measures for mycoplasma pneumonia mainly include: ① Stay away from the source of infection, regularly open windows indoors for ventilation, and it is recommended to wear a mask when going to crowded and closed places. ② Perform good hand hygiene, wash hands frequently with soap (hand sanitizer) and running water, or use alcohol-based hand sanitizer to wipe your hands. ③Eat more fresh vegetables and fruits, drink enough water, get enough sleep, and exercise moderately to enhance immunity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Ruilin, director and chief physician of the Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine of the Second Provincial Hospital, reminded that during the period of high incidence of respiratory infectious diseases, if you have upper respiratory tract infection symptoms such as cough and fever, it is recommended to seek medical treatment as soon as possible to find out the cause. Treat in a targeted manner and do not take medicine on your own to delay the condition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[体验“人生的旷野”后，两位985大学生选择回归国企和考研]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260901]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 05/14/ZJx5I7atgzPCjqiRvBFQtetVpSN3VGDPyg6VvrzP.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2449&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/05/14/ZJx5I7atgzPCjqiRvBFQtetVpSN3VGDPyg 6VvrzP. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;234068&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #0000ff;&quot;>;Click to play this podcast↑&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Every year during the school recruitment season, we can hear different employment stories of college students. In many narratives of 2023, the word &quot;wilderness of life&quot; appears frequently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although more and more college students are joining the difficult job search path of civil servants, central enterprises, state-owned enterprises, large Internet companies, etc., there are still some people who choose to find the wilderness of life on the so-called non-mainstream path. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two guests on this podcast, one of whom is a graduate with a double 985 master&#39;s degree, chose to take 3 months out of the busy school recruitment season to study cooking at New Oriental School and graduate. It has been on the hot searches on Weibo and Xiaohongshu twice. Another guest is also from 985 University. After graduating from undergraduate degree in 2021, he has experienced 100 different lives through various unique part-time experiences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, after experiencing the wilderness of life, they eventually returned to the traditional path. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly has higher education brought us? Do we have to return to the mainstream path eventually? Does the wilderness of life really exist? Let’s find the answer in this podcast conversation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000;&quot;>;Guests for this issue: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Qianyu&amp;nbsp;2022 Master&#39;s Degree from Renmin University of China Graduate, currently working in a state-owned enterprise in Shanghai&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;KAMA (pseudonym) 2021 undergraduate graduate of Nanjing University, currently preparing to take exams in the art field&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #800000 ;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Listening tips:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 03:25 Before and after graduation, I was on two hot searches&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 09:52 at In college, you will feel that everyone has the same goals&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 13:48 Life is a process of constantly collecting plastic bags&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 25:57 Leaving the step-by-step study life , I chose a stamp collecting part-time job&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 36:25 Young people always have to do a reverse weaning from their parents&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 38:43 When I was working part-time, I concealed my academic qualifications &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 50:11 Learning to cook at New Oriental made me feel that people can live no matter what&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;► 52:20 After leaving college, I realized my shameful sense of superiority&lt;/p>; p>; &lt;p>;► 60:44 Does higher education constrain our choices? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Editor: Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right ;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;Promotion and operation: Liao Zhichun, Zhao Wenyi, Zheng Yuchun&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 21:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[双向出击拉拢英菲，日本意欲何为？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260861]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-19 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 15, 2023, the United Kingdom will send 150 soldiers to Japan to participate in the &quot;Alert Island 23&quot; military exercise . This bilateral exercise is the first joint exercise since the &quot;Reciprocal Access Agreement&quot; between the two countries officially came into effect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A week ago, the fifth &quot;2+2&quot; meeting between Japan and the UK&#39;s foreign ministers and defense ministers was held face-to-face after a lapse of five years. In a joint statement issued after the talks, the two sides made it clear that they would increase the frequency of joint exercises. In addition, Japan will also provide cooperation with the United Kingdom in dispatching an aircraft carrier strike group to the Indo-Pacific in 2025. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Providing cooperation for the deployment of British aircraft carriers to the Indo-Pacific is just the latest step in deepening defense cooperation between Japan and countries outside the Asia-Pacific region. At present, Japan is promoting the joint development of next-generation fighter aircraft with the United Kingdom and Italy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan not only extended military cooperation invitations to European countries, but also played diplomatic cards in Southeast Asia. Previously, from November 3 to 5, Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida visited the Philippines and Malaysia for the first time. Since the beginning of this year, the Kishida government has frequently visited Southeast Asia, covering almost 10 ASEAN member states. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan&#39;s efforts to win over countries in and outside the Asia-Pacific region such as the United Kingdom, France, Australia, and the Philippines are nothing more than wanting to revisit its old dream of the Russo-Japanese War and seek more interests for itself. While the United States continues to promote its Indo-Pacific strategy &#39;, and in the context of great power competition, relevant countries have also followed suit, trying to get a share of the regional game.&quot; Teng Jianqun, director of the Diplomatic Research Center of Hunan Normal University, told Southern Weekend reporters that in the context of multipolarization of international politics and global economicization, At the moment, Japan is trying to win over a large number of countries to stir up trouble in the Asia-Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 9, the spokesperson of the Chinese Embassy in the UK responded to the erroneous remarks about China in the UK-Japan “2+2” joint statement, saying, “China has indisputable territorial sovereignty and maritime rights in the East China Sea and South China Sea. rights and interests. China will unswervingly safeguard its sovereignty and rights and interests, and firmly oppose relevant countries to sow relations between regional countries and create confrontation and confrontation. If the UK and Japan really want to become responsible countries, they should stop fanning the flames and stirring up trouble everywhere. Do things that contribute to regional peace and stability.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/E8VmoXNPlqgtjxiaGlfabmI7LvYMgX0hrypTsScd.jpg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1700&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/E8VmoXNPlqgtjxiaGlfabmI7LvYMgX0hrypTsScd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258739&quot; >;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On January 11, 2023, local time, London, England, British Prime Minister Sunak (right) and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida in London Towers sign defense agreement. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Winning over&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On November 7, Fumio Kishida met with the US Secretary of State at his official residence. Lincoln talks, exchanged views on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict, and confirmed that the two sides will cooperate on related issues. The day before, Blinken had just concluded his &quot;whirlwind diplomacy&quot; in the Middle East and arrived in Japan to attend the Group of Seven (G7) foreign ministers&#39; meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The G7 Foreign Ministers’ Meeting, held in Tokyo from November 7th to 8th, was the last offline meeting hosted by Japan during its tenure as the G7 Presidency. During the meeting, Japanese Foreign Minister Yoko Kamikawa held talks with the foreign ministers of Canada, Germany and other member states, and took the opportunity to hold 95-minute consultations with the British Foreign Minister and Defense Minister. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In talks with defense ministers from various countries, the concept of a &quot;free and open Indo-Pacific&quot; was frequently mentioned by Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan&#39;s reaffirmation of the &#39;Indo-Pacific Concept&#39; through the G7 Foreign Ministers&#39; Meeting is just a rehash of old tunes with nothing new. What really deserves attention is Japan&#39;s gradual advancement in implementation.&quot; China Institute of International Studies Tang Qifang, associate researcher at the International Institute for Strategic Studies, analyzed this to a Southern Weekend reporter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, the Japanese government adopted three security documents: the revised &quot;National Security Strategy&quot;, &quot;National Defense Strategy&quot; and &quot;Defense Force Preparation Plan&quot;, which not only clearly stated that it must have counterattack capabilities, but also emphasized that While taking the Japan-U.S. alliance as the foundation, we will deepen cooperation with so-called &quot;friendly countries that share values&quot; and strive to realize the concept of a &quot;free and open Indo-Pacific.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Less than a month after the &quot;Three Security Documents&quot; were released, Japan and the United Kingdom signed a &quot;Reciprocal Access Agreement&quot;, allowing both sides to conduct larger-scale and more complex military exercises on each other&#39;s territory. At this point, the United Kingdom has become the only European country that can conduct bilateral military exercises on Japanese territory, and is also the second country to sign this agreement with Japan after Australia. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After the promulgation of the new security strategy, Japan&#39;s defense policy has shifted from defensive to offensive, and the weapons and equipment, combat posture, and troop deployment of the Japanese Self-Defense Force have also changed from defensive to offensive.&quot; Teng Jianqun pointed out, &quot;The signing of the Reciprocal Access Agreement means that the relationship between Japan and relevant countries is entering a paramilitary alliance. The Japanese Self-Defense Forces can use this to go out and send troops to the United Kingdom and Australia to achieve the so-called &#39;national normalcy&#39; in a roundabout way.&quot; At the same time, Japan also wants to take the opportunity to release its military production capacity and accelerate the entry of weapons and equipment into the international market.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to linking up with countries outside the Asia-Pacific region, the Philippines has also become a key target for Japan to try to win over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 3, Fumio Kishida arrived in the Philippines and held talks with Philippine President Marcos. In Manila, Fumio Kishida delivered his first speech to the Philippine Congress. In his speech, Kishida Fumio praised that bilateral relations between Japan and the Philippines have entered a &quot;golden age.&quot; At the same time, Japan and the Philippines also reached a consensus on launching negotiations on the Reciprocal Access Agreement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The targets chosen by Japan are all core members of the US military alliance. Australia is known as the US&#39;s &#39;Southern Anchor&#39; in the Asia-Pacific region, and the UK is its core ally in Europe.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out, &quot;Although the Philippines is weak, the new President Marcos has tilted his foreign policy toward the United States after taking office. The United States is trying to turn it into a sharp thorn wedged in the South China Sea.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Linkage&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Japan is not only &quot;casting a wide net&quot; on the road to expanding its &quot;paramilitary alliance&quot;, but also continues to promote joint military exercises with relevant countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japanese media reported that the goal of the &quot;2+2&quot; talks between Britain and Japan is to enhance military coordination and interoperability by holding &quot;more frequent and more complex military exercises.&quot; After the signing of the Reciprocal Access Agreement, the first joint military exercise between Japan and Britain is on the way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, during the meeting of the G7 foreign ministers, the United States dispatched two aircraft carriers, the USS Ronald Reagan and USS Vinson, and the Japanese helicopter carrier USS Hyuga to conduct joint military exercises in the Philippine Sea. Rear Adm. Carlos Sadillo, commander of the U.S. Navy&#39;s First Aircraft Carrier Strike Group, pointed out that the exercise was designed to &quot;demonstrate how the United States and Japan can quickly respond to crises and interoperate and coordinate.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Australia, the Japan Air Self-Defense Force is seeking to normalize military deployment. Japan plans to station F-35, F-15 and F-2 fighter jets at air bases in Australia as early as fiscal 2024, with each deployment lasting several months. Japanese media pointed out that there is no clear legal basis for dispatching permanent troops to Australia or providing security assistance when necessary. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The Reciprocal Access Agreement facilitates joint military operations between Japan and Britain and Australia, and the same equipment purchased from the United States provides a sufficient platform for mutual integration and interoperability.&quot; Military Expert Wang Qunhuai told Southern Weekend reporters. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2020, the United States approved the sale of 105 F-35 fighter jets to Japan. Adding the 42 previously purchased, Japan will have a total of 147 F-35 fighter jets. Australia and the United Kingdom are also &quot;die-hard fans&quot; of F-35 fighters and have ordered a total of 210 F-35 fighters from the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, in 2023, the United States successively agreed to sell hundreds of &quot;Tomahawk&quot; cruise missiles to Australia and Japan to enhance its naval long-range strike capabilities. It is worth mentioning that the United States has always been very cautious about the export of &quot;Tomahawk&quot; missiles. Prior to this, Britain was the only country besides the United States to possess this type of missile. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In fact, the sale of weapons and equipment is an important tool for the United States to strengthen alliance relationships. The more American equipment is used, the deeper the relevant countries will be tied to the United States, and the more military sovereignty concessions will inevitably be made.&quot; Analysis by Wang Qunhuai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Japan’s military assistance to the Philippines came more directly. &quot;The Kishida government not only wants to provide money and equipment, but also tries to send troops to the Philippines.&quot; Tang Qifang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his visit to Manila, Fumio Kishida sent a &quot;maritime gift package&quot; to the Philippines. According to a senior Japanese government official on November 3, Japan will provide five sets of fixed coast surveillance radars to the Philippines. This is the first time Japan has provided defense equipment to a foreign country under this mechanism since it established the &quot;Government Security Capability Strengthening Support&quot; (OSA) framework in April. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In the past, Japan focused on relying on &#39;government development assistance&#39; (ODA) and using economic diplomacy to expand its international influence, but now it has turned to improving the security capabilities of recipient countries.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out, &quot;Japan It is hollowing out the peaceful constitution step by step, trying to transform from an economic power to a military and political power.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Team formation&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The interviewed experts and scholars told Southern Weekend reporters that Japan and the United Kingdom , the Philippines and other countries inside and outside the Asia-Pacific region &quot;form a circle&quot; and actively carry out defense cooperation, each getting what they need and utilizing each other. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2016, then Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe held talks with Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and proposed the &quot;Free and Open Indo-Pacific Strategy&quot; for the first time in the joint communiqué. &quot;Since then, Japan has continued to promote this proposition in diplomatic settings, intending to cooperate with the United States in enhancing its intervention capabilities in the East China Sea, South China Sea and even the Asia-Pacific region, and to demonstrate its presence and enhance its international status and influence.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Tang Qifang’s view, Japan’s continuous breach of red lines in defense policy is inseparable from the acquiescence and connivance of the United States. &quot;The United States expects Japan to act as a &#39;pawn&#39; in the Asia-Pacific and help it reduce its burden and pressure. Japan also hopes to vigorously develop its military power and pursue becoming a military and political power. Although the interests of the two sides are different, the strategic goals are basically the same.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;The United Kingdom, Australia and other countries also have their own plans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;After Brexit, the UK has become an &#39;outcast&#39; in Europe. Based on geopolitical considerations, the UK hopes to use Japan as a &#39;bridgehead&#39; to strengthen its military deployment in the Asia-Pacific and highlight its status and From the perspective of business interests, the UK attaches great importance to the economic vitality of the Asia-Pacific region.&quot; Teng Jianqun analyzed that this is also the main reason why European and Asia-Pacific countries are willing to cooperate with Japan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as March 2021, the British government released &quot;Global Britain in the Era of Competition: A Comprehensive Assessment of Security, Defense, Development and Foreign Policy&quot;, which pointed out for the first time that the UK&#39;s global strategy must move towards the &quot;Indo-Pacific&quot; &quot;region&quot; tilt, and in May of that year dispatched the most advanced &quot;Queen Elizabeth&quot; aircraft carrier strike group to the Indo-Pacific region for the first time to conduct so-called &quot;freedom of navigation&quot; operations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the British aircraft carrier&#39;s &quot;global journey&quot; did not go smoothly. Two destroyers accidentally separated from the formation. In September 2023, the British Navy&#39;s &quot;Queen Elizabeth&quot; aircraft carrier conducted joint patrols with allies along the coast of Norway and the North Atlantic. Due to the significant reduction in the number of British Air Force fighter jets, the British aircraft carrier, which can normally carry about 30 F-35B fighter jets, only carries 8 fighter jets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The wish of &#39;Global Britain&#39; is very good, but Britain is no longer the &#39;Empire on which the sun never sets&#39; in the past. Whether its strength can match its ambitions is still a question. And the Philippines is not only weak in strength. On the other hand, the determination to follow the United States is not as strong as that of Japan, Britain and Australia.&quot; Tang Qifang pointed out, &quot;It remains to be seen how important the relevant countries can play in the so-called &#39;Indo-Pacific strategy&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Facts As a die-hard ally of the United States, Japan is not willing to become a &quot;tool&quot; of the United States and still hopes to regain its autonomy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In December 2022, the United Kingdom, Japan and Italy announced that they would jointly develop a common airframe for next-generation fighter aircraft. The three countries are determined to integrate their respective capabilities in cutting-edge air combat technologies such as stealth and high-tech sensors. By 2035 The latest fighter jet was launched years ago. It is worth noting that this is the first time since World War II that Japan has participated in a joint research and development program for advanced fighter aircraft that does not include the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Japan has specially set aside funds in its defense budget for fiscal year 2024 and plans to develop an air-to-air missile for use by the next-generation fighter aircraft jointly developed by the three countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Japan does not want to put all its eggs in the American basket, nor does it want to hand over its military industry dividends to the United States. However, historically speaking, no matter what kind of cooperation Japan adopts, it will It is difficult to break through the restrictions imposed by the United States in military production. This time is no exception. The United States will try its best to block it and strangle its research and development plans, including Japan&#39;s new generation fighter aircraft, in the cradle.&quot; Teng Jianqun concluded, &quot;Japan&#39;s Strategic independence has always been difficult to escape from the constraints of the Japan-US alliance framework.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>