<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[贵人鸟转型卖吃的，国产运动鞋三巨头正在分岔路口]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259989]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/04/eaa4eb85be65a96bdaa301cfe2d17880.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;631&quot; height=&quot;841&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/04/eaa4eb85be65a96bdaa301cfe2d17880.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As one of the most sought-after items in the fashion circle, the popularity of sneakers is receding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 22, Guirenniao issued an announcement stating that in view of the decline in revenue and continued losses of the sports shoes and apparel business since the judicial reorganization, and the increasingly fierce market competition, the company will end the sports shoes and apparel business that has been in business for 36 years. And the grain business will be the company&#39;s main business development direction in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guirenniao’s financial report shows that from January to June 2023, Guirenniao’s sports shoes and apparel business achieved operating income of 232 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 19.51%. From 2018 to 2022, ST Guiren’s annual net profit attributable to the parent company suffered 4 losses, with a cumulative loss of more than 2 billion yuan. The number of &quot;Guirenniao&quot; brand retail terminals has dropped from 2,358 in 2019 to 1,584 in the first half of 2023. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/4e35dce86edf26ad3c2e59e5511f4fe6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/4e35dce86edf26ad3c2e59e5511f4fe6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257038&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, Anta Sports, Li Ning, and Xtep International have successively released their financial reports for the first half of 2023. Facing the recovery in performance of Nike and Adidas in China, domestic products are still struggling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, compared with last year’s report card where Anta’s revenue surpassed Nike China’s and Li-Ning’s revenue was ahead of Adidas China’s, there is still a certain decline in performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/93ba6b3e658359194e85bd53db909e2e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/93ba6b3e658359194e85bd53db909e2e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257039&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Data show that in the first half of this year, among the three major domestic sports brands, only Xtep is still significantly expanding its stores. The current total number of stores is 8,256, ranking second. Li Ning has a net decrease of 155 main brand stores and is the only group that has no net increase in brand stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ea57ccb33ca4fc7db4141baa349f8f4e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ea57ccb33ca4fc7db4141baa349f8f4e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257040&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In the past, due to the brand effect of several major fashion brands, Adidas and Nike had absolute advantages over domestic Anta, Li Ning, Xtep, and 361 Degrees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d2cbe8eccffe6128694adefe9d34b673.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d2cbe8eccffe6128694adefe9d34b673.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257041&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;Today, the three giants of domestic products are deeply involved in their own core technologies - Anta&#39;s &quot;nitrogen technology&quot;, &quot;Li Ning&#39;s&quot; flick technology, and Xtep&#39;s &quot;XTEP ACE cushioning technology platform&quot;. They have fully blossomed with differentiated strategies. Anta and Li Ning have continued to Leading the domestic sports brand market for two years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/57b049e6ef9c40de403b13c20b8132ba.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/57b049e6ef9c40de403b13c20b8132ba.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257042&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;In the future, if sports brands want to go further, they cannot just &quot;rest on their laurels&quot; or &quot;rest on their laurels&quot;. The addition of design languages ​​such as accessories, graffiti, and deconstructive splicing in shoe design has been squeezed out of the mainstream. The scope of the discussion was replaced by the proposition of &quot;how to make sneakers not like a pair of sneakers.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e009a49268a310f5faf5ecea0da8dfb1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e009a49268a310f5faf5ecea0da8dfb1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257043&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;De-sneakerization and artificial intelligence are innovative paths worth exploring. At the same time, guided by audience thinking, sports brands must better understand the hearts of young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3e9648a7aab0c4e2c59e37f9a8fe3a93.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height= &quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3e9648a7aab0c4e2c59e37f9a8fe3a93.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257089&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;140&quot; data- mce-height=&quot;140&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the rise of DIY culture, more and more young people are creating secondary creations on sports shoes, transforming old shoes through graffiti, modification, and homemade methods. With the emergence of the national trend, the sales of Huai Li Guochao modified shoes have increased rapidly and are loved by many young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, &quot;Know&quot; will discuss with you how domestic sports shoes can break through the bottleneck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子用16.8万彩礼钱环游中国：抽身离开也是一种觉醒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259967]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Do you agree with this kind of &quot;living yourself&quot;? A man in Shanxi broke off his engagement due to a temporary increase in the price of the bride&#39;s bride price, and used the bride price to resign and travel. On June 1 this year, Zhu set out with his luggage on his back. In five months, he visited more than 40 cities and spent more than 30,000 yuan. &quot;The main means of transportation are green trains, and it doesn&#39;t cost much to stay in a youth hostel.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu introduced that he and his girlfriend met through a blind date, &quot;We have been dating for almost eight or nine months, and I feel that When the time comes, we are ready to get married.&quot; He said that a bride price of RMB 188,000 is the &quot;normal market&quot; in the local area. &quot;Ours is called a &#39;big package&#39;. This money includes wedding photos, three coins, etc. RMB 188,000. I have savings of RMB 168,000 and 2 I just borrowed it from a friend.&quot; Later, his girlfriend asked for an additional 30,000 yuan, &quot;I said I couldn&#39;t afford it, and I borrowed these from others,&quot; and they broke up after a quarrel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Frankly speaking, Zhu still hasn’t let go. Taking the green train and staying in a youth hostel, the five-month trip only cost more than 30,000 yuan, which is very economical. This is probably because this is the hard-earned money that I have saved and I don’t want to spend it lavishly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More importantly, he sympathizes with the hardships of his parents, saying: &quot;Every time I go on a blind date, I feel a little uncomfortable. I eat Haidilao with the girls, watch movies, etc., but my parents have never eaten Haidilao.&quot; &quot;Lao.&quot; His parents originally planned to help him pay the down payment for buying a house in Taiyuan. &quot;I also feel sorry for my parents. They have never been to many places and they are still thinking about buying me a house.&quot; I did not tell my parents about my resignation. &quot;I will tell you if I have the opportunity in the future, but I may not tell them for the time being. I am afraid that they will not accept it and say that I am not doing my job properly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be seen that Zhu and his parents are both relatively traditional people in terms of values. They are down-to-earth, simple, have long-term considerations for life, and have a solemn attitude towards marriage and family. On the surface, 30,000 yuan was the straw that broke the camel&#39;s back; in fact, Zhu was probably worried that once this case was opened, it would be endless in the future. The reason why his girlfriend asked for 30,000 yuan was that &quot;her best friends all paid back.&quot; In addition, I asked for another 30,000 yuan.&quot; There is no end to the comparison, and your married life may not be comfortable and harmonious in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of evolutionary psychology, the origin of marriage or monogamy is: women have a 9-month pregnancy period, and there is a lactation period after the baby is born. It takes a long time for human children to reach adulthood, and It is necessary to acquire various survival skills, which requires a father&#39;s role to provide protection and survival resources for mother and child, and to teach his children through words and deeds; what men gain is to reduce the uncertainty of father and son (paternal uncertainty) through marriage, and to assume family responsibilities and social responsibility. The father in the sense is a product of cultural construction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whether it is Chinese or Western, traditional marriage values ​​and underlying logic are the same. However, after entering modern society, this set of values ​​was first impacted by individualism and then deconstructed by progressivism/postmodernism, making it increasingly unsustainable. Raising your own children gives you a continuous sense of gain and happiness, but it is indeed hard work, consumes money and effort, and also requires a sense of responsibility and the ability to delay gratification vs. spending money immediately to enjoy the present and carpe diem. Which one will the chic &quot;modern people&quot; choose? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, when some women complain about what they get from marriage, some men will also reflect on why they got married. When some women talk about having a boy or a girl and the so-called right of surname, they say to the man, &quot;Does your family have a throne to inherit?&quot; Some men will suddenly realize and ask themselves: There is indeed no throne in my family to inherit, so I will spend a lot of money. Is it worth getting married and going through all the hard work of raising children? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When more and more men and women ask &quot;What is the meaning of getting married, starting a family, and having children?&quot; this in itself means the weakening of the reproductive instinct and the decline of marriage and family values, which in turn means the value of the benefits of childbearing. Write down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, betrothal gifts are not the same thing as betrothal gifts in traditional society. Bride price is the price paid by lower-class men to enter the marriage market, but it has been rising and becoming more general in recent years. The marriage market is a regional and multi-level composite structure. The bottom market may have more men and fewer women, but the top market may have more women and fewer men. According to the logic of supply and demand, when there are more men and fewer women, the man will pay the bride price, but when there are more women and fewer men, whether Will it be the other way around? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you get divorced a few days after getting married, it is almost impossible to get back all the bride price; one party will add the other party&#39;s name to the real estate certificate and lose half of the house. &quot;Talk about feelings and hurt money&quot;, investors are facing increasing risks. In the marriage market, the investor, as Party A, will consider reducing transactions when faced with excessive requirements and costs. This is squeezing marriage from the cost of childbearing. Zhu broke off the engagement due to a temporary increase in the price of the bride&#39;s bride price, which is another vivid case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In modern society, the self-awareness of men and women is constantly strengthening, which is the so-called &quot;self-awakening&quot;. Since there is a female awakening, there will be a male awakening, and the awakening must eventually be two-way. There may be a sequence of awakenings, but equality is the final outcome and stable equilibrium. In a system that evolves over time, the transient state solution is a temporary phenomenon, and the long-term steady solution is the final result. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, a female teacher in Zhengzhou’s resignation letter, “The world is so big, I want to see it,” became popular on the Internet. Public opinion praised her for her self-awakening, courage to pursue personal freedom, and living her life. Zhu&#39;s decision to break off the engagement and then use his savings to travel around China based on the same motivation deserves the same evaluation. As an adult, regardless of gender, if you don’t want to live a routine and step-by-step life, if you want to chase your dreams and be responsible for your own decisions, there is nothing wrong with that. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To what extent will men and women awaken in the future? What will be the shape of a stable marriage and family in the future? It’s hard to say, but one thing is certain: it must be based on the principle of equality between men and women, and a new stable balance will be formed based on equality between men and women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Any worthwhile marriage must be based on love and morality. Only in this way can home be a haven where people can relax physically and mentally, rather than a place where the spirit is exhausted. This requires all kinds of reciprocity: reciprocity in love, reciprocity in family responsibility, reciprocity in giving, reciprocity in providing emotional value... A relationship in which one party always gives and the other party always extracts cannot go far. Therefore, when you find that you are entering such a relationship, you need to stop your losses in time; or, after you find that you have entered such a relationship, you need to get out. Who can deny that this is an awakening? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[索南才让：写最后一代游牧人的故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259932]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/RaZv85deQGOVAoK0hsyPdiKIWKD5XbflDNetMbJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/RaZv85deQGOVAoK0hsyPdiKIWKD5XbflDNetMb JQ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256518&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking off the maroon or indigo Mongolian clothes, taking off the top hat, and putting on a polo shirt is like opening a portal and stepping into another world. The 38-year-old writer Sonam Cairang&#39;s figure is not considered tall and majestic among herdsmen. After leaving the bright clothes and running pastures, walking in the crowded city, even the slightly laborious raised tongue reveals a reserved and bookish tone. He habitually put on a polite, courteous, and gentlemanly face, and sat down at the dining table, reminding himself that there wasn&#39;t much red wine in the glass, but he still had to take a sip first. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Having just left his hometown in his twenties, the outside world’s default behavior of standing at the wine table for a toast and saying a bunch of toast words made him at a loss. He followed the example in panic for a while, and then lied that he never drank. When he returned to the grassland, he relieved his psychological burden and started drinking. The rule in the pastoral area is that no matter how hospitable the other party is, no one will stand up and thank the host with a glass of wine and say that I will return the invitation next time; nor will the other party be offended just because he said the wrong thing. In no particular order, everyone started making fists after having two or three glasses of wine, &quot;It&#39;s much simpler, especially direct and rough.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People living in grasslands, especially in alpine areas, can&#39;t be said to be indifferent in their emotions. In short, they are not that Rich.&quot; When grazing, it is common to go two or three days without seeing anyone to communicate or talk. The longest time, judging from Suonan Cairang&#39;s personal record, this silence lasted forty or fifty days. He was talking to himself in a desolate and vast environment, and he had developed a distant and overlooking gaze, making it difficult for him to be sentimental. &quot;Man develops this kind of character in an interdependent relationship with the environment. His attitude towards living creatures is different and more ruthless.&quot; Livestock fed by hand can be a tool for herders to travel far, or a Food to go with alcohol. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Sonam Cairang’s short story collection &quot;Looking for Signals&quot; published in 2023, these animals have also become the real murderers that drive the plot. During a dialogue at the Shanghai Book Fair in August, guest Han Songluo deliberately counted the ways of death that appeared in the book in advance, and recited at the scene in a tone like a bill report, &quot;One death from freezing, one sudden death, two deaths from being run over by a cow.&quot; times, and once fell from a horse to death...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compare the &quot;modern ways&quot; of death in Alice Munro&#39;s writings about those who fled the town, such as plane and train crashes, cancer, shipwrecks and drowning, etc. , Han Songluo classified the passages in Suonan Cai&#39;s book in which he sacrificed his life to contend with nature or interact with animals as &quot;pre-modern&quot;. The author explained that this is indeed an environmental test that plateau herders face every day. &quot;There are often floods and lightning in Qinghai. People are struck to death by lightning, thrown to death by horses, and various accidents occur.&quot; Han Songluo With emotion, &quot;I thought we were very far away from pre-modern society, but Sonam&#39;s words bring us back to this scene, where the relationship between humans, animals, land, and death is still maintained by instinct.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yes. The conversation took place in the Miguel de Cervantes Library, next door to the fashionable Julu Road. Some viewers in the audience did not buy it and raised questions, saying that in such an environment, &quot;it is completely impossible to think of the grassland.&quot; , and also didn’t understand, “What does it mean to tell stories about the past?”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Suonan Cairang still responded in a low voice, “There is a lag in writing. What you feel at the moment cannot immediately become a work. After Only through precipitation and fermentation can we write about the grazing experience passed down from our fathers.&quot; As for whether it can convey a strong sense of foreignness, this is actually an important clue for Suonan Cairang&#39;s writing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His novel collection &quot;In the Wasteland&quot; published in 2021 was once spotted by director Wanma Caidan, and his new work &quot;Looking for Signal&quot; was also shortlisted for the 7th Pingyao International Film Festival in October 2023. &quot;Migration Plan·From Literature to Film and Television&quot; section - the story must exude a completely different temperament from the city, which is why directors have successively purchased the copyright and tried to adapt it; but this kind of northwest ranch style is not the focus of his text, as the final A generation of nomads, he shouldered personal experiences, the memories of his father&#39;s generation, and the collision of life when he went out to work as an adult. After a few years, he returned to his hometown with mixed eyes. Therefore, he was never satisfied with recording the strange scenery on the surface, but stood in the Explore the spiritual changes of herdsmen from a broader perspective - facing the expansion of urbanization undoubtedly reveals more and more consistent ways of living and thinking, making readers unable to feel the &quot;grassland&quot; coming towards them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2008, he came to Beijing with 300 yuan in his pocket and worked in a factory that made urban sculptures. Before entering the factory, he bought two volumes of the Nobel Prize in Literature collection, as well as a collection of works that cost more than 100 yuan. A biography of Faulkner that cost almost half of his net worth. One time I didn&#39;t go back to my hometown during the Spring Festival. I was watching fireworks alone in an empty factory. I suddenly felt a force, as if Qinghai Lake was close in front of me. I pushed open the invisible door of my home. My father, who had drunk too much the day before, was lying on the sofa with his hat on. sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“My hometown is the bloodline of my writing. Later I started to doubt it, and the thread of pulling became weaker and weaker. Only after I leave can I write about my hometown and understand it.” Now there are no sheep left in his family, and there are about 80 of them. The cattle are usually taken care of by his younger brother, and he returns to the ranch once a month. In order to maintain his creative state, he lives in Haiyan County, not far from the ranch, and retains some urban living habits. When he gets up every day, he jogs, makes coffee, eats eggs, and then reads a book for a while. After 8 o&#39;clock, Go to the studio and start writing for the day. When I write seven to eight hundred words a day, I no longer want to write, so I go do something else. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The editor of the new book once concluded, &quot;Most of his novels are about stories about alpine grassland pastoral areas, but they do not make readers feel distant.&quot; The reason is Liu Xiaolin, vice chairman of the Qinghai Provincial Writers Association and a critic. After some analysis, &quot;he did not deliberately highlight the nationality and regional customs, lacked the quiet, simple and melodious pastoral mood of ordinary prairie novels, and did not examine the nationality in the binary opposition between the world and the local, tradition and modernity.&quot; The past and the future, and he has no intention of turning the novel into a national allegory. The usual thinking in the writing of these national literatures does not seem to affect him at all. He prefers to adopt a cold and calm narrative, focusing on the secular life of the grassland. , daily life such as grazing, drinking, and falling in love, showing the increasingly chaotic living conditions and life forms of the grasslands under the impact of modern civilization.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/11/01/l2VGmDF1AHXwd1npPJEKUFA3j1fCJQZKAIjXoWV6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;546&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/11/01/l2VGmDF1AHXwd1npPJEKUFA3j1fCJQZKAIjXoWV6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256523&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Suonan Cairang’s own ranch&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The last generation of nomads in their hometown&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang:&lt;/ strong>;&lt;span>;I especially like watching movies. Hong Kong police and gangster movies and TVB costume martial arts movies have been with me growing up. Every year except winter, there is a mobile tent video hall on the grassland. It is very popular. At night, the speakers start playing videos to attract customers. Grasslands are different from cities. The sound penetration is particularly strong and can be heard within a radius of more than ten kilometers. When we heard it, we felt so itchy that we couldn&#39;t sit still at home. We immediately ran to a heavily trafficked three-way intersection a few kilometers away and got into a mobile tent set up on the roadside. The chairs take up space, so in order to seat as many people as possible, everyone sits cross-legged, not even able to stretch their legs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before going to school, my uncle was a movie projectionist on the grassland. I sat on his carriage and followed him to more than a dozen villages to enlarge the film. When I dropped out of school at the age of 12 and returned to the ranch, I started watching in mobile tents until I was in my twenties. At first it was VCD, then DVD, and the price rose from 50 cents to one dollar. The shows are different every day, not just Hong Kong films, but also some classic films from the Mainland, as well as foreign films like &quot;Gone with the Wind.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sounds like a wonderful teenage period. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The only thing I have not regretted until now is leaving school. At that time, conditions did not allow (study). My family was in a pastoral area. If I wanted to study, I had to go to the county town. The winter pasture was 40 kilometers away, and the summer pasture was 70 or 80 kilometers away. There was no boarding school in the county, so I had to stay with relatives, and there was no one to take care of me. In addition, I couldn’t read it myself, and my family was very happy when I stopped reading, because I needed help. Looking back later, I probably gained more outside of school than in school. I didn’t study in school. I only studied after I came out. Going to school and studying are two different things. School is about learning, not reading. The first book I came into contact with was &quot;Dragon and the Eight Parts&quot;. I took that book to herd sheep. It was winter, and it was a day full of yellow sand, but I had no time to pay attention to other things all day long. I don’t even know where my flock is. That was the beginning of my real reading. As for movies, I probably watched thousands of them in those years. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;These movies will be helpful for you to write novels in the future Impact? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think a big part of my writing is film, whether it is narration or observing the dialogue of characters. Or in terms of demeanor, it will definitely have an impact in a subtle way. Because when I watch a movie, I will be particularly immersed in it. I will remember the lines in a good movie. I can even imitate the expression, intonation, and speed of each character when they say those lines. The scene environment will also be in my mind. vivid in my mind. I really long for that kind of ability right now. If I&#39;m watching a movie and you&#39;re talking to me next to me, I won&#39;t hear you at all. Although this habit has not been completely lost, I still cannot concentrate as before, including reading. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Watching a movie in a mobile tent saw Twenty How old were you? Did you have a TV at home at that time? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Electricity was introduced to our home in 2008. I was 23 years old. I was already married by that time, and tent movies were slowly disappearing. The boom is booming. After the advent of solar energy, many herdsmen bought a small black and white TV, a VCD, two large solar chargers and a battery to watch at home, as did my family. I often see that the battery is depleted. The electricity is used for winter pastures and settlements. Where other nomadic sites have electricity, it is still powered. Anyway, the tent movie still managed to survive for seven or eight years before it was completely gone. Later, everyone had mobile phones. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Do you think the current life in the pastoral areas is different from that in the city? Is the gap still big? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There is basically no difference. There is actually no difference after having a mobile phone. There is no lag in the flow of information between cities and pastoral areas. When you get such important information, it will pop up on our mobile phones immediately, but the focus is different. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A lot of things happened in the lives of the herdsmen. Big change? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, especially the impact on the younger generation is a complete transformation. Our parents have always been in a nomadic sequence. When they got older and were succeeded by our generation, their lifestyles changed like a fault. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nearby farmers will come to the pastoral areas to build houses and do some temporary work during their spare time. Without exception, they will envy us. Because they saw that all the men, young and old, looked very leisurely. The older ones drank, rode horses, walked around, drove sheep back and forth all day long; the younger ones either played or played billiards every day. Watch movies and fall in love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Is it still possible for teenagers to go herding now? No, they all went to study, and the perceptions of all the herdsmen changed. I used to not think that studying was the only way out, or the best prerequisite for the future of life, but now I do so. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;But you didn&#39;t take that road either. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Many of our group have not left, so our generation is the last nomad, and there will not be many in the next generation. Individuals will become truly nomadic, and nomadism is shrinking. This shrinkage is not only determined by ourselves, but also due to the adjustment of ecological policies. Qinghai is an important protected area. Everything is based on protecting the ecology and providing a good cycle, so grazing is not encouraged. There are many restrictions. For example, you cannot raise too many cattle and sheep. It depends on the carrying capacity of the pasture. If you have a thousand acres of pasture, you can only raise two to three hundred sheep. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yYMPeuFO6Ju7Wkz3NVTlS0taekLSKwGzQf6SdUMh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 683&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yYMPeuFO6Ju7Wkz3NVTlS0taekLSKwGzQf6SdUMh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256519&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 >;Both roughness and delicacy are the truth on the grassland&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Looking back now , do you think not going to school is a good choice? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I don’t think my daughter can persist on this road for so long. That is unrealistic. It&#39;s an individual case and requires a little bit of talent. Sometimes I still can’t imagine it—how could I become a writer inexplicably? If I weren&#39;t a writer, I would definitely be in business or doing something else. I think it&#39;s boring to stay in the same environment all the time. I always want to change my way of life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You now go to the county studio every day , the range of activity seems to be smaller. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Wouldn’t my own spiritual space be larger? I also often go to the pastoral area, which is very close. I usually just go for a walk and do nothing. Sometimes I go to see friends to have fun or help relatives. There are also houses over there, and sheep and cowsheds are ready-made. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Similar to &quot;Invite a Cow to Eat&quot; Is the story something you heard, or is it based on something that happened in your bullpen? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;It is a fictional story conceived from a very small point. There is a big pot at the door of our house, filled with various vegetable leaves and leftover rice. Every night when the yaks return to their pen, one or two will come to eat. The two of them occupied that place. When other cows came, they would attack with their horns. After a few times, the others stopped coming. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Electricity was already available at that time. The wires connected from the old house to the new house were too long, and a pole was erected in the middle. One day, the two of them stopped eating, and they were The lingering, vibrating sound burst out of the chest like a vent, breaking the pole. I was so angry that the power pole fell down. Although no one was hurt, it caused me a lot of losses. The wires were torn off on both sides and all the insurance was burned out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When they are making trouble, they consciously know not to harm their owners, so they do not knock on the door or break in. Do you know what annoyed us most before? In summer and autumn, when it is almost dawn, at four or five o&#39;clock in the morning, the cows will eat slowly until they come to the tent. Because people move around and pour some water, there is salt in that area. You can&#39;t even drive them away. You can only take two or three steps outside. After a while, they come back and eat the tent&#39;s canvas edges, chewing them until you can sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bbhbALOhJpzgz4f89UXuCgxQvoW2yviZp3xM87IA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height= &quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bbhbALOhJpzgz4f89UXuCgxQvoW2yviZp3xM87IA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256517&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Will herdsmen become more patient as a result? Because you need to know how to adapt to this kind of interaction with animals. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;No, they are all bad-tempered. The animals have not changed anything, but have only worsened. There are many who abuse cattle and sheep. Yes, the past two years have been slightly better. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;That kind of simple and crude language environment, you Do you think it’s good or bad for you to write novels? Do you think I might need to be more delicate? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Don’t my novels just look simple and crude? Of course, of course, I am trying hard to make my text have a delicate element in the roughness. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When did the change begin? It was because of others Evaluation? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sonam Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I realized it myself. When you reach a certain level, you will realize this. It&#39;s impossible to write two or three books and still be like this and still talk about it and think it&#39;s self-righteous. After reading too much and writing too much, &quot;Looking for Signals&quot; is the product of this awareness. You can see that the novella &quot;Portraits of Saints and Ivory Mahjong&quot; is different from &quot;In the Wasteland&quot;. I wrote it much more delicately. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The first article in the new book &quot;Professor of Philosophy&quot; It is about a professor whose stepmother marries into the protagonist&#39;s family. I think the description of the psychology of the 18-year-old boy is quite detailed. How did you come up with that story? Does it have something to do with your experience when you were young, or was there a foreign professor like this in the local area? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;After thinking for a long time&lt; /span>;) I remember, it’s not the professor, it’s the Elvis Presley stereo! I wanted to buy a speaker at that time, and I was choosing it over and over again. Finally, I settled on a model made of Elvis Presley walnut wood, and I suddenly thought, if this speaker had a story, what would it be? In fact, that was just an introduction, and later in the novel the sound was completely forgotten. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Now that I have a delicate awareness, I start writing Will it feel very different from before? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;After having this awareness, I will be a little alert and a little anxious. But if I pursue one aspect too much, I will lose the other aspect. Writing still requires a balance. I can&#39;t throw too much here and too much there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You still cherish the benefits brought by your identity as a herdsman extensive. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Suonan Cairang: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;That style is a reality on the grassland. Its authenticity is particularly important, but it does not mean that there is no delicacy in the authenticity on the grassland. There is delicacy, but I have not fully learned it yet, so I will continue to learn, and when learning, I must balance the relationship between the two sides. . &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我国新增4处世界灌溉工程遗产]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259983]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Anhui Qimenyan Irrigation System, Jiangsu Hongze Ancient Irrigation District, Shanxi Huoquan Irrigation Project, Hubei Chong The Baini Ancient Weir in Yang County was successfully selected into the 2023 (tenth batch) World Irrigation Engineering Heritage List on the 4th. So far, my country&#39;s world irrigation engineering heritage has reached 34. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter learned from the Ministry of Water Resources that the tenth batch of the World Irrigation Engineering Heritage List was announced at the 74th Executive Council of the International Commission on Irrigation and Drainage held in Visakhapatnam, India. Chen Mingzhong, chairman of China&#39;s National Irrigation and Drainage Commission and director of the Department of Rural Water Resources and Hydropower of the Ministry of Water Resources, said that my country&#39;s world irrigation engineering heritage covers almost all types of irrigation projects. It is the most abundant type of irrigation engineering heritage, the most widely distributed, and the most outstanding irrigation benefits. nation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Qimenyan Irrigation System is located in Shucheng County, Anhui Province. It was first established in the Western Han Dynasty. It uses the form of wetlands to &quot;form canals and ponds for storage&quot; and has played an important role for more than two thousand years. It plays an important role in irrigation, flood control and drought prevention. It currently irrigates 200,000 acres of farmland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Hongze Ancient Irrigation Area is located in Hongze District, Huai&#39;an City, Jiangsu Province. It is a water storage irrigation area and consists of water storage, water intake, water transportation and drainage projects. Since the Eastern Han Dynasty, ancient people have diverted water for irrigation and farming. Water conservancy facilities have been built in the past dynasties, and the irrigation area continues to this day. Currently, the irrigation area controlled by the irrigation district is 481,300 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Huoquan Irrigation Project is located in Hongdong County, Shanxi Province. It has been clearly recorded since the Zhenguan period of the Tang Dynasty, and it still plays a role in irrigation, water supply, ecology, tourism and other functions. At present, the total irrigation area of ​​the project is 101,000 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Baini Ancient Weir is located in Chongyang County, Hubei Province, and includes two ancient weirs, Shijian Weir and Yuanpi Weir. According to literature, the ancient weir was first built in the Five Dynasties and the Later Tang Dynasty. It still plays a role in irrigation, flood control, drought resistance, water supply and other functions, with an irrigated area of ​​about 35,000 acres. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The World Irrigation Engineering Heritage List was established in 2014 to sort out the development of irrigation civilization in the world, promote the protection of irrigation engineering heritage, summarize the wisdom of traditional irrigation engineering water control, and provide historical experience and inspiration for sustainable irrigation development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that along with my country’s four heritage sites, there are 15 projects from India, Indonesia, Iraq, Japan, Thailand, Turkey and other countries that are included in the tenth batch of World Irrigation Engineering Heritage List. Currently, there are 159 irrigation engineering heritage items in the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“海”中取粮]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259946]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/y4O4A33lBsLB3TRC9iI9iD6PgQUk9TK3l1GPwqIJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;593&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/y4O4A33lBsLB3TRC9iI9iD6Pg QUk9TK3l1GPwqIJ. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Researchers are building bird-proof nets for rice. During the grain-filling period of seawater rice, bird prevention is particularly important. Failure to take measures may result in no harvest&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Early morning As the sun just rose, Zhang Shuyin put on his sun hat, held a test record book in one hand, and a large-capacity water bag in the other, and got into the green rice waves, where he stayed all morning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Shuyin is a scientific researcher at the Qingdao Sea Rice Research and Development Center. He and six colleagues took root in the experimental field of about 100 acres at the National Southern Breeding Research and Breeding Base in Sanya. They stayed there for half a year. They were breeding in the experimental field. Nearly two thousand rice germplasm resources. For Zhang Shuyin and his colleagues, &quot;We touch and think about rice every day. Every variety in this field is like our child, and we cannot live without them for a day.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/hV72HFJ9duFfnIK5Or93SaqKjU5epYGrRWkGAosp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/hV72HFJ9duFfnIK5Or93SaqKjU5epYGrRWkGAosp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256505&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Researchers Gu Xiaozhen (left) and Yin Huide (right) are taking field records, including rice growth, plant height, number of tillers, etc.&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/picture)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What is &quot;sea rice&quot;? Zhang Shuyin explained that literally, &quot;sea rice&quot; is rice related to sea water. It does not refer to rice that can grow in seawater, but to salt-alkali-tolerant rice that can be grown on coastal beaches and inland saline-alkali lands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/CPxtRxs7AA4sFPt1oSQh8PRxf2sMpHtXFEDOE0Da.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;618&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/CPxtRxs7AA4sFPt1oSQh8PRxf2sMpHtXFEDOE0Da.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Scientific researcher Zhang Shuyin is replenishing water. The temperature in Sanya is high all year round, and scientific researchers have to carry large-capacity water bags every day &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Human beings have never stopped Challenge the dangerous natural environment. Planting &#39;sea rice&#39; on saline-alkali land is one of the ways.&quot; Zhang Shuyin introduced that the Qingdao Sea Rice Research and Development Center is headquartered in Qingdao. Since 2016, he and his colleagues have gone there every autumn. Sanya Nanfa will sow rice, and when the rice is mature and harvested in April or May of the following year, it will return to the headquarters with the high-quality salt-alkali tolerant rice varieties for further research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/JD0I9L3swqxxfMbqJNbRTh1jBivSrAYWsNMtRcAR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/JD0I9L3swqxxfMbqJNbRTh1jBivSrAYWsNMtRcAR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256506&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color ) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the Nanfan Base, scientific researchers inspected rice fields, selected rice plants to conduct hybrid experiments, and manually threshed rice materials... day after day. &quot;Hainan can carry out experimental research on rice all year round, which can speed up the breeding process and shorten scientific research time by half.&quot; Zhang Shuyin said that when they cultivate a new rice variety, they need to undergo an average of eight updates to obtain a stable variety. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/69zGhORE7gDfoStZOfXARtjxYxDd5xk88eaATqsB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/69zGhORE7gDfoStZOfXARtjxYxDd5xk88eaATqsB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yu Meng is walking in the muddy rice fields, one foot is deep and the other is shallow (&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;Zhang Mao/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Wan Jili, director of the Technology R&amp;D Department of Qingdao Sea Rice Research and Development Center, said, &quot;Currently, we have nearly 2,000 germplasm resources. The salt tolerance of the germplasm has also been continuously improved, from the initial 3‰. To the current 8‰.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DvLNQNmj2dlVcSV386QDR0ZE3wjAygAQa45iCEPb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DvLNQNmj2dlVcSV386QDR0ZE3wjAygAQa45iCEPb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256504&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Strong ears of hybrid rice. This shows that the hybridization test is successful and hybrids can be harvested from 2012 to 2022. The &quot;sea rice&quot; has developed from the scientific research and experimental stage to industrialization and large-scale promotion. As of the end of 2022, the planting area of ​​&quot;sea rice&quot; in my country has exceeded 1 million acres, and the varieties cover the four major types of typical saline-alkali lands across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Ry0MumwOXN7tZRQMN0ywoRbVvhXLh5sN5iThHsMu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Ry0MumwOXN7tZRQMN0ywoRbVvhXLh5sN5iThHsMu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Phoenix snails will cause harm almost throughout the entire growth period of rice&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;There are 1.5 billion acres of saline-alkali land in the country, of which 500 million acres are suitable for growing food, and the utilization potential is huge. In the near future, those saline-alkali lands that previously seemed “of little use” may become “regenerated fertile land.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/tHUXMLc8ErnYEhyMG4wPGyuPM7r3TUg8IJCxPVXn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/tHUXMLc8ErnYEhyMG4wPGyuPM7r3TUg8IJCxPVXn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256516&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Rice breeding expert Yang Hanshu (right) leads scientific researchers to check the growth of rice and guides the breeding work&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/picture)&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/zor9FwWokvX43ONAFEcO9f2dpWiQwqz7sDgFL66d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960 &quot; height=&quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/zor9FwWokvX43ONAFEcO9f2dpWiQwqz7sDgFL66d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style =&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Scientific researchers are investigating rice seed production materials. The isolation film on the tree is to prevent pollen from secretly pollinating and &quot;exchanging&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2aTkg7ZtQzIGh0ZMjjDMTTNUqi3h2pUzPZtdjVL4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;546&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2aTkg7ZtQzIGh0ZMjjDMTTNUqi3h2pUzPZtdjVL4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256512&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Scientific researcher Peng Nanxi Rice is being threshed. He uses a relatively primitive foot-operated thresher to facilitate cleaning and prevent seeds from being mixed &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Zhang Mao/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src= &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d8o2Pxve2K1vWdhNVZYHUm6gIJxmVkfozN8UTvng.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images .infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d8o2Pxve2K1vWdhNVZYHUm6gIJxmVkfozN8UTvng.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot; >;Researchers turn on the adjusted proportion of seawater to irrigate rice&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DpftIXzh8QpHPXtENJBmdHBWuSHmR1nKKj26ZudD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DpftIXzh8QpHPXtENJBmdHBWuSHmR1nKKj26ZudD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Harvest for scientific researchers of different rice seeds. Every bag of seeds may hide good varieties &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/U0Lp7Nf0B8wssfiiGjCmLOVOQBRd00FYdYFvjuHc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/01/U0Lp7Nf0B8wssfiiGjCmLOVOQBRd00FYdYFvjuHc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256513&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Yazhou, Sanya City, Hainan Province District National Salt-Alkali Tolerant Rice Technology Innovation Center Sea Rice Experimental Base&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Zhang Mao/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[广东恩平4.3级地震，广东省地震局：已发生余震5次]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259985]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 21:47:53&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the official measurement of the China Seismological Network, at 19:24 on November 4, in Enping City, Jiangmen City, Guangdong Province (22.08 degrees north latitude, 112.25 degrees east longitude) A magnitude 4.3 earthquake occurred with a focal depth of 8 kilometers. The epicenter was located near Dahuai Town, Enping City, Jiangmen City, Guangdong Province, 3 kilometers away from the People&#39;s Government of Dahuai Town, Enping City, Jiangmen City, 13 kilometers away from the urban area of ​​Enping City, Jiangmen City, 37 kilometers away from the urban area of ​​Yangjiang City, and 156 kilometers away from Guangzhou City. As of 20:00, a total of 5 aftershocks had occurred, with the largest aftershock measuring 1.3. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is understood that the earthquake was felt strongly in Enping City, Jiangmen City, and in Guangzhou, Shenzhen, Macau, Hong Kong, Dongguan, Foshan, Yangjiang, Zhanjiang, Maoming, Zhongshan, and Zhuhai. No reports of casualties or property damage have been received yet, and the mood of the local people is stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the earthquake, the Provincial Seismological Bureau launched a Level III emergency response and sent an earthquake field team (8 people) with the Guangzhou Earthquake Monitoring Center Station to Enping City to understand the earthquake situation and carry out intensive observations. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This earthquake is about 1 km away from the Cangcheng-Hailing Fault. Within 100 kilometers of the epicenter, there has been one earthquake of magnitude 5 or above. The largest earthquake occurred in Yangjiang, Guangdong on July 26, 1969. A magnitude 6.4 earthquake (63 kilometers away from the epicenter). Since 1970, the largest earthquake was the 4.0-magnitude earthquake in Enping City, Jiangmen City, Guangdong Province on September 18, 1989 (7 kilometers away from the epicenter). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the earthquake, the Provincial Seismological Bureau immediately launched a joint consultation with the China Seismological Network Center via video link. Based on the analysis of regional structure, historical seismic activity, and earthquake sequence types, it is believed that the original earthquake area of ​​this earthquake is unlikely to have a larger earthquake in recent days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 22:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[保障房规划与城中村改造结合，楼市祭出供给侧改革“组合拳”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259973]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The relationship positioning and development model of affordable housing and commercial housing have also been further clarified. Visual China/Picture &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/31c0abb395.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/31c0abb395.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257008&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The relationship positioning and development model of affordable housing and commercial housing have also been further clarified. Visual China/Photo&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On August 25, 2023, the State Council executive meeting reviewed and approved the &quot;Guiding Opinions on the Planning and Construction of Affordable Housing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A real estate expert involved in system design confirmed to Southern Weekend reporters that the &quot;Guidance on Planning and Construction of Affordable Housing&quot; (Guofa [2023] No. 14) (hereinafter referred to as No. 14) was It was distributed to various cities at the end of August, mainly targeting megacities with a net inflow of population and cities with a permanent population of more than 3 million in built-up areas, a total of 35 cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Document No. 14 clarifies two major goals. The first is to increase the construction and supply of affordable housing, &quot;allowing working-income groups to gradually realize home ownership&quot;; the second is to promote the establishment of a new model of transformation and development of the real estate industry, return commercial housing to commodity attributes, meet the demand for improved housing, and promote stability. Land prices, stabilizing housing prices, and stabilizing expectations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only is affordable housing highly valued, its relationship positioning and development model with commercial housing have also been further clarified. Some people believe that this is a &quot;new round of housing reform&quot; similar to the Singapore model. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“Reform is gradual and forced”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to the above-mentioned experts, a major focus of Document No. 14 is to launch allotment-type affordable housing. China has previously established a housing security system that integrates public rental housing, affordable rental housing, and shared property housing. The new allotment-type affordable housing will be connected with it to form an affordable housing system parallel to commercial housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia, chief researcher of the Housing Policy Research Center of the Guangdong Provincial Institute of Urban Planning, told Southern Weekend reporters that currently affordable housing accounts for 20%-30% of the existing housing stock, mainly for people with urban household registration, such as minimum living allowance and low-income families. Income groups, coverage is limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the changes in the population structure and the increase in housing prices, new citizens, young people and other groups are facing severe housing difficulties, and the contradiction between the scope of housing security and actual needs has become increasingly prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“There are 300-400 million new citizens and migrant population in the country, and most of them do not have houses. The anxiety about owning property rights houses has risen to the level of class promotion.” Li Yujia once wrote an article. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, during the real estate boom period, commercial housing and land prices soared, and local governments were not very enthusiastic about investing in the construction of affordable housing. There is a big gap between affordable housing and commercial housing in terms of location, quality, and public services, making it difficult to truly meet needs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If we do not vigorously build affordable housing, we must tolerate the existence of urban villages, factory dormitories and other informal housing that are free from urban public services.” Li Yujia believes that this has led to the The housing pattern shows a &quot;dual split&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, commercial housing for middle and high incomes and informal housing for low and middle incomes dominate, with the middle form weak, and there is a ladder fault in housing consumption. In the &quot;first half&quot; of the real estate market, where urbanization is advancing rapidly, house prices are not high, and price increases are expected to be strong, this problem is not yet obvious. As real estate enters a downward period, the problem becomes more prominent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since the end of 2021, measures to rescue the real estate market have continued. Various localities have successively relaxed loan restrictions and purchase restrictions, and introduced various policies to stimulate real estate consumption, but they have not had the same immediate effect as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Reform is gradual and forced. The time has come. Otherwise, real estate may face the risk of &#39;stalling&#39;.&quot; Li Yujia said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The &quot;combination punch&quot; of supply-side reform&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The focus of Document No. 14 is the supply-side reform of real estate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts who participated in the design of the No. 14 system said that the important problem caused by the past real estate development model was the mismatch between supply and demand. The leading idea of ​​​​the new round of housing reform no longer starts from the demand side, but adjusts the supply. Structure, planning and construction of affordable housing, that is, allotment-type affordable housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meaning is that it is built and sold by state-owned enterprises and supplied at cost price. The owner has complete property rights, but it can only be transferred in a closed manner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some houses are for new construction, and the land is allocated and supplied. The construction entities are local state-owned enterprises and urban investment companies, and private enterprises are also encouraged to participate in agency construction. Funds come from special bonds, bank loans, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts analyzed that selling at cost will allow the investment in such affordable housing to be recovered and avoid increasing hidden debts. This also requires that this type of affordable housing must be able to be sold so that it can be built to order and provide effective supply. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Revitalizing stock is also an important means of raising funds. Document No. 14 clarifies that in cities with a large inventory of commercial housing, existing commercial housing can be appropriately renovated or purchased to be used as affordable housing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Document No. 14 also proposed that there is conditional support for the use of idle and inefficient industrial, commercial, office and other non-residential land to build affordable housing. If the land use is changed, the land price will not be paid back, and the original allocated land will continue to be retained. transfer method. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts believe that revitalizing the stock is more important. Because new land is limited in big cities, allocable land is concentrated in the periphery of the city, making it difficult to meet the needs of job-housing balance. And under the downward pressure on housing prices, these areas will be more obviously affected, and the affordable housing constructed may not be popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, real estate has entered the era of stock. Li Yujia introduced that it will take more than five years to digest the general inventory in many peripheral areas of cities. According to a survey by the Ministry of Land and Resources, 40% of the country’s existing land is idle or inefficiently used. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the plan of Document No. 14, this type of affordable housing is mainly aimed at working-income groups who have housing difficulties and low income, as well as groups such as imported talents needed by the city, and people who have been protected by the urban village transformation previously implemented The degree of overlap is high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In July 2023, the State Council executive meeting reviewed and approved the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Actively and Steadily Promoting the Transformation of Urban Villages in Mega-Cities&quot;. On October 12, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development disclosed that the urban village reconstruction information system has currently included 162 urban village reconstruction projects in the database, and the urban village reconstruction in super megacities is being implemented in three categories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yujia introduced that the renovation of urban villages is mainly aimed at affordable rental housing. It raises housing resources through demolition, reconstruction and inventory improvement. It is mainly to provide rental options for new citizens, young people, etc., and it is a rent-to-rent guarantee. house. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The combination of the allotment-type affordable housing planning in Document No. 14 and the transformation of urban villages has formed a &quot;combination&quot; of real estate supply-side reforms. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The basic logic is that through government-led affordable housing, people with housing difficulties can enjoy urban public services and become citizens. Build &#39;rent before buy&#39;, &#39;small before big&#39;,&#39; &quot;Get on the bus first and then improve it,&quot; the housing asset ownership ladder will eventually become a property owner in the city.&quot; Li Yujia wrote in an article. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Challenges&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;However, whether the allotment-type affordable housing planned in Document No. 14 can achieve the expected results also faces challenges. One of the keys is closed circulation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 1994, China promoted affordable housing and sold it to low- and middle-income groups at a price lower than commercial housing. However, because there were no closed circulation restrictions, many houses ended up being traded in the second-hand market, which not only created space for rent-seeking, but also gradually lost their protective role. Construction was no longer available in 2003. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to &quot;Xinhua News Agency&quot;, at the conference call on planning and construction of affordable housing work held on September 4, 2023, Vice Premier He Lifeng emphasized that affordable housing must implement strict closed management. Not allowed to be listed for trading. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts involved in system design said that this means that this type of affordable housing will have restrictions on property rights and stipulate a closed period of a certain number of years. During the period, it cannot be transferred and can only be repurchased by the government. After the closed period, it can only be transferred internally among groups that meet the guarantee conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another key issue is whether the existing land can be revitalized and high-quality land parcels can be truly produced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned experts said that during the preparation process of affordable rental housing, attempts were made to revitalize existing land, but the results were not good. The reason is that the adjustment of land planning is restricted by the overall planning of the area, and whether the public facilities can be constructed after it is converted into residential buildings is also a big test. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Moreover, land is an important asset in the eyes of all economic entities. Some enterprises and institutions that occupy high-quality land are more inclined to provide housing benefits to insiders. Can they use the land to build affordable housing and provide housing to the whole world? Social cost price placement is also an issue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Achieving home ownership through affordable housing will be helpful to the future development of the commercial housing market.” The above-mentioned experts believe that if the placement-type affordable housing planned in Document No. 14 can achieve the expected results, It will meet the housing purchase needs of new citizens, young people and other groups, and further solve the dilemma of demand gap and high inventory pressure in the real estate market. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[逃不掉的，侯孝贤说]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259942]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/01/oIlWQzZZTDpZ7S7fGr5ibXWqXIxgFpINyhNeGd65.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/oIlWQzZZTDpZ7S7fGr5ibXWqXI xgFpINyhNeGd65. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256541&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the &quot;New Wave of French Films&quot; produced two big figures, Godard and Truffaut, Taiwan&#39;s new films also have two heroes, one of whom is rooted in the soil. Hou Hsiao-hsien, and the other is Edward Yang, a programmer who returned from the United States. With a Western perspective, Edward Yang is good at capturing the urban feel, and his films are more genre-based. The urban feel of Taiwan at that time was a middle ground between rural and urban areas, and the unique flavor was very iconic in his shots. To this day, many aspects of society can still be seen in their movies. Speaking more broadly, if Edward Yang had not passed away prematurely, &quot;Taiwan&#39;s New Cinema&quot; would have had a different pattern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taiwan&#39;s new film begins with the 1982 platter film &quot;The Story of Time&quot;, which was screened across Taiwan. Among the co-directors was Edward Yang, who studied and worked in the United States and later returned to Taiwan to make movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Hou Hsiao-hsien, who had already made three romance films that were very successful at the box office, joined the following year. He and two other directors made another platter movie &quot;My Son&#39;s Big Doll&quot; - —At this time, Hou Hsiao-hsien obviously hadn’t found himself yet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a filmmaker &quot;sees himself&quot;, to be more specific, it means that his attitude towards things and people can be reflected in the film, and he cannot deceive people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s style first appeared in &quot;The Man From Fengkuei&quot; in 1983. A very modern emotional state, akin to melancholy and alienation, is evident when viewed from a distance. The lives of several confused young people are observed from a distance with fixed camera positions and long lenses. The camera suddenly gained an attitude, a bit pushing away the audience and asking everyone to calm down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Previous Taiwanese movies were not like this. In the early 1970s, Taiwan was dominated by martial arts films and Qiong Yao-style romance films; in the late 1970s, many pornographic or violent films appeared. Business was not business, and rurality was not rural; by the 1980s, a generation of young Taiwanese people were facing The pull between Chinese traditional spirit and Western modern culture sways with the wind in life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/OdDvG7jpCBunuQg2L77akjJfKs0toKpp5rKL2M2Y.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/OdDvG7jpCBunuQg2L77akjJfKs0toKpp5rKL2M2Y.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256536&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Hou Hsiao-Hsien Zeng said in an interview: &quot;A director can only make one movie. The method of attention can change, but the angle is the same... Edward Yang left Taiwan for the United States and came back after so many years. His memory compared with his current view. I grew up in the countryside in southern Taiwan. I read classical books. Natural growth and life are my vision...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The concept of modernity in Hou Hsiao-hsien is mixed and rich, oriental Form, Eastern thinking, and the core point of view connects the West. At that time, he and several directors of the same age were discussing this matter, which attracted a lot of praise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the best years of Taiwan&#39;s new films, the average annual film production could reach about 120. &quot;This film reform movement inspired by the new generation of film workers and film directors was short-lived in the 1980s. It has experienced ups and downs in a few years, and has reached a peak that is still unreachable for Taiwanese films, giving Taiwanese films a place in the history of world cinema.&quot; This is a summary of Taiwanese new films that I have read from a lot of information. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On January 24, 1987, the &quot;Taiwan Film Manifesto&quot; was released. At this time, the peak of new films had passed and everyone began to struggle. This declaration is divided into three parts: &quot;Our views on movies&quot;, &quot;Our concerns about the environment&quot;, and &quot;The changes we expect and our own determination&quot;. I went out of my way to see the worries and doubts of these young filmmakers back then, and they proposed: We believe that movies have many possibilities, and we must strive for space for the existence of &quot;another kind of movie&quot; besides commercial movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At this point, new films as a trend have quickly dissipated. Since then, everyone’s creations have had to follow the market and personal destiny. For example, many filmmakers do not focus on the reality of Taiwan and do not seek funds from the country ( &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The same is true for Hou Hsiao-hsien&lt;/span>;). The advantage of doing this is that it will not be affected by certain policies in Taiwan. The disadvantage is that it will distance you from reality and indulge in memories. Suspicion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Actually, Hou Hsiao-hsien is not my film inspiration. In 2015, I finally watched Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s movie &quot;The Assassin&quot; on the big screen in mainland China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wrote a paragraph after watching the movie:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;&quot;The Assassin Nie Yinniang&quot; does not tell how Nie Yinniang became an assassin, but how she did not become an assassin. First of all, the camera sets the atmosphere .When many directors take pictures of a group of talking people, Hou Hsiao-hsien pays attention to the people standing in the corner. He is behind the camera and does not lead us to see anything. Instead, he follows the movement of the camera to feel what is hidden inside. , there is always a pair of eyes lingering near the speaker.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, news came out that the director was suffering from Alzheimer&#39;s disease, and his family confirmed that he had fully returned to family life and was recuperating. In fact, there have been rumors in the circle about Director Hou suffering from dementia for several years. I think it&#39;s boring to say that a director like him has &quot;retired&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Acheng wrote about a scene in an article. He said that there was originally a braid-cutting scene in &quot;A Dream of Life&quot;, which required more than a hundred braids to be cut off at once. In one shot, it could only be filmed. once. Everyone was very nervous during the filming. As a result, the camera of a female reporter flashed as soon as the braid was cut. Everyone immediately looked at the little girl. No one dared to speak. The little girl was so frightened that she cried. Hou Hsiao-hsien said nothing. &quot;Anyway, the shot was in vain, so there&#39;s no way we can shoot it again.&quot; This quote comes from cinematographer Yao Hongyi, who has worked with Director Hou for many years. In fact, it quite reflects Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s attitude towards movies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, there have been news from time to time about Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s new film &quot;Searching for the River God&quot;, but I think it may not be seen. If you can’t see it, it doesn’t matter. He likes to say to young people who make movies: &quot;You can&#39;t escape what kind of person you are when you make whatever you want!&quot; In one of his movies, the young man, regardless of what kind of person he is, shot the movie under prohibited circumstances. A group of young people rode motorcycles and passed by the Chiang Kai-shek Memorial Hall, leaving him far behind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SbJLfSLKF8mdame1OTbhxi33amRDigs5TW8L3lWS.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/SbJLfSLKF8mdame1OTbhxi33amRDigs5TW8L3lWS.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256540&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many years In the future, when I revisit these vivid and somewhat joyful movie scenes, I will feel a kind of gratitude that is difficult for others to understand. There are already so many works by Director Hou that can be watched over and over again, isn’t that enough? It just so happens that this last film has a meaningful name - &quot;River God&quot; may refer to himself. Therefore, some people speculate that this movie may be done by the descendants he has trained for many years... This is because it is too unclear what kind of person Hou Hsiao-hsien is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Starting from &quot;The Man from Fenggui&quot; in 1983, Hou Hsiao-hsien became more and more isolated on his path until &quot;The Assassin&quot; won the award at the Cannes Film Festival in 2015. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the movie road, such people are almost extinct. What does such a person look like? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even though he could blend in, he could keep up with the new era, he could incite young people...he didn&#39;t have any of it. I am reminded here of a quote by Truffaut: “If my films contradict the times in which I live, as I am sometimes accused of doing, it is perhaps because I sympathize with those who have to struggle to enter a world from which they are excluded. People of the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The confused young filmmakers will come to their senses sooner or later. The existence of Hou Hsiao-hsien means an &quot;ecology&quot;. There is at least a gap left in the world of movies, which is much more important than countless specific movies. The bigger the bubble, the more likely it will burst; no matter how weak the hope is, it is still hope. Maybe I&#39;m pessimistic, but sometimes optimism can be deceptive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if his friend Edward Yang was still alive, even if the new movies were still a hit, and even if art films finally opened up a market of their own, Hou Hsiao-hsien might have said: &quot;There is no one like him.&quot; He had already seen clearly that All true artists, in the end, will not be able to have anyone around them - at that time, they will become &quot;everyone&quot;, the so-called &quot;see themselves, see the world, and see all living beings&quot;. There is no escaping this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[盲人“看”世界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259957]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;According to relevant data from the China Blind Association, there are approximately 17.3 million blind people in our country. The world of the blind is not just the darkness in front of them, what they have to face is struggling to live in a void. Rather than caring and pity, they want to treat each other as equals and want others to think that blind people can do more than just be masseurs.</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[爆款剧都在开售后演唱会，剧粉福利还是“割韭菜”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259330]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After-sales concerts are becoming a standard feature of hit dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Following the successful after-sales concert of the popular summer drama &quot;Lotus House&quot;, another hit drama &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; also recently held a famous concert It is an after-sales concert for the &quot;First Season Finale Celebration Wilderness Tour Carnival Night&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, during the live broadcast of the carnival night, complaints such as &quot;embarrassment&quot; and &quot;refund&quot; were hotly searched one after another. This is not a problem with the actors, but with the party planning. , the game session was a mess. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;From the earlier TV series &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; and &quot;Shan He Ling&quot; to the recent &quot;Lotus Tower&quot; and &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot;, after-sales concerts have become more and more common. It has also become a new way for the platform to make money - how did the after-sales concerts become a trend? How profitable is it? What is the risk of rollover? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fiWgxYqvKNZUfpp1H9Ub1xSPXFZE9m7IZiAkH5RK.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;711&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/fiWgxYqvKNZUfpp1H9Ub1xSPXFZE9m7IZiAkH5RK.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256321&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills of &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;After-sales concerts are becoming more and more popular&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In an era where video websites are competing for hegemony, more and more attention is paid to the &quot;after-sales&quot; of drama series. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;A drama is not finished after it is aired. If we can provide drama fans with better after-sales service and experience, we can take out more from the fans&#39; pockets. More money can also increase the loyalty of drama fans to the platform, which will help increase the value of platform members. Therefore, after-sales services in the form of after-sales concerts, after-sales parties, after-sales sharing sessions, etc. are becoming more and more popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After-sales concerts are generally broadcast simultaneously online and offline. Offline tickets need to be purchased at a high price, or only by purchasing a platform membership card can you get the chance to draw tickets. Online live broadcasts require the purchase of live broadcast tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At the concert, the main creators gathered together to sing theme songs, restore famous scenes, and play interactive games, which formed the main content of the concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The trend of after-sales concerts was first sparked by the 2019 &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the series ended, the platform held two Chinese-style concerts in Nanjing, selling more than 16,000 tickets in six price ranges from 627 yuan to 1,980 yuan5 It was sold out within seconds. If you didn’t grab the ticket, you can still buy the platform’s online live broadcast tickets at prices ranging from 25 yuan to 50 yuan. &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; successfully tested the waters, allowing the industry to see the huge market space for after-sales concerts of popular dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2020, the fairy tale drama &quot;Liu Li&quot; became a dark horse in the summer season and gained many loyal fans. Since it is impossible to gather offline due to the epidemic, the platform has customized a cloud singing party for drama fans. Audiences can pay to watch it at prices ranging from 25 yuan (member price) to 50 yuan (non-member price). &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 2021 hit drama &quot;Shanhe Ling&quot; has replicated the amazing popularity of the &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; after-sales concert. There were two consecutive concerts in Suzhou, with the highest ticket price reaching 2,280 yuan (more expensive than a ticket for a first-line singer&#39;s concert). 600,000 people bought tickets online, and it took 14 seconds to sell out. Online live broadcast tickets also cost 68 yuan each. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Afterwards, with the official crackdown on chaos in the entertainment industry, the format of after-sales concerts for popular dramas stopped for a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This summer, an improved version of after-sales concerts will return. However, both &quot;Lotus Tower&quot; and &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; have significantly reduced the number of offline audiences, with only a few hundred people offline. This can make the approval of performances more efficient, and can also avoid some uncontrollable chaos in the entertainment industry, and avoid Public criticism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Offline tickets are exclusive to high-level members. Only those who have purchased a one-year membership will have the chance to win the lottery. Online viewers can choose to pay to purchase live broadcast viewing tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wsYEwtIPBpAFe4Kt5CzoPTYnxdgouKD5nps7OgrP.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/wsYEwtIPBpAFe4Kt5CzoPTYnxdgouKD5nps7OgrP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256320&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Stills from &quot;Lotus Tower&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The money from drama fans is really good&lt; /strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The after-sales concert is really a &quot;charity&quot; for the platform. Is it going to give back to the fans of the drama and provide benefits to the fans of the drama? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Obviously not that simple. If it is really a benefit, then should online viewing be free? It may be true that the platform gives back to drama fans, but it must be true that it makes another wave of money from drama fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; has verified how strong the purchasing power of drama fans is. A single offline ticket for &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot; was sold to 150,000 by scalpers; online VIP tickets are 30 yuan/ticket, non-VIP tickets are 50 yuan/ticket, and group tickets are 25 yuan/ticket. The total number of people in the live concert room exceeds 3.2 million. If Based on an average of 30 yuan per person, the total online revenue is nearly 100 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only are the offline tickets for &quot;Ling of Mountains and Rivers&quot; more expensive than those of &quot;Chen Qing Ling&quot;, but the price of online live broadcast tickets is as high as 68 yuan per piece, but at no point It did not affect the enthusiasm of fans of the drama. The Douban score of &quot;Shan He Ling Born Bosom Friend Concert&quot; is as high as 9.5 points, which shows that fans of the drama are very happy with their money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lotus Tower&quot; has changed to a new format. Even if the number of offline concert tickets is limited, they are basically not sold to the outside world. Buying members and drawing tickets can also It provides a great boost to the platform’s membership fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Drama fans need to purchase a 448 yuan/year Star Diamond membership (or membership level V7) to get 1 chance to draw tickets, and the number of times they purchase a Star Diamond membership Unrestricted. In order to be able to draw tickets, some fans of the drama bought a 10-year Star Diamond membership in one go. The membership fee also costs 4,480 yuan, which is more expensive than offline concert tickets, and they may not be able to win the lottery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; is also played in a similar way. Users who purchase the SVIP annual card of the platform can get 10 lottery opportunities, and the annual card price is 488 yuan. The platform limits the number of recharges for the SVIP annual card, which can only be recharged a maximum of 3 times. This avoids excessive consumption by fans and can also increase users’ enthusiasm for paying for prize draws. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In short, there are always ways to make money when the platform holds after-sales concerts. In the short term, you can directly collect money from fans of the drama. In the long term, after-sales concerts will become part of the platform’s membership services. If there is a second season like &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot;, it can also build momentum for the second season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Main actors who have starred in hit dramas will basically attend after-sales concerts. This helps extend the character&#39;s popularity to the actors. What&#39;s more, if other main creators are participating, a single leading actor may be accused of being &quot;insincere&quot; by fans of the drama, and may be &quot;out of touch&quot; or &quot;back-stepped&quot;. . Therefore, as long as most of the core creators agree to hold an after-sales concert, the remaining starring actors will only have the option of &quot;agree&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;It pays to fool drama fans&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Due to character filtering Mirror, drama fans are very tolerant of after-sales concerts. For example, if the actor is not a professional singer, they do not require him to sing well. Drama fans generally have a request, hoping to see traces of the characters in the interactions of the actors, so that the beautiful emotions in the drama can continue offline, and the regrets in the drama can be made up for offline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This puts forward high requirements for the restoration and interaction of after-sales concerts - this is why many after-sales concerts have actors wearing costumes from the drama Costumes are used in performances to give drama fans a stronger sense of immersion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lotus Tower&quot; is like this, with a high degree of restoration, full of sincerity, and has been well received. Although &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; received many bad reviews, the restoration of the Qingshui Town part of the play became a highlight of the concert. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Once the degree of restoration is poor and the interactivity is insufficient, the after-sales concert will instead make the audience laugh and let the audience &quot;get out of the trap&quot;. The previous Cloud Song Concert of &quot;Liu Li&quot; shocked drama fans because the male and female protagonists had almost no interaction on stage. The Douban score of &quot;Liu Li Finale Cloud Song Concert&quot; was as low as 2.4 points. As soon as the after-sales concert ended, the actor dropped a few points. Thousands of fans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This time the &quot;Sauvignon Blanc&quot; after-sales concert was criticized, it was not the actor&#39;s problem. Yang Zi&#39;s emotion for the character is still very touching. Tan Jianci was late because of a traffic jam. When he arrived, he sang, danced and adjusted the atmosphere. He was very dedicated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The problem mainly lies in the planning of the concert, such as asking the five main actors to pose strange poses in front of the flower arrangements, having Zhang Wanyi recite, and having Deng Wei Cooking, and having Yang Zi and Dai Luwa wearing high heels recreate the fighting scenes in the play... there was little restoration, and the interaction was awkward. It was originally intended to build momentum for the second season, but it actually caused some fans of the show to leave disappointed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After-sales concerts seem to be very profitable, but planning them well is not easy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;When the characters in the play are like each other, the offline actors may not be familiar with each other in reality. This requires efforts in planning and in the early stages. Coordinate and communicate more with the actors. For example, you can let the actors wear costumes to continue &quot;performing&quot; in the play, or you can use interesting game designs to allow the actors to have more interactions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is foreseeable that after-sales concerts of &quot;small scale offline, money to watch online&quot; will become a new normal for hit dramas in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Drama fans are willing to spend money to &quot;buy benefits&quot;. However, it is worth noting that if the platform is fooled and really treats drama fans as &quot;leeks&quot;, it will It will damage the credibility of the platform and also have a negative impact on the actors. When the platform wants to organize after-sales services, actors may not participate, members are unwilling to pay, and the platform has completely lost a way to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刘家昌自曝家丑为哪般？“先小人后君子”才能财产婚姻两全丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259969]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 26 and November 1, 2023, the famous musician Liu Jiachang published two long articles in succession Accusing his ex-wife Zhen Zhen attracted public attention. Liu&#39;s first long article elaborated on his version of the inside story of the &quot;mother and son fighting for the birth&quot; of his ex-wife and their son, while the second long article accused Zhen Zhen of being incompetent in raising her son and &quot;being a shameless mother.&quot; After Liu Jiachang published his first long article, Zhen Zhen also published a thousand-word article to counterattack, and the two of them were &quot;at odds with each other&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Weibo promotion&quot; caused by celebrities&#39; &quot;divorce essays&quot; once again occupied the hot search, and showed a similar plot to similar incidents in the past: one party took the lead in attacking, and looked eloquent. The words are righteous and well-founded; the other party fights back and refutes point by point, which seems to be righteous and sensible. For a time, public opinion was greatly divided. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jiachang’s main accusation against Zhen Zhen can be divided into two parts. The first is the issue of division of marital property. Liu Jiachang accused Zhenzhen of transferring Liu&#39;s assets to her name in various ways over the years, including but not limited to company equity, music copyrights and cash income; the second was the issue of his son&#39;s education and growth. Liu accused Zhen Zhen of controlling his son but failing to teach him how to spoil him. He made his son drop out of school again and again and became naughty. He got into troubles including drunkenness, racing, beating people, and soliciting prostitutes. Liu tried his best to encourage his son to make music, but failed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To sum up, Liu Jiachang claimed that he &quot;disclosed his family affairs&quot; because of his failed marriage and hurt feelings. He posted a long article accusing Zhenzhen mother and son just to vent his anger so as not to &quot;die unjustly&quot;. It seems inappropriate. It was all about fighting for property, because he also promised to donate his property to charity if he won the case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Regarding Liu’s first long article, Zhen Zhen also issued a counterattack, accusing Liu Jiachang of being addicted to gambling and suppressing his son. It was Liu Jiachang who stole his property, not the other way around; Liu Jiachang After the second long article was released, Zhen Zhen also criticized Liu Jiachang for slandering herself and her son, saying, &quot;It&#39;s really shameless.&quot; Their son Zhang Liheng (formerly known as Liu Ziqian) also supported his mother on social media. The &quot;mutual conflict&quot; between the two sides shows that each has his own words, but in order to determine which is right and which is wrong, we should return to the level of facts and legal principles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the property dispute between the two parties, there are many factual issues that are not difficult to prove or falsify. Written evidence can be used to determine whether these properties were earned by Liu Jiachang, or whether they were simply &quot;registered in the name of his wife Zhenzhen&quot; as joint property of the couple. For example, the audit report mentioned by Liu Jiachang, and the Income details, tax return records, property registration records from across the Taiwan Strait, the three places and the United States, as well as legal documents regarding music copyrights, company equity, real estate ownership, and the agreements between the two parties on the property, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhen Zhen accused Liu Jiachang of being &quot;addicted to gambling&quot;, and Liu Jiachang responded that &quot;he only used his own money for gambling.&quot; Liu Jiachang accused Zhen Zhen of &quot;not filming for forty years&quot; and that all the joint property was earned by herself. Zhen Zhen also personally told the media that every penny earned by Liu was given to Zhen Zhen and her family. It&#39;s not difficult to prove. Liu&#39;s accusation and response can be summarized as, &quot;It is normal for a husband to make money outside and leave it to his wife to take care of, but Zhen Zhen should not assume that she earned all the money.&quot; Whether this argument can be established is the key issue in determining whether the dispute is right or wrong. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second part of Liu Jiachang’s accusation, “Unvirtuous wife and unfilial son,” is even more difficult to verify because of its rich details and specific descriptions. Liu Wen accused Zhen Zhen of failing to teach her son well and his son was naughty and naughty. He was forced to drop out of school in Hong Kong, Shanghai, and the United States. He also got into troubles including drunkenness, beating people, speed driving, and soliciting prostitutes. Zhen Zhen even &quot;solicited prostitutes on behalf of her son.&quot; , these are specific and severe public accusations. Liu Jiachang should be responsible for providing evidence and ensuring the authenticity of the accusations, otherwise it will be suspected of slander. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Jiachang also revealed in the long article that his son was able to successfully enroll in school or escape punishment many times by relying on his connections with &quot;big men&quot; such as Run Run Shaw. If these incidents really happened, there must be others. There are too many informed third parties who can verify one by one, and it does not rule out that there are still many cases that can be verified. Liu Jiachang also mentioned that he tried his best to help his son make music but failed. This can also be supported by the record company and related people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From a legal perspective, it is meaningless for both parties to resort to personal attacks in moral trials. The focus should still be on the common property division issues in divorce proceedings. Both parties accuse each other of embezzling their own property. This should be left to professional lawyers who specialize in marriage law and company law to litigate the game. Everything should be carried out according to normal litigation procedures; Zhen Zhen said that the two parties had divorced in the United States in 1987, and Liu Jiachang said It is said that the divorce was filed in Hong Kong in 2015. The truth needs to be determined by courts in many places and even many countries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whose essay should the public believe? This still requires facts as the basis and law as the criterion in order to arrive at a fairer judgment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The divorce dispute between Liu Jiachang and Zhen Zhen has actually been going on for many years. The reason why old matters have resurfaced is because of the property division disputes arising from the divorce, as well as the huge interest entanglement mixed with the relationship between parent and child. Even an ordinary couple will have similar &quot;Rashomon&quot; problems during divorce disputes, let alone a celebrity couple who need to divide huge amounts of property and have huge conflicts of interest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from Liu Jiachang&#39;s accusations, he is quite resentful of &quot;having his feelings hurt by money&quot; and resentment of &quot;having money hurt because of his feelings.&quot; The impression between the lines is that he was originally He is an &quot;old-school face-saving person&quot; who follows the traditional Chinese marriage and family values ​​of &quot;men taking care of the outside and women taking care of the house&quot;, but he is exhausted physically and mentally by his wife&#39;s deliberate &quot;marriage competition&quot;. The reason why their marriage failed was that they fell into a vicious cycle of &quot;talking about feelings hurts money, talking about money hurts feelings&quot;. Unclear financial decisions and inadequate marriage and love decisions were also important factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparing many cases of &quot;peaceful breakup&quot; and &quot;mutual divorce&quot; between celebrity couples, it can be seen that the key to the success of &quot;peaceful breakup&quot; is that both parties have fully completed the notarization of pre-marital property and the division of post-marital property. Procedure, the method of &quot;first being a villain and then being a gentleman&quot; is equivalent to &quot;pursuing common feelings with common interests&quot; rather than &quot;seeking interests in the name of feelings&quot;. Before marriage, clarify the distribution of property and custody rights in the event of divorce. In the end, the respective interests of both parties are better protected, and they will not be reduced to online battles with short essays. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is said that the merger of two well-off houses in first-tier cities is like the merger of two companies, and there will be problems in the distribution of large amounts of property. It is best to divide the property before marriage to effectively avoid possible disputes. In comparison, celebrity marriages involve huge amounts of property. Before getting married, they should agree on how to divide property and child custody rights in the event of a breakup. Otherwise, they will inevitably fall into a &quot;complaint dispute&quot;. This time Liu Jiachang and Zhen Zhen were at odds with each other, which once again proved this point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>