<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[苹果“芯”，闭环未完成丨科创要闻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256950]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 11:57:16&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/19/EF18nz4G745NrZGbfXK5vE46XmfTmtmdvfpRt0BX.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1423&quot; height=&quot;692&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/EF18nz4G745NrZGbfXK5vE46 XmfTmtmdvfpRt0BX. png&quot; data-key=&quot;251156&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Communications &amp;amp; Chip&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://investor.qualcomm.com/news-events/press-releases/detail/1351/qualcomm-announces-agreement-with-apple-for-chip-supply&quot;>;&lt;strong>; Qualcomm and Apple reached a three-year chip supply agreement&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 11, Qualcomm announced that it had reached a new agreement with Apple. Qualcomm will provide Apple with chips in 2024, 2025 and 2026. The iPhone launched in 2017 supplies Snapdragon series 5G modem and radio frequency systems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 13, Apple released the iPhone 15 series, bringing a full range of smart islands, USB-C interfaces, and 48 million main cameras. Among them, iPhone 15 Pro and iPhone 15 Pro Max were upgraded to use the world’s first 3nm process Process chip, 6-core image processor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The iPhone&#39;s baseband chip has long been tied to Qualcomm. In 2010, Apple introduced Qualcomm&#39;s 3G/4G baseband products for the first time on the iPhone 4. Since 2011, Qualcomm has become the exclusive supplier of iPhone basebands and takes 5% of the sales price as a patent licensing fee. Around 2018, disputes broke out between the two parties during contract renewal negotiations for 5G baseband chips, and they initiated patent lawsuits against each other. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold; &quot;>;At the same time, Apple is also trying to create a closed loop of self-developed chips. In July 2019, it acquired most of Intel&#39;s mobile phone baseband chip business for US$1 billion. In March 2021, it invested in the construction of a new European semiconductor laboratory in Munich, with the first phase of investment. 1 billion euros. According to the six-year licensing agreement reached between Apple and Qualcomm in 2019, Apple will stop purchasing 5G baseband chips from Qualcomm after 2024. However, judging from this supply agreement, although Apple’s 3nm process chips are currently leading the commercial market, self-developed baseband chips are still on the way, and Qualcomm cannot be untied yet. (Tang Jiale)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;strong>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1973239/000119312523216983/d393891df1.htm&quot;>;ARM is included in the list Stark listing&lt;/a>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 14, ARM, a chip design company under SoftBank Group, was officially listed on Nasdaq with the stock code &quot;ARM&quot;. A total of 95.5 million American depositary shares were issued. After the IPO, Japan&#39;s SoftBank Group still retains about 90% of the company&#39;s shares. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the 2021-2023 fiscal year, ARM’s R&amp;D investment will be US$814 million, US$955 million, and US$1.133 billion; its revenue will be US$2.027 billion, US$2.703 billion, and US$2.679 billion respectively. ARM’s revenue mainly includes two parts: licensing and royalties/royalties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : ARM was founded in 1990. It was initially jointly invested by Acorn Computers, Apple Computer and VLSI Technology. Since then, it has experienced ups and downs in the capital market until it was acquired by SoftBank in 2016. At present, most electronic consumer products such as smartphones, computers, and smart wearable devices have chips based on the ARM architecture. According to ARM&#39;s own data, a total of 250 billion chips based on the ARM architecture have been shipped since its release. In fiscal year 2023, more than 30 billion chips based on the ARM architecture will be shipped. There are 15 million developers in the ARM ecosystem. The closing price of ARM on its first day of listing increased by 25% from the issue price, with a market value of US$65 billion. With the rise of artificial intelligence, a new era in which computing power is king has arrived, which is also a new opportunity for ARM. (Tong Jiale)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/open-networks-ecosystem-competition-successful-projects&quot;>;&lt;strong>;UK £88m for O&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;O&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;pen&amp;nbsp;RAN&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;scheme&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;September 14 , the British government announced 88 million pounds (US$109 million) in funding for 19 projects to demonstrate the Open Radio Access Network (Open&amp;nbsp; RAN) potential to achieve better mobile services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The projects come from the winners of the Open Networks Ecosystem (ONE) competition, the UK government’s £250 million ($312 million) 5G telecoms supply chain diversification strategy (&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/5g-supply-chain-diversification-strategy&quot;>;UK 5G Supply Chain Diversification Strategy&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;). The competition aims to showcase Open&amp;nbsp;RAN, a new way of building mobile networks that provides fast, reliable connections in busy places where wireless connections are needed. It allows technologies from different companies to work together, rather than using only one company&#39;s equipment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Open RAN refers to an open wireless access network. Currently, British telecom operator Vodafone has officially commercialized 5G Open RAN in Europe. The UK is using real money to promote the Open RAN research and development plan, aiming to break down the barriers between different companies and equipment. For users, at least signal coverage must be improved. (Tang Jiale)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/K4GEB1hyOslOY5qNLxVAKA&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Huawei takes the lead in completing all 5.5G functional tests&lt;/strong >;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 11, 2023, Huawei completed all functional test cases for 5G-A (also known as 5.5G, full name 5G-Advanced, the name officially determined by 3GPP for 5G evolution), covering Uplink and downlink ultra-wideband and broadband real-time interaction 5G-A key technologies. As an evolution and enhancement of 5G, 5G-A has achieved a 10-fold improvement in network capabilities such as connection speed and latency. At the same time, it has introduced new revolutionary technologies such as synaesthesia integration, passive Internet of Things, and endogenous intelligence. It is the key to building the future. Infrastructure for smart societies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The iteration of mobile communication technology from 5G to 6G will take time. During the transition period, 5G-A has high hopes. At the 2023MWC Shanghai World Mobile Communications Conference, Huawei Vice Chairman, Rotating Chairman, and CFO Meng Wanzhou said that in 2024, Huawei will launch a full set of 5.5G network equipment for commercial use to prepare for the commercial deployment of 5.5G. Every upgrade of communication technology will bring about new developments in the industrial ecology. (Zhao Jun)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Car&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en /press-room/20230911IPR04912/state-of-the-eu-ukraine-green-deal-economy-china-artificial-intelligence&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The EU will launch a countervailing investigation into Chinese electric vehicles&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a >;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 13, Ursula von der Leyen, President of the European Commission, stated in her “State of the Union Address” at the European Parliament that she would launch a campaign against China’s electric Anti-subsidy investigation of automobiles. Von der Leyen stressed the importance of a fair transition for farmers, households and industry and said Europe would maintain its competitive advantage &quot;at all costs&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : In 2021, 2022 and the first half of 2023, China&#39;s automobile export sales will be 2.01 million, 3.11 million and 2.14 million vehicles respectively, a year-on-year increase of 102%, 54% and 76% respectively, of which new energy vehicles account for the majority. In the first half of 2023, it will replace Japan as a major automobile exporter. The situation is very good, but the total amount is still very small, and we should not be overly optimistic. We must be adequately prepared and coping with the complexity and intensity of international competition. (Zhao Jun)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://global.honda/en/newsroom/news/2023/c230912eng.html?from=latest_area&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Ford, BMW and Honda&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Join to build charging network&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 12, Ford Motor Company, BMW Group and Honda Motor America announced the establishment of a new charging network. The company ChargeScape aims to build a platform that connects power companies, car manufacturers, and electric vehicle owners. Car owners can feed energy back to the grid through charging management, energy sharing services, etc., thus saving money and even earning profits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;ChargeScape will also provide utility companies and system operators with secure energy data to enable smart use of electric vehicle batteries. The three automakers will share equal shares in the new company, and other automakers are welcome to join. However, the new company still needs regulatory approval and is expected to begin operations in 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Electric vehicles are not only energy users, but also energy storage carriers. With the integration of cars and networks, car manufacturers have finally joined forces to take action. (Luo Xianxian)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h3>;&lt;strong>;Technical News&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h3>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/scitranslmed .abo6889&quot;>;&lt;strong>;New ideas for stabilizing microtubules in the treatment of chronic traumatic encephalopathy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 13, research was conducted by the Shanghai Institute of Organic Chemistry, Chinese Academy of Sciences and the University of Pennsylvania. Cooperating with institutions, a publication titled&lt;em>;A&amp;nbsp;microtubule&amp;nbsp;stabilizer&amp;nbsp;ameliorates&amp;nbsp;protein&amp;nbsp;pathogenesis&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;neurodegeneration&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;mouse&amp;nbsp;models&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;re in Science&amp;nbsp;translational&amp;nbsp;medicine petitive&amp;nbsp; A research paper on traumatic&amp;nbsp;brain&amp;nbsp;injury&lt;/em>;reports that repetitive traumatic brain injuries (repetitive&amp;nbsp;traumatic&amp;nbsp;brain&amp;nbsp;injuries,&amp;nbsp;rTBI) can induce physiological tau protein to cause Alzheimer&#39;s disease (AD)-related Pathological changes and further promote the pathological spread of tau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, researchers from the above-mentioned research team used a previously developed microtubule stabilizer CNDR-51657 to treat mice with repeated brain injuries. This microtubule stabilizer can penetrate into the brain and play a role. After a period of medication in mice, the neuronal projections in the optic nerve tract were restored, the deposition of punctate tau protein was reduced, and the activity of neurons in the visual cortex was restored. The mice&#39;s vision Functional recovery, behavioral experiments showed that the mice&#39;s cognitive function also improved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The above studies have proven that microtubule stabilizers may play an important role in regulating the abnormal aggregation and spread of tau protein, and may be beneficial to brain tissues such as chronic traumatic encephalopathy, Alzheimer&#39;s disease (AD), and frontotemporal lobe dementia (FTLD). It provides new therapeutic targets and ideas for neurodegenerative diseases in which pathological deposition of tau protein occurs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06473-y&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Screening for autism through single-cell brain organoids developmental defects&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 13, Nature published a paper by a research team from the Institute of Molecular Biotechnology (IMBA) of the Austrian Academy of Sciences (IMBA) and ETH Zurich&lt;em >;Single-cell&amp;nbsp;brain&amp;nbsp;organoid&amp;nbsp;screening&amp;nbsp;identifies&amp;nbsp;developmental&amp;nbsp;defects&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;autism&lt;/em>;&amp;nbsp;. This study developed a CRISPR-human organoid-single-cell RNA sequencing system, referred to as the CHOOSE system, which allows researchers to track the impact of each mutation at the single-cell level and map the developmental trajectory of each cell. This system uses validated gRNAs, inducible CRISPR-Cas9-based gene knockouts, and single-cell transcriptomics to perform loss-of-function screening of chimeric brain organoids, revealing 36 autism-related features of transcriptional regulation. Impact of risk gene mutations on different cell fates in brain organoids, with dorsal intermediate progenitors, ventral progenitors, and upper excitatory neurons being the most vulnerable cell types. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : Autism is known as one of the most complex diseases of the human brain. The above innovative methods provide new insights into autism research. By understanding the common molecular mechanisms of disease-causing genes, it also brings new insights into the clinical research of autism. hope. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-023-06473-y&quot;>;&lt;u>;&lt;/u>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;h5>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.qiluguquan.com/guquan-article-read-11391.html&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Qilu Equity Trading Center’s “Specialized, Specialized and New” Special Board Launched&lt;/ strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/h5>; &lt;p>;On September 13, the &quot;Specialized, Specialized, Special and New&quot; special board of the Shandong regional equity market, built by the Qilu Equity Exchange Center, was officially launched. The first batch of 226 companies registered in the special board. plate. According to the different development stages of enterprises, Qilu Equity Trading Center has set up an incubation layer, a standardization layer and a cultivation layer in the &quot;Specialized, Specialized, Special and New&quot; special board, and issued the rules for board entry; focusing on the services of special board enterprises, it has built a &quot;six major services&quot; The &quot;six-seven-eight&quot; comprehensive service system with the main content of &quot;carrier, seven exclusive service tools, and eight key service products&quot; strengthens the construction of the listing cultivation system. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;Comments : The regional equity market, also known as the &quot;four-board market&quot;, has not received much attention in the past. The high-profile launch of the &quot;Specialized, Specialized, Special and New&quot; special board by Qilu Equity Trading Center is an important measure to serve the financing of small and medium-sized enterprises. On September 1, 2023, the China Securities Regulatory Commission issued the &quot;Opinions on the High-Quality Construction of the Beijing Stock Exchange&quot;, proposing to strengthen multi-level capital market interconnection and carry out institutional docking between the New OTC Market and regional equity markets. If this &quot;specialized, special and innovative&quot; board can open up channels for enterprises to enter the multi-level capital market, it is really possible to open up the innovation test field of the &quot;four boards&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杨妞花不放过余华英：这样的不宽容彰显正气与血性丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256958]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 18, 2023, the Guiyang Intermediate Court sentenced Yu Huaying to death for child abduction and trafficking. The court found that: From 1993 to 1996, Yu Huaying, together with Gong Mouliang (deceased), traveled around Guizhou Province, Chongqing City and other places to find suitable children for abduction and trafficking. After they succeeded, the two took the abducted children to A total of 11 children were abducted and trafficked in Handan City, Hebei Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Huaying expressed her right to appeal in court, which also showed that she was neither satisfied with the verdict nor wanted to die. However, thinking about the 11 children who were deceived, kidnapped and trafficked by her, which parent would not hate her to the core? &amp;nbsp;When a child disappears, parents become furious, shed tears, and look for it locally or across the country. Normal life and work are disrupted, joy is lost, and families are broken up. In this process, some parents fall into self-blame and are unable to extricate themselves. Their lives have lost meaning, or they have given up on themselves, or died in depression. Some parents have given up hope at a certain point, but the wounds in their hearts that will never heal will often feel dull pain or even... In acute attacks, there are also parents who are unwilling to give up and will not stop. However, given the size of China, it is extremely difficult to find their children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the court hearing, there were family members of the victims and even those who were trafficked and are now adults but will always be &quot;children&quot; in the eyes of their parents. Yang Niuhua was one of them. In the process of bringing Yu Huaying to justice and giving him the punishment he deserved, Yang Niuhua played an irreplaceable role. It was her persistence and perseverance that allowed Yu Huaying to be finally arrested, and we were able to see what happened on September 18 That scene. In a word, Yang Niuhua is a well-deserved and admirable hero. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1990, Yang Niuhua was born in Zhijin County, Guizhou. She is the youngest daughter in the family. She has a happy family and many unforgettable childhood memories. It is these indelible memories that have become her heart The eternal light helped her find her way home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yu Huaying and her gang lived near Yang Niuhua&#39;s house. She was &quot;very good to herself and her sister. She would take them shopping and buy things.&quot; One day, when there were no adults at home, Yu Huaying defrauded and abducted 5-year-old Yang Niuhua for 2,500 yuan. Yang Niuhua will never forget: After being tricked into boarding the train, Yu Huaying immediately changed into a fierce face, not only punched and kicked her, but also poured boiling water from the thermos directly onto her head, in order to &quot;reduce management&quot; Cost” obedience training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2012, Yang Niuhua began a long journey to find her relatives. In April 2021, she posted information about searching for relatives on a short video platform, recalling every moment of getting along with her family: she fell into a puddle and almost drowned, and her sister cried beside her when she climbed up; she fell from a pig pen and suffered a bloody head. Flow, my sister went to find her mother crying behind her back. On May 3 of the same year, Yang Niuhua’s video aroused the concern of a girl named Yang in Zhijin County, Guizhou. She had heard from her elders since she was a child that a cousin was lost in 1995. After DNA comparison and confirmation, Yang Niuhua, who had been abducted for 26 years, finally embarked on her way home. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Unfortunately, after she was abducted, her father passed away in 1997 due to excessive drinking due to sadness, and her mother also passed away the next year due to being unable to bear the mental shock, leaving her sister as an orphan. Later, her sister told her that at night, her parents would take her to the train station to find someone, and they would lay bunks on the station floor at night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In an interview with the media, Yang Niuhua said: &quot;When I didn&#39;t find a home before, I never thought about looking for human traffickers. It was only after I found my home that there were so many changes in my home that I made up my mind. We are looking for human traffickers.&quot; In June 2022, Yang Niuhua provided clues to the Guizhou police. 24 days later, Yu Huaying was captured by the Nanming Branch of the Guiyang Municipal Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, the Nanming District Procuratorate of Guiyang City prosecuted Yu Huaying for the crime of &quot;child abduction and trafficking.&quot; According to Wang Wenguang, Yang Niuhua’s attorney, the prosecutor initially recommended a 14-year prison sentence. Yang Niuhua was not satisfied with this sentencing recommendation. She entrusted a lawyer to apply to transfer the case from the Nanming District Court of Guiyang City to the Intermediate Court of Guiyang City for trial. We have all seen the following parts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 11 child trafficking cases that Yu Huaying was accused of this time did not include the cases that had been tried and closed before, nor did they include her own son that she sold. It was the proceeds from this time that made her Tasted the sweetness and blood, I couldn&#39;t stop it from now on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Southern Weekend, during the trial, Yu Huaying apologized twice to the abducted family, hoping to gain their understanding and hope that the court would give him a lighter punishment. But Yang Niuhua found it difficult to accept Yu Huaying&#39;s apology. Such intolerance shows justice and bloodshed! There is a classic dialogue in &quot;The Analects of Confucius&quot;, which may be said: How about repaying evil with kindness? Confucius said: How to repay virtue? Repay vengeance with straightness and repay kindness with kindness. When a person suffers great harm, is deprived of rights, insulted, and loses his original life, he certainly has the right to demand the justice he deserves from the perpetrator. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The victim has the right to demand justice, and whether he or she can finally get justice are, of course, two different things. The former cannot automatically lead to the latter, but requires the victim himself to &quot;do merit.&quot; Yang Niuhua did not let go of the human traffickers. Her direct motive was to seek justice for herself and her parents. At the same time, she also sought justice for all the abducted children and their families, and also for us. This society has established a sense of integrity and integrity. Be subjective for yourself, objectively benefit others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Go further, punish evil and promote good. If you don’t punish evil, how can you promote good? It is the greatest mockery of good and justice for the bad guys to end up good. Only when there is more and more righteousness and bloodiness in this society, those with evil intentions will have scruples and think twice before doing evil things, and we will be able to enjoy greater freedom and security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[赛百味700亿卖身：降不住中国胃的轻食还会越吃越肥？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256932]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/18/c01164b14aab8acb3eb16ac74acd8b48.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/c01164b14aab8acb3eb16ac74acd8b48. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251105&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（IC photo&amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, the world-famous Fast food chain Subway has successfully &quot;sold itself out&quot;. According to its official website, it agreed to the acquisition proposal from private equity firm Roark Capital, with an acquisition price of approximately RMB 70 billion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the news came out, it immediately became a trending topic. Many foodies left messages lamenting that the fast food chain Big Mac, which had more stores than McDonald&#39;s and KFC at its peak, is no longer popular. Data shows that Subway has been in operating difficulties since 2014. As of November 2022, the number of Subway stores worldwide has decreased by nearly 8,000. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, Subway&#39;s stores are mainly concentrated in first- and second-tier cities. A sandwich sells for 30 yuan. It focuses on being &quot;healthier&quot; than ordinary fast food. It has been famous for providing freshly customized sandwiches, wraps, salads, etc. It is widely popular in weight loss and fitness circles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, as competition in the catering industry intensifies, under the name of health, waves of ketogenic diets, meal replacements, and sugar replacements come one after another, and various &quot;fat-reducing diets&quot; &quot;Meals&quot; are emerging one after another. Gradually, Subway&#39;s sandwiches have lost their originality and are no longer fashionable in the eyes of Chinese foodies who pursue healthy consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;An endless stream of weight loss meals&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In order to successfully lose weight, people take great pains in their diet, and this can always be captured by keen merchants, so over the years, diets in the name of weight loss have Wave after wave. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meal replacement is quite popular nowadays. Meal replacement, as the name suggests, can replace part or all of the main meals. It is a type of food that quickly, conveniently and quantitatively provides the human body with appropriate amounts of protein, fat, carbohydrates, fiber and other necessary nutrients. There are meal replacement powders and meal replacement milks. Shakes, meal replacement porridge, meal replacement snacks, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Meal replacement was initially mainly targeted at patients with certain diseases, astronauts, mountaineers and other people. Later, it quickly became popular among weight loss people, and the market scale expanded rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to Tmall statistics, sales of meal replacement light food products in 2021 increased by 290% year-on-year. The number of meal replacement consumers increased by 78% in three years, and the per capita annual consumption amount has exceeded 3,000 yuan. . Statistics from global market research company Euromonitor International show that in 2017, China&#39;s meal replacement market size was approximately 57.17 billion yuan, and is expected to reach 120 billion yuan in 2022. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Substitute sugar is similar to meal replacement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sugar substitutes have a sweetness similar to sucrose, but do not produce calories or have very low calories. This is most common in beverages and snacks, which are all labeled with &quot;zero sugar&quot; and &quot;zero calories&quot; to tell consumers that they can satisfy their cravings without gaining weight. For example, drinks represented by Yuanqi Forest under the banner of &quot;zero sugar&quot; adjust the taste by adding sugar substitutes &quot;erythritol&quot; and &quot;sucralose&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the stereotype of some dieters, sugar and carbohydrates are the main culprits of obesity, so in addition to avoiding sugar, some people also do everything possible to reduce or even eliminate carbohydrates. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ketogenic diet, which rejects all carbohydrates, has become popular. The traditional Chinese eating habits are too high in carbohydrates, and the ketogenic diet goes to the other extreme: only eating lean meats and vegetables, and not eating staple foods containing carbohydrates, thereby producing a large amount of ketone bodies and forcing the body to burn fat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The next step is the fat-reducing meal. Simply put, it is a meal that can reduce fat. It is generally less oil, less salt, and low in calories. Unlike the ketogenic diet, its nutrition is relatively balanced. Most diets for weight loss are not delicious. Fat-reduction meals now stand out on social platforms because they can be &quot;delicious&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, some people found hope in the burgers and fried chicken of the carbohydrate giant. On the one hand, burgers and chicken legs can not only provide excellent protein and necessary fat for the human body, but on the other hand, their calories are not as high as imagined. For example, some burgers only have 450 calories. The daily caloric intake of adult women in my country is about 1,800 kilocalories, and that of adult men is 2,250 kilocalories, so eating a hamburger for one meal is not a big problem. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with other weight-loss meals, fat-reducing meals are becoming a major source of traffic on social platforms. Other weight-loss meals can basically only be bought from merchants, which are unpalatable and expensive. However, fat-loss meals are suitable for DIY. There are a wide variety of menus to share on social platforms. All kinds of food are available. They are delicious and can help you lose weight. Why not? for? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/af1c4b7c289a7bcdee642927260594ac.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/af1c4b7c289a7bcdee642927260594ac.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251104&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;It may not work&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;But, can Internet celebrity weight loss meals really help you lose weight? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, many Internet celebrity weight loss meals are specious and just seek psychological comfort. For example, the various meal replacement snacks that have become popular in the past two years, such as oatmeal brittle, compressed biscuits, cereal yogurt, and instant corn flakes, are not low in sugar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although some sugar substitute biscuits replace sucrose with sugar substitute and wheat flour with coarse grain flour rich in dietary fiber, the main ingredient is still starch. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Another example is the popular salad set on the takeout platform, which is piled with vegetables, fruits and some meat, and looks very healthy. In fact, although fruits supplement vitamins, their sugar content is not low; avocados are not low in fat; a few grains of purple/brown rice just look like whole grains and are probably refined carbohydrates; more importantly, there are various sauces that enhance the taste. Ingredients, the calories are very likely to explode...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Salad sets on takeout platforms often do not provide accurate energy tables, but merchants with little nutrition knowledge prepare them at will, and consumers spend more money. Just buy a psychological comfort. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if it may not work, Internet celebrity weight loss meals may also bring health risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, although meal replacement is a way to supplement nutrients and reduce energy intake, the nutrients in meal replacement cannot replace a balanced diet, and studies have shown that long-term consumption of meal replacement shakes , will affect intestinal peristalsis, reduce metabolism, and in severe cases may cause endocrine disorders in the body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same goes for sugar substitute products. After eating sugar, the human body will automatically undergo a glucose metabolism reaction. If you eat sugar substitutes but do not take in the required calories, the normal glucose metabolism reaction will be weakened, resulting in a subsequent decrease in glucose tolerance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ketogenic diet carries greater risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the standards of the &quot;Dietary Guidelines for Chinese Residents&quot;, 55%-65% of adults&#39; daily energy intake should come from carbohydrates. A ketogenic diet that refuses carbohydrates will cause insufficient energy for the body, leading to side effects such as fatigue, gastrointestinal dysfunction, and irregular heartbeat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A study in &quot;The Lancet&quot; showed that there is a U-shaped relationship between carbohydrate intake and life expectancy. A low-carbohydrate diet will reduce life expectancy by up to 4 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The biggest bug with various fat-reducing meals is that we can eat them for a month to achieve the goal of reducing fat, but can we eat them for a lifetime? Once it fails, the next problem will be: rebound. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior nutritionist pointed out: &quot;A single food weight loss method actually deviates from a healthy dietary pattern. The result is that the more you reduce your basal metabolism, the lower your basal metabolism will be, and the rebound will be more severe.&quot; Long-term deficit habit The body will fully absorb them when exposed to carbohydrates and fats to help the body return to normal operating levels, and the weight will rebound quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Isn&#39;t this just &quot;losing your wife and losing your troops&quot;? The operation was as fierce as a tiger, but in the end it returned to the same way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/3710cf01919af6f3692376196c081165.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/3710cf01919af6f3692376196c081165.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251108&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;（IC photo &amp;nbsp;/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Shut up and open your legs&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;What is the truly effective way to lose weight? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is the clichéd six words, &quot;Shut up and open your legs.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Keeping your mouth shut does not mean not to eat, but it means to control your diet appropriately and ensure a balanced diet. The &quot;Reference Intake of Dietary Nutrients for Chinese Residents&quot; clearly states: The recommended dietary energy supply ratio for adults is 50%-65% carbohydrates, 20%-30% fat, and 10%-15% protein. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Humans are not machines. Only by consuming sufficient and balanced nutrients can normal metabolism be maintained. Of course, overeating is not advisable, but if you diet blindly, once the intake cannot cover the basal metabolism, it will have a negative effect on the body, causing muscle and bone loss. Therefore, any kind of weight loss meal must be based on health. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person’s fatness or thinness is not only related to the total daily caloric intake, but also related to the total daily caloric consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If there is a calorie surplus, the body will gain weight. If calorie consumption is greater than calorie intake, then the body will lose weight. To successfully lose weight, your total energy intake should be less than your total energy expenditure. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many internet celebrity weight loss meals focus on reducing intake, but their low energy intake has fallen below the bottom line of health. The healthy fat loss formula is: caloric consumption >; caloric intake >; calories required for basal metabolism. The body&#39;s caloric deficit is between 10% and 15% of total consumption. The best way to burn calories is to spread your legs and move. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So it’s better to just “keep your mouth shut and open your legs” if you follow all kinds of celebrity weight-loss meals on the Internet and the prices are quite low. Maintaining a normal and balanced diet while ensuring a certain amount of exercise may not make you lose weight immediately, but it will give you a well-proportioned figure and a healthy body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[如何评价历史人物？从“被泼脏水”的隋炀帝说起]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256914]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Over the years, there are probably very few &quot;tyrants&quot; in history who have not been demonstrated by researchers or history buffs He is &quot;actually a talented and strategic monarch&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Indeed, the images of many &quot;tyrants&quot; left in history books, especially their images in traditional literature, are often far from their historical prototypes. After a change of dynasty, if the new dynasty wants to prove its legitimacy, the history books will throw dirty water on it. The identity of the &quot;tyrant&quot; has been recognized, and folk literature and art like to use him to tell erotic and violent stories - after all, deep in human nature, there is such a hobby, but it is not appropriate to place this hobby on a good person, so the &quot;tyrant&quot; &quot;It&#39;s always good to make it very pornographic and violent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fate of popular emperors in literary and artistic works such as Shang Zhou and Sui Yang Emperor is probably always like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the question is, peel off the outer layer of skin, what is the inner layer exposed? Let’s take Emperor Yang of Sui Dynasty as an example. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty first came to the throne, he inherited a powerful empire that had not been seen for hundreds of years after the fall of the Han Dynasty, and it was also a huge powder keg. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First of all, long-term divisions have been unified in a very short period of time, and some people are dissatisfied with the current regime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, his father, Emperor Wen of the Sui Dynasty, had some important institutional reforms and policy practices, which were very beneficial from the national level, but felt uncomfortable at the social level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, the household registration management in the Sui Dynasty was particularly good. According to official population statistics, the population has increased from 29 million to 46 million in less than 30 years. These 17 million people are definitely not just the result of everyone trying their best to have children when the world is at peace, but the population that was originally hidden has all been plundered. From the perspective of the imperial court, the country had extremely abundant manpower and material resources at its disposal. However, if you look at the perspective of ordinary people at that time, these people did not have to pay taxes or serve in the military. Now all these burdens have been placed on them, and they are not necessarily happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If these people are all in disarray, there is nothing they can do even if they are dissatisfied. But Emperor Wen of the Sui Dynasty also made another major reform, which was to change the three-level local administration of state-prefecture-county to the second-level state-county administration, and abolish the county level. As a result, tens of thousands of people, from county chiefs to ordinary officials, were about to be laid off. From a national level, this is reducing staff and increasing efficiency. But with so many officials losing their vested interests, they will definitely be furious. If the Sui Dynasty returned all the savings to the people, then the people should be very happy to see these people lose their official positions. But the problem is that the Sui Dynasty concentrated all the profits in the court, and the people of the Sui Dynasty did not get any benefits from this reform that could have benefited them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above two reforms, together with other new policies, resulted in a great increase in the income of the Sui Dynasty and a decrease in expenditure. Therefore, many scholars have noticed that when it comes to ancient dynasties, it is said that In terms of &quot;national wealth&quot;, it is unmatched by the Sui Dynasty. But at the same time, this also means that as long as someone wants to rebel, there will immediately be tens of thousands of unemployed officials with administrative organizational skills, and tens of millions of dissatisfied people who can take advantage of them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Emperor Yang of the Sui Dynasty was completely unaware of the existence of this problem. He was from a good background, had a smooth life since childhood, and was really smart. He had no ability to empathize with the pain of ordinary people. 。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他只看见现在朝廷里资源那么多，所以想做大事，于是开挖大运河，三次征辽东，这都属于对社会承受力的极限测试。隋炀帝也不是没有感受到自己的皇位受到威胁，但不是来自这个巨大的火药桶，而是原来隋朝赖以成功的关陇集团。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;偏偏当皇帝之前，隋炀帝指挥平定南方的战争，又特别成功，他笼络南方士族的能力，远远超过了关陇集团老一辈的名将名臣。这就给了他一种错觉，我有新的势力可用，你们也没什么了不起。于是又加剧了统治集团的撕裂。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这样一来，顶层的被排挤的关陇权贵，中层的下岗官吏，基层的被繁重徭役、赋税压得喘不过气来的普通老百姓，从上到下怒气值都满了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;隋炀帝确实不是文学作品中的色情狂和虐待狂，但是，挑战面前，他显得完全不是一个合格的政治家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;顺境的时候太任性，我不要你觉得，我要我觉得，干不成的事情，撞墙了也不放弃。而真到逆境的时候，又缺乏韧性和意志力，意志力说崩就崩了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天下大乱，隋炀帝到了江都，其实已经不指望夺回北方了。但是他的军队都是北方人，就害怕不回去，于是都在商量着要造反。有个宫女听到了消息，就和萧皇后说了。萧皇后还是很精的，说你自己去说。结果一说，隋炀帝就大怒，这是你有资格说的吗？就把这个宫女杀了。后来军队要造反的消息越来越多，萧皇后就和宫里的人说，不用和陛下说了，何必再增加他的烦恼呢？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其实，就隋炀帝当时手下军队的战斗力来说，还是非常强悍的，但人生最后关头，隋炀帝已经放弃治疗了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;总结就是，作为一个政治人物，隋炀帝这个人：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一，没有能够调和复杂政治、社会矛盾；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二，没有打造一个忠于自己也有能力的核心团队；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三，形势开始不利的时候没有变道的意识；&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第四，形势非常不利的时候没有坚持的意志。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于他干了一些事，如修大运河，则不妨这么看：讨论中长时段的历史，一个人哪怕是皇帝，他的影响力，可能没有那么重要。财税、技术扩散、生产力、经济社会结构等等因素的研究，足以说明问题，不妨不涉及人物评价。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要做人物评价，看的就是短时段的历史。历史意义上的短时段，对于普通人来说就是一辈子。隋炀帝引爆的隋末社会大崩溃，那是几千万的人死亡和流离失所，这是实实在在的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所以，传统史书和文学作品，往往给人物涂抹太多油彩，这个问题确实存在。但若是觉得把传统记载翻过来才是真相，还是省省吧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人贩余华英获死刑，受害家庭：“几十年的辛酸，终于清楚了”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256948]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 10:16:43&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/f6b4e7615e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/f6b4e7615e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251151&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月18日，余华英以拐卖儿童罪被判处死刑。 （贵阳市中级人民法院/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年9月18日，贵阳市中级人民法院公开宣判被告人余华英拐卖儿童罪一案，对余华英以拐卖儿童罪判处死刑，剥夺政治权利终身，并处没收个人全部财产。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;媒体拍摄的视频中，杨妞花在法院门口把判决结果念给寻亲家长，希望他们都能看到希望。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杨妞花在5岁时被余华英拐卖，25年后方寻亲成功。 2022年，杨妞花向警方报案并提供线索，余华英拐卖儿童一案正式立案。 （详见相关报道《&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/253854?source=134&quot;>;人贩余华英被判死刑：拐卖11名儿童，还卖过亲儿子&lt;/a>;》）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;经贵阳中院审理查明：被告人余华英于1993年至1996年期间伙同龚某良（已故）为牟取非法利益，在贵州省、重庆市等地流窜，物色合适的孩童进行拐卖，得手后二人将被拐儿童带至河北省邯郸市，通过王某付、杨某兰介绍，寻找收买人进行买卖，以此获利，其间共拐卖儿童11名。贵阳中院认为，被告人余华英为牟取非法利益，多次拐卖儿童，其行为已构成拐卖儿童罪，犯罪情节特别严重，社会危害性极大，应予以严惩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;余华英当庭表示上诉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“希望她死，又不希望她死”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;尽管只是一审判决，旁听宣判的受害人家属蔡回英却觉得心口大石落地，她跟亲人在电话里说：“咱们这几十年的辛酸和累，咱们终于搞清楚了，终于明白了。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;蔡回英走出法院后，开始给家人打电话。第一个是被拐的当事人——弟弟蔡战胜。蔡战胜在遵义被拐时6岁，和哥哥一块走失。几个月后哥哥独自回来，不见弟弟。直至2022年底余华英案立案后，蔡战胜才通过DNA比对回家。三十年过去，蔡战胜对很多细节都已记不清了，但还记得高颧骨、长脸的余华英。蔡回英说，得知余华英被判处死刑，弟弟也很高兴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;蔡回英第二通电话打给父母。弟弟丢失后，父亲曾坚持出门寻亲二十余年，云南、四川、广西、广东、福建、河南、江西等地都去过。哪里有消息，父亲第一时间出去核实，一次次抱着希望出去，又一次次希望破灭。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;按理说，父亲应该非常痛恨余华英。但两个月前，父亲得知检方在一审中建议判余华英死刑时，“第一句话是我希望她（余华英）死，但是我又不希望她死”。蔡父希望余华英被判死刑，因为她给自己家庭带来无尽的伤害和痛苦；不希望她死，则是想要给她一些时间，把这些年拐卖的孩子都说出来，让更多父母找到孩子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;蔡回英回复父亲：“这是我们共同的想法，可是她能做到吗？”蔡回英曾旁听一审的庭审，当时余华英对许多作案情节表示“不清楚”“记不到了”。唯有谈及自己的儿子及女儿时，余华英才落泪哽咽。这让蔡回英颇为愤怒，不时攥紧拳头。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;余华英拐卖儿童11名，涉及8个家庭。此次法院宣判，有5个家庭的亲属前来旁听。一位母亲被拐两个儿子，另一位母亲则被拐一儿一女，还有一位母亲则是被拐一个儿子。蔡回英看到从遵义赶来的那位母亲在余华英被判死刑后，激动得站了起来，似乎想去打她。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中午吃饭的时候，蔡回英和几位母亲聊起各自的情况：5个家庭的孩子在杨妞花报案后，陆续找回。可是亲生家庭与养育家庭关系颇为复杂，有些被拐孩子难以应对，没能接受认亲，也鲜少回来团聚。 “但我们都感谢妞花，因为她报案，我们才找回亲人。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;亲情断裂的遗憾出现在多个受害家庭。在重庆大足，被余华英拐走儿子的柏体才全然不知道此次庭审宣判，他告诉南方周末记者，孩子自2020年春天认亲后，再没有来看过他，两人之间断了联系。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7486ba21cd.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1706&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/19/7486ba21cd.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251152&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月18日，贵阳中院门外聚集的寻亲家长。 （受访者供图/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;鼓励寻亲家长“不要放弃”&lt;/h2>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;9月18日的贵阳中院门外，依旧里三层外三层地围着前来寻亲的家长，和7月庭审时一样。每个人都在胸前举着一块寻亲信息板，上面以最显眼的红底黄字印刷着被拐孩子的信息。被拐的时候孩子都还年幼，印刷的照片是他们一两岁的模样，大都模糊不清。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;7月庭审时，南方周末记者曾见到前来寻子的安仕明，他举着寻亲信息板早早来到法院门口直播。这次宣判，他再次和部分寻亲家长早早赶来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;蔡回英8点前抵达时，看到这次寻亲的家长比一审时还多。她远远地站着，不敢走进人群中间，“我觉得我一站在那里，一听到他们诉说，自然而然地控制不住那种情绪”。对于还在寻亲的家长，蔡回英觉得自己能说的话苍白无力：“再有勇气一点，再继续一下。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;杨妞花敢于对寻亲家长发言。在庭审结束后的媒体直播中，她再次鼓励找孩子的父母不要放弃。她提到自己这一例子：首次采血寻亲是在2012年，近十年过去一直杳无音信。可是2021年，短短的一个多月里，她通过短视频平台奇迹般地找到自己的家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;找到家以后，杨妞花常住河北，余华英在重庆，拐卖案发生地在贵州，三地相距甚远，看起来找人贩子很难。但现在，余华英已受到法律制裁。 “真的永远不要放弃”，杨妞花说。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;每次开庭前后，杨妞花的行程都紧凑繁忙。一方面寻亲家庭希望借此机会扩散寻亲信息，找到她一块直播、录视频；另一方面媒体采访不断，杨妞花反复述说被拐的经历、成长的苦难。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;姐姐桑英看着杨妞花总是冲在在前头，有些心疼。姐妹俩其实都是受害者，杨妞花于1995年被拐后，父母伤心过度，分别于1997年、1998年离世。桑英失去了自己的家，被迫外出打工。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电诈受害者的银行卡困境:报案后要被冻结多久]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256940]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/2ea2e16682.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1365&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/2ea2e16682.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251128&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年9月10日，北京警方在宣传反电诈。图文无关。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被骗走三万余元的一周内，深圳市民黎筝不停地向警方、银行证明自己已经清醒，不会再给骗子转钱了——受骗报案当天，她名下的所有储蓄卡、信用卡即被警方采取保护性止付措施，不能使用，原因是防止她再次被骗。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓保护性止付，是指为保护受害者不再遭受损失，对其银行卡停止支付功能，只可转入，不能转出和取现。黎筝的银行卡开户行客服告知，对有可能再次受骗的银行账户，采取为期一个月的止付措施是全国一致的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可保护性止付让黎筝忽然间无法用银行卡买菜、坐车，甚至无法给孩子交学费，她觉得异常不便。她发现，不仅是她一个人在想办法解除保护性止付，全国各地都有受害者遇到了同样的问题，不少人还身负房贷，焦虑得不知如何是好。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;主动报案后被冻卡&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2023年9月7日，黎筝接到诈骗电话时，正在嘈杂的大街上，对方让她确认社交账号安全中心里的“百万保障保险”是不是免费的。黎筝赶着去办事，本不太想理会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;电话那头的人说只需要几分钟，按照指示确认即可。黎筝在路上听着对方的语音，有一搭没一搭地回话，按照对方要求下载一款“银行APP”，来回输入不同的业务编号、订单编号，尝试转款是否成功，从7元、8元的小额，一直到两万多元的大额转账。转角走进一处僻静的地方后，她忽然意识到被骗了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎筝当即挂断了骗子的电话，拨打110报警。此时她已经给骗子转账三万多元，不知能否追回。深圳市公安局福田分局福田派出所很快接警，打电话让她暂时在原地等待，将派警车过去接她。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;派出所民警将她带去问话、做笔录。黎筝说，当时民警仅是对嫌疑人的账户做了冻结，并未提及会对自己的银行卡进行保护性止付。警方还把报案详情上传到国家反诈APP，后续登录时也能看到相关信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当晚9点，黎筝居住地所属的南山分局招商派出所民警上门，询问她是否遭遇诈骗，向她宣传反诈知识。黎筝以为诈骗案的处理到此告一段落。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但次日她准备用手机支付时，才发现自己名下的两张储蓄卡、一张信用卡均不能使用了。咨询开户行后，她得知是由反诈警方操作的保护性止付，按规定冻结一个月，如果要解除可以咨询南山分局反诈中心。但黎筝发现该电话不易打通，又通过全国反诈热线96110投诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，黎筝分别接到福田派出所、深圳市公安局、福田分局的民警电话，得到答复都是“为了保护你不再受骗，需要冻结你的银行卡一个月”。黎筝对此并不认同，她正是意识到受骗主动报案的，也遭受了财产损失，“怎么可能再向骗子转账？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她认为止付措施给她造成了诸多不便，家庭的吃穿用度、公司的流水都要用到银行卡，现在一切都“动弹不得”。而信用卡仍要继续还款，有可能面临逾期风险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月11日，在黎筝的强烈要求下，民警陪同她将两张卡里的7000余元取出。尽管如此，她认为储蓄卡不能转账、信用卡不能使用，仍然难以维持日常生活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月12日，南方周末记者致电南山分局反诈中心查询，反诈中心工作人员表示黎筝名下的银行卡的确处于“保护性止付”状态，将48小时止付持续循环直至一个月，如何解除可以咨询南山分局。但此前，黎筝已经多次和南山分局招商派出所沟通，并不能解除止付。福田分局民警则告诉南方周末记者，黎筝遭遇的是普通的电信诈骗案，解除保护性止付事宜已跟南山分局沟通，协调处理，更多案件详情则不便透露。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎筝奔波于两个派出所的时候，发现她遇到的情况并非个案，现场有不少来申诉银行卡冻结问题的电诈受害者。在网络上，各个社交媒体也有受害者询问保护性止付该如何解除，所在地的ID地址包括江苏、湖北、浙江、福建、安徽等：“上个月21号止付到现在都还没解，有没有知道该怎么处理的”“我还有银行按揭受影响”……&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;初衷是防“执迷不悟”&lt;/h2>; &lt;p>;北京市盈科（深圳）律师事务所律师郭志浩长期关注解冻卡类案件，提供解冻卡方面的法律咨询。据他了解，保护性止付最初源于2020年的“断卡”行动。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据公开资料，2020年10月10日，国务院召开打击治理电信网络新型违法犯罪工作部际联席会，决定自该日起，在全国范围内开展“断卡”行动，目的主要是应对电信网络诈骗持续高发的一大根源——电话卡、银行卡的管理失控。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;郭志浩律师称，“断卡”行动开始后，银行卡因流入不明资金而被冻结的情况增加了，他一周就能接到上百起解冻卡的咨询，其中保护性止付的咨询也偶有出现，但总体比例较低。2020年至2022年，咨询解冻卡的100件案件里，仅有一两件是保护性止付；2023年以来，这类案件的咨询量增加，100件案子里有四五件。对于保护性止付，郭志浩建议当事人如果不急用银行卡的话，不必找律师代理，因为一个月后绝大多数也会自动解除，“折腾来折腾去也只是提前一两周”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;至于止付咨询数量增加的原因，郭志浩并未发现2023年有新增的公开文件，应该只是个别地区在执行方面的调整。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者发现，2023年6月以来，全国已有多地公安发布《关于开展反诈劝阻及保护性紧急止付的通告》，其中止付的时间及解除方式的表述不一：江西省宜春市公安局袁州分局在6月7日的公告中提到：“如果您已经向涉诈账户转账，分局将第一时间对您的账户进行保护性止付，48小时后可自行解除”；青海省西宁市公安局在8月的公告中提示：“如您名下银行账户出现只收不付的情形时，请您尽快前往就近公安机关说明情况，提请解除止付恢复银行卡正常使用”。郭志浩认为，各地止付的初衷都是一致的，防止受害者执迷不悟，再次向诈骗账号转账，但尚无明文规定执行尺度。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者在采访中联系上一位曾“执迷不悟”的受害者。27岁的广州在读博士生陈强7月曾深陷投资炒股诈骗群。那是一个精心设计的骗局，开户时对方可以视频真人验证，转账提供的是第三方对公账户，且该公司是存在且营业的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈强深信不疑，连续三日向该账户转账“投资”。7月19日，反诈警察将他接到警局，告诉他在给“预警账户”转钱，陈强完全不信，“我不可能被骗”，警察反复“教育”两小时，并对他的账户采取48小时紧急止付。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈强将信将疑，将自己已被提示受骗的信息告诉了骗子。骗子先是私信他，告知说自己也因为公司银行账户风险问题被叫去警局了，目前“机构”已经在调查，不会影响投资安全。次日，“机构”发布了处理通告。几番操作后，陈强转而又相信了骗子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;紧急止付结束后，陈强继续向骗子转钱，直至数日后，骗子诱导其把所有钱都投入其中，陈强才恍然大悟，自己的五万多元已被锁定，无法取出。陈强坦言，他走出骗局花了几天时间，48小时紧急止付的确起到一定作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种案例不在少数。在浙江的王雪妮于8月11日被骗时尚未意识到问题，直至公安机关发现诈骗分子的银行账户接收过她的转账，提示她正在遭遇电信网络诈骗。当天，她到派出所接受民警问询，所有的银行卡开始止付，持续时间为32天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一位在广州的受害者林晴晴也是在警方提示下到当地派出所报案做笔录。不过，林晴晴称，她解除止付流程很顺利，到反诈中心填写“解除保护性止付申请表”后，居住地附近的派出所民警上门核实并进行反诈宣传，很快银行卡解冻了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;根据林晴晴发布在社交账号上的“解除保护性止付申请表”，表格内容除了基本的信息以外，还要求填写“有无与民警见面劝阻”；要写明被止付的银行卡解除止付后的用途，交易情况要写明向谁转账，并附上转账理由等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但许多网友的解除止付流程并不顺利。在知乎上，一个IP属地在江西的网友称被异地公安止付，解除后仍然限制非柜台交易；一位江苏的网友称，当地解除止付需要40天，必须亲自过去；有人很慌张，表示即将要还款，不知道止付措施什么时候能解除。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/f282d2ba16.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;1707&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/f282d2ba16.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251129&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;林晴晴发布在网上的“解除保护性止付申请表”。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“灾后重建”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;陈强形容被骗以后的生活是“灾后重建”。这些年来他一直在上学，仅有的微薄积蓄在这次诈骗中一扫而光。“被骗后连吃个15元的牛肉面都会犹豫一下。”陈强说，而更令人窒息的是这样的日子预计还将持续一年多。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他一方面反思自己的贪婪和自大，对第一次进警局的表现感到可笑，“（自己）态度非常恶劣”。在他醒悟后，曾给当时做笔录的警察打电话，询问是否有追回的可能，对方告诉他，境外诈骗难以追回，更何况距转账时间太久。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，陈强希望“灾后重建”能顺利一些。在他停止转账，完全走出骗局后7天，接到了老家公安局打来的电话，告知其所有银行卡将止付一个月。“好不容易被骗钱后自己看开了，结果卡给我封了。”陈强说不知道止付需要持续多久时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王雪妮也提到银行卡被止付后的焦虑。她多次电话询问警方及开户银行，什么时候可以解除止付，对方只说“再等等”。出事前，她曾借了一笔微粒贷，止付后只能借钱还款。在得知确切的解冻时间前，她非常担心借朋友的钱还不上。王雪妮没有告知家属自己被骗，而止付后没有钱用，很容易露馅。为此，她吃不好也睡不好。“保护性止付其实也是对被骗的人的一种惩罚吧，让自己记住这个教训。”王雪妮说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎筝不认同“教训”的说法，她认为自己是受害者，被骗已经是极大的教训。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在社交媒体上，寻求解除止付方案的帖子很多。浙江的朱静娴由于丈夫的疏失被骗63万元，报案后银行卡冻结48小时。但案发25天后，银行卡仍被保护性止付，同时还会接到各个街道派出所询问被诈骗的情况。35天后，其银行卡依旧未解，到公安局说明情况后，回复需要再等48小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黎筝理解发帖的网友，她认为应该具体情况具体分析，已然醒悟的受害者可以提早解除止付，而非一刀切。9月13日，招商派出所民警将黎筝名下所有信用卡解冻，同时将一张储蓄卡暂时解冻，让她先还上公司贷款。黎筝说，9月14日，福田派出所负责人向其告知，派出所内部针对此案做了讨论，认为其中存在警方内部信息交换不够通畅的问题，应该对市民诉求予以体恤，协助解决问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（除郭志浩外，文中均为化名）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[大科学装置“夸父”首次亮相]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256934]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-19 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;太阳，是生命的源泉&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;太阳，是光明的象征&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，人类想在地球上造出一个“太阳”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;让能源不竭，水清天蓝，生命永续&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新华社记者独家探访&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;建设中的中国大科学装置“夸父”（CRAFT）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看看这个研究平台&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如何为未来的“人造太阳”研制“发动机”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/a963d796ae46fc31456463f2c9833a29.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;634&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/a963d796ae46fc31456463f2c9833a29.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251117&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;“夸父”园区效果图（中国科学院合肥物质科学研究院等离子体物理研究所供图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“夸父”的学名为&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“聚变堆主机关键系统综合研究设施（CRAFT）”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;是“十三五”立项的国家重大科技基础设施项目&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年12月获批开工建设&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;预计2025年底全面建成&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/72f3a1a844b0a5a10a625b33b41fcbe0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;562&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/72f3a1a844b0a5a10a625b33b41fcbe0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251114&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月11日拍摄的“夸父”园区建设实景。新华社记者周牧摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从无到有&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国的科研工作者和工程建设者夜以继日&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;边建设、边使用&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今的“夸父”园区已交付启用&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;来，让我们“乘坐”无人机&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;尝鲜体验下“夸父”雄姿&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/d5a2f74e5b6917a7281e18ba39ef16a2.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/d5a2f74e5b6917a7281e18ba39ef16a2.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251116&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/859da3df9eb8f315ac8bde9a98f1857e.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/859da3df9eb8f315ac8bde9a98f1857e.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;251115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;万物生长靠太阳&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;太阳发光发热是因为内部的核聚变反应&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果能在地球上造一个“太阳”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人类有望实现能源自由&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20世纪中叶人类开始核聚变能源研究&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我国在20世纪七十年代开启“人造太阳”梦想&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经过几代科研工作者接力奋斗&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国如今已建成&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“东方超环（EAST）”“中国环流器”等&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一批“人造太阳”实验装置&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;取得多项重大成果&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/f03086a0e373dcc66506720de669e12b.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;863&quot; height=&quot;1294&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/f03086a0e373dcc66506720de669e12b.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国自主研发的EAST装置&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拥有核心技术200多项、专利近2000项&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;汇聚“超高温”“超低温”“超高真空”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“超强磁场”“超大电流”尖端技术于一炉&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/bbe72b3589ffbb990f5c0dc75f7827a7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;838&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/bbe72b3589ffbb990f5c0dc75f7827a7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251113&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此基础上，中国下一代“人造太阳”——&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国聚变工程实验堆（CFETR）已完成工程设计&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而为建设CFETR研究关键技术&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正是“夸父”的主要使命&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;相比EAST&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;CFETR将更大、更高、更精密、更先进&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前在“夸父”的实验室里&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;已经可以看到CFETR部分部件的雏形&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如这个巨大的“橘子瓣”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/b5ee6877a7d005912032db75b6125974.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1778&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/b5ee6877a7d005912032db75b6125974.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251121&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这就是未来“人造太阳”的重要组成部分&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外表很壮观&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“夸父”的科技内涵更可观&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如同中国古代神话传说中的夸父&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;胸怀大志、向往光明、不惧艰辛、勇于追梦&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;100余家国内合作单位&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;60余家国际合作单位&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1000多名建设者&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;历经5年多时间&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;攻克一系列科研与工程技术难题&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/316d9093e6869944dd0436025acd1e96.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;667&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/316d9093e6869944dd0436025acd1e96.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月15日，工作人员在“夸父”园区安装调试设备。新华社记者周牧摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/244c718348dc72838a1e15059416ebd1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;670&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/244c718348dc72838a1e15059416ebd1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;251120&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;9月15日，这是“夸父”园区内象征自力更生、艰苦奋斗精神的早期聚变装置发电机实物。新华社记者周牧摄&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;向着光明&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;向着美好未来&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国“夸父”奋力前行&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《装腔启示录》导演李漠：梅菲斯托在身边]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256868]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-18 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/FM7VX0iOsJ6arOkmiBSYPNhTTwMO1lKzTzZnPSPd.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/FM7VX0iOsJ6arOkmiBSYPNhTTwMO1lKzTzZnPSPd.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250970&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;导演李漠&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在电视剧《装腔启示录》的豆瓣评论中，该剧导演李漠写自己“专业装腔30年”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;初中，他无法忍受男生宿舍的汗味，喷上了一款圣罗兰的女士香水，成了同学里第一个喷香水的人（后因味道太大妥协为妮维雅的走汗珠）。学校门口的租书铺，他避过大家都看的金庸、古龙、梁羽生，拿起一本弗洛伊德的《精神分析导论》。后来因为看不上通俗哲学，硬啃了几页黑格尔的《小逻辑》。他研究过莎士比亚的十四行诗，琢磨古英文与现代英文表达的差别。看完《007》，他去酒吧学着詹姆斯·邦德叫一杯Martini。他曾是专业的音乐生，从小学古琴。他从Radiohead乐队的《Ok，computer》中获得摇滚启蒙，玩了十多年乐队，主攻吉他，兼打架子鼓、当主唱、做program、弹贝斯。他考上了音乐学院，读了一年后退学又考上北京电影学院，摸爬滚打近十年，成为一名导演。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一切解释了他看到小说《装腔启示录》时的兴奋。 “合上书，我琢磨着，大概没人比我更擅长拍这个了。明确又委婉，虚伪又真挚，胆怯又勇敢。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，改编自同名小说的电视剧《装腔启示录》播出，豆瓣评分8.1，成为他继《我在他乡挺好的》（2021，评分8.1）、《三悦有了新工作》（2022，评分8.4）之后第三部豆瓣评分8分以上的作品。对当下的国产电视剧导演而言，这个成绩足够亮眼。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/T1a3hqh7ssxmzIxwXb5AT5XoqEoaWNA8s4ZPhDc8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/T1a3hqh7ssxmzIxwXb5AT5XoqEoaWNA8s4ZPhDc8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250971&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;李漠在《我在他乡挺好的》中饰演警察&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三年三部剧，皆是关注当代都市年轻人的困境。 《我在他乡挺好的》讲的是大都市里的异乡人，他们在漂泊中经历生活、事业、感情的种种考验。 《三悦有了新工作》中，主角赵三悦阴差阳错进入殡仪馆担任化妆师，见证了往生者的生前身后，折射出众生群像。 《装腔启示录》的故事发生在北京CBD，投行精英许子诠和律师唐影相遇，他们一面应付着工作重压，一面极力维系着有腔调的都市生活，从互相试探到逐渐放下戒备走到一起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;出生于1988年的李漠经历过类似的困境。大学毕业后，他弹琴、拍电影、写小说、当老师，还差点去考博士，说自己“什么都想要”。最终在导师的点拨下，他细看《心经》和《金刚经》，静下心来从宗教中获得启发，更笃定了心中的答案：“我就是想做表达的工作、做创作的工作，我可以去体验不一样的生活。”当导演是他目前的表达方式。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/MBhjCuHSJicaNAGq0yKfmTzIsjDx8iMtxu5Jiqj8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/MBhjCuHSJicaNAGq0yKfmTzIsjDx8iMtxu5Jiqj8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250969&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《装腔启示录》剧照&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李漠的微信名是Mephisto（梅菲斯托），微信签名是：“I can give you everything you want，but you just pay yourself.”（我能给你想要的一切，但你要付出灵魂。）它们来自德国作家约翰·沃尔夫冈·冯·歌德创作的诗剧《浮士德》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;书中，浮士德垂垂老矣，在昏暗的书房里钻研半生，感到无比厌倦，这时恶魔梅菲斯托降临，引诱他签署了协议：满足他生前的所有要求，直到他死后拿走他的灵魂。这也是梅菲斯托与上帝的一个赌约。为追求真理，浮士德历尽艰险，走遍了人类追寻过的道路，经常失败和沉沦，但他没有放弃，最终获得了救赎。李漠很喜欢这部作品，看过很多遍，他觉得浮士德和梅菲斯托是人类的两面。 “人长大的过程中，灵魂好像越来越不重要。我把那句话写在我签名里，希望所有我认识的人看到能够想到这一点：如果它不那么重要，在你身上你都不探究它，那把你的灵魂卖掉好不好？浮士德在经历了一切之后，他发现灵魂最重要。这就是梅菲斯托的意义。我想要做一个梅菲斯托在身边的人，提醒大家、也提醒我，给你一切，把你灵魂卖掉好不好？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/C9UzP4aOLdFWxcahhdVh9OxRytG7qk1xOTnIljuN.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/C9UzP4aOLdFWxcahhdVh9OxRytG7qk1xOTnIljuN.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250972&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;导演李漠&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;strong>;无力感&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;是最&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;能&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;让我共情的都市人困境&lt;/strong>;——对话李漠&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;正向表达“我爱你”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《装腔启示录》中，许子诠给唐影写了一个香水名，但不是原著里的那一款。剧中还有很多类似细节的不同，这些是你改的吗？为什么要这么改？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李漠：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;原著里边那款停产了。很多修改都是希望它变得更接近当下。我预判到大家会对这些东西比较敏感，比如说剧开头许子诠在飞机上用的Le&amp;nbsp;Labo香膏，原著里面没有提到。那是我个人很喜欢的一款，我觉得很方便，随时拿着上飞机。后来我才知道那个也停产了，但是写剧本的时候还没停。我想把电视剧改得更接近我生活里的一些（实际情况），里面用的酒也是。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;道具怎么呈现是表达的一部分，这都不是带货，是我觉得他那样的人大约是用那样的东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;结局为什么要加上求婚的桥段？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李漠：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很多台词是书里延续下来的，只是求婚这个行为在书里面没有。因为剧结束了，我希望给观众一个结束的观感，是一个有仪式感的交代。他是求婚，不是结婚，我不觉得他俩就结婚了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;求婚跟结婚差别还挺大的，求婚意味着自己的决心和意愿，我想跟你一直在一起。也没说白头偕老，说的是我想跟你构建属于我们的世界。我知道或许步入婚姻以后，我们会遇见很多困难，但我相信我和你有能力把生活过成我们想要的样子，这个是我想说的决心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唯心和唯物不矛盾，我心里这么想，我要有一点行动来证明，在我有财力的情况下，我买一个钻戒跟我的爱人表达。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在结局里放这么一场戏，就是想告诉观众许子诠是一个真诚的人。很多观众看他很帅，他屁股很翘，他有车有房，他是个金融男……于是就推论出这（求婚）一切不成立，这段爱情是个童话，他不可能这么喜欢一个三年级律师——长得也就那样。但爱情不是做买卖，爱上一个人没有道理，我就爱你。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到最后求婚的时候，许子诠的爱情观是改变了的，他愿意跟唐影构建“我们的世界”，愿意把一个人的生活变成“我们俩的生活”，我觉得这就是求婚的价值和意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我愿意在我的戏里面去倡导正向表达我爱你，表达我愿意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这也是你的爱情观吗？这种正向的表达和相信？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李漠：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我不停地去探寻爱情是什么，才能够比较相信它。我相信爱情是从遇见我老婆开始。许子诠有很大一部分是我的投射。他不觉得这世界上有这么一个人，可以支撑我，可以看到我最糟糕的地方还依旧爱我，能够包容我、理解我。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;唐影才是会谈恋爱、懂爱的人，许子诠懂的是撩拨、是技巧，他懂怎么招人喜欢。我最喜欢浴室里那场戏，许子诠非常糟糕的时候，唐影没有数落他的糟糕，而是告诉他：你应该告诉我你状态不好，你应该跟我分享，你应该把你不好的那面展露给我，你放心，我能接住，我觉得你是最好的，你都不知道你有多好。这是我人生中也经历过的一刻，让我觉得我在被人爱着、被人包裹着、支撑着。她让我觉得虽然我状态这么糟糕、我这么情绪波动、我事业面对低谷、我看不到未来，但她依旧不嫌弃我，没有以这些衡量我，没有谴责我。她告诉我：我爱你，你有多好你都不知道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那一刻让我理解了什么是爱。原来爱不是索取，也不是付出，而是互相之间的给予，是能看到他最糟糕的那一面也依旧爱他。这个是我想跟大家讲的爱情观。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/RUmrzlT0NgeYRX9rp0B9x0P0HAmubDRtmCGSdJwj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/16/RUmrzlT0NgeYRX9rp0B9x0P0HAmubDRtmCGSdJwj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250968&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《装腔启示录》剧照&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;不努力连结果都没有&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你说很喜欢韩东君（饰演许子诠）身上的疲惫感，这种疲惫感为什么触动你？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李漠：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得我想讲的圈层的人他们不配喊累，没有资格说自己辛苦。他们挣的钱比较多，在剧里的语境中，挣钱挣得比较多的人卖惨，这是不可以的。但真正接触到这些人的生活，他们有困境，他不可能跟别人说我累、我惨、我不愉快。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你在CBD上班，你这么忙，你考上北大清华，你五院四系研究生毕业，你上了红圈所，你去了国投，你干到了中层，这人生已经很顶峰了，你还要怎样？你还惨什么？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他们最惨的地方就是他们没有资格说惨，他们上有老下有小，旁边有竞争对手，一步错就会被人扳倒，生活现状没有人看得到。人家觉得你活该，你应该的，你凭什么喊惨，我都吃不上饭了，我都没喊惨，你天天锦衣玉食，出入奢华的场合，你有什么好惨？所以我没法在这个戏里面替他们叫惨，我只能把他们的状态表现出来，疲惫感就是这种，他没法表达，他只能笑着跟人说，是，你说得对。这是我认识的这圈人给我的感受。当然我也不觉得他们惨。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我要讲这圈人，就得把这圈人身上最具特质的部分抓到，对我而言这部分就是这帮人都很累，很疲倦，但是他不能表达。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你拍的《我在他乡挺好的》《三悦有了新生活》《装腔启示录》口碑都不错，你希望表达的东西是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李漠：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;都是都市生活，都是讲都市年轻人的困境。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我也曾经在困境里，现在或许也在困境里。困境会帮助人成长，更好地磨练自己。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;剧里哪些困境是你最能共情的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李漠：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是工作上的无力感。明明知道这件事能做好，也知道该怎么做好，但就是做不到。这种时候会觉得自己在这个城市里很渺小。不知道问题在哪，能做的都做了，事情还是这样。这是最能让我共情的都市人困境。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是我更希望告诉大家，面对这种困境别放弃。放弃是一种自我保护，因为不抱期待了，好像就不会失望，就不会受伤。无论是面对工作、爱情或是亲情，都在以一种退避的方式自我保护。我一个人也挺好，我不上去也挺好，我躺平也挺好，照样拿工资。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可就算是这样也应该去尝试，失败有多可怕？失恋有多可怕？我有时候觉得失恋是一个挺快乐的事，可以感受到很多平时感受不到的情绪，多难能可贵的人生体验啊。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;你看所有我聊的这些都挺唯心的。物质层面也重要，但其实怎么都能活，也不用非要挣很多钱，主要是弄明白自己想要的生活水平，把今天的事儿干好就挺了不起。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你现在觉得自己已经走出这种困境了吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李漠：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;很难走出，依旧会有无力感，哪怕是觉得比以前做的事多了，但是依旧有事情做不到。我工作时间越长，觉得这种无力感越重，很多事人能操控的部分很少。导演好像挺有权力的，能决定很多事，但今天下不下雨我决定不了，明天开不开会我决定不了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当你察觉到无力的时候，是没找对跟这个世界相处的方式，一旦找到，就能感受到世界给你的支撑，而不是你跟这个世界的对立。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你什么时候开始感觉到世界给你的是助力而不是阻力？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李漠：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当我不跟世界死磕的时候。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在的社会结构带给人的无力感可能无法消解。现实就是我们努力也不一定会带来正向的回报，个人也无法仅靠努力就能实现命运的改变。你在表达中有没有思考过这样的现实？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;李漠：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我后面一个项目准备跟大家聊聊这个事，讲的是一个00后的年轻人，从小特别有抱负，考上了北京很好的大学，2019年入学，赶上了三年新冠疫情，毕业以后找不着工作。现在在写剧本，明年会拍这个项目。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我觉得现在是转变的时代，跟以前不一样。大家要接受转变。每一代人的人生中都会面对时代转变，比如社会波动、战争、变革，不用太恐慌。你说的在结构性的问题面前，人们需要去调整面对这个时代的目标和自我定位，不是说时代变了，努力也得不到和上个时代同样的结果，所以我不努力。这个时代努力有这个时代的结果，不努力连结果都没有。努力不是选择，努力是应该的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;或许我明年那个戏拍完了，也能给大家带来一些讨论，我想把究竟该怎么脚踏实地放到那个戏里跟大家讲。但我在这儿还是想跟大家说，不要放弃，你在这个时代躺平的时候，有一群不躺平的人就把机会夺走了。每一个时代都是这样，你放弃的机会会被别人拿走，你做努力的人你就有可能找到机会。积极面对人生，在任何时代里面都不是坏事。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 23:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[历经社会毒打为何屹立不倒？因为“男人至死是少年” ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256898]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-18 22:00:36&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“男人至死是少年”，这句话的传播之广众所周知，以至于我的耳膜时不时被震动一下。例如，多数男人一直保留着少年时期的爱好，比如游戏、玩具、运动、手艺活。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更进一步，“男人至死是少年”，是一句充满了生活哲学的评语，它简直是为一群经历了社会的残酷毒打却能每每屹立于人世间的男人所“量身定做”的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位外国脱口秀演员在接受采访时表示，吃着披萨喝着酒，坐在电视机前看看球赛，骂骂裁判，就这样一个人度过愉快的时光，别提多幸福了。当被问一周看这么多球赛累不累时，他回答说：“一点也不累，因为我是那种头脑简单的男人，光是坐着看球赛就能获得快乐。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，“会跟妻子一起看球赛吗？”他的回答是：“不会，她心思比较复杂，很难专注做一件事，一些女人就是因为这样所以每天都觉得不开心。”有点吐槽自己老婆的意思。不过，有一个事实是不错的：男女偏好差异客观存在，很多时候，这种差异性也有喜感。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;知乎上一位男性答主说，他网购清单里有一堆想买但是深知毫无用处的东西，一根十几块钱的木棍子排在第二。棍子到手后，他给缠了手胶，带到了单位。女同事问他买这个干吗，他说就是想买，她表示很不理解。这意思似乎是说，十几元也是钱，拿来买把大葱也不浪费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他就断言：“我就把棍子放这，你看哪个男的过来不玩一下？”结果这棍子一下午有六七人上手把玩，她看不懂，就给她老公发个照片，一会她老公回复：这棍好啊！&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;答主感慨，这根棍子从男孩几岁到几十岁通杀，而男的只要看到小时候玩的东西，立刻无缝衔接上手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于这一点，我也有着切身的体会。我十三岁玩篆刻，用功颇多，虽然人到中年后有所松懈，但磨石头的爱好保留了下来。只要看到刻刀和印石，心中就会感到亲切，拿起石头磨一磨，从中体会到非功利的欢喜。不久前，我岳父母听了我的建议，为我在乡间的鸡圈里，置起“磨石台”，我常常把俗事收起，在此专心磨石。磨石时，鸡走虫鸣，风吹叶落，好生自在。那一刻，这种无一事相缠绕、不为五斗米奔忙的极致宁静，是迷人的、有魔性的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;说到底，很多男人之所以能至死都是少年，就在于一直体验着简单快乐的精髓。别说十几元的东西都能让他们快乐起来，就算不值钱的东西，例如，一根树枝，一块戈壁滩捡来的石头，都能让自己沉浸其中，把玩半天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而真正的快乐，许多是不花钱的。一位毕业自北大的好友告诉我，他喜欢物理与数学，每次上网看看，就很开心。我的一位老领导，也喜欢每天深夜下了班，在单位坐一会，和网络上的围棋高手对弈片刻。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我注意过单位附近一个叫红庙的小街里的象棋客和观棋客，他们除了下大雨，都在街边旧桌子上下棋、看棋，随着棋局的变化，有时他们表情紧张“不敢高声语”，有时却轻快愉悦。我在此地十余年，因此细心留意过，下棋和看棋的始终就那几位。多年下来，他们除了面相显老，快乐的神情丝毫未变。那一盘棋局，关乎钱财？关乎名誉？关乎地位？并不是。他们只不过在“偷得浮生半日闲”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作家汪曾祺也写过一位做面鱼做得忘我精彩的老者的故事，赞其为“活庄子”。所谓的“活庄子”，要义不在“高深”，而在意象悠远、无拘无束吧。那些在寂静无人的河道边一坐就是一天的“钓友”，也是如此。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;绝大多数男人当然不可能绝然世外，名利之累也是有的。但是步入中老年岁月后，很多男人顿悟，既然工作与职级也就那样了，一辈子能到的高度也就那样了，得不到的就放手好了，留下一片素净天地让自己过得更简单、更纯真，岂非更好？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种考虑，是一种质朴品性的折射。当一个男人把个人荣辱、人生得失想透彻了之后，剩下的事就简单许多了。于是，从与自己的相处中得到乐趣，就成为一件每天要完成的课目。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;与自己相处，某种意义上是难度最大的。如果一个人总是心怀不切实际的目标，总是和自己较劲；那么，这种自处的质量就会很糟糕，人格还容易撕裂。当然，如果一个人出于攀比心，总是（对配偶）心怀不切实际的目标，使劲催逼自己的配偶“努力”，去挣更多的钱、要有权，那么这种相处的质量就会很糟糕，家庭也很难和睦。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;反过来，如果一个人能意识到人生的某个阶段并不是追求到什么才是快乐，能保持一份平常心，就很容易让自己的“影子”也被自己营造的天趣所感染，从而真正融合在一起，让自己变得更强大，更从容。如果家人比较理解或也是这样的人，家庭就会比较融洽和睦。这种自在、放松、忘我、乐在其中，与消费主义助推的、极易带来痛苦的攀比，很不一样。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;人不免受到欲望袭扰，但人还是要努力做到与自己的相处达到平衡之境。童心未泯，是一个很平易却是至高的境界。它的基础是刚健的秉性、快乐的真谛。说到底，很多男人对于“简单快乐”的尊崇，代表了一个群体对于自身价值的客观评价和对“世外”的不卑不亢之态度，它延续着个体的童心，也让世俗生活多了几分恬淡的意趣。这就是“至死是少年”所暗藏的男人的秘密。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刺客模式丨意长意短]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256930]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-18 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/IoH3LnypZUwNhU91O62T9wKXgOBVpGdB4mr6Axlw.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1365&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/18/IoH3LnypZUwNhU91O62T9wKXgOBVpGdB4mr6Axlw.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;251102&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;法国巴黎圣拉扎尔地铁区域快铁（RER）站。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在乡下度日，没有什么着急上火的时候，无非是下暴雨了赶出去收衣裳，或者把进水的窗户关起来。但进城就不一样了，尤其是在巴黎有很多焦急的时刻，比如赶车赶飞机。那种时刻，我一般会开启“刺客模式”，不断告诫自己：集中注意力，直奔目标，才能不耽搁事儿。比如有一天早上，我约了一个从国内来逛美术馆的朋友，一起在她的宾馆吃早点。我出门发现已经有些晚了，要坐72路去卢浮宫，眼看着72路从我眼前开过，距离下一站还有五百米的样子。趁着车子等红绿灯，我一口气向前跑去，想在车子到下一站之前赶上。我跑了大约一百米的样子，公车师傅赶上我，摁了喇叭让我上车。上去之后，满车的人都用同情的眼光看着我。他们一定在想，这女人真是有点儿拼。我一时有些茫然，向师傅道谢，又手忙脚乱地刷卡。其实我没想到更拼的还在后面，就是这次坐飞机回国的时刻，体会到什么叫分秒必争。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我先是打算坐车去的，一切都安排得井井有条。我的朋友迈克是一个漂在巴黎的意大利小资产阶级（黎漂，热衷于去超市购物、攒积分，发现各种省钱攻略）。他一直都没有送我去过机场，因为他之前开着一辆污染等级5级的柴油车，除了周末的有些时候，基本不能开出去。现在他有了一辆污染等级2级的新车子，可以随时上路了，就热情地说要送我。而且时间也是巧，他五点下班，我们五点二十出发。我的飞机是九点二十的，提前四个小时出门，戴高乐机场距离我住的地方也不过三十公里，一个小时应该也到了。我盘算了一下，觉得很合适。我五点时去附近的店铺里买了一碗鱼片盖饭，上面铺了一层金枪鱼和三文鱼，没有汤汤水水，可以在登机前享用，就不用在飞机上吃东西。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们是在差不多五点半时出发的，气氛轻松，听着音乐，又说又笑。开始的几公里还算畅快，一上环线，路上基本是停车场状况，只有摩托车在汽车中间的空隙飞驰，救护车和警车一辆辆过去，两边的车会让开。我看着窗外，心想大城市有什么好，简直太纷乱了。但时间真的很充分，我尽量放松，车子的收音机放着爵士女歌手比莉·哈乐黛（Bilie&amp;nbsp;Holiday）舒缓、忧伤、悠扬的歌声，像一种灵魂的按摩，讲的是一个女人为爱疯狂，可以为爱挪开大山什么的。迈克说，你如果是住在桥底下的流浪者就好了，不用赶回去上班。我也想那样啊，可是我喜欢柔软的床铺，我爱我的工作，我要赶回去上班。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们在环线上活活堵了一个小时，打算下去了，但一下辅路，车子更是死死停在那里，不能向前，不能倒退。在地图上，整个城市的路线都发红了，又原地等到了差不多七点钟。我在窗口看了看，前后左右都是车，越来越心慌，已经开始想象因为赶不上上课被学校开除的悲惨处境，就连轻快的爵士小调都无法让我的心境平缓下来，窗外的城市好像越来越咄咄逼人，蓝天白云也显得很空洞。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迈克一筹莫展，只有从钱包里拿出一张车票跟我说：“你从这里下去，往前走是4号线，你从那里坐车到北站，再坐快线RER、B线到戴高乐，需要一个小时赶到机场。这个区域很乱，小心钱包和手机。你准备好了吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我没有准备好，但是我硬着头皮下了车，如果中间有任何差错，一个小时赶不到，我就误机了。但如果我坐在车上干等，误机更是必然。我从后备箱里拿了行李（我庆幸自己是四轮行李），在自行车道上飞奔起来，像一只在草原上遭到狮子追击的羚羊。我一边跑一边开启了“刺客模式”，目标是在一个小时之内赶到机场。我庆幸自己穿了板鞋，还有退休运动员般良好的体力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开始还算顺利，我站在地铁站里，犹豫从哪儿下去，一老太太大声说：“两边都一样。”一下到地下，就有地铁开着门等着。上去之前，我还和一个文质彬彬的男人确认了是不是去北站。我很警惕地看着站牌，担心错过了。但坐到北站，事情变得复杂起来了，里面有很多火车、RER线路和地铁线，我一下找不到B线，按照指示牌却走错了地方，还好上车前问了一下，没有上错车。我像无头苍蝇一样乱走，看见一个正在打电话的执勤人员，飞奔过去，问他去戴高乐机场去哪里坐，估计是我满头大汗震撼到他了。他一边讲电话，一边快速把我领到了坐车的地方，巧的是，这时我要坐的车子也到了，赶上飞机的可能多了一筹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然后是焦心的四十分钟，每一站都似乎无比漫长，每一站都有人不紧不慢地上下车。我想，这时只有山洪、地震、恐怖袭击、地铁故障才能阻碍我去机场。我很心焦，不停地看手机，看着坐在旁边两个神情自若的女人，她们也带着巨大的行李，只是她们一定有更多的时间。我感叹自己昨天下午还在河边的躺椅上，吃着生火腿和奶酪，喝着啤酒，今天就要经历这样的考验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;终于到了戴高乐机场，距离关闭办登机牌还有二十分钟。我跟着人流飞奔到柜台前，一个英俊的黑人小哥张开手来，对我说：“别着急，来得及的。放松点儿。”我把护照递给他，心想我看起来一定很狼狈，真是如匪过境。旁边的旅客也在抱怨今天的大堵车，似乎替我的晚到解释。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;寄了行李，在安检那里排队，发语音给意大利朋友说今天的遭遇。前面的姑娘居然是意大利人，就对我说：“您排我前面吧。如果是我，也焦虑死了。”真是四海之内皆姐妹。她说她在巴黎欧莱雅做了三年，现在去上海待三年，她的飞机在我的后面。我对她道谢，就毫不客气地排到了她前面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了登机口那里，我发现自己身上的汗变得冰冷，T恤完全是湿透的，印在上面的黄色鱼图案变成了褐色，顿时感觉很忧虑。我看到旁边有一家零售店，就花了二十欧重金买了一件旅游纪念T恤，去洗手间里换上，又擦干了头发，做到万无一失。这时候，登机口已经不用怎么排队了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我在排队登机了。”我给迈克打电话，让他放心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“我也刚回家。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“今天多亏了你的机场轻轨票，谢谢。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不客气，很抱歉没把你送到。我在吃你忘在座椅上的鱼片盖饭，还不错。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“祝你胃口好。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“祝你一路顺风。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后我穿着一件胸口印着硕大的艾菲尔铁塔、略显俗气的T恤从重庆机场走了出来，像一个去外面刚打了卡的游客。我得说，这次赶上飞机的事，让我在庆幸之余增添了很多面对未来的信心。我想起了一句经文：凡事都有定期，天下万物都有定时……寻找有时，失落有时；保守有时，舍弃有时；撕裂有时，缝补有时；静默有时，言语有时……我觉得，一切都有定数，误机有时，赶上趟也有时：必要的时候开启“刺客模式”，保持警惕&lt;strong>;，&lt;/strong>;勇往直前，总有一线赶上的生机。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 21:25:12 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[导游变身导买，这样的旅游团还能走多远？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256920]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-18 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, I signed up for two tour groups, namely Three Gorges and Wulong. The orders were placed on the same travel platform. The customer service is very patient, the procedures are very standardized, and electronic contracts, travel notices, insurance purchases, etc. are all available. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The scenery on both sides of the Three Gorges is beautiful. On the cruise ship, you can watch the rising sun in the morning and the bright moon and stars in the evening. You can hold a sleeve of breeze and watch the river flowing eastward. It is really a good place to express your love for the mountains and rivers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The gap between the Tiankeng and the ground in Wulong is even more amazing. The Tiankeng is really as if God accidentally dropped a huge boulder, creating a huge crater on the ground. It is majestic, strange, dangerous and... It&#39;s quiet; the crack in the ground is like a narrow crack in the depths of the earth. The rock walls on both sides are steep, with springs and waterfalls splashing above, and streams flowing below. It&#39;s endlessly ethereal and breathtaking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the beauty of these two journeys only ends here, because traveling also requires eating, sleeping, and a tour guide, which does not feel so wonderful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let’s talk about the tour guide first. Tour guides have long implemented the local accompanying system. They change tour guides at each place. When they arrive at the scenic spot, they change to another commentator. Along the way, there are many tour guides. One face is not familiar yet, and another face is changed immediately. It’s a revolving door. Similar. This is very unfriendly to me who is face blind, but that&#39;s it - there&#39;s nothing I can do about it - after not traveling far for three years, I was surprised to find that the guide system has always been the same, but now the tour guide&#39;s style has changed again , have turned into guides and bought. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After we swam at the Three Gorges Dam, on the way to the dock, the tour guide started selling beef, small fish products and sesame food in the car. She said that the quality of these products was guaranteed and the prices were reasonable. She wanted to buy them. Earn money for interest classes for my daughter. The driver cooperated and drove slowly, and then simply stopped on the side of the road. About one-third of the tourists bought the products she put in the car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the middle of the trip to the Three Gorges, we got on a small boat and traveled to Shennu Creek. In addition to the boatman, there is also a tour guide named Amei on the boat. Shennu Creek is very beautiful, and the guide’s introduction was pretty good at the beginning. However, after only being “good” for a while, she introduced her hometown and various specialties from her hometown, which are “purely natural, pollution-free, and have special effects on the human body.” Efficacy&quot;. As I expected, on the return trip, she started selling the local specialties that had been placed on the cruise ship. During the entire return journey, I heard the tour guide shouting in the headset: &quot;Please support our hometown.&quot; &quot;How many packs do you want?&quot; The mood of watching the scenery was ruined. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After arriving in Chongqing, the tour guide did not help me buy any real items. What she sold was a night tour in Chongqing, three places, 70 yuan. When the car arrived in the city, she got off the bus with the tourists participating in the night tour and asked us to go to the hotel to check in. Then the tourists got into a quarrel at the hotel front desk over who checked in first and who last. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wulong Tour also took us to a Miao Village Scenic Spot. In this scenic spot, the most impressive thing was that the tour guide of the scenic spot constantly promoted their silver products. In his mouth, these silver products are unparalleled in the world. The only thing left is that it has a full range of health care effects, blah blah blah. As a result, no one bought it, so he ignored us. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Let’s talk about food. Most of the two tour groups include meals. Except for the three meals on the cruise ship, which are normal, the rest is hard to describe. The meal price is 40 yuan per person, eight dishes and one soup. These eight dishes include meaty ones such as very fatty pork belly, stir-fried chicken offal with onions, etc., and vegetarian ones such as cold skin, potatoes, pumpkins, etc. The soup is a veritable soup. I only saw three pieces of radish in one radish soup... &lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;As for the accommodation, each person is only guaranteed to have a bed to sleep on. As for whether the lights are on, whether the bath water is at a suitable temperature, and whether the door lock is broken, tourists are left to their own devices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When traveling, you don’t make a guide, don’t plan a route, don’t bother to think about the car, meals, hotel, etc., but leave it all to the travel agency and become a hands-off shopkeeper yourself. I think it’s very strange. Economical and convenient model. Your travel agency makes money, and I, the tourist, enjoy the beautiful mountains, rivers and good mood. Both parties get what they want, how wonderful! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But what I wonder is, why is the tourism industry running in the opposite direction? You see, the tour guide will almost reach into your pocket and take out the money. The group meal costing 400 yuan per table can be reduced to 40 yuan. The cheaper the room, the better, no matter what facilities it has. Don’t they think they are seeking a dead end and pushing tourists away? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three years after the epidemic, the market demand for tourism is huge. If the tourism industry seizes this trend, rectifies its business practices, provides high-quality services, changes its image, and builds reputation, it should be able to attract many tourists. under their command. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What a pity, they are going further and further on the road of deceiving tourists. I don’t know how far this kind of tour group can go. At least, I don’t dare to join the tour group again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a retired teacher in Jiaxing, Zhejiang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; •&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(The &quot;hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of Southern Weekend App is looking forward to your contributions. Submission email: nfzmreaders @163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>