<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[悔婚拒退彩礼引发血案：当从悲剧中吸取教训丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260694]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Surveillance video circulated online shows that at 13:38 on November 11, two people were killed in a mahjong parlor in Liangshan, Sichuan. A woman playing mahjong was killed by two men with knives. According to media reports, insiders revealed that a knife-wielding man and a woman who was hacked were originally lovers and had paid a bride price of 300,000 yuan, but the woman regretted the marriage and was only willing to return 150,000 yuan. The two men are father and son, and the other woman is related to the woman who regretted her marriage. The next day, local police stated that the two assailants were controlled by the police on the spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This tragedy sparked a lot of discussion. A mother said: &quot;Ever since my daughter entered the society, I have taught her that it is OK to fall in love, but you cannot use other people&#39;s money. You are not allowed to accept money or transfers from others!&quot; Some netizens said: &quot;You can go to the court to sue and demand She would not go to this step to return the gift.&quot; However, someone immediately appeared to give their own testimony or quoted the news to prove how difficult it is to return the bride price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The nature of betrothal gifts is different from the betrothal gifts in traditional society. There is a wedding ceremony of a scholar in &quot;Book of Rites&quot;. Scholars were the lowest class nobles; there were six rites for marrying a wife, which were nacai, asking for name, naji, nazheng, asking for date and personally welcoming. Nazheng was the betrothal gift. This set of common people was imitated and integrated into traditional marriage customs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Betrothal gift is a &quot;new custom&quot; that has emerged in recent years. What is worrying is that betrothal gifts are becoming more and more popular. Not only are the prices getting higher and higher, but there is also a trend of generalization. Betrothal gifts were not available in some places, but now they are beginning to be given. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The current legal definition of bride price is &quot;a gift for the purpose of marriage.&quot; The biggest problem caused by this characterization is that it has given rise to the stereotype that &quot;getting married is starting a business and getting divorced is getting rich&quot;. Some women disappear immediately after taking the bride price, or after receiving the marriage certificate, they refuse to live with the man, and then ask for a divorce in order to keep the high-priced bride price as their own. When more such incidents occur, social problems arise, and the judicial system has no choice but to add some patches to this characterization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Supreme People’s Court’s Interpretation on the Application of the Marriage and Family Section of the Civil Code of the People’s Republic of China (1) Article 5 stipulates: If a party requests the return of a betrothal gift paid in accordance with customs, if it is found that it falls under the following circumstances, the People’s Court It should be supported: (1) Both parties have not completed the marriage registration procedures; (2) Both parties have completed the marriage registration procedures but have not lived together; (3) Pre-marriage payments have caused difficulties in the payer&#39;s life. The application of the provisions of the second and third items of the preceding paragraph shall be conditional on the divorce of both parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In judicial practice, some courts will use their discretion to determine whether and how much the bride price should be refunded based on the length of the marriage. Mastering the stick, but aiming for the yard. Some women have come up with some tricks: maintain the marriage for one year and then file for divorce, so that the probability of the court ruling to return the bride price is very small; install cameras at home, refuse to live as a couple, and use various methods to anger the man and induce him to take action. Photographing it will be evidence of domestic violence, so that the court will justifiably support the woman&#39;s various demands. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long ago, a man in Zhumadian, Henan Province released a video saying that his wife had domestically abused him and set a fire indoors. The incident occurred at around two o&#39;clock in the morning on June 16, 2023. The video shows: the man was robbed of his mobile phone and was slapped by the woman without fighting back; the woman set fires in many places in the house, and the flames were visible on the sofa, dining table and kitchen trash can, and the man followed and doused them one by one. The man said that he had spent all his parents’ savings in order to get married, spending a total of nearly 200,000 yuan including 100,000 yuan in betrothal gifts. Now, after only four months of marriage, the woman is about to get divorced. “Tell me to get out of here, just a penny of betrothal gifts.” Neither will retreat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;Rule of Law Daily&quot; report, recently, the Henan Provincial High Court concluded a divorce dispute case. In March 2022, the man Xiao Yijing introduced him to the woman Xiaoshuang. In May of the same year, the two registered their marriage; in July of the same year, Xiaoshuang announced that she was pregnant and had an abortion that month due to fetal abnormalities. Subsequently, Xiaoshuang sued for divorce, and Xiaoya agreed to the divorce, but countersued for the return of the 186,000 yuan gift. In both the first instance and the second instance, the court ruled that the parties were divorced, but did not support the request for return of the bride price. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiaoya was dissatisfied and applied for retrial. After the retrial, the court found that: In the original trial, Xiaoya claimed that Xiaoshuang used the name of marriage to obtain property, and said that after the lawsuit, it was found that Xiaoshuang had married 6 men before getting married, and all of them got pregnant and had abortions within a short period of time after the marriage and then divorced. , and all received expensive betrothal gifts. The court held that the bride price was paid for the purpose of getting married, starting a family, and living together for a long time. Otherwise, it would violate the true intention of the party who paid the bride price and should be returned. However, it only awarded a refund of 100,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you get married once or twice, get pregnant for a short period of time, have an abortion, and get divorced, it may be true; if you repeat this routine seven times in a row, the possibility of it being true is very slim. The woman was probably trying to get the bride price by defrauding her, and the purpose was to establish evidence of living together. But even so, the 186,000 betrothal gifts received for the seventh marriage can still keep 86,000, and the &quot;profit rate&quot; is too high; plus the betrothal gifts received for the first six times, I am afraid it will easily make a profit of one million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In this context, we can have a more profound analysis of why the Liangshan tragedy occurred. Liangshan is a very poor place in Sichuan. After receiving a bride price of 300,000 yuan, only 150,000 yuan was returned. For the father and son, it was equivalent to taking away their entire lives. Moreover, if you really go to court to sue, the court may not order a full refund; even if it orders a full refund, the woman may not fulfill it: currently, more than 10,000 people have been executed for breach of trust due to disputes over betrothal gifts. After the tragedy, the two perpetrators will also pay a heavy price for their actions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Betrothal gifts are something with inherent contradictions: those who can afford the betrothal gifts often do not need to pay a betrothal gift when they get married; on the contrary, only families that cannot afford a betrothal gift or have a difficult time need to pay a betrothal gift when they get married. Moreover, it is a high-priced betrothal gift. In order to afford the betrothal gift, such families often have to live frugally, borrow here and there, and even take out loan sharks. If the latter encounters the &quot;get rich from divorce&quot; scheme in order to defraud the bride price, it will be difficult to accept it, and they may resort to extreme measures, causing irreparable consequences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When facing disputes over betrothal gifts, you should resolve them through reasonable and legal means and safeguard your rights and interests in accordance with the law. However, while pondering the aforementioned tragedy, it is also necessary to reflect on the legal characterization of bride price. The judiciary cannot encourage the &quot;get rich from divorce&quot; routine. When only money belongs to money and property belongs to property, marriage can belong to marriage. If marriage becomes a tool for wealth redistribution, it will inspire and encourage the evil of human nature, which will not only harm marriage, but also property, and cause various undesirable things. Tragedy will happen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[山西永聚煤业发生火灾，已致11人遇难]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260696]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:25:06&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Yongju Coal Industry Joint Construction in Lishi District, Luliang City, Shanxi Province A fire broke out in the building around 6:50 a.m. today (16th). As of press time, 11 people have been confirmed dead, and the specific casualties are still being counted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the situation at the scene, the burning building has 4 floors. A total of 63 people have been evacuated so far, 51 of whom were sent to Luliang First People&#39;s Hospital for treatment. The rescue is still in progress and the cause of the fire is under investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[黑猩猩没有“祖母假说”模式？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260599]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When talking about chimpanzees, our close relatives, we cannot fail to mention British biologists, animal behaviorists and famous animal conservationists. Jane Goodall is a person who studied chimpanzees, but the “grandmother hypothesis” in this article is not based on Goodall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The documentary film &quot;The Legendary Life of Jane Goodall&quot; shot by the BBC and Goodall&#39;s book &quot;The Book of Hope: Jane Goodall on Human Survival, Future and Action&quot; give people a deeper understanding of Learn about chimpanzees and how they live like humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During his 38 years of living with chimpanzees, Goodall discovered that chimpanzees can use tools (putting plant stems into ant nests to detect, using tree sticks to reach into the water to retrieve food), and they can also Making tools (removing leaves from plant stems) breaks the long-held belief that only humans can make tools. At the same time, chimpanzees will also form teams to hunt other small mammals, and wars will occur between different groups of chimpanzees, and weapons will be used in the battles. There are also some chimpanzees that attack and kill their own kind, sometimes just for fun. Chimpanzee society also has a strict hierarchical system. Each chimpanzee has its own status in society. Their overt and covert fights for social status are no less than that of humans. These findings also break the previous belief that war and cannibalism are uniquely human behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in addition to Goodall, other researchers have studied chimpanzees and found that chimpanzees also have a &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model similar to humans, but this model in chimpanzees is much weaker. The &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; means that healthy and surviving grandmothers and grandfathers can help take care of their grandchildren, increase their survival rate, and thus help their children have more children. This health effect, in turn, ensures the inheritance of your grandmother’s longevity genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Researchers from the University of California, Santa Barbara, compared three groups of chimpanzees, hunter-gatherers, and horticultural producers and found that people’s production contributions in old age also exist, and are far greater. Higher than chimpanzees. Chimpanzees can have a 20% food or material surplus in their gathering and production capacity at age 30, 7% at age 40, and only 2% at age 50. But hunter-gatherers have a production surplus of 66% at age 30, 45% at age 40, and 24% at age 50. A horticultural producer&#39;s production surplus is 64% at age 30, 40% at age 40, and 21% at age 50. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From this comparison, we can know that after chimpanzees enter old age, their production capacity drops significantly, and their ability to help their families and grandchildren also drops off a cliff. Therefore, even if chimpanzees have the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model, its effect is limited. Not big. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, a new study completely rejects the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model in chimpanzees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A team composed of research institutions such as Arizona State University in the United States, the University of California, Los Angeles, and the Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology in Germany studied the Ngo in Kibale National Park in western Uganda. A 20-year study of the wild chimpanzee community in Ngogo found that female chimpanzees in the community will survive menopause and childbirth, but they will not help their daughters raise grandchildren when they enter old age, nor will they live in nearby. Therefore, chimpanzees do not have a social system supported by grandparents, that is, there is no &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model. But Ngogo&#39;s female chimpanzees still live beyond their reproductive years and beyond, even to old age alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no survival problem in old age for chimpanzees in captivity because humans will provide them with good food, nutrition and medical care. However, chimpanzees in the wild will not be so lucky. Survival mode is more difficult. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To study the lifestyle and survival patterns of chimpanzees in the wild, researchers from the joint research team studied 185 female chimpanzees from group statistics collected from 1995 to 2016. Mortality and fertility rates, the proportion of time the observed female chimpanzees spent in sterilization as adults was calculated, and hormone levels were measured in urine samples from 66 female chimpanzees. The female chimpanzees varied in reproductive and sterilization status, survival and age, ranging from 14 to 67 years old. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This research process was very arduous, lasting decades and thousands of hours of fieldwork in Ngogo before collecting chimpanzee urine samples to study menopausal hormone levels. . Hormone studies in chimpanzee urine are similar to those in humans, monitoring changes in levels of follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) and luteinizing hormone (LH), as well as ovarian steroid hormones including estrogen and progesterone. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These hormonal changes can determine whether chimpanzees have entered menopause. The estrogen levels of human menopausal women are below 100pmol/L, and the progesterone levels are below 2.2nmol/L. By comparing them with female chimpanzees, we can know whether they are menopausal and have entered menopause (sterilization state). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The researchers found that, like other groups of chimpanzees and humans, the chimpanzees they studied lost fertility after age 30 and became infertile after age 50. Meanwhile, some data collected on hormone levels in chimpanzees show that menopause in Ngogo female chimpanzees is similar to that in humans, starting around age 50. Female chimpanzees reach adulthood at the age of 14, and spend about one-fifth of their adult life in the sterilization period, which is about half of the sterilization period of humans. That is, the old age of chimpanzees after entering menopause is only half of that of humans. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Menopause for chimpanzees means the beginning of old age, but Ngogo female chimpanzees can live over 50 years old even if they do not take care of their grandchildren and do not live with their children. Chimpanzees are prone to death from diseases originating from humans and have little natural immunity to these diseases, so living over 50 years is considered a long life, and living to 67 years is considered a long life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can Ngogo&#39;s chimpanzees survive into old age without the &quot;grandmother hypothesis&quot; model? The answer suggested by the study is that their post-neuter lifespan may be a temporary response to extremely favorable ecological conditions, as the group enjoys a stable and abundant food supply and they are isolated from human-induced stress. Survive longer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, some researchers such as primatologist Susan Alberts of Duke University in the United States doubt this result because not all chimpanzees will go through menopause. Alberts believes that in most chimpanzee populations outside the Ngogo group, adult females live to be around 30 years old because they are stressed by predators, disease or other factors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Alberts admitted that the study&#39;s results were so solid that she couldn&#39;t refute them. But she believes the next step should be to conduct similar long-term studies in larger populations of wild chimpanzees to determine whether Ngogo chimpanzees are unique in that they survive longer beyond their reproductive years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[螺蛳粉疯狂布局线下门店，能否成为下一个兰州拉面？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260351]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since this year, snail noodle restaurant stores have grown rapidly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Xiao Lu, a netizen who lives in Guangzhou, said that several snail noodle stores have recently opened in the business district near her home, many of which are chain stores of a certain snail noodle brand. ——This has aroused the curiosity of many netizens: Has snail noodles also begun to focus on offline stores? &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;With the characteristics of &quot;smells bad, tastes delicious, and is very popular&quot;, snail noodles have become a popular Internet celebrity food in just a few years. The sales volume of the channel remains high. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, compared with its popularity online, the offline development of snail noodles has obvious shortcomings. What kind of distinction does the online and offline development of snail noodles show? How can snail noodles achieve offline breakthrough? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/pdJbFUnNE17d3MkdvHFhyInXFEMsFNYPnJFwQpXt.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258356&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Hot online sales&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Snail noodles originated from the Liuzhou Night Market in the 1970s. It gradually became popular in the 1980s, but it was mainly limited to the local area, and then slowly spread to all of Guangxi and the neighboring Guangdong Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2012, &quot;A Bite of China&quot; brought snail fans more into the public eye, but for people outside the Guangdong and Guangxi regions, it is still only As the name suggests, Luosifeng’s offline stores have not expanded too much to other provinces, and there are no online sales channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2014, Liuzhou’s first prepackaged snail noodle company was registered, and industrially produced bagged snail noodle appeared. At the beginning of 2015, the Liuzhou Municipal Government proposed the development concept of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; of Liuzhou&#39;s snail noodles, and determined the road for Liuzhou&#39;s snail noodles industry to be packaged and industrialized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2016 is the first year of live broadcasting. Luosi fans have keenly grasped the trend of the times and jumped on the &quot;Internet +&quot; short video and live broadcast express. The characteristics of &quot;smellful and smelly&quot; are quite contagious and quickly spread out of the circle through online channels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2019, the industry output value of Liuzhou&#39;s bagged snail noodles exceeded 6 billion yuan. The impact of the epidemic, the rise of the &quot;stay-at-home economy&quot;, and the booming live-streaming of goods have boosted the online popularity of snail noodles. In 2020, the annual output value of bagged snail noodles exceeded 10 billion. In 2022, the sales revenue of the entire industry chain of Liuzhou snail noodles will be 60.07 billion yuan, and the sales revenue of bagged snail noodles will be 18.18 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Naturally, the online sales of snail noodles account for half of the total. According to iiMedia Research’s research data, among the channels through which Chinese snail noodle consumers purchase products, online shopping malls rank first with a proportion of 78.70%. Other data show that in 2022, 113 million snail noodle packages were sent through express delivery channels, becoming the first single product in Guangxi with an annual delivery volume exceeding 100 million. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The popularity of snail noodles online is not only due to its close integration with &quot;Internet +&quot;, but also because it fits the &quot;fast food life&quot; of this generation of young people. The characteristics of the food require that the food should not only be convenient and efficient, but also sufficient and delicious. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Other instant noodles have few ingredients. Snail noodles are rich in ingredients, including yuba, pickled bamboo shoots, pickled beans, fungus, peanuts, dried radish and other common accessories. Bao snail rice noodles have everything, and they are more attractive to young people’s stomachs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/qQaycB5JHwjp4VIJdLJ2rQsIUXTRJxhCjzFbLsgY.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258357&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;Offline stores have shortcomings&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, compared with the popularity of online stores, offline stores of snail noodles have obvious shortcomings. plate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the one hand, there are now more than 40,000 offline stores of snail noodles. Compared with the approximately 500,000 offline stores of Lanzhou Ramen, It&#39;s like a small witch can see a big witch. Not to mention, the annual sales of Lanzhou Ramen are roughly estimated to exceed 400 billion yuan, which is several times that of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, relevant data shows that the average offline catering chain rate of snail noodles is only 15%, compared with 45% for tea drinks. Coffee is 55%, which shows that there is no strong enough brand of snail noodles to go offline, and the risk of &quot;having a category but not a brand&quot; has intensified. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Not only that, there are also some worrying aspects regarding the existing offline stores of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;First, the offline stores of snail noodles are mainly concentrated in Guangxi and Guangdong, and the national penetration rate is still relatively low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For example, iiMedia Consulting data shows that from 2020 to February 2023, most of the new snail noodle companies are located in Guangdong and Guangxi, and the proportion of snail noodle companies in Guangxi is as high as 21.63% and 21.21% of snail noodle companies are located in Guangdong Province. This is much weaker than the national radiation intensity of Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian snacks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, due to the low chain rate, many offline snail noodle stores are small &quot;mom-and-pop&quot;-style workshops with varying tastes and quality, and individual stores are hygienic. The worrying situation has lowered consumers’ trust in offline stores of snail noodles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some time ago, rumors spread widely that &quot;there were many mice jumping up and down in the back kitchen of a snail noodle shop in Chongqing&quot;. Although the Municipal Supervision Bureau of Jiulongpo District, Chongqing made a report stating that law enforcement officers did an on-site inspection and found no traces of rats in the snail noodle shop; the video was taken in March this year, because the decoration of the shop next door damaged the flue outlet of the shop, causing rats to enter After discovering the situation in the back kitchen, the person in charge of the store immediately carried out disinfection and repairs and rectifications in the store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Such rumors have done great harm to the offline stores of Luosi Fen, and also reflect the public&#39;s concerns about food safety issues. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thirdly, offline snail noodles stores only offer a single variety of food, and relying solely on snail noodles will limit the development of offline stores. For example, Lanzhou Ramen Shop not only offers ramen noodles, but also Northwest-style pasta products such as rice bowls, steamed buns, and cold noodles; Shaxian snacks include mixed noodles, steamed dumplings, flat dishes, duck leg rice, and other choices. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/eoTDhBOBwFpinLd8rjTPIIrBC0BQjM65vIjZKfWF.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258355&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; >;&lt;strong>;The snail noodles&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;stand out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Of course, compared with the offline stores of Lanzhou Ramen and Shaxian Snacks, Sloan noodles are blooming everywhere, and offline stores of snail noodles still have broad room for expansion, but this does not mean that snail noodles should &quot;underestimate themselves&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In fact, compared with Lanzhou Ramen, the development route of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; of snail noodles is earlier and more mature. There are many ramen noodle restaurants in Lanzhou, but they are also faced with the embarrassment of &quot;having categories but not brands&quot;. This is a shortcoming that Lanzhou ramen is now making great efforts to make up for. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;To successfully break through, snail powder offline stores must, on the one hand, give full play to the advantages of &quot;industrialization, standardization, branding, and scale&quot; and transform the current few stores into The snail noodle brand continues to grow bigger and stronger, and the chain layout is accelerated. It is necessary to establish both the category and the brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Secondly, efforts should be made to industrialize the supply chain and build a professional, platform-based supply chain service provider to fill the gap in the snail noodle supply chain business. Blank, so that even small workshop-style snail noodle stores can obtain stable quality snail noodle raw materials, so that consumers can taste snail noodle with stable taste and stabilize the reputation of offline snail noodle stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Third, as a regional delicacy, if snail noodles want to conquer the stomachs of people across the country, in addition to making authentic snail noodles, we also need to enrich the line. The gourmet food category in the lower store. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;One ​​way is to focus on snail noodles but also sell other local delicacies from Liuzhou and even Guangxi to enrich consumers&#39; choice space, such as some from Liuzhou Local delicacies, such as Yong Tau Foo Pao, Niu Xianzi, Yun Pian Cake, Miao Sour Pork, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another way is to combine it with local cuisine and move toward integration, launching cross-category meals, stir-fries, soups, etc. This kind of integration poses a very big challenge to the management of chain brands, which must not only ensure standardization, but also successfully &quot;do as the Romans do.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although snail noodles have fully opened up the online space, if snail noodles want to continue to break through the upper limit of the industry, they must walk both online and offline. Luosifen offline stores are accelerating the layout. Whether it can create miracles like online stores is worth waiting to see. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么年轻人不愿意生孩子？社会学家山田昌弘谈日本低生育困境]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260643]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6Ignwi5oPp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1039&quot; height=&quot;1559&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/taEK4maI9T2bb8Z7gCUaLE0BNS59Ew6I gnwi5oPp. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258346&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Japanese sociologist Yamada Masahiro, professor at Chuo University, specializes in family sociology and emotional society Xuexue, etc., are the authors of &quot;Society with a Few Births&quot;, &quot;The Era of Marriage&quot;, &quot;The Low-Birth Trap&quot;, etc. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Masahiro Yamada, a professor at Chuo University in Japan, has been deeply involved in the field of family sociology for many years. Before high school, he once wanted to be a mathematician, but &quot;because I don&#39;t have a family of my own, I decided to explore what family love is&quot; and since then entered the &quot;world of studying messy families.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When teaching in school, he used a lot of family materials to tell the origin, current situation and whereabouts of modern Japanese families. The seminars he held with students were on cutting-edge topics and discussed issues such as: To what extent do people need to &quot;rent friends&quot; when they are lonely? Does &quot;cohabiting partnership marriage&quot; (note: only cohabitation without marriage) explore another possibility beyond the current marriage system? There are more and more single young people in Japan. Where can their emotional needs for intimacy be met? He finally found some answers in cabaret clubs (note: places that provide singing and dancing performances), real or virtual idols, and pets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the book &quot;The Low Fertility Trap&quot;, Masahiro Yamada tries to answer a question: Why are young people in Japan reluctant to have children in recent years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Low fertility rate has always been a dark cloud lingering over Japanese society. Since 1989, Japan&#39;s fertility rate has continued to be sluggish, with the total fertility rate remaining below 1.6 for more than 30 years. In 2022, it reached a historical low of 1.26. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;532&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/15ki05kPI4oa4sovRe8QOk5LByuBCKIbPNPX7uAi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258344&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Since 1989, Japan&#39;s fertility rate has continued to be sluggish, with the total fertility rate below 1.6 for more than 30 years, and it reached a historical low of 1.26 in 2022 . The picture shows a still from the Japanese drama &quot;Obstetrician Kotori&quot;. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Information map/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past thirty years, Japanese society has tried to solve this &quot;stubborn disease&quot;, but with little success. Yamada Masahiro was a member of the Committee on Countermeasures against Birthrate Reduction. Once, a committee member proposed holding a publicity campaign titled &quot;Parenting is Wonderful&quot; to increase the public&#39;s enthusiasm for childbirth. &quot;Many insightful people and policy leaders in Japanese society have ignored for a long time two important factors directly related to the cause of Japan&#39;s declining birthrate, namely &#39;non-marriage&#39; and &#39;the widening gap in the economic level of young people&#39; .&quot; Yamada believes, &quot;For the majority of people who &#39;want to have children but do not have the conditions, so they do not have children&#39;, it is meaningless to carry out such publicity activities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yamada Masahiro&#39;s view , young people’s desire to have children is linked to the overall economic status of society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1955, the Japanese economy entered a period of rapid growth. The prosperous economic environment gave rise to young people&#39;s positive expectations for the future. They tended to believe that through personal efforts, they could join the &quot;middle class&quot; and live a better life than their parents. A better, richer life. &quot;From World War II to about 1980, people did not think about the great risks in their economic life after marriage. At that time, men could count on becoming full-time employees, and their income would be based on the &#39;seniority system&#39; (note: wages will vary according to merit). (increasing with age and length of service).&quot; In Yamada Masahiro&#39;s view, people of that generation firmly believed that their children would grow up in a better environment than themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1980s, the situation reversed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Entering the Heisei Era (Note: January 8, 1989), Japan&#39;s economic structure was adjusted, and a large number of informal employees (referring to fixed-term employees, part-time employees, dispatched employees, etc.) appeared. Social gaps have arisen in terms of employment, which in turn has led to gaps between the rich and poor families and the educational environment of their children, and the polarization of society has further developed.&quot; Masahiro Yamada said in an interview with Japanese media, &quot;For most informal employees, regardless of whether No matter how hard I try, I can&#39;t earn the income that will allow me to live a prosperous life in the future, nor can I get married and start a family. In other words, my future has become hopeless.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yamada observed, The Japanese pay more attention to the significance of marriage from an economic perspective and will make a careful risk assessment before making a decision to get married. The evaluation often starts from two perspectives: first, whether the standard of living after marriage will be better than before marriage, or at least not worse; second, whether after marriage, the child can create a better growth environment than oneself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Behind this view on marriage and childbearing are the unique values ​​of modern Japanese society: the hope to avoid risks in future life. The Japanese regard maintaining a middle-class living standard as their highest goal and believe that in life design, The series of issues of &#39;men and women dating&#39;, &#39;marriage&#39;, &#39;childbirth&#39;, &#39;child rearing&#39; and &#39;children&#39;s education&#39; are not single and separated, but are intertwined.&quot; Yamada Masahiro in the paper &quot;East Asian Characteristics of the Declining Birth Rate Problem&quot; wrote. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This awareness of risk also extends to the relationship stage. Yamada found that in Japan, many young people are even losing their desire to fall in love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;NHK Broadcasting Culture Research Institute once conducted a survey of Japanese middle and high school students and found that the proportions of middle and high school students who &quot;have a crush&quot; were 41% and 54% respectively in 1982. In 2012, this figure dropped sharply to 25% and 31%. In 2014, the Japanese Cabinet Office conducted a survey on young people and found that more than one-third of the respondents preferred to spend time on work and study, and 46.2% felt that &quot;love is troublesome.&quot; In Yamada Masahiro’s view, “trouble” may mean “not cost-effective”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the 1990s, when the phenomenon of declining birthrate first appeared in Japanese society, demographers held a mainstream view: young people just postponed marriage to enjoy single life, and one day they would get married. . Masahiro Yamada believes that such a logical basis may not be established. Over the past few decades, as Japanese society has gradually developed into a &quot;high-consumption society&quot;, the anxiety and pressure of childcare has also hit young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/sZwSWsI8dblFzL7uTjuuPTz6YmJTOauI6ffsygCC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258345&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In December 2022, on the streets of Tokyo, Japan, a couple took wedding photos on the streets hung with Christmas lights. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China Map/Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2015, Japan’s National Institute of Social Security and Population Issues conducted a survey on 30 -Why married women in the 34-year-old age group fail to have the expected number of children? 81.1% of the survey respondents believe that the reason is that &quot;the raising and education of children is too expensive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Yamada’s view, modern society’s expectations for the function of marriage and childbearing are different from pre-modern society. In a society centered on agricultural production, childbirth means supplementing the labor force. Parents place expectations on their children to inherit the family business and take care of their parents later in life. Children are a kind of &quot;productive property.&quot; But after the 1950s, Japan began to &quot;nuclear family&quot; with reference to the family system in Europe and the United States. A couple and their unmarried children became the basic family unit. In modern society, raising children requires a large amount of childcare money, and children have therefore become &quot;consumable property.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The significance of children as a labor force no longer exists, and when the nuclear family becomes a principle, it is difficult to expect children to provide support and care in their old age. In addition, parents who can let their children inherit the family business It has also become less.&quot; Yamada Masahiro wrote in &quot;The Low Birth Trap&quot; that unlike European and American parents who enjoy the joy and fun of parenting itself, many times, East Asian parents care about whether to have a &quot;high-value&quot; child—— In the social evaluation system established by external factors such as academic qualifications and work, whether children can take the top spot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yamada believes that East Asian parents often have a &quot;protective feeling&quot; for their children and do not want their children to &quot;live a hard life&quot;. It is also part of the value of parents for children to receive help from their parents when they receive higher education and even become adults. . As a result, the age of responsibility of East Asian parents for their children has been extended indefinitely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In October 2023, Japanese sociologist Masahiro Yamada accepted a written interview with a reporter from Southern Weekend. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;East Asian parents take it for granted that they spend money on their children&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;China&#39;s total fertility rate fell to 1.09 in 2022, which is lower than Japan&#39;s 1.26 and higher than South Korea&#39;s 0.78. In 2022, the total fertility rate of the three East Asian countries dropped to historical lows. You have done a lot of research on fertility wishes in Japan. Why are young people reluctant to have children? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在东亚（中日韩），结婚和育儿首先会从经济角度进行考虑。人们在养育孩子时，会想把超出自己父母培养自己的钱花在自己的孩子身上。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前（日本是50年前，中韩是30年前），大多数年轻人的父母的生活，以及年轻人自己的成长生活都处于相对贫穷的水平。又由于社会整体处于经济增长期，年轻人未来收入的增加是可以预期的。所以，在那个时候，把超出自己父母培养自己的钱花在自己的孩子身上会更容易，实际上也确实很容易。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，日本从30年前开始，中韩从10年前开始，上一世代被父母花了更多金钱养育的孩子，如今成了需要花钱养育自己孩子的人。这些年轻人，往往拥有比自己更富裕的父母。中国则由于独生子女多，这一代独生子女的花费估计会是日韩的两倍以上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在经济增长趋缓的情况下，想要在未来出生的孩子身上花费更多的钱，是非常困难的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;东亚社会家庭现代化的过程，是模仿学习欧美核心家庭的过程，同样的社会模型，为何东亚国家现阶段面对的生育困境比欧美社会更加剧烈？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;东亚国家模仿的只是核心家庭的模式，但因为不同的社会环境和传统，这些模式得到的反馈自然也不同。例如，东亚的父母更多地认为给孩子花钱是理所当然的，也能带来很多情绪价值；比起夫妻之爱，更相信亲子之爱。这也导致如果不打算生孩子的话，结婚的必要性就大幅下降了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧美认为养育孩子到成年为止，而东亚各国则认为负担孩子的高等教育费用是理所当然的。相比之下，东亚国家的父母要承担更多的育儿责任，甚至在孩子成年后，也经常需要帮助解决孩子遇到的各种问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;过去几年，中国政府出台了一些鼓励生育的政策，比如三孩政策、多地提出建立育儿补贴制度等。你在《低生育陷阱》里说，日本政府没能赶上干预低生育的最好时机，日本的少子化政策因此失败了。日本经验能给其他国家带来哪些教训和启示？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;必须考虑减轻孩子的教育费负担。有四分之一的年轻人对未来感到不安，是日本少子化的主要原因。要采取让年轻人不会对未来过不上富裕生活而感到不安的措施。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;要将我们的社会改造成一个无论哪个年轻人都有希望将来能够不让自己的孩子受苦的社会。即，建立一个工作可以重新再来、对双职工家庭同样友好，以及万一出了问题也可以通过社会保障重新自立的社会。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;能否结合你自己和你的上一代、下一代的经历，谈谈日本年轻人婚育处境和观念的变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;观念本身并没有太大的变化。如果有过上相对好的生活的预期，那就自然会结婚生子。区别可能在于，上一代的人会认为，仅靠丈夫的收入就能过上富裕的生活（大概30年前）。即便在今天，那些能够达到预期的将近四分之三的年轻人也都已经结婚生子，而剩下四分之一的年轻人之所以不选择结婚生子，大多也是因为自身收入不稳定，以及无法预期在结婚生子后能过上相对好的生活。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;婚育事关体面？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提出了一个观点：等待适合自己的对象出现然后结婚，这种从前被普遍接受的想法，如今很难把人领入婚姻。今天的年轻人如果想结婚，需要参加“婚活”（注：寻求结婚对象的各种活动，由山田昌弘首次提出），为何会有这样的变化？难道不参加婚活，就无法结婚了吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为让年轻人可以自然相互邂逅的场所变少了。不说男性，就连女性所谓的“即便自己不主动，男性也会主动搭讪”的状况都变少了。不得不由社区或者企业提供一些机会，让年轻男女可以有更多的接触。如果想要找到结婚对象，还是应该积极采取行动。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“婚活”在中国叫做相亲。对于中国1970、1980年代出生的人来说，自由恋爱结婚在他们年轻时是普遍的婚恋观，但在如今的年轻人中，门当户对的观念正在被重提。日本社会是否有类似的婚姻观念变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在日本，“先恋爱后结婚”的意识并没有改变。年轻人对恋爱结婚的憧憬和讨厌父母干涉自由恋爱的意识还是比较强烈的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然没有那么在意对象的家庭背景，但婚后的经济生活，即婚后夫妻两人的整体家庭收入是很重要的参考因素。现在的年轻人“中流”意识十分强烈，他们大多觉得在父母身边时处于一种中流的生活状态，因而非常不希望婚后生活会从中流跌落，这也是习惯“规避风险”和“重视体面”的日本社会特征的反映。不过日本没有像中国那样，结婚时男方家庭需要出很多钱的习俗。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你似乎非常强调在经济层面上分析婚姻、生育的动机。你提到，在欧美社会，人们将构建家庭（结婚、生子）与经济状况联系在一起的想法并不强烈，但在东亚社会不是，为何东亚社会如此强调这两者之间的关联性？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;东亚人更看重体面，也就是中文里的“面子”。人们不想让别人看到自己过着不幸福的婚姻生活，或有着较差的育儿水平。过着贫穷的生活会有很强的耻辱意识。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在欧美，夫妻之间的爱情才是幸福的表现，生活贫穷也可以幸福的意识很普及；而在东亚社会里，即使没有夫妻间的爱情，过着富裕的生活也可能是很幸福的，这种意识十分强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有一种观点认为，现代家庭“男主外，女主内”的分工意味着女性要为育儿付出更多的时间和精力，你怎样看待这个现实问题？日本社会对此有何对策？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;女性拥有一定的收入并持续工作，正在逐渐成为富裕家庭生活的前提。既然能够做到“男主外，女主内”的高收入男性人数有限，那么为了在富裕的生活条件下养育孩子，女性外出工作和男性参与家务就变得十分必要了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在日本，通过普及产假和完善幼儿园的建设，这一理想正逐渐变得现实起来。不过日本政府对女性工作与育儿的“两立支援”也显然还远远不够，后续仍需要继续完善工作环境，消除性别歧视，并让更多的女性从事有意义的工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;培养“高价值”的孩子，一种扭曲的期待&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到，日本年轻人抱有一种“不能让孩子受苦”的想法，这种想法在中国年轻人当中也存在，为什么年轻人会对哺育下一代产生如此强烈的责任意识？ “受苦”的意涵是否随着时代的发展也在发生变化？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在东亚社会里，让子女接受比自己更好的教育，找到比自己更好的工作，是父母的生活意义所在。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另外，孩子之间的歧视意识也很强，现如今的年轻人会担心自己的贫穷会让孩子受到欺负。孩子们在一起玩耍的时候，有时也会需求类似Switch游戏机这样的外部硬件。如果不买这些东西，会不会让孩子感到痛苦？年轻父母的这种想法正越来越强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以前只要父母能够陪在孩子身边就足够了，但现在越来越多的父母觉得，不能在孩子身上花费足够的金钱会很难受。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在中国，未婚适龄男女可能会遭到父母和长辈的催婚，被称为光棍、剩女，带有一定贬义。日本有类似情况吗？你如何理解这种现象？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;单身=不受欢迎，这一等式会让人间接联想到，没进入婚姻是不是因为男性收入低，或者是不是因为女性的容貌有问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在日本，因为未婚率高得非常明显，想结婚却做不到的人，和能做到但不想结婚的人都混杂在一起，因而单纯对于未婚者的贬低并不常见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样由于未婚率非常高，来自父母的压力已经要比以前小很多了。很多父母会认为，与其让孩子和收入低的人结婚，然后过上不太理想的贫困生活，还不如独身在家。在日本，越来越多的父母认为，与其被奇怪的结婚对象缠住，还不如让孩子保持单身。继承家业的意识在日本正逐渐淡薄（现在70岁以上的人仍然有很强烈的这种意识）。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到，在前现代社会，子女是一种“生产性财产”，进入现代社会则变为“消费性财产”，需要投入较高的育儿金，拥有一个“高价值感”的孩子成为育儿行为追求的价值，而高价值感由孩子的学历、工作的光鲜程度等因素决定。为什么父母对育儿会有这样的期待？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;孩子的地位=父母的地位，东亚文化圈的这种关乎面子或虚荣心的意识很强烈。从感情上看，这源于父母希望子女在经济上能过着无忧无虑的生活。虽然初心是好的，但随着体面意识带来的比较心理，培养高价值的孩子也就成了一种扭曲的期待。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;欧美的传统则有很大的不同，孩子成年后不再在经济上依赖父母，有着较强的自我责任意识。对于父母来说，孩子在养育过程中很可爱，长大后则只期待情绪交流的存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;看上去，育儿正在逐渐演化成一种竞争。日本有没有“学区房”“鸡娃”现象？高度竞争的社会是否会对生育率产生影响？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;日本的就业市场对学历的要求则相对比较宽松，高中毕业和大学毕业的工资差距在世界上也算小的。也就是说，即使是高中毕业或专科毕业，也有可能过上相对好的生活。父母也没必要那么热心，尤其是那些自己本身也只是高中毕业的父母。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;年轻人规避风险的倾向在不断加强&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;年轻人结婚意愿消退的一个可能的原因是，越来越多人意识到婚姻是一种契约关系，而契约有破裂风险。为何越来越多年轻人倾向于对结婚这件事做风险评估？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对年轻人来说，将来能否过上中流生活是他们非常关心的事情。在日本，1990年以前，大多数年轻人都可以期待依靠“年功序列制度”过上工资每年都增长的生活，但随着全球化的发展，经济风险越来越大，如今的年轻人已经不能再乐观地认为“将来总会有办法的”。出于这个原因，年轻人规避风险的倾向在不断加强。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果从一开始就过着相对贫穷的生活，那么一般都不会觉得有什么风险存在，但现在的很多年轻人在未成年时期过着相当充实且富裕的生活。不想放弃这种生活的意识会很强烈。特别是作为独生子女的这一代中国年轻人，这种意识应该会更加强烈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你提到一个现象：如今的年轻人甚至连恋爱的欲望都在消退。韩国有“三弃”（放弃爱情、婚姻、生育），日本有“草食男”（恋爱被动、不积极），中国也有一些年轻人觉得恋爱是件麻烦事，为何年轻人会丧失恋爱的欲望？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为现代的年轻人觉得，恋爱感情总是会“降温”的。在欧美，“与相爱的人在一起”就是人生的意义。但是，在东亚各国，这种想法并不普及。在不少人看来，谈恋爱其实就是寻找结婚对象的一种过程，因此他们也认为，和明知道不能结婚的人交往，是在浪费时间和金钱。越来越多的人认为，恋爱本身就是一种需要顾虑别人的不快乐的事。因为色情行业的扩大，尤其在日本，谈恋爱的性价值也降低了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;许多人通过虚拟关系满足恋爱需求，比如时下流行的AI男女友，或是“嗑CP”，在围观他人恋爱的过程中获得情感满足。你怎么理解这些现象？也有人质疑，通过数据计算、金钱付出而获得情感满足，削弱了爱情的复杂性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;虽然我认为这是逃避的一种形式，但对现在的年轻人来说，有越来越多的人认为这是比现实恋爱还要愉快的交流时间。如果现实恋爱的满足度下降了，那虚拟恋爱的价值就会上升。也许现在已经不能说现实中的满足就更优越了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1997年你就命名了日本社会的“单身寄生族”现象，近年，中国社会也出现了“全职儿女”，即儿女们放弃工作，回家承担家务、给父母养老，生活开支由父母负担，部分全职儿女还会得到父母开的工资。你似乎有意强调“单身寄生族”和婚育意愿的关联，能否再展开谈谈？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在遇到自己理想的结婚对象之前，在父母身边过着富裕的生活，这种“等待”很可能是没有尽头的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在欧美，因为成年后必须脱离父母自立，所以两个年轻人凑一起过日子会比较有利。但是在东亚国家，脱离父母独立，一般意味着孩子能在外面过上比待在父母家里更好的生活。在遇到能一起过上更好生活的结婚对象之前，先在父母家里“等待”也没什么关系，甚至父母也如此期待着。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，一直等不到理想的人出现，而就这样慢慢老去的“前”年轻人层出不穷，在日本，人到中年也依然与父母同居的未婚者正在不断增加。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;人们通常认为，年轻人拥有无限可能，正是积极试错的年龄段。但你却提出“社会为什么对年轻人冷酷无情”的疑问，为什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;山田昌弘：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;如果能像欧美那样，大多数孩子在成年后就离开父母自立，那么即使在社会中冒险失败，重新来过也确实不是什么难事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但是，在东亚各国，年轻人会拿自己和父母做比较，越来越多的年轻人认为达不到父母的水平就是失败。在父母的关照下过着富裕生活的人更是如此。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，在日本，很多年轻人认为就业和结婚是不能重新来过的，这也是很重要的影响因素之一。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 10:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贫困生攒钱看演唱会惹争议，该不该限制助学对象高消费？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[习近平同美国总统拜登举行中美元首会晤]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260688]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:43:26&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011765296853&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;Exclusive video丨Xi Jinping and US President Biden held the China-US Presidential Meeting.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/d9dca36avodtranscq1251434507/ 79e1b7263270835011765296853/sampleSnapshot/sampleSnapshot_10_0.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b726327083501176 5296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot; 360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/79e1b7263270835011765296853/8IaqSQsxTcYA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Local time 11 On March 15, President Xi Jinping held a China-US Presidential Meeting with US President Joe Biden at Philori Estate in San Francisco, USA. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;习近平指出，我和总统先生上次会面是在巴厘岛，已经过去1年了。 A lot has happened in the past year. The world has emerged from the COVID-19 pandemic, but the huge impact of the epidemic remains. The world economy has begun to recover, but it lacks momentum, industrial and supply chains are disrupted, and protectionism is on the rise. These problems are very prominent. As the most important bilateral relationship in the world, China-U.S. relations must be thought and planned against the backdrop of the accelerating changes in the world over the past century, so as to bring benefits to the people of both countries and demonstrate responsibility for human progress. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that over the past 50 years, Sino-US relations have never been smooth sailing. There will always be problems of one kind or another, and they will always move forward amid twists and turns. It is impossible for such two big countries not to deal with each other. It is unrealistic to try to change each other. No one can bear the consequences of conflict and confrontation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I still have the same view. Great power competition is not the background of this era and cannot solve the problems facing China, the United States and the world. This earth can accommodate China and the United States, and our respective successes are opportunities for each other. China and the United States have different histories, cultures, social systems, and development paths. This is an objective reality. However, as long as both sides adhere to mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation, they can transcend differences and find a way for the two major countries to get along correctly. I firmly believe that the future of Sino-US relations is bright. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The President and I are at the helm of Sino-US relations and bear heavy responsibilities for the people, the world, and history. I look forward to having an in-depth exchange of views and reaching new consensus with Mr. President today on strategic, overall and directional issues related to China-US relations, as well as major issues related to world peace and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[被摘牌的55个中华老字号：停产、换新店、准备重申]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260668]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Ministry of Commerce will review 1,128 time-honored brands in 2023. The picture shows citizens in Suzhou on October 29 At the Golden Autumn Consumer Carnival event for time-honored brands. Pictures and texts have nothing to do with each other. Visual China Pictures&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/14ca44a779.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width =&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/14ca44a779.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258384&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Ministry of Commerce will review 1,128 time-honored brands in 2023. The picture shows citizens attending the Suzhou Time-honored Brands Golden Autumn Consumption Carnival on October 29. Pictures and texts are irrelevant. Visual China Picture&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After being stripped of the &quot;hat&quot; of a time-honored Chinese brand, the inheritor Wu Zhiyong explained to a dozen old customers: Because he missed the time to submit information, he was removed according to regulations, but Wu&#39;s Bacon (brand treasure) Xingshan)&#39;s factories are producing normally and stores are operating normally. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 9, 2023, the Ministry of Commerce disclosed the results of the review of Chinese time-honored brands at a regular press conference. Those that have been operating poorly for a long time have even gone bankrupt, canceled, closed down, or have lost the ownership and use rights of registered trademarks of time-honored brands. 55 brands were removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands; 73 brands with poor operations and declining performance were required to be rectified within 6 months; 1,000 brands with standardized operations and good development were continued to be retained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wujia Bacon is one of the 55 brands. Chinese time-honored brands were first selected by the former Ministry of Domestic Trade, and more than 1,600 were assessed in 1991. In 2006, the Ministry of Commerce re-certified 429 Chinese time-honored brands in the first batch; in 2010, the Ministry of Commerce recognized 699 in the second batch. As of the beginning of 2023, there are 1,128 Chinese time-honored brands across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In January 2023, in order to promote the innovative development of time-honored brands, the Ministry of Commerce and other five departments issued the &quot;Measures for the Administration of the Demonstration Creation of Chinese Time-honored Brands&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Measures&quot;). In this &quot;Measures&quot;, the &quot;Measures&quot; were established The &quot;traffic light&quot; mechanism, that is, the dynamic management mechanism of &quot;in and out&quot;, takes rectification or removal measures for time-honored brands that do not meet the requirements. In February 2023, the Ministry of Commerce publicly stated that the &quot;honor&quot; of China&#39;s time-honored brands is not once and for all, let alone resting on the credit book to &quot;show off seniority&quot; or &quot;rest on one&#39;s laurels.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three months after the &quot;Measures&quot; were issued, the Ministry of Commerce, together with the Ministry of Culture and Tourism and other ministries and commissions, decided to review the existing Chinese time-honored brands and carry out the certification of a new batch of Chinese time-honored brands, so that time-honored brands can &quot;come in and out&quot; . This is the first time that Chinese time-honored brands have been reviewed since they were recognized, but it is not the last time. The &quot;Measures&quot; stipulate that in principle, a new batch of Chinese time-honored brands will be recognized and published every three years. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;55 time-honored brands delisted&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As of this delisting, Wujia Bacon has been a time-honored brand in China for nearly 30 years. In the early 1990s, Wujia Bacon in Linfen City, Shanxi Province was rated as a Chinese time-honored brand by the former Ministry of Domestic Trade. At that time, Wu Zhiyong, who had just grown up, as the fifth generation successor, was learning the ancestral condiment formula and processing technology from the basics. Now he has reached the age where he knows his destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong told Southern Weekend reporters that because he was busy launching a new production line at the time, he did not pay enough attention to the review. At the same time, it took too much time to search and complete historical data, resulting in missing the time to submit materials. Wu Zhiyong speculated that the removal may be due to Article 20 of the &quot;Measures&quot;: Enterprises are bankrupt, liquidated, disbanded, canceled, have their business licenses revoked, or have not carried out business activities for more than three years. They will be removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands and the right to use the Chinese time-honored brand logo and plaque will be recovered. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The company owned by Wujia Bacon is Wujiabaoxing Bacon Products Co., Ltd. in Yaodu District, Linfen City. The company was liquidated in 2017. Wu Zhiyong explained that the company was jointly owned by his father Wu Baoshan and his second uncle. Due to their old age and poor health, and the original bacon processing factory was demolished due to urban expansion in 2014, the two &quot;retired&quot;, and the Wu family bacon business also hiatus for 6 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the 55 brands that have been removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands, many are in a similar situation to Wu’s Bacon. Southern Weekend reporters found out that most of the brand companies that were removed from the directory were canceled, bankrupt, removed from the list, etc., and even seriously violated the law. Some legal representatives of the companies were also listed as dishonest persons subject to execution, and high consumption was restricted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters tried to contact the 55 brands on the removal list, but most of them refused to be interviewed, except for some that could not be contacted. Among the few brands interviewed, the reasons for delisting varied. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The person in charge of Shanxi Yanhu brand told Southern Weekend reporters: &quot;When the last order on the handle is completed, I will never do it again.&quot; The person in charge of Inner Mongolia Dashengkui brand said that the company is still open, but it is not Produced, just to maintain the brand. Anhui Shouchuntang said that it is in the process of changing its store and will wait until a new place is found. The person in charge of Shanxi Mingquanbao said that the company is still open, but it is no longer producing, &quot;because the national standards do not allow the use of current boilers, and production can be resumed after replacing new boilers.&quot; The person in charge of the Shandong Shi Toad brand said that he had no idea about being &quot;kicked out&quot; of a Chinese time-honored brand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a businessman, a Southern Weekend reporter consulted a relevant person from the Circulation Development Department of the Ministry of Commerce. The other party replied: &quot;There are various reasons for being removed. It is not just bankruptcy or no longer operating that will be removed. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In real scenarios, the decline of some Chinese time-honored brands is more intuitive. Beijing Hua Nv Underwear, which was approved by the Ministry of Commerce in 2010 to become a time-honored brand in China, was founded in 1938. It was the first women&#39;s products store in Beijing. It once proposed that Chinese women wear &quot;Hua Nv&quot; underwear. There is no trace of the Chinese lingerie brand that once opened a store on Wangfujing Street. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Linlang Wedding Photography Shop, once located in Shangxiajiu Commercial Street, Guangzhou, was founded in 1947. At that time, it was the largest photography shop in Liwan District where it was located. Now the store has been occupied by sports brands. Granny Chen, who is nearly 80 years old, recalled to Southern Weekend reporters that the previous photo studio was a two-story arcade, which belonged to a high-end consumer brand. She had taken work photos at Linlang Photo Studio in the 1970s, but never wedding photos. One room is used for taking photos, and the outside is used as the lobby. It is relatively high-end and there are quite a lot of people.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On the eve of the Double Ninth Festival in 2023, citizens and tourists queue up to buy Double Ninth Cake from time-honored brands in Shanghai. According to data from the Ministry of Commerce, the operating income of time-honored enterprises will exceed 1.2 trillion yuan in 2022. Visual China Map &quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ea6f938e95.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot; //images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/15/ea6f938e95.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258385&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the eve of the Double Ninth Festival in 2023, citizens and tourists lined up to buy Double Ninth Cake from a time-honored brand in Shanghai. According to data from the Ministry of Commerce, the operating income of time-honored enterprises will exceed 1.2 trillion yuan in 2022. Visual China Map&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Plans to return to the time-honored brand list&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong regrets being removed from the time-honored brand list but is not discouraged: “We have learned from the experience and cannot let the brand stay on the family business model. We are confident that the next application (for Chinese time-honored brands) will be successful.&quot; According to the &quot;Measures&quot;, those who have been removed from the list of Chinese time-honored brands are not allowed to apply again within two application cycles from the date of the decision.也就是说，直到2032年，吴志勇才能再次申报。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Wu’s bacon business does not seem to be affected. The Chinese Time-honored Brand plaque awarded by the Commerce Department has not yet been notified of its withdrawal. The packaging bags with the &quot;Chinese Time-honored Brand&quot; logo can no longer be used, and there are not many goods left. , the loss is not big. At the end of 2020, Wu Zhiyong and his brother Wu Zhijun raised funds to build a new factory in another location. Today, the factory covering an area of ​​6 acres can produce about 800 kilograms of bacon every day, which is sold by four local stores in a day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the productivity of the fourth generation, the area of ​​the new factory has been reduced but the production capacity has been increased. According to Wu Zhiyong, his secret recipe was prepared by his ancestors who were doctors in the third year of Guangxu (1877). During this period, his grandfather improved it once, and it has been used ever since. There are about 22 Chinese herbal medicines in this secret recipe. Different ingredients are used in different seasons. Pork, beef, chicken, rabbit and other ingredients are also different, and even the ingredients used in different parts are different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong told Southern Weekend reporters that for many years, the Wu family’s secret recipe for bacon has been dictated. He recalled that he and his younger brother were taken to the batching room by his father. The batching room had no windows and only one door. His father taught them the recipe for cooking pig head meat in summer. They could only memorize it by rote. If they wrote it down on paper, they had to cook it before going out. Lose. Not only that, this recipe can be passed down to sons and daughters-in-law, but not to daughters-in-law. Wu Zhiyong said that all 7 brothers of his father&#39;s generation have completed the inheritance; there are 10 cousins ​​of his generation, and 5 of them are currently running the business; now, the baton is slowly being passed to the hands of the sixth generation. Among this generation, There are 10 males, 9 of whom are minors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, Wu Yazhou, the sixth generation inheritor, has begun to learn how to make ingredients, as well as washing, soaking, pickling, boiling, smoking, drying and other techniques. Wu Zhiyong revealed that Wu Yazhou, who is currently 25 years old, does not fully understand the ingredients of the secret recipe. He will not be able to teach all the secret recipes until he reaches the age of 35 and matures mentally. Another inheritor is Wu Zhiyong’s son Wu Yaxuan. He is still in his second year of high school and has not yet decided whether to inherit the family business. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhiyong feels that Wu’s bacon, which has lost the title of a time-honored Chinese brand, is not only a food, but also the hard work and bitterness of the older generation, and he wants to carry it forward. Now, the new factory is debugging a high-temperature sterilization flexible packaging production line. After debugging is completed, the products can be launched into foreign markets. Not only that, he plans to introduce live streaming to deliver goods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 9, the day the Ministry of Commerce disclosed the results of the review of Chinese time-honored brands, Ministry of Commerce spokesperson He Yadong said that in 2022, Chinese time-honored brands will achieve operating income of more than 1.2 trillion yuan, and nearly 70% of them will be profitable. . In the first three quarters of 2023, operating income has exceeded the full-year level of 2022. The Ministry of Commerce will work with relevant departments to further establish and improve the long-term mechanism for the protection, inheritance and innovation and development of time-honored brands, promote time-honored brands to dig deep into their cultural heritage, benchmark against advanced concepts, adhere to integrity, innovate and develop, and better play a demonstration role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中山大学通报“贫困生炫富”：终止发放助学金]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260686]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 23:46:35&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 15, the Student Financial Aid Management Center of Sun Yat-sen University issued a briefing on the situation of students from financially disadvantaged families at the school. Zhao Moumou responded to reports of showing off his wealth and excessive consumption. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The notice stated that after verification, the student was identified as a student from a family with financial difficulties. The identification procedures and materials were complete and in compliance with relevant regulations. However, during the verification, it was found that the man was not frugal in his life and had excessive consumption. According to the relevant regulations of the school, it was decided to terminate the grant of scholarships. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, some netizens posted on the forum of Sun Yat-sen University that a poor student from the school’s Sino-French School of Nuclear Engineering and Technology who received a scholarship used an Apple series four-piece set (generally referring to Apple-branded mobile phones, computer, tablet and watch), and also bought Wang Jiaer’s concert tickets worth 1,517 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the post, the netizen who broke the news disclosed the student ID information of the student who received the scholarship, showing that this 2021 undergraduate student at Sun Yat-sen University belongs to the &quot;especially difficult&quot; category. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The complete situation is reported as follows:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On November 14, the Student Financial Aid Management Center of Sun Yat-sen University received a report about Zhao Moumou, a student from a financially disadvantaged family in our school, showing off his wealth and excessive consumption. , his college and our center quickly launched investigation procedures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After verification, the student was identified as a student from a family with financial difficulties. The identification procedures and materials were complete and in compliance with relevant regulations. However, during the verification, it was found that the man was not frugal in his life and had excessive consumption. According to the provisions of Article 21, Paragraph 3 of the &quot;Regulations on the Administration of Bursaries for Undergraduate Students of Sun Yat-sen University&quot;, it was decided to terminate the payment of its bursaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The school attaches great importance to student financial aid and provides all possible assistance to students from families with financial difficulties to help students grow and become talents. Next, the school will further strengthen the management and supervision of student financial aid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Yat-sen University Student Financial Aid Management Center&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 15, 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 23:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[重生剧，重生了个寂寞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260538]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;Recently, two rebirth dramas have been broadcast one after another. The former is &quot;For the Secret Fragrance Comes&quot;, and the latter is &quot;Peace is Like a Dream&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What a coincidence, the main plot of them is &quot;the evil girl decides to be a good person after rebirth&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first life of Hua Qian, the arrogant daughter of Hua Qian, in order to plot against the uncle who does not love her, he designed to frame the second daughter&#39;s family. In the end, not only was she kicked out, but her own family was also destroyed. , repented before his death. After rebirth, she returned to her wedding night. Unfortunately, she had already done all the bad things, so she had no choice but to turn the tide and make amends for her bad deeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/81b97614dc7a65dbf1268fc6a908e4ba.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/81b97614dc7a65dbf1268fc6a908e4ba.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ning&#39;an Queen Jiang Xuening in &quot;Like a Dream&quot; was a selfish person in her first life. She was devoted to the position of queen and planned every step, letting down many people who fell in love with her. When the imperial power fell, she lost all hope and committed suicide. After rebirth, she returned to her teenage years, and she still had time to change her life path. Whenever she had to make a choice, she made a different choice from her previous life, not wanting the tragedy to happen again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/74951bcdfcdb2f12eba8eb9212f5b073.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/74951bcdfcdb2f12eba8eb9212f5b073.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Weiyou &quot;Secret Fragrance Comes&quot; and &quot;Ning&#39;an Like a Dream&quot; were respectively adapted from the Zhihu novel &quot;Washing the Leading Flowers&quot; and the Jinjiang novel &quot;Kunning&quot;. The original works were both popular hits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In online novels, &quot;rebirth novels&quot; are a type that attracts a lot of attention. &quot;Harem stories&quot; and &quot;house fighting stories&quot; are only popular periodically, but &quot;rebirth stories&quot; have a long-lasting momentum, and &quot;Rebirth of Me xxxxxx&quot; has become a popular title template. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to attract readers in the first three golden chapters, some authors even put a &quot;rebirth&quot; shell on ordinary costume romance novels, but this setting has little impact on the subsequent plot. &quot;Pseudo-rebirth literature&quot; is not within the scope of our discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a term in psychology called &quot;unfinished complex&quot;, which may be used to explain the popularity of rebirth literature. It refers to an individual who, because of something or a situation that has not yet been satisfactorily resolved, especially a trauma, always dwells on it subconsciously, constantly embellishes the unfinished alternative, and then continues to seek compensatory satisfaction in later life. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, another life trajectory in parallel time and space has attracted countless people&#39;s yearning for it. There is no regret medicine in the world, and no one can start over, so it is better to give this hope to the fictional protagonists in the rebirth novel and let them live again with their own memories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Being able to repeat such a setting is also very popular in the drama market. Looking at the rebirth dramas in the past two years, they are usually divided into two types: dramas in which villains are reincarnated and reformed, and dramas in which good guys are reborn and revenge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rebirth of evildoers is to correct the mistakes in life. This type of drama promotes correct values, highlights the importance of choices, and guides everyone to be kind to others. Just like Andy Lau&#39;s classic line in &quot;Infernal Affairs&quot;, &quot;I didn&#39;t have a choice before, but now I want to be a good person.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The aforementioned &quot;For the Secret Fragrance Comes&quot; and &quot;Ningan is Like a Dream&quot; can both be classified into this category. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first episode of &quot;The Secret Fragrance Comes&quot; is when Hua Qian&#39;s family was sanctioned and she witnessed the death of her parents. She heard a hazy whisper on the edge of life and death: &quot;If I could have my life over again, Opportunity, will you make a change?&quot; &quot;I will&quot; sets the tone of the whole play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/53329d2a69b1d633f364c8545098effa.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;607&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/53329d2a69b1d633f364c8545098effa.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258140&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a38f9135dfd9bc86e14faee19a7de622.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;624&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/a38f9135dfd9bc86e14faee19a7de622.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258141&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Ning&#39;an Like a Dream&quot; has been added based on the original text A deceptive introduction: A modern female writer was writing a book about the demon queen&#39;s execution (this is the first life), and suddenly decided to change the heroine Jiang Xuening&#39;s character (this is the second life), and wrote &quot;This time, Jiang Xuening&quot; , will never enter the palace again.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c0f57245e9382396f43395d0ca92f7e2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;597&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/c0f57245e9382396f43395d0ca92f7e2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258142&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/11c564e31885728c60dd3d2caa117307.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;597&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/11c564e31885728c60dd3d2caa117307.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It can be said that the lives of Hua Qian and Jiang Xuening are all happy. With the original intention of &quot;doing good&quot;, can you get what you want after being reborn? Is the river of destiny so easy to figure out? The answer is of course no. Along with the &quot;unfinished complex&quot; comes obsession and compulsion. Driven by the mentality of &quot;I have to force myself&quot;, the restarted life may not be perfect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Remorse brings shame and glory, so Hua Qian becomes humble and polite, seriously acts as the uncle&#39;s wife, and strives to have a good relationship with the people around her. In order to make up for the debt owed to the second female lead in her previous life, Hua Qian also tried her best to bring her relationship with the uncle together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/262921949e592c455bd6625ebff7b358.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/262921949e592c455bd6625ebff7b358.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258143&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But she changed , everyone&#39;s attitude has also changed accordingly. In the previous life, no one loved her despite all the institutions, but in this life, her true love cannot withstand the active flattery of all men. The series falls into the cliche emotional line of one woman vs. three men: the wavering uncle, the strategizing head of the family, the loyal and passionate bodyguard, how to choose? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/4e82acbecac76ed8705a53bbcc1f02cc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/4e82acbecac76ed8705a53bbcc1f02cc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258144&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other side, Jiang Xuening&#39;s restart of life focuses on avoiding pitfalls. The thunderbolts he stepped on in his previous life are all lessons for his current life. So in the eyes of everyone, this unruly daughter-in-law actually became much smarter in a matter of days. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/7505f4c4ef268ac28a56d509fec7f246.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/7505f4c4ef268ac28a56d509fec7f246.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258145&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The male protagonist Xie Wei also began to pay special attention to her. The person who &quot;forced her to commit suicide&quot; in her previous life was destined to suffer another disaster that she could not escape. Coupled with her Bai Yueguang and childhood sweetheart, isn&#39;t this a coincidence? Another emotional line of one woman vs three men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/ec95baf7e5cab7909e66b14c89e25b23.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;457&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/ec95baf7e5cab7909e66b14c89e25b23.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258147&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Using Sociology Interpreted from the perspective of Zygmunt Bauman, the expression of individualization is the transformation from the &quot;bearer&quot; of the identity to the &quot;responsible person&quot;. Hua Qian and Jiang Xuening were hateful in their previous lives, but they were also the bearers of a tragic fate. In this life, they opened their eyes wide and began to learn to take on their own rights and responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the subsequent development of the series still leads to the myth of fatalism. I have heard many truths and learned to be a good person, but I can avoid tragedy A but cannot escape tragedy B. The design of fate can always give people Surprise and shock. TV dramas need such twists and turns to better build dramatic tension, but it also leads to the failure of the audience&#39;s psychological expectations. We actually don&#39;t want to watch a plot that is too sadistic, especially since it is a rebirth drama. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A revenge drama in which a good guy is reborn is actually more in line with the physique of drama fans. A good man who always does good, but falls into the trap of others and steps into the abyss. If he could live again, we would see him kill everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is why &quot;The Temptation of Going Home&quot; will become a classic. Lin Pinru fell and Gao Shanshan stood up. Although it is not a rebirth drama, the psychological roots are the same. As Bacon said, &quot;Revenge is brutal justice&quot;, and the plot of &quot;an eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth&quot; is in line with the audience&#39;s imagination of happy grudges. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Last year&#39;s domestic drama &quot;The Lost Years&quot; and the Korean drama &quot;The Youngest Son of the Chaebol Family&quot; were both revenge dramas in which good guys were reborn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first three episodes of &quot;The Lost Years&quot; tell the story of the heroine Lu Anran&#39;s past life at 5x speed. She is a good wife, mother, daughter and sister, but she cannot escape the tricks of fate. Reborn in episode 4, she discovers that everything is not accidental, and every step contains the calculation of her husband, so she decides to take revenge on him and seek justice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/74d5d3556cce35ff1aa4174a6170c8d2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/74d5d3556cce35ff1aa4174a6170c8d2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258148&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Chaebol Family&quot; In &quot;The Youngest Son&quot;, Song Joong-ki plays a low-level worker from a wealthy family who was killed after draining all his value. After rebirth, he became the grandson of a chaebol family, and the enemies in his previous life are hidden among his relatives in this life. The object of his revenge is not only the concrete person, but also the entire cannibalistic plutocratic constitution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/6600b99e4a3d180fa80d1b13fccd393f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/6600b99e4a3d180fa80d1b13fccd393f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258146&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A good man is reborn with revenge The play emphasizes pain and pleasure. In the early stage, the protagonist endured all the way and experienced situations that ordinary people could not bear. The pain was felt both in his body and in the hearts of the audience. The desperate counterattack when being squeezed to the extreme is the highlight, so the audience is looking forward to the golden finger on the road to rebirth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Disregarding the usual shortcomings of rebirth dramas - shocking endings, &quot;The Last Days&quot; and &quot;The Youngest Son of the Chaebol&quot; had completely different reputations during their broadcasts, with the former being scolded by the audience. &quot;It&#39;s so frustrating and lonely,&quot; but the latter triggered a nationwide craze to watch the drama. Everyone wanted to see how cool it was for the protagonist to control the Korean economy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The root of the problem is: in rebirth and revenge dramas, the word &quot;pleasure&quot; is at the forefront. The audience does not want to think too much and just wants to watch the protagonist&#39;s gorgeous turn. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The male protagonist played by Song Joong-ki was just a pawn of the chaebol family in his previous life. He completed his domestic duties meticulously and took care of the outside affairs. He had no ambitions or desires and only looked forward to the meager amount that was enough to survive. Just a salary. Who would have thought that a former serf who sang songs and became the heir to a chaebol group would not only be able to make money crazily with the help of information gaps, but also be able to crush his enemies in all aspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/787f226cfa122356163cf5a242439723.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;459&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/787f226cfa122356163cf5a242439723.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258150&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Anran Otherwise, she would work hard to manage her second life, only to find that no matter how much she played cheats, she could not compare to her sinister and cold-natured husband. All your hard work is in vain, and you always live in his shadow, which is even more painful than the first life when you were kept in the dark. The male protagonist who has no sense of existence is like a complete outsider. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/836ca02206bae2f98d0377e13e645f52.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/13/836ca02206bae2f98d0377e13e645f52.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258149&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Yixin Audiences looking for pleasure certainly don’t want to be tortured in “The Year of the Fall”, but just want to warm up to a pot of yellow rice dreams in “The Youngest Son of the Plutocratic Family”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, domestic rebirth dramas have been making waves, big or small, due to their own gimmicks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, there are very few people who can be good-looking without being unfinished, twisty but not annoying. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From successful broadcast to word-of-mouth acclaim, this subject still has a way to go. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[以人为本，爱有差等，呵护仁心：古典儒家论“人兽之辨” ]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260649]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“四川崇州恶狗伤人事件”经过几轮深入报道，至今仍在持续发酵，这起惨剧本该成为全社会审视和评估城市养犬对公共安全威胁水平，进一步推动法制健全的一个契机。 Unfortunately, however, relevant discussions on multiple social platforms have gone beyond the incident itself and become an outlet for various emotions and contradictions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are also some people taking advantage of the situation to put forward a series of vague pan-moral views. As one of the ideological cornerstones of traditional Chinese culture, the Confucian sages in the pre-Qin period conducted a series of thoughts on the relationship between &quot;human beings, animals, and society&quot; two thousand years ago, which can help us clarify our thinking and clarify the public opinion field. Some views and opinions on. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The Difference between Humans and Animals&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As a philosophical thought dating back more than 2,000 years ago, the most valuable part of Pre-Qin Confucianism is undoubtedly its ubiquitous humanism in principle. This point is also very clear in the &quot;Difference between Humans and Animals&quot;. Mencius said: &quot;The creatures of heaven are the same as the basics.&quot; Human beings are the only subjects of moral practice. The difference between humans and animals is that humans have &quot;the intolerance&quot;. &quot;Heart of compassion&quot; and &quot;heart of compassion&quot; are all part of &quot;benevolence&quot;. As the saying goes, &quot;heart of compassion is the origin of benevolence&quot;. &quot;Benevolence&quot; is not only one of the principles of moral practice, but also the highest purpose of moral practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For society, all manifestations of &quot;civilization&quot;, whether it is respecting the elderly and caring for the young, protecting vegetation, and being kind to animals, are people as the subject practicing the principle of &quot;benevolence&quot; and pursuing &quot;benevolence&quot;. &quot;One of the results produced during the goal process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the master of all things and the only subject in moral practice, man certainly has the right to treat and dispose of &quot;things&quot; in the way he wants. The things here include both inanimate dead things and living things. Living things. &quot;The Analects of Confucius&quot; says, &quot;A fisher does not have a clear outline, and a sailor does not shoot at a perch.&quot; Confucius used a fishing rod to fish, but not a net, and shot birds, but did not kill the birds that returned to their nests to roost. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a similar discussion in later Confucian classics. A gentleman has the ability to catch all the fish in the lake, but he only catches the parts he needs to eat, and he will no longer catch excessively. A gentleman has the right to hunt in the mountains and forests, but he will not shoot birds at will just to show off his superb shooting skills or for fun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The fish did not die because of human greed, and the birds were not killed because of human whims. This is not because fish and birds have the same right to survive as humans, but because humans have different rights. The &quot;compassion&quot; of fish and birds is the result of practicing &quot;benevolence&quot;. The moral basis of &quot;benevolence&quot; in the relationship between humans and beasts lies in humans&#39; moral consciousness and the subject-object status of humans and beasts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is not an &quot;equal right to live&quot;, nor does it mean that &quot;human beings cannot deprive animals of their right to live even under serious potential threats.&quot; The subject-object relationship between humans and animals is reversed. In this absurd world where &quot;dogs eat human food without checking it, and people who are hungry on the road don&#39;t know how to get rid of it&quot;, there is no way to talk about &quot;benevolence&quot;, and the so-called civilization is just a joke. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Be kind to people and love things&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Difference between Humans and Animals&quot;, the relationship between humans and animals is positioned as the relationship between humans and objects, and there is an insurmountable gap between humans and objects. , therefore this relationship must be lower than the relationship between people. Mencius said when discussing the relationship between people and people and things:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;A gentleman&#39;s relationship with things is to love them but not to be benevolent.&quot; ; To the people, be benevolent without being close to them. Be benevolent to relatives by benevolent to the people, benevolent to the people and love things.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The meaning of this sentence is that no matter how much a gentleman loves things, he will not treat &quot;benevolence&quot; Give priority to things, and although you are kind to the people, you will not give love to your relatives. Only when a gentleman loves his relatives can he be benevolent to the people, and only when he is benevolent to the people can he care for all things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This logical relationship is the so-called &quot;differences in love&quot;. &quot;Differences&quot; are concentric circles with the center of the circle being the self. The ethical relationship between each other is determined through the outward distance: family, clan, Rural people, Chinese people, and outsiders are treated with the most basic ethics as human beings at the outermost level, and they are &quot;things&quot; beyond the outermost level. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When animals are treated kindly, the civilization of human society has reached a certain height. &quot;Old people are like old people and people are old, young people are like young people and people are young&quot; has become the moral consensus of the entire society, and human rights have been improved. After protection, &quot;differential love&quot; will ultimately benefit animals, rather than saying that as long as animals are protected and treated well, society will naturally be civilized. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Any emotion that violates this logical relationship is false. For example, if someone does not love his family but loves his country, or does not love his tribe but loves outsiders, then his love for his countrymen and outsiders is also false. It may be some kind of twisted projection of hatred towards family and tribe. In the same way, if someone claims that they love animals more than people, it is probably some kind of distorted projection. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So Mencius asked King Hui of Liang: &quot;Now your kindness is enough for animals, but the merit is not for the people. (Now, your kindness can be extended to animals, but it cannot be extended to the people.) Why?&quot; is sarcastic and critical. This question can also be used to question those who claim that they love animals more than people. How much of their &quot;love&quot; for animals is true? Or is it true? Is it my own selfish desires? &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;There are differences in love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Another focus of debate in the &quot;Vicious Dog Injury Incident&quot; is that some people who do not own dogs advocate the formulation and implementation of strict and effective urban dog-raising regulations. At the same time, we will thoroughly clean up and kill stray dogs that may threaten public safety. Some dog owners think this is too barbaric and cruel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two have completely different perceptions of this issue, because they project completely different feelings towards animals. For the former who do not own dogs, they have no feelings for dogs at all.而对养狗的后者来说则复杂得多，他们的情感很容易从自己的狗蔓延到他人的狗，从他人的狗蔓延到所有的狗（包括流浪狗）身上去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无法认知和控制情感的边界，放任其蔓延是心智不成熟（比如小孩子）的认知特点。而“爱有差等”则限定了人类情感的边界，最大程度上避免了个体情感无限制的蔓延，妨害其他社会个体的权益和公共权益。总而言之，人是主体。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儒家思想之所以能够两千年来根植于中国传统社会而生生不息，根本在于其发于人性，阐于常识，因此在各种观点横行的今日，更显出其历久弥新的光辉一面。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 22:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>