<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[平均降价58%，​第九批国家药品集采41种药品采购成功]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260089]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On November 6, the ninth batch of state-organized centralized bulk procurement of drugs produced results in Shanghai. 41 types of drugs were successfully purchased in this centralized purchase. The average price of the selected drugs was reduced by 58%, and it is expected to save 18.2 billion yuan in drug costs every year. Pharmaceutical companies actively participated in this centralized procurement, with 382 products from 262 companies participating in the bidding. 266 products from 205 companies are eligible to be selected, including 260 products from 200 domestic pharmaceutical companies and 6 products from 5 international pharmaceutical companies (including 1 original research drug and 5 imported generic drugs). The winning rate is about 78%, with an average of 6.5 companies for each category planning to be selected. This centralized procurement has a high selection rate for enterprises, and has a good effect on reducing the burden on the masses, achieving a balance between the multiple goals of &quot;reducing burdens, promoting development, and ensuring supply.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This centralized purchase covers medications for common and chronic diseases such as infections, tumors, cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases, gastrointestinal diseases, and mental illnesses, as well as key drugs such as emergency drugs and shortage drugs. Lenalidomide capsules for the treatment of multiple myeloma will be included in the centralized procurement in time after the patent expires in May 2023. The average price of each capsule (25 mg) has been reduced from about 200 yuan to 15 yuan, which can save about 3,880 yuan in monthly drug costs. Patients The burden is significantly reduced. The prices of three nationally focused drugs monitored for rational use, including rabeprazole oral sustained-release dosage form and esomeprazole magnesium enteric-coated dry suspension for the treatment of gastrointestinal diseases, have been significantly reduced. Five kinds of shortage drugs and emergency drugs, including amiodarone injection to treat arrhythmia, dopamine injection to rescue shock, and oxytocin injection to induce labor, have been used to stabilize corporate expectations through the &quot;volume-based&quot; procurement method to ensure supply and Balance of multiple objectives for reasonable price reduction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2018, the National Medical Insurance Administration has organized and carried out nine batches of nationally organized drug procurement, including a total of 374 kinds of drugs, with an average reduction of more than 50%. In the next step, the National Medical Insurance Administration will work with relevant departments to guide various localities and selected companies to implement the winning results to ensure that patients across the country can use the selected products after the price reduction of this centralized purchase in March 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 08:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“吃不完剩下点很正常”？节约习惯还得从小塑成丨养儿育女]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260019]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;As a working mother, I always believe that it is important to prepare a hearty, delicious and nutritious meal for my second-grade son every day. The rich and satisfying breakfast was indeed a &quot;big job&quot;. Recently, in the morning, I followed my child&#39;s request and packed breakfast for him at the bakery or community cafeteria downstairs. When I came home in the evening, I found that he always had more than half of a hamburger or rice ball left. I curiously asked him why he wasted some food every day, and he answered me nonchalantly: &quot;It&#39;s normal not to be able to finish the rest!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After listening to the child&#39;s words, I gave him a detailed calculation. An economic account: If he wastes 9 yuan a day, 63 yuan a week, and 252 yuan a month, he wastes more than 3,000 yuan a year. This money can buy a good mobile phone, a A branded washing machine can also cover the living expenses of a poor rural person for a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The child was extremely shocked by what he said. He sighed repeatedly, &quot;Mom, before you calculated this account for me, I never thought that if you waste a little bit every day, you would lose so much. I will ask you to buy less in the future, please remember it!&quot; Seeing the sincerity on his face, I couldn&#39;t help but sigh, modern children&#39;s awareness of thrift really needs to be cultivated from an early age! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is true that today’s favorable material living conditions can easily cause children to lack the concept of money. From childhood, when you open your mouth to eat or stretch out your hands when wearing clothes, if you open your mouth to ask for anything, parents will satisfy you without reservation. Some parents even feel that they suffered too much in childhood and have not experienced many fun in childhood, so they feel that they cannot be owed anything. child. Over time, mentally retarded children will no longer know where money comes from, let alone how difficult it is to make money. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the same time, wrong guidance from parents is also the main reason why children have no concept of money. With the development of modern technology, people tend to use mobile payment instead of cash payment. During e-commerce festivals such as &quot;6·18&quot; and &quot;Double 11&quot;, many parents &quot;buy, buy, buy&quot; regardless of whether it is useful or not. Behind the convenient and fast payment, children cannot feel what money is, and they will not ask &quot;how much money does my family have&quot; or &quot;how much money can my parents earn in a day&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, the limitations of school education methods are also an important reason for children&#39;s lack of money concepts and awareness of saving. I believe that all schools will warn children to develop the habit of thrifting from an early age, but it is obviously difficult to exert their due effect by admonishing and urging children. Of course, it is also difficult to arouse children&#39;s empathy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;We all know that children are in a critical period of forming their outlook on life. Proper guidance from parents and schools is particularly important for them to develop correct values. Because of this, as parents, we must first guide our children to establish a correct concept of money. Use plain and easy language to calculate accounts for children, so that they can concretely understand the concept of money and truly feel that money is hard-won. You might as well prepare a piggy bank for your children, let them save money and use it by themselves, and warn them not to buy and spend randomly. Take your children to participate in some social labor, let them experience the hardship and fun of making money, and let them realize that making money is not easy during labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Teaching by words and deeds is worse than words and deeds. Parents are role models for children to follow. Good examples inspire people to make progress, but bad examples can cause endless harm. As parents, we ourselves must develop a good habit of saving, teach our children why we need to save and how to develop a good habit of saving in every aspect of our lives, tell them that money should be spent wisely, and then create a culture of spending money when it is appropriate and being thrifty and thrifty. family atmosphere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no doubt that school education and social guidance are also extremely important for children to develop thrifty habits. In school education, we carry out themed study activities such as &quot;Spend January with 100 Yuan&quot;, organize children to go to rural poverty-stricken areas to experience life and feel poverty, so that they can truly understand that making money is not easy and life is difficult, and encourage them to develop thrift. virtue. At the same time, mass media such as radio and television should also promote the &quot;new trend of frugality on the dining table&quot; and encourage everyone to promote traditional virtues. We can also encourage children from developed areas in the east to pair up and help each other with children from poor areas in the central and western regions, so that the &quot;little princesses&quot; and &quot;little princes&quot; living in honey pots can use their own actions to help children in poor areas realize their &quot;dream of going to school&quot; and &quot;seeking knowledge&quot; &quot;Dream&quot; to promote common growth and let the &quot;little princesses&quot; and &quot;little princes&quot; truly realize the great role of saving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a civil servant in Quzhou, Zhejiang)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;• &lt;span>; As a parent and teacher, share the scenery you have experienced and the principles you have learned on the way your children grow up. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div >;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[​黑龙江佳木斯一体育馆发生坍塌，初步确认3人被困丨滚动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260091]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 22:02:48&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Beijing time November 6, 21 Hours 58 minutes&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reporter learned from the relevant departments of Jiamusi City, Heilongjiang Province that at around 19:40 on November 6, 2023, the Yuecheng Gymnasium in Hunan County, Jiamusi City partially collapsed. The building was a two-story frame. The structure, with a construction area of ​​about 2,000 square meters, collapsed in the basketball area on the second floor on the west side. The collapsed area was about 500 square meters. It was initially confirmed on site that three people were trapped in the gymnasium. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, fire protection, public security and other departments are working hard to rescue. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span>;(CCTV News)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;21:00, November 6, Beijing time&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;​A gymnasium collapsed in Jiamusi, Heilongjiang, and rescue operations are underway&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;November 6 On the evening of the same day, a gymnasium collapsed in Huannan County, Jiamusi, Heilongjiang. Relevant departments have arrived at the scene for rescue. Videos taken by netizens showed thick white snow on the collapsed building. It is reported that the scene has been sealed off and local rescue has been launched. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; Surrounding merchants told reporters that a gymnasium did collapse. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/c7865ffe43bc9b27db8a41302fde4a36.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;595&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/c7865ffe43bc9b27db8a41302fde4a36.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257222 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/a1bd13d49c78172c78bcec02522df3c8.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;638&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/a1bd13d49c78172c78bcec02522df3c8.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257221&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition, the Huanan County Meteorological Observatory upgraded and issued a blizzard red warning signal at 16:47 on November 6, 2023: The amount of snowfall in our county has reached more than 15 mm within 6 hours and the snowfall is still continuing, which is harmful to traffic. Or agriculture and animal husbandry may have a greater impact, please take precautions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;span>;（Southern+）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[年轻人“断亲”怎么看？“陌生人社会”不是要消灭“熟人社会”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260048]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The topic of divorce for those born in the 90s and 2000s has been very popular in recent years. Recently, some media published a report describing a female monster born in 1991. One day in July 2022, she severed ties with her relatives by deleting WeChat and blocking her phone number: List Including 3 cousins, 1 cousin, aunt, and parents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The article stated that in 2022, she was fired from an Internet company in Suzhou. She suffered a cerebral infarction and a stroke the next day after drinking the break-up drink. She will need to take care of herself for at least a year. In addition to not drinking alcohol or eating high-fat foods, In addition to salty food, you also need to go to the hospital regularly to prescribe medicine, which requires a medical fee. Her parents divorced when she was 8 years old and each formed a new family. She grew up under the care of her grandmother and aunt, so she asked her closest aunt, but her aunt said it was &quot;inconvenient to bear&quot;; she also asked her father for help, hoping that every month Borrowing two to three thousand yuan from himself, her father said that he could only pay for her hospitalization expenses; she asked her mother for help, but her mother had no response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many such reports in the media. For example, there is a report about the separation of relatives, which describes the 37-year-old Ye Wen. When he was a child, he was a left-behind child. His parents were working in Dongguan. He did not go to college. , works as a photography apprentice, opens a photography studio, likes literature, and writes worker poetry, but &quot;is not understood by his family or even his parents.&quot; He believes that his relationship with his father is broken by the word money. In 2019, he wanted to open a photography studio and borrowed 10,000 yuan from his father. His father did not speak. In his words, he was &quot;playing dead.&quot; He continued to ask: &quot;Do you want to borrow it or not? Let&#39;s talk.&quot; The father replied: &quot;I can&#39;t take care of your business.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above two cases of divorce are quite extreme. . There are two definitions or types of renunciation: one is (actively) severing contact with parents, family members and relatives, which is very clear; the other is the so-called &quot;lazy or negligent communication with relatives&quot;, which is also very clear. Vague, will be discussed further later. A common misunderstanding is to use extreme cases of the former to cover the latter, in order to exaggerate the breadth and severity of disconnection among young people. In fact, there are differences between the two situations and should be discussed separately. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First discuss the above two cases and the first type of divorce. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The 32-year-old female Xiaoguai and the 37-year-old Ye Wen both had shortcomings in childhood: one was that her parents divorced and formed new families, and they did not raise her by their side; the other was a left-behind child when she was a child, and her parents It&#39;s pitiful that I can&#39;t be with you when I&#39;m busy working to make money. However, these two people have already grown up. As adults, how to view and deal with the relationship with their parents, family members and relatives should also be done in an adult way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are no more than two ways for adults: one is the modern way, where one is independent, has personal rights and dignity, and can take responsibility for oneself vs. other individuals who are equally independent and have boundaries; In the traditional way, everyone belongs to a big family or family, and blood is thicker than water, and family ties are important. Big families or families are natural blood communities, and have mutual financial and insurance functions. You can only choose one. Each method is equal. You will get what you pay for. No one can take anything and ask for it blindly. It cannot be said that I want all the advantages and disadvantages of both methods. That is extremely refined egoism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2022, Xiaoguai is 31 years old. Grandma and her aunt took care of and raised her after her parents divorced. This is not the aunt&#39;s duty, but a matter of affection. This is tradition and help from the extended family. After she became an adult, her aunt also had her own small family, and it was not unreasonable to &quot;not be able to bear&quot; her maintenance and medical expenses. Why did she have such high psychological expectations for her aunt? To have so much resentment and sever ties with my aunt after not meeting expectations? She must have been working for some years. Has she ever repaid her aunt for her kindness in raising her in the early years? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;An adult who follows modern ways and does not expect to receive any help from his parents or extended family and does not maintain relationships with his parents, family members and relatives on a daily basis should be held responsible for his actions, e.g. After earning money, you should save money to prepare for emergencies; choose a healthy lifestyle and take care of your physical and mental health, because you have made up your mind to only rely on yourself. You cannot talk about personal freedom and independence when you are active and active. When you encounter trouble, you will think of your parents and extended family. In fact, after she opened her mouth to her father, he was willing to pay her hospitalization expenses as an adult and was kind to her. He just didn&#39;t meet her request to &quot;lend herself two to three thousand yuan a month.&quot; Why did she have to sever ties with her father? ? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similarly, in 2019, Ye Wen was 33 years old and borrowed 10,000 yuan from his father to open a photography studio. When his father refused to borrow the money, he severed the relationship with his father. This also caused a high psychological impact on his father. Expectations, and when expectations are not met, a lot of resentment arises. Speaking of modern methods, it is a matter of affection to be a father, but it is a duty not to be a father. In this sense, a father is the same as anyone else. If you borrow money from any friend, borrowing money from a friend is a matter of affection, but not borrowing money is a duty. Will you fall out because your friend refuses to borrow money? Doesn’t this confirm the correctness of not borrowing from friends? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Secondly, for the second type of severance, some people believe that the reason is that some young people no longer value &quot;blood relations&quot; and hate family gatherings with male elders as the core in a patriarchal society; the significance of progress It&#39;s very big, &quot;You can&#39;t choose relatives, but you can choose friends&quot;, which reflects the change from &quot;acquaintance society&quot; to &quot;stranger society&quot;. These arguments are all debatable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As mentioned above, the extended family or family is a natural blood community, which itself means that you are born with social capital (birthright). Why abandon it like worn out shoes? To a certain extent, trust based on blood and family ties is irreplaceable, and the maintenance cost of family ties is very low. If you are in the local area, you should visit regularly; if you are out of town, make a phone call or send a text message during the holidays to show yourself mind. In an era of peace and prosperity and when you are happy, these relationships may not be needed; but when facing difficulties and challenges, it is most reliable for family members to stay together and resist risks. Atomized individuals have poor ability to resist risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are two possibilities for &quot;being lazy and neglecting to interact with relatives&quot;. One is that you have essentially broken off the relationship. The problem is: you just don’t have to interact with relatives who are weird or have bad character, but you don’t have to essentially cut off contact with all relatives. Confucianism says &quot;cultivate one&#39;s moral character and bring order to one&#39;s family.&quot; People who have bad relationships with all their relatives may have problems themselves. If you are driving on the highway and find that all the cars are going the wrong way, there is only one truth: it is not others who are going the wrong way, but you. The other is just that you think so in your heart, and your parents still come forward to maintain the relationship for you while you are away from home for a long time. This is a false breakup. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can indeed choose friends, but close friends and life-and-death acquaintances are rare and require a high degree of spiritual and values ​​​​fit + deep trust established by long-term living and communication together. How many close friends, life and death friends, can a person have in a lifetime? What&#39;s more, there is no substitute for maintaining family relationships and making friends, and they can go hand in hand. Moreover, it may be difficult for those who have severed blood ties and family ties to establish deep connections and trust with people who are not even blood related, and it is also difficult for them to become trustworthy friends in the eyes of others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short, the so-called &quot;stranger society&quot; does not mean to eliminate the &quot;acquaintance society&quot;, but the &quot;acquaintance society&quot; is embedded in the &quot;stranger society&quot;. The world you face is still a world with Different concentric circles, the center of the circle is yourself, and the small family and the big family wrap you up in turn. As for the term &quot;patriarchal society&quot;, it is a deconstruction of fathers, marriage and family (one of the cornerstones of civilization). Civilization domesticates men, makes them assume family responsibilities, provides resources and protection, and improves the survival ability of children. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 21:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当“爱”已成往事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260087]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 20:31:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;When a love affair turns into a marriage, a lawsuit will be filed. When love becomes a thing of the past, children become the focus of contention. Ai Fukuhara may face more than two years in prison due to the custody dispute. What will Jiang Hongjie win and lose?</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 20:55:20 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[只要改变，晚年也不算晚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260066]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/06/nvinpd6IpuIPaGpXr7eFQvWbMofoUvOrpkNW6dcG.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1133&quot; height=&quot;1133&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/nvinpd6IpuIPaGpXr7eFQvWbMofoUvOr pkNW6dcG. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257177&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Insisting on exercise and a balanced diet...maintaining these good living habits can contribute to health. This concept has been widely recognized in the scientific community, but in real life Whether people can maintain a healthy lifestyle affects people&#39;s actual physical and mental state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently, researchers from the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention and other institutions have studied the impact of a healthy lifestyle on people&#39;s lifespan by analyzing the genes and living habits of a large number of elderly people. It was found that people with healthy lifestyle habits tended to have a lower risk of death and longer life expectancy, even in later life. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Nature and nurture&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;According to data observed by the research institute, if elderly people with low genetic risk have relatively healthy lifestyle habits, they are expected to have The life expectancy may be 3.84 years longer than other people. If people with higher genetic risk have healthy living habits in their later years, the life expectancy can be 4.35 years longer. Relevant research will be published in &quot;The Lancet Healthy Longevity&quot; in October 2023. It can be seen that people with higher genetic risk benefit more by maintaining a healthy lifestyle, while those with high genetic risk but unhealthy lifestyle have the highest risk of death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Innate genetic factors and acquired social environmental factors are two basic variables that affect human health. Research on long-lived elderly people shows that the death risk of elderly people over 110 years old is relatively stable, and there is no significant correlation with genetics, living habits, age, gender and other factors. But for most people under the age of 110, genetics, age and a healthy lifestyle are all important factors that affect lifespan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Based on twin studies, it is estimated that about 25% of the difference in life span between people can be attributed to genetics. But in 2018, Columbia University scientist Yaniv Erlich and others analyzed the lifespan patterns of more than 10 million people through family trees and believed that the impact of genetics on lifespan may not be that great. Explains 16% of the difference, which is less than one-fifth. This shows that factors such as living environment and lifestyle may have a greater impact on people&#39;s life span. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, in order to comprehensively measure the impact of genetics, lifestyle and other factors on the life expectancy of the elderly, the latest research analyzed data from these two aspects at the same time. Relevant health data comes from the Chinese Health and Longevity Survey from 1998 to 2018, which recorded the conditions of more than 36,000 people over the age of 65. During the follow-up study period, a total of more than 27,000 people died. To compare the impact of life expectancy factors provide a reference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the definition of researchers, a healthy lifestyle generally includes four aspects, not smoking, not drinking excessively, regularly participating in physical activities, and maintaining a healthy diet. It is worth mentioning that the scope of sports activities is also very wide, not only regular exercise is recognized, but also housework, gardening, raising animals, playing cards and other activities are included in the statistics. Considering that the elderly are prone to protein deficiency, only a diet that contains high-protein foods such as meat, eggs, and fish will be defined as a healthy lifestyle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When combined with the health habits of these older adults and their longevity, the findings actually emphasize the importance of developing a healthy lifestyle. Even in old age, these habits may help increase life expectancy. However, due to limitations of the research design, the latest research cannot provide a scientific explanation of the mechanism behind this. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;It does not happen overnight&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;For the elderly, health and longevity are inseparable from a series of diseases. As aging intensifies, the incidence of many diseases, such as dementia, continues to increase. In 2022, a forecast study by the Global Burden of Disease Project estimates that the number of people suffering from dementia worldwide is likely to increase significantly from more than 57 million in 2019 to approximately 150 million in 2050, an increase of 166%. During this period, the number of sick people in China may increase from more than 15 million to more than 45 million, an increase of 197%, which is equivalent to a tripling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Alzheimer’s disease and other dementias are related to the cognitive ability and self-care ability of the elderly, they will not only affect the quality of life of the patients themselves and their families. Once they become lost or separated from care after the disease, It may also be life-threatening. In recent years, more and more studies have found that diseases such as dementia are also related to living habits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, researchers from the Department of Biological Sciences at the University of Southern California used health data of nearly 50,000 elderly people to study the relationship between sedentary behavior and dementia, and found that the length of sitting is related to the onset of dementia. There is a clear link to risk, with longer periods of sitting associated with a higher risk of dementia. Compared with a median of 9.27 hours of sedentary behavior, those who sit for 12 hours a day have an increased risk of more than 60%, and if they sit for 15 hours a day, the risk more than triples. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;None of these elderly people were diagnosed with dementia at the beginning of the study. The average age was over 65 years old. They carried monitoring devices on their wrists and accurately recorded their sedentary time in subsequent years. Here, some people are diagnosed with dementia. But that doesn’t mean dementia is caused solely by sitting for long periods of time in old age. Existing scientific observations show that education, smoking, obesity, high blood sugar and other conditions may affect the risk of dementia. Lifestyle factors associated with geriatric disease can be traced back to younger ages. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2019, psychology researchers at the University of Sussex used an observational study lasting nearly thirty years to explore the long-term health effects of symptoms such as depression and found that if people accumulate If there are too many symptoms of depression, anxiety, etc., cognitive functions will be more damaged in middle-aged and elderly people, such as poorer memory and lower accuracy of information processing. This evidence means that the relationship between some diseases may be interlocking and can induce other diseases decades apart. Not only should early detection, early intervention and early treatment be required, but also the development of healthy lifestyles should be early. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, for depression, scientists have discovered that there is a causal relationship between a healthy lifestyle and this type of disease. If you adhere to a healthy lifestyle, reduce sitting for long periods of time, increase social activities, exercise regularly, do not smoke, drink less alcohol, and maintain a healthy diet and sleep, it will help prevent depression. Research on older people has also found that developing even a hobby can help reduce people&#39;s symptoms of depression and improve their happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Mental health diseases such as dementia and depression are just one case that affects people’s health and longevity. In reality, there are many diseases that affect people’s health. Although the pathogenic mechanisms of various diseases are mostly complex, existing Scientific evidence shows that lifestyle factors are at work behind a considerable number of diseases. In other words, by changing your lifestyle, it is possible to reduce the risk of disease and even death. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The Brutal Truth&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The latest research released by the Global Cardiovascular Risk Alliance shows that more than 50% of cardiovascular disease cases and about 20% of all-cause The deaths can be attributed to five modifiable risk factors. The five risk factors are: body mass index (BMI), systolic blood pressure, non-HDL cholesterol, smoking and diabetes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Specifically, about 57% of cardiovascular disease cases and 22% of various death cases among women are affected by these five risk indicators, and about 53% of men are affected. % and 19%, relevant research was published in the &quot;New England Journal of Medicine&quot; (NEJM) in October 2023. Modifiable risk factors serve as weather vanes. Abnormalities in a single indicator will not suddenly cause disease or death, but they can give people time to identify disease risks early and make changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Body mass index (BMI), which can measure body fat and thinness, has been widely used in health management and disease risk prediction. Overweight and even obesity are obvious risk signals. Blood pressure and cholesterol are usually items that can be checked during a physical examination. Smoking is harmful to health, and quitting smoking as early as possible can greatly reduce the risk of disease. As for diabetes, as an important risk predictor of other cardiovascular diseases, it is a chronic disease in itself. Preventing and controlling blood sugar levels as early as possible requires developing many healthy lifestyles and persisting for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Concerning health and longevity, in recent years there have been some scientific opinions that do not seem serious enough, such as &quot;people with higher incomes live longer&quot;, &quot;people who love art live longer&quot;, etc.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, behind They all point to the issue of lifestyle affecting life span. Although these economic, social, and cultural factors, such as diet, hobbies, etc., are simple, common, and even interesting, scientific proof shows that they can all be used as environmental factors that affect life span and affect human health together with genes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, artistic hobbies affect lifespan, probably because these cultural and sports activities not only exercise the body, but also activate the brain. They also provide opportunities for social interaction, improve people&#39;s sense of happiness and belonging, and reduce It relieves loneliness, which is very rare for the elderly. An epidemiological study in Norway found that people who regularly participate in singing, dancing and other artistic activities will reduce the risk of death by more than 40%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for those with higher incomes and longer lives, the relevant evidence is more abundant, and it also confirms the widespread influence of factors such as economic and social status. Public health studies in the United States, Norway and other places have found that the life expectancy of people in the top 1% of income levels is nearly 10 years longer than those in the bottom 1%. In societies with different welfare systems and varying degrees of inequality, economic factors play surprisingly similar roles. It is a cruel truth that people with high incomes can live longer. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Developing good habits as early as possible&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It is actually related to a series of healthy lifestyles. From the perspective of basic material conditions such as diet and housing, healthy diet and high-quality living environment are often more expensive and require higher income support. Medical care, services closely related to health and lifespan, and physical exercise facilities also rely on economic basis. In addition, education, income, health awareness, etc. are often related. People with higher incomes may be more aware of the importance of health, understand more health knowledge, increase exercise, and smoke less, drink less, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When these healthy lifestyles are concentrated in cities, comparative data show that people living in big cities tend to live longer overall, including low-income groups living in big cities. . Although the income is not high, they may benefit from the overall public health services, policies and health culture of large cities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the secret of longevity, the scientific community has never stopped exploring. In recent years, some preliminary findings in some animal experiments are actually related to lifestyle. Researchers at the University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center observed hundreds of mice for nearly four years, the equivalent of a lifetime. In 2022, their nearly four-year study showed that dietary patterns can change the lifespan of mice, specifically reflected in the amount of food and the time of eating. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Restricting 30% of the caloric intake can extend the lifespan of mice by 10%. If the caloric intake time is further restricted and eating during normal activity times according to the circadian rhythm, the lifespan can even be extended by 35%. This provides a reference for humans to understand the mechanism of longevity, and also proves the importance of a healthy lifestyle to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it should be noted that it is difficult to grasp all the information about a person’s daily life in various current studies on healthy life, especially when observing diseases and life span through the lifestyle of large-scale groups. There are many limitations, and more research is needed in the future to uncover the secrets of health and longevity. In view of the fact that some healthy behaviors also have a positive impact on people&#39;s current lives, such as regular exercise, healthy eating, and smoking and alcohol control, these recognized daily healthy behaviors are worth developing as early as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[猪心脏移植手术再次失败了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260084]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On September 22, 2023, the University of Maryland Medical Center announced that the medical Doctors at the center transplanted a heart from a genetically modified pig into a 58-year-old heart disease patient two days ago. Within a week after the operation, the patient recovered well and was able to speak independently and sit up. One month later, doctors detected a strong immune rejection reaction in the patient. However, the latest news shows that the patient died on October 30 and did not survive longer than the first patient to receive a pig heart xenograft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/fOu2F2QHapWf3QcyXUdPXmBWyk4ZdOwhI4tqYzHC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1216&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/fOu2F2QHapWf3QcyXUdPXmBWyk4ZdOwhI4tqYzHC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257207&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The University of Maryland Medical Center recently performed the world&#39;s second pig heart xenotransplantation. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(University of Maryland Medical Center/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Immune rejection remains the biggest threat&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;The pig heart transplanted this time came from a genetically modified pig and was provided by Revivicor, an innovative biotechnology company specializing in the cultivation of donor pigs for xenogeneic organ transplantation. It is a subsidiary of United Therapeutics Corporation. of subsidiaries. This genetically modified pig involves a total of 10 gene modifications. The main purpose is to &quot;disguise&quot; pig organs as human organs so that the human immune system cannot distinguish them, thereby reducing the body&#39;s immune rejection of foreign organs. Three of the genes were &quot;knocked out,&quot; or inactivated, to eliminate alpha galactose from the pig cells, a sugar that triggers a severe reaction in the body&#39;s immune system, leading to organ rejection. In addition, six human genes were introduced into the pig genome to improve acceptance by the human immune system, and another pig gene that controls the growth of the pig heart was modified to prevent the pig heart from continuing to overgrow after transplantation into a human. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The recipient of this xenogeneic organ transplant is 58-year-old Lawrence Faucette. According to a University of Maryland Medical Center news release, the patient had advanced heart disease and complications from peripheral vascular disease and internal bleeding that precluded a traditional heart transplant. On September 14, Fawcett was admitted to the University of Maryland Medical Center due to heart failure. Without a pig heart transplant, the patient&#39;s life may be in danger at any time. With the informed consent of the patient and his family, doctors at the center performed a pig heart xenograft surgery on Fawcett on September 20 and injected him with anti-immune rejection antibody drugs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The experimental xenotransplantation procedure received emergency approval from the U.S. Food and Drug Administration&#39;s (FDA) &quot;Compassionate Use&quot; program, which is designed to treat patients when no other treatments are available. Investigational treatment assistance is provided to patients at risk of death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Preliminary observation results show that the patient recovered well two days after the operation, and the implanted pig heart functioned well without any auxiliary facilities.当时患者已能自主说话，能在椅子上坐起来，还能开玩笑。在患者接受手术后的一个月时，马里兰大学医学中心发布了一段视频，显示该患者亦能站立，并能有辅助地行走。当时医生声称暂时没有观察到强烈的免疫排斥反应。不过，器官移植后的1-3个月内是最关键的时期，也是免疫排斥反应最强的时期。根据马里兰大学医学中心发布的最新声明，福赛特先生可能死于免疫排斥，但是最终结果有待进一步公布。负责移植手术的外科医生巴特利·格里菲斯在一份声明中说，“福赛特先生最后的愿望是，让我们充分利用从经验中学到的东西。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;首例猪心脏移植提供了宝贵经验&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2022年开展的第一例猪心脏异种移植临床试验也是由马里兰大学医学中心的外科教授穆罕默德·莫希丁（Muhammad M. Mohiuddin）和巴特利·格里菲斯（Bartley Griffith）领导完成，一名57岁的晚期心脏病男性患者大卫·贝内特被植入了基因改造猪的心脏，猪心脏同样来自Revivicor公司。在移植后的最初几周内，贝内特没有出现急性排斥反应的迹象，但在移植发生的2个月后，他突然因心力衰竭离世。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据莫希丁教授和格里菲斯教授团队发表在国际著名医学杂志《新英格兰医生杂志》的研究论文显示，该患者植入的猪心脏出现严重水肿，重量增加了近一倍，心肌细胞出现分散性的坏死，表现出与异种器官移植存在的免疫排斥典型特征不一致。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据该团队在另一个国际著名医学杂志《柳叶刀》上发表的更详细分析结果显示，可能有多种原因叠加导致了患者的心力衰竭。一方面，患者的内皮广泛损伤，表明患者受到抗体介导的强烈免疫排斥反应，而且他在手术前免疫系统已严重受损，更容易受到免疫系统抗体攻击。另一方面，患者在术后注射了用于抗排斥的抗体药物，也可能导致心肌细胞受损。另外，医生还在植入的猪心脏中检测到猪巨细胞病毒/猪玫瑰疹病毒，可能导致移植功能障碍，不过并没有检测到猪内源性病毒外溢到人体组织中。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，在第一例猪心脏异种移植的基础上，此次异种移植临床试验进行了一些改进，比如利用更灵敏的检测方法，筛查猪细胞是否存在猪内源性病毒，以避免猪内源性病毒对移植功能的干扰，也为了避免猪病毒对人体造成潜在感染。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;需要更多临床试验&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;器官移植供体短缺是全球性医疗难题。据美国器官供体官方网站数据显示，目前约有10.4万名患者登记需要器官移植，其中3000多人需要心脏移植，但是每天约有17名患者因为等不到器官而死亡。 2022年，超过4.2万人接受了器官移植，其中肾脏移植有2.5万多例，肝脏移植有9500多例，心脏移植也有4100多例。器官供体主要依靠志愿者捐献，但是自愿捐献器官率偏低、器官难以配型等问题导致器官供体数量严重不足。由于猪的器官大小、功能和代谢特点等都与人类器官相近，而且猪繁殖能力强，便于进行基因操作，也不像灵长类动物那样存在严重的伦理争议，因此猪器官被认为是人体器官的重要替代品。其实，猪长期以来一直被用于人类医学，包括猪皮移植和猪心脏瓣膜植入。最近几年，中国等国家的科学家还开展了猪胰岛细胞异种移植的人体临床试验，对Ⅰ型糖尿病的疗效不错。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，异种器官移植要成功，需要经受住超急性排斥反应、急性血管性排斥反应和细胞排斥反应等多重考验，因为不同物种之间存在天然的隔阂，其他动物的组织器官很难在人体长期存活。随着基因修饰技术的兴起，科学家眼前突然一亮，如果利用基因修饰技术，将器官供体动物的细胞改造得接近人类细胞，就有望躲过人体免疫系统的攻击。因此，经过基因改造后降低免疫排斥反应的基因改造猪也被认为是解决器官短缺的重要选择。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在人体临床试验之前，异种器官移植的研究主要在动物身上开展，比如将猪的器官移植到狒狒等灵长类动物身上，但是由于这些灵长类动物与人类仍然存在较大的差异，而且灵长类动物器官移植手术成熟程度远低于人体器官移植，因此灵长类动物的异种器官移植试验对人体临床试验的参考价值有限。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为了开展临床试验，研究人员还在脑死亡患者体内进行异种器官移植的尝试。 2021年10月-12月，来自纽约大学朗格尼健康中心（NYU Langone Health）的研究团队宣布，相继将Revivicor公司生产的基因修饰猪肾脏，成功移植到两位已脑死亡并依靠呼吸机维持体征的患者体内。经过两天多的观察，研究人员发现基因改造猪的肾脏不仅继续以正常速率过滤废物并产生尿液，而且还将患者由肾功能不良引起的异常肌酐水平恢复到正常水平，同时在观察期内也没有观察到严重排斥反应。这项临床试验虽然只是在脑死亡患者身上实施，但是基因改造猪肾脏能在体外发挥正常功能，并没有引发严重的排斥反应，这对即将开始的异种器官移植临床试验是一个极大的鼓舞。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然目前两例猪心脏异种移植患者都只是存活了两个月或更短，本次临床试验的医生、患者及其家属也对临床效果并未抱过高期望，但是从某种意义来说，这些勇敢的早期患者为异种器官移植临床应用提供了宝贵经验。比如，第一例异种器官移植手术的结果表明，基因改造猪的心脏可在人体免疫系统受到充分抑制的情况下正常运作，为后来的人体临床试验树立了信心。另外，首例异种器官移植手术也发现了一些容易引起免疫排斥反应的因素和一些潜在的安全风险，这都可以在后面的临床试验中加以避免和排除。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;异种器官移植无疑是一个创新性极高、风险性极大的新疗法，只有开展更多的人体临床试验，才能在真正的人体临床试验中发现问题，才能不断改进异种器官移植手术相关程序，排除潜在风险，不断提高患者的术后生存时间和质量，有望最终让猪的器官在人体中长期健康存活，为那些等不到人体器官的患者带来福音。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 19:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[最高法再审百亿金海矿山案，山西前首富张新明败诉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260044]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2009年山西煤炭资源整合开始后，金海煤矿被单独保留，市价急剧飙升至百亿元。视觉中国/图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/795278dcc0.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/795278dcc0.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2009年山西煤炭资源整合开始后，金海煤矿被单独保留，市价急剧飙升至百亿元。视觉中国/图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾震动司法界的山西“百亿矿山争夺案”，出现重大转折。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;17年前，山西前首富、金业集团董事长张新明及其关联方为缓解资金困局，将手中金海煤矿的股份先后转让给国企山西煤炭运销集团晋城阳城有限公司（下称阳城煤运）和吕中楼执掌的沁和投资有限公司（下称沁和投资）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但随2009年山西煤炭产业拉开兼并重组帷幕，金海煤矿价值急剧飙升，张新明方开始向阳城煤运、沁和投资及其董事长吕中楼发动一系列诉讼，理由是原告向被告转让股权时，价格过低。张新明方在这些诉讼中全部获胜。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金海煤矿，位于山西晋城市阳城县，煤田面积约53.7平方公里，资源总储量4.09亿吨，在煤矿遍布的山西，极其罕见。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此系列案件的判决结果曾引发巨大争议，两位煤炭大佬张新明和吕中楼的命运，也就此走向殊途。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张新明有“山西地下组织部长”之称。2014年8月，张新明在太原被公安机关带走，之后再无消息。山西官场亦地震不断，官员接连落马。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近日，上述系列诉讼中有三起经中华人民共和国最高人民法院（下称最高法）及山西省高级人民法院（下称山西省高院）审理后，均撤销原判，还有一起维持原判。“消失”九年多的张新明，也因这些案件的重启再次回到台前。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年6月，阳城煤运与张新明之子张文扬就金海煤矿的股权纠纷再审，张新明作为其子的诉讼代理人出现在庭审现场。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;知情人士向南方周末记者透露，张新明约于2020年中以保外就医的名义出狱，相关判决书保密。在2020年5月的一张照片中，时年57岁的张新明坐在轮椅上，一身休闲打扮，神情放松。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;综合新旧判决书，一场多方角力的抢矿大战得以重现。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;百亿矿山案与落马最高法副院长&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;2004年，张新明拿到了金海煤矿的采矿权，并为此成立山西金海能源有限公司（下称金海能源），注册资金3000万元。除了在当年3月15日取得金海煤矿的采矿许可证外，该公司没有进行过其它投资与经营。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那一时期，山西煤炭资源还属于行政划拨，或给企业无偿使用，或象征性地交些资源费。这意味着，短时间内，获得新矿的人就能攫取暴利。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金海煤矿的矿产资源费共2.24亿元（0.55元/吨），分6年缴清。2004年5月，金海能源交纳了首期3738.49万元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年，金海能源资金短缺，开始引入外部投资者。当时在金海能源，张新明及其相关自然人持股60%，北京鑫业投资有限公司（以下称北京鑫业）持股40%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在上述60%股权中&lt;span>;，张新明持股17%，其子张文扬持股40%，冯小林持股2%，王向东持股1%。&lt;/span>;张文扬和冯小林曾在庭审中称，二人均是为张新明代持。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《财经》杂志曾报道，王向东为一位山西省委前主要领导人之子。此案知情人士亦向南方周末记者证实这一点。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京鑫业原执行董事、法定代表人为神秘晋商闫琦。据《财经》杂志，闫琦原为山西省物资厅子弟，后创办山西云长房地产公司。在其职业生涯中，从未涉足煤炭开采。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;闫琦之后创办了三亚鹿回头旅游区开发有限公司，开发了著名的别墅大盘“半山半岛”，其旗下企业还有三亚爱地房地产公司、香港天福公司。&lt;span>;2015年，闫琦以90亿元资产位列胡润富豪榜中海南首富。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2005年12月，金海能源和阳城煤运签订股权转让协议，张文扬、北京鑫业分别出让13%、15%股权，阳城煤运为这些股权支付了840万元的转让价款，折合30万元/股，与每股注册资本金价格相同。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，阳城煤运为北京鑫业和金业集团（张新明任董事长）旗下跃峰洗煤厂各提供2.8亿元委托贷款，期限6年，利息按银行同期存款利率计算。获得金海煤矿28%股权后，阳城煤运又缴纳了7476万元资源价款，金海能源的采矿权得以延续。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2007年，金海能源又拉吕中楼的沁和投资入股。当年9月，金海能源6名股东与沁和投资共同签订股权转让协议书。张新明、张文扬、冯小林、北京鑫业分别将17%、27%、2%以及15%的股权，转让给沁和投资。后者支付股权转让金1830万元，同样是30万元/股。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，沁和投资亦向北京鑫业提供3.75亿元5年期无息借款，连同张新明三方签订借款协议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京鑫业将股权转让给沁和投资后，双方又签订了一份补充协议，将北京鑫业15%股权的转让款由450万元变更为2亿元，此前约定的3.75亿元的借款失效。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到了2009年，王向东1%的股权也以30万元的价格转让给沁和投资。至此，金海能源股东变为沁和投资、阳城煤运和北京鑫业，三方各持股62%、28%、10%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这时，山西煤炭资源开启兼并重组，金海煤矿却被单独保留，市价急剧飙升至百亿元。据上述报道，2009年上半年，张新明多次劝说吕中楼以9亿元卖掉62%的金海煤矿股权，但吕不同意。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;之后，张新明开始起诉沁和投资，要求解除股权转让协议，理由是金海煤矿每股股权价值远大于30万元。官司一路打至最高法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;最高法引用案外人北京鑫业和沁和投资的补充协议，参照北京鑫业所持金海能源15%股权转让款变更为2亿元，认为沁和投资从张新明处受让的46%&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;的股权市场价值应超过&lt;/span>;6亿元，沁和投资支付的款项“明显低于涉案股权的市场价值”，并据此维持原审法院支持张新明方解除合同、让沁和返还股权的请求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该案于2012年9月作出判决，案号为“（2011）民二终字第76号”，也称“76号判决”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这起判决引起了巨大争议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2013年1月，针对“76号判决”的两场研讨会在京召开，法学家江平、中国社会科学院教授梁慧星、中国政法大学教授李曙光等三十余名民商法学者出席讨论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁慧星在上述研讨会上称，如果煤炭价不涨，也就没有了这个案子。他认为，“最高法院依据公平原则，作出判决，这是错误的。”既然双方当事人都是商人，那么双方约定的就是公平的，只要不违法，不损害国家和社会利益，法院就没有权力干预。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;时任最高法副院长&lt;span>;奚晓明还曾将此案编著进《最高人民法院商事审判指导案例(2012)公司与金融》&lt;/span>;一书中。2015年7月，奚晓明因涉嫌严重违纪违法被调查，最终被控收受1.14亿元巨额财物贿赂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据《财新》报道，张新明通过掮客向奚晓明行贿3000万元，其中1800万元给了奚晓明之子奚嘉诚，余下1200万元归奚晓明所有。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“76号判决”为最高法终审判决，如果对判结果不服，沁和投资还可以向最高检申请抗诉。吕中楼对南方周末记者表示，沁和投资正在准备申请抗诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“76号判决”之外，2010年至2012年，阳城煤运、沁和投资及吕中楼等相关方也先后遭到张新明及其关联人、北京鑫业的起诉，诉求皆为解除金海煤矿股权转让协议，各方归还股权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中，便有此次再审的4起案件。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;重新启动&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;另一接近金海煤矿股权纠纷案的知情人士告诉南方周末记者，这一系列诉讼沉寂10年都没什么动静，他是2022年年底突然得知，案件要重新启动，2023年开春之后，审理节奏又逐渐放缓，进入正常节奏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月，阳城煤运接连收到两份终审判决，分别来自最高法和山西省高院，落款时间分别为2023年9月7日和9月18日，均撤销原判。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2011年和2012年，张文扬和北京鑫业先后将阳城煤运告上法庭，他们辩称金海能源转让给阳城煤运的28%股权包括5.6亿元贷款本金，请判双方股权转让协议无效，并返还股权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;两起案件的原审法院山西省高院和山西省晋城市中院均引用“76号判决”，认为金海能源“每股30万元的转让价格不是协议双方真实意思表示&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”，&lt;/span>;从而支持张文扬和北京鑫业。阳城煤运不服，分别上诉至最高法和山西省高院，此后两起案件再无进展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;本次负责终审的最高法和山西省高院则认为，涉案金海能源28%股权的全部转让对价既包括转让协议中明确约定的840万元，又包括张新明方通过委托贷款方式低息使用5.6亿元6年的商业利益。因此撤销原判，认可股权转让协议的有效性。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“市场经济法律制度的核心要求就是保护产权，这两份判决展现了最高法对于市场交易秩序及市场主体意思表达的尊重。”阳城煤运代理律师胡晓勇向南方周末记者表示。他从2012年起接手阳城煤运和张新明方的股权纠纷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“商业利益可理解为机会价值。”胡晓勇解释，张新明方获得了6年低息使用数亿元资金的机会价值，然后用于投资其它地产项目，从而获得巨额商业利益。这部分商业利益共同构成了股权转让价款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2023&lt;/span>;年9月18日，最高法也作出了北京鑫业诉沁和投资的终审判决，撤销原判，支持了沁和投资的部分请求。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2011&lt;/span>;年，北京鑫业起诉沁和投资称，双方约定沁和投资以借款方式将15%的股权转让款转给北京鑫业，共计3.75亿元，每股2500万元。&lt;span>;北京鑫业如约将股权信息变更到沁和投资名下&lt;/span>;，沁和投资仅支付2亿元，还有1.75亿元未付。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京鑫业认为沁和投资构成根本违约，一审请判解除双方股权转让协议和借款协议，并让后者返还股权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在案件审理过程中，北京鑫业法定代表人闫琦否认其与沁和投资签订过补充协议，即股权转让款由450万元变更为2亿元，还报警称补充协议是“伪造的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山西省高院的一审判决同样引用“76号判决”，表示“76号判决”与上述案涉15%股份“是基于相同的背景、在同一次股东会议、同一时间、以每股相同的价格同时变更的”，认为“每股30万元股权转让价格明显偏低”。最终作出协议无效、沁和投资返还股权的判决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;沁和投资不服上述一审判决并向最高法提起上诉。2013年5月29日，最高法立案后组成合议庭进行了审理，没有下文。2023年1月，最高法合议庭变更后再次审理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本次，最高法采信了补充协议，从而认定沁和投资应向北京鑫业支付2亿元股权转让价款。最终认可沁和投资已支付1.47265亿元股权转让款，对应所有11.044875%股权，判令沁和投资向北京鑫业返还剩余3.955125%的股权。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“基本上公平。”沁和投资代理律师姬敬武对南方周末记者表示，但这份判决仍有不尽如人意之处。在他看来，北京鑫业已在一审中自认沁和投资支付了2亿元股权转让款，那么沁和投资无需再对此举证。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在此基础上，姬敬武认为，&lt;span>;北京鑫业以沁和投资没有履行借款协议为由的诉讼请求不能成立，法院就应依法驳回北京鑫业的诉讼请求，而目前的判决结果则是改变了其诉讼请求&lt;/span>;。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“腾笼换鸟”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;目前仍有一起再审维持原判，也是再审4起案件中最早出的一个判决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2009年3月12日，金海能源股东王向东签署授权书，将金海能源股权转让一事，委托闫琦全权处理。闫琦担任过北京鑫业和金海能源的法定代表人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当年4月9日，闫琦代王向东与沁和投资签订股权转让协议，约定王向东将其持有的1%股权，作价30万元转让给沁和投资。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2011年11月，王向东将沁和投资告上法庭，理由亦是股权转让价过低，请判解除转让协议，返还股权。该案历经两次审理，山西省高院二审于2012年9月27日维持原判，支持王向东。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;王向东在庭审中认可授权书的真实性，但称其对股权转让的情况不知情，也没同意把价值高于2000万元的股权以30万元的注册资本价值进行转让。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;两审法院都认为，30万元的股权转让价格明显低于闫琦和沁和投资明知的转让价格，双方未经王向东同意，以明显过低的价格转让了王向东的股权，损害其利益，闫琦与沁和投资的行为构成恶意串通。沁和投资不服，向最高法申请再审。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原审法院判断闫琦明知股权转让价格过低的主要根据，是北京鑫业与沁和投资签订的补充协议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年4月28日，最高法对此案作出终审判决，仍以补充协议为依据，认定金海能源1%的股权将超过1300万元，闫琦及沁和投资共同损害了王向东的权益，维持原判。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在姬敬武看来，王向东和沁和投资间的案子是金海煤矿股权纠纷系列诉讼中最简单的一个，“这么简单的案子需要审10年吗？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他认为，王向东是全权委托闫琦办理股权转让事宜，那么闫琦代王向东和沁和投资签署的股权转让协议并没有超过代理权限。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，在本案判决前，补充协议的真实性并未受到任何法院认可。其次，即便该协议真实，法院依据一份案外人的协议，认定本案股权转让价格偏低也不合理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不知股东之间的纷争可否就此停歇。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;目前，历经再审后的金海能源，股权架构变为：张新明方46%、阳城煤运28%、北京鑫业13.955125%%、沁和投资11.044875%、王向东1%。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本应大放异彩的金海煤矿，这些年一直处于停滞状态。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;山西省人民政府安全生产委员会办公室发布的2021年度煤矿分类名单显示，金海煤矿为D类煤矿，即长期停工停产煤矿。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，金海煤矿或将有新进展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年3月，金海煤矿出现在2021年山西省属国有企业“腾笼换鸟”首批发布项目名单里，所属省管国企为晋能控股集团有限公司（下称晋能集团）。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“腾笼换鸟”是山西国企改革的重点举措，具体包括通过处置低效无效资产，有效盘活沉淀资金；通过出让部分股权，收回现金的同时引入各类资本，实现股权多元化；通过出让上市公司部分股份获得资金，优化上市公司股权结构等。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金海煤矿之所以由晋能集团负责，可能是因为晋能集团控股阳城煤运。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2022年6月20日，阳城县人民政府办公室发布《关于成立阳城大宁金海煤矿项目建设领导组的通知》，通知称，金海煤矿计划2022年四季度正式开工，建设工期为两年。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南方周末记者通过电话、短信多次约访张文扬（替张新明代持）和北京鑫业的代理律师，二人均婉拒采访。&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[烂尾楼生活翻篇了，昆明“别样幸福城”业主圆了住房梦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260052]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从“全国”到“中央”， 这些会议在升格]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260058]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月31日，中央金融工作会议闭幕。人民视觉供图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/1d131217ee.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;648&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/06/1d131217ee.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257184&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月31日，中央金融工作会议闭幕。人民视觉供图&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2023年10月31日，中央金融工作会议闭幕，“金融强国”这一概念首次被提出。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;“金融不强，血脉不通。”中央党校（国家行政学院）中国式现代化研究中心主任张占斌告诉南方周末记者，“金融强国”这一概念在中央金融工作会议上首次被提出，体现出金融工作的紧迫性。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;会议名称定为“中央金融工作会议”，更是体现了中央对金融工作高度重视。上一次召开金融领域的高规格会议还是在2017年，会议名称是“全国金融工作会议”，有5位政治局常委出席。而这次，7位政治局常委悉数出席，会议通稿4次出现“必须坚持党中央对金融工作的集中统一领导”等相关表述。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;不仅是金融工作会议，南方周末记者梳理发现， 中共十八大以来，全国政法工作会议、全国统战工作会议、全国城市工作会议、全国人才工作会议等已先后升格为以中央名义召开的工作会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;华南师范大学政治学与行政学系主任阮思余，长期研究会议政治，在他看来，原来的全国工作会议，一般都是系统内的会议，升格为以中央名义召开的工作会议，体现了党中央对该领域的重视，也便于加强集中统一领导，“很多问题在部门内部解决不了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“金融监管和治理能力薄弱” &lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在经济发展中，金融起到“血脉”的作用。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;张占斌认为，当前金融领域大案要案频发，金融监管仍存在问题，金融体系尚需健全，需要维护金融安全稳定，守住不发生系统性风险的底线，“对标金融强国蓝图，差距体现在方“很多问题在部门内部解决不了”。方面面”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中央金融工作会议明确指出，“金融领域各种矛盾和问题相互交织、相互影响，有的还很突出，经济金融风险隐患仍然较多，金融服务实体经济的质效不高，金融乱象和腐败问题屡禁不止，金融监管和治理能力薄弱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;早在2023年3月，中共中央、国务院印发的《党和国家机构改革方案》中，已提出组建中央金融委员会和中央金融工作委员会。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中央金融工作会议指出，要完善党领导金融工作的体制机制，发挥好中央金融委员会和中央金融工作委员会的作用，落实属地责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在张占斌看来，这体现了中央领导金融工作的决心，有助于消除经济发展中所存在的各个地方一味追求局部利益，而忽视国家全局利益和社会整体效益的一些做法。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;开会时间短，准备时间长&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对于全国金融工作会议升格为中央金融工作会议，阮思余的理解是，前者通常由国务院某个部委组织，而后者是在中央组织指导之下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中共十八大以来，先是全国政法工作会议在2014年升格为中央政法工作会议，此后，全国统战工作会议、全国城市工作会议、全国人才工作会议等相继升格。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在阮思余看来，会议升格不仅体现出党中央对某一领域的重视，在实践层面，党中央和地方党委协调工作更加顺畅，很多问题“需要党委出面整体推进”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;以人才工作为例，2021年，“全国人才工作会议”升格为“中央人才工作会议”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;会议要求完善党委统一领导，组织部门牵头抓总，职能部门各司其职、密切配合，社会力量广泛参与的人才工作格局。各级政府教育、科技、工信、安全、人社、文旅、国资、金融、外事等部门，充分发挥职能作用，共同抓好人才工作各项任务落实。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;过去一些部门开展人才工作没有抓手，组织部门抓人才工作，但社保问题需要人社部门解决，如果引进教师，又离不开教育部门的政策。阮思余认为，在党中央和地方党委高度重视，要求各部门在人才问题上做好文章后，提高了各部门工作的积极性和主动性，“有了更大的空间”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在会议程序上，中央名义召开的工作会议“开会时间很短，但会议的准备很长”，对有关问题的研究比较成熟，对未来的发展方向和改革思路有明确指示。全国工作会议多数只涉及政策吹风、工作总结和任务布置。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;以中央名义召开的工作会议结束后，会在全国层面开展全方位宣传，同时纪委监委也会对贯彻落实党的路线方针政策开展巡视巡查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;除了全国性工作会议升格，中共十八大后还以中央名义召开了一些此前未开过的会议。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;2019年党中央召开了中央政协工作会议，两年后又召开了中央人大工作会议，这在中国共产党历史上都是首次。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[福原爱或面临2年以上监禁：抚养权的归属应以有利于孩子成长为原则丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260062]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-06 15:05:14&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;福原爱与台湾人江宏杰的婚恋及婚变，一直广受媒体的关注。目前，因遭前夫向警方刑事控诉，“福原爱或面临2年以上有期徒刑”，在社交媒体引发大量讨论。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大陆网友对福原爱素有好感，她长得可爱，熟稔中文，一口玉米馇子味的东北话令人倍感亲切。在福原爱出轨与婚变之后，许多大陆网友仍以“娘家人”自居，愿意为她说话。这就导致了一个很有意思的现象：目前，福原爱在日本与台湾的舆论形象是比较负面的，但在大陆还是偏正面的。这大概就是真爱的力量。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;福原爱生于1988年，3岁开始打乒乓球，曾是日本国家队主力，参加过多届奥运会，或是最受国人喜欢的日本运动员。江宏杰则是台北队乒乓球选手。两人于2016年9月官宣结婚，2017年产下一女，2019年又生一男，2021年7月宣布离婚。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在婚变之前，有日媒报道称：福原爱表面上看起来很幸福，其实默默忍受了丈夫及其家人多年的语言暴力；婆家还把她当摇钱树。从中读出的信息是，江宏杰全家“吃软饭”，还不感恩，当时舆论对福原爱是一边倒的同情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，很快事情就出现了大转折。福原爱在婚内被媒体拍到与一已婚男子有非常亲密的举止，又同去酒店过夜。当时她不承认自己出轨，说对方是自己的好朋友，两人是一人住一间房。在离婚后，福原爱与该男子公开谈起了恋爱。然后，该男子的前妻出来控诉，他们离婚就是因为福原爱第三者插足，这让福原爱苦心经营的人设与形象一下子崩了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坦率讲，江宏杰及其家人对福原爱有言语轻慢与凌辱，将她当挣钱工具，外人无从确认真假，只能见仁见智。不过，福原爱此后出轨与撒谎被抓了现行，成了实锤，就降低了这些爆料的可信度。不少人会猜测：这些所谓爆料就是因为自己另有新欢，为了降低婚变对自己的道德压力与舆论指责，而刻意向媒体投喂的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而且，在福原爱被曝出轨时，她的母亲还在江宏杰家，此后很快回日本。媒体报道称，母亲是自认没有立场、也不好意思再继续待下去，才决意回日本的。后来，母亲更是拒绝与福原爱同住，说明对她出轨与离婚是有看法的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今年7月27日，江宏杰在日本召开发布会，表示：由于福原爱完全失联，他已经一年没见到孩子了。此前，福原爱以探访为由，偷偷将儿子从台湾带回日本。江宏杰宣布：“有件事想报告一下，在7月20号收到日本法院的裁判结果，内容是法院要求福原爱小姐将孩子交付给我的命令。很感谢日本法院的判决，也很希望赶快跟孩子见面。”福原爱则通过律师声明：日本法院的裁定只是暂时处分，并不是最后的判决。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;显然，两个多月过去了，事情还没有解决，所以江宏杰采取了进一步法律行动。根据日本刑法，有“未成年者略取及诱拐罪”（第224条），实施者可判3月以上7年以下惩役；有“所在国外移送目的的略取及诱拐”（第226条），将人略取及诱拐至国外，可判2年以上惩役。这和实施者是不是亲人及有没有以营利为目的无关。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，江宏杰的目的是要回儿子，而不是让福原爱坐牢。此事如何发展，还得继续观察。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对此事可以延伸出两点直接解读。一是日本社会的法治观念还是挺强的。法院判决，尊重事情的是非曲直与法理，既不和稀泥，也不承认既成事实，更没有因为福原爱是日本国籍而倾向于她。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二是日本社会的家庭观念与道德观念还是挺强的。舆论对婚内出轨及谎言的容忍度很低。自诉婚姻不幸福要追求自由与真爱可以，但烦请把婚离了再说。一个公众人物，在婚内出轨，又对大众撒谎，在出轨被实锤、谎言被戳破之后，所遭受的反噬与后坐力会相当之大，本人的人设、形象与事业都会受到极大的影响。在公众看来，在有这些前科的基础上，偷偷将孩子从父亲那里带走，又拒不履行法庭的命令，道德与法律上都不占理，很难予以共情与同情。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更进一步的思考是：哪怕婚前海誓山盟，某些婚姻总会破裂，有孩子的话，往往会涉及抚养权的争夺。一方要另一方不要，这好办，通过离婚协议书就可以解决。双方都要或都不要，就比较难办。国内已有夫妻要离婚，都不想要孩子的抚养权，然后法院不准离婚的案例，这里面最惨的是孩子。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双方都要孩子的抚养权，协议解决不了，最后闹到法院，法院该怎么判？当然应该考虑孩子的意愿，想跟哪一方，不过孩子很小时没法表达自己的意愿，或孩子所表达的意愿未必符合自己的最大利益，法院又如何考量呢？还是要考虑由哪一方监护最有利于孩子的身心健康与成长，不能把成年男女的利益置于孩子的利益之上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一方有更好的经济条件与教育背景，有正当稳定的职业，当是一个优势因素。因为孩子与这样的父亲或母亲一起生活，不仅生活上能得到更好的照顾，大人本身也是一个好的榜样，能通过言传身教给孩子更好的家庭教育，尤其是价值观教育，更有利于孩子良好品性的养成。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果离婚过程中一方有重大过错，违反了道德或法律，显示了个人价值观与品性有问题，那孩子跟随这样的大人生活，价值观可能会被带歪。很少有人会正视自己的错误，所以在自己有重大过错时，要么会扭曲事实，给孩子错误的叙事版本，要么扭曲判断是非的标准也就是价值观，例如把自己出轨美化为真爱至上。无论哪一种情形，对孩子的成长都是不利的，或让孩子憎恨没有过错的大人，或让孩子的心智与价值观迥异于一般人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;故而，如果必须通过法院来决定孩子抚养权的归属，应确立最有利于孩子成长的原则，让孩子留在最爱TA的大人身边，而不应该纵容通过争夺抚养权以争夺更多的财产份额，或把争夺抚养权当成报复另一半的手段。孩子应该是目的，而不是工具。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>