<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[解构“讲课费”，数读藏起来的医药腐败丨H5]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258351]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打击缅北电诈有重要突破！揪出幕后“金主”、组织头目23名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258333]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p class=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;span>;From June 25 to September 30 this year, the Party Committee of the Ministry of Public Security Based on the characteristics of public security and the security and stability situation, we coordinated and directed the public security organs across the country to mobilize all police officers and go all out to carry out a summer public security crackdown and rectification operation to crack down on various illegal crimes and severely rectify outstanding public security problems, referred to as &quot;Summer Operation&quot;. On October 10, the Ministry of Public Security held a press conference to introduce the measures and overall results of the summer public security crackdown and rectification operations carried out by public security agencies across the country. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/12bb94e7ad11a35ebaacaedc57bc199b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 640&quot; height=&quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/12bb94e7ad11a35ebaacaedc57bc199b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253568&quot; data-mce-width=&quot; 0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ministry of Public Security: 2,317 suspects in northern Myanmar arrested for crimes involving China&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ministry of Public Security&quot; Yin Chunji, deputy director of the Office of Summer Operation and deputy director of the Public Security Administration, said at a press conference held on the 10th that the Ministry of Public Security insisted on opening the way during the &quot;Summer Operation&quot; and formed a severe and high-pressure situation. The Ministry of Public Security deployed a special operation to crack down on China-related crimes in northern Myanmar, strengthened border police cooperation, and captured and handed over 2,317 China-related fraud suspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the Ministry of Public Security, under the command and deployment of the Yunnan Provincial Public Security Department, the Pu&#39;er Public Security Bureau further expanded its results. 209 telecommunications network fraud suspects were successfully handed over to us on October 1. At the same time, Lincang Public Security Bureau&#39;s border police law enforcement cooperation has made significant progress. The relevant local law enforcement departments in Myanmar handed over 497 telecommunications network fraud suspects to us in two batches on September 25 and October 7 respectively. This is another important breakthrough made by the Yunnan public security agencies in border police cooperation, following the Xishuangbanna and Puer public security agencies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At present, relevant criminal suspects have been detained by public security organs in Inner Mongolia, Heilongjiang, Zhejiang, Anhui, Fujian, Henan, Chongqing and other places involved in the case. The public security organs will thoroughly investigate all the facts of his crimes, and while cracking down on fraud crimes in accordance with the law, they will also dig deep into related crimes such as black and gray products in the country to ensure that the entire chain is cracked down and severely punished in accordance with the law. After continuous and effective crackdowns, &lt;strong>;2,317 suspects of telecommunications network fraud in northern Myanmar have been successfully captured and handed over to us,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;including 23 behind-the-scenes “financiers”, organizational leaders and backbones. , there are 94 people at large online, which has effectively squeezed the living space of overseas fraudsters. Recently, the number of telecommunications network fraud cases across the country has shown a clear downward trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;During the &quot;Summer Operation&quot;, the Ministry of Public Security solved a total of 566,000 criminal cases&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yin Chunji introduced at the press conference that during the operation, the Ministry of Public Security solved a total of 566,000 criminal cases. There were 566,000 criminal cases, 2.042 million public security cases were investigated and handled, and 975,000 suspected criminals were arrested; 2.846 million conflicts and disputes were resolved, and 865,000 hidden security risks were eliminated; the 110 criminal and public security police reports nationwide decreased by 13.8% year-on-year respectively. , 5.2%. The number of road traffic accidents and deaths nationwide dropped by 11.5% and 16.7% respectively year-on-year. The action achieved the expected goals. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ministry of Public Security: 38 gang-related organizations have been beaten since &quot;Operation Summer&quot;! &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Xiang, deputy director of the &quot;Summer Operation&quot; Office of the Ministry of Public Security and deputy director of the Criminal Investigation Bureau, introduced at a press conference held on the 10th that public security agencies in various places have deepened the normalization of crackdowns on gangs and evil. The struggle has further developed in depth. Since the &quot;Summer Operation&quot;, a total of 38 gang-related organizations, 430 evil groups, and 286 evil gangs have been eliminated, and 8,146 criminal suspects have been captured. Among them, the &quot;fish that slipped through the net&quot; was captured. 348 fugitives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Xiang said that all localities accurately grasp the characteristics of summer crime patterns and insist on &quot;quickly, accurately and ruthlessly&quot; cracking down on all kinds of illegal and criminal activities such as provoking troubles, gatherings to fight, intentional injury, robbery and robbery, and digging deep into the underworld. Based on the clues of evil forces, 238 evil gangs were eliminated and 1,808 criminal suspects were arrested. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Since the &quot;Summer Operation&quot;, the Ministry of Public Security has recovered 683 missing and abducted women and children&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zheng Xiang said at a press conference held on the 10th, With a &quot;zero-tolerance&quot; attitude, public security agencies in various places have carried out in-depth special operations to crack down on crimes of trafficking in women and children, crimes of sexual assault, and crimes of medical insurance fraud. Since &quot;Operation Summer&quot;, 212 criminal suspects suspected of abducting and trafficking women and children have been captured, and 683 missing abducted women and children have been recovered; 16,000 criminal suspects suspected of committing sexual assault have been captured; and criminal suspects suspected of committing medical insurance fraud have been captured 1,657 people were recruited and 83 criminal gangs were eliminated, effectively deterring crime. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Fight scalpers! The Ministry of Public Security has determined that more than 50,000 &quot;scalper&quot; accounts have been intercepted&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Yin Chunji introduced at a press conference held on the 10th that the public security organs were involved in pornography, gambling, guns and explosions, and scalpers. We have always maintained a &quot;zero tolerance&quot; attitude towards illegal crimes such as ticketing. In the &quot;Summer Operation&quot;, public security departments across the country insisted on focusing on both prevention and control and controlling the source, and mainly adopted measures in three aspects:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;First, focused on carrying out a special attack on &quot;eradicating pornography, gambling and controlling the source&quot;. After the &quot;Summer Operation&quot; began, the Ministry of Public Security listed and supervised the handling of 173 major pornographic gambling cases, and deployed four rounds of cluster campaigns against 30 series of pornographic gambling cases. In accordance with the unified deployment, public security agencies in various places carried out a series of special projects to &quot;eradicate pornography and gambling and control the source&quot; and arrested more than 7,000 suspects. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The second is to deepen special operations to crack down on gun explosion crimes. Together with relevant police departments, we launched a cluster campaign on 4 major gun-related cases focusing on the three key areas of domestic manufacturing and trafficking, online sales, and overseas smuggling. We checked 3,084 clues involved and solved 53 cases. During the &quot;Summer Operation&quot;, the Ministry of Public Security organized more than 170 cities across the country to carry out intensive activities to destroy illegal firearms and explosives, safely destroying more than 140,000 firearms such as air rifles and shotguns, as well as a large number of explosives, detonators and other explosives confiscated in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The third is to carry out in-depth special work to crack down on &quot;scalpers&quot;. In response to the implementation of Category B and B control measures for COVID-19 infections, the Ministry of Public Security held a video conference to organize local public security agencies to continue to carry out special crackdowns on issues such as commercial performances, events, and ticket scalping in popular scenic spots. Since the operation, a total of 19,000 online ticket scalping clues have been investigated in various places, more than 900 criminal suspects have been arrested, 12,000 tickets of various types have been seized, a number of ticketing platforms have been interviewed and rectified, and more than 300 illegal ticket online stores have been delisted and dealt with. More than 50,000 &quot;scalper&quot; accounts were intercepted, effectively maintaining the order of the ticketing market and the healthy development of the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 16:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男版《俗女养成记》，Loser的一生，也要好好过]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258329]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;&lt;span>;Since 2021, Ruby Lin has As a producer, he rode the wave of the revival of Taiwanese dramas and launched many popular dramas: the female entrepreneurship drama &quot;The Story of Their Entrepreneurship&quot;, the suspense-style female group drama &quot;The First Light of the Night&quot;, and the The large-scale crime suspense drama &quot;Copycat&quot;, and she achieved a reputation reversal with these popular dramas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the Douban short review section of the latest Taiwanese drama &quot;In This Lifetime&quot;, everyone also gave unanimous praise - &quot;I am willing to pay Ruby Lin to make 100 films a year.&quot; &quot;Ruby Ruby&#39;s production is a guarantee of quality. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;While affirming the quality of the series, she also affirmed her vision as a producer. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/d36a3561e1cf83ce44d25b8e265723f2.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;684&quot; height=&quot;53&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/d36a3561e1cf83ce44d25b8e265723f2.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253541 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/25676c20aca338526690775999aa6040.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;686&quot; height=&quot;71&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/25676c20aca338526690775999aa6040.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253543&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The Taiwanese drama &quot;Once Upon a Time&quot; scored a high score of 8.8 after its premiere. It is one of the most popular Chinese dramas in recent times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/ed05668b911d5233ada1f1356b8c92e6.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1523&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/ed05668b911d5233ada1f1356b8c92e6.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253546&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It brings together the backbone of the Taiwanese film and television industry: director Xu Zhaoren, who has directed dramas such as &quot;Love Knot Chitose&#39;s First Love&quot;, &quot;Skyscraper&quot; and &quot;Love Is Delicious&quot;; screenwriter Du Zhengzhe is Ruby Lin&#39;s The gold medal partner has worked together in &quot;16 Summers&quot; and &quot;The Lights Are Coming&quot; and won the Golden Bell Award; in terms of actors, there are young actors like Wu Kangren, Zheng Yuanchang, and Zhang Rongrong, as well as veteran actors like Xixiang and Yang Guimei. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For countless audiences who have watched the film, the story of &quot;In This Life Time&quot; is no stranger. It is similar to the movie &quot;A Man Called Ove Decides to Die&quot; 》Similarly, it also relies on the idea of ​​​​&quot;suicide&quot;. Introduced from the perspective of the male protagonist, it peels away the ordinary daily life, pays attention to the close connection between people, and then draws the conclusion that this connection is both a dilemma and a harbor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/72b9154b128945f585394a4613352694.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;432&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/72b9154b128945f585394a4613352694.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253544&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The 41-year-old male protagonist Gao Jiayue (played by Wu Kangren) is a &quot;loser&quot; in the secular sense. When he was young, he took NT$1 million given by his mother to open a restaurant in a foreign country. However, the business failed and the restaurant was on the verge of bankruptcy. At the same time, his girlfriend of 12 years also openly cheated on her and became pregnant with someone else&#39;s child. A third party came not only to destroy the store, but also to &quot;rob&quot; his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gao Jiayue parted ways with his girlfriend, but he still couldn’t figure out what his problem was. His girlfriend mocked him: “You will never understand what I’m talking about in this life, but you can consider reincarnation, maybe in the next life. You will understand.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/1f4c7850048146d8a0d6da9400ad6164.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style =&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;587&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/1f4c7850048146d8a0d6da9400ad6164.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;253542&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;These words from his girlfriend stimulated Gao Jiayue&#39;s thoughts of committing suicide. He attempted suicide several times without success. Then he decided to dive into the depths of the sea, unplug his oxygen tank, throw away his equipment, and wait for death. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But when he was floating alone on the sea, he suddenly thought of his family. This gave him the idea of ​​saying goodbye. &lt;span>;So, after being away from home for more than ten years, he returned home again and reconnected with his family and the world as an &quot;uninvited guest&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/8bd33b1a2f650d969b653b2a306d3b2a.png&quot; border=&quot;0 &quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;521&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/8bd33b1a2f650d969b653b2a306d3b2a.png&quot; data- key=&quot;253545&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The title of the drama &quot;In My Lifetime&quot; is actually the name of Gao Jiayue&#39;s suicide note: it was originally named &quot;Suicide Note&quot;, but he crossed it out; it was changed to &quot;The Long Farewell&quot; Finally, he crossed it out again; he was afraid that the &quot;suicide note&quot; was too heavy and the &quot;farewell&quot; was too sad. After repeated evaluation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, he finally wrote this line - &quot;It is not bad to grow up to this size in my lifetime.&quot; Now.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/d3547b32691eb58587672f3d83d23041.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;459&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/d3547b32691eb58587672f3d83d23041.jpeg&quot; data-key &quot;253547&quot; They are all about &quot;bringing joy in mourning&quot;, painful and funny, so some people call &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; the &quot;male version of &quot;The Development of a Common Girl&quot;&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s just that in &quot;The Story of a Common Girl&quot;, the plight of middle-aged women is directly addressed. The heroine has a clear understanding of her own life dilemma and will speak out without any scruples. Cry loudly. The portrayal of the male protagonist&#39;s situation in &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; is much more restrained, which is more in line with the impression of &quot;a man will not shed tears easily&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/be0777d754785d01a6d9e3d1417dc2ca.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/be0777d754785d01a6d9e3d1417dc2ca.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253548 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Gao Jiayue is the eldest son of the family. When he returned home, he found that everyone in the family was not living as he wished and was going through their own tribulations in life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;My parents have a cold relationship and have been sleeping in separate rooms for many years. My father was cheating on the little nurse in the hospital, and my mother knew it, but for the sake of face, she could only tolerate it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Because he is an adopted son, the second brother Gao Jiayang consciously assumes more support obligations, but he is very tired because of the elders and children. At the same time, he also tries to get in touch with his biological children. parents. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/a43a8e41ba1b3e866e86e16dcd402976.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;502&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/a43a8e41ba1b3e866e86e16dcd402976.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;253549 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The third brother Gao Jiakai does not have a formal job, so he works in his parents&#39; breakfast shop. He obviously has a girlfriend, but he is secretive and dare not let his family know. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;My nephew Gao Chengyou is in his adolescence. He is worried about online dating and causing trouble on campus. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/80d9af27b68486d5b0b557653f747cac.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;412&quot; height=&quot;194&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/80d9af27b68486d5b0b557653f747cac.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;253552 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The arrival of Gao Jiayue is like a fuse, causing family conflicts to break out. He tried hard to please his family, but he always accidentally made the atmosphere at home extremely awkward. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;But even so, the family&#39;s concern still flowed silently into Gao Jiayue&#39;s heart. He came home drunk without saying hello. After going crazy, he passed out on the sofa. His father stayed with him all night. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/0a16336db0c9076fe55be30ef4eb5e8c.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;517&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/0a16336db0c9076fe55be30ef4eb5e8c.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253551 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;There was already a rift between the parents, but in order to make room for Gao Jiayue, they still lived together again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The second brother was lukewarm towards Gao Jiayue. Seeing him doing nothing after returning home, he couldn&#39;t help but beat him: &quot;You are still chewing on the old at this age, don&#39;t you think Is your life a failure?&quot; However, in order to make his eldest brother sleep more comfortably, he took the initiative to buy a mattress for his eldest brother. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Even the nephew Gao Chengyou cares about Gao Jiayue in his own way. Gao Chengyou accidentally saw Gao Jiayue&#39;s suicide note, but instead of revealing his uncle&#39;s secret, he introduced his &quot;online girlfriend&quot; to his uncle, hoping to satisfy Gao Jiayue&#39;s wish to &quot;have a good relationship.&quot; &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/e8a28e183c4bb2461544c634660d2595.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;421&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/e8a28e183c4bb2461544c634660d2595.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253550 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;As a family drama about the flow of life&lt;/span>;, the biggest feature of &quot;Lifetime&quot; is that it firmly grasps the word &quot;life&quot; and captures the warmth in the short stories of the parents. Feeling the sorrow and joy of ordinary people while stumbling. As netizens said, &quot;This is not a drama, this is a documentary.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My nephew Gao Chengyou&#39;s friend encountered &lt;span>;school violence at school and committed suicide by jumping off a building. As a middle school student, Gao Chengyou was more helpless. His most &quot;deviant&quot; move was that with the help of Gao Jiayue, he occupied the school radio room and sang in memory of his friends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/ef5aa78208e68f37dc55cf51b5fcd7c5.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;359&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/ef5aa78208e68f37dc55cf51b5fcd7c5.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;253553 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In terms of shooting techniques&lt;/span>;, the play uses a large number of long shots to express family relationships in space, of which two are the most impressive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One scene is the night Gao Jiayue arrived home and came in drunk. The camera followed him and brought out the relationships and personalities of the Gao family through the process of him embracing his family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In another place, the next night the three brothers of the Gao family celebrated their father&#39;s birthday. In a slightly cramped space, Gao&#39;s mother was comforting Gao Chengyou who had been scolded, while the second brother was blaming&lt;span>;Gao Jiayue, weird He led his son to fool around on campus, while Gao Jiayue retorted absentmindedly and poured vinegar into the pot by mistake for soy sauce...&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;For more than twenty seconds The picture condenses the family&#39;s exciting evening stories and family ties, making people feel that this is a real Fujian family. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/23521f930f48a04a5d7290f3b5017005.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot; opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;319&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/23521f930f48a04a5d7290f3b5017005.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;253554 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; &quot;In This Lifetime&quot; has a total of 12 episodes. The frequency of weekly updates and the soothing plot may prevent it from becoming a big hit. But for lovers of slice-of-life dramas, it&#39;s palatable enough. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This kind of plain and freehand flow of life allows people to relieve their impetuous minds, accept the unsatisfactory life, and feel its warm and healing moments. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 15:25:07 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[老得慢些，死得快些：我的信条与追求]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258160]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently I saw a saying, &quot;Grow slower and die faster.&quot; It may sound a bit confusing at first, but in fact it explains the truth of life very clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To put it simply, a person should try his best to age slowly, keep his mind young, live a quality and glorious life, and once he faces death and there is no way to recover, he should have a good time. , be optimistic about life, and don’t go against objective laws and make meaningless “struggles”. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A friend talked about an incident. An old man had entered the last moments of his life, and a relative with whom he had a very good relationship was out of town. The old man’s children considered letting them see each other for the last time, so they prepared to use the ultimate method to Medical means extend the life of the old man and let him &quot;wait&quot; for his arrival. He considered and refused again and again, on the grounds that it would add unnecessary pain to the old man before he died. Even if it &quot;makes sense&quot; to him, it&#39;s not humane. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone is afraid of the word &quot;old&quot;. Many people are desperately looking for beauty treatments, no matter how much money they spend, they are not afraid of getting old. There are also many people who are obviously old, but they are taboo about being called &quot;aunt&quot; or &quot;uncle&quot;. But physical aging is an objective law that no one can resist. &quot;Are you young? It doesn&#39;t matter, you will be old in two years.&quot; Zhang Ailing&#39;s famous saying fully expresses the impact of the law of aging on the illusion of &quot;eternal youth&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Old&quot; can be divided into two situations. One is that the body ages and the body functions become weaker. The original straight back has collapsed, the original beautiful features have turned into a &quot;mess&quot;, the original speedy steps have turned into slowly moving steps with a cane... The second is psychological or spiritual aging. Some people have a good mentality and appear young, even if they are seventy or eighty years old, they are not old. Some people age faster than their peers under heavy pressure. The so-called &quot;a 30-year-old has a 60-year-old heart&quot; and &quot;premature aging&quot; all have this meaning. The latter type of people is actually more common. Their hallmark is that they want to work hard on the &quot;Hot Wheels&quot; every day, and they also frown and sigh all day long, accompanied by white hair and wrinkled faces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For those who are not involved in childbirth and are pampered, it is relatively easy to achieve the goal of aging slower. Even at different stages of a person, there are big differences. For example, the &quot;Sha Wujing&quot; who was leisurely swimming in the Liusha River back then must be more beautiful than the Sha Wujing who was walking on the road to seek Buddhist scriptures, eating and sleeping in the open and carrying everyone&#39;s luggage on his shoulders. Appear youthful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most people cannot have freedom of wealth, nor can they rely on others to support themselves without working. This will inevitably lead to people plotting for rice and trying their best to get tomorrow’s steamed buns. Because in reality, it is not easy to make a living, and there are all kinds of internal and external frictions all the time, so there are nine out of ten people who are exhausted both mentally and physically. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What to do? As ordinary people, since we cannot change our situation, the only thing we can do is to take it lightly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I once had a neighbor who was in his nineties and could ride a bicycle very fast. Why? In fact, he was not strong when he was young. Instead, he had problems here and there, but he just had a good mentality. Whether you encounter a small trouble or encounter a hurdle that others may think is almost insurmountable, you should be able to deal with it calmly, think less, and worry less. Such people should live longer. &quot;Be heartless and live a long life&quot; may not sound good, but the words are rough and rational, and the mentality of &quot;if you can afford it, let it go&quot; is worth learning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person should work hard when working, and should also &quot;try hard&quot; to rest when resting. That is, he should neither be distracted when he should be working, always thinking about lying down, nor should he be lying down when he should be working. I always think about work when I am resting, and as a result, my work is not good and my rest is not good either. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You can enter the world and you can emerge from it. This is the highest state of life. It seems difficult to achieve, but it is not. How to work and how to rest is a science. As an individual, you must learn to adjust, relax the tight strings in a timely manner, balance work with rest, and laugh at gains and losses. This is a skill that can be mastered. If you can&#39;t do it the first time, do it again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People are afraid of old age and even talk about death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Speaking of &quot;die faster&quot;, this does not conform to the philosophy of many Chinese people. In contrast, it is greed for life and fear of death. Even if you die a moment later, it seems to be good. This is instinctive and understandable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to die slowly, many people (mainly family members of the deceased) do whatever they can to survive. As long as they can breathe one more breath in the human world, they are willing to suffer all kinds of hardships. This mentality has far-reaching influence. Most of the savings of many people&#39;s lives are not spent while enjoying life and raising children, but are thrown into the water in a &quot;surprise attack&quot; one or two months before death. Death is already an irreversible outcome. No matter how much money is spent, it is in vain. At most, it can delay the death a little. In the end, one person will lose both his life and property, and even his children and grandchildren will be burdened with heavy debts. It is really not worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the face of disease, some people are even &quot;scared to death&quot;. As soon as they heard that they had an incurable disease, they would fall into a state of panic and disorder, causing physical and mental harm and exacerbating physical diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most difficult thing in life is to remain transparent on the subject of death. If a slower death equals long-term torture—including torture for children—then the meaning of life will also change. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;My father told me that there was an old lady in the family who lived alone and lived to a ripe old age. She had done &quot;white things&quot; during her lifetime, and she became a favorite story in the village. If a person has seen through life and death, and the true meaning of &quot;disappearance&quot;, what is there to be afraid of, and why must he do it even though he knows it cannot be done? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To let go of life calmly is a kind of great love. It’s not about going against the trend and forcibly delaying death, it’s about cherishing life. Knowing the deadline, waving your hands and going away, isn’t it a kind of optimism towards life? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, there is no need to doubt the significance of saving lives and healing the wounded. Reducing illness and pain in life is a legitimate pursuit. But what we need to take warning from is gambling-like “fighting” in order to die slowly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are reports that after someone learned that he had terminal cancer, he specifically told his closest relatives not to needless treatment, let alone to &quot;intubate&quot; himself when he was dying, so as not to spend more money. . Having such an open heart is a rational choice after insight. Of course, financial hardship is also one of the reasons, but in general, it is still based on optimism about life and great love for family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To grow old slowly and die quickly is my creed and pursuit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 14:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[有冇蛋散？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257980]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/LSoqRSrnSyZBlr1s57t36ByNrvH2VbqJ0Lb9A70o.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/LSoqRSrnSyZBlr1s57t36ByNrvH2Vb qJ0Lb9A70o. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252439&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Song Dong&#39;s work &quot;You Are There&quot;. Standing below and looking up, I appear in the mirror, caught in a fishing net, with age symbols on the left and right. This is where different eras, regions and myself meet &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (Liu Lang/Photo) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Look, everyone, this is the &#39;Big Egg Powder&#39; that has become very popular recently -&quot; A teacher-looking person pointed to the exhibit behind him with one hand and held up a microphone with the other, speaking to the person in front of him. said a dozen young people. They were wearing uniform white short T-shirts. It was probably a summer vacation activity organized by a nearby school. On August 29, 2023, the second GDMoA Annual Artist Academic Nomination Exhibition was launched at the Guangdong Museum of Art and will last until October 8. The works of the 21 nominated artists are displayed in several exhibition halls on two floors. They are rich in types and styles, attracting a steady stream of visitors. For several consecutive weekends, the admission quota for 1,000 people every half day has been reserved early, and there is a long queue at the entrance of the Guangdong Museum of Art. When the crowds are the strongest, it takes an hour to queue to enter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The most photographed exhibit on social media in this exhibition is the &quot;big egg powder&quot; in front of these students. It was made by artist Feng Yu using bamboo curtains and wooden frames, and is called &quot;Wei&quot;. The work is introduced as &quot;an exploration of ancient space emotions, and also an extreme mechanical challenge to traditional Chinese soft materials.&quot; The bamboo curtains and wooden frames are curled and twisted to form several looping and twisting pipes, occupying nearly half of the venue, standing tall and full to the left and right. The promotion speech written by Zhang Zikang, director of the Central Academy of Fine Arts Art Museum, described it this way, &quot;The artist uses the relaxing combination of the movement rhythm of Chinese calligraphy to form a unique spatial scale experience and emotional experience. Every viewer will have a different feeling when entering it.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/IspoXu1Bh7c0Oomwnsl8AwykobOsjT79lvEohzGi.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/IspoXu1Bh7c0Oomwnsl8AwykobOsjT79lvEohzGi.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252438&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Feng Yu’s work &quot;Wei&quot; is called &quot;Dan San&quot; on social media and is widely circulated&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liu Lang/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Judging from the feedback, in the audience’s feelings, it has derived an image that is more suitable for the Internet context - Dansan. Egg powder is a traditional snack in Guangdong. It is made of flour, gluten flour, eggs and lard, fried in oil until light yellow, scooped up and dipped in maltose before eating. In Cantonese, Dan San also refers to a timid or unpromising little person, taking his characteristic of being &quot;not strong enough&quot;. The color of the bamboo curtain and wooden frame is very similar to the light yellow color of the eggs when they come out of the pot, and the irregular bends are like the appearance of the eggs on the plate. Compared with the words in the recommendation, &quot;This spatial art installation will no longer be retained as the exhibition closes. Just like fireworks and life, no matter how gorgeous and bright they are, they will eventually pass away with the wind...&quot;, it is obvious that &quot;the eggs are scattered&quot; Closer to young people’s daily experience. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A work that is also highly visible on the Internet is the artist Song Dong&#39;s &quot;You&quot;, which is very Cantonese from its name - &quot;无&quot; comes from Cantonese, pronounced mǎo, meaning nothing, This word was first seen in &quot;Guangdong Tongzhi&quot; compiled by Huang Zuo during the reign of Emperor Shizong of the Ming Dynasty. From the perspective of word creation, the word &quot;无&quot; is the provincial meaning of the word &quot;有&quot;. Song Dong, who was born and raised in Beijing, has a close connection with Guangdong. His works were included in the first Guangzhou Art Biennale as early as 1992. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2017, Guangzhou Fei Art Museum invited Song Dong to hold a solo exhibition. He walked around the vegetable market next to the art museum for a long time and thought that the smoky-looking vegetable market should not be separated from the tall Class A office buildings and private art museums next door. Can you make an unbounded wall? So, he built a 106-meter wall made of old windows. It was made of glass and walls. Various exhibitions could be held inside. The name of the work was &quot;Wall without Borders&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The art museum invites residents from surrounding communities to put in small items that they are reluctant to throw away at home, including Teresa Teng’s audio tapes, thermos bottles with double happiness printed on them, and even BB cameras. During the launch, the museum held a long street banquet. Everyone gathered around the 106-meter wall and chatted while eating Poon Choi: &quot;Where is the boundary between life and art?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;Have You&quot;, Song Dong continued his previous style. A rectangular fishing net is pulled out on the second floor of the art museum, and it is covered with about 200 old mirrors. They have different shapes, but they have a unified sense of age. On the back of the mirror are yellowed figure paintings, calendar scenery, and various block letters. words, or clean and old brown wooden boards. When you stand under the work and look up, you will see yourself in the mirror, caught in a fishing net, with age symbols on the left and right. This is where different eras, regions and yourself come together. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Song Dong wrote: &quot;The title of &quot;You&quot; uses the local characters of Guangdong, expressing the juxtaposition of the words &#39;have&#39; and &#39;no&#39; to form the title. I have always believed that nothing is the ultimate The big being is the great nothing. The mirror is not only an indispensable object in life, but also a philosophical object for thinking and understanding. I have been asking &#39;what is a mirror&#39; for a long time, and I think &#39;everything is Mirror&#39;, the mirror divides the world into real and virtual, existence and non-existence. It also integrates real and virtual, existence and non-existence into one place. It is the critical interface between &#39;being&#39; and &#39;empty&#39;. I use a big net to catch The collected mirrors form a &#39;diaphragm&#39;, dividing the space into virtual and real worlds. These mirrors have seen different people and objects, and they are constantly refreshed and vacated. As the saying goes: everything is a mirror body and place. , catching all emptiness and nothingness in one sweep.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This thinking text received another interpretation from the students. After they stared at the &quot;Egg Powder&quot; for a few minutes, the teacher asked: &quot;Do you want to go in and have a look? The original intention of this artwork is to hope that the audience can walk among it, interact with the work, feel the changes in the space, and have different emotional experiences.&quot; . Do you think so?&quot; After receiving a unanimous nod, she said with a smile: &quot;But now it&#39;s blocked and you can&#39;t get in. Let&#39;s just close our eyes, imagine, and pretend we&#39;re walking through it. Come on, let&#39;s start. ——&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;They really closed their eyes and entered a kind of existence and non-being. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 13:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[最后的“老猎”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258331]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 12:10:29&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[放下猎枪20年：使鹿鄂温克人的现代化之路]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258325]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678021856083094&quot; data-media=&quot; video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;China&#39;s last hunting tribe, raising reindeer in the Daxingan Mountains.mov&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/10/axGGjfymsBkbfbnrKyhAdFttnt16PyWWEfk3fGGH.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/d97a528f5576678021856083094/ lX55HJ107gwA.mov&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot; 360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/d97a528f5576678021856083094/lX55HJ107gwA.mov&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A kind of turbulence The infectious disease is spreading among the reindeer in Aoxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the morning of July 18, 2023, veterinarian Lao Ge received a notice from the village that four reindeer had died in a row at a tourist spot, and he had to go check what was going on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Aoxiang, the full name is Aoluguya Ewenki National Township. Driving 250 kilometers northeast from Hailar, the central city of Hulunbuir, Inner Mongolia, is Genhe, the county-level city where Aoxiang is located. It borders Mohe, the northernmost part of China, and is the &quot;China Cold Pole&quot; certified by &lt;span>;National Climate Center&lt;/span>; ”——The annual average temperature is minus 5.3 degrees Celsius, and the heating period is 9 months. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Genhe, the name that is more famous than &quot;China&#39;s Cold Pole&quot; is undoubtedly &quot;Ewenki&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ewenki are one of the ethnic groups with a small population in China. According to statistics from the seventh census, there are 34,617 people in this ethnic group. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, there were three tribes of the Ewenki people. Among them, the safari Yakuts are called the &quot;deer tribe&quot; because they raise reindeer. The Ewenki people in Aoxiang are descendants of the Shilu tribe, also known as the Shilu Ewenki people. Their population has always hovered between one and two hundred people. They are the smallest micro-group within the tribe and the only ethnic group that raises reindeer in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Rudolph the Red-Nosed, who pulls Santa’s sleigh, is the star among the reindeer. This is an animal that lives in the tundra around the Arctic Circle. Its two towering antlers are more than one meter long and have many branches like tree branches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But the reindeer in Aoxiang are facing a survival crisis. Lao Ge judged that the reindeer that died this time had a high probability of suffering from a blood parasitic disease with a very high fatality rate. He was &quot;not surprised&quot; by this situation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;In 2003, Genhe implemented the &quot;ecological immigration&quot; policy. The Evenki people who originally lived in the deep forests put down their shotguns and went down the mountains to settle. Lao Ge suspected that the reindeer&#39;s illness may be related to the small animals that come with tourists. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In media reports, the Ewenki people are called &quot;China&#39;s last hunting nation.&quot; Today&#39;s Ewenki people are ending hunting and embracing a modern lifestyle. They also face the process of adaptation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, for this micro-ethnic group, which has been maintained at a scale of a hundred people for a long time, it is also a choice that must be made in order to survive and develop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/qRn508Oi3WcF8vf82ReSkwFmTsVqMaPgORodRf9U.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1015&quot; height= &quot;672&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/qRn508Oi3WcF8vf82ReSkwFmTsVqMaPgORodRf9U.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253537&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 18, 2023, tourists fed reindeer in the largest reindeer park in Aoxiang. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&quot;I miss you very much in Aoluguya&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt; /h4>; &lt;p>;Ewenki originally means &quot;people who live in the mountains and forests.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, both humans and deer lived in the deep forests of the Greater Khingan Mountains, and reindeer had never been heard of contracting infectious diseases. &quot;It&#39;s hard for reindeer to work in the mountains.&quot; Lao Ge sighed, &quot;There&#39;s nothing we can do to make money.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to being a veterinarian, Lao Ge also has another identity - the operator of the largest reindeer park in Aoxiang. By. On the way to see a doctor, his cell phone rang almost every ten minutes. Most of the calls were made by acquaintances who wanted to waive the 70 yuan ticket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Visitors who visit the reindeer park for the first time are often surprised: the reindeer roam freely in the scenic area without fences, and people can freely have close contact with them. If you spend 20 yuan to buy a basket of fresh moss, you will soon be stared at by the reindeer&#39;s big round eyes, its round and soft nose will come over, and it will dig straight into the basket. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The staff teaches tourists how to take very dynamic photos: lift a bamboo basket filled with moss above your head and run, and the herd of reindeer will follow obediently. However, most tourists were so frightened that they dropped their bamboo baskets on the ground when they heard the hoofbeats of the reindeer behind them. At this time, you can always hear the staff shouting from behind, &quot;Don&#39;t be afraid, don&#39;t be afraid, the reindeer will not hurt people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Besides the reindeer, Lao Ge himself is considered the second &quot;star&quot; in the reindeer park. &quot;. He is 51 years old, a mixed race of Ewenki and Russian, with curly silver hair, a high nose bridge, deep eye sockets, and bronze skin. It is said that he looked like the French movie star Alain Delon when he was young. Tourists who have done some planning in advance often take photos with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If reporters visit, the local propaganda department will most likely bring them to Lao Ge. He has a strong desire for expression and a vivid Northeastern dialect, which always makes reporters come home with a full load. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Most of the time, tourists can find him in the most luxurious hotel in the park. Choluozi is the traditional residence of the Ewenki people in the mountains and forests. More than ten pine trees are intertwined to form a cone shape, and a layer of birch bark is spread outside. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason why the tuoluozi is said to be &quot;luxurious&quot; is because the birch bark is densely surrounded by a layer of roe deer skin. There are dozens of them. According to Lao Ge, the cost is &quot;worth seventy-eight dollars at least.&quot; Ten thousand&quot;. In the past, that was a treatment enjoyed only by &quot;old hunters&quot; (the term given to experienced hunters). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going west from Luyuan, less than 10 minutes’ drive by sightseeing bus, you will find the settlement of the Evenki people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2003, the Evenki hunters had just moved to this settlement. There were 62 bungalows with red roofs and white walls in the settlement. In 2008, in order to develop tourism, the Aoxiang government renovated the house and specially invited a Finnish construction company to design it. The exterior facade was covered with dark brown wooden boards and the sloping eaves were wider, aiming to create a &quot;Nordic style&quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twenty years later, except for a dozen families who still live here, most families have moved into residential communities in Genhe City. Their houses in Aoxiang have been converted into B&amp;Bs and specialty shops. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I miss you in Aoluguya&quot; - the now pervasive Internet celebrity street signs have also invaded Aoxiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Beside the street sign is the most conspicuous house with a huge reindeer mural painted on the exterior wall. It is a B&amp;B run by Yang Lan, the granddaughter of Maria Suo, &quot;the last female chief in China&quot; . &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maria Suo is the prototype of the protagonist in Chi Zijian&#39;s novel &quot;The Right Bank of the Ergun River&quot;. She died on August 20, 2022, at the age of 101. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many tourists are attracted by the old man’s legendary experience and follow his footsteps. On a sightseeing bus, the tour guide told the tourists the story of Maria Soo adopting a dozen orphans. &quot;How come I didn&#39;t see any of them?&quot; the sightseeing bus driver muttered after hearing this fictional story. The title of &quot;the last female chief&quot; is somewhat of a packaging color. There is no chief among the Ewenki people, but Maria Suo is indeed the most respected elder among the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Can&#39;t you tell some true stories?&quot; However, for this driver, there is nothing to complain about. Driving a sightseeing bus in scenic spots gives him an extra 3,000 yuan in monthly income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Due to climate restrictions, Aoxiang’s tourist season is short. In previous years, Aoxiang’s attractions were only open from June 1st to October 8th. In 2023, due to the influence of the Zibo Barbecue Fever, the working season of the reindeer was advanced one month. At the end of April, before the snow had completely melted, the scenic spot opened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/PxXZX0PVOrtCubThYs07UZs3yAmsHN6hBa6hkX9b.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1269&quot; height= &quot;1099&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/PxXZX0PVOrtCubThYs07UZs3yAmsHN6hBa6hkX9b.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253535&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Migration route map of the Ewenki people. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Liang Shuyi/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;The third settlement&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;During the tourist season, Whenever he gets the chance, Lao Ge still likes to jump to the deer spot on the mountain. There was no cell phone signal there, and no one could find him. It was quiet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Except for the 32 reindeer that come down the mountain to &quot;work&quot;, most of Laoge&#39;s reindeer are still herding deep in the Greater Khingan Mountains. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After some hunters came down to settle down in the mountains, they still maintained &quot;deer spots&quot; where reindeer were grazed on the mountains. Officially, Deer Point is also called Hunters Point to distinguish it from the settlements at the foot of the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On July 26, 2023, Lao Ge set off from Aoxiang, traveled more than 200 kilometers north to Alongshan Town, and then drove into the forest fire road from the only main street in the town. On the road, birch trees and larches are scattered at random, rose-red willows grow wildly on the roadside, and sables pass quickly in front of the car from time to time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Walking another 60 kilometers along the fire road, you can reach his deer spot, a place that cannot be pinpointed on the map. Lao Ge hired four relatives to take turns guarding the more than 180 reindeer on the mountain. As soon as we got off the car, the air was filled with a strong scent of pine. Four or five hounds approached Lao Ge with their tails wagging, and the sound of deer bells could be heard in the nearby woods. This is the environment the Evenki people are most familiar with. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Historically, the Ewenki were divided into three tribes: Solon, Tungus and Yakut, each engaged in agriculture, animal husbandry and hunting. In 1957, after ethnic identification, these three tribes were collectively called the Ewenki. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lv Guangtian, an ethnology scholar at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, has verified that as early as 2000 BC, the ancestors of the Evenki people lived on the shores of Lake Transbaikal and Lake Baikal. In the 17th and 18th centuries, the Shilu Ewenki people (hereinafter the Ewenki people are specifically referred to as the &quot;Shilu tribe&quot;) came to the Greater Khingan Mountains on the right bank of the Ergun River, the border river between China and Russia, and never left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;People living in the mountains and forests&quot; began to descend from the mountains after the founding of New China. At that time, the Ewenki people were hunting on the right bank of the Ergun River. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1957, the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region approved the establishment of Qigan Ewenki National Township. Since then, allowing the Evenki people to settle has become a goal that the party committee and government hope to achieve. After the government built the wooden house (a typical Russian dwelling made of wood and mud), the Ewenki people had a place to settle for the first time. However, although they have a home at the foot of the mountain, except for the township head and the director of the supply and marketing cooperative who live there all year round, the rest of them live in a state of settlement and hunting. They hunt in the mountains for a long time and occasionally live at the foot of the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 1965, the Ewenki settlement moved eastward from Qigan to a place 17 kilometers north of Mangui Town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kong Fanzhi, who once served as deputy director of the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress of Genhe City, is a researcher of Ewenki culture. He said that the location of the relocation was very particular: in order to resolve the conflict between hunting and settlement, the settlement was chosen to be close to the hunting grounds and suitable for reindeer living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;That is the original and real Aoxiang, so named because it is surrounded by the Aoluguya River. In the Ewenki language, &quot;Aoluguya&quot; means a place with lush poplar trees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to distinguish it from Aoxiang after the relocation in 2003, the settlement chosen at that time was habitually called &quot;Old Aoxiang&quot;. For the Ewenki people, the period after the relocation was their &quot;golden years.&quot; Schools, grain depots, post offices, hospitals, cultural stations and banks were built where 126 Evenki people originally lived. In order to develop the economy, the township has also set up wood processing plants, hunting production teams and ethnic trading companies. Foreigners also came. At its peak, there were more than 500 people living in Lao Ao. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kong Fanzhi recalled that in Lao Ao Township, the Ewenki people were considered &quot;nobles&quot;. Maria Suo&#39;s family became the first 10,000-yuan household in the township in the 1980s. Many Ewenki families have bought cameras, bicycles, and &quot;several watches.&quot; It does not cost money to go to school and see a doctor, and students can also receive living allowances. &quot;All outsiders are willing to marry Ewenki people.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, young Ewenki people had settled at the foot of the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Kong Fanzhi, by the 1980s, 40 of the 71 Ewenki adults in Aoxiang had jobs, becoming the first generation of teachers, doctors, drivers, and waiters among the tribe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;However, nearly 40 years after moving to Lao Ao Township, the public facilities have begun to age, the government buildings have cracked, and the power grid and dams need to be repaired. The repair cost is estimated to be more than 10 million yuan, which is greatly exceeded. Root River&#39;s financial ability to pay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2003, the State Council launched the Western Development Plan, with funds earmarked for ecological migration. Therefore, the leaders of Genhe City decided that instead of repairing in situ, it would be better to apply for &quot;ecological immigration&quot;, and the funds would also come from a source. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The leader’s idea led to the third settlement in the history of the Evenki people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;At 8 a.m. on August 10, 2003, the first batch of relocated 11 households with 37 people and 260 reindeer took 12 Dongfeng extended vehicles and headed for the new rural address more than 200 kilometers away. ——Departs from a place only 4 kilometers away from Genhe city. Teams organized by towns along the way lined the road to see off. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Genhe City Chronicle records that at 4 p.m., the convoy arrived at the new Aoxiang in the drizzle. &quot;The new township site had colorful flags flying, gongs and drums roaring, and two elderly yangko teams singing and dancing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than ten days before the move, Kong Fanzhi started busy receiving reporters. They recorded the last class of the school in Lao Ao Township, the &quot;minimum post office&quot; with only one employee, and the last bonfire before departure. Party. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;Return to hometown after one day down the mountain&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This relocation attracted Xie Yuanyuan, a Ph.D. in sociology from Peking University. On September 18, 2003, she arrived in Aoxiang and began a one-year field investigation. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;What aroused her interest was the reversal of the hunters&#39; emotions. Before setting off, she noticed the report in &quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Beijing Youth Daily&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&quot;, the title was &quot;&lt;/span>;China&#39;s last hunting nation&lt;span>;The Ewenki people returned home after just one day of going down the mountain. Township&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Beijing Youth Daily&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Reporters at&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Hunter&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;relocation times&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Visiting Aoxiang on the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; day, I found that the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;yard was surprisingly quiet&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, and &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;some houses were empty&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;. Some hunters made a rough calculation: the annual income of a reindeer is about &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;200 Yuan &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; no &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; investment when raising stock in the mountains. After going down the mountain, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;we have to &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; reindeer &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; in captivity &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; just the feed money, every day A reindeer costs thousands of dollars every year. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Originally, what the government promised was that the hunters would move, the reindeer would be kept in captivity, and someone would feed them. “The hunters would just hold the wine bottle and watch the reindeer smile.” &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The reality is that there is no feed at all in the rows of deer pens blocked by brick-red barbed wire in the settlement. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;During the relocation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, some reindeer were lost, injured, and some were not used to eating bean cakes and choked to death. A total of more than 90 reindeer were lost. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Li Mengchu, chairman of the Aoxiang People’s Congress, was the Minister of Armed Forces of Aoxiang at the time. He recalled that at that time, the township government mobilized cadres to go up the mountain to collect moss, mushrooms and willow twigs. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;A reindeer can eat a sack of moss in a day&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, which is equivalent to what one person can harvest in a day. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;A few days later, the hunters &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; took the deer out of the deer pen and led &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; back to the mountain. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;They&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;first &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; reared them around Aoxiang, but &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;the moss in the mountains and forests around the city did not grow well&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Go north again&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and continue deep into the hinterland of the Greater Khingan Mountains&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Now, there are 14 deer spots scattered in the mountains and forests of Xinlao Ao Township. &lt;p>; span>;20 years later, when talking about this matter, a former deputy mayor of Aoxiang said bluntly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Writer Chi Zijian visited Aoxiang in 2004 and found that there was not a single reindeer in the deer pen, only a group of lazy goats wandering along the overgrown path. Go shopping. The butterfly effect caused by this situation was that the Ewenki people descended from the mountain and became the origin of the writing of &quot;The Right Bank of the Ergun River&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;While reindeer were being raised in captivity&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Evenki people&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; also put down their shotguns. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In fact, as early as 1988, with the promulgation of the Wildlife Protection Law, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; it was clear that &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; hunting was prohibited , killing national key protected wild animals&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;common prey of the Ewenki people, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;moose&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, black bear, roe deer, gray rat &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;They are all on the list&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. In 1996, the Gun Management Law was promulgated, which imposed stricter regulations on civilian use of guns. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;At that time, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Xie Yuanyuan obtained a document clarifying the meaning of &quot;ecological migration&quot; of the Ewenki people from the then director of the Ethnic Affairs Bureau of Genhe City. She was attracted by a few &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; short sentences with strong tone: &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1. If the mode of production does not change, settling down will become a sentence Empty words. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;2. Without changing the mode of production, it will be difficult for various economies to develop. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The material clearly expresses the point of view: to change the production method, reindeer must be kept in captivity so that hunters can put down their shotguns. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This also makes the third settlement essentially different from the first two: in the past two settlements, the government did not restrict the Evenki people’s choices, but instead increased their travel options. An alternative to hunting. But this time, the goal of letting the Evenki people go down the mountain to settle down is more clear. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;We must change the &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;safari &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; such &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; &quot;production&quot; Way&quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Ecological immigration has accelerated the process of closing guns. Li Mengchu remembered that the Public Security Bureau confiscated the guns of the Ewenki hunters right after they moved. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Gu Taozeng, a documentary director who filmed the &quot;Ewenki Trilogy&quot;, recorded&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;this process&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. Li Mengchu&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;is concerned about&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;that the Evenki people&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;have hunted for generations to survive&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and their guns are gone. , which means a change in the tradition of hunting people. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Changes inevitably bring confusion. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Two months after the relocation&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;More than a month later, the then Aoxiang Party Committee Secretary&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Liu Panchang&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;’s nose bone was hunted by Ewenki The people interrupted, and the township head Gu Xianglian, who was also an Ewenki, was sued by his own aunt. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Gu Xianglian’s aunt wrote to the then Secretary of the Hulunbuir Municipal Party Committee: “In the past, without subsidies or assistance, the hunters lived quite well. But now, in Genhe &quot;To subsidize life is just like begging for food.&quot; &quot;This is not trying to achieve a well-off life, it&#39;s just trying to make us eat chaff!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as it&#39;s time to go to work, a circle of people rush into Gu Xianglian&#39;s office. The long sofas on both sides of the room were filled with villagers, and the radiator by the window was also crowded with people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The ancient fragrant lotus has nothing to do with it. She complained to Xie Yuanyuan: &quot;I have no selfish intentions at all. I don&#39;t have a house of my own, so I live in a hunter&#39;s business. It&#39;s worse than a hunter&#39;s house! If you were to be the mayor of the township, what would you do?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There are problems everywhere. In November, the temperature in Aoxiang reached subzero, the new house began to get damp, and black hair grew on the walls of the house. The floor made of wooden boards in Lao Aoxiang was replaced by milky white ceramic tiles. &lt;span>;The designer obviously doesn’t have much experience in rural life. As soon as you enter the house in winter, the snow stuck to the soles of your shoes melts quickly, and you may slip&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; accidentally. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Making a living has become difficult&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, the Ewenki people used to be respected in Lao Ao Township&lt;/span>;&lt; span>;It seems&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; is gone too. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Their appearance is easily identifiable: high cheekbones and deep-set eye sockets. When Xie Yuanyuan and Ewenki women went shopping in a store in Genhe City, they would always see the clerk pointing out, &quot;Look, that&#39;s from Aoxiang.&quot; The restaurant owner also laughed at Xie Yuanyuan for their old-fashioned ways: they only served free side dishes and drank almost all the wine. Before the main dishes were served, I paid and left. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xie Yuanyuan recorded the scene she saw in the winter of 2003: except for the hunters raising reindeer, there was almost nothing for others to do. The only way for pure hunters to amuse themselves is to drink, drinking low-quality liquor that costs 1.5 yuan per pound and is filled with mineral water bottles. &quot;There are three or five people, very quiet, not talking or laughing, just leaning on the sofa or leaning on the bed.&quot; Drinking like that. It feels like they want to get into a state of &#39;drunkness&#39;, the sooner the better.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;Twenty years have passed, and Gu Xianglian, who was the township head at the time of the relocation, is now the deputy director of the Standing Committee of the Genhe Municipal People’s Congress. &quot;There is no need to talk about the past.&quot; On July 28, 2023, in her office, she quickly interrupted the reporter&#39;s question, &quot;Go to Aoxiang and see for yourself. I don&#39;t know how much everyone&#39;s living standards have improved. . That&#39;s a huge change.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/mtXgU30A1jUSpsFVSkB0wppXC6tGAq5bHLcoNYyr.jpg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1014&quot; height=&quot;758&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/mtXgU30A1jUSpsFVSkB0wppXC6tGAq5bHLcoNYyr.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253539&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;The Ewenki hunter settlement in Aoxiang is full of Nordic style. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;“Almost forgotten everything”&lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;The latest improvement in living standards &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; celebrates &quot;ecological migration&quot; &quot;20th anniversary. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;On September 12, 2023, at the celebration ceremony, 15 dark green high-power tractors were lined up, which were allocated to the mountain&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Deer point. A month ago, the township &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;had &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;replaced &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; each deer spot with 5,000-watt solar energy storage panels. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;When fully charged &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; , the solar panel &lt;/span>;&lt;span>; can provide &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;8 kWh of electricity. This means that you can use a refrigerator, TV, rice cooker, and even hot pot at the same time on the mountain. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The summer travel season has also met expectations, ushering in a major outbreak three years after the epidemic. The price of accommodation in the two hotels in the scenic area is about 1,000 yuan per night. The price of a B&amp;B with simple facilities not far from the scenic spot starts at 500 yuan per night, and it must be booked at least a week in advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Genhe, a resource-based city built for forestry, has now positioned the cultural and tourism industry as a &quot;city-building industry&quot; in the government work report, and &quot;Aolugu Ya&quot; has become a key focus The “brand” created. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The living standards of hunters have improved a lot in recent years, and the original oppositional emotions have almost been forgotten.” Kong Fanzhi said when talking about the development of Aoxiang in recent years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Change cannot occur without reindeer. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2005, three years after the relocation, Li Mengchu was appointed deputy mayor of Aoxiang. How to allow the Ewenki hunters to make a living under the mountains became a difficult problem that he had to face as soon as he took office. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not long after taking office, he organized the first Reindeer King Competition, hoping to build the reputation of the reindeer. According to the plan, the antlers of the top three deer kings will be auctioned on site. Worried that no one would bid, Li Mengchu specially arranged a few &quot;trustees&quot; in the auditorium. Unexpectedly, the person in charge of a company auctioned off all the top three antlers, and the most expensive pair was auctioned for 7,000 yuan. At that time, an adult reindeer was worth only 5,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The township government also took over the entire township’s deer antler business. Deer antlers are deer antlers that have not yet been boned. In traditional Chinese medicine, they are considered to have nourishing properties. Starting in 2005, Li Mengchu led the township cadres to various deer spots to cut the antlers, which would be processed by the township, packaged and sold. &quot;After the sales are completed, the hunters will be given money, and they will be happy with every penny they receive.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After a few years of unified sales, hunters no longer need government support. After the rise of tourism in Aoxiang, deer antlers are sold by the same gram as ginseng, with prices ranging from 8 to 20 yuan per gram depending on the quality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Reindeer is the spirit of the Greater Khingan Mountains and the treasure of the Ewenki people.&quot; Lao Ge often repeated this sentence when interviewed by the media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No one can say how the tourism industry in Qing Ao Township became so popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As soon as the Ewenki people came down from the mountain, the Aoxiang government made plans for tourism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Xie Yuanyuan was investigating in Aoxiang, the government had built a &quot;folk custom village&quot;. At first, there were only two buildings: a tent and a tuoluozi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The township government arranged for Asuo, a young male hunter, to live in a tent and raise 6 reindeer nearby. As long as he stays there, Asuo can receive a monthly salary of 100 yuan. However, Asuo&#39;s situation seemed awkward: he stayed there alone, drinking, dazed, and being sucked by mosquitoes. Later, the township leaders said that the &quot;Folk Custom Village&quot; was located in a remote location and lacked &quot;life&quot;, so Asuo&#39;s &quot;work&quot; was stopped. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After that, hunters gradually took over the business of the folk village, but they were all in a slump. In 2007, with the support of the township government, Lao Ge invested more than 100,000 yuan, and the township government signed a ten-year contract to take over the business of the reindeer park. &quot;I never dreamed of it, but it started slowly.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Li Mengchu’s impression, around 2008, Hulunbuir’s tourism business suddenly became popular. At that time, tourists drove around Genhe and couldn&#39;t find a place to stay. &quot;They were all confused at the time.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lao Ge’s specific feelings about Aoxiang’s tourism industry “taking off” come from the increasing number of reporters visiting. Several groups of reporters from different CCTV channels came. The camera crew of Japan&#39;s NHK&#39;s &quot;China Railway Journey&quot; also came, as well as teams from Thailand, Singapore, and South Korea. Reporters from various countries came to see it all. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also took reindeer to Changsha to record the variety show &quot;Happy Camp&quot;. Lao Ge clearly remembers the broadcast time of the March 5, 2011 issue. He chartered a truck, hired two drivers, and took the reindeer with him, and it took him 85 hours to reach Changsha. Finally, the Ewenki clip appeared on the show for 5 minutes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lao Ge was originally worried that the reindeer would be frightened after coming on stage and run wild all over the place. The result was good, the deer was calm and even peed on the stage. On the contrary, he himself was very nervous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This deer was later named &quot;Little Hunan&quot; by Lao Ge. The day after returning to Aoxiang, &quot;Little Hunan&quot; disappeared. Half a month later, a forestry worker 40 kilometers away discovered it. Its mouth and body were covered with hunter&#39;s nooses. &quot;Little Hunan&quot; did not survive that autumn and passed away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, a Hunan tourist made a special trip to the reindeer park and bought the antlers of &quot;Little Hunan&quot; for 2,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/LshBZyp56uNBLZi123aXA1287nCOlpYo2v8q7kmf.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height= &quot;514&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/LshBZyp56uNBLZi123aXA1287nCOlpYo2v8q7kmf.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253536&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 28, 2023, tourists watched birch bark boats at the Aoxiang Museum in Genhe City, Inner Mongolia. This was the most commonly used means of transportation by the Ewenki people half a century ago. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;No longer follow the order of the past&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt; p>;In 2022, Lao Ge’s reindeer park began to be “regularized”, and the Aoluguya Tourism Development Company controlled by the Genhe Municipal Finance Bureau signed a three-year contract with him. Tickets are 70 yuan each, and he takes a 10% commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;He is a busy man!&quot; Speaking of Lao Ge, He Xie had not seen him for some days, let alone drank with him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Xie, the eldest son of Maria Suo, the &quot;last female chief&quot;, is known as Boss He. He always likes to wear a military green jacket and sits on a bench outside his home with his wife Zhuoye. He rarely speaks, holding a 3 yuan and 5 bottle of Hailar beer in his hand, and the volume of the radio on the window sill is turned to the maximum. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he was young, he enlisted in the army and served as a firefighter. After changing his job, he was assigned to work as a judicial assistant in the township government. At that time, he had thick, long black hair with natural curls, like a rock star. Now, he is 56 years old, his hair is gray, his face is covered with wrinkles, his eyes are squeezed to only a slit, and almost all his teeth are missing. Aging has completely overcome him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The distance from the bedroom to the bench is less than ten meters, which is the distance Zhuoye moves every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Twenty-six years ago, He Xie was cleaning a gun at home, and the gun went off. The bullet penetrated the thin wall panel and entered Zhuoye&#39;s head. It has not been removed yet. The accident left her with no mobility in her right leg. After that, she stopped going out and became increasingly fat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a curious tourist passes by the door and asks the couple about their Ewenki story, He Xie always walks slowly into the house and takes down two large photo albums from the top of the refrigerator - there is no smartphone yet. In the popular era, visiting reporters and photographers would always mail them to him after developing their photos. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the photo, they are skiing, singing, and drying dried meat in the forest. If you want to eat meat, pick up your gun and go out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When it comes to hunting, the energetic young hunter will briefly return - He Xie is the &quot;old hunter&quot; among the tribe who never misses. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Things in my memories are long enough. Most of the Evenki hunters in the photo have passed away, and the cause of death is somewhat related to alcohol. Of Maria So&#39;s seven children, only He Xie and his sister Dekesa remain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If I hadn&#39;t looked at him, he would have been gone.&quot; Zhuoye said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If you don&#39;t drink, what else can you do?&quot; He Xie pushed back. His memories seemed to linger forever in the mountains and forests. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bai Lan, a researcher at the Institute of Ethnology of the Inner Mongolia Academy of Social Sciences, has been following the Ewenki people for more than 30 years, and has become old friends with He Xie&#39;s family. Sometimes, Bai Lan would receive a voice message from Zhuo Ye, lamenting that there used to be people in front of her house, but now, they are the only ones left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We are all busy now, so how can we have time to drink with him.&quot; In Bai Lan&#39;s view, He Gong&#39;s arrogance as &quot;Boss He&quot; disappeared. He Xie loves to make money, and as soon as he has some money, he calls friends and invites people to drink. But today&#39;s Aoxiang no longer follows the order of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/kdRbls3Jq6AprFfu5f2yAbPlRrJThsUqHp55Ojoe.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1015&quot; height= &quot;672&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/10/kdRbls3Jq6AprFfu5f2yAbPlRrJThsUqHp55Ojoe.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253538&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On July 23, 2023, He Xie was in front of the graves of his mother Maria So and his father Rajmi He. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Han Qian/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The young Evenki people have their own way of survival. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;36-year-old Gu Musen has 300,000 fans on the short video platform. In 2022, he founded his own media company, signed up young people in the countryside to be &quot;artists&quot;, and attracted tourists by relying on the fans he accumulated on the Internet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some people who went to big cities to make a living have also returned. After graduating from college, Jue Le originally worked as an administrator in a hospital in Beijing, bought a house, got married, and had children in Beijing. But he felt that the work in the hospital was boring, and staying in the cubicle &quot;was like turning on the mechanical mode.&quot; In 2016, Juele returned to Genhe and ran a tourist spot not far from Aoxiang. &quot;It was very open, just like playing.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Doing tourism business in Aoxiang can indeed bring considerable income. Juele estimates that he will earn more than 100,000 yuan from tourism in the summer of 2023, which will be enough to support his family throughout the winter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Bai Lan gave He Xie some advice. The couple was humorous in their dealings with others, and He Xie played the harmonica well. If they could clean up their house and start a small business in the tourism industry, they could make money. He Xie was not willing to do it and thought it was &quot;boring&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He Xie still maintains a rough drinking method: drink vigorously for a few days to get stronger, then sleep for a few days and nights, wake up, then get up and continue drinking. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lao Lie, who was once envied by others, has become a person who is left behind and &quot;has not made progress&quot; in the eyes of his relatives. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of July 2023, He Xie returned to Lao Ao Township. Not long after the Ewenki people moved out, the land was acquired by a real estate businessman in Daqing with plans to develop an international hunting ground. As a result, the plan was aborted, the hunting ground was not built, and all the old wooden carving houses were demolished. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Old Aoxiang became a deserted land, and the weeds on the roadside grew as tall as half a person. He Xie walked around Lao Aoxiang with his hands behind his back, but he didn&#39;t recognize where his house was. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A fellow traveler asked him if he would be willing to come back to raise deer again. He thought about it seriously. This place had been uninhabited for a long time, and there were more wolves and lynxes nearby. &quot;It might not be appropriate to come back again.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span>;&quot;Romanticism&quot; and &quot;Realism&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As National Day approaches, a brown bear has become big news in Aoxiang . At around 5 o&#39;clock in the morning on September 26, 2023, Lao Ge received a call that a bear had entered the reindeer park - he entered through the ticket gate, and he was familiar with the road. This is the third time it has visited the deer park in half a month. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lao Ge joked, &quot;If it comes again, then we will have to deal with it.&quot; When it comes to the beasts that appear more and more frequently, the deer herder on the mountain doesn&#39;t sound so relaxed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2021, a brown bear visited Yang Lan’s deer spot and killed 7 reindeer in one night. In another household, after the arrival of the wolves, only 8 of the more than 30 reindeer were left. In the year when the beasts were most serious, the entire Aoxiang lost more than 200 reindeer, and the total number of reindeer was more than 1,300. In other words, one out of every six reindeer died due to beasts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Really annoyed, Yang Lan&#39;s father complained to her that if the guns could be returned to the hunters for a week, the problem of animal harm could be solved. Otherwise, in a few years, deer farmers will face personal danger even if they survive in the mountains. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Both the speaker and the listener know that this is just angry talk. They are all nationally protected animals, who would dare to fight them? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Ewenki people are also gradually losing their ability to survive in the mountains and forests, which makes Bai Lan feel a little anxious. How to choose between modernity and tradition? &quot;Everything has given Ewenki an external intervention, so this culture will inevitably have its flaws.&quot; Bai Lan put forward this point of view in an interview with the media at the beginning of the ecological migration in 2003. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She felt that if hunters could decide their own development model, obtain certain resource management and use rights in ethnic areas, and be able to engage in moderate logging and hunting, the situation might be different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“That’s the view of literati.” In 2003, Kong Fanzhi had a remote debate with Bai Lan. When he mentioned it again now, he still couldn&#39;t agree with Bai Lan&#39;s point of view. &quot;We can&#39;t just let the Ewenki people live in Zuoluozi in order to protect their traditional culture, right? Who doesn&#39;t want to live a modern life?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Xie Yuanyuan&#39;s view, these two attitudes come from completely different things. value judgement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the research, she and Maria Saw lived in Deer Point for more than half a month. Get up at around five o&#39;clock in the morning and work, such as beating legba, milking deer, picking wild fruits, cooking leather, and sewing leather goods... The days are simple and repetitive, and no one thinks that life needs any changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, Ewenki people of different ages have different pursuits. When younger hunters see the broader world, they will naturally feel that their nation&#39;s customs are backward and want to make changes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;谢元媛在博士论文末尾也写道，眷恋森林生活的传统猎民并没有参与进话语权，不能轻易牺牲掉那些对人类长远发展更有价值和意义的东西”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20年后，博士生谢元媛成了清华大学国家战略研究院研究员。如今，在她看来，白兰的观点是“浪漫派”，而孔繁志则代表“现实派”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;微型群体走进现代化，是一种社会发展的必然。现在的谢元媛觉得，从国家治理的层面上看，为了民族发展，这是必须要做出的牺牲。面对现实，理性的态度是，记住那部分人，给予他们及后代一定的补偿，“这才是现实”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，从使鹿鄂温克人的第一次定居、接触外部世界后，一些传统已慢慢在改变。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;鄂温克语没有文字，只能通过一代代人口口相传。即便是何协、老革这般年纪的人，能使用的鄂温克语，也不及老人们的一半。鄂温克人在半个世纪前最常用的交通工具桦皮船，也早就从大兴安岭的河道漂进了博物馆。在老革年轻时，就开始用几个橡胶轮胎绑一块当船用，比做桦皮船简单多了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从1957年鄂温克猎民第一次定居算起，现在回家养鹿、经营旅游业的年轻人已经是定居后的第三代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那再下一代呢？ ”&amp;nbsp;白兰觉得，正当年的第三代人从小在山林中长大，多少对驯鹿有感情，如今还没成年的第四代孩子，从小就生活在水泥地上，“以后驯鹿是啥，可能都不关心了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;孔繁志则觉得，驯鹿不会在敖乡消失，它如今是使鹿鄂温克人最重要的标志，也是游客们奔向敖乡的原因，“别的没啥说的了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;参考书籍：&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;孔繁志《敖鲁古雅的鄂温克人》&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;谢元媛《生态移民政策与地方政府实践：以敖鲁古雅鄂温克生态移民为例》&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;顾桃&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;《敖鲁古雅·敖鲁古雅》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 11:25:13 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[官方通报“北极鲶鱼”事件：深圳市原交通局货运管理分局局长钟庚赐被开除党籍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258327]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 11:18:38&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，深圳市纪委监委对深圳市原交通局货运管理分局局长钟庚赐严重违纪违法问题进行了立案审查调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;经查，钟庚赐对党不忠诚不老实，多次串供对抗组织审查；借机敛财，违规从事营利活动；未经批准，违规兼职取酬；利用职务便利为他人谋取利益，非法收受他人财物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钟庚赐严重违反党的政治纪律、廉洁纪律，并构成严重职务违法，应予严肃处理。依据《中国共产党纪律处分条例》、《中华人民共和国监察法》、《中华人民共和国公职人员政务处分法》等有关规定，经深圳市纪委常委会会议审议，决定给予钟庚赐开除党籍处分，按二级科员确定其退休待遇；收缴其违纪违法所得。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;钟庚赐简历&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;钟庚赐，男，汉族，1947年11月生，深圳宝安人，大专学历，1968年2月参加工作，1971年6月加入中国共产党。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;历任深圳市原运输局福田分局副局长、局长；深圳市原运输局罗湖分局局长；深圳市原交通局货运管理分局局长。2007年11月退休。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 11:25:13 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蔡锷遗孤如何教养]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258317]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/uBvoJJ2YFUMTDBdbKYROoYTgy45uIZbJoptyqOqD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;549&quot; height=&quot;934&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/uBvoJJ2YFUMTDBdbKYROoYTgy45uIZbJoptyqOqD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253481&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;蔡锷遗照。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（资料图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1916年11月8日，蔡锷在日本福冈医院病逝，留下五个孩子，夫人刘侠贞所出：铸莲10岁，福莲8岁；如夫人潘蕙英所出：淑莲4岁，端生2岁，永宁不满周岁。蔡锷公而忘私，身后萧条，遗言“无一语及家事”，来不及考虑身后子女的抚养和教育。幸有梁启超、谭延闿、熊希龄等师友代为谋划遗孤教养，情谊感人，而过程颇为曲折。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/XSS8hEUs7F0U5LvWNclWRSn5I5prgY7gCQIsCVK7.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;758&quot; height=&quot;629&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/XSS8hEUs7F0U5LvWNclWRSn5I5prgY7gCQIsCVK7.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《东方杂志》刊登的蔡锷全家福。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;蔡公遗孤教养协会&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;1917年2月初，湖南省政府批准蔡公遗孤教养协会立案，公布了协会的七条规则和职员名单：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;本协会以筹画替理蔡公遗孤教养事宜为职。（二）本协会公推评议员若干人执行左列职务：规画遗孤教养方针；筹措保管分配遗孤教养费；推定主任。（三）本协会推定左列各项主任受评议员全体之委托执行其职务：教育主任，主计画监督遗孤教育之进行、审度学科、选择学校、考察学绩等；驻湘会计主任，主在湘教养费之保管；驻沪会计主任，主在沪教养费之保管。（四）各主任须将职务上进行情形，每半年报告评议员一次，若进行有障碍时，求评议员全体之解决。（五）评议员之评议以通信行之。（六）各主任有辞职者，由评议员全体审查改推。（七）本协会俟遗孤成年后，由评议员全体决议撤销之。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;评议员：梁启超、熊希龄、谭延闿、范源廉、蒋方震、张孝准、石陶钧、曾继梧、范治焕、张嘉璈、萧堃、袁家普、赵恒惕、袁思亮、刘庚先、陈复初、何鹏翔、唐巘、岳森；教育主任：石陶钧；驻湘会计主任：岳森、唐巘；驻沪会计主任：袁思亮、张嘉璈。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁启超是蔡公遗孤教养协会的发起人，在蔡锷逝世的次月即拟定了协会规则，征求了相关人员同意，由石陶钧就近提请湘省政府立案。梁启超起草的立案呈词情理俱壮：“故上将服官滇桂，供职京都，先后凡十余年，时以国事忧劳，家计未遑过问，清风两袖，劲节孤鸣，刻下白发在堂，黄口在抱，善后事宜百端待理。超等或素同患难，或谬许知交，悲元勋之长逝，通遗孤之无依，爰集同人，组织蔡公遗孤教养协会。关于遗孤教养事宜本会应随时悉心规画、协力赞助，务期六尺有托，蔚国器于将来，内顾无忧，慰英魂于地下。”本已参与其事的湘省政府省长谭延闿，当即批示备案，并饬令湘江道尹暨长沙、宝庆两县知事一体查照。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/KhSZoB5bYYKmJgoXQpy6K3S6p68uWuMO6VwV12Zj.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/KhSZoB5bYYKmJgoXQpy6K3S6p68uWuMO6VwV12Zj.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;《谭延闿日记》中关于蔡锷遗孤教养协会的记载。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;梁启超对蔡公遗孤教养协会的设计颇费心思，其目标任务、责任分工及运作方式均明确可行。早在1916年12月初，熊希龄便提出：“时局变幻莫测，为松公遗族筹恤，似宜从速通电中央、各省借助”，并请梁启超领衔通电募集。梁启超通过在沪与蔡锷遗族接触，发现“其家事极纠纷”，于是决定发起成立蔡公遗孤教养协会，以减少家庭矛盾对遗孤教养的影响。也不采取通电筹集善款，以免违背蔡锷“生前耿介之意”，而是发动亲友赠送，并拟以版税补助。所邀请之人经过了梁启超选择，或是蔡锷的师友，或是同事同乡，熊希龄、谭延闿、范源廉、赵恒惕、蒋方震还是影响湘省乃至全国的大人物。在湘、在沪分设会计主任，一者为方便当下的教养，一者为方便将来留学海外，考虑长远而周全。另外，计划了两种筹款来源：一是国家恤金，二是同志及海内外义士赞助；三种善款保值增值方法：一是购置不动产，二是投资有价值之公股，三是储蓄于银行。梁启超的设计得到了谭延闿、熊希龄等的一致赞同，认为“允称协洽”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1917年4月17日，谭延闿来到设在长沙市陆军测绘局内的蔡公营葬事务所，参加蔡公遗孤教养协会会议。这是蔡公遗孤教养协会第一次实际运行，在湘的张孝准、石陶钧、曾继梧、范治焕、萧堃、袁家普、赵恒惕、刘庚先、陈复初、何鹏翔、唐巘、岳森等，大概率和蔡锷遗族一起参加了会议。会后，谭延闿将会议议定意见电告熊希龄，征求意见：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;筱日（编者注：即17日）蔡公遗孤教养协会开会，议决事项如下:一、山门地方财产归太夫人收用。二、新置省城及宝庆城内两处房屋地皮,归端生（即蔡端，作者注）兄弟所有。三、新旧动产,除提一万元为太夫人膳费外，其余各项股票及现金,概归端生兄弟所有。四、照蔡公生前之命,端生归夫人抚养，永宁归如夫人抚养,一切动产、不动产平均分管,不得变卖。五、调查旧账，分别清理。六、夫人、如夫人现暂同居分爨,当否?&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;分配方案以蔡端、蔡永宁兄弟为中心，具有男尊女卑的时代色彩。山门地方财产在蔡家侨居的武冈县山门镇（今属洞口县），为年租十石的田产及旧屋一间。新置省城及宝庆城里两处房屋地产，一是长沙市南门外天鹅塘樟树园一号住宅，规模偏小；一是宝庆城内旧协署废址，在蔡锷逝世后由唐巘出面购买，原计划建筑蔡母养老住所，因资金不够尚未动工。财产的大头为湖南华昌矿业公司股份，其时炙手可热，一共34000元，其中5000元是三年前梁焕奎感念蔡锷劳苦功高无产而赠资代为购买的。当年旅长月薪高达2000银元，蔡家所有财产加起来不超过40000元，与同时代的地方大员相比，实显寒酸。其中第六条“夫人、如夫人现暂同居分爨”，印证了“其家事极纠纷”，显然让谭延闿也有点为难。此电见于《熊希龄先生遗稿》，应该同时发给了梁启超等人，只是其他人未保存而已。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;重后裔以报故人&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;护国运动胜利之后，依然是战争频仍、社会动荡、民生艰难，蔡家也大受影响。受国际局势等影响，纯锑价格急剧下降，湖南华昌矿业公司经过短暂繁荣之后，1918年即陷入困境，稍后破产。杨度、熊希龄等公司管理层还受到美国人的持续诉讼勒索，甚至被扣押。蔡家的重要资产湖南华昌矿业公司股份34000元，收取利息不到两年，一下全部血本无归。又受战争和灾害影响，蔡家田租、房租几乎绝收。世事艰难，协会同人也深受其害，但依然把关心扶持蔡锷遗孤的责任放在心上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1921年2月19日，在广东军政府的谭延闿致函石陶钧:“蔡公遗孤,吾辈必不能漠然置之。此间人太少，恐问心尚不如吾辈。弟谓吾辈当为拟定一办法乃佳，大众料无不赞同，公有何主张，望示也。”这是谭延闿给石陶钧的回信，面对蔡家财源枯竭的困境，石陶钧请求谭延闿设法救助，希望在广东找一条新路子，尽管谭延闿也想不出什么一劳永逸的办法，但责任意识、关切之情溢于言表。四年以后，石陶钧之子石潮白与蔡铸莲在上海结婚，随后一起留学日本，也算是对同乡好友的一个交代。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/jaiAoaID918ardyBcujrPDHc5gbSfoHa1PqKJQzR.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;772&quot; height=&quot;441&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/09/jaiAoaID918ardyBcujrPDHc5gbSfoHa1PqKJQzR.png&quot; data-key=&quot;253484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;1917年2月17日《新闻报》关于蔡锷遗孤教养协会的报道。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1922年5月末，梁启超致电湘省政府省长赵恒惕请托关心蔡锷遗孤、保护蔡家产业，正文如下：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;敬启者,启超日前晤秉三、静生诸公，偶及蔡身后诸事，教育问题为吾辈应当特别注意事件外，对于遗族所置产业，既定为蔡公仰事俯蓄之资，自不能不有略思预防之法。查蔡公遗孤教养协会所有存款为数无多，只能专备教育经费，万难再移作别项之用。其遗族生活问题自不能不专于已置之产业，此项产业保存非有官方力为之巩固，难保不发生地痞侵蚀或滥用情事。协会同人自应力尽维持监督之责，则尊重功勋后裔者即所以报故人也。兹□合词函恳执事迅予刊发布告，令交蔡公产业所在地方官署，禁止买卖抵押，以资维护而重久远。言纫公谊，专此奉达，顺颂勋安。梁启超同启。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;赵恒惕曾经因反袁罹罪，经蔡锷救援得免，十分感恩，又是蔡公遗孤教养协会评议员，当即令蔡家原籍宝庆知事遵即贴张晓谕，俾众周知。也可见，梁启超、熊希龄、范源廉等一直没有忘记蔡锷和蔡家遗孤，常常努力设法维护。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1927年初，伴随北伐战争和民众运动发展，湘省收回租界收回领事裁判权运动、反军阀、惩治旧官僚绅士运动声势空前，省政府先后颁布《湖南省惩治土豪劣绅暂行条例》和《湖南省惩治贪官污吏暂行条例》，成立特别法庭、清查逆产委员会，查封、没收逆产运动波及全省。省清查逆产处对举报逆产者实行奖励，举报动产奖励没收数额的百分之二十，举报不动产奖励没收数额的百分之五。省总工会等团体积极推动，利用召开会员大会等大面积发放逆产调查表，大力鼓励举报逆产。唐巘名下有一座规模不小的房产，位于长沙市大东茅巷31号，被宣布为逆产，行将被没收为省矿业工会的办公楼。三日后，蔡端兄弟就此通电各界，大意是：该房产虽由唐家建筑，但各项权利已经转移到蔡家，理应归还。随即，在军界要人唐生智等人的过问下，此套房产被移出逆产名单。唐巘（1875-1929），字规严，宝庆人，留学日本期间加入同盟会，1905年归国后，先后担任广西陆军学堂主事、云南讲武堂主事，随后参加辛亥革命、护国运动，一直与蔡锷共进退，被蔡锷以兄视之，是护送蔡锷赴日就医的随员之一。之后，唐巘担任湘省政府财政司司长、省务院院长、省厘金局局长，是省长赵恒惕手下的要员，又担任过北洋政府财政部司长。军阀赵恒惕和北洋政府均是当时湘省要推翻打倒的，因为这层关系，唐巘名下产业，被列入逆产名单。两年后，唐巘在上海逝世，家人按照其遗愿将此房产捐给隔壁的仁术医院。可见，蔡端兄弟通电是为唐家友情援助，是社会对蔡锷遗孤的尊重保全了唐家的产业。在此前后，蔡锷二弟松垣私自用房产抵押借款而有意烂账，由蔡锷夫人刘侠贞出面登报称被人欺诈，并向警署报案。随即被对方揭穿，并在报纸上公开声明，不过仅登载三日即停，又是背后有要人干预，着意维护蔡锷遗族。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十几年来，梁启超通过倡行国葬、定期纪念、筹办松坡图书馆、为蔡母征寿诗等形式扩大影响，以关照蔡锷遗孤，去世前一两年还在家书里提到：“蔡松坡家里的人已经饿饭了，现在流离在上海”，自然又免不了设法救助。蒋方震在长沙期间，就居住在蔡锷家里。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;十年间，张孝准、范源廉、梁启超、唐巘、谭延闿相继故去，但是蔡公遗孤教养协会同人甚至圈外人士，从未放弃对蔡锷遗孤的帮助，情谊感人。1931年6月，经张人杰等呈请，国民政府拨给蔡锷遗族年恤金800元，月给子女教育费400元，建祠补助5000元。蔡锷小女精神抑郁，一度在莫干山疗养，故旧部曲闻讯赠送钱财，帮助减小医疗费用压力。1935年5月2日，蔡母王夫人在长沙逝世，各界要人纷纷函电吊慰，赠送不菲的赙仪，湘省当局筹办了盛大的葬礼，蔡家声誉达到了蔡锷国葬之后的最高点。大约在1950年，在朱德的安排下，蔡端、蔡永宁进入华北人民革命大学学习，随后分配了工作。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;一点遗憾和意外&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;蔡锷遗孤成长成才情况如何，公开的有关史料很少。根据一般的说法，除了夭折的蔡福莲之外，两男两女都是大学毕业，蔡端就读北平辅仁大学史学系，蔡永宁就读西南联大史学系，蔡淑莲就读浙江大学病虫害系，蔡铸莲还留学日本。据《北平辅仁大学校史》记载，1934年蔡端入北平辅仁大学史学系，1935年参加过一二·九和一二·一六反日示威运动并受伤，可见颇具少年豪气。北平辅仁大学是教会办的大学，师资和设备倶优，但学费昂贵，每学年400元左右，一般家庭根本负担不了。蔡锷遗孤教养协会同人和义士的关心，保障了四人超过常人的生活和教育水平。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蔡端毕业后进入国民政府外交部工作，新中国成立后先后在全国政协文史资料研究委员会、光明日报社工作。蔡永宁先后在云南富滇银行、北京体育学院工作。蔡淑莲在云南昆明松坡中学任教。四人都受到了良好的高等教育，步入社会后获得一份还算体面的工作，可以说基本成人成才。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1946年下半年，蔡锷的同乡旧部雷飚将军在《国防月刊》连载长文《蔡松坡先生事略》，满怀深情详细回忆蔡锷的功业和品格，文末大发感叹甚至愤怒：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;惟其死后之家庭状况，亦有令人深为叹息不已者，身为上将军，家无立足地，老母在堂，两弟读书未成，寡妻幼子，教养无恃，虽蒙梁任公老师，由各方奠金项下凑集一二万金，聊作家庭暂时须用，而当民九、十年间，南北战事复起，原籍宝庆尤当冲要，其老母妻妾子女，终岁家无宁处，不得已分居云南、北京等处，而所蓄已尽，虽故友部曲，赠送有人，亦甚几希，最可耻者，有受惠最深，而代管各方所集之赠款，为遗孤养金者，不下数万元，一并吞灭之，不意护国军中，竟有如斯之人哉。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1905年上半年，蔡锷任湖南教练处帮办兼湖南武备学堂、兵目学堂教习，雷飚是兵目学堂的学员，当年6月毕业后即随蔡锷赴桂，以后入滇入川，参加了辛亥革命和护国运动，一直担任重要军职。蔡锷离川之际，叮嘱雷飚掌握一支军队，支持省长戴戡。因为远在四川，又可能不为梁启超熟悉，所以没有参与蔡锷遗孤教养协会。雷飚作为蔡锷的同乡、学生、部下，以其身份和经历来看，所言应该基本可信。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;蔡锷遗孤教养协会很多同人都参加了护国军，其中石陶钧、曾继梧、萧堃、刘庚先、何鹏翔、唐巘、岳森是和蔡锷交往更多的宝庆同乡，何鹏翔、唐巘还分别是蔡锷的副官长和秘书，从理论上说这些人都可能是雷飚所说的那个人。至于协会同人之外就难以猜测了。不过，时人普遍认为，石陶钧与蔡锷交往长久频繁，后来又成了儿女亲家，两家关系最为密切。李肖聃的《蔡锷别传》指出：“其同学石陶钧，为经纪其家事。”因此，雷飚暗指石陶钧的可能性很大。当然，这一切只是推测，到底真相如何，有待新的史料来证明。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如此一项集体义举，间杂个别人的私心劣行，不能不说是一个很大的遗憾。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 10:25:13 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[最高人民检察院依法对杜兆才决定逮捕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258323]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 10:10:11&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;国家体育总局原党组成员、副局长杜兆才涉嫌受贿一案，由国家监察委员会调查终结，移送检察机关审查起诉。日前，最高人民检察院依法以涉嫌受贿罪对杜兆才作出逮捕决定。该案正在进一步办理中。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 10:25:13 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小学生写字用左手还是右手，是个问题吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258319]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-10 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;今年儿子上小学了，报名的时候一看，满满全是人；到教室一看，拥挤，原本每班40人，现在快到60了。但刚开始令我和妻子纠结的是：孩子用左手写字还是用右手写字。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿子左利手，是少数，据统计十个人有一个是。我们家左利手多，母亲、妻子、大女儿，都是左利手，照这个统计，都达到百分之六十的多数了。儿子跟着我写毛笔字、画画时，周围许多人都吃惊地说：左手！我和妻子在这一点上是比较一致的，一直没让他强行用右手。所以，当别人惊讶时，我会对儿子说：儿子，你想用哪个手写就用哪个手写，爸爸不会强迫你的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;跟我学写字，儿子非常随意。可是上一年级了，写字的问题又首先浮现出来，似乎回到十几年前大女儿的时候。因为女儿的左手写字，是被她的小学老师强行改过来的，只是刚开始不适应，后来就变成右手写字，左手还是优先干别的事，但左手不会写字了。回想女儿改右手写字的经历，只是写数字和字母出现镜像，有时b与d之类的容易搞错，但慢慢就习惯了。对儿子，刚开始用彩笔画画时同幼儿园的老师交流过，就一直用左手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因为左手右手的问题，我查过不少资料，但准确的经过科学考证过的答案几乎没有。这是一个待研究的问题，还是一个不是问题的伪问题，值得思考一下。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上网一搜，许多名人包括爱因斯坦、比尔·盖茨都是左利手，他们离我们很远。我所知的最有名的是清朝画家，江南八怪之一的高凤翰，其在青岛博物馆专门有数百平方米的作品展示区。他是左手写字的名家，但不知是不是左利手，因为他是右手病废后才用左手的。另一个是本地的诺贝尔奖获得者莫言，经常看到他用左手题字，但也不知道他是不是左利手，更不知道他的最有名作品是左手的灵感还是右手的灵感。假设两人都是右利手，右手写都没问题，左利手顺其自然用左手，当然不会有什么问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们生活在一个习惯右手为主写字吃饭做事的世界上，因为人数少，所以人们对左手做事的人有些许好奇心。从这角度看，左手写还是右手写的问题是一个社会现象，一种社会包容度的指示器。当少数，唯一的问题可能是要在异样的眼光下成长，这很不容易。虽然不易，但对于儿子的左手写字，我还是倾向于顺其自然。对称的人体结构，没法说哪一边更有优势，所以，对左利手像右利手一样平常心看待、自然地对待就尤其重要。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我之前曾认为，这个问题会引来许多家长热心地讨论，但当我在班级群发出后，却一个回音都没有。第一次小学家长会后，我同孩子的班主任交流，得到的答案很令我意外：儿子所在的班级，55个孩子中只有一个左手写字的，当然左利手的不只他一个。我向身边熟悉的大小朋友询问，得到的信息是：一位四年级小学生说，他们班只有一个同学用左手写字；一位二年级小学生说，他们班没有用左手写字的；一位教三年级的班主任告诉我，她印象中，任教的这么多班级中，只有一个孩子用左手写字。看来纠结我们好长时间的用左手还是用右手的问题，对大部分人来说根本不是问题，当然也就不需要讨论。或许，这个问题在刚上幼儿园开始拿笔时，家长们曾做出过选择，或许在那时纠结过，但大部分人选择了主流，即用右手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天生左利手的孩子注定是人群中的少数，而选择左手写字，现在看来，在我们这个小地方，只能是少数中的少数。如果换个角度看，顺应自然地用最方便的手写字，左利手用左手写与右利手用右手写都不是问题。但放在只看左右的角度上，尤其是更多的人只看右手的角度上，成为少数，确实是个挑战。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;儿子若选择右手写字，也是个挑战，是挑战自己的身体极限，这是个个体问题；但选择左手，选择少数，是一种心理和社会性的挑战。孩子，虽然你是极少数，要挺住！&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为山东高密市民）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目期待您的来稿。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 09:25:13 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>