<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[2023年前8个月基本医保基金收入同比增长9.3%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258746]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 17:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The National Medical Insurance Administration recently released data showing that from January to August 2023, the basic medical insurance fund (including maternity insurance ) total revenue was 2.092333 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 9.3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among them, the income of the basic medical insurance fund for employees (including maternity insurance) was 1.473806 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 13%; the income of the basic medical insurance fund for urban and rural residents was 618.527 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 1.3%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data show that from January to August 2023, the total expenditure of the basic medical insurance fund (including maternity insurance) was 1.786477 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 18.3%. The expenditure of the basic medical insurance fund for employees (including maternity insurance) was 1.12573 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 19.6%, of which the expenditure of maternity insurance fund benefits was 70.945 billion yuan; the expenditure of the basic medical insurance fund for urban and rural residents was 660.748 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 16.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 17:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“早睡早起身体好”？早睡和早起哪个更难？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258744]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The old saying goes, &quot;Early to bed and early to rise are good for good health.&quot; Is this true? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Broad Institute of MIT and Harvard University analyzed data from nearly 840,000 adults and found that their average sleep time is to fall asleep at 11 p.m. and get up at 6 a.m. Then their &quot;sleep time midpoint&quot; (the halfway point between the time to fall asleep and the time to wake up) is 3 am. If the &quot;sleep midpoint&quot; is moved forward by one hour, the risk of major depression will be reduced by 23%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a study in the journal Sleep Medicine found that people who went to bed early had a 29% increased risk of death or major heart disease compared with those who slept at normal hours (10 p.m. to 12 p.m.). Risk of vascular events. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the &quot;China Sleep Research Report (2022)&quot; released by the Chinese Sleep Research Association, more than 40% of young people aged 19-25 in China stay up after midnight, and 40% of young people aged 26-35 stay up after midnight. One-third of people habitually stay up late, and even minors have a 24% rate of staying up late. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/JHLH9Shht1otyVAHvNq4J9QsSbTBDGEqlbRo17Bs.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;647&quot; height= &quot;427&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/JHLH9Shht1otyVAHvNq4J9QsSbTBDGEqlbRo17Bs.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254285&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Screenshot of &quot;China Sleep Research Report (2022)&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What exactly affects you to go to bed early and get up early? Which is more difficult, going to bed early or getting up early? Let’s talk&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color: orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https: //feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[咬伤2岁女童的恶犬主人被找到]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258758]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 17:15:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;At about 8:00 on October 16, 2023, Hengda Xichen Oasis Community, Yangma Street, Chongzhou City A girl was bitten by a dog. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;After the incident, Chongzhou City quickly organized the public security, health, Yangma Street and other departments to set up a joint investigation working group to carry out the investigation. The illegal facts have been initially identified, and the relevant The situation report is as follows. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;It was found that at 7:20 on October 16, the two dogs involved ran into the community where the incident occurred, and an injury incident occurred at around 8:00. At 8:20, the white Labrador involved was captured at the scene, and the dog owner, Jia, arrived at the case at about 21:00. At about 22:00, the black Rottweiler was captured. At about 3:00 on October 17, the owner of the black Rottweiler, Tang, arrived at the scene. At present, the police have opened a case for investigation into the incident and have taken criminal coercive measures against Tang, the owner of the black Rottweiler dog, in accordance with the law. The case is under further investigation. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;In order to get better treatment, the injured girl was transferred to West China Hospital at about 23:00 on October 16 for further treatment by a team of medical experts. Her vital signs are currently stable. We will continue to do a good job in treating and caring for girls. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Chongzhou City Joint Investigation Working Group&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;October 17, 2023&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[越来越多的女性获得诺奖]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258700]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/16/Gye4nF1LMB1HIOx3viFpaemOfhUEm408X0cHkb6R.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/Gye4nF1LMB1HIOx3viFpaemOfhUEm408X0cH kb6R. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254168&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Female Nobel Prize winners from 1901 to 2023. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（Nobel Prize Outreach/Photo）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are 4 women winners of the 2023 Nobel Prize, and 11 winners in all 6 prizes Among them, accounting for 36% (4/11). In the history of the Nobel Prize, it is the class with the second most female winners and the second highest proportion. In 2009, there were the most female award winners, with 5 women winning the award, accounting for the highest proportion of 38% (5/13, a total of 13 people won the award that year). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This year&#39;s four female winners are Katalin Karikó, the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine; Anne L&#39;Huillier, the Physics Prize ); Narges Mohammadi for the Peace Prize and Claudia Goldin for the Economics Prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Interestingly, the achievement that won the economics prize was the study of gender differences. US economist Claudia Goldin was awarded the prize for her research on key drivers of gender differences in women&#39;s participation in the labor market. The award citation said her research &quot;has advanced our understanding of women&#39;s labor market outcomes&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In layman’s terms, Goldin won the award for studying why women’s income is not as good as men’s. This can be seen as the gender difference in labor remuneration between men and women. Gender differences exist in all aspects of social life, and even the winning of Nobel Prizes has huge gender differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Golding not only studies the difference in income between men and women, but even after winning the award, he complained that there were more men than women in the economics prize. She said that &quot;serious inequality still exists&quot; between men and women in the Nobel Prize in Economics. Indeed, Goldin is the third female economist to win the Economics Prize. From 1969 (the Nobel Prize in Economics began to be awarded in 1969) to 2023, the Nobel Prize in Economics has been awarded 55 times, with a total of 93 winners, of which women account for only 3.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the Nobel Prize comprehensively from the statistical data on the Nobel Prize official website, the gender gap between men and women winning prizes is also quite disparate. From 1901 to 2023, the Nobel Prize was awarded a total of 621 times, with 970 individuals and 30 organizations (groups) winning the prize, and a total of 1,000 people and organizations winning the prize. Among them, 65 are women. Looking at individual proportions, the proportion of women is about 6.7% (65/970). However, if we consider that Marie Curie won the award twice (in 1903 for Physics and 1911 for Chemistry), only 64 women won the award, so the actual proportion is 6.6% (64/970). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the various Nobel Prize categories, due to wars and various reasons, different Nobel Prize categories in history have had different awards and number of winners. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 1901, the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine has been awarded 114 times, with a total of 227 winners, of which 13 were women, accounting for 5.7%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Physics Prize was awarded 117 times, with 225 winners, of which 5 were female winners, accounting for 2.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Chemistry Prize was awarded 115 times, with 194 winners, of which 8 were female winners, accounting for 4.1%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Literature Prize was awarded 116 times, with 120 winners, of which 17 were female winners, accounting for 14.2%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Peace Prize has been awarded 104 times, with 141 winners, of which 19 were female winners, accounting for 13.5%. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Looking at the six awards, the highest proportion of female winners is the Literature Award, which is 14.2%, and the lowest is the Physics Award, where women account for 2.2%. The economics prize that Golding complained about is considered good. Women account for 3.2%, which is not the bottom. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why is the proportion of female winners so low? Looking at the total number, they only account for 10.3%. In this regard, Goldin analyzed that the reasons why women earn less than men can also be used to explain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although Goldin believes that there are many reasons for the gender pay gap, such as gender discrimination, she coined a term - greed for work to explain it, believing that this is the main reason. Greedy work is when a person works longer hours or has less control over their hours and is paid disproportionately more per hour, effectively penalizing women who need to seek flexible labor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, this situation also creates a lose-lose situation for both sexes. For men, they give up time with their families, while for women, they often give up their careers. The essence is that many jobs pay much higher hourly rates when working longer hours, being on call, busy schedules, evenings and weekends, or unpredictable hours. However, in most couples who are highly educated, have careers and children, the woman is the on-call professional at home, and the man is the on-call professional at work. Therefore, men earn more than women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reason behind this is that women have to have children and take care of the family, so they have less time to work, and of course their income is less than men. If this reason is used to explain why women have only accounted for 10.3% of Nobel Prize winners over the past 100 years, it is also valid. Because women devote less time to work and research than men, this prevents them from achieving higher achievements in different fields and therefore winning Nobel Prizes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Whenever career and work achieve results, one is talent and the other is diligence. There may be different opinions on the proportion of the two, but it cannot be denied that diligence is the most important factor in producing results. factor. &quot;A person who is capable of one thing can benefit himself by a hundred, and a person who is capable of ten can benefit himself by a thousand.&quot; This is the true meaning of it. As long as you engage in a job or profession, and persevere over a long period of time, practice makes perfect and results will come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The importance of professional perseverance can also be seen from the history of the Nobel Prize. As long as women participate in scientific research and work, the chances and number of awards will increase. From 1901 to 1925, 4 women won the award; from 1926 to 1950, 8 women won the award; from 1951 to 1975, 3 women won the award; from 1976 to 2000, 15 women won the award Award-winning, from 2001 to 2023, 35 women won the award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In comparison, in the 50 years from 1901 to 1950, 12 women won the award, but in the 22 years from 2001 to 2023, 35 women won the award. This not only shows that the number of female award-winners has increased with the development of the times, but also shows that modern women’s large-scale participation in work and scientific research is an important reason why they can achieve the same results and win awards as men. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These explanations and facts are also reflected in Golding&#39;s research. In her latest book, &quot;Career and Family: Women&#39;s Centennial Journey to Equality,&quot; she mentions the impact of multiple factors on women&#39;s careers, such as the history of women&#39;s pursuit of careers and families, coeducation in higher education, and the impact of birth control pills on women&#39;s careers. The impact of women&#39;s career and marriage decisions, women&#39;s married surnames as a social indicator, and the reasons why women make up the majority of undergraduate students. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Goldin analyzes more than two hundred years of data to demonstrate how and why gender differences in earnings and employment rates have changed, such as the use of birth control pills, which has provided new insights into women&#39;s career plans. opportunities, giving them more time and opportunity to work and participate in scientific research, so that they can achieve the same results as men, and these results may win the Nobel Prize. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, receiving higher education, participating in work and scientific research are important foundations for women to gradually win more Nobel Prizes and increase their income. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[独臂船长徐京坤和他的超级赛船丨封面人物]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258546]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/3KlQURn8IAiq75Cy8HWajQ9l7ECu7pLrtLJOg8Ig.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/3KlQURn8IAiq75Cy8HWajQ9l7ECu7pL rtLJOg8Ig. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253648&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 23, 2023, at Qingdao Olympic Sailing Center, Xu Jingkun sailed a sailboat out to sea&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern People Weekly reporter Liang Chen/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the autumn of 2021, Xu Jingkun decided to buy a super racing boat to participate in the 2024 Vendée Singles. Intermittent round-the-world sailing race. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Vendée Globe, held every four years, is the &quot;Everest&quot; of competitive sailing - more than 26,000 nautical miles (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;48,000 kilometers&lt;/span>;) is an ultra-long race in which one person and one boat sail around the earth without any supplies or supplies. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I know this is difficult, and I may not be able to do it, but I may be the closest to it. If I don’t do it quickly, there may not be any Chinese people in the next twenty or thirty years. Come and touch this event.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To win a ticket to the 2024 Vendée Globe, he must first participate in the designated qualifying competition-in the 2022 season, Xu Jingkun became the first person to be selected for the &quot;Rum Road&quot; &quot;The Chinese skipper of the solo transatlantic sailing race is also the first Asian skipper to finish the race in the IMOCA category. In July 2023, he and Five-Star Red Flag appeared on the official website of Vendée Globe for the first time, becoming the first official candidates for the 10th Vendée Globe in 2024. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 4, he received a confirmation letter from the Coffee Road Organizing Committee. The team passed the 1,200 nautical mile storm test and won the qualification to participate in the 2023 Coffee Road Double Transatlantic Sailing Race. It will be held on October 10 On the 29th, it set sail from the race village of Le Havre, a famous seaport in France. This is the first time a Chinese team has been selected for the world&#39;s top two-person transoceanic competition, and it is also the first Asian team in the history of Coffee Road. Although the Café Road is not one of the five single qualifying events designated by Vendée Globe, it, like other world-renowned high-difficulty championships, can help racing boats accumulate difficult sailing miles. When the team that has obtained Vendée Globe qualification review exceeds the limit When the quota is determined, help the team win in the competition of selecting the best among the best. If the coffee road is successfully completed, Xu Jingkun is expected to seize the ticket to the 2024 Vendée Globe and become the first Chinese person to participate in the world&#39;s top offshore sailing competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Hd3xHdzNkoG4N6kRSfJqHQTcMGvEn9wAdP9Oe8rZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Hd3xHdzNkoG4N6kRSfJqHQTcMGvEn9wAdP9Oe8rZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253644&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun’s super racing boat IMOCA60&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot; The road ahead is too long”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“Buying the IMOCA60 is indeed an important turning point. I used to sail around the China Sea and around the world. Most people can do it with hard work, but entering the field of racing , everything is different.&quot; Xu Jingkun calls the recognition from the media and insiders &quot;everyone&#39;s praise&quot;. He himself does not take it too seriously. Only when he talks about his identity as &quot;rowing captain&quot;, he is full of pride. . &quot;Although I used to sail my own boats and others called me &#39;captain&#39; very early on, in my mind, I didn&#39;t really consider myself a captain until I drove IMOCA60 and managed the racing team.&quot;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;IMOCA60 is the designated boat type for the 2024 Vendée Globe. In 2007, Xu Jingkun was training overseas in Rhode Island, USA as a member of the Chinese Disabled Sailing Team. He saw the IMOCA racing boat on the cover of a sailing magazine for the first time. &quot;It&#39;s so dreamy, like a spaceship!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/esXSHu2ovTOfUKr558ukBPh2CzYb143BbZNgzYBv.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/esXSHu2ovTOfUKr558ukBPh2CzYb143BbZNgzYBv.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253646 &quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun gathered with friends at the restaurant bar where he worked back then&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Characters Weekly reporter Liang Chen/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;With the continuous upgrade of IMOCA racing performance, traveling around the world in 80 days has long since become a reality from science fiction. The route of the Vendée Globe is not the most economical and safe trade wind route. Instead, it tries its best to incorporate dangerous capes, equatorial windless zones, and stormy waves into the course. Even so, there have been five captains in the history of the Vendée Globe. After reaching the 80-day mark, the fastest record is 74 days, 3 hours, 35 minutes and 46 seconds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jingkun never thought that one day after the Paralympic sailing team was disbanded, he would go out to sea alone, own a super racing boat, and race against the waves with the captains of the world&#39;s top professional racing boats. In 2021, there are less than 20 hydrofoil super single-hull racing boats in the world. Standing on the boat, he had a strong sense of unreality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;IMOCA60 integrates the most cutting-edge monohull sailboat design and shipbuilding technology. The signature design is the swinging keel inserted vertically into the sea and the hydrofoils extending from both sides of the hull. The carbon fiber hydrofoils are light and elegant but strong enough to When standing in the wind, it looks like the wings of a flying fish, helping the ship reduce the friction of the water and achieve faster speeds. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/igg3a26AZN6NW6OYjC1NyCVraXPlAaupJur759F5.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/igg3a26AZN6NW6OYjC1NyCVraXPlAaupJur759F5.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253641&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun and his wife Xiao Shuyao in their first year of circumnavigation&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p>;It can sail unimpeded in the world&#39;s dangerous sea areas and harsh sea conditions, with a maximum instantaneous speed of more than 40 knots (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1 knot Equivalent to 1 nautical mile per hour, which is 1.852 kilometers per hour&lt;/span>;). If captains want to stay ahead of others in the Vendée Globe, they must maintain an average boat speed of more than 20 knots day and night for several months. The resistance of sea water, the load of ships and the attack of storms mean that the optimal speed of modern warships can only be about 30 knots. For a full carbon fiber monohull ship, traveling at such a speed in the deep sea is already equivalent to traveling at sea. Driving an F1 car. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Before I boarded a ship for the first time, I had never experienced it in real life. I only learned about it from watching videos. When I got on board, I found that the ship was really ‘flying’ on the sea.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since Xu Jingkun was selected into the Chinese Disabled Sailing Team in 2005, he has been constantly exposed to various types of boats. He has completed extreme challenges such as a solo circumnavigation of the China Sea and a non-stop solo transatlantic crossing in a 6.5-meter boat. He also used it with his wife Xiao Shuyao. It took three years for the Chinese to complete the first catamaran circumnavigation of the world. &quot;Among the many boats I have sailed before, none of them can compare with it. It is a completely different concept.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A brand-new IMOCA60 sells for more than nine million euros. He bought a second-hand boat with excellent performance for &quot;only&quot; two to three million euros. Parking the ship at the pier of the port of Lorient, France, he carefully hung a sign on the bow to remind passing ships to keep their distance, &quot;Don&#39;t touch my ship, I can&#39;t repair it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;From then to now, he is always short of money. “The money on hand is not enough to overhaul a racing boat.” The money to buy the boat is sponsored by various brothers who love sailing. “I have never had a dedicated business team to help I found all the big sponsors myself.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When he bought the boat, he insisted on going to France alone. &quot;I didn&#39;t even bring any luggage, I just carried a backpack.&quot; He had already done it. Plan and save when you can. &quot;The road ahead is too long, and we may not be able to go on at any time due to lack of funds.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no upper limit on the budget to form a racing team. In his words, &quot;Buy The boat is the first step. To maintain the racing boat every offseason, you have to spend money to buy a boat.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The labor cost alone for a large racing team is one to two hundred per season. 10,000 euros, &quot;We have kept the funds to a minimum. Now there are 5 people in the team, and we will add more people before the start of the game. The German team has 50 people.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http:/ /images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/tipTMrAtBG4M91Sqq3Rsc12lE0td8rQvP1t0AF0W.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com /cms/medias/image/23/10/11/tipTMrAtBG4M91Sqq3Rsc12lE0td8rQvP1t0AF0W.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253640&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2014, Xu Jingkun participated in the MINI TRANSAT solo transatlantic competition. &quot;No one told me how to control this MINI with one hand. I had to find my own method&quot; &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;The boat was parked at the dock and he slept in the car. After buying the boat, his wife Xiao Shuyao soon joined. The two born in the 1980s formed the &quot;Xu Jingkun Global Sailing Team&quot;. Each person plays multiple roles: Xu Jingkun is the captain, maintenance worker, chef and video editor; most of the time, Xiao Shuyao is the only captain. His subordinates are the press officer, translator, administrator, and cashier of the fleet. Before the start of the Coffee Road race, the couple simply moved to a boat because short-term rentals were too expensive. &quot;This boat is too spacious for two people to sleep, and it can also save an hour of commuting time.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Eating is on the shore. In the container, &quot;I also renovated a small kitchen, which is very convenient for cooking. It&#39;s great!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Excellent&quot; is Xu Jingkun&#39;s mantra, even if he is afraid of heights and climbed to a 30-meter-high mast. While working, his legs would tremble with nervousness, but he would still grab his phone to take pictures of the evening clouds, &quot;It&#39;s so beautiful! It&#39;s great!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/10/11/4L7PolWNYc5Ak9whvzGtNJ2qPLJosnJdOoE8G6aR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;494&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/10/11/4L7PolWNYc5Ak9whvzGtNJ2qPLJosnJdOoE8G6aR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253635&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Length 6.5 meters, width 3 meters, interior The 529 has less than 2 square meters of space. I only got this boat a week before the start of the season. In order to save budget, I moved to that boat from that day on. When I went to sea for training during the day, I had to move all the daily necessities to the dock. I went out for the boat race, came back in the evening and moved back and it became my home. In the cold and windy Lorient, 529 became my warmest home” &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (provided by interviewee/picture) &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is no running water in the container, so they have to go out to get water to wash the dishes. When they are busy, they often fail to wash the dishes in time, &quot;just grab one from the dirty bowl and use it.&quot; Xu Jingkun The most interesting thing is that my wife never complains, &quot;On the contrary, sometimes I will be pretentious and yell a few words, &#39;What kind of life are we living here, like savages! We have to rent a house tomorrow, and I want to sleep in the bed. , eat at the table, use clean bowls!&#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why rent it? It&#39;s so expensive!&quot; Xiao Shuyao shouted, and picked up the oxygen bottle he would use to clean the boat later, &quot;Work Go! Go quickly!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/7PA4ssxJBAqoD0g6olcyIBVOhz0Nl6ADOhxnCG4E.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/7PA4ssxJBAqoD0g6olcyIBVOhz0Nl6ADOhxnCG4E.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253636&quot;>;&lt;/p >; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Xu Jingkun (first from right) served as the flag guard at the opening ceremony of the 2008 Beijing Olympic Games in Qingdao &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (received by Provided by the interviewer/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“This child is useless”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“She is so interesting. Sometimes I am also observing her changes. It is my greatest pleasure now. Just teasing her. &quot;Before meeting Xu Jingkun, Xiao Shuyao was a 100% literary young woman. After graduating from college, she traveled around the world, opened an inn in Yunnan, and went to Tibet to see Mount Everest... Xiao Shuyao herself also lamented, &quot;In recent years, long hair, long skirts, The long shawl has been lost on the road, and I am becoming more and more neutral. I work crazily in the two time zones of China and France every day. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“If any one of us is missing, this project will not go forward. &quot;Xu Jingkun said that Xiao Shuyao &quot;has a belief&quot; in sailing. &quot;She talks about the stories and characters in the sailing circle with great clarity. She even knows more about the data and performance of IMOCA60 than I do. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Shuyao is a well-known freelance writer in the navigation circle, with the pen name &quot;Ajiu&quot;. She has interviewed many sailors and captains, and uses columns and podcasts to record and spread the passion and madness of sailors. Xu Jingkun feels that Xiao Shuyao loves the sea more than him and has more sailor temperament, &quot;She is very romantic and casual, while I am very realistic and cautious. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0aQr1T8Z76WAbukzDH33EH3wzHbPhuxgYZxyqWAa.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;717&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/0aQr1T8Z76WAbukzDH33EH3wzHbPhuxgYZxyqWAa.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253643&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In 2012, Xu Jingkun spent 7 months alone to repair the first Dream Number bit by bit&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot; >; (Provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“He never said this in person. He is a Virgo who pursues perfection. He is very demanding and never praises me. &quot;Xiao Shuyao now helps Xu Jingkun manage the competition team. In addition to romance, her work covers everything. She takes on all the chores of the competition team. Every time she signs up for a competition, she has to fill out a lot of forms. &quot;When I used to go to school and work, I hated filling out forms the most. , even if it is for award evaluation, if I have to fill out a form, I would rather not participate, I am too lazy to fill it out.&quot; In the past few years, I have &quot;filled out a lifetime of forms.&quot; After each event is completed, there are thousands of emails to communicate, &quot;There are also payments, Coordination, all kinds of bargaining...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two first met in Sanya in 2013. Xu Jingkun was planning his first solo transatlantic trip, and Xiao Shuyao helped him sort out the conditions for the competition.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; “Do you think it’s possible? &quot;Xu Jingkun asked anxiously.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Theoretically it is possible, but the ship cannot break down, the people cannot get sick, and the weather cannot have problems. Once a game is canceled or the schedule is shortened, it&#39;s all over. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/t7N3qu2le5RTx8hXa2hMumRdke4FMLMpRDHxyehD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/t7N3qu2le5RTx8hXa2hMumRdke4FMLMpRDHxyehD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253649&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On November 9, 2022, Xu Jingkun drove the Dream from Saint Malo to the Caribbean, a journey of 3,750 nautical miles&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;( Provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two have been tightly tied together since then, one riding the wind and waves in the sea, and the other overcoming thorns on the shore. &quot;She treats me better than I treat myself. Confident, she always said with certainty, &#39;You can do it! You can do it! &#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;We are much better off now than we were then. Although we are short of funds, it is not like at the beginning when we had to use our own money to buy a boat. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/VeA34TiTI4hRqhQJeid6N3zz2uYdCIxJkqBGYGJO.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/VeA34TiTI4hRqhQJeid6N3zz2uYdCIxJkqBGYGJO.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253653&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Electricity, machinery, hydraulics, structural maintenance, and sail painting are all Xu Jingkun&#39;s jobs. What requires the most physical strength is cleaning the bottom of the ship twice a week. It takes two hours to wait in the water. Three hours &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo provided by interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In order to participate in the 2015 MINI TRANSAT transatlantic competition, Xu Jingkun bought a pair of shoes named 529 An old 6.5-meter boat, the young couple who just got married used this boat as a temporary home. In the morning, Xu Jingkun sailed out to sea for training, and in the evening they squeezed into a small cabin of less than two square meters to spend the night, eating rice and potato cubes. , diced carrots were put into a small rice cooker brought from China and simmered in one pot. It was the &quot;Chinese feast&quot; that the two had in the port of Brittany, France.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Shuyao never thought that Seeing that Xu Jingkun complained about suffering, Xu Jingkun said nothing and secretly marveled in his heart, &quot;Actually, I often think about it now. She has not been suffering like me since she was a child. Why can she suffer like this with me? ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Xu Jingkun was 12 years old, he was injured in an accident. Two-thirds of his left hand and left forearm were amputated. His brain deleted many painful memories out of self-protection. He only remembered being carried away. On the stretcher going to the hospital, a fellow countryman’s voice sounded in my ear, “This child is useless! ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Since 2015, the competitions Xu Jingkun has participated in have been the world’s top offshore sailing competitions. There is no special preferential treatment for people with disabilities. He must prove that he has the same competitive ability as normal people to be qualified. &lt; /p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Shuyao once asked him why he had such a difficult journey but never thought of giving up, &quot;Because I have no way out. When I retreat, I just say, &#39;This kid is useless!&#39; &#39;&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/7V9ZkmW2b7jpDZyeanHEPJMDCt4IYAkAAAn2hCQC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/7V9ZkmW2b7jpDZyeanHEPJMDCt4IYAkAAAn2hCQC.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253654&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style= &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Electricity, machinery, hydraulics, structural maintenance, and sail painting are all Xu Jingkun&#39;s jobs. What requires the most physical strength is cleaning the bottom of the boat twice a week. Two or three hours &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Defeat to the angry sea&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Xiao Shuyao and Xu Jingkun were just in When we were together, many friends around me didn’t understand, but as soon as I got in contact with them, they would naturally forget that Xu Jingkun was missing an arm, “My friends said he didn’t feel disabled. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jingkun always naturally exposes his left arm, using it to hold his mobile phone to make calls and hold the microphone during sharing meetings, &quot;I can cut vegetables and meat, and I can also make dumplings... …Many times when I fell into the sea, I relied on it to hold me up. It’s great! It followed me really hard and this is my mark. &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xiao Shuyao believes that sailing cured Xu Jingkun, &quot;He has encountered numerous doubts and accusations, which stimulated him to a certain extent and gave him a desire to fight when he set sail. As the voyage progressed, he felt more and more care, help, and kindness. He became peaceful and rational, and his voyage became more pure. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Xu Jingkun agreed, “Sailing has completely changed me. &quot;Since entering the sports school at the age of 16, he has always felt insecure in competition. &quot;If it weren&#39;t for sports, you wouldn&#39;t be able to get out at all, so I would say that I must stay here. He often had the fear of falling into hopelessness. He was once very angry. When he was participating in the Paralympic team selection, he said to himself every day, &quot;If you fail this time, you don&#39;t have to go back. You can just jump into the sea and die.&quot; . &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the Paralympic team was disbanded, he couldn&#39;t find his life goal for a long time. He hated a life without a sense of goal. Captain Zhai Mo&#39;s return from a global voyage gave him a direction, &quot;It turns out that the team After disbanding, I can still sail on my own. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;His first ship and first voyage around the China Sea were full of tragedy. “A man lived alone in a small shipyard in Laoshan, busy like a madman every day, separated from life, and lost everything.” Contact may even seem to be starting to be forgotten. &quot;He spent more than 7 months repairing and renovating an almost abandoned ship and named it &quot;Dream&quot;. He set sail from Qingdao on September 18, 2012, &quot;taking the brave man away and never returning it. That kind of tragic mood, even with some resentment, why does my life have to be so difficult? Why couldn&#39;t my parents come to the scene when I set sail? If you don’t believe it, I will fight to the death! With such energy! &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Fa Xiao &quot;Monkey&quot; shouted on the shore, &quot;Jingkun! &quot;Jingkun!&quot; &quot;Oh, he yelled so sadly, I didn&#39;t dare to look back. I was gambling with fate in my heart. If I die, I will die. What&#39;s going on?&quot; ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/4AwubDVqVgNDKraQShoUGUTLCudu23xeqOlwKoPZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height =&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/4AwubDVqVgNDKraQShoUGUTLCudu23xeqOlwKoPZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253652&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Electricity, machinery, hydraulics, structural maintenance, and sail painting are all Xu Jingkun&#39;s jobs. What requires the most physical strength is cleaning the bottom of the ship twice a week. It takes two hours to wait in the water. Three hours &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Courage and Love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In these years, when Xu Jingkun completed a Another goal. After feeling that he could take control of his life, his worries receded and his anger subsided. He became more and more relaxed and more professional. Friends, elder brothers and sponsors around him did not know much about him at the beginning of his career. Many people knew him through Xiao Shuyao. It was only after writing his book &quot;The Humble Dreamer&quot; that I learned about those past experiences.&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I read that book carefully and was very touched. &quot;Yin Zhicheng is the deputy general manager of the Dolphin Club of Qingdao Maritime Vocational School and has come into contact with many sailing people. &quot;Jingkun is very focused and will not be easily distracted. He is persistent in his goals and moves forward step by step. When others look up, they will notice He has reached unattainable heights. ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“The biggest characteristic of Jingkun is rigor and professionalism,” Noah Tianze Insurance Brokerage Company has been a partner of Xu Jingkun and Xiao Shuyao since they started sailing around the world on a catamaran in 2017, and has been providing services to them until now.赛队提供保险服务。天泽董事长田丰密切关注着赛船的状况，“咖啡路1200海里资格赛，他们按照规定必须穿越风暴赛段，追着风暴跑下来，赛船完好无损，充分证明他工作做得很细。那么大一条船，每个细节他都亲自维护到位才能有这样的状态，这种职业精神是对自己负责，也是对赞助商、对家人负责。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“其实在海上偶尔我还是会（情绪）爆发。 ”2022年朗姆路单人跨大西洋的时候，他连续穿越3个大风暴，最大风力超过70节，“整个海面鬼哭狼嚎，非常让人恐惧。 ”孤身一人在风浪中，徐京坤冲着大海怒吼，“来吧！怎么样吧！ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他笑了起来，“没有人看到过我那个样子，以前也没跟人说过。很戏剧化，一边叫喊着，一边开着我的船迎向风浪！ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“那次还干了一个非常冒险的事，”IMOCA60赛船上有8面帆，每面帆都有一百多公斤重，一趟朗姆路跑下来，大风吹坏了3面帆。“有一面帆直接掉到海里去了，船还在跑，三百多平米的帆兜着几十吨的海水，靠人力是根本拉不上来的。 ”徐京坤拿着一把利刃跳进冰冷的大西洋，“一点点切，把它切成碎片拿回来了。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;深海航行最忌讳的就是人船分离，大洋深处，连救援力量都没有能力抵达，“事后想来想去，以后还是不能这样干了。 ”徐京坤说这种行为跟自己理性稳妥的天性严重不符，他甚至都无法解释，“但这都是人在岸上、在正常情况下的想法，紧急时刻，你的想法会不一样。如果不跳进海里，帆可能会把船拖沉，比赛会被迫终止，而我为这个比赛付出了那么多，绝对不甘心就这样放弃。我的船也不只是一条船，它像我的孩子一样，不可能不去救它。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除了充满勇气的冒险竞赛，极限航海中也有许多关于人与船、人与人之间的爱的传递。2020旺代环球就曾上演61岁的传奇航海人让·勒·卡姆和几位船长冒死营救船只发生灾难性断裂的船长凯文的故事，极少流泪的徐京坤说，“这些故事很容易触动我的泪点。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;船长们是懂得表达爱的，那些在最凶险的海域守望相助过的水手们，常常会结伴参加咖啡路双人跨大西洋赛。肖姝瑶在“徐京坤环球航海赛队”公众号上除了发布关于徐京坤赛队的消息，还会介绍很多航海英雄和海上传奇，她写了这样一段话——&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“1997年，前一年在旺代环球80节暴风中救下几乎失温的拉菲尔·迪内利的皮特·戈斯，作为伴郎参加完迪内利的婚礼，两人又组合来咖啡路拿了个CLASS2组别冠军，成为离岸航海界的一段美谈。 2012年旺代让·勒·卡姆（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;对，就是2020年救人的这位&lt;/span>;）翻船18个小时之后，文森特·里乌赶来救了他一命，两人搭档到咖啡路拿了个IMOCA组别冠军。旺代生死之交的组合来咖啡路&#39;刷&#39;冠军，似乎已经成为传统了。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“阿九是懂航海的！ ”虽然他总爱开玩笑称肖姝瑶为“不靠谱的阿九”，内心里却深知她的宝贵。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;徐京坤由衷赞叹这些海上传奇超越了胜负，“我很喜欢听她给我讲这些人和故事，不过一问她，她就停不住了，我就喊停停停，我要去干活了……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《南方人物周刊》记者9月底在青岛见到徐京坤时，距离咖啡路开赛还有不到一个月的时间，“前段时间太累了，我必须调整。这次回来基本没有安排什么事情。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们一起往奥帆中心走，秋天的风吹过来，他眯着眼睛，“真棒！这是最好的季节！很舒服！ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你左胳膊怎么了？ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛奥帆中心看门大哥的脸晒得黝黑，可能来城市的时间也不长，说话还是乡音。徐京坤和一行人从他面前经过，大哥竟然脱口而出这么一问。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“小时候出了点儿事故。 ”徐京坤的语气和神情都非常平静，并且停下脚步，面带微笑地定定望着大哥。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;看门大哥坐着不动，抬起脸，眼里满是关切疼爱，带着乡里人的直接和热忱继续发问，“现在生活还好吗？ ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“还好，挺好的。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他给我们指他的“梦想号”曾经停靠的地方，“那里，那条红船的旁边。 ”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[患认知障碍的老人“被消费”60万：公检法对“坑老”现象应有力介入]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258702]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;据上海《新民晚报》2023年10月14日报道，市民任阿姨反映，她的哥哥患有严重的认知障碍，无法与人正常交流，至今未婚。任阿姨称，哥哥日常和她们生活在一起，外出超2016年，北京一美容店把不少大妈拉到店里做免费足疗，顺势推荐“能治病”的按摩项目，让客户花钱办卡，骗取十余人百万余元。海淀法院一审以诈骗罪，判处美容店经理赵某和店长冯某有期徒刑10年，判处3位美容技师4年至5年不等的有期徒刑，并处罚金。可见，美容美发行业针对老人尤其是失能老人的诈骗行为，无论是经手具体事宜的工作人员，还是企业管理者，情节严重者都需为此承担刑责。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;司法机关应让法律有牙齿，对更多同类案例强化问责，也是向各行业商家发出警示：对老人设以种种消费陷阱，甚至利用其身体或精神疾病，诱导加强制其消费，公检法应有力介入。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过一两公里就要家人陪同。2019年，他独自去了家门口的文峰宛平店理发，迄今竟在文峰美容美发宛平店和天钥桥店内“被消费”近50次，妹妹们多年来省吃俭用为他积攒的近60万元看病钱、养老钱被掏了个干干净净。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;所谓认知障碍，据首都医科大学宣武医院主任医师贾建平介绍，认知障碍又称认知缺陷，常分为轻度认知障碍和痴呆两类，患者可同时出现性格、情绪改变、异常行为等表现。一个存在认知和沟通障碍的独身老人，是限制民事行为能力人。民法典第二十二条规定，不能完全辨认自己行为的成年人为限制民事行为能力人，实施民事法律行为由其法定代理人代理或者经其法定代理人同意、追认。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从任阿姨哥哥的反馈来看，门店不仅派“专人”跟着去银行或取现或转账，还“帮”着他们眼中的“笨爷叔”借贷。如此行为，显然是利用老人的认知障碍欺骗或强制其消费。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任阿姨还发现，其哥哥不仅在该美容店消费近60万，还存在充值与电子付款记录在时间和金额上均不相符、数万元消费只有手写充值凭证而没有出现在文峰收款记录、收款方显示为外地广告公司、“文峰全身养护金典精油”单次消费达1万元等反常情况。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果任阿姨陈述属实，该文峰美容店已涉嫌诈骗罪。《关于公安机关管辖的刑事案件立案追诉标准的规定（二）》规定：合同诈骗案以非法占有为目的，在签订、履行合同过程中，骗取对方当事人财物，数额在二万元以上的，应予立案追诉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刑法第二百二十四条关于合同诈骗罪的规定：诈骗公私财物，数额较大的，处三年以下有期徒刑、拘役或者管制，并处或者单处罚金；数额巨大或者有其他严重情节的，处三年以上十年以下有期徒刑，并处罚金；数额特别巨大或者有其他特别严重情节的，处十年以上有期徒刑或者无期徒刑，并处罚金或者没收财产。司法解释《关于办理诈骗刑事案件具体应用法律若干问题的解释》第一条规定：诈骗公私财物价值三千元至一万元以上、三万元至十万元以上、五十万元以上的，应当分别认定为刑法第二百六十六条规定的“数额较大”“数额巨大”“数额特别巨大”。对照刑法及最高法、最高检相关解释，任阿姨哥哥在文峰美容店“被消费”近60万已属“数额特别巨大”，司法机关当立案调查。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任阿姨哥哥的遭遇并非个案，随着中国逐步进入老龄化社会，老人群体的权益保障备受各界关注。2016年，全国老龄办、民政部等共同发布的第四次中国城乡老年人生活状况抽样调查结果显示，我国失能、半失能老年人大致4063万人，占老年人口18.3%。其中伴随失智的老人比例也不低。失能、半失能老人往往全部或者部分丧失了生活自理能力，而作为监护人的配偶、子女，受种种原因所限无法时刻伴随身边，也就容易给某些不法者可乘之机。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“老吾老以及人之老”本为社会伦理，但某些人却视老人为待宰羔羊。近年来，针对老人群体的不法案例屡屡曝出，2022年4月，平安中国建设协调小组牵头部署全国打击整治养老诈骗专项行动。6月，最高检公布6件打击整治养老诈骗犯罪典型案例，6件典型案例覆盖了投资养老产业、预定养老公寓、销售收藏品、提供老年人诊疗服务、代办“养老抚恤金”等多种养老诈骗典型手段，涉及集资诈骗罪、非法吸收公众存款罪、诈骗罪、侵犯公民个人信息罪等涉养老诈骗相关罪名。坑害老人的套路有多深，法律所应发挥的问责效力就应有多大。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 14:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[公费定向师范生违约屡见不鲜，多集中于工作后]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258728]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，广东陆丰市教育局发布《广东省公费定向培养粤东粤西粤北地区中小学教师（定向汕尾陆丰）违约人员名单》，引起社会关注。该名单显示，共有5名毕业生未履约。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实上，据南都记者调查，近年来公费定向师范生违约的情况屡见不鲜。作为学校公费定向师范生的一名班主任，广州大学粤港澳大湾区社会发展与教育政策研究院常务副院长谢爱磊教授接受南都专访时表示，虽然违约人数的占比并不大，但违约人数有明显的上升趋势，“工作后才违约的情况比较常见”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在他看来，学生违约反映的是个人利益与公共利益的冲突，如果能从政策等层面增加学生个人的获得感，其实可以实现公共利益与个人利益的双赢。为此，他建议相关政府部门应该更多地在“前补偿”的基础上开展“后激励”措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;现象：近年多地公布未履约名单工作后违约较多&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;据了解，2020年，广东省教育厅、中共广东省委机构编制委员会办公室、广东省财政厅、广东省人力资源和社会保障厅发布《关于公费定向培养粤东粤西粤北地区中小学教师的实施办法》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中提到，为进一步精准补充乡村教师，优化教师资源配置，提升广东省教师队伍的整体素质，按照“自愿报名、择优录取、公费培养定向从教、限期服务”的原则，每年为粤东粤西粤北地区中小学培养一批高素质的学前教育、特殊教育、小学教育（全科）和义务教育阶段学校音乐、体育、美术等紧缺学科教师，为高中阶段培养专业突出、底蕴深厚的研究生学历层次教师。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4a95c819d799b760f5145616e3b18e61.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;2144&quot; height=&quot;1189&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4a95c819d799b760f5145616e3b18e61.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254228&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;南都记者调查发现，《广东省公费定向培养粤东粤西粤北地区中小学教师（定向汕尾陆丰）违约人员名单》发布于今年9月底，共有5名毕业生未履约，毕业时间为2023年6月。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这并非汕尾陆丰首次公布违约人员名单。 2022年2月，就有4名毕业生未履约，毕业时间为2021年6月；11月，又有2名毕业生未履约，毕业时间为2022年6月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同样在今年9月，广东雷州市教育局发布通报，2人于2023年毕业后因个人原因未履约；另2人于2022年毕业在雷州市服务满1年后因个人原因不再继续履约。 10月，潮州潮安也公布违约名单，3人因个人原因未履约，毕业时间为2023年6月。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/fbe643db5c234a27039decf97890bc04.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;2144&quot; height=&quot;1189&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/fbe643db5c234a27039decf97890bc04.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254229&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/317238fdb3fc3e6d86f92948bcb54bdc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;798&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/317238fdb3fc3e6d86f92948bcb54bdc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254230&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，近年来诸如汕尾海丰、茂名化州、云浮郁南、清远连南等地也都公布过违约名单，既有应届毕业生违约，也有工作后违约的情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据调查，公费定向师范生到定向安排的学校（含村小、教学点）任教不少于6年。在规定服务期内，公费定向培养对象不得以升学、调动为由不履行限期服务约定。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那么，违约成本有多大呢？ 《实施办法》中明确，对服务期内未能履行协议规定的，各地负责按照规定追缴公费定向培养对象退还所享受的培养经费，并按照培养经费总额的30%收缴其违约金，超过1个月缴纳时限的每天按照应缴交费用1‰的比例加收其逾期付款违约金，其违约行为应记入人事档案和社会信用体系，并予以公布。各地收缴的违约退缴资金按照“谁管理、谁使用、谁负责”原则，专项用于支持和补助地方中小学教师队伍建设。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;分析：违约反映的是个人利益与公共利益的冲突&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“据调查研究，公费定向师范生违约人数的占比并不大，但违约人数有明显的上升趋势，因此也引起社会的广泛关注。”谢爱磊告诉记者，违约其实要分为主动违约和被动违约来看。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被动方面，《实施办法》有相关规定，学生若未能在基本修业年限内获取毕业证书或学位证书的，或因个人原因（除因身体健康、应征入伍外）中断学业等情况出现，“经培养院校研究、计划来源地同意，取消其公费定向培养资格，由所在高校按照国家有关规定负责处理”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;主动方面，对于应届毕业生而言，由于对毕业后要去的乡村教师工作范围、现状、环境等不满意，希望追求更高层次的工作单位，也有学生希望升学深造而违约。而对于工作的毕业生而言，主要是发展诉求得不到满足。由于已经积累了足够的经验与资本，毕业生希望流动到更好的工作岗位，且有足够的经济基础支付违约金而违约。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此外，还有部分已经工作的公费定向师范生无法适应地方的工作实际情况、文化和氛围，未达到履约的工作年限便离开岗位。据调查，有些地方形成主管部门在制定公费定向培养计划需求时，未能科学预测、合理规划、及时调整，导致公费定向师范生毕业后的岗位匹配出现问题，出现“哪里缺老师就派到哪里去”“教师专业与工作岗位不对口、不匹配”等情况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“总的来说，违约时间较多集中在毕业后，工作好几年才违约的情况比较常见。”谢爱磊说道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为定向班的班主任，谢爱磊也观察到，并非所有学生在入学之初就清楚该项目的实际情况。 “包括我带的学生，部分人是父母帮忙做的选择，他们对定向教师这个岗位、将来的工作情况等都不太了解。”他告诉南都记者：“我留意到一些趋势，学生刚入学的时候，很多人更关注违约的成本和责任，但对将来要工作的地方认识不充分。到了大二，学生就开始焦虑，思考回去工作该怎么办、毕业后有没有可能有其他选择等。到了大三，学生就考虑万一回去不适应怎么办、定向6年后会是怎样的情况等。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从社会学的角度来看，违约其中很大的一个原因是学生早期在做选择时并没有认清现实情况，后期的职业认同没有被充分发展起来。从教育经济学的角度来看，违约其实反映的是个人利益与公共利益的冲突，并不能一味指责学生；如果能增加学生个人的获得感，也是可以实现公共利益与个人利益的双赢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，自新生入学开始，谢爱磊就定向地开展干预，通过定期一对一交流、开班会课等形式，普及公费定向师范生的权利和义务、教师工作的内涵、将来工作岗位的环境等，并带领学生开展粤东粤西粤北县域学校调查，以此来增强学生的职业和岗位认同感。 “据观察，毕业后学生违约主要是离开工作岗位，但很少离开教师职业。如果学校、老师能有意识地干预，学生的专业认同、职业认同、岗位认同都会有更好的结果。”&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;建议：在“前补偿”的基础上实行“后激励”举措&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;虽然针对违约，政策层面也有一定制约机制。但在谢爱磊看来，惩罚只能说是兜底，但并不能从根本上解决该问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他建议，对于学生而言，在进入公费定向项目之前，需要更充分地思考自己的职业规划，了解乡村教师的工作内容、实际的工作条件。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于培养院校而言，要重点把握好志愿填报前期的关键时间节点，加大宣传力度。学生入学后，院校也要从管理的角度入手，在让学生充分掌握专业技能的同时，持续关注和引导学生的职业、岗位认同感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于地方教育部门而言，要结合教师教育改革发展的实际情况，科学预测区域内基础教育领域紧缺学科教师的补充需求，合理编制每年的公费定向培养计划。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;除此之外，相关政府部门还应该更多地在“前补偿”的基础上开展“后激励”措施。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如，政府部门可以根据学校的偏远程度、环境情况等，实施分类分层级的奖励机制。 “我有学生利用粤东粤西粤北县中学校教师的数据做了一个调查，发现学校离珠三角经济发达地区越远的老师越想要流动。如果按照这个情况来看，是不是可以有差异化的奖励机制。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，根据履约年限进行奖励，在专业发展、晋升渠道等方面给予更多的机会和优待政策，增强公费定向师范生的工作动力。 《实施办法》里就提出，鼓励公费定向培养对象通过自学考试或函授、在职攻读研究生等形式提升学历。谢爱磊还提到，可以联合高层次的师范大学，建立定向师范协同培养中心，为符合条件的毕业生提供高层次的教育硕士学位，在体制机制方面解决他们的后顾之忧。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在学生履约完成后，能否获得高质量的流动，也是值得思考的方法之一。”谢爱磊说道。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 13:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[原来还有这种工作？那些年轻人的新职业]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258686]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/ixlq7CuqiKTEFc36f3raE7dUDrkxpTycW2Xp6LRI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/ixlq7CuqiKTEFc36f3raE7dUDrkxpTycW2Xp6LRI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254139&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;近年来，许多新职业崭露头角。2019年，一位供职于辣卤食品电商公司的“品兔师”受到关注，他每年要试吃两千多个兔头。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;天刚亮，王霏一行人备足干粮，驶过几百公里的戈壁滩，前面是行行重山，看不到人，也没有信号。她们需要不断观察天气变化，计算水和油的存量，上矿山时，沿途放一些干粮。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;矿山上的路异常狭窄，车轮压在悬崖边，他们几乎不敢大口呼吸。终于到达海拔4500米处，放眼望去，形形色色的玉料正四散在地面上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这是王霏寻宝过程中的某个缩影。她是一名宝石猎人，这份职业每天充满着刺激与惊险。她的故事被记录在《新潮职业》一书中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据国家统计局公布的数据，2023年8月，全国城镇调查失业率为5.2%，比上月和上年同期有所下降。而在4月，全国16-24岁劳动力调查失业率为20.4%，青年失业率首次突破20%。如今，随着体制内缩编、互联网裁员，越来越多年轻人不再拘束于某个“格子间”，而是开始跳脱出传统行业，寻求新兴职业。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2021年，B站联合DT财经发布的《2021年青年新职业指南》显示，12%的年轻人已经在兼职尝试新职业，5.5%全职从事，58.5%想要尝试但还未行动。78%的年轻人青睐新职业是因为“符合兴趣爱好”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《2021年淘宝冷门新职业观察》盘点了十大冷门新职业，分别是：玩偶医生、绘梦师、多肉寄养师、游戏捏脸师、整理收纳师、制云师、猫粮品尝师、铸甲师、直播间布景师、手机入殓师。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;许多新职业不成规模，也不够稳定。比如上述提到的制云师，他们模拟云彩的模样，从制模、造型、打磨到成品，存在透明立方体里面，但从事者寥寥无几。这并不影响一些新职业从事者将热爱化作事业，探索出特殊的生存之道。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以下是一些新职业从事者的故事：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/kushWlXZWxL9CyRbDFg0KGmvYw6jGQv1hxQrJv1P.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;941&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/kushWlXZWxL9CyRbDFg0KGmvYw6jGQv1hxQrJv1P.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254138&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;海娜手绘乍看和文身有些相似，实际上是用植物颜料手绘在皮肤上，两周左右自然消退。成为海娜师之后，十三有时会遭遇异样的眼光。 &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;海娜师&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;画的，不疼&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;十三常被误认为是文身师。由于在朋友圈晒出海娜手绘图案，一次租房前，她曾被合租人误以为是做文身的，找借口拒绝了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然都是在人体上作画，海娜手绘，其实是用海娜花为原料的膏状植物颜料画在皮肤上，流行于中东、印度一带，一般只在皮肤上保留两周左右，之后就会自然消退。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“不是文的，不是贴的，画的！不疼！”十三特意在摊位上挂上显眼的标语。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;高中毕业后，十三辗转于不同城市，记不清换了多少份工作。她在朋友介绍下尝试海娜手绘，4天赚了2000元。练习得最疯狂时，她把自己身上能画的地方几乎都画满了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在，十三成为一名全职的海娜师已经五年了。每晚在深圳的市集，她埋头作画，一头蓝红长发在人群中很突出。不过十几分钟，一个融合着藤蔓、花朵等意象的海娜图案便呈现在顾客手背上。对她来说，最难的是控制膏体挤出的量，量不合适，线条就不够流畅好看。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一位做外贸的上班族客人，要求十三画在衣服能遮挡的地方。她的工作场合要求正式，下班后才能做回另一个自己，露出身上的图案。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个初中生被母亲带来，他的手腕处布满自残的划痕，希望用绘图覆盖它们。十三给他画了一个卡通图案，特意轻松地说：画上了这么好看的图案，以后不能再用锐器划自己了。男孩答应了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;偶尔也会遇到奇怪的人和异样的眼光，一位陌生大爷指着她脖子上的“虾线”图案，直呼恐怖。好在十三并不在意，“我不可能因为他们的个人审美去改变我自己”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;整理收纳师&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：“都是人类的家里，又能怎样呢？”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;李楠楠日常奔波于城市的各个角落，为不同人家做整理归纳。她在家政公司接受过专业培训，需要按类别和颜色归置好衣物，或是按瓶装的高矮把化妆品罗列在梳妆台上。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;虽然收纳工作繁琐而漫长，但那些私人空间里的秘密让人神经兴奋。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一天夜里11点，李楠楠去一位男主播家里做收纳，发现衣柜里置有大码女装、假发，推测他可能是扮女装做直播。她说，这种“非典型生活状态”很有意思。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有些房子乱到难以想象。一次从房间角落翻出一大堆快递盒，李楠楠准备分门别类，刚一翻动，爬出了许多正在蠕动着的小虫，还有蟑螂和老鼠。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“都是人类的家里，又能怎样呢？又没有什么特别危险的东西。比较难处理的是客户没办法安放的情绪安放在我身上。人的情况不是容易处理的。”李楠楠对南方周末记者说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有时在一旁整理着，顾客之间就吵了起来，李楠楠习以为常，不觉得尴尬。偶尔一些怒火也会烧到她身上，顾客莫名挑她的刺，上门收纳者成了家中矛盾的出气筒。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一次，顾客责怪她把贵重物品和不值钱的物件混在一起摆放，怪她不专业、不懂。每当这个时候，李楠楠都秉承“沉默是金”的原则，少说话、多做事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从事这份工作，李楠楠见识了人间百态。一个初中生趁父母不在家，请她来整理书房。那个暑假男孩总是独自在家，整理结束后，他让李楠楠留下来一起打游戏。后来，李楠楠又去陪他玩了几次，仿佛见到了青少年时期的自己。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;仿真宠物定制师&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;把它留在身边&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;做过两年兽医的陈子婷遇到过很多无力回天的情况。面对宠物主人焦急的面孔，她难以开口让他们去和宠物做最后的告别，有时甚至跟着一起哭起来。长期下来，她难以负荷这么多的悲伤。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;后来，她开始用羊毛毡做成仿真的宠物，制成挂件、摆件或钥匙扣，有些只做宠物的头部，有些要做全身，都是一针一针扎出来的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三分之二来定制的客人，宠物都已经去世了，他们拿着宠物生前的照片，希望用仿真版留作纪念。很多主人在收到快递的那一刻，看到与宠物相似的样貌，都会忍不住落泪。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一个顾客为她的加菲猫定制了一个头像摆件。这只猫从毕业后就一直陪在她身边，后来小猫患上皮肤病，主人特意为它换了工作，搬去了一个更干燥的城市。但在一次她出差途中，加菲猫心脏病发猝死，她连夜赶车回去将它火化了。她找到陈子婷，希望以另一种形式将它留在身边。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;陈子婷也养了一只猫，宠物对她来说是“家人一样的存在”。她理解宠物离开后，主人极度的悲伤与不舍。她希望在不幸发生之后，“还能再为他们做点什么”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;动物沟通师&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;它&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;们需要被尊重”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;动物沟通师罗心妍同样试图为这些悲伤的宠物主人做点什么。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她是生活在广东的台湾人，主要工作是和动物进行沟通。在台湾，这是一个较为成熟的职业，有专门的行业协会和培训课程。沟通师认为自己可以通过声音、画面、意念甚至味道等等，和动物的灵魂进行交流。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;开始沟通前，罗心妍通常请主人先向宠物“预告”，告知会有沟通师和它们聊天，先获取宠物的基本信息和近照。她声称，这样有利于宠物的配合，“我知道你要来找我，因为妈妈有说过”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其中比较特别的是和离世宠物的沟通，据罗心妍介绍，通常要等宠物去世后7-14天才可以预约。在她的转述里，和一只离世小狗的“对话”是这样的：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“在动物王国（天堂）过得好吗？都在做什么？”“没什么事能做，有时候会稍微无聊一下下。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“喜欢放骨灰的地方吗？”“喜欢，颜色我也喜欢。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;曾有一位主人的小狗病逝后，着急地找到罗心妍，想知道它死后过得如何，是否收到了自己烧去的礼物和纸钱。罗心妍说，她向小狗解释了它身旁一沓软软的纸是爸爸给的钱，还见到了球和娃娃等小物件。男主人听后激动地确认，的确烧了这些东西。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这只小狗去世后，女主人深陷自责，认定是自己没有照顾好它。罗心妍说，小狗让她转达，自己离世不是他们的错，不用为它担心，以后要开心地生活。虽然其他人都无法听到或验证这些对话的真实性，但这对主人确实得到了宽慰。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对罗心妍来说，每只动物都是一个个体，“有感受、有爱，很纯真，很包容，它们需要被尊重”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/q9E8eOoBU0sCHOxb7q3GTwinSZbhy94j0vvXe505.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/q9E8eOoBU0sCHOxb7q3GTwinSZbhy94j0vvXe505.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254140&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;寻求玩偶修复的顾客大多不舍将陪伴自己多年的玩偶丢弃，把它们当成了朋友。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;玩偶修复师&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;它不是玩具，是我的朋友&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;有人对宠物不舍，也有人将情感寄托于陪伴多年的玩偶。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卢晓希有一只陪伴自己十七年的白色毛绒兔子，只有小臂般大小。十七年的时光使她从小孩成长为大人，小兔子原本繁密的毛绒开始掉落，某些区域几乎变得光秃。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她在网上偶然看到有人专门做玩偶修复，想寄去修复，但高昂的价格让她望而却步。小时候卢晓希曾跟姥姥学过一点缝纫，就摸索着自己进行修复。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;兔子的嘴、手、脚的毛几乎掉光，需要修补的面积很大，她断断续续修复了一个月，才将这些部位重新植完毛。这之后，卢晓希开始接单，将玩偶修复作为兼职。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有的玩偶磨损严重，需要植毛，有的需要充棉，也有的只是裂线，需要缝补。修复一只玩偶，通常要花上一两周。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;植毛是最麻烦的。如果只是少量掉毛，可以从它身上取下浮毛，搓成一小撮，再根据玩偶里的网格状纹路用镊子压穿回去。如果掉毛太过严重，就像她的兔子一样，就要重新买毛布，将毛揪下来再植上去。通常植一小块区域就得花费两三个小时，手也会很疼。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;卢晓希很喜欢这个新工作，她觉得玩偶承载着许多回忆，哪怕玩偶破损严重，主人也舍不得扔掉，这种情感她很理解。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一位顾客曾经寄来一只需要修复的小熊，并附上了一封信件。信是以小熊的口吻写的，它说，自己已经陪伴了主人十三年，跟着她去了很多地方，希望能帮忙好好修复。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“它们不是玩具，跟朋友差不多。”卢晓希告诉南方周末记者。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/PWA1ql1QbWM9wftp13WP5i6grXgwdrUR7iYcXxSI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;1280&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/16/PWA1ql1QbWM9wftp13WP5i6grXgwdrUR7iYcXxSI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254137&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;彩妆修复师刘程每单20-40元不等，按照修复难度定价，月入上万元。&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者供图/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;彩妆修复师&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;二十元一单，月入上万&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;如果说修复玩偶是出于浓浓的情感，那么修复彩妆的顾客更多则是带着实用的目的。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彩妆修复师刘程的工作台如同一个实验室，消毒柜、口红模具、粉饼压盘、薄膜、烧杯等应有尽有。作为一个不久前对彩妆一窍不通的男性，现在已对市面上的常见品牌如数家珍。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他以前从事房地产，入行纯属偶然。疫情期间闲着无事，他发现妻子有些化妆品坏了，但扔了可惜，试着修复了几次，效果不错。几个月前，妻子开始在网上替他接单。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这份工作相当精细。早些时候修复某个粉饼时，刘程按既定的步骤进行，效果却不太好，后来他才发现，粉饼还有烘焙质地，工艺不同，方法当然不通用。研究完相应的质地后，才最终修好。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在抖音、小红书等社交平台，彩妆修复博主不算稀有，业务覆盖范围很广，包括粉饼修复、彩妆的分装与合装、口红改色等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据刘程观察，顾客大多是年轻的大学生，总体来看，18至40岁的女性都有，市场很是庞大。光顾彩妆修复的人，有些是勤俭节约，还有些是因为物品为亲朋好友相赠，不舍它承载的情感意义。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最常被修复的是粉饼和口红，粉饼一般是碎了需要复原，口红可能是断了，或是想改变颜色。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;修复并不总是顺畅。有一次修复口红，刘程返工了4回，一回是修复完后仍有裂痕和气泡，还有一回，口红熔化的过程中黏在杯壁上，修复完只剩下四分之一，只得又熔化重来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;刘程修复一单的价格大约二十元，难度较高的就三四十元，目前每个月能有一万元以上的收入。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;宠物经纪人&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;敬业的星探&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;作为一名宠物经纪人，双双的工作是对接品牌方和宠物模特，还要通过各种渠道找不同品种的宠物，挖掘合作模特。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有一次逛商场，她见到一个女生牵着一只漂亮的边牧路过，双双立刻拔腿追上去，整整三层楼才追上，顺利要到了主人的联系方式。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它的毛色是边牧品种中较为少见的三色陨石，眼睛特别蓝，体型也不大，双双一眼就看中它是做模特的好苗子。而且，它在拥挤的商场里乖乖地跟在主人身边，说明稳定性不错，适合棚内拍摄。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;事实证明，双双这个星探眼光不错。拍摄那天，这只边牧表现出了极高的配合度，只用了十三分钟便完成了七个不同角度和姿势的拍摄，而一般宠物平均的模卡拍摄时长是半个小时到一个小时。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;双双不愿意透露宠物的具体报价，这算是商业秘密。她介绍了一般行情，专业宠物模特一天的出场费大约是一千至两千元。不过，不同的宠物身价不同，外形突出、有镜头感、稳定性和配合度高，待遇就更高，主人好沟通、时间自由也是加分项。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;想做好宠物经纪人，双双需要尽可能搜集更多品种的宠物，同一品种也需要不同颜色和体型。同一体型和颜色的宠物最好有三四只，拍摄出现意外可随时顶替。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拍摄时，双双会变身助理，随时跟在宠物模特身边进行照看、引导和安抚。有一次出外景，刚到拍摄场地，模特狗就跟路过的其他狗打了起来。她和同事一起先“摁住”自己的模特，让人赶紧牵走另一只。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每天围着宠物打转，双双觉得幸福。心情很低落时，狗狗伸出爪子摸摸她，就让她感到治愈，“每一个瞬间都是感动的”。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;宠物日托主理人&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;：&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;“就像小朋友上幼儿园”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;任梦音喜欢动物，她养了一只猫、两条狗，最大的八岁，最小的也有六岁。她从学生时期就开始养宠物，工作后陪伴它们的时间锐减。她发现，这也是大多数上班族的现状，他们早出晚归，宠物只能自己待在家中。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;她和朋友共同开了一家狗狗日托店，面向的就是这些上班族，白天他们上班前，就把小狗寄放在店里，“就像小朋友上幼儿园一样”。大多数家长会办理一个“学期”，即30天。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早上，他们用“校车”上门接来狗狗，晚上再送回家。狗狗通常在店里吃早餐，食物基本都是自带的。每天“上学”的日程满满当当，比如下午茶环节，设计了不同的活动形式，有时用漏食玩具喂食，或是把点心放在草坪上，让它们自己去寻找着吃。傍晚时，任梦音和同事会带着狗狗去店外的溪边散步。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;正如每个班有不同性格的同学一样，狗狗中也有“i狗”和“e狗”。他们会“因材施教”，对不太喜欢社交的“i狗”来说，更吸引它们的是气味、触感和氛围，刚来日托时，让“i狗”慢慢观察和适应环境，有些小狗可能会找一个舒适的地方自己晒太阳。而“e狗”性格开朗，会主动和其他狗一起玩。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个月三四次，日托店会组织类似秋游的活动，带狗狗去海边或草地，玩一些巡回游戏或拔河游戏。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任梦音一直记得那个画面，有一次下着雨，竹叶在雨中摇摆，狗狗们一起在靠近户外的区域，嗅闻着空气中的气味。看到这一幕，她忽然很有成就感，“它们满足了，好像你也没有什么其他所求了”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（应受访者要求，文中人物皆为化名）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[10天涨粉百万，普通青年“于文亮”如何引发热议？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258716]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日本知名音乐人谷村新司逝世]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258726]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 10:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span>;据日本NHK电视台16日报道，日本知名&lt;/span>;音乐人谷村新司10月8日逝世，终年74岁。据悉，谷村新司于今年3月因急性肠炎进行&lt;span>;了手术并住院接受治疗。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;谷村新司的一生与中国结缘甚深，不少知名歌手演唱过许多他的作品，比如张学友的《遥远的她》。 《遥远的她》原曲为日本创作歌手谷村新司的《浪漫铁道（蹉跌篇）》，其词曲皆由谷村新司创作，发行于1985年6月。同年在香港被改编、录制为粤语版本《遥远的她》，由潘源良填词，卢东尼编曲，欧丁玉监制，张学友主唱，歌曲推出后大受欢迎，成为1985年年尾至1986年中期电台播放率最高单曲之一，亦与《情已逝》《月半弯》《蓝雨》等一同成为张学友出道早期著名单曲之一。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4630dc403a13077145f08e9a16e4e068.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;796&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/4630dc403a13077145f08e9a16e4e068.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254233&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;除了张学友，邓丽君、罗文、谭咏麟、梅艳芳、关正杰、徐小凤、张国荣、郭富城、黎明等人均演绎过他的作品。他曾经表示张学友和谭咏麟是与他最有默契的香港朋友。他在1984年与赵容弼和谭咏麟共同创建PAX MUSICA，中文名为“音乐的和平世界”，旨在推动文化交流和世界和平。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/15ae3ba9d860e52f686ac237bc41f4ed.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/15ae3ba9d860e52f686ac237bc41f4ed.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254232&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;谷村新司曾与张学友同台演出。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;谷村新司传播度最广的名曲为《昴》，被改编过不同的语言版本，国语版本为凤飞飞的《另一种乡愁》（晨曦填词）、姜育恒的《我的心没有回程》（李子恒填词）和陈彼得的《夜行》（陈彼得填词），粤语版本为关正杰的《星》和罗文的《号角》（两首皆由郑国江填词）。他亦参与和制作了多次关于中国与日本友好的演出，包括应日本政府和中国政府之邀请参与策划中日建交三十周年大型晚会等一系列节目。 &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/f78d0d0c611de340af772974a715afb4.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/f78d0d0c611de340af772974a715afb4.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254231&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;谷村新司曾多次访华演唱这首《昴》。 2008年3月24日，谷村新司被授予2010年上海世博会形象大使头衔。 9月16日，谷村新司应相约北京之约，与亚洲13个国家和地区的歌手共同出席了在北京展览馆剧场举办的亚洲之夜大型歌会，演唱了其成名代表作品《昴》。 2010年4月30日，谷村新司在中国2010年上海世界博览会开幕式上演唱了《昴》。 6月12日，他在上海世博会日本国家馆日世博中心红厅举行的“连接起来，为了和谐的未来”主题表演中再次演唱了歌曲《昴》。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/bad225c8659a8d0481aa62d81c50bfdf.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/bad225c8659a8d0481aa62d81c50bfdf.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254234&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;谷村新司在上海世博会开幕式上演唱。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;谷村新司一生都在致力于音乐创作和促进中日友好，他的去世消息出来后，不少中国歌迷到他生前最后一条微博下留言道别。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/fb60057e706d69d13617c15991642a81.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;757&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/17/fb60057e706d69d13617c15991642a81.png&quot; data-key=&quot;254235&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;不少中国歌迷到他生前最后一条微博下留言道别。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 10:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[河南郸城几百农民哄抢玉米上热搜：维护农业投资者权益不能和稀泥丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258678]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，河南周口郸城县一片玉米地在收割时被附近几百农民哄抢的视频，成为社交媒体热点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据新京报等媒体报道，2023年10月14日，一段很多农民“抢玉米”的视频冲上社媒热搜。视频中，一片玉米地中挤满了人，旁边的路上停满了大大小小的三轮车，还有些车直接开到了地里。视频中一名目击者的声音表示，这块玉米地总共有2000亩，被抢了有几百亩，警察来了都无法阻止，因为村民人数实在太多了。视频中也出现了警察到达现场的画面。视频最后，当地乡政府工作人员表示，乡长已经到场维护秩序。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地乡政府和郸城县农业农村局随后都否认发生了哄抢，称那些农民只是到收割过的地块“捡拾”漏下的玉米。根据郸城县农业农村局发布的情况说明，玉米地也没有2000亩那么多，只有400亩。在承包土地种玉米的公司和乡政府联系后，乡政府“立即安排乡村干部和派出所民警到现场维持秩序，劝导群众有序离开，机收工作正常进行”。当天下午，该公司400亩玉米已全部收割完毕。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;到底是哄抢还是捡拾？从视频看，大多人确实是在收割过的地里捡玉米。但是，根据目击者的说法，一开始这些人确实是跟在收割机后捡，但是后来很多人围上来，收割机都动不了，就有不少人开始抢了。退一步说，即使是机器收割过的地块，难道就可以马上去捡了吗？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在农村，确实存在捡漏的情况。这是一件好事，能够避免粮食浪费。但是，只能在主人家收获之后去捡。现在大多数人使用收割机收获农作物，经常会漏掉很多。正常情况下，主人会在机器收割结束后再人工捡漏一遍。再剩下的，别人才能去捡。直接跟在收割机后面收，那不是捡，就是抢。从承包公司报警这一举动来看，显然是不愿意看到这些农民跟在收割机后“捡拾”玉米的，更不用说还有可能存在跑到还没收的地里“捡”的人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着农村人口减少，各级政府鼓励社会资本到农村流转土地进行投资创业。但农业创业者遭到偷抢的情况不时见诸网络：大学生回乡创业养基围虾被村民哄抢，外乡人承包大棚里的西瓜被偷，还有偷南瓜的、偷桃子苹果的……总之，不管创业者种啥养啥，都可能被偷。很多创业者被迫竖起铁丝网，装上视频监控，养几条狗看护，成本高了不说，收效也不佳。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;而发生偷抢事件后，当地也会以各种借口为农民开脱。有的就像河南郸城一样，说农民不是偷抢，而是“捡拾”，是在正主收获完了之后去捡漏的；有的说是被谣言蛊惑，谣言说正主不要了，可以随便捡；有的甚至直接偏袒偷抢者，曾经有瓜农与偷瓜贼发生拉扯导致偷瓜贼倒地受了一点小伤，警方到场后竟然让瓜农赔小偷300块钱，引起舆论极大关注后，也只是让小偷退钱了事，最终也没有认定盗窃行为，偷瓜者没受到任何惩罚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;摘一两个西瓜、几个南瓜，捡几十根玉米，看起来没多少东西，好像不用“大惊小怪”。但是一旦人多了，那被摘走捡走的就不是小数目了。如果一两个人“摘”“捡”农作物的行为得不到严厉制止和惩罚，那就会有成群结队的人来“摘”来“捡”，给投资者带来巨大的损失。这样的事件一再出现，也会严重打击农业投资者的信心和积极性。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;农村劳动者减少，把土地有偿流转给外来投资者规模化经营，收取租金，有些人还可以到农场工作，获得工资，这本来是双赢的格局。但是，如果投资者的利益得不到充分的保护，那他们可能就不会再来了。没有外来投资者，本村又没有人种，结果土地就只能撂荒，农民也没了收入。农村发展又从何谈起？ &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;解决这个问题，必须旗帜鲜明地保护农业投资者的利益，打击盗抢行为，不能再和稀泥，不能再“法不责众”。也许当场因为盗抢者人员众多，难以立即全部控制，但完全可以留下视频证据，事后要求他们退回盗抢的财物，并依法进行处罚。其实只要严厉地罚一次，罚几个人，就足以震慑心存侥幸之徒，让这些当地人得到教训，不敢再去偷抢。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>