<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[长相与年龄不符意味着什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259588]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;People are growing older all the time, but their appearance does not necessarily keep pace with their age. When the appearance does not match the age and clearly looks older or younger than the actual age, different people will have different explanations for this. Especially if you look older than your actual age, it is often interpreted as premature aging. In fact, many scientific studies support the reasoning that there are actually signs of aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A long-term follow-up heart study in Copenhagen found that gray hair, facial wrinkles and male baldness are several obvious signs of aging, which may indicate that people have a higher risk of myocardial infarction, especially People with much longer gray hair have a significantly higher risk than those without gray hair. In addition to these specific external characteristics, the general feeling of &quot;looking older&quot; also has reference significance for assessing health risks. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is not easy to guess a person’s age based on visual information alone due to the interference of external factors such as clothing and grooming. In 2016, researchers from the Institute of Public Health at the University of Southern Denmark conducted a comparative study on nearly two hundred groups of identical twins and found that even if twins have the same genes and very similar looks, people can still tell the difference between their faces. Read the clues to aging too quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These elderly twins were over 70 years old as early as 2001. Researchers asked people to guess the age of the elderly people through their ID photos. The results found that whether it was changing their faces or dressing up, it would affect the age of the elderly people. People&#39;s perceptions of the age of the elderly. Statistics more than a decade later also show that the older twin is more likely to die earlier. Facial cues become a predictor of risk of survival or death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although many studies have discovered some health secrets hidden behind the face, there are not many studies that systematically analyze the relationship between appearance and aging. In order to clarify what it means to look inconsistent with age, in March 2023, researchers from Erasmus University in the Netherlands and other institutions tried to investigate how people&#39;s perceived age is related to a series of aging by analyzing more data. relationship between diseases. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Look younger and healthier&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;As expected, the results were as expected. Corresponding to the higher risk of older-looking people, those who looked younger than they actually were Younger people, who are at lower risk for many age-related diseases, also have better cognitive function overall. Relevant research was published in the British Journal of Dermatology, providing a certain reference for scientific face reading. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The phenomenon of appearance and age inconsistency is very common in daily life. In order to understand this phenomenon more scientifically and deeply, we must first distinguish three concepts about age. In addition to sensory age, which can be assessed by people&#39;s appearance alone, chronological age and physiological age are also more valuable references for health and aging. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Daniel W. Belsky, an associate professor at Columbia University School of Public Health who has long studied aging issues, told Southern Weekend reporters, “Actual age measures the time since birth, while physiological age It is a measure of health. A physiological age value can be understood as a person&#39;s typical health status at this actual age.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In other words, according to the normal aging rate, a person in good health will Their biological age should be close to or even consistent with their actual age. But in reality, some people&#39;s biological age will deviate significantly from their actual age, showing an atypical health state. Among them, if the biological age is younger than the actual age, it means that the overall health status is better than that of the average person of the same age, while the biological age is greater than the actual age, the degree of aging is deeper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The analysis of sensory age in the latest research actually explores the possibility of identifying aging through a simple way of vision, and the results show that looking younger is indeed associated with a higher risk of various diseases. lower. Specifically, looking five years younger than your actual age has a significantly lower risk of osteoporosis, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, cataracts, and hearing loss, as well as better cognitive performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;These results are based on the analysis of health data of more than 2,600 European middle-aged and elderly people. It is worth noting that the age distribution of the people included in the study ranges from their fifties to their eighties and are in the process of age-related diseases. Significantly elevated stage. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Young people’s bodies are not necessarily young&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Although current relevant research focuses on middle-aged and elderly people, it does not mean that the rhythm of maturity and aging is only in It starts to accelerate suddenly after entering middle age. There is evidence that among young people in their twenties and thirties, as their chronological age steadily increases, the gap in their biological ages begins to appear. Looking at specific manifestations, people who age faster have poorer physical abilities, cognitive decline, and brain aging. These people often feel that their health is getting worse and they look older. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Relevant research was published in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS) in 2015. What&#39;s even more cruel is that these observed aging gaps occur between the ages of 26 and 38. The same 38-year-old is not yet middle-aged, but the physiological age of different people is obviously different. Daniel Belsky, now an associate professor in the Department of Epidemiology and Center for Aging Research at Columbia University, was involved in the study. Over a period of nearly 12 years, researchers recorded changes in a range of physiological indicators in nearly a thousand participants. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Aging is a process that begins early in life. We can see signs of it in healthy young people, and some people age faster than others already at a young age. Therefore, maintaining a healthy lifestyle and seeking an environment with clean air and water are safe and reliable, and creating opportunities to participate in social interactions is also a priority.&quot; Daniel Belsky told Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;In some aspects , this is all self-evident. But it is important to realize that even in youth, which we tend to think of as indestructible, our lifestyle and environment can influence the trajectory of our aging, with long-lasting consequences.&quot;&lt; /p>; &lt;p>;At present, it is not easy to study aging, because compared with the life span of animals such as mice, which can be quickly observed in animal studies, the time span from birth to death in humans is much longer. After entering middle-aged and old age, the increase in age-related diseases makes it easier to observe people&#39;s aging. Relatively speaking, the signs of aging in young people are less easy to detect. However, when it comes to delaying aging, young people actually have more time and opportunities to make changes to improve their own health. Therefore, identifying the signs of aging as early as possible and understanding the laws of aging are of great significance to alleviating the pressure on global public health in the context of aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Perceiving the Signs of Aging Early&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;“I’m not sure individuals really need to measure their biological age.” explains Daniel Belsky, Popular Aging needs to be measured in medical research, not only to identify factors that accelerate or delay aging, but also to evaluate the effectiveness of some anti-aging projects, policies, life interventions and drug therapies. &quot;However, for those who do want to know more about their aging and health, there are a range of tools on the market that can help estimate biological age, from blood tests to DNA tests. These tests themselves are not dangerous, but the results should Interpret with caution, and it is best to interpret relevant results with the help of healthcare professionals.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In September 2023, a research report published in &quot;The Lancet Healthy Longevity&quot; It shows that chest X-ray examination, an already widely used technology, may be used to assist in the assessment of human aging. By training and developing related artificial intelligence models, the researchers used chest radiographs to estimate the age of the client. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The results show that for relatively healthy people, the age estimated by artificial intelligence through chest X-rays has a strong correlation with the actual age. But for people with pre-existing medical conditions, the difference between estimated and actual age is associated with multiple chronic conditions, identifying increased risk for hypertension, interstitial lung disease, chronic renal failure, and more. This means that common picture information such as chest X-rays may become an aging biomarker to help people evaluate the status of chronic diseases and even predict life span, while improving the level of personalized intervention and treatment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with these methods that rely on medical equipment, looking at faces directly and roughly assessing aging and related health risks based on whether appearance matches age is obviously more concise, although the accuracy is limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, it should be noted that, including looking at faces to assess sensory age, many relevant studies currently include thousands of samples, but the sources are relatively single and lack sufficient representation. Differences actually play an important role in sensory age assessment, which is also an obvious limitation of related research so far. Whether the health implications of appearance and age mismatch are effective in all types of communities remains to be confirmed by more research. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Comparative studies on skin aging have long found that the skin aging trajectories of Asians and Europeans are very different. Taking Chinese and French women as an example, a small sample study shows that Chinese women start to develop wrinkles on their faces almost ten years later than French women. This time difference will make Chinese women look significantly younger at this time, but by the age of four In their teens, Chinese women will experience rapid aging in terms of facial wrinkles, showing a non-linear trend. In comparison, French women&#39;s aging in this aspect is relatively stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Such as this, due to the differences in facial development between different races, the accuracy of applying the sensory experience of one group to predict the age of people in another group will be relatively limited. In addition, there are cultural differences in how people dress in different societies. If we understand the phenomenon of appearance and age mismatch in a cross-cultural context, we may find different rules. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;Efforts to delay aging&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;In fact, when it comes to looking at faces, whether appearance matches age is only one aspect. In 2022, biological research also found that there may be a connection between physical attractiveness and health indicators such as immune function. After a series of experiments and tests, researchers found that people who were more physically attractive also had better immune performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Summer Mengelkoch, an experimental social psychology researcher at Texas Christian University who participated in this study, told Southern Weekend reporters that although a person who cares too much about physical attractiveness may appear They are very superficial, but their research shows that when people pay attention to the physical attractiveness of their partners, they may actually care about more than just looks, and may also use this to select a healthy partner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The latest research starts from the gap between sensory age and actual age, providing more evidence for scientific face reading. By identifying the signs and risk factors of aging as early as possible, you can take action to slow down aging. In May 2023, researchers from Harvard Medical School found in studies on mice and humans that physiological age will fluctuate in both directions under the influence of stress. When stress is excessive, physiological age will increase, and after recovery from stress, physiological age will increase. Age will reverse repair. This may provide a suitable entry point for future interventions targeting aging. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Whether we are middle-aged or still young. To promote healthy aging, the things we can do are actually the same. Eat a healthy diet, do a lot of physical activities, and participate in family activities. , socializing with friends and community, cultivating a sense of purpose and meaning, and avoiding toxic stress and pollution.&quot; Daniel Belsky emphasized to Southern Weekend reporters, &quot;The scientific community is now developing new drugs that can slow down physiological aging and extend the healthy life cycle. At the same time, we already know how to promote healthy aging by changing the environment in which we live—reducing pollution, ensuring safe and secure housing, and providing affordable and healthy food. We should invest in these areas as well. .&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[从魂魄、中阴身到幽灵Vs魔鬼：万圣节话中西之鬼异同]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259582]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Every year before Halloween comes, all kinds of creative and scary costumes bloom everywhere, and you can constantly watch short videos. Although today&#39;s Halloween is no different from &quot;Cosplay Festival&quot;. But its original &quot;ghost-driving&quot; element is still vaguely visible - even though in modern society, ghosts and gods have long become the objects of ridicule played by humans. However, various countries&#39; understanding of &quot;what is a ghost&quot; still follows thousands of years of tradition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is a wonderful discussion and definition of &quot;what is a ghost&quot; in &quot;Book of Rites·Jiyi&quot;: &quot;Zaiwo said: I heard the names of ghosts and gods, but I don&#39;t know what they mean. The Master said: Qi is also , the prosperity of gods. The prosperity of souls, the prosperity of ghosts. The combination of ghosts and gods is the ultimate teaching. All living things must die, and after death they must return to the earth. This is called ghosts.&quot; Zaiwo didn&#39;t understand what ghosts and gods were, so Confucius told him: &quot; God is essence, and ghost is soul. All living things will die, and after death they will return to dust, which are called ghosts.&quot; - Confucius played a homophonic joke here: ghosts are all living things. ultimate destination. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because of this, in China’s oldest traditions, ghosts and gods are often not clearly distinguished. As the saying goes, &quot;Ghosts are ancestors, and ancestors are also ghosts.&quot; The Confucian attitude towards ghosts and gods is also very interesting. Confucius once said: &quot;Respect ghosts and gods and keep them at a distance.&quot; He also said: &quot;If you can&#39;t serve people, how can you serve ghosts?&quot; In short, he tried his best to avoid the issue of ghosts and gods, and even showed an agnostic tendency to a certain extent. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the other hand, Confucianism places great emphasis on respecting ancestors and offering sacrifices on time. If ghosts and gods do not exist at all, then what are they worshiping? Confucius added another patch to this: &quot;Sacrifice to the gods as if they were present, and sacrifice to the gods as if the gods were present. Confucius said: If I don&#39;t offer sacrifices, it would be as if I didn&#39;t offer sacrifices.&quot; In other words, when offering sacrifices to ancestors, it seems as if the ancestors are really in front of you; when offering sacrifices to gods, It was as if God was really in front of me. Confucius also said that if I do not personally participate in the sacrifice, the sacrifice will be the same as no sacrifice. From this, it can be seen that Confucius emphasized that those who participate in the sacrifice should have pious emotions in their hearts. According to Confucianism, sacrifice is a moral ritual used to unite the community, rather than a religious ritual used to pray for blessings and ward off disasters. Therefore, salutes are just out of recalling the feelings of ancestors. As the saying goes, &quot;sages teach with Shinto.&quot; And the sacrifices are mainly for the living people to see: &quot;Be careful and pursue the long distance, and the people&#39;s virtue will be strong.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From today&#39;s perspective, Confucius&#39;s view is very advanced. However, on the other hand, it seems to be contradictory to avoid the issue of ghosts and gods while requiring people to worship sincerely. Mohism, the lifelong enemy of Confucianism, once seized this point and vigorously ridiculed Confucianism. Contrary to Confucianism, Mohism strives to prove the real existence of ghosts and gods, so it regards sacrifice as more important than Confucianism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for Taoism, the attitude is more distinct than that of Confucianism. It is believed that after death, one returns to heaven and earth, and there is no such thing as ghosts and gods. Therefore, &quot;Zhuangzi&quot; sings with drums and pots, and &quot;Liehzi&quot; believes that death means eternal rest. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, when Mozi argued that &quot;the ghosts and gods must be solemnly sacrificed&quot;, he also exposed his true thoughts: &quot;Although the ghosts and gods are asked to die, this can still bring joy to the crowd and get relatives in the hometown&quot;—— &quot;Even if there are really no ghosts and gods, we can still connect with the villagers through ritual gatherings.&quot; This is the same as Confucianism, which shows that Mozi&#39;s own belief was not so firm. After all, it is hard to imagine that monotheistic believers would say, &quot;Even if there is really no God, belief in God can have the following benefits...&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even the Mohist school, which emphasizes ghosts and gods the most among the local schools, has this kind of attitude towards the existence of ghosts and gods. Attitude, it is not difficult to understand why the early setting of the underworld in Chinese mythology is so monotonous. Before the introduction and prosperity of Buddhism, although China had the concept of the underworld, it was still very simple: the underworld is the destination of the soul and is controlled by the Lord Taishan, but there is no such thing as hell; and although the story of reincarnation appeared very early, it is not It is regarded as a fixed procedure in the underworld, and is just an anecdote similar to &quot;seizing the body&quot; in later generations. Therefore, there is no concept of reincarnation and rebirth. For the ancients, death still means eternal separation and tranquility. As the saying goes, &quot;What is the way to die? The body is supported by the same mountain.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Going to hell after death is also the oldest view of life and death in China. It is still used as a euphemism for death to this day. There is also a famous story here, where Zheng Zhuanggong dug into the ground to meet his mother:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Zheng Zhuanggong decided that his younger brother had rebelled, he was very angry with his mother Wu Jiang who favored his younger brother. He put Wu Jiang under house arrest in Yingdi, and swore a poisonous oath: &quot;It&#39;s not as good as Huangquan, and we won&#39;t see each other again.&quot; This means we won&#39;t see each other until we die. As a result, Ying Kaoshu, an official of Yingdi, successfully persuaded Duke Zhuang of Zheng and aroused his family affection and filial piety. But Duke Zhuang still used the oath of poison as an excuse, so Uncle Yingkao said: &quot;This is easy to do. We can dig tunnels until the yellow spring water is dug out, and build an underground courtyard there. Can&#39;t you guys meet?&quot;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;So Zhuang Gong, mother and son were able to meet in the tunnel. They hugged each other and cried, and reconciled as before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many people were speechless when they first read this paragraph: they reconciled as before, but the problem is that Zheng Zhuanggong and his mother didn&#39;t like each other at first... And the Yellow Spring is really a yellow spring? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Obviously, Huangquan Temple comes from burial. After death, people go underground, not just Huangquan. Most scholars believe that the original meaning of Huangquan is underground water, because many three-generation ancient tombs are located below the water level. When Buddhism brought reincarnation in, it combined with the view of Huangquan to create &quot;Hell&quot; (Naluka) - the Indian native &quot;Naluka&quot;, which is more similar to a parallel universe or an alien space. After death, people will enter this Space is judged; but Chinese tradition believes that after death, people must go underground. Therefore, the Buddhists had no choice but to move &quot;Naluojia&quot; underground, which gave it the name &quot;Hell&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The reincarnation of Buddhism is inherited from the traditional setting of Hinduism. There are actually similar theories all over the world. For example, the ancient Greek philosopher Plato often mentioned reincarnation in his books. But for most civilizations, this theory is just an anecdote, not a universally accepted assumption. Only in South Asia, reincarnation is the axiomatic basis of all religions and philosophies. Even the reason why the Buddha became a monk was to find the right path to escape the suffering of reincarnation. Buddhism believes that if all living beings are freed from reincarnation, it means the end of all &quot;suffering&quot;. This is what Buddhism says &quot;all living beings are suffering&quot;. Beings who are not in the &quot;reincarnation&quot; are no longer sentient beings, but Buddhas. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the Buddhist theory of reincarnation is obviously in conflict with China’s native sacrifices. In order to solve this conflict, there are various patches, such as &quot;Ghosts line up in the underworld waiting to be reincarnated, and they have to live during the lottery.&quot; This &quot;lottery&quot; state between two reincarnations and two deaths is called the &quot;bardo&quot; in Buddhism. But this patch is still incomplete - the emperor wants to offer sacrifices to his ancestors. Is it because the ancestors have waited hundreds of years and still not passed away? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So after Taoism absorbed the concept of reincarnation, it added another patch: humans have three souls and seven souls, and the three souls are the heaven soul, the earth soul, and the life soul. What dissipates after death is not the soul, but the soul. The three souls reincarnate after death, the heavenly soul goes to heaven, and the earthly soul lives in the ancestral hall or tomb. Therefore, before a person&#39;s life soul is reincarnated, all the money burned is for the life soul. The soul of life is reincarnated, and what is burned is for the soul of earth. Different Taoist schools have different patch theories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in modern times, Christianity has brought heaven into the world, and the situation has become even more confusing: After death, a person can enjoy the sacrifices of his descendants in the underworld and enter the six realms of reincarnation. Can he also watch his descendants in heaven at the same time? Some people have tried to reconcile this: after death, people enter Hades to be judged. After the verdict, the guilty go to reincarnation or hell, and the innocent ascend to heaven where they are, and accept sacrifices, perfect. In fact, these are not important, because the Chinese people&#39;s attitude towards life and death still comes from Confucianism: everything is a moral ceremony rather than a religious ceremony, and everything is to comfort the living. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As for the Christian attitude towards ghosts, it is also very interesting to study in detail: the devil (Satan, the devil) or demons (that is, the fallen angels who follow the devil) we often call, although they are translated as &quot;ghosts&quot;, But it is not the same thing as Chinese ghosts. The ghost that the Chinese talk about is closer to the ghost that the Europeans talk about. According to the Bible, after death, the soul will sleep with the body, waiting for the arrival of judgment and resurrection in the last days. People who belong to Christ will go to the Kingdom of God after death, which the Bible calls the new heaven and new earth; people who do not belong to Christ will go to the Kingdom of God after death. Imprisoned in Hades. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, Christianity believes that ghost phenomena in the world are all illusions made by Satan, and there are no ghosts in the world at all. Some Christians believe in the existence of ghosts, but are opposed to any form of communication with them because the Old Testament repeatedly warns against ghost communication rituals. Therefore, we can see that ghosts rarely appear in European and American ghost films. Vampires, werewolves, and cursed children are the common protagonists - but even these ghosts are also opposed by Christianity. Therefore, every year on Halloween, there are still Christian churches in Europe and the United States advocating a boycott and advocating that if children come to ask for candy, they can be given a Bible or a cross as a gift. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海关总署：11月1日起出入境人员免于填报健康申明卡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259653]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 10:42:24&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In accordance with the relevant provisions of the &quot;Frontier Health and Quarantine Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot; and its implementation rules, the General Administration of Customs decided to Starting from 0:00 on November 1, 2023, entry and exit personnel are exempted from filling in the &quot;People&#39;s Republic of China Entry/Exit Health Declaration Card&quot;, but they have infectious diseases such as fever, cough, difficulty breathing, vomiting, diarrhea, rash, and unexplained subcutaneous bleeding. Entry-exit personnel who have symptoms or have been diagnosed with infectious diseases must actively declare their health to the customs and cooperate with the customs in health and quarantine work such as temperature testing, epidemiological investigations, medical inspections, and sampling tests. Those who conceal or evade quarantine will bear corresponding legal responsibilities; those who cause the spread of quarantine infectious diseases or pose a serious risk of spread will bear corresponding criminal responsibilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is an announcement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;General Administration of Customs&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;October 26, 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 10:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[专访德勤中国副主席吴卫军：  “巩固银行改革成果，需要一张干净的资产负债表”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259629]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The elephant danced, and everyone was shocked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the list of the top 500 companies in 2023 released by Fortune, China&#39;s four major state-owned banks are all in the top 50; in the 2023 world&#39;s 1,000 banks based on Tier 1 capital released by the British &quot;Banker&quot; In the ranking, four major state-owned banks have ranked among the top four for the sixth consecutive year. In terms of net profit alone, the four major state-owned banks have surpassed their international peers: in the first half of 2023, the total exceeded 603.5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;More than twenty years ago, the four major banks fell into &quot;technical bankruptcy.&quot; After China&#39;s accession to the WTO, the country&#39;s door opened wide, and foreign banks entered China frequently, and since 2006 they have enjoyed national treatment. Observers and the industry have been crying wolf for this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2003, China Construction Bank and Bank of China were designated by the State Council as pilot projects for the shareholding reform of wholly state-owned banks, and were expected to &quot;transform into internationally competitive modern joint-stock commercial banks in about three years.&quot; After unprecedented financial restructuring and the introduction of international strategic investment, China Construction Bank and Bank of China were listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange and Shanghai Stock Exchange in 2005 and 2006 respectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This move has clarified a replicable path for the shareholding reform and listing of ICBC, Agricultural Bank of China and Postal Savings Bank of China. As Jiang Jianqing, the then chairman of ICBC, said, the joint-stock reform is a glorious prelude to the reform of my country&#39;s state-owned banks. It is also a desperate battle with no retreat and a reform that cannot afford to lose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After the glorious prologue, strengthening corporate governance is an important task. Under layer upon layer supervision, the four major industries are moving inwards and innovating continuously. A clean financial statement trusted by global investors is an example of 20 years of practice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Deloitte, PricewaterhouseCoopers, KPMG, and Ernst &amp; Young are the four internationally renowned accounting firms (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Big Four&quot;). Among them, Deloitte China Vice Chairman Wu Weijun has served as the Bank of China and China Postal Savings The signing accountant for the stock reform and listing of banks. The former is the pilot stock reform and listing of China&#39;s state-owned banks, and the latter is the final project of the stock reform and listing of China&#39;s state-owned banks. He is praised by the financial industry for participating in and leading the design of a &quot;bank reform roadmap&quot; suitable for China&#39;s national conditions, and providing technical guidance for promoting the reform of the four major state-owned commercial banks in the three areas of corporate governance, financial reporting and capital restructuring. He is also known as the accountant most familiar with China&#39;s state-owned banks, as he has served as the signing accountant for Bank of China, China Construction Bank, Agricultural Bank of China and Postal Savings Bank of China. Today, he has served as the signing accountant for the annual report of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China for three consecutive years. As early as more than 20 years ago, he served as a partner of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms, actively promoted the implementation of the localization transformation plan of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms, and has been committed to playing the role of auditors as &quot;gatekeepers&quot; in the capital market. &quot; value and have a &quot;capital eye&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a fellow traveler in the great era of China&#39;s banking reform and opening up, on the occasion of the 45th anniversary of China&#39;s financial reform and opening up, Wu Weijun repeatedly emphasized in an exclusive interview with Southern Weekend that the reform of China&#39;s four major state-owned commercial banks is a The results and historical significance of the arduous reform despite all difficulties are also remarkable. Today, the world is facing major changes unseen in a century, and China&#39;s financial industry will face huge historical challenges. At this important moment in the deepening and development of international and domestic finance, the presence of Chinese financial entrepreneurs is crucial. They will lead Chinese financial companies to shift from expanding externally to strengthening connotation with high quality. He personally is willing to continue to serve the development of the country&#39;s financial industry professionally. “It is the most glorious thing in my profession that the accounting statements I sign can be recognized by the international capital market and international supervision.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Weijun particularly emphasized the internationalization of talents. &quot;I suggest that Chinese enterprises comprehensively review the existing international talent training system and build an advanced international talent competency model. Without talents with international vision and international standards, it will be difficult to consolidate the results of 45 years of reform and opening up, and it will be difficult to Become an effective participant in the international capital market and international financial industry.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/9TrwL1UXbKQdly518gBthsTEVJlaP6YexFRnaiaH. jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;596&quot; height=&quot;894&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/9TrwL1UXbKQdly518gBthsTEVJlaP6YexFRnaiaH.jpg&quot; data-key= &quot;256118&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Wu Weijun: Vice Chairman of Deloitte China and one of the first Chinese partners of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms. Starting from 2021, he will serve as the signing accountant for the accounting statement audit of Industrial and Commercial Bank of China. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Photo courtesy of interviewee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;If the accounting statements signed out are recognized by the international capital market, it will be my most glorious &quot;Things&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Weijun grew up rapidly from an ordinary farmer&#39;s family in the tide of reform and opening up. He was not only the first Chinese partner of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms, but also the first to obtain the British Chartered Certified Accountant after 1949. Qualified Mainland Chinese. During his more than 30-year career, he has worked in mainland China, Hong Kong, New York, London and Sydney, and has participated in, promoted and witnessed many historic transformational events in the financial and accounting fields. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As early as 1993 to 1994, he assisted American expert Tom Macy in serving the People’s Bank of China’s Financial System Prudential Supervision Reform Consulting Project, introducing the most basic risks into the risk management of commercial banks. Evaluation method - five-level classification of loans, and establish an accounting system for the Chinese banking industry that can be basically understood and accepted by international organizations and global peers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When assessing the historical value and even the impact of these two events on today, he said, &quot;The impact of these two events cannot be overemphasized. The accounting system of commercial banks is in line with international standards and has provided international Investors and counterparties recognize our banks, and the Basel banking regulatory system accepts our banks, creating conditions for state-owned commercial banks to establish accounting controls, risk management and modern corporate governance systems. The five-level loan classification not only provides banks with It provides basic risk management tools, helps maintain asset quality, and also provides regulatory agencies with a regulatory grip for financial stability. This is the institutional foundation for modern financial development. It is important to realize that the institutional construction for the development of China&#39;s modern financial industry only takes 30 years In two years, we still have a lot to learn and improve.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, he experienced an unforgettable memory in his career - participating in and leading the design of the &quot;Bank Reform Roadmap.&quot; He commented on this, &quot;The reform of China&#39;s four major state-owned commercial banks is an arduous reform that overcomes all difficulties. But its results and historical significance are significant.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why can the reform persist and advance rapidly? Wu Weijun said, &quot;Supporting such a difficult banking reform to move forward is the determination of the central government&#39;s top management, as well as the professionalism and courage of the leaders at the executive level. At that time, I was the only one in the leadership team of the audit team who grew up in mainland China. . I very much want to carry out the reform of China’s banking industry and bring China’s state-owned banks into the ranks of the international banking industry. If the accounting statements I sign can be recognized by the international capital market and international supervision, it will be a great achievement in my major. The most glorious thing.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He also participated in the formulation and implementation of the localization transformation plan of the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms from 2010 to 2012. &quot;I value the inheritance of professionalism. Professionalism has two supporting points, one is moral integrity, and the other is professional service to the country, because the premise of professionalism is patriotism. Professionalism is the foundation of professionals.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He believes that in financial companies, the work of external auditors has special characteristics, that is, high-quality external audits are not only needed to protect the rights and interests of shareholders, but also to meet the regulatory compliance needs of domestic and foreign banks, and are also global financial and commodity trading counterparties. needs for party exposure risk management. The total on-balance sheet assets of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, where he serves as the signing accountant, exceed 40 trillion yuan. He told the team that they must make professional efforts to help ICBC increase its return on assets, even if it is only one ten thousandth. One ten thousandth of 40 trillion yuan in assets is 4 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Not only serving the banking industry, in important overseas capital markets, the &quot;Big Four&quot; members generally serve more than 70% of the listed companies. At present, China&#39;s capital market has become the second largest market in the world, but as of the end of October 2023, there were about 5,300 A-share listed companies, of which the number of companies with audit reports issued by the &quot;Big Four&quot; Chinese member firms only accounted for about 7%. Faced with such a gap, Wu Weijun believes that there is still much room for improvement in being a &quot;capital eye&quot;, which mainly includes clarifying the relationship between financial information preparers, auditors and regulators in the financial reporting chain and consolidating responsibilities; using large Data analysis and other technological means can improve the accuracy and effectiveness of audits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is generally believed that audit reports signed by the &quot;Big Four&quot; accounting firms, including Deloitte, are a passport to the international capital market. With it, the price of international financing for enterprises can be maintained at a more reasonable level. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“&lt;strong>;Without international talents, it is difficult to achieve&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;international integration of capital chains”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt; /strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said that when professional service organizations first entered China, they helped attract foreign investment. Later, their services focused on supporting the reform of Chinese enterprises and their entry into international capital. market. May I ask, what was the biggest difficulty in attracting foreign investment into China in the 1990s? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 1978, China began to implement the policy of reform and opening up. In the early 1990s, China&#39;s economic system reform entered a new stage of transformation, starting from a &quot;planned economy as the mainstay, market regulation as a supplement&quot; to a &quot;socialist market economy&quot; system. In 1992, the 14th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed the establishment of a socialist market economic system, and China&#39;s economic system began to undergo profound changes. How can international investors have enough confidence to enter China and understand China? The biggest difficulty in attracting foreign investment at that time was how to convince international investors that the Chinese government could truly embrace the market economy, follow international rules, and protect the legitimate rights and interests of investors during the transition from a planned economy to a market economy. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern Weekend:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During the state-owned bank reform period that began in 2003, state-owned banks What are the difficulties for commercial banks to attract foreign capital to invest in Chinese state-owned banks? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wu Weijun:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;In 2002, I served in the restructuring and share reform and listing of Bank of China Hong Kong. This project made me realize that the real stage for China’s financial system reform is in the mainland.回到北京后，我服务于中国银行的改革。 2005年，中国银行相继引入国际战略投资者——苏格兰皇家银行、淡马锡、瑞银集团、亚洲开发银行。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国有商业银行在21世纪初引进国际战略投资者时，中外双方谈判的主要焦点包括以下方面：第一，是否夯实了资产负债表；第二，是否有能力建立公司治理机制，并按照董事会章程和议事规则运作；第三，风险管理机制是否长久有效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;外资进入中国，吸引他们的，除了中国经济的体量及高成长性带来的市场机会，还有勤奋好学的劳动者，以及愿意遵循国际规则、与国际合作的管理者。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金融合作的根本在于对手方的“能力”和“意愿”。比如说，你借了别人的钱，借钱给你的人最在意的是你有偿还能力吗？你有意愿偿还吗？因此，我们不能损害和失去已经在国际资本市场上建立起来的商誉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;以你接触的外资企业来看，它们现在对中国投资环境有何期待？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;外资进入中国，是因为它们在中国能够赚到钱。赚到钱的基础不是没有风险，而是对风险有认识，回报可预期。只有政府的规则透明，办事有章可循，资本方能更加有效地流动起来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“四大”在中国的服务重点是支持中国企业改革和进军国际资本市场。与二十多年前相比，中国企业现在出海呈现什么样的新现象？你对有“走出去”战略的企业有什么建议？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们应该讨论的不仅仅是中国企业“走出去”，而应该扩展至中国企业的国际整合和国际融通问题。人才永远是发展战略的根本和核心竞争力的来源。如果没有国际化人才，中国企业很难实现“走出去”，进军国际资本市场，更不用谈供应链的国际整合和资金链的国际融通。我建议中国企业全面审视现有的国际化人才培养体系，构建先进的国际化人才胜任力模型，探索数字经济时代和后疫情时代更加有效的人才培养模式，让国际资本市场更好地看到是什么样的人在管理现在的中国企业。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国银行和中国工商银行在海外五十多个国家和地区开设了经营机构和营业网点，它们为中国企业与世界经济的融合提供金融支持。中国银行和中国工商银行的海外金融牌照和网络资源是中国金融业改革积累的重要资产。在当前的国际地缘政治环境下，中国金融机构几乎不可能再在海外重要金融中心城市获取金融牌照。所以，对中国金融机构的海外牌照资产和网络资源要格外珍惜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我国的金融机构要派最优秀的人才到海外金融中心城市历练，积累与国际监管机构的协作经验，建立沟通渠道，形成国际金融人才梯队。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;要有如履薄冰的态度&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;早在1993年至1994年，你协助美国专家汤姆∙梅西（Tom Macy）服务中国人民银行的金融体系审慎监管改革项目。 30年前，中国金融业的监管与国际差距在哪里？ &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;30年前，中国金融业的监管与国际同业的差距主要在于监管的专业性不足。直到银监会和保监会成立，也就是到2003年，中国才形成专门的监管机构和监管队伍。 1993年，中国金融监管与国际同业的对话没有技术基础，所以，我们协助人民银行设计会计科目体系，引入最基本的风险评价手段——贷款五级分类。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时中国金融业改革的大方向是市场化和国际化，无论是监管者还是被监管者，都有积极学习国外经验的热情和主动性。这是开始国际对话的起点。专业服务机构，比如德勤，主要发挥了中国监管机构、金融企业和国际组织对话沟通的桥梁作用。而中国金融机构改革上市的时候，我们又发挥了“嫁女儿”抬轿子的作用。有差距不可怕，可怕的是在差距的两端没有愿意迈出一步的人。在金融业，我们仍然没有骄傲的资本，我们要有如履薄冰的态度。在金融战场上，打败自己的永远不是竞争对手。这就叫专业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;20年间，金融监管体制发生了多次变化。银监会和保监会脱胎于人行并于2003年同步成立，后于2018年合并为银保监会，直至2023年国家金融监督管理总局挂牌。你认为，与国际监管体制相比，还有变革空间吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对于中国金融业，2023年是极不平凡的一年。中国金融监管体系变革为“一委一行一局一会”。无论机构如何设置，变革的空间只有一个，那就是提升专业性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在过去20年中国监管水平提升的过程中，我在三个领域提出过自己的专业观点并产生了积极影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第一个观点是，强化金融监管的“铁三角”关系。这个观点是在2009年我从英国金融监管局结束借调回国后提出来的。在金融监管架构下，“铁三角”关系是指金融监管部门、中央银行和财政部的三方关系。金融危机考验的是一个国家的金融应急和领导能力。提升“铁三角”关系的协调能力，对危机作出快速和有效的反应起着重要作用。解决金融体系的问题，仅靠一家政府机关是不够的。即使在经济运转正常时期，这三家机构也需要协调，为金融体系提供清晰和不重复的指导。在金融体系统一领导方面，这种“铁三角”的协调和执行力还要继续提升，因此，中央金融工作委员会的设立是现代经济、金融管理的需要。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第二个观点是，建立监管三方会谈机制。这个观点是在2003年3月银监会成立后，我作为会计师事务所的代表，与时任银监会领导交流时提出的。当时，我提出要借鉴国际先进做法，监管当局每年组织受监管金融机构和其外部审计师的三方会议，讨论监管关注的财务和业务风险问题，布置监管工作。有时，甚至可以安排闭门会议，即在受监管机构的管理层不在场的情况下，监管机构和外部审计师针对重要的和重大的问题进行沟通。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;第三个观点是，对金融机构的股东进行监管。这是在2005年，为中国银行上市做准备，在河北香河召开的一次研讨会上，我认真向参会领导提出来的。银行的资本充足率要求是8%，即银行用的是12.5倍的杠杆率。如果不对股东进行监管，银行可能就会受到股东不良行为的影响。对股东进行监管这一建议的讨论也扩展至汇金公司的管理模式。我坚定地表达支持汇金模式，推动汇金成为专业管理机构。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在回过头来看，我的这些观点都经得起时间的检验。我相信，我今天表达的一些观点也会在30年后被证明是重要的，会出现在我专业报国的成绩单上。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;近年来，我国金融监管体系的架构已进行了大幅调整与优化。在现有监管架构下，如何提升监管制度和运作机制的有效性？从运行实效上讲，特别要做好下面三篇文章：一是如何吸引和留用最优秀的金融人才加入金融监管队伍；二是如何协调央行、金融监管总局和证监会等监管部门之间的监管协作，如何尊重财政部作为最后拯救者的地位，如何发挥好金融国资委（目前由汇金和财政部金融司承担）的股东监管作用；三是如何开发和应用更为强大的监管科技工具，提升监管质效。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你建议吸收和留用最优秀的金融人才加入监管队伍。在公务员序列里，如何实现突破，用市场价格吸引优秀人才？国外金融监管机构有可借鉴之处吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;金融监管和财政管理等机构都要尊重专业性。它们发挥功能，是以专业为基础的。我们一定要信任专家，不要怀疑专业人士拥有的爱国主义精神。技术型的人才在公务员体系中要得到保护和支持。在英美的金融监管体系中，只有高层，比如美联储主席等级别的人士排列在公务员体系里，其他专业人士全按照市场价格给予薪酬待遇。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你之前说过，金融业要强化监管。事实上，金融业一直在加强监管。怎么看强监管和改革创新的关系？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;强监管和改革创新并不矛盾，不可偏废。只有加强监管，才能防范和化解系统性金融风险；只有改革创新，才能提升金融产品、服务的多样性，提升金融市场的广度和深度，更好地满足人民群众和实体经济的金融需求。有智慧的金融企业家认为，支持实体经济，就是支持金融业的未来。实体经济和金融业这两者之间的关联度的强化和黏合需要金融创新来完成。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;强监管和改革创新是“既要”“又要”的关系，关键在于平衡监管和创新的关系，把握监管的力度和边界。简言之，监管既不能不足，亦不能过度。监管过度就会妨碍金融可持续发展的改革和创新。改革和创新当然不能以显著增大系统性金融风险为代价，不能纵容脱离实体经济的金融行为。脱离实体经济外的、金融环节内的“空转”型金融创新，是以金融逐利为目的的“伪创新”，必须制止。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;“&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;尊重专业是&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;银行改革&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;临危不惧的胆识保障&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;监管体制不断变革，银行也在不断变革。你曾参与并领导设计了适合中国国情的“银行改革路线图”。当时四大银行因不良资产极其庞大被认为已经“技术性破产”。你们设计“改革路线图”、参与银行改革的勇气从哪里来？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;改革前，中国四大国有商业银行“在技术层面上是破产的”，仅靠隐含的国家财政担保来维持生计。如果不进行股改，四大国有商业银行就会从“技术性破产”走向实际破产。这是当时中国经济制度改革迫切需要解决的问题。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们敢于为“技术性破产”的四大国有商业银行设计改革路线图，是因为我们看到了国家破釜沉舟、排除万难的改革勇气和定力；是因为我们对自身的专业能力有信心，我们有能力对金融机构面对的问题动手术；是因为金融机构的管理层有担当，并且敢于承担责任，能够把我们列出来的任务清单执行下去。 2003年，在完成中国银行的审计后，我们提出了五百多条管理建议，中国银行的行领导专门责成内审部成立工作组，监督落实我们提出的建议。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2003年至2006 年，你担任签字会计师，协助中国银行在香港和上海两地上市。 2012 年，你担任签字会计师协助中国邮储银行在香港上市。你对国有大行进一步深化改革有信心吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我对国有大行的改革和发展一直充满信心。这种信心的基础是对金融改革决策者和领导者的认同，包括对他们制定的政策方向的认同。金融机构的领导者意识到不改革便是死路一条，他们利用自己的知识储备，愿意与国内外专家配合，寻找改革的出路，是他们提出来，“我们需要一张路线图”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当时的金融改革决策者和领导者，坚持市场化和国际化方向，尊重专业人士，信任并充分发挥国内外专家的力量。国有大行已经完成改革阶段的工作任务，当前面临的挑战是持续提升核心竞争力，更加高效地适应新环境、新变化、新趋势。与我们打过交道的国有大行的领导者是专业的。在任何时代，我们都需要尊重专业，尊重专业是信心的来源，是临危不惧的胆识保障。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;除了协助中国银行和中国邮储银行股改上市外，你还曾担任或正担任中国建设银行、中国农业银行、中国工商银行的签字会计师。在上市之后，国有银行改革和发展的难点是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;对于股改上市之后中国银行业的发展，我想用八个字来概括：成就巨大、任重道远。在股改上市之后，国有控股大型商业银行取得了令人瞩目的成就：财务和风险防控能力增强；资产负债表比较夯实，创造利润的能力增强；建成了以“四会一层”为核心，获得国际资本市场认可的公司治理体系；形成了国际化经营的布局。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但如今，银行改革和发展面临着更加复杂、严峻的挑战。如何建设现代化的商业银行永远是一个难题，是一个复杂而艰巨的工程，涵盖战略管理、风险管理、信息系统和企业文化方方面面。尤为艰难之处是，国有商业银行的领导要明确如何平衡国有银行的政策属性和商业属性，在坚持党的领导前提下，实现经济效益社会责任兼顾。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;它们为何有动力自我革命？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;国有大行的自我革命动力主要来自以下三个方面：国家和政府办好银行的决心和领导力；国有大行与国际接轨的治理体系已经建立；金融企业家和职业银行家的成长、成就和积极作为。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;以国有大行董事会的有效性为例，我做个说明。国有大行的董事会主要由三组董事组成，一组是代表国有股东的股权董事，他们来自财政部和中央汇金公司；一组是独立董事，他们具备国际经验及风险管理、法律、会计等领域的专业知识；一组是负责经营管理的执行董事，他们是中管干部。这是一支兼具专业性和政治性的、强大的银行战略管理队伍。他们的自我驱动力很强，有崇高的使命感。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;增强“数目字管理能力”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;2018年，作为清华大学国家金融研究院金融与发展研究中心客座研究员，你专注深度研究中国银行业及金融体系改革的相关问题，总结改革开放40年在会计发展和银行改革方面累积的经验。请问，在会计领域，你提出的主要问题和总结的经验是什么？会计和金融的关系是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;会计准则体系、审计市场建设和会计人才水平直接影响一个国家的会计能力。回首改革开放的45年，中国会计准则不断优化完善，实现行业覆盖，全国统一，国际接轨；审计市场进行制度性改革，建成适应国家市场体系的多层次会计师事务所；会计人才培养获得重视，建立国家会计学院，开展全国会计领军人才项目，为中国改革与发展培育专业力量。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“经济越发展，会计越重要”。企业会计准则是市场经济的重要规则，注册会计师行业承担着建设社会诚信的重要责任，而会计人才也是国家发展需要的战略人才。会计准则，注册会计师行业和会计人才的水平是会计能力的重要因素。一个国家的会计能力反映了它的经济制度和政府管治软实力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄仁宇教授在《万历十五年》一书中论述了他的大历史观。其中最为重要的一个理论是国家的“数目字管理能力”。他认为，一个稳定的和成熟的商业社会需要具备计算和记录整个社会的资源的能力，只有这样，“资金方便对流，实物经济变为金融经济，可以交换的条件增多，分工进一步合理化，整个国家可以以&#39;数目字管理&#39;”——进而国家可以强盛。简单而言，黄仁宇教授认为，数目字管理能力是国家强盛的基础。我十分认同这个观点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;会计能力是国家治理能力的基础，特别是在数字经济时代，形成和运用数字资产都需要会计这一基本功能的存在。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;关于会计和金融的关系，我的观点是鲜明的。企业的金融是财务，社会的财务是金融。会计、财务和金融将是“三位一体”的学科。每个人都应老老实实地学点会计知识，因为所有的经济活动最终都要经受“借记”和“贷记”的检验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;金融企业需从“外延做大”转向“内涵做强”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最新的世界500强名单里，四大行均在前50名；在英国《银行家》杂志的评选中，四大行霸榜前四。你观察，中国银行业在逆周期经营能力和风控能力方面存在哪些挑战？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;国有商业银行的资产负债表不再是简单的商业经营实体的资产负债表，而是由中国经济基本面支撑，它反映了中国社会的金融资产分布。商业银行的资产质量，将高度依赖国有经济和政府财务状况的健康度。这是国有大行资产负债表的主体特殊性。银行要发挥好在经济运行中的风险代理监督作用，及时发现风险，并向国家相关部门呈报经济运行中存在的风险和隐患。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;国有商业银行的成绩单必须以“长期主义”为基础，资产负债表的快速扩张更加需要执行严格的风险纪律，特别是严格的信贷纪律。银行家需要更执著地坚持专业主义精神，吸收上一轮去杠杆的教训，提高放贷和购买债券的质量标准，在增量上管好不良资产的入口，同时不断夯实存量资产质量，保持充足的资本和损失吸收缓冲垫，坚持科学的流动性管理方法，坚守一张干净的、健康的、可持续的资产负债表。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;目前看，你认为中国国有银行业还需要深化哪些改革和促进哪些发展？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;吴卫军：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;金融业的发展始终与时代大局保持高度关联。当今世界面临百年未有之大变局，中国金融业已经迎来巨大的历史挑战。在国际和国内金融深化与发展的重大时刻，中国金融企业家的存在，至关重要。作为世界第二大经济体，今天中国的金融业，比任何时候都更迫切地需要一支强大的金融企业家队伍，需要他们充分发挥领导力，引领中国金融企业从简单地外延做大，转向高质量地内涵做强。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;我们要爱护中国的金融企业家。金融是承担风险的行业，金融企业家要做的业务决策就是承担风险的决策。如果运用没有边界的问责制度来束缚金融企业家，这肯定会扼杀金融企业家承担风险的主动性，削弱金融对实体经济的支持。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金融企业家在社会经济运行中还发挥着一个鲜为人知的功能，他们对社会经济的运行履行着代理监督作用。以银行家为例，他们把贷款借给企业，令他们感到日夜不安的是借款人无法偿还贷款本息的风险。因此，银行家从放贷之日起，就会定期走访企业，要求企业维护健康的财务状况，满足贷款合同要求，这种监督作用提高了中国经济发展的效率；同时，金融机构也累积了有关借款人和行业的知识，为资金有效地流向实体经济把握方向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中国创新为何会成功？因为中国的经济体量大，试错成本平摊下来很小。成功之后，创新带来的总体经济效果很大。因此，必须要鼓励这样一个试错机制，更好地吸引资本进入创新市场。这就需要投资银行的参与，我们要鼓励培养一批在中国扎根、支撑中国经济向高质量、高效率发展的投资银行家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[约瑟夫·奈：中美不会彼此构成威胁]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259615]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-31 07:57:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;video width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35970adf3270835011604556288/NaBoGdbWdHEA.mp4&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; data-fileid=&quot;3270835011604556288&quot; data-media=&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;成稿555&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35970adf3270835011604556288/NaBoGdbWdHEA.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/93ffc8dfvodgzp1251434507/35970adf3270835011604556288/NaBoGdbWdHEA.mp4&quot;>;&lt;/source>;成稿555&lt;/video>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[日常用语的“职业密码”丨人在职场]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259566]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 23:02:01&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;朋友是资深律师，一天接到老同学的电话，问他医院有没有熟人，家里长辈突发疾病，需要立即住院。正在应酬，律师急问：“你父亲涉嫌什么罪名？”一言既出，众人大笑，他才愣住：酒还没多喝，话怎么乱了？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;多年之前，也是这位律师，也是到饭店用餐，一位迟到的兄弟打电话问他在哪个包间，他自信满满地回复：第三法庭！——看看，一个人的口误里，藏着多少他的职业信息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;每个张口说话的人，都有程度不同的口音，大致可以“听”出他的出生地或成长地。那些貌似天生说一口标准普通话的，其实也不过是他的口音。日常交流时，人们遣词造句、引经据典，往往则有着他职业的烙印，或许只是用语的惯性而已。有道是，三句话不离本行。有时，一个词句就可能暴露当事人的职业信息，也算一种“话里有话”吧。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;三百六十行，行行有行话。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;省级电视台一位同行，和我一样口拙，平时也操一口原产地“不懂话”。他是专门做监督类报道的，我有些担心他的暗访能不能顺利。“不懂话”同行得意地向我透露：因为口音重，到家乡方言区周边暗访、明查，更有迷惑性，都被当成家乡人。一旦“跨区”，鸡同鸭讲，常常要急出几身汗，不知道对方“唱什么歌”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，那位电视同行在自己的方言“舒适区”也屡屡遭遇尴尬。在追踪调查一件民生投诉时，他以当地百姓身份，亲历办事程序，政务中心接待人员阅人无数，颇有经验，当场发现“破绽”：你，你是……记者吧？问这问那的，而且翻来覆去。咱们老百姓来办事很直接，不会像你这样！一语识破暗访者，那位同行假装苦涩一笑飘过，只好默认倒霉，换个时段再去暗访一回。这一次，默念三遍：去套路，去套路，去套路。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“你当时是怎么想的”“这件事你怎么看”“这个问题有什么解决办法”……记者的套话，已经潜入我们的日常。最近一次从老家返回省城，手机上嘀嗒了一辆顺风车，司机提前半小时接上我，然后南辕北辙，去接下两位乘客。闲聊间，我的记者职业习惯发作，先问他载客情况，后问他乘客背景，再问他从业经历和感受，又问他行业竞争的形势，有一搭没一搭，想了解了解当下顺风车车主的辛酸和快乐。途中服务区休息时，司机主动凑近我：老板，你人真好，和我们聊天客客气气，把我们当自己人，不像有些老板，上了车就催快开快开，一点不能耽误……我笑笑，准备给他解释刚才的聊天行为，不过是一次“流动采访”，他不过是我的又一位“采访对象”。话到嘴边，我还是决定以“老板”自居，回应他的感激：大老板都有人开车，小老板才搭顺风车。顺风，不一定顺路。要顺路，就独享不拼车。我们都是打工的，能理解你的不容易。——一段回应，好像又不自觉暴露自己的职业身份。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“三句话不离本行”，揭示人的表达习惯背后大脑使用的习惯——思维习惯。职场之中，人们沟通交流、处理信息，往往有专用术语或特定话术，日复一日地高频应用，容易形成思维（表达）定势，而当现实场景不断发生变化之时，人们往往难以即时转场、切换到位。人在某个岗位（职位）上的时间越长，相应的表达惯性越大。“三句话不离本行”，也凸显人在思维、表达上的“路径依赖”。人有不同的生活、成长、专业背景。熟悉的话术，令人更有安全感，甚至是优越感：计算机专业出身的官员主政一方时，处处强调“系统化思维”；长期从事职业教育的官员转岗基础教育后，大力倡导“适合的教育”……昨天的“屁股”何以指挥今天的“脑袋”？可能也是一种“肌肉记忆”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（作者为江苏媒体人）&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（南方周末App“hi，南周”栏目之“人在职场”，欢迎来信分享职场心声、吐槽职场经历、打破刻板印象、揭秘行业规则。投稿邮箱：nfzmreaders@163.com）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《完蛋！我被美女包围了！》热销：戳中男性痛点，顺利开辟生态位]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259621]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 22:25:30&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;日前，《完蛋！我被美女包围了！ 》仅上线一天就成为Steam国区游戏热销榜第一名，对这一游戏的讨论还上了社交媒体热搜。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一现象值得关切与分析。该游戏的情节线设定特别简单，你变身男主角顾易，用第一视角沉浸式与六位年龄、长相、性格与家庭背景迥异的美女相识、互动与交往，可以选择她们其中的一位深发展、使其成为你的另一半：爱去夜店的魅惑魔女、爱好文艺的知性姐姐、不物质的清纯学妹、刁蛮富家大小姐、独力抚养孩子的性感辣妈及内心想做回小女生的冷艳总裁，与哪位走到最后，选择权在你，你可以从心所欲。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;显然，这是一个男性向的恋爱通关游戏，目标受众是男性，没有开后宫，也没有擦边，就是纯洁地谈恋爱，满足男性对另一半的各种幻想。市面上这一游戏品类是比较少的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;大众有这样的印象：年轻人尤其是年轻男性爱玩游戏，这诚然是对的。我们的祖先在部落时代所从事的狩猎、战争是生存的第一要务，这成为刻在基因里的对力量与胜利的追求，男性所钟爱的主流是动作、战斗、战争、文明争霸及策略类游戏，涉及斗智斗勇，在这类游戏中，男性玩家居多，恋爱要么没有，要么仅仅是加料或点缀，大概率游戏出品方建立了这样的心智占位：每一个男人的梦想都是征服世界，谈恋爱也是通过征服世界来俘获女人的心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这个游戏的设计思路很不一样，只是让一个非常普通、没有任何金手指的男性纯纯地跟美女谈恋爱，虽然说游戏有12个隐藏结局，上百种路线选择，“你的每一次选择都将触发意想不到的隐藏故事”，但相对于市面上的主流男性向游戏，真算不上复杂，也谈不上做工有多精致，所以这么受欢迎，一定有特别成功之处，妥妥戳中了年轻男性的痛点。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该游戏的一大特色是“真人互动影像”：六位风格迥异的美女都是由真人扮演与拍摄的。在GPT-4引领的通用人工智能（AGI）时代，用AI设计出比真人更完美的绝色美女并不难，而且成本更低，此种做法对贩卖个人照片的“福利姬”盈利模式已经造成了冲击。该游戏出品方反其道而行之，选用真人上镜出演，把各种情节线都像正牌影视作品一样预先拍出来，供玩家任意选择想要深发展的对象与情节，让玩家有成为影视男主角、自行主宰与推动情节发展的权力，还能逼近与现实生活中真人互动的体验，可谓用心了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一游戏的性转版是所谓的乙女游戏。乙女即少女，女性选择与男性谈恋爱，或霸道总裁，或富二代，或明星，或赛车手，总之也是满足女性对另一半的完美想象。从比例关系来说，乙女游戏比男性向的恋爱游戏多几个数量级。在这个意义上，《完蛋！我被美女包围了！ 》之所以受到如此追捧，可能就是因为此类游戏太少了，游戏出品方对男性的此类情感需求是忽略与低估的，再加上“真人互动影像”填补了空白，所以一下子就开辟了一个生态位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一游戏之火，也足以说明：男性的世界也不全是打打杀杀和工作挣钱，男人也有情感需求。我们的传统文化并不鼓励男性敞开心扉表达自己，“男儿有泪不轻弹”，男性必须显得强大，扛起所有，不能有软弱与畏缩，但，是个人都会有软弱的时候，都有情感表达的需要，都有扛不住、情绪崩溃的时刻。男人也是人，他们的心灵世界也应该得到关爱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;长久以来，男人的声音在舆论中是缺位的。在某些商家的表述中，甚至不乏有“男人消费力不如狗”的说法。不过，这一现象正在改观。新一代年轻男性的价值观与消费观同他们的父母有非常明显的不同，更加关爱自我，对自身形象与精神世界有更多的投入，例如这些年，男性化妆品的消费量与消费额每年增速显著。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;艾媒咨询数据显示，中国选择通过网络直播渠道购物的用户中，男性比例占58%，女性占比为42%，其中80后、90后是购物主力军，占比总和超过80%；直播电商购物用户主要分布在一、二线城市，二线城市以42%的占比领先。这与一些人的印象很不一样。年轻男性的消费力在崛起、在井喷，是一个值得关注的趋势。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当男性把自己的生产力转化为消费力，他们也就赢得了商家的殷勤相待，这是消费社会的游戏规则。 《完蛋！我被美女包围了！ 》大火又是一个注脚。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，既然是恋爱类游戏，势必会引发一些人探讨游戏与现实的关系。有人担心，恋爱类游戏中异性对象的质量比现实生活中高出一大截，会导致玩家无形之中抬高了内心的择偶预期与标准，会对现实中的可选择对象产生不了兴致。这一效应有没有、有多大，应该有切实的社会调查，空对空地谈也没有意义。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，一个工作时间要挣钱养家干事业的人，只是在下班时间或周末偶尔花一些时间打游戏，以满足自己现实生活中实现不了的梦想与幻想，不应该受到苛责，也不至于因打几把游戏而丧失现实感，因为现实世界的引力很大，足以将TA拉回地面。偶尔陷入幻想之中，哪怕实现不了的幻想，也会让一个人的内心熠熠发光，或令灵魂获得松弛感与超越感，这对一个人的精神健壮是必要的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当然，因缺乏现实世界的锚而完全沉浸与迷失在幻想之中，再也不想走出虚拟世界，或者用虚拟世界的完美对象来要求现实世界的可选对象，那当然是一种病态，并不可取，一个理智的成年人任何时候都不应该走到这一步。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 22:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[​张又侠：中国军队绝不答应、绝不手软]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259617]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 21:25:13&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[对话上野千鹤子：学术是弱者的武器丨视频]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259590]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[500万人次求助，800亿元捐赠：慈善法修正可否终结个人求助争议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259592]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2022年一位女孩坠楼事件中，其家属在水滴筹上求助。目前这类个人求助捐款已超800亿元。华商报视觉中国图&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/7c81d5a9fb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/30/7c81d5a9fb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256024&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2022年一位女孩坠楼事件中，其家属在水滴筹上求助。目前这类个人求助捐款已超800亿元。华商报视觉中国图&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年10月25日开始，经过十四届全国人大常委会第六次会议审议后的慈善法修正草案正式公开征求意见。修正草案中新增规范个人求助行为和个人求助网络服务平台管理内容，被认为是填补立法空白而备受关注。在全国人大网上，这被称为此次修正草案四大看点之一。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在近期成都2岁女童遭罗威纳犬撕咬事件中，就曾出现个人求助的舆论质疑。女童被咬后，家属在轻松筹平台发起筹款200万元，5小时18分钟内，超过8.7万人次捐款，捐款目标达成。但女童一家迅速陷入救助金额与资金用途的争议。10月25日，轻松筹发布退款说明，对未使用的所有善款全额原路退回。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据报道，全国人大常委会法工委副主任许安标表示，此次修法初衷是完善突发事件时的慈善、募捐、资助、服务等制度，针对慈善领域出现的一些新情况新问题，总结实践经验，比如互联网时代出现的“指尖公益”“人人公益”等新情况、新问题，有必要对这些现象进行合理规制，完善相关制度。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;个人求助问题层出不穷&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;慈善法于2016年3月经全国人大会议审议通过，施行已有7年，但此前并未将个人求助纳入其中进行规制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;清华大学公共管理学院教授、公益慈善研究院副院长贾西津向南方周末记者介绍，慈善法的立法目的是为促进公益慈善，对公益慈善行为、慈善组织进行规制。慈善组织基于公益目的能够公开募捐，并享受免税优待，相当于使用了公共资源，那么它的受益方一定是非特定的众数，而不是某个特定的个体。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;个人求助并不符合公益目的，因此慈善法立法之初并未对个人求助加以规范。但近些年来，在爱心筹、轻松筹和水滴筹等网络筹款平台的助推下，个人求助比慈善活动更活跃、突出，个人求助领域的问题也层出不穷。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2016年，广东深圳6岁女孩罗一笑不幸罹患白血病，其父亲罗尔为此在网上撰文筹集治疗费用270万元左右。随后罗尔被曝家中有三套房、三家公司，并在采访时称“深圳的房子是留给儿子的”，因而备受质疑。在舆论漩涡中，罗一笑因病去世，罗尔也将所有捐款全部退回给捐赠人。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2018年，河南太康县3岁女孩王凤雅患视网膜母细胞瘤，其母在多个网络平台发起求助。2018年4月，其母被曝涉嫌骗捐，15万元善款被其挪用为儿子治疗兔唇。尽管经警方调查，骗捐说法不实，但王凤雅于当年5月病逝，她的家人也遭到网暴谩骂。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在一次次的争议声中，对网络筹款平台加强监管的呼声越来越高。2018年，爱心筹、轻松筹和水滴筹三大网络筹款平台在民政部的指导下，发布自律公约，2020年再次升级，提出平台应遵守七项“底线规则”，加强平台自律管理、提升风险防范水平、健全社会监督机制。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年11月6日，全国首例网络个人大病求助纠纷案宣判。该案中，莫先生为患重病的儿子在水滴筹上发起个人求助筹款，但因隐瞒名下财产和其他社会救助，被筹款平台告上法庭要求返还善款。北京市朝阳区法院审理后认定，莫先生违反约定用途将筹集款项挪作他用，构成违约，一审判令全额返还筹款15万多元并支付相应利息。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在该案宣判后的新闻发布会上，朝阳区法院望京法庭庭长王敏指出，互联网个人大病求助领域存在相关法律定义不清、规定过于原则的问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;该案的判决书也提到：“目前仅有部门规章规定个人求助行为不属于慈善募捐、慈善公开募捐信息，对于互联网个人大病求助中网络平台与赠与人之间的权利义务尚无明确规定。”此外，审理过程中还出现许多边界模糊的地方，比如莫先生是否全面提供了信息，筹款平台是否应该提供单独项目逐项填写家庭财产情况，是否核查不足，等等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;为此，朝阳区法院向民政部、水滴筹平台分别发送了司法建议，建议民政部协调推进个人大病求助行为的立法，建立健全部门规章，促进互联网个人大病求助有序开展。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;北京市致诚律师事务所律师何国科向南方周末记者分析，个人求助作为一项个人权利，本身不受法律限制或禁止。比如上街乞讨，只要不违反城市管理规定即可；生病后在同学群、亲戚群里寻求帮助，属于小范围的个人求助，求助的信息真实与否，也只涉及捐赠人和受赠人双方之间的权利义务问题。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;但在网上的个人求助筹款，则由于互联网的因素，传播范围及影响力都发生了巨大变化，这时求助信息的真实与否就具备了一定的公共性。在网络筹款平台做出捐赠的网友既是捐赠人，也是该平台的用户，那么平台从为用户提供服务的角度，也需要对求助人信息的真实性进行核验，“为我们广大的捐助人把好关”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更重要的是，互联网的个人求助体量很大。国内首份《个人大病求助互联网平台研究报告（2022）》显示，据不完全统计，2014年9月至2021年底，累计超过500万人次大病患者通过个人大病求助互联网服务平台发布求助信息，超过20亿人次通过包括水滴筹在内的大病求助平台捐赠资金，筹款规模超过800亿元。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“个人求助是目前社会上比较活跃、大量存在的现象，慈善法对此做出原则性的回应是必要的。”贾西津说，但目前慈善法修正案中增加个人求助的内容，并不意味着将个人求助视作慈善活动。&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“信息查验”而非“信息审查”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;作为民政部社会组织管理局专家咨询委员会委员，何国科曾参与慈善法修订草案的会议讨论。据他介绍，由于个人求助与慈善公益活动有本质区别，个人求助部分并未加入慈善捐赠、慈善募捐等章节，而是将其放到附则部分，并以授权立法的方式，由国务院民政部门会同有关部门另行制定具体管理办法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此次慈善法修正草案明确：个人因疾病或者其他原因导致家庭经济困难，向社会发布求助信息的，求助人和信息发布人应当对信息真实性负责，个人求助网络服务平台应当承担信息查验义务，具体管理办法由国务院民政部门会同有关部门另行制定。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何国科认为，最新发布的修正草案相较于第一次发布的修订草案，个人求助内容主要有三个调整：首先对个人求助的定义更强调“个人因疾病”的原因；此外，修订案中“网络服务提供者”在修正案中明确为“个人求助网络服务平台”，这意味着将来民政部在制定具体管理办法时，很可能对平台方重新进行资质认定，以做更严格的管理。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;最后一个调整是平台应当承担“信息审查义务”修改为“信息查验义务”。“&#39;审查&#39;比&#39;查验&#39;要重。”何国科说，平台没有被授予像政府部门、司法机关这样的权责，不能对求助者名下财产进行审查，“比如求助者说他只有一套房产，平台方只能看这套房子的房产证明基本属实，但不能去房管局查他一共有多少房产”。在综合多家平台的意见后，做了这一调整。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贾西津认为，慈善法修正草案中，增加的原则性内容“求助人和信息发布人应当对信息真实性负责”是很必要的，因为个人求助的根本仍是民事上的“赠与”关系，首要的责任主体是捐助者和受助者双方，“谁发布的虚假信息谁负责”；平台作为促成合作的第三方，需要做必要的形式审查，比如要求提供家庭经济情况证明、医疗证明等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在上述水滴筹的案例里，朝阳区法院认为水滴筹平台负有严格的形式审查义务、严格的监督义务。在该案中，法院认定水滴筹存在审查瑕疵，但不影响莫先生承担退回善款的责任。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据水滴筹向南方周末记者提供的信息，水滴筹目前加强了保障筹款案例真实性的措施，采用技术加人工的方式，通过初审、复审、第三方审核等多种方式对用户信息进行持续审核，平台审核信息无误且符合资格后，方可正常发起线上筹款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在水滴筹提供的材料中，该平台日均拦截12个不符合要求的筹款申请案例，上半年拦截并驳回了不符合发起条件的筹款申请共计2096例，其中有544个违规用户被平台永久拉黑，禁止再次发起筹款。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，在贾西津看来，个案救助和个人求助对于大病家庭的困境而言，都像“事后药”，可以存在但不需要做大做强。她认为更重要的应是建立多元应对机制，比如普惠性医疗保险和医疗救助体系、商业保险、公益的事业倡导和受益人服务等。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[明星发声缘何遭遇舆论反弹：公共空间不应是少数人表演的舞台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259569]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-30 19:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;近日，围绕四川崇州恶犬伤人事件的讨论愈演愈烈，逐步延伸到城市流浪动物管理与处置等诸多公共事务上，成为一段时期内社会情绪的一个宣泄点，其中既有相对理性的思考和建议，也有比较激进的言论和主张。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这种“借题发挥，宣泄情绪”的现象本身是常见的，但其中一个现象非常有趣，数位知名演员在个人社交媒体发表呼吁善待流浪动物的言论后，其评论区均遭“群情激愤”的网友攻陷，还有大量粉丝留言“取关”“脱粉”，多位演员已关闭评论区，以此消极对抗舆论风暴。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在传统传播学领域中，一般认为，影视明星依靠其个人魅力，以及长期在公共事务中营造的人设，还有自身带有的粉丝和流量，在公共舆论场中具有巨大的号召力和影响力，数位明星的共同“发声”，往往就能改变舆论走向，然而在这次事件中，明星们却无一例外地在公共舆论场折戟沉沙，这一耐人寻味的变化，其实包含着一系列相当深刻的社会变革。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“少数人的舞台”和“多数人的社会”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;在电视媒体时代和网络媒体时代早期，“一元主体性”和“中心聚焦性”体现得淋漓尽致，边疆和乡村的年轻人从时尚杂志、电影电视和电脑屏幕中凝视着北上广的钢筋水泥森林里中产人群的男欢女爱和悲欢离合，尚未意识到自我主体表达的需要。绝大多数文化产品从超级都市产出，也只描绘那里的生活。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;就这样，多数人的社会围绕着少数人的舞台，并将舞台上演绎出的那种超级都市中产市民的生活方式视为一种先进的、文明的、放之四海而皆准的范式和模板。对这种生活方式的模仿被认为是一种时尚的、进步的、文明的追求，反之则被认为是一种陈旧的、落后的、野蛮的保守。而这种“进步主义的生活模板”也并非都市中产市民原创，而是对更早实现现代化和城市化的欧美中产市民生活方式的模仿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;诞生于超级都市的文化产业通过对这种“进步主义生活模板”的模仿和演绎产出文化产品，再通过文化产品将其推向全社会。而演员作为文化产品的制造者之一，自然也必须接受这种“进步主义生活模板”以及其背后所蕴含的思想，否则不仅无法顺利地工作，甚至难以在圈子里立足和栖身。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此我们不难看到，尽管演员们的表演风格不尽相同，但相当一部分演员在生活层面上的人设是高度一致的：热爱自然、运动和旅行，有一定的思想深度和艺术品位，重视物质享受和情绪价值，有热衷环保和公益事业的“人设”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;因此，一些明星在“恶犬伤人事件”衍生出的一系列公共讨论中，为“善待流浪动物”发声的举动既是其营造和维护人设的商业行为，也是其价值观念的真实体现。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而部分明星却忽略了两个问题，他们的文明标准是基于他们的生活环境和生活方式的，他们在生活中遭遇被无绳猛犬和流浪狗撕咬致伤的概率微乎其微。但对普通的民众而言却并非如此。一项公共卫生研究中的数据显示，以河南省郑州市为例，郑州市每年存在狂犬病暴露风险案例超过9万例，犬咬伤占77.68%，超过80%的咬伤案例发生在城区，这个数据还不包括那些被咬伤后未就诊的案例。以郑州市接近1300万人的人口基数来看，在城市里被狗咬伤的概率并不低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;民众从崇州恶犬伤人事件，结合自身的生活环境，进而产生对自身安全的焦虑是一种自然而本能的反应。部分明星们在空洞地呼吁“善待动物”的同时，既缺乏对事件本身具有深度的理性思考，更提不出任何有意义的建议和具有可行性的解决方案，反而因为自居“文明”，有意无意地将那些忧虑自身安全的网友推向了“野蛮”的对立面，自然会遭到激烈的反弹。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;其次，互联网时代的社会舆论扁平化趋势愈发明显，“一元主体性”遭到消解，打着自由和多元的旗号消灭自由和多元的套路越来越多地引起民众的反感，过去几个明星号召粉丝就能逆势扭转舆论这种情况很难发生。相反，这却很容易让“发声”明星成为众矢之的和群体情绪的宣泄对象，出现评论区沦陷、影迷集体脱粉的那种状况。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;让银幕的归银幕，让现实的归现实&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;与发达国家相比，我国的现代化过程过于迅猛，在现代化的过程中，影视行业又发展得尤为迅猛，因此相当一部分社会民众对演员这一职业缺乏准确的认知，同时相当一部分演员也对自身职业缺乏准确的定位。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;把演员在现实中的形象和其在戏曲中所扮演的形象混为一谈，是前现代社会民众较为普遍的一种心理。而我们过于迅猛的现代化过程，使得这一心理也或多或少延伸到现代社会中，演员在银幕上扮演的政治家、科学家、商业巨头等社会精英形象，以及这些精英形象颇具思想深度的台词，使得观众很容易忽略一个最基本的事实：&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论演员在舞台和银幕上扮演的医生、科学家、军人如何专业和杰出，他们本身最专业和杰出的领域仍旧是表演，只有在表演领域，他们才是真正出类拔萃的专家。他们在其专业之外的其他领域或许也有闪光之处，但归根结底仍是一个普通人，他们的意见一旦超出其专业领域，也很容易犯和普通人相同的错误。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而因为这一职业在经济繁荣期所形成的那种远超社会一般行业的超高收入水平和超高社会地位，使得上述基本事实更容易被忽视。不仅有相当一部分普通民众普遍性地将明星视为在道德和智识上都高人一等的“意见领袖”进行追随，也有相当一部分演员越来越多地在公共事务上发表自身专业以外的意见。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而随着互联网扁平化带来的“祛魅”效应，越来越多的民众对明星的观感日趋成熟，能客观认识到演员只是诸多职业中的一个，明星在其演艺事业光环外，也只是一个术业有专攻的普通人。在面对明星发表的一些建设性不足，欠缺深度思考，纯粹情绪表达的公共意见时，更加敢于发表不同意见，而非盲从。这也是导致诸多明星的评论区翻车的一个重要原因。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;这一“翻车”事件衍生的思考其实不止上述两点，但完全可以肯定的一点是：在一个前现代状态持续过长，而后现代状态又到来过早的社会环境中，“文明”的标准由少数人来制定，并要求多数人接受，绝对不是一个文明的方案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 19:55:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>