<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[巴以新一轮冲突已造成双方超过3500人死亡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258616]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Statistics released by the Palestinian health department show that as of 11:55 local time on the 14th, a new outbreak in Palestine and Israel Since the first round of conflict, 2,215 people have been killed and 8,714 injured in the Gaza Strip; 54 people have been killed and more than 1,100 injured in the West Bank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/r3ul30Yf0qpASfHeUb5c5ZXZyQhhsrSXuY3QL1Jt.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height= &quot;533&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/r3ul30Yf0qpASfHeUb5c5ZXZyQhhsrSXuY3QL1Jt.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;254060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>; In addition, according to a report by the Jerusalem Post on the evening of the 13th, data from the Israeli Ministry of Health showed that since the current round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, the number of Israeli deaths has exceeded 1,300, and the number of injured has reached at least 3,484. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This round of conflict between Palestine and Israel has killed more than 3,500 people on both sides. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 23:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[诺贝尔文学奖得主格丽克逝世：她的诗有超越创伤与丧失的力量]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258626]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/ 10/30/8e55339d6974425b5125d21cabec25cb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;738&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/20/10/30/8e55339d6974425b5125d21cabec25cb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;117172&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: # aaa;&quot;>;Picture/Katherine Wolkoff&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The word &#39;poet&#39; must be used with caution; it names a desire, not a profession.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;Years ago, Louise Glick wrote in an autobiographical essay: The desire to make art produces an ongoing experience of longing, a restlessness that sometimes ends in a romantic or sexual way. There always seemed to be something ahead, the next poem or the next story, visible but out of reach. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;To fully understand it is to let it haunt and torment; a certain sound, a stone, becomes a torment - the poem that symbolizes this sound seems to be somewhere, completed, It is like a lighthouse, but the difference is that when you swim towards it, it retreats.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In his nearly 60 years of poetry career, he has accumulated 13 poetry collections, which are stacked in the corner of the room. Occasionally, Glick would deliberately suppress some &quot;sneaky&quot; complacency and lament that he &quot;didn&#39;t waste time.&quot; Now, a new stamen has been added to her crown - the Nobel Prize for Literature. The award citation praised her &quot;unpretentious poetic voice that universalizes individual existence.&quot; Her first reaction after winning the award was: Oops, I won’t have any friends! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps in response to the suffering and shadow of the current global epidemic, jury chairman Anders Olsen quoted &quot;Snowdrops&quot; in his speech, which was the novel that won Glick the Pulitzer Prize. Award-winning poetry collection &quot;Wild Iris&quot; (1992). It depicts the miraculous return of life after winter and seems to symbolize the poet&#39;s &quot;radical transformation and rebirth,&quot; who, despite being constantly troubled by life&#39;s mistakes and changing circumstances, is still able to &quot;make leaps from a profound sense of loss.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She saw a vision of death at the age of seven, and was choked by anorexia as a teenager. The precocious girl shouldered the destiny of the poet to &quot;witness&quot;. With the help of myths and religious fables, she traveled between the holy and the underworld, transcending the &quot;confessional poets&quot;. As predicted in the poem, she is indeed more like Lazarus than Joan of Arc - the person in the Bible who was saved and resurrected by Jesus, whom the poet Sylvia Plath wanted to &quot;imitate&quot; but ended up The lost road. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;In her poems, the self listens to its remaining dreams and fantasies, and no one is stronger than her in the face of its own fantasies.&quot; Olson said. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Hungry is not for experience, but for understanding​&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;I was born cautious, in Taurus under the sign./I grew up and thrived on an island,/in the second half of the twentieth century;/the shadow of the Holocaust/barely touched me.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1943 Glück was born in Long Island, New York, to a Hungarian-Jewish family. These few words are the &quot;autobiography&quot; she wrote for herself. As the title of her second collection of poems suggests, this &quot;house on the swamp&quot; is not stable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Her father is a successful businessman with a long-cherished wish to be a writer, and he often tells her legends and historical anecdotes such as Joan of Arc. My mother graduated from Wesleyan Women&#39;s College, where many ladies were born, and served as the &quot;arbiter&quot; of the family&#39;s art education. She also had a sister who would become a banker in Manhattan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Glick&#39;s writing is not Cold War-style politicization, but personal politics. Her writing returns to the identification of human identity. This is a key point. All the women in her works are Looking for my own voice.&quot; Fan Jinghua, the translator who first introduced Glick to China, pointed out that the rise of personal writing in the American poetry tradition, including the rise of Western feminism, is the reason why Glick has won many important awards over the years. background. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For Glick, family seems like her &quot;concentration camp&quot;. &quot;I have a strong desire to speak, but this desire is often thwarted: my sentences, if interrupted, are completely altered—transformed rather than interpreted.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In short , &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;She does not meet the definition of a child: full of hope for everything.&quot;&lt;/span>; As an adult, she wrote in her poem Wrote, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;All the defense, spiritual stubbornness, persistence/taking off the mask of ordinary people and revealing the tragedy,/these are actually the The ignorance of the world./Means that which is partial, changeable, capricious -/everything that is excluded from the &#39;absolute&#39;.&quot; (&quot;Birthday&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, the real The family trauma occurred 7 days before her birth, when her &quot;sister&quot; died unfortunately. &quot;Her death is not my experience, but her absence is; her death made me born.&quot; Glick later realized that she made such a dazzling declaration in her first collection of poems: &quot;Birth, not birth.&quot; Death is the unbearable loss.&quot; (&quot;Cottonmouth Snake Country&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The tension between mother and daughter turns into a zero-sum game between the two sisters competing for maternal love in fantasy. In &quot;Ararat&quot;, the &quot;Book of Death&quot;, Glick wrote, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;When my sister dies,/my mother&#39;s heart changes Very cold, very hard, like a tiny iron pendant./ Later I felt that my sister’s body/ was a magnet. I could feel it sucking/ my mother’s heart into the earth,/ so that it would grow.” (“Loss” &quot;Love&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She also rewrote the story of Solomon&#39;s verdict. When two mothers fight for one child, the mother is torn between the two daughters, and she is &quot;willing to destroy herself&quot; to prove who is the righteous child and cannot bear to split her mother apart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This mental symptom is related to the early realization of the &quot;destiny&quot; of writing. Not only out of the overwhelming will to get rid of her mother, but also the &quot;obsession with purity and control&quot;, when she was a teenager, Glick began to strictly implement a diet, from 85 pounds to 75 pounds, to some extent, she also imitated Zhen. De&#39;s asceticism eventually developed into anorexia, and he almost starved to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;It quietly begins/in some girls/the fear of death, in the form/of devotion to hunger, / Because a woman’s body is a tomb; it will accept / anything. I remember / lying in bed at night / touching soft, discrete breasts, / touching, at 15 / the disturbing flesh / that I would have sacrificed / until Limbs no longer / blossom and escape: I feel / what I feel now, align these words - / the same need for perfection, / death just a by-product.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The need for perfection Linked to forms of resistance, body and mind are both unified and separated, leading to a &quot;metaphysical hunger&quot;: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Hunger is not for experience/ It is to understand as if it were available in the abstract.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Seven years of psychoanalytic treatment saved Glick. After dropping out of high school, she interrupted her formal professional education and entered a poetry seminar at Columbia University, where she studied under two American poet laureates, Leonie Adams and Stanley Kunitz. Under the influence of the latter, she changed from being arrogant and arrogant to being humble and restrained. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She said frankly, &quot;Psychoanalysis taught me to think. It taught me to use my ideological tendencies to oppose the clearly expressed parts of my thoughts. It taught me to use doubt to check my own words and discover (self-expression It gave me the intellectual task of transforming paralysis—an extreme form of self-doubt—into insight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/5baeee3b828154edc453d9aa22355dc5.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot; 656&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/20/10/30/5baeee3b828154edc453d9aa22355dc5.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;117173&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;Some works by Louise Glick&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;When I feel safe , I can love&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Glick viewed this experience in a positive light, &quot;The feeling of hunger helped me control my greed, which was very helpful in gaining an independent self.&quot; And this seems to be It also established her own &quot;poetics of desire&quot;: in love, nothing is desired. She expresses her desire for someone or something in the world that she wants to possess by saying &quot;no&quot; instead of &quot;yes.&quot; What is undoubtedly revealed here is the finitude of human beings. Just like &quot;Ripe Peaches&quot;, from the door to the dining table, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Certainty, a dead thing/...accompanied by that obscene mouth/ Hungry for love -/it&#39;s like love&quot;&lt;/span>;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Perhaps, because love is as scary as death, this has been planted since childhood: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Fear, of loss The fear of disease; / the fear of disease wearing the bride’s white dress” (&quot;Joan of Arc&quot;)&lt;/span>;; and the mother who “knitted red scarves of various colors” also said to her grown-up son: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;It&#39;s not surprising that you are like this, / afraid of blood, your women / are like brick walls after brick walls.&quot; (&quot;Poetry of Love&quot; )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the representative work of his mature period, the collection of poems &quot;Averno&quot;, Glick reinterpreted the story of Persephone in Greek mythology: she accidentally ate Pluto&#39;s pomegranate, Kidnapped as a wife and returning home &quot;stained with red juice&quot;, she realizes that &quot;she has been a prisoner since she was born a daughter&quot;; Pluto wants to say, &quot;I love you and nothing can hurt you&quot;, But he thought it was a lie, and what he finally said was, &quot;You are dead, nothing can hurt you.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Burning Heart&quot; and Dante&#39;s &quot;Divine Comedy: Inferno&quot; The protagonist Franziska&#39;s dialogue explains the power of the &quot;male gaze&quot;: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Both fire and eternity/... even when I am touched Before, I already belonged to you;/You only need to look at me.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A more controversial poem is &quot;Mountain Plum Blossom&quot;: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;I hate them./I hate them as much as I hate sex,/that man&#39;s mouth/it blocks my mouth, that man&#39;s body/it makes people limp&quot;&lt;/span>; , the upper and lower positions of the body during sex, are as conventional as choosing which flower to &quot;light up the yard,&quot; but are essentially rooted in forced silence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, Glick has always refused to be labeled as a &quot;hyphenated poet&quot;, and &quot;feminism&quot; is the most prominent prefix. Glick once emphasized that she and her sister were raised &quot;to reorganize, to achieve and to aspire to glorious achievements... We were never asked to believe that such achievements were impossible, either because of our gender Or our historical period.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is logically puzzled by the determination of some women today to write as women, since this appears to be an existing notion of ambition being constrained by gender differences. Rather than gendered distinctions, she cares about a &quot;bigger distinction&quot; between symmetry and asymmetry, harmony and homophony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, we cannot forget that Glick calls herself an &quot;untrustworthy speaker&quot; in her poem. In her case, language is a medium that switches between frankness and disguise. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mother suffering from postpartum depression in &quot;First Born&quot;, the emotionally numb and silent daughter mourning her father in &quot;Ararat&quot;, the anger in the face of cheating and broken marriage in &quot;The Pasture&quot; The provocative wife... These images more or less reflect the loss and isolation that Glück constantly encountered in his life: he was divorced twice, and a house was burned down by fire. From then on, she became &quot;a dreamer and a viewer&quot;, an author &quot;obsessed with loss&quot;, &quot;waiting for 20 years to endure the inescapable loss&quot;. &lt;p>; /span>;This straightforward spoken language suddenly appears at the end of the entire collection of poems &quot;Rebirth&quot;, leaving a blank space with an aftertaste, which is also humorous and spicy. &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;I once told myself/From nothing/Nothing can be taken away./But can you still love anyone?/When I When I feel safe, I can love&quot;&lt;/span>; - this is the answer given by &quot;New Life&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In Greek mythology, Dido committed suicide because of the loss of Aeneas; when they reunited in the underworld, he asked for her forgiveness, but she walked away without saying a word. In Glick&#39;s writing, she asked the goddess of fate to allow him to repay her passion, &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>; &quot;Even if the time is short. What is the difference between a short time and a lifetime: Indeed, in these moments./They are all the same, all eternity.&quot; (&quot;Queen of Carthage&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This poem was included in the book &quot;America&#39;s Favorite Poems&quot; 》Anthology. In his introductory work on Glück, scholar Daniel Morris noted with interest this anecdote: An administrative assistant in Kansas City, Missouri, described in detail how the poem spoke to her and helped her gradually come out of it. Intense intimacy with a scientist, moving on. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Individualistic and universalistic, ordinary and oracular, ephemeral and mythical, tragic and comic...&quot; Daniel Morris pointed out that Glick&#39;s &quot;subject status&quot; in contemporary literature ” has enough room for malleability, it’s hard to think of another American poet since Bishop who has attracted such a wide range of critics, readers, and contemporaries. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glick&#39;s early &quot;Garden&quot; poems include &quot;fear of birth&quot;, &quot;fear of love&quot; and &quot;fear of burial&quot;, which are always Glück&#39;s The core theme, but the song &quot;Garden&quot; mixed in it still overflows with the true desire for love: &quot;But still/there is something you need,/your body so soft and alive, among the animals of stone./Admit it: being like them is scary,/more than hurts.&quot;&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No wonder the poet Zhou Yan said: After Plath, how do women love? I recommend reading Glick. &quot;For a poet like her, if you are deceived by the surface coldness, aloofness, repulsion, and even the rudeness from time to time, you will be stupid. This kind of poet does not waste energy on the surface. What she focuses on is Human emotions, spirits and symbols. So it must be compassionate and warm inside. It is not the kind of poet who is cold or numb inside. This is the fundamental difference.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This voice is in &quot;The Triumph of Achilles&quot; 》 is even more firm: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;He is already a dead person, sacrifice/because of the part that can love, the part that can die.&quot;&lt;/span >;Translator Liu Xiangyang summarized Glück&#39;s expression as &quot;love is greater than death.&quot; Desire goes beyond the trappings of self-protective life and is connected to the recognition of virtue and glory. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Let more voices fall off the paper&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;It was from &quot;The Triumph of Achilles&quot; that Glick drew inspiration from mythological characters, those who were abandoned and abandoned. The voice of punishment and betrayal was re-contextualized in modern society and became her personal and universal &quot;mask&quot;. In the words of poetry critic Helen Vendler, &quot;give experience a permanent mythical form&quot; instead of turning your autobiographical experience itself into mythology like Plath, Lowell and other confessional poets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glick regarded the first collection of poems with the imprint of the &quot;Confessional School&quot; as a &quot;failure&quot;. Although the Nobel Prize committee complimented her by saying that &quot;in her own severity and unwillingness to accept simple principles of faith, she is more like Emily Dickinson than any other poet,&quot; Glick said that Dickinson was just her &quot; One of the Early Heroes,” which later became unreadable, like chalk on a blackboard or scratches of fingernails, or the voice of a crazy little lady—like a kitten. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;American Narcissism,&quot; she pointedly pointed out the seductive misleading nature of Rilkean romanticism, &quot;In our poetry, narcissism reaches its most terrifying definition: It is not an extension of the self but a substitute for it, as if the lifeless mirror somehow allowed the surviving boy to survive.&quot; The end result: &quot;He reaches the end of his insight.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;There is an automatic sentence pattern in Glick&#39;s mind, starting with &quot;Poets should not...&quot;, and the following blanks can be filled with anything. Originally, teaching also fell into this category. But she unexpectedly accepted a teaching position, taught poetry classes at Yale every fall, and served as a judge for the Yale Young Poets Prize. She was grateful for this and believed that it inspired her creative motivation. The rhythm and structure of one of the young poets gave her great inspiration. She also apologized to him specifically for this, fearing any suspicion of &quot;plagiarism&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is as strict with her students as she is with herself. The technique for preparing new poems is to completely forget the previous one. Each book is a resistance to the previous one. &quot;I have nothing to do with polishing milestones.&quot; Interest.&quot; Glick said in the interview, &quot;What I am thinking about is how to make the poems live longer. In these ever-expanding poems, he needs to reach different destinations from different starting points.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;Typical Glick, with a language style that is &quot;alloy-like&quot;, always with coldness and restraint. However, different from the gloomy image on paper, she would imitate horse braying when reading poetry and also liked to laugh loudly. Humor itself has become a weapon for her style renewal. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Glick said she always tries to &quot;let more voices fall onto the page&quot; in order to shift gears at any time. She likes poems like this: you think you are reading one poem, but you are actually reading another, and then a third. &quot;Each sentence itself is not derived from the previous sentence.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This kind of musical The polyphony has already appeared in &quot;Meadow&quot;, and Mozart&#39;s opera has become the aria in the poem. Poet Nicholas Kristof commented on the collection of poems &quot;Averno&quot; and said that the 18 poems are rich and harmonious, &quot;with complex interrelated images, recurring characters, overlapping themes, forming a unified collection, but among them Every part counts as a whole.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And all her collections of works are not a unified collection? When the translator Liu Xiangyang contacted Glick in 2007 to discuss the publication of the Chinese version of &quot;Selected Poems&quot;, Glick was reluctant at first and hoped to publish it in full. In the United States, &quot;Poetry 1962-2012&quot;, which was published in 2012, was not titled &quot;Complete Works&quot;. It did not make any modifications except for proofreading, and there was no personal introduction. &quot;Poetry is the only thing she left to the world.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the collection of poems &quot;Village Life&quot; ten years ago, the 66-year-old Glick seemed to declare some kind of impossible truce: &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&quot;Body, thinking that we won&#39;t be together for much longer, I/begin to feel that I have a new kind of tenderness for you, which is very raw and unfamiliar, / Just like the love of my youth that I can remember.&quot; (&quot;Crossroads&quot;)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She is still writing, and she is not writing slowly. The 2014 collection of poems, &quot;A Night of Faithfulness and Virtue,&quot; continues to approach the theme of death with extraordinary grace and lightness. The latest collection of poems is also expected to be published in the United States next year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past, &quot;hunger&quot; was always present. This is Sisyphean drudgery, &quot;The artist lies because he is haunted by arrival, he feels that the pinnacle is where he will dwell forever, a place where his burdens are transposed: Every moment of my life, I stand At the top of this mountain. My hands are empty. And that stone has increased the height of the mountain.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s very different now - there&#39;s no rush at all.&quot; Glick in recent years In the interview, she admitted that she could sit on the terrace and write trivia while thinking, &quot;This is the most beautiful thing in life, the sweetest thing.&quot; Just change the sentence and think, oh, this is okay. That sense of joy.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;It was a beautiful summer, everything was growing in the garden, and there were no obligations.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: italics, italics _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Reference: Louise Glück, &quot;Alloy of Moonlight&quot; and &quot;Until the World Reflects the Deepest Needs of the Soul&quot; (translated by Liu Xiangyang and Fan Jinghua); Louise Glück, &quot;American Originality&quot; &quot;; Daniel Morris, &quot;The Poetry of Louise Glück: A Thematic Introduction&quot;)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 22:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[王毅同美国国务卿布林肯通电话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258628]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 21:30:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On October 14, 2023, Wang Yi, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Foreign Minister, communicated with U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken at request Telephone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Blinken introduced his current visit to the Middle East and the US position on the current Palestinian-Israeli conflict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yi said that the Palestinian-Israeli conflict continues to escalate and faces the risk of losing control. China opposes all actions that harm civilians and condemns all practices that violate international law. China believes that safeguarding its own security cannot be at the expense of harming innocent civilians. There is no way out through military means, and using violence for violence will only create a vicious cycle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yi pointed out that the top priority is to cease fire and cool down the situation as soon as possible to avoid exacerbating humanitarian disasters; abide by international humanitarian law and open up channels for humanitarian relief; support the United Nations in building international consensus and the Security Council in playing its due role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yi emphasized that the fundamental way to solve the Palestinian issue lies in implementing the &quot;two-state solution&quot;, establishing an independent Palestinian state, and realizing peaceful coexistence between Palestine and Israel. Without reconciliation between the Arab and Israeli nations, there will be no peace in the Middle East. China calls for the convening of an international peace conference as soon as possible to promote the achievement of broad consensus. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Yi said that when dealing with international and regional hot-spot issues, major countries should adhere to objectivity and fairness, maintain calmness and restraint, and take the lead in abiding by international law. China will continue to promote peace talks in accordance with the basic principles proposed by President Xi Jinping. The United States should effectively play a constructive role and push the issue back to the track of political settlement as soon as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Blinken said that the United States supports the &quot;two-state solution&quot; to resolve the Palestinian-Israeli issue, supports the United Nations in playing a role in easing the situation and providing humanitarian relief, and is willing to strengthen communication and coordination with China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The two sides also briefly exchanged views on Sino-US relations. Wang Yi said that China and the United States have recently carried out a series of high-level contacts, and bilateral relations have stopped declining and stabilized, which has been welcomed by the people of the two countries and the international community. It is hoped that the United States will work with China halfway, implement the consensus reached by the two heads of state in Bali, overcome interference and remove obstacles, lengthen the positive list and shorten the negative list, effectively respect China&#39;s core interests and major concerns, and push China-U.S. relations back to the track of stable development. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Blinken said that the United States is willing to work with China to implement the important consensus reached by President Biden and President Xi Jinping in Bali, manage U.S.-China relations responsibly, and promote the stability of U.S.-China relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 21:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[3D还原水下绝境，亚洲第一人陨命九顿天窗洞穴深处]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258618]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[154套新房雪藏12年后打折抛售，一个多月内近九成未成交]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258601]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 20:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[《坚如磐石》编剧陈宇：在经典叙事中，做人性实验]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258592]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/11/KyKxXJnZBTyfvTFlRrv8TG4pP5T55r4tXATQia9k.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/KyKxXJnZBTyfvTFlRrv8TG4pP5T5 5r4tXATQia9k. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253693&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the respondent/ Picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;1&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The movie &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; will be released on National Day in 2023. The script was originally written by Chen Yu. Chen Yu is a screenwriter, director, and professor at Peking University School of Arts. A few years ago, after he finished writing this story, he felt that he had &quot;made a fortune&quot; and wanted to find a strong director to work with. He turned it to Zhang Yimou, who decided to shoot it the next day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So there was the first collaboration between Chen Yu and Zhang Yimou. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 27, the day before the movie was officially released, Zhang Yimou, Chen Yu and the leading actors sat in a row on the edge of the stage at the premiere at Beijing Wanda CBD Cinema. Chen Yu recalled that after Zhang Yimou read the script, he made an appointment with him for the next week to discuss the script. A week? Chen Yu was confused. Zhang Yimou said, just plan it for a week and talk every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day later, on the night when &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; was released in theaters, I met Chen Yu in his studio. When talking about the process, he said, &quot;I have to understand that he is I know what he is thinking about and his current artistic creation philosophy. On the contrary, he is also curious about me.&quot; As a scholar-type creator, Chen Yu inevitably thinks that the film they are about to make will occupy the highest position in the coordinates of film history. where? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After chatting for a week, the two reached a consensus on their creative views and methods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What the audience saw in the finished film was this story: a bus bombing occurred in Jinjiang City, and the suspect died on the spot. Subsequently, Li Zhitian, chairman of Jinwu Group, and the deputy mayor were implicated. Zheng Gang&#39;s infighting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many wonderful group scenes in the film, and several main characters are also dramatic: Deputy Mayor Zheng Gang, played by Zhang Guoli, married the daughter of a high-ranking official, and along the way, he did whatever it takes to get his official position; Li, played by Yu Hewei, Shida was born into a poor soldier. He started from scratch and grew into a big company. The group is involved in real estate, entertainment and other industries. He always has to deal with complex interpersonal relationships, including winning over officials, guarding against peers who want to conquer the world together, caring for his innocent daughter, and investigating those who want to help him. The superior son-in-law. Since that explosion, the fact that the officials represented by Zheng Gang and the businessmen represented by Li Zhitian have been colluding for many years has gradually been revealed, and their relationship has gradually broken down. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Jianming, a police officer played by Lei Jiayin, is involved in the investigation of the bombing case. He is highly intelligent but slow-witted. He relies on intuition and experience to investigate the case. He is led along the way, and finally realizes that there may be an unscrupulous person behind his adoptive father. A black hole, in which his secret life experience is hidden. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Mid-Autumn Festival and the National Day holiday are over, and the National Day schedule has concluded. &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; leads the box office with 880 million yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After hitting it off with &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot;, Chen Yu served as the original author and screenwriter and collaborated with Zhang Yimou on two other films, which were released in the past two Spring Festival festivals. &quot;Sniper&quot; (2022) sees the big from the small, focusing on the cold gun battle between the squad leader and soldiers of the fifth squad and the enemy on the battlefield to resist U.S. aggression and aid Korea. &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; (2023) is based on the suspense genre, supplemented by comedy elements. It tells the story of the civil strife in Qin Hui&#39;s mansion after the death of the famous anti-gold general Yue Fei. It ranked first in the 2023 Spring Festival box office with a score of 4.544 billion yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The three films co-written and directed by Chen Yu and Zhang Yimou show some commonalities, such as the creators&#39; fascination with drama and their pursuit of classic narratives. &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; has a solid plot, and &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; and &quot;Sniper&quot; are in line with the &quot;Three Unities&quot; principle, telling stories that serve one theme in one day and one space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/tK4paBl06q4ikz59llIIfdapVcVBsY4rjGH9nYHI.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/tK4paBl06q4ikz59llIIfdapVcVBsY4rjGH9nYHI.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253694&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A group photo of the main creative staff of &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;2&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;People may go to the opposite side of themselves, Chen Yu said. Before he became obsessed with content, he had an extreme fascination with form. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He went to college in Xi&#39;an, &quot;an extremely simple environment.&quot; While others in the cafeteria were queuing up to serve rice and dishes with stainless steel plates, he insisted on holding two blue and white porcelain plates under his arm. He used this as an example to describe the artist-like self he had in the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Later, I entered the Beijing Film Academy to study as a graduate student in the directing department. My first assignment was titled &quot;What is Love?&quot; Chen Yu&#39;s film looked like this: two teacups of the same color (&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;represents a pair of lovers&lt;/span>;) was put into a tray, &quot;entering into some kind of agreement or marriage&quot; - he recalled with interest: a teacup Leave and put together with teacups of other colors; four teacups form new pairs; finally they separate again, leaving only one teacup on each tray. This is a story made entirely of still images: love is the sets of teacups on the tray. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;You can also say it is very unique. I was quite proud of it back then, but today it seems to be a clever creative attitude.&quot; Chen Yu said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating with a master&#39;s degree, Chen Yu felt that he still lacked in the principles of dramatization and actor guidance, so he decided to study for a doctorate at the Central Academy of Drama. In the interview, he recalled that it was &quot;an enlightening help&quot; to him. In his doctoral thesis, he compared the nature of theater and film. The principles of drama provided a methodological fulcrum for him to write film scripts in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Egg Fried Rice&quot; (2011), which can be seen on streaming media, is a work written and directed by him. From the special era to the reform and opening up, and the rise of the market, three children in Beijing&#39;s hutongs grew up. Some stayed where they were, while others went south to make their own way. In the extremely small changes in the relationship between the characters, images of big history occasionally appear alternately. This film was shortlisted for the main competition of the 18th Beijing University Student Film Festival and won the Best First Film Award. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The change in creative outlook coincides with the growth of personal mind. &quot;From a relatively extreme self, I grew up, matured, and formed a relationship with this society. My self echoed and resonated with other people.&quot; Chen Yu summed it up this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In terms of creation, Chen Yu turned to classic narrative. The principles he agrees with include: the narrative must be complete - have a beginning, development, climax, and ending, and each part fully completes the corresponding function; there is a relatively scientific set of Effective solutions reveal, hide, and convey information within the timeline; the narrative should conform to values ​​that most people can appreciate, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He wanted to make a &quot;hard-hitting&quot; movie that was solid enough from plot, structure to character design. Do you want to chew this hard nut? he asked himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; was created under this background. Thinking and creating is hard. It is normal to sit in front of a blank word document, watch the cursor flash, and sit and think for hours. The longest time, for three days in a row, Chen Yu didn&#39;t write a word. At that time, he went to eat and sleep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/B503aQQiAaFpH0MWrMopgpEoeZFpxaQeIlHaYSkD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;600&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/B503aQQiAaFpH0MWrMopgpEoeZFpxaQeIlHaYSkD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253695&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Sniper&quot; stills&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;3&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Early 2020 , Zhang Yimou called Chen Yu and wanted to make a book. He had three requirements: talk about resisting U.S. aggression and aiding Korea, not making grand narratives, and strengthening the charm of the narrative - this is the starting point of &quot;Sniper&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The title of &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; is a house in Shanxi. Zhang Yimou took Chen Yu to visit and asked him to think of a story based on it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After cooperating on three films, it is normal for the screenwriter and director to have differences and arguments. For example, for a character, somewhere, Zhang Yimou thinks he should be stronger, but Chen Yu thinks he should hide. There are many times like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Usually, Chen Yu will turn the argument into an explanation, &quot;What did we think at the beginning? We have several methods. What are the advantages and disadvantages of each method? In summary, I recommend this method .Send it to him. We will not discuss this issue. I will implement it according to his final decision. Let’s move on to the next question. As a person I respect and as a director, I believe in him from any angle. The final decision was the one that best suited the movie.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhang Yimou once commented on Chen Yu: &quot;Chen Yu, you can still come up with some good stories and tell them very well. Ups and downs.&quot; In the future, they will collaborate on a fourth film. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From &quot;Rock Solid&quot; to &quot;Sniper&quot; to &quot;River Red&quot;, the scripts can withstand analysis, and there is suspense at the beginning: &quot;Sniper&quot; is set in the vast snow, and the US military wants to capture a sharpshooter. , and the Fifth Squadron was ordered to bring back the prisoners of war; the beginning of &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; is a messenger of death, a lost secret letter, and a panicked soldier; &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; leads the audience into a case where the murderer is clearly visible car crash and fatal explosion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The academic article &quot;Genre Film Creation Methodology Based on &quot;Narrative Dynamics&quot; - A Dialogue with the Original Writer and Screenwriter of the Film &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot;&quot; published in the core journal &quot;Contemporary Film&quot; in 2023 In &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot;, Chen Yu used the concept of &quot;dimensionality improvement&quot; when analyzing &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot;: in the seemingly unlucky soldier Zhang Da, the dimensionality improvement in plot actions is reflected in &quot;survival by solving crimes - assassination and revenge - forcing poetry and dedicating oneself to justice&quot; changes; and at the same time complete the dimensionality of the characters, &quot;spy and ruthless soldier - astute assassin - hero and martyr&quot;; thereby realizing the dimensionality of the theme, from survival, to revenge, to &quot;the manifestation of the spirit of family and country&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A good script must have precise purpose, structure and fulcrum. However, Chen Yu emphasized that the narrative ultimately points to the exploration of the essence of human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the story developed, the audience discovered that the squad leader of the fifth squad in &quot;Sniper&quot; fought against the enemy under extremely limited objective conditions, completed an almost impossible task, and showed the light of humanity; &quot; In &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot;, the soldier being wrongly accused is not the main plot. The failed assassination of several small figures is not the ending. It is a poem that makes everyone die for it. In &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;, the death of a stakeholder company boss is not the final answer. Because in addition to money, there is money, and there is also an official position. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/KGq2LVKvpgX5gvCmiyXmz6zlc8yBpfH6u8AhDH0x.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/KGq2LVKvpgX5gvCmiyXmz6zlc8yBpfH6u8AhDH0x.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253692&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; stills&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The blend of animality and divinity may be The Essence of Human Nature - A Conversation with Chen Yu&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The little glimmer of light in the darkness&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot; font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;During the week when you and Zhang Yimou discussed &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;, what kind of conceptual consensus did you find? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;The first sentence he asked me was, what kind of movie do I think this is? What kind of video is it close to existing? I&#39;ll give you a rough idea of ​​what I expect this film to be in the future. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What do you think of &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot; at the script stage? 》Close to what? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I will use some keywords: cold, cold, hard core, explosion, depth of humanity, light of humanity. This is a crime film, but it is actually about human desires. When desires are alienated, what kind of tragedy will happen? There is the alienation of the villain, but in the process of fighting against dark things, the light of humanity shown by the struggle of the positive characters under alienation is what I am particularly looking forward to presenting. I am not obsessed with the beauty of darkness, but the little glimmer of light in the darkness. So I focused the story on Su Jianming. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The darkness between the two big guys (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Zheng Gang and Li Zhitian&lt;/span>;) The fighting and game show the wonders of human nature after it has been alienated. Su Jianming, a normal and sympathetic person, was strangled in the middle. He showed the strength of a person in the face of a powerful whirlpool. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you wrote this original script, you used what you just said Are those keywords consciously connected? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;At that time, my creative concepts and creative methodologies began to become relatively mature and stable. I wanted to write a solid classicist tragedy. Because everyone has desires, and desires are distorted under specific periods, circumstances, and behaviors, people will inevitably be swallowed up by the darkness formed by the people around them, including themselves. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Classical aesthetics has formed a classic narrative today, classical - you can say it is classic, in line with most people&#39;s aesthetics, and has a classical meaning. I think it is by far the most effective narrative method that is acceptable to most people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are many stages in the history of film where we are all exploring new film languages, and I was very obsessed with these. But after actually entering the industry, I found that those experiments should be internalized and serve the narrative. I would make it my first goal to tell the story well and clearly, instead of letting being unique and clever become my focus. Hands, I began to return to the classic narrative. When writing &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;, first of all, I started from this perspective. I wanted to challenge the hard nut of classic narrative. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Second, I am particularly fascinated by the understanding and recognition of human nature. A story ultimately points to an understanding of human nature. I think human nature is a black box, and studying oneself is the most difficult. We can only keep experimenting, looking at human behavior under different experimental conditions, and finding out what the characteristics of human nature are. Quite hard to find. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many authors write about human nature. People want to realize their desires in the name of liberating their nature. In essence, it is animal nature and bestiality. This is just one animal. The other end is divinity, and some people can sacrifice their own interests and lives for some noble value. For example, sacrificing one&#39;s life to save a friend is completely contrary to animal nature. In animal nature, I must save my own life, even snatching a bite of food from my own child&#39;s mouth and eating it. The aspect that appears between animality and divinity, or the blending of animality and divinity, may be the essence of human nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Especially after being influenced by classic drama works, I returned to the creation and exploration of narrative art that I considered to be more grand and mainstream. The proposition of expressing human nature became the goal and motivation of my creation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;What are the classical dramas that make you watch and think about again and again? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I have read many others, but Sophocles&#39; &quot;Oedipus the King&quot; and Shakespeare&#39;s &quot;Macbeth&quot; &quot;King Lear&quot;, Arthur Miller&#39;s &quot;Death of a Salesman&quot;, Tennessee Williams&#39;s &quot;A Streetcar Named Desire&quot;, Cao Yu&#39;s &quot;Thunderstorm&quot;, Lao She&#39;s &quot;Tea House&quot; are some of the examples that have achieved this. Analyze and think about every word and sentence. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Kionwfx9oIFiU2PmbkSLsXBZWGUykDMMawv9IaG8.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 686&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/11/Kionwfx9oIFiU2PmbkSLsXBZWGUykDMMawv9IaG8.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;253696&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Steady as a Rock&quot; stills&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;An excellent script, Based on scrap manuscripts of 500,000 to 1 million words&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You say The work of screenwriting is very pragmatic and difficult. Can you talk about it in detail based on your creative experience? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;This is what I tell my juniors and students. If you want to write an excellent script, it doesn’t have to be between 500,000 and 1 million words. Based on the scrapped manuscript, it is unlikely. These theories, these things you think about clearly, should eventually form your instincts and body memories. When you write it out, it may be terrible at first, but when you think of dozens of such characters, you will gradually get better at it. No matter which path you take or what methodology you use, you have to do these things. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;is an unavoidable penance. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, only with this kind of hard work can we complete an excellent work. Before &quot;Solid as a Rock&quot;, I wrote hundreds of thousands or millions of words. When I just graduated, China&#39;s film industry had not yet emerged, so I did everything, including commercials, promotional films, and various TV series. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I don’t believe in the emergence of genius, especially for a highly integrated, systematic, and technologically demanding form like film. Just like a musician, when a piece of music comes to mind, It’s very rare to have your inspiration written down and become an eternal song. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Similar to this - facing a blank document in front of the computer - a difficult thinking process, I actually exercised the complexity of thinking. I have always believed that human thinking has dimensions. Most people&#39;s thinking is one-dimensional: I like this boy, I am good with him; I don&#39;t like this leader, I stay away from him. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The troubles in daily life may be two-dimensional: Although I don’t like this leader, I have to support my family, so although I resent him, I must regulate my work well so that he can Pay attention to me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In literary and artistic works, it may be even deeper: I don’t like this person’s style, and I have to cater to him, but in the end I still slam the table at him. It forms three dimensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Establishing multi-dimensional thinking and looking for the relationship between these dimensions, I attribute it to the ability to carry out complex thinking. The creation of a movie involves a lot of elements, at least thousands of thinking points must be thought of, and it must be formed into a structure, which is very complicated. Saying that an author is relatively mature may have a lot to do with what I just talked about. With training and thinking, he gradually acquires the ability to think about complex problems and the methods to organize complex thinking. Maybe the works he can produce will reach a better level in terms of depth, integration, and self-consistency. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This dimensional thinking has also entered my methodology. I often discuss my work with my team. There are three dimensions that are the basis for a script. I still have to do it. It is very difficult to improve one dimension above these three dimensions. It is not a mechanical superposition, but an increase in dimensions. It seems that what I am writing is about breaking through the ceiling of this dimension and entering a new direction in the new dimension. But they are related, not running around. The audience thinks that&#39;s it, I want to come up with something new and unexpected to give the audience this kind of psychological feeling. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;When you and your team create, you will visually combine this Is the process presented, like drawing a force analysis diagram? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Draw thinking maps from various angles. Content creation is a systematic project. Screenwriting can be divided into two stages: first, the planning and original story stage; second, the script stage. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Planning an original story means clarifying what kind of movie we want to make, what is its proposition, and what is its aesthetic style? What kind of audience interest do we correspond to? You need to understand society, the current popular psychology in China, as well as the film’s partners, investment scale, etc. These become an entry point for original stories. We all analyze and discuss together as a team. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I will also divide some of the work. For example, if we want to make a detective film, we will list related literature and movies, which is equivalent to a paper. When making a detective film on this basis, where is our contemporary nature reflected? We can no longer write like Conan Doyle and Agatha Christie. At least we have to stand on the shoulders of Keigo Higashino and look at the problem. Then we will brainstorm the story and come up with, for example, 10 story models, assign them to everyone, and first write a 500-word summary (summary). Let&#39;s go forward - circle this land, we don&#39;t know where there is water, we dig holes, if this road is a dead end, then don&#39;t go; the remaining three holes seem to have potential and may produce running water. , write down to 3,000 words, and then compare them to find the right pitfall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the second stage, I started writing the first draft of the script and completed it in one go. Later, the revision of this first draft will come in, with various specific elements of the project coming in. Once the actor is determined, we will make adjustments based on the actor’s situation. For example, in &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot;, I may strengthen Shen Teng&#39;s strengths in the script and give him a more advanced sense of humor in his lines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The industry’s understanding of screenwriting in a broad sense is “Bring me a notebook.” However, the difference between these two parts (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;the above two stages&lt;/span>;) is very big, and the former one is even as important as the latter one. It is not only about screenwriting ability, but actually involves understanding of society and the industry. Only with these first can a good project be produced. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You have said before that your team adopts a very scientific approach creative method. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Yes, a good work is seamless, like a natural organism, and it is difficult to separate the parts from the whole. The more difficult a work is to disassemble, the more organic it is. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;You know the stress structure of the script. As long as the components can be extracted and this piece can be disassembled, then improve it. For example, I know very well that the narrative information in this dialogue is not enough, so we need to increase the conflict of this dialogue and complete the presentation of narrative information in the conflict. Do detail polishing like this. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, creation is a combination of sensibility and rationality. What drives you to write a work must be emotion, anger, sympathy, emotion, regret, etc. The emotions inspired by the creator are particularly precious. The longer you work in the industry, the harder it is to inspire emotional impulses because you have seen them more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To protect this emotion, even if a small article or a song makes my heart tremble, I will immediately think, what moved me? This cannot be a general good. I care for this flame very carefully, analyze and summarize it, and amplify it into a flame. This flame is the motivation that inspires me to engage in subsequent rational creations. Be very clear about what this flame is. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;How can you be sure that the flame you cherish will also be moved? Most people, can it be developed into a classic narrative film? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;Every artist has his own unique feelings about the world, but people need someone who gradually understands others and truly integrates with society. process. I don’t think an artist should be absolutely unique, unless he spends his life doing experimental and avant-garde art, which is very valuable and explores the boundaries of human thoughts and emotions. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But other excellent works are constantly searching for the noble meaning of the human spirit, looking for consensus and presenting it. The value of the creator lies in connection. I think you are truly mature when you can gradually submerge yourself in the crowd and understand the emotions common to most people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Why do I think what touches me can touch other people? First of all, I am a human being. Secondly, when I become a mature person, my understanding of the world is broader, I can accommodate more life styles and emotional operation methods, and my heart is fuller, then my breathing, feelings, and Others&#39; frequencies will be more likely to converge. The extremely personal part of me can gradually form a certain resonance with other people. At this time, I can gradually understand the psychological pulse of the public. There are situations like this: I was very moved when I saw this story, but it is not that important to other people; but there are also some stories that I can naturally judge that have emotional value to more people, and I can present them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, I hope that my works can communicate with more people. Many literary and artistic young people think this is degeneracy, but I don&#39;t think so. I hope my works can influence and touch more people, and give more people emotional comfort. This moment is the moment when I feel my creation is the most valuable. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Artistic creation comes from restrictions&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;《 &quot;Sturdy as a Rock&quot; is a complete script you wrote yourself. The original ideas for the last two films you collaborated with director Zhang Yimou, &quot;Man Jiang Hong&quot; and &quot;Sniper&quot; were not proposed by you. After receiving the invitation, how did you make it happen? They become works that come from your soul and can move you. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I think art comes from limitations. Dance was born when words were not allowed and only body movements were allowed to convey information and emotions. Opera is created when speaking in a normal way is not allowed, but complex narrative information needs to be conveyed. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I also mentioned in other interviews that Yimou will have some keywords. For example, we will make a movie about resisting U.S. aggression and aiding Korea and telling a sniper story. I need keywords and restrictions. I can tell a real-time story, from a person&#39;s perspective to see him involved in complex things. Although there is a lot of freedom in telling stories from multiple viewpoints, you will find that this kind of story is not that interesting when told. Many times, the pleasure and value of narrative come from this precise control of perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As far as the movie situation is concerned, restrictions will make you freer and more imaginative. Sometimes when I recruit students for exams, I just throw them questions like this: Now you are a helpless person, and you are forced into the toilet of a shopping mall by gangsters. The gangsters are smashing the door outside to rush in. You want to get out of trouble, but there is no second door, what should you do? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Essentially this is a partial training. The audience just wants to watch, but when they are cornered, what can the creator do? When you really come up with a valuable method, accomplish it unexpectedly and reasonably, and the audience feels satisfied, you have completed your conspiracy with the audience. Creators also have to push themselves into a corner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For example, what kind of solution would you give to the proposition just now? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;There are all kinds. For example, they tried to trick him in the east and hit him with a stone; they let the water tank ring and I walked to another compartment. Others wonder how to contact the outside world and call security... There is no standard answer. This actually depends on your creativity and how many ways you can convey and present information in the same scene. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I will also ask another question, such as naming 15 uses for glass. Most people would say, I can use it to grow flowers, raise goldfish, drink wine, drink water, and drink juice. This answer gets no points because it only uses the container properties of the cup. Some people will answer, put a light bulb inside it, shake it, and create light spots on the wall. You can take five glasses and stand on them as plum blossom piles. You can break it and use the pieces to commit suicide. You can use it to focus sunlight and use it as a convex lens. The scoring started. If you can think outside the box, your creativity will obviously be stronger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Southern People Weekly:&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;You said before that screenwriting is a profession that requires a lot of film industry literacy , you are in academia and industry at the same time, will you look for a common methodology and promote it? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Chen Yu: &lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;I do not regard it as a golden rule that should be promoted to the entire industry. Everyone may have different concepts about movies, and even the same concept may have different emphasis, and different authors have different ways of expressing it. All I can do now is use my own method to work with my collaborators to complete something that I think is OK. In teaching, I introduce my methods to students, and they find their own creative methods. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, should you do the structure first or the characters first? There are two different kinds of creation: I first think of the structure of the story, and then put the people in it; or I first build the person, and let the people move and do things on their own to form a structure. Aristotle believed that both were possible, but he preferred structure first. I do the same thing myself, do the structure first. But there are also many excellent creators who let the person in my mind appear first. With each frown and smile, how he does things and how he reacts when meeting people, I let him face these things as a character. I think it&#39;s also very good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[17岁少年抢劫杀害房东，浙江台州警方通报]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258612]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 10/14/26IHYH9dV545IMyscP6p93AvxNM57h4MflEJToPi.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;1654&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/10/14/26IHYH9dV545IMyscP6p93AvxNM5 7h4MflEJToPi. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;254058&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[亲友借债找我担保：给别人无限兜底，自己终将无法自拔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258565]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;“A relative whom I haven’t seen for many years asked me to provide guarantee for his huge personal debt. After being refused, he viciously insulted me. What should I do if I am still scolded by my relatives for not saving my life?&quot; This post on the Internet points to the darkness of human nature and the plight of a soft-hearted person. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Amplifying one&#39;s own financial problems into problems related to relatives. Once he cannot get what he wants, he will immediately break up and hit the other party with a moral stick, not hesitate to ruin his reputation within the family. He can be described as a philistine, cold and cold person. cruel. Of course, we cannot let such an approach go unchecked. Relative relationships are based on blood and are particularly tender, but this does not mean that one person has the responsibility and obligation to save another person from financial crisis. This is the first thing the questioner who panics after being scolded should understand. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This matter is like a wedge, attracting resonance and complaints from many netizens. The story told by a netizen is quite typical. There was once a classmate who had not been in contact for many years. I didn’t know where to get the phone number and found him. I asked him to borrow tens of thousands of dollars. Of course, the respondent politely refused, so the other party downgraded to 10,000, and finally the borrowed amount becomes 1,000. Faced with such moral kidnapping, the respondent hung up the phone and blocked the other party. This situation is quite common, because many people will face a relative or friend who appears out of nowhere and asks for help. If you don&#39;t agree, there is a high probability that you will be teased by the other party. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you have the ability, you can consider borrowing money. Even if you don&#39;t pay it back, if the amount is not large, it probably won&#39;t hurt your muscles and bones. However, among all kinds of private economic relationships, guaranteeing for others can be called the most confusing and dangerous behavior. One respondent told such an incident: His cousin and cousin-in-law opened a wood processing factory with others, and asked him to use his marriage certificate as a guarantee for his brother-in-law and sister-in-law to get a loan of 100,000 yuan. He didn&#39;t agree, and his cousin didn&#39;t give up and kept trying in various ways, but in the end he didn&#39;t agree. And inadvertently he learned that his cousin had no such thing as partnering with others to open a factory, and his cousin was already extremely poor. He felt afraid. If he agreed in a hurry, the matter would be on the line. If something happened in the middle, wouldn&#39;t all the pressure be put on him? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the perspective of those seeking help, in addition to some who wantonly deceive and &quot;trap&quot; their relatives and friends, there are also many who ask for help with the truth of their embarrassment. Therefore, it is not necessary to classify all help seekers as untrustworthy &quot;others&quot;. But even so, we still need to treat others&#39; requests for help with rationality and calmness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, more and more people have started businesses, and the demand for investment, funds, and guarantees has naturally increased. Some people embark on a project with the determination to &quot;go bankrupt&quot;. Once the funds cannot keep up and the overall situation collapses, the first thing they think of when they are anxious is to find relatives and friends to help, maybe with profit, or with love. , in short, I hope relatives and friends will lend a helping hand. This sentiment is understandable, but the specific response is worthy of discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A friend told me that he was asked by his cousin to mortgage his property in exchange for life-saving money to receive a blood transfusion to extend his life. But after careful consideration, he still declined because he only had two apartments, one for himself and one for rent to support his family. He had neither the extra power to help others nor the substantial ability to withstand risks to &quot;cover the bottom line.&quot; The cousin naturally complained a lot. But he felt that he was not capable of not helping his cousin, nor did he cause any harm to his cousin&#39;s interests, so he felt no guilt. What&#39;s more, he later learned that his cousin was not the only one who had spoken to him, nor was he the only one who refused. The stakes of this matter are actually this: the real estate matter is a family&#39;s wealth and life, and it cannot withstand the storm at all. The cousin&#39;s request itself is a bit excessive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As the saying goes in Guangdong, &quot;If you don&#39;t play the middle, you don&#39;t play the guarantee, and you don&#39;t play the matchmaker, the three generations will be good.&quot; Throughout the ages, many guarantors have suffered so much that their intestines turned green because of a single guarantor, so they left &quot;ancient precepts&quot; to warn future generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Securing a guarantee may seem like a simple matter of signing and making a pledge, but the truth is that it is not the case. Providing a guarantee is indeed a major matter involving serious legal consequences, and its severity often exceeds the financial capacity of an ordinary family. No matter how the guarantee is provided, once the guaranteed person runs away, the corresponding legal consequences are entirely likely to be passed on to the guarantor. There are countless examples of this. A few years ago, the Tianning District Court of Changzhou City, Jiangsu Province enforced a case in which the guarantor paid 255,000 yuan because the borrower &quot;ran away&quot;. It is also common for the guarantor to be restricted from spending too much and taking high-speed trains and airplanes because of being implicated. After the guarantee fails, there are many examples of marital discord and divorce, which is really not worth it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;People in the legal profession remind you that there are many pitfalls in guaranteeing others. For example, if there is no guarantee share when writing the IOU, the guarantor will bear joint liability. The reason why some guarantors make &quot;missteps&quot; is, on the one hand, because they cannot save face, and on the other hand, they agree rashly because they have little understanding of the risks and responsibilities they may bear. As everyone knows, your &quot;loyalty&quot; is making it difficult for you to &quot;protect yourself.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When a person is in a realistic economic status and family situation, he should not shoot himself in the foot out of impulse. Instead, he should decisively say &quot;no&quot; to unreasonable requests for help. Undoubtedly, if you can&#39;t protect yourself well, how can you &quot;protect&quot; others? You know, when you get into a lot of trouble because of a wrong decision in a moment, most of the people who asked you to be your guarantee will not come out to save you. In comparison, the reputation you bear for refusing to guarantee is the smallest price to pay. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, you have the right to defend your rights if you are insulted, ostracized, and ruined by your relatives because of your refusal to provide guarantee. The worst case scenario is to &quot;swear&quot; him back, or simply break up the family relationship. The best way to deal with family kidnapping is to see the trick first. In short, no matter what the situation, you can&#39;t just pretend to be fat and get involved in other people&#39;s financial whirlpool that has nothing to do with you just because you have a good relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the final analysis, regarding the controversy surrounding guarantees, a sense of boundaries should be established. It is true that we are relatives, and we are true that we are brothers and sisters. We should be cautious about boundaries. We can neither force others nor make unreasonable demands, nor can we be forced by others and agree to unreasonable demands. There is a saying in Nanjing, where I live, that &quot;if relatives don&#39;t share wealth, there will be no sharing of wealth.&quot; This is also derived from many lessons. The essence of this statement is that among people, it is your duty to live your own life and solve your own problems. Relatives and friends can indeed help each other, as long as it is within the scope of their abilities and does not affect their own lives. This is also the meaning of family ties. However, when dealing with major financial issues, you should never cross the boundaries and bottom lines and rashly give unlimited benefits to others. Keeping things secret will eventually make you sink into a quagmire that you can&#39;t extricate yourself from. At this point, not only will your relatives be unable to do anything, your life and family may also be over. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[重庆33层高楼底层挖出“四室一厅”，街道要求恢复原状]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258605]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 16:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[普通话是满式汉语吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/258561]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, the US &quot;National Geographic&quot; published a tweet: &quot;Chinese Mandarin is only Chinese?&quot; This Mandarin Just Disappeared&quot;, which stated that Manchu was once the official language of China&#39;s 300 million people, but now it has disappeared. After this tweet was sent out, it immediately attracted ridicule and complaints from many Chinese netizens. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The author has read the general content of this article. To be fair, this tweet is indeed full of errors and omissions. It is obviously stitched together by randomly searching a few Manchu-related articles on the Internet, and the materials used are of mixed quality. Manchu was the official language of the Qing Dynasty. At its peak, the population was more than 300 million. The expression &quot;the official language of a population of 300 million&quot; is not entirely wrong. But the numbers are still debatable. After all, the population in the late Qing Dynasty reached more than 400 million. In addition, there are far more serious errors in this tweet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, one of them says:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Although Manchu has disappeared, Mandarin is actually Mandarin. Chinese, Beijing dialect and Northeastern dialect have many Manchu sounds. The stains left behind after the clothes are stained with dirty things are called He Leng in Northeastern dialect, and the original meaning in Manchu is ripples of water. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The oil has gone bad. It is called &quot;Haweier&quot; in Beijing dialect, which comes from the Manchu har, and its original meaning is The spicy smell hits my nose. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Smoothing out wrinkled things is called Masa in Northeastern dialect, and the original meaning in Manchu is to stretch. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been studying Manchu for a while, and it is not difficult to find that this large paragraph is full of fallacies: 1. The ripple in Manchu is irahi or iren, which is completely different from the pronunciation of &quot;he Leng&quot;. coherent. 2. The use of &quot;ha&quot; to describe the smell of spoiled oil is very common in Xiang, Wu, Min, and Southwest Mandarin. This is obviously a native Chinese word. The original character is (left stink and right harm). Because this character is so uncommon, it was written as the homophone &quot;ha&quot;. 3. As for the word &quot;Masa&quot; in Northeastern dialect, which means soothing, it is obviously the word &quot;Momo&quot;, and there is no doubt about its meaning and pronunciation. The Manchu word &quot;stretch&quot; is sarahvn, which is completely different from &quot;masa&quot; - you have to ask if there is any word in Manchu that has the same pronunciation as &quot;stroke&quot;, and it is true, but the Manchu word &quot;masa&quot; means to play on a swing. It means...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, if you search this paragraph online, you will find that it was copied from various self-media accounts. The original authors of these accounts, as well as the author of this tweet who copied them indiscriminately, obviously do not understand Manchu at all. I don’t know where they got these rumors from and made them up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Mandarin/Beijing/Northeastern dialect is Manchu Chinese&quot; is also a famous old rumor - linguists have long determined that there is basically no Manchu in Beijing dialect and Northeastern dialect. Vocabulary, grammar and pronunciation have not been influenced by Manchu. Missionaries who came to China during the Ming Dynasty recorded the Ming Dynasty Beijing dialect using Western alphabet spelling, and there was no obvious difference from modern Beijing dialect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, rumors like &quot;Manchu is everywhere in the Northeast&quot; are still very popular today. For example, the place name Changchun is often said to be the transliteration of the Manchu &quot;Cha Ah Chong&quot; - however, there is no word &quot;Cha Ah Chong&quot; in Manchu at all. The name of Changchun began with the establishment of &quot;Cha Ah Chong&quot; in Jilin during the Liao Dynasty. &quot;Changchun Prefecture&quot; is obviously a Chinese place name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you really want to count the Manchu words in Beijing dialect and Northeastern dialect, they basically only have nouns like &quot;Shaqima&quot;. However, this kind of vocabulary borrowing is inevitable. Cantonese and Hokkien also have the word Shaqima. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, if you think about it for a moment, you will understand that Manchu will not leave many traces in northern Chinese. This is just like there are basically no Aboriginal words in American English. There are no Austronesian features in Taiwanese Hokkien. Because Chinese is a language that has matured a long time ago and has a very rich and sufficient vocabulary, there is basically no need to borrow words. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If there are any concepts that are easier to express in Manchu, they are basically related to fishing and hunting. For example, there are many words in Manchu to describe pigs of different ages, dogs of different colors, and various methods of fishing... But neither the Han citizens in Beijing nor the Han farmers traveling to Guandong need to use these. Fishing and hunting vocabulary. In turn, Manchu words related to agriculture, industry and commerce, academia, and science and technology are basically borrowed from Chinese - for example, the Manchu word &quot;gong&quot; means &quot;gung&quot;, the word &quot;jin&quot; means &quot;gin&quot;, the word &quot;stone mill&quot; means &quot;mose&quot; (mill), and the word &quot;baby&quot; means boobai. ...all borrowed from Chinese. Another example is &quot;body&quot;. Most other Tungusic words are words like beye. But Manchu is ᠪᡝᠶᡝ ᡩᡠᡵᠰᡠᠨ=beye (body) + dursun (physique) = body...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Chinese only used synonymous compounds for redundancy checking after the degeneracy of the medieval phonology system. In Manchu, beye is already a two-syllable word. Wouldn’t it be too verbose to add dursun? What’s even more amazing is that the Manchu word “child” is actually ᡶᡠᠯᡤᡳᠶᠠᠨ ᠵᡠᡳ (fulgiyan jui) – literally meaning “red fetus”...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although it is a little outrageous to understand child as a red fetus, But I can barely find some ancient books to support it. But the Manchu word for &quot;naked&quot; is also fulahvn beye (light red body), and &quot;barefoot&quot; is fulahvn bethe (light red legs). This is a completely literal mechanical translation, and the wrong meaning is chosen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Modern genetic testing has found that the Tungusic speaking populations (such as Hezhe, Xibe, Ewenki, Oroqen, etc.) are genetically consistent, but the Manchus are an exception - the Manchus have obvious blood differences with other Tungusic populations, but are more similar to the Han people There is basically no difference. A molecular anthropology institution tested 2,938 Manchus and found that only about 3% had Tungusic ancestry, even lower than their southern Han ancestry (6.57%). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The modern Manchus are basically indistinguishable from the Han in blood, which implies that the Manchus have intermarryed with the Han on a large scale over the past few hundred years, and in the end the Tungus bloodline was diluted to the point that it was negligible. Before the emergence of modern media and compulsory education, anyone’s mother tongue was learned through blood transmission. If every generation of a Manchu family intermarry with the Han people, the bloodline, language, customs, and culture of a group of people will not be any different from those of the Han people, and it will be difficult to distinguish them. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（ This article is only the author&#39;s personal opinion and does not represent the position of this newspaper)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[赵红程：无障碍通行，不只有轮椅人士需要]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/256808]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-14 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;How to understand barrier-free access? She is skilled in wheelchair driving. She has released more than a hundred city accessibility evaluation videos. She has falsified the &quot;need for gratitude&quot; and told the public not to have endless pity. &quot;Give up being condescending and give up false concern. We should be friends.&quot; !&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&lt;video id=&quot;contents-video-0&quot; data-fileid=&quot;5576678020725550870&quot; data-media =&quot;video&quot; data-resource=&quot;tencent&quot; data-filename=&quot;People Weekly Issue 766 Youth Power Zhao Hongcheng Video.mp4&quot; data-cover=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/17/f1ecwIvAVZ4NqjMwdtC7yBzco9Htg2T1pO42EUrC.jpg&quot; data-url=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/5aa5934a5576678020725550 870/cx3pjkQur5oA.mp4&quot; poster=&quot;&quot; controls=&quot;controls&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot; 360&quot;>; &lt;source src=&quot;http://1251434507.vod2.myqcloud.com/02f2b5c2vodcq1251434507/5aa5934a5576678020725550870/cx3pjkQur5oA.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Accessibility It seems that the only way to attract people&#39;s attention is to take an eccentric approach. Recently, videos of young people from many places “commuting to get off work in electric wheelchairs” have appeared on social media, sparking heated discussions. Suddenly, accessibility became an issue of public concern and in urgent need of “management.” &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“I really don’t understand how the topic ‘Young people focus on electric wheelchairs’ became so popular.” Zhao Hongcheng, an accessibility evaluation video blogger, expressed his doubts. As a former product manager of a major manufacturer, Zhao Hongcheng expressed his doubts. , she thinks this is obviously a marketing tool for businesses, &quot;Can you go out 100 meters in an electric wheelchair? Can people drive here? Open your eyes and take a look at the barrier-free facilities here. Let people who should go out first be able to go out. , and then think about how to &#39;manage&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/uGJx4Wh4nUQk9YhMNtxKakJusCqNwtUHVsim7EIP.jpg&quot; border= &quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/13/uGJx4Wh4nUQk9YhMNtxKakJusCqNwtUHVsim7EIP.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;250533&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;For related reports, please see &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infzm.com/contents/250873&quot; title=&quot;The story of wheelchair girl Zhao Hongcheng &quot;Accessibility&quot; drama: Do I make you nervous? &quot;>;Wheelchair girl Zhao Hongcheng&#39;s &quot;Accessibility&quot; drama: Do I make you nervous? &lt;/a>; 》&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Hongcheng contracted polio when she was 1 year old and was in a wheelchair when she was in middle school. Today, she is quite skilled in wheelchair driving. She has been releasing videos on city accessibility assessments since 2019. After resigning from the Internet industry two years ago, she turned into a full-time video blogger. The video she produced, &quot;Black and Red List of Barrier-free Facilities,&quot; was once on Weibo&#39;s hot search list. So far, she has released more than a hundred urban accessibility assessment videos, covering Shanghai, Hangzhou, Guangzhou, Macau, and Taiwan, showing the daily life and travel obstacles encountered by people with disabilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Data from the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation shows that as of 2022, the total number of disabled people in China will reach more than 85 million, accounting for more than 6% of the total population. However, they are rarely seen in public places. On June 28, 2023, the third meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress voted to pass the Barrier-free Environment Construction Law. This law will come into effect on September 1, 2023. On March 1, 2023, the &quot;Shanghai Barrier-free Environment Construction Regulations&quot; came into effect. More and more people are aware of the importance of barrier-free environment construction, but it is not easy for the city&#39;s supporting system to keep up. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In a Shanghai accessibility evaluation video, when Zhao Hongcheng and her husband went to watch a talk show, they asked the theater staff about the location of the accessible toilets. The staff suggested that you can use diapers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhao Hongcheng believes that for-profit cultural and artistic venues such as art exhibitions and theaters are the &quot;hardest hit areas&quot; for accessibility. &quot;It seems that as a disabled person, you can confidently make demands when traveling on the subway, but in terms of cultural enjoyment, your confidence will be much weaker.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in the evaluation video, Zhao Hongcheng still tried Go swimming, go to Disney, go to Universal Studios, and document it on video. The inconvenience of legs and feet should not ultimately constitute difficulties in the entire living system of the disabled group because the city&#39;s supporting facilities are not in place. She hopes to promote the construction of barrier-free facilities in the country, and also hopes to bring people with disabilities, a long-marginalized social group, into the spotlight, be seen and have their own voice. &quot;Sometimes when I go out and walk on the street, I can find out from many people&#39;s expressions and questions that I am the first person in a wheelchair they have seen in their lives.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023 In May, the one-man drama &quot;Where is the nearest barrier-free toilet?&quot; based on Zhao Hongcheng. ” was staged at the Shanghai Grand Theater. It is the first domestic drama adapted from real people with disabilities. The first row of seats under the stage has been opened up as barrier-free wheelchair seats. Audiences in wheelchairs are seated in every performance, including 20 audience members in wheelchairs in one performance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the stage, Zhao Hongcheng uses a dramatic performance to present her travel difficulties. Her daily travel is sometimes like an urban adventure: car horns, bus announcements, chaotic voices, and cars passing by. Amidst the noise, she drove her wheelchair around the city, not knowing which direction would be less obstructed. No matter how early she left her home, she was always late. Those praises for &quot;self-improvement&quot;, the prying eyes of strangers, the &quot;good intentions&quot; of others doing good, and the selective ignorance on more occasions... &quot;It seems that I always need to be constantly grateful.&quot; said Zhao Hongcheng, the lead actor in the drama and the prototype of the story. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Of all my expectations for this drama project, the most important point is that I need to make this happen. I want a story about people with disabilities to be staged in the theater.&quot; Successive dramas After the performance, Zhao Hongcheng felt that he finally had his own voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This drama will be performed in Beijing on September 16. Zhao Hongcheng still pays attention to all information about barrier-free access on the Internet, and directly expresses his attitude towards some inexplicable pity, &quot;Give up being condescending and give up false concern, we should be friends!&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>