<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[掰掰告别狮子林桥后，天津还有哪些快乐？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257898]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 08:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[东亚家庭的悲剧与温情，全程哭着看完]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257890]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;The son who has been away from home for many years suddenly received a call from his old man. How will he face the call from his mother who wants to take a posthumous photo and explain what happened after her death? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The documentary &quot;House of God&quot; from Taiwan starts with this phone call and reveals the painful past of a family. The son in the film is the documentary director Lu Yingliang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/5e40d477465b42d4a99706cdccee27b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1542&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/5e40d477465b42d4a99706cdccee27b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252723&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The film is in Last year, it won four awards including the million-dollar first prize, the Best Documentary Award, the Best Editing Award and the Audience Choice Award at the Taipei Film Festival. It was also enthusiastically received during the film festival in Switzerland, and it also has a good score of 8.3 on Douban. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Because the film cuts into the native family from the director&#39;s perspective and shows every detail of rural life, many people compared it to the 2017 &quot;Four Spring&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in addition to similar themes, similar perspectives, and both being filmed over a longer period of time, the emotional undertones of the two films are actually very different. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/551c0fa59ff4e2e0b15fb68fce76c31b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;1620&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/551c0fa59ff4e2e0b15fb68fce76c31b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252724&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《Four &quot;Spring&quot; is like a simple literary utopia. We long to grow up in such a family, enjoy the influence of music, and have a warm life like the director; and &quot;House of Gods&quot; reproduces another situation of East Asian families - There was no dialogue, they tortured each other, and after &quot;living&quot; based on instinctive consciousness, they escaped from this cursed place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mother who is thin and works all day long; the father who has nothing to do and is addicted to lottery tickets; and the brother who is just muddling along and accomplishing nothing. Director Lu Yingliang does not directly present the desperate state of these family members, but through a &quot;god&quot;. A rare perspective that reflects everyone&#39;s inner world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the director&#39;s hometown, there has always been a strong belief in gods, and the Lu family attaches great importance to it. They have a separate room upstairs for worshiping a shrine and an incense altar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/355fc9f42b250a57564de8f63af746e6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;613&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/355fc9f42b250a57564de8f63af746e6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252725&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;All this source When Yu Lu Yingliang&#39;s brother was 12 years old, he suddenly became &quot;psychic&quot; and was chosen by the gods. He became a celebrity who traveled far and wide to seek guidance from gods. For many years after that, in addition to farm work, my brother also worked part-time as a fortune teller for others, and the Lu family became connected with the gods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But through the director’s lens, we will find that family members have different attitudes towards gods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although my mother is in poor health, she still climbs up and down every day to worship the gods. When asked repeatedly by her son why she persisted, she said lonelyly: &quot;In the past, when your brother left home, you and your father were not at home. Your sister went to work, and I was the only one left at home. They were all there to accompany me.&quot; Me.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/a599f88aa86a6400037aa147b2a4c52d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080 &quot; height=&quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/a599f88aa86a6400037aa147b2a4c52d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252726&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Unlike his mother&#39;s simple emotional sustenance, his father is utilitarian towards gods. He always wanted to guess the numbers from the smoke coming out of the incense and use it to buy lottery tickets. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The elder brother, who has been dealing with gods for half his life, gradually fell into an embarrassing situation on camera. The film specifically uses the &quot;little tomato incident&quot; to expose the conceptual gap between the two generations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Before planting tomatoes, my brother specifically asked the gods for instructions on the farming date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/224bc1a4bc313d1d17b872c64c05f5a5.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;602&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/224bc1a4bc313d1d17b872c64c05f5a5.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252728&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But right here Not long after the fruit seedlings were planted, heavy rains for days flooded the farmland, but the gods did not play any role. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The young nephew was unwilling. He first said angrily that he had stopped believing in gods for a long time, but soon after, he burst into tears, hoping that his brother could ask the gods to find a solution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The elder brother did not want to deceive his son, but in order to soothe the next generation&#39;s uneasiness and confusion, he could only pretend to have a breath with the gods, saying that Hua Tuo would greet his friends and solve the dilemma. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, God becomes the comforter of this ordinary family. When the family finds no hope in reality, the more they place their hope on the gods. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/9b655e87cb3cd81be4aa2e6434d3b5a0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/9b655e87cb3cd81be4aa2e6434d3b5a0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252727&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Like a director When my brother was doing farm work, he asked in despair and confusion: &quot;Do you really think God has helped our family? Or should I say, is there really a God?&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There are few Chinese speakers. The film explores such metaphysical themes, not to mention situating this discussion among members of a rural family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of course, we don’t need to compare &quot;House of God&quot; with religious films such as &quot;First Reformed&quot; and &quot;The Last Temptation of Christ&quot;. Director Lu Yingliang does not have this ambition. The reason why he Raising this question is based on his despair for his original family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/efcf3ab445698828ae8311d7db21a9fb.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/efcf3ab445698828ae8311d7db21a9fb.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252729&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yingliang&#39;s father He almost never fulfilled his responsibilities and only knew how to idle around. Even because of gambling debts in his early years, the whole family had to move. Although his elder brother was good-hearted, he lacked ability and failed to start his own business several times. He had to borrow money to pay off the debts. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yingliang had no choice but to work hard in a big city at the age of 18 and almost never came back because he knew that once he fell into this house of gods and men, he would become the same as those god tablets and become the entrustment of the whole family. &quot;hope&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From the beginning of the film until the middle and later stages, Lu Yingliang rarely appears in the picture. He basically communicates sparsely with his family in voice-over, and is full of confrontation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This situation did not change until my father was suddenly diagnosed with cancer. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/e1175bd37c5b0692749d2ef4e85ea3f8.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;601&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/e1175bd37c5b0692749d2ef4e85ea3f8.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252731&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lu Yingliang finally decided I helped my parents take photos of their deaths, and when choosing photos, I had a rare conversation with my father, and the family sat together, a rare moment of warmth and harmony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I believe this scene will make many people cry secretly, because its tenderness uses the photo of the deceased (death) as a bridge to connect. The resentment that had been built up for many years gradually dissipated, not because the Lu family was on the right track, but because his father would eventually pass away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is a sad ending for an East Asian family. Just like the recent &quot;That Time a Ghost and I Became Family&quot;, the father played by Tuo Zonghua finally opened his heart because Mao Bangyu had passed away. Regret makes people put aside their prejudices and their attitudes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/13e3dceb1b845daa801316bac97ef234.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;605&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/13e3dceb1b845daa801316bac97ef234.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252732&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《神人Near the end of &quot;Home&quot;, Lu Yingliang finally returned to the home that had made him frustrated. He tasted the sweetness from the tomatoes grown by his brother, and took his mother on a train to see the sea, fulfilling her long-cherished wish. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The place where this old woman lives is actually only a few dozen kilometers away from the coastline. Apart from her wedding photos, she only had one young and beautiful photo when she was young. All her life since then has been dedicated to it. Three children and a useless husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If there is a god in &quot;House of Gods&quot;, then it is Lu Yingliang&#39;s mother. She is the real glue of this family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/c659b1d78540742f7908265a93145cec.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;599&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/c659b1d78540742f7908265a93145cec.png&quot; data-key=&quot;252730&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Watch &quot;God When reading &quot;Human Home&quot;, it always reminds me of Huang Zi&#39;s &quot;Xiaowei&quot; and Dapeng&#39;s &quot;Auspicious Ruyi&quot;. One of these two films is an art film, and the other is a documentary in the form of a meta-film, but to some extent, they both belong to the category of private family films. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The creators of these films have honestly presented the disease, death and discord among members of the native family, whether it is long-term silent hostility or uncontrollable tension. It all reminds us of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;House of Gods&quot; may not be called a blockbuster of the year, let alone a high achievement in terms of images, but the sincerity of emotional expression is indeed something that has not been seen for a long time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Director Lu Yingliang went from watching his family worshiping gods with a cold eye, to shifting his perspective away from the gods and towards his parents and brothers. This change in perspective is clearly visible. This tells us invisibly that he no longer carefully observes himself and his family in a binary opposition, but chooses to recognize his former identity and accompany his mother on the endless coastline. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当幼儿园的儿子变得“社会”时，父亲在想什么丨养儿育女]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257882]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 22:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My son, who is in the third grade of kindergarten, came back from school one night and told me in a low mood: Dad, I can’t do it tomorrow. Because I was talking to my classmates today, the primary teacher who was supposed to be on duty tomorrow was assigned to another classmate by the teacher. I said it didn&#39;t matter, there would be another chance in the future, and then I pulled him with a smile to get ready to play. Unexpectedly, my son scolded me for my passive and careless attitude. He said no, so he would do it one less time. He would not be able to talk nonsense to his classmates next time. I was stunned for a moment. It was really I wonder why he is so interested in being a little teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Under my gentle questioning, my son told the truth that he wanted to be a primary school teacher: because this way he could control other children. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The answer surprised me. It was clearly a sign of a desire for power. I heard that this is a kind of power given by teachers to children who perform well in order to facilitate daily management. Children who serve as primary school teachers can help the teacher supervise other children, mainly in that they can criticize children with irregular behaviors. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I wanted to indoctrinate my son and tell him that this idea was wrong. As soon as I said one sentence, I was already lacking in confidence and knew that my dogmatic words would be contradicted by him. I changed my way of saying this: When you are a primary school teacher, you should serve the children. When you find a child making a mistake, don’t scold him loudly, otherwise the other person will be sad. You should speak in a gentle tone. The son said very maturely, I understand. It seems that he has become accustomed to the rules of this little teacher&#39;s game, which I did not expect. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;He said that being a primary school teacher is sometimes difficult. Once, he and a classmate were both primary school teachers. His good friend was called out by the classmate when he was speaking. He wanted to be accommodating, but was rejected by the classmate. This made him very distressed and didn&#39;t know what to do. Another time, he criticized a classmate when he was a primary school teacher. A few days later, the classmate deliberately called his name when he was a primary school teacher. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I was stunned when I heard these stories. I was at a loss and felt very familiar at the same time. Isn’t this the epitome of the workplace for us adults, and it is too “social”. My son didn’t understand what I meant by “society”. I told him that what the other person did was wrong and you can’t do that. I asked a few friends who have children and they reported similar situations. The only comfort I can find is that such a mechanism can restrain children from some irregular behaviors in class, but it may not be effective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Maybe children don’t want to become too “social”. Sometimes they have no choice like us adults, or they are trapped in it without knowing it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The mother of her son’s classmate told me something: Once, my son told her that one day her child was punished by the teacher at school to stand in the back of the classroom and talk to other children. She asked my son, how did you know, and he said without hesitation that the teacher made us stand while we were talking together. After listening to it, we burst out laughing. We were thinking about saying goodbye to others, but we suddenly exposed ourselves. Perhaps this is a contrast between &quot;society&quot; and innocence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Many times, children’s world is becoming adult, and children experience the rules and confusion of adult society prematurely. When we face our own problems, we usually appear powerless or messed up. When our children encounter the same situation, how can we expect them to be perfect? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I went to pick up my son from school one day, he happily said that today he was on duty as a student. I thought to myself, what&#39;s so good about being a duty student? Isn&#39;t it just voluntary labor? But he told me that being a student on duty was to help the teacher sweep the floor and arrange chairs. It was a task assigned to him by the teacher, and it was a supreme honor. Thinking about children&#39;s &quot;society&quot;, there may be a gratifying point, that is, the threshold for happiness is very low. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Recently I watched a movie online called &quot;Goodbye, Our Kindergarten&quot;. In the movie, the kindergarten children sang a song at the graduation ceremony, &quot;We have spent countless days here. Every night, we laughed many times, cried many times, caught cold many times, we played here with so many dear friends, we ran here, fell here, fought here, goodbye to our Kindergarten, this is our playground.” The singing and lyrics moved me very much. Kindergarten should be a pure and happy playground, with less social fetters and worries. I recommended this movie to my son. He refused at first, but when I told him that it was about a few children going on an adventure to visit a good friend who was seriously ill, he expressed great interest. That weekend afternoon, because there was no Mandarin dubbing, I read all the lines to him with great emotion. After the movie ended, he said he was going to cry. I knew that he must have the same empathy for other people&#39;s sadness and happiness as the children in the play. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(The author is a worker in the cultural industry)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>; •&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;(&quot;Raising Children&quot; in the &quot;Hi, Southern Weekly&quot; column of the Southern Weekend App, welcome Write a letter to share the scenery and principles you have learned as a parent and teacher on the way your children grow up. Submission email: nfzmreaders@163.com)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 22:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[打工人为什么越来越反感团建？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257819]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 21:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 09/27/IZMnXlFgOEJEXwna8gI3vyBrOXpfwcN464su8Xku.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;920&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/IZMnXlFgOEJEXwna8gI3vyBrOXpfwcN464 su8Xku. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252394&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Absurd Show&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;18 faces are on the ground, 18 hands are stretched out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18 employees in black team uniforms lay flat on the stage of a hotel conference hall, pointing in a worshiping posture to the judges&#39; seat where the team&#39;s appearance is scored - the seat of the training instructor. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The high scores given by the judges were like a black hole, sucking eight teams composed of employees into endless rehearsals and competitions. It seems that after being assigned the team names of &quot;War Wolf&quot;, &quot;Electric Wolf&quot; and &quot;Wild Wolf&quot;, people&#39;s wolf nature can be stimulated. The salesperson who doesn&#39;t like to exercise stacked up four layers of arhats without safety protection; the girl who usually speaks slowly and quietly yells &quot;Hello everyone&quot; while kicking in goose steps to compete for the glory of the team; to express her love for the company Out of gratitude, a team simply knelt down collectively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The door to the conference hall was pushed open by the diligently practicing team members before 8 o&#39;clock in the morning, and was reluctantly closed until 1 o&#39;clock in the morning. Rehearsing exhaustingly, just so that one of the teams can show the most unique posture, the neatest steps, and the loudest slogan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The team building organized by the company made Li Yang a performer of spectacle. Before, he couldn&#39;t believe that he would show his style as &quot;falling headfirst&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yang is a salesperson at a private lighting company. When he sees videos displayed by other teams on Douyin, he always sneers at those exaggerated actions. Unexpectedly, the person in the video now is himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On an ordinary weekend in August 2023, in Changzhou, Jiangsu, under the threat of salary deduction from the personnel department, Li Yang and more than 200 other colleagues boarded the team-building bus angrily. In the hotel where the team was built, they devoted themselves to all activities day and night, without any fear of leaving behind hoarse voices, bruised limbs, and colds, as if everything was done willingly from the beginning. The anger of being forced to &quot;work overtime&quot; and the 100 yuan of self-funded team building fees seem to be just small hurdles that need to be overcome in the process of &quot;soul sublimation&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The sublimation of training activities is to let employees learn to be &quot;thankful&quot;, which is the appeal of the company boss. Li Yang recalled that this team building did sometimes touch the soft hearts of some employees. Listening to the training instructor&#39;s exaggeration, an employee who had left his hometown had an epiphany with tears in his eyes: he should regard the company as his &quot;home&quot;; the boss carried two employees on his back and ran panting around the venue to simulate the &quot;hardship of starting a business.&quot; Li Yang will also feel compassion when he sees it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, reason reminded him that these sensational points are more like the fog lingering on the abnormal logic: &quot;The mentor said that the boss runs on the back of his employees, just like when he started a business, he carried the burden for his employees. Why do I think it&#39;s the other way around? It&#39;s obviously the employees who are carrying the boss&#39;s weight forward. The instructor just wants us to feel guilty and work hard.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yang does feel guilty, but This has nothing to do with the company&#39;s favor, but more to do with one&#39;s own actions against one&#39;s will. He confessed that he did not understand the value of these games, but he became the component that maintained their operation; he knew the mentor&#39;s &quot;lies&quot;, but accepted his every instruction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After leaving his previous company, this is Li Yang’s first year at this company and he has not yet established himself. He didn&#39;t dare to stand up and refute anything, &quot;I can&#39;t be the kind of person who dares to be the first in the world.&quot; Seeing a group of &quot;post-00&quot; colleagues sneak away in the night after experiencing the first day of training, Li Yang&#39;s feet were still nailed In place. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Those who stayed behind, like Li Yang, carried out their &quot;behave&quot; to the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The &quot;Life and Death Grid&quot; with &quot;team collaboration&quot; as the training purpose: nearly 300 people pass through the same net hole one after another. If someone touches the net, everything will be cleared and restarted. The whole process lasted for more than 4 hours, with the supervisor interrupting again and again and the team members numbly repeating the devastating actions. Meditation designed to teach people self-reflection: While everyone was meditating in soothing music, a dozen training assistants suddenly rushed out of the darkness and cursed at the employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Li Yang doesn’t have many complaints about his boss, the initiator of team building. What he dislikes the most is &quot;Brother Guo Shi&quot;, the training instructor who issues orders and designs courses - a man in his forties with unknown educational background and qualifications, who calls himself &quot;the master&quot;. &quot;He likes to ask us closed-ended questions, and his catchphrase is &#39;understand the applause&#39;, just like a pyramid scheme.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/09/27/lHBup7JvgoG3V87TLGXrNJ1Y9JzN0VMY92m0mYQl.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;534&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09 /27/lHBup7JvgoG3V87TLGXrNJ1Y9JzN0VMY92m0mYQl.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252392&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Employees of Li Yang’s company conducted a team presentation&lt;span style= &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(provided by the interviewee/picture)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Brother Guo Shi appeared with his head held high among a group of &quot;teaching assistants&quot; who were kneeling. On the podium, he emphasized that as long as Obey, don&#39;t argue, he has the power to eliminate anyone. A female employee in her fifties fell to the ground from exhaustion while being punished in a game (doing hundreds of push-ups). Instructor Guo yelled at those who came to help and urged the punished to complete it alone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Instructor Guo is just one of the symbols of this closed venue. Along with him, suppressing the free movement of participants, there are banners hanging on the four walls: &quot;To love him is to strictly demand him&quot;, &quot;There is no you and me, only us&quot; &quot;If you don&#39;t provide results, the boss will bear the consequences&quot;; There is a game mechanism with bonuses for the top three, more than 200 uniform black T-shirts, and a queue shouting louder than the other. Li Yang explained, &quot;Although it seems absurd, in that environment, everyone did it, and you had no choice but to follow it.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/ cms/medias/image/23/09/27/WtiOFFAbblHFrnkf54zAo7rXxfnwuRJW8TuW6aFV.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;664&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/ 23/09/27/WtiOFFAbblHFrnkf54zAo7rXxfnwuRJW8TuW6aFV.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252393&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Today&#39;s team building is not training&quot;, “Team building is biased towards entertainment and has even been demonized”, “bad money drives out good money”, this is the evaluation of the current team building market by Xia Hui, general manager of the experiential training institution Renzhongren in South China&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa ;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The loneliness of experiential training&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;No matter whether the experience is good or bad, &quot;team building&quot; is something that most migrant workers avoid today. I am afraid of the shackles of the workplace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is nothing new to rely on rationality to undergo certain magic operations in team building like Li Yang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A steady stream of companies send their employees on team-building tours that are infuriating and humiliating. On the Internet, every once in a while, there will be hot searches such as &quot;slapping each other&#39;s face team building&quot;, &quot;kowtow to the leader team building&quot; and &quot;cruel survival team building&quot;. What was once shocking news is now commonplace. They seem to form a part of our country&#39;s workplace culture, to an extreme degree and in a stable state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“Today’s team building is not training”, “Team building is biased towards entertainment and has even been demonized”, “Bad money drives out good money”, this is Xia Xia, General Manager of South China Region of Renzhongren, an experiential training institution. Wei’s evaluation of today’s team building market. Rather than “team building”, people in the industry prefer to use “experiential training” to refer to these corporate team trainings designed to challenge oneself, build a team, and improve performance. Xia Hui said that &quot;team building&quot; was originally just the name of a course in experiential training. Because it is designed with low difficulty, broad goals, and high demand, it has gradually become the most popular type among peers. Among them, games and activities are the easiest to imitate, so &quot;team building&quot; has become synonymous with various activities of corporate teams. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The market is filled with all kinds of experiential trainers. Some, like &quot;Instructor Guo&quot;, specialize in corporate courses and are good at using chicken soup stories and game commands to establish themselves as authorities; some have switched careers from military training instructors and continue to enjoy the unique field control of this job in outdoor projects. more often, they act as &quot;tour guides&quot; in relaxed team-building trips. They rarely make guidance summaries, and their faces are vague in the minds of employees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In China, there is currently no unified and official professional qualification certificate for experiential trainers to enter the industry. Training institutions set entry thresholds for trainers, and they all do so in their own way. Xia Hui said that perhaps we will see many &quot;team building alliances&quot; that have introduced some trainer assessment standards, but those are all &quot;private certifications.&quot; Renzhongren&#39;s trainers will undergo half a year of training courses and half a year of internal assessment before officially taking up their posts. Mr. Hu from Shaanxi relied on his previous experience as a military training instructor and self-study online to expand his training knowledge. He was able to work directly in a company he knew well. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Wei, general manager of Shanghai Zhongji Development, feels dismayed by the uneven qualifications of trainers. &quot;Some colleagues distort experiential training into military training and devil training. It is not like this. It should be relatively mild.&quot; What he deplores even more is the loneliness of the golden age of experiential training. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When experiential training was introduced from Europe and the United States to mainland China via Hong Kong 28 years ago, it was not as notorious as it is today. At that time, it was a niche, professional, high-level industry that was easily recognized by customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To find a true etymology for experiential training, it is Outward Bound. “Outdoor Development” and “Outward Bound” were both its translation names. Overseas, its identity is not a business-oriented service, but an education model. Its predecessor was the Seamen’s School of the same name founded by German-Jewish educator Kurt Hahn in Wales during World War II. Hann believes that the one-month wilderness survival training can allow trainees to break through themselves, hone their will and form a close team bond through &quot;personal experience&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first company in China to try something new is Renzhongren. In 1995, Renzhongren introduced Outward Bound to China, turned it into a corporate training business, promoted it in China, and registered the trademark &quot;Outward Bound&quot; for it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders call the most prosperous decade of the experiential training industry at the beginning of the 21st century the &quot;Expansion Training Era.&quot; In 2004, when Lin Wei first entered the industry, experiential trainer was a profession with a halo. Most of those who came to participate in the first round of interviews with Lin Wei had a master&#39;s degree or above, including many with Ph.D.s and even university teachers who worked part-time during the winter and summer vacations. Undergraduate students with a background in education or psychology may also be selected, but it is best to have more than three years of work experience. After the first round of careful selection, the remaining 12 candidates will go to the base to receive a one-month training course. While attending class, he was eliminated. In the end, only five people were left in formal positions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;What attracted Lin Wei to join the industry was the high salary and dignity that this career brought. In 2004, the average monthly salary of a white-collar worker was around 5,000 yuan, but a Shanghai trainer who gave 15 classes a month could earn a salary of more than 20,000 yuan. A course lasts for 1-2 days, and one trainer is responsible for leading more than ten students. Whether they are ordinary employees or wealthy entrepreneurs, they all respect trainers as &quot;teachers&quot; - not through preaching, but through guidance and encouragement, allowing students to transcend previously unreachable limits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the classic project of high-altitude broken bridge, students need to climb an 8-meter-high shelf, walk on a broken narrow board, and jump from one end to the other. Of course, this is while wearing a fall arrester. Whenever students tremble at the take-off point due to fear of heights, Lin Wei would say soothing words on the edge of the bridge, teach them to take a deep breath, lower their posture, and tell them &quot;it can be done.&quot; During the review session, Lin Wei will summarize the students&#39; performance and explain the psychological mechanism behind the game, &quot;By breaking through situational pressure and expected pressure, people can get out of their comfort zone and grow.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Students and training The trainers were reluctant to leave when they left. They even cheered and threw the trainer high into the air. Lin Wei believes that &quot;obtaining such great recognition from people in such a short period of time is unmatched by other professions.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today, Lin Wei can no longer see the reverence he once had in the eyes of his students. and admiration, &quot;They no longer call trainers teachers, but &#39;coaches&#39; instead. However, this is not a position for training people&#39;s skills.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to statistics from Kanzhun.com, currently, experiential training in Shanghai The average salary of a teacher is around 13,000 yuan. Lin Wei told Southern People Weekly that most of the original batch of high-quality trainers have now switched to in-house training (a type of corporate consulting that focuses on the right medicine and focuses on theoretical explanations). What left with them was Lin Wei&#39;s enthusiasm, a passion that &quot;sees that the peers around me are all excellent and I can learn a lot from them.&quot; He doesn’t understand why fitness coaches can also be trainers. “Physical fitness is not the focus. Improving mental understanding through experience is the purpose.”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Experiential training has low investment threshold, high income, and market demand. Large, various activity courses are also easy to copy. The sinking of &quot;high-end industries&quot; has led to the industry attracting many profit-seekers, but there is a lack of internal regulatory constraints. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Customers favor fun activities and do not care about the &quot;training value&quot; behind them. To adapt to this, the proportion of business expansion training courses that require carefully designed outlines and emphasis on educational content is decreasing; the proportion of simple entertainment team building (such as simple games, fun sports, themed activities) is increasing. Entertainment team building accounts for 50% of Renzhongren’s business and as high as 70% for Zhongji. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Lin Wei pointed out that current team building is like letting participants simply watch a movie. While watching, their emotions fluctuated greatly; after leaving the theater, what happened in the dark had no impact on their future lives. &quot;Actually, the sharing session after the movie is the most valuable. The previous training was to guide the students to talk about these &#39;movie-viewing experiences&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images. infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/EsBEbeEWTuyWxB7uIFakKT3iBXPjaMjNLP8a3lAZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/09/27/EsBEbeEWTuyWxB7uIFakKT3iBXPjaMjNLP8a3lAZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252391&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On a personal level, Kang Ying The team building she participated in was regarded as &quot;the cleansing of the soul.&quot; However, she firmly believes that team building cannot bring the relationship between employees and the company closer &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Team building is not that Important&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Kang Ying, who returned from the United States six years ago, was full of child-like desire to explore when she first came into contact with team building. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After graduating from college in 1999, Kang Ying has been working in the United States. He returned to China in 2017 and worked as a director in two domestic pharmaceutical companies. In recent years, she has unlocked team building, a unique domestic employee collective activity. &quot;I think it is very fresh and fun, so I am more involved.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To this day, Kang Ying is still grateful for the desert hike two years ago. The spiritual wealth that team building brought to her. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One day, 15 kilometers, Dunhuang Gobi. For Kang Ying, who doesn&#39;t usually exercise much, this is an astronomical figure. After learning about the team building content, she almost had the idea of ​​resigning. At that time, she was pulled into a WeChat group by the service provider, which was designed to prepare for the subsequent hike. The trainer requires employees in the group to clock in and start running one kilometer every day. Mileage gradually increases until 8 kilometers per day. Colleagues check in together and encourage each other. Kang Ying gritted her teeth and persisted. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This activity even helped her develop an exercise habit. &quot;It&#39;s hard to imagine that without this group, I would be able to run 8 kilometers alone. After that, I successfully lost 20 pounds and my whole body has reversed growth. It seems that I have really developed some perseverance.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p >;The long journey in the desert exhausted Kang Ying’s physical strength gained through running, and also allowed her to experience friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The hiking activity starts at 7 a.m. and plans to cover 15 kilometers along the &quot;Xuan Zang Westbound&quot; route in 8 hours. After only 3 hours, Kang Ying could no longer move her legs. In her 46 years of life, she felt the despair of being physically exhausted for the first time. Looking up at the huge sandy slope, she paused in a daze. Suddenly a colleague&#39;s voice came from beside him: &quot;Don&#39;t think too much, step on this sand nest with your left foot, step on that one with your right foot, and climb up step by step.&quot; The other colleagues were not in a hurry and stopped to tell them Her knack for climbing. The trainer encouraged her while handing her water. The slope was finally over. The mutual-help friendship forged under difficult circumstances continues to this day. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;I thought about it afterwards, and it&#39;s the same at work. As a superior, when I need my team&#39;s subordinates to overcome difficulties, I shouldn&#39;t threaten them: If they can&#39;t do it, come see me with your head raised. . You should stand in their shoes and give more specific guidance. Even if it is as simple as &#39;step your left foot first and then your right foot&#39;.&quot; Kang Ying concluded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On a personal level, Kang Ying regards the team building she participates in as &quot;the cleansing of the soul.&quot; However, she firmly believes that team building cannot bring employees and the company closer. Effects such as &quot;strengthening employees&#39; sense of belonging to the company&quot; and &quot;deepening their recognition of corporate culture&quot;, in Kang Ying&#39;s view, are all illusions created by team-building advertisements. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If the desert team building helped the company accumulate some goodwill in Kang Ying&#39;s heart, then this goodwill has been completely lost in the lazy working environment and workplace factional struggles. Kang Ying believes that the CEO&#39;s behavior is the factor that actually affects a company&#39;s corporate culture the most. If the CEO notices that his subordinates are blaming others, but fails to stop them, blaming behavior will continue to occur in the company. Kang Ying&#39;s direct boss in the company is the general manager, but she once received a message from the human resources department: the group CEO wanted her to be his eyes and ears - to report all the general manager&#39;s activities at any time, including his private life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When she thought that the leaders might be burying spies and scheming, but the company was always happy to organize team building and create a scene of concerted efforts, Kang Ying began to question the meaning of team building itself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Also two years ago, the company failed in financing and carried out large-scale layoffs. Kang Ying lost her job. The mountains I climbed, the speeches I heard, the games I fought, and the philosophies I learned were like a dream, leaving nothing behind. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Kang Ying said that it is too reluctant to expect to gain a &quot;sense of belonging&quot; in the company through team building. If she can work in a company for more than ten years, she will naturally feel &quot;home&quot; about it. But in the past two years, she didn&#39;t know if the company would one day abandon her. A team building session cannot resolve this sense of crisis. Kang Ying believes that if employees show emotional dependence on the company, it is most likely a performance to &quot;show compliance.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sometimes, team building is not only a performance by employees to their superiors, but also a performance by the company to the outside world. A staff member of Renzhongren revealed that when many customers book experiential training services, it is more for promotional purposes. With an excellent video team, multi-camera shooting, high-end equipment, and skilled editing, team-building activities are recorded as blockbusters and become advertisements for recruiting new members. The actual feelings of the actors are not important, and it is not important whether the training purpose is achieved. What is important is to show to the outside world that &quot;this is an exciting and accomplished collective activity.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wearing a mask may be a survival rule for some people. Some people are also trying to take off their masks. In August 2023, a company in Hunan was worried that group travel would cause discomfort to some employees, so it changed the payment to 3,500 yuan per person, which can be freely disposed of; the personnel of a company in Chengdu discovered that when the boss arranged a weekend team building, no one After signing up, a full vote was initiated and the event was scheduled for Friday afternoon. They don&#39;t know yet what they will lose, but they seem to have regained a little bit of the fun they had been deprived of before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(At the request of the interviewee, Li Yang, Teacher Hu, Kang Ying, and Bobo are all pseudonyms in the article.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a >;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[许家印被采取强制措施！可能涉嫌多项罪名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257888]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 20:46:44&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; Various rumors about the current situation of Xu Jiayin, the actual controller of Evergrande Group, have finally come to light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 28, 2023, China Evergrande issued an announcement on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange stating, &quot;The company has received notice from relevant departments that Xu Jiayin, the company&#39;s executive director and chairman of the board of directors, has been detained in accordance with the law for suspected illegal crimes. Take compulsory measures. Trading of the company’s shares on the Stock Exchange will be suspended from 9:00 a.m. on September 28, 2023, and will continue to be suspended until further notice.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A criminal law expert told 21 A reporter from Century Business Herald said that the content of Evergrande Group’s announcement was very clear. According to Evergrande Group&#39;s announcement, the company should have received a definite notice, and the notice characterized Xu Jiayin as &quot;suspected of illegal crimes&quot; and compulsory measures were taken. It is common sense to guess that when there is notification from relevant departments, the coercive measures taken are likely to be different from the &quot;residential surveillance&quot; that has been misreported by overseas media. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned criminal law experts said that in the context of the early stage of the China Securities Regulatory Commission’s investigation into Evergrande Real Estate and the public security departments taking criminal coercive measures against suspected criminals such as Du Mou of Evergrande Fortune, Xu Jiayin was suspected of illegal crimes. The results should not surprise many people. Public opinion has previously focused more on “when” to take action. Judging from the current public information, the issues he is involved in are likely to be related to multiple crimes. They are very complicated and may take quite some time to clarify. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior observer in the field of corporate governance told the 21st Century Business Herald reporter that Xu Jiayin had previously publicly declared high-profile slogans such as &quot;No one is allowed to lie flat&quot; and &quot;I can have nothing&quot; in 2021, but comprehensively considering all aspects, Judging from the information and reports, in fact, Xu Jiayin and his company said one thing and did another, tried to &quot;sit down&quot; at every turn, and threw the burden of resolving various problems and contradictions on society, leaving a mess that is difficult to clean up. From this perspective, it is no exaggeration to say that public opinion criticized him verbally and writingly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The above-mentioned observers pointed out that at this cusp of great pressure from all parties, Xu Jiayin was shouting slogans to deceive creditors, but at the same time he had a &quot;silent technical divorce&quot; with Ding Yumei. Due to the agreement of Evergrande Group to be listed in Hong Kong through the &quot;small red chip&quot; structure, among the more than 90 billion Evergrande Group has previously distributed in accumulated dividends, the British Virgin Islands and Cayman Islands are 100% controlled by Xu Jiayin and Ding Yumei respectively. The offshore company received most of the dividends through China Evergrande (03333.HK), and transferred them overseas before and after the accident. Through the &quot;technical divorce&quot; operation, it eventually fell into the pocket of &quot;overseas ex-wife&quot; Ding Yumei. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A senior partner of an accounting firm who is familiar with cross-border restructuring pointed out to the 21st Century Business Herald reporter that at present, Evergrande Group’s overseas debt restructuring may be due to Xu Jiayin and some senior executives being suspected of illegal crimes. The situation faces major changes. But whether it is domestic or overseas, whether the reorganization is successful or liquidated, I believe there are sufficient legal channels for domestic and foreign creditors to safeguard their rights and interests and pursue the responsibilities of Xu Jiayin and others. At the same time, the regulatory authorities are also likely to investigate Xu Jiayin and other executives&#39; illegal violations. The crime and subsequent investigation will be investigated and held accountable in accordance with the law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 20:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[刑事自诉小慧君诽谤立案：孙灏羽的“好运”可以复制吗？丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257796]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;There is new progress in the &quot;Xiao Huijun&quot; rumor-mongering sexual assault incident. Chidu Company founder Sun Haoyu recently posted on social media that the procedural issues in his criminal private prosecution case against Xiao Huijun for defamation have been resolved and will be heard soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At the end of 2020, the well-known cross-dressing blogger &quot;Sien Xiaohuijun&quot; publicly accused her former boss Sun Haoyu of sexually harassing her online. Fortunately, Sun Haoyu later obtained evidence to prove that the so-called sexual harassment was just a rumor created by Xiao Huijun in order to terminate the contract with the company at a low cost. Including Xiao Huijun and several other contract anchors under Chidu premeditated and planned this rumor and slander incident in a group. After obtaining the evidence, Sun Haoyu filed a civil lawsuit against Xiao Huijun and others, which was supported by the court. The court clearly stated in the civil judgment that the evidence proved that the alleged sexual harassment was fiction, and ordered Xiao Huijun and others to apologize and compensate for losses to Chidu Company and Sun Haoyu. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Afterwards, Sun Haoyu filed a criminal private prosecution with the court, requesting that Xiao Huijun be held criminally responsible for spreading rumors and defamation. Initially, the court in Xiao Huijun&#39;s place of residence believed that it had no jurisdiction and ruled to dismiss Sun Haoyu&#39;s lawsuit. The higher court ruling published by Sun Haoyu this time determined that the court at Xiao Huijun&#39;s place of residence had jurisdiction and ordered the court to open the case and accept it. At this point, there is no obstacle to filing a criminal case against Xiao Huijun for defamation, and the next step will be to enter the formal trial process. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From being rumored to be sexually assaulted, to winning the civil lawsuit and the court confirming that &quot;Xiao Huijun&quot; spread the rumor, to finally filing a criminal private prosecution case, the journey has been difficult. In view of the frequent occurrence of similar rumors on the Internet, many netizens hope that Xiao Huijun&#39;s case will deter those who try to follow suit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In recent years, there have been constant incidents of accusing others of sexual harassment or even sexual assault through online essays. However, many of them are difficult to distinguish between true and false, and some have been deemed by judicial authorities as lacking evidence or even being slanderous. For example, a female employee of a well-known large factory alleged that she was raped by a male leader, but police investigation showed that there was no rape. Recently, another host was also accused of rape, and police investigations revealed that the woman suffered from schizophrenia and experienced hallucinations and delusions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For these online essays alleging sexual assault, many netizens often choose to believe the parties involved for the first time. The reason is often that &quot;women will not use their innocence to slander others.&quot; However, many facts prove that in the face of interests, nothing is impossible. For example, Xiao Huijun did not hesitate to sacrifice her &quot;innocence&quot; in order to terminate the contract with Chidu Company at a low cost. There are also some people whose motives for slander are difficult for ordinary people to understand, and they may simply have mental problems. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After Xiao Huijun accused Sun Haoyu of sexual harassment, many netizens believed it to be true. Sun Haoyu and Chidu Company were bullied online and threatened offline. The company&#39;s door and front desk were smashed many times, and people were everywhere when Sun Haoyu went out. Followed by taking pictures and cursing. An MCN organization that was originally at the top of the industry has almost come to a standstill and is now unknown in the industry. A well-known host was at the peak of his career, but after being accused of sexual harassment, he was put into hiding, and his career and reputation were ruined. Although they won the lawsuit, their careers struggled to recover. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is extremely difficult for these men who have been falsely accused to defend their reputations. In civil litigation, it is difficult to obtain evidence recognized by the court. Sun Haoyu was lucky. Someone in Xiao Huijun&#39;s &quot;Blood Battle Chidu&quot; small group found his way back and provided the chat records Sun Haoyu needed. Zhang Heng, another well-known online article author who was falsely accused of raping an underage female fan more than ten years ago, has been unable to obtain the identity of the false accuser through legal channels, let alone prosecute. The accuser just wanted to make a famous person look bad, but he &quot;hidden his fame and achievements&quot; and didn&#39;t even reveal his true identity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Even if the civil lawsuit is won, the compensation received is very little. The defendant&#39;s apology is often light and perfunctory, and the amount of communication of the apology is also very different from that of the false accusation. , it is difficult to clarify the facts and restore reputation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;To deter rumors and defamation, the rumor makers must pay a greater price, such as criminal liability. However, the criminal law stipulates that spreading rumors and defamation is generally a private prosecution crime, and the victim needs to collect evidence and file a lawsuit. It is even difficult for victims to collect evidence for civil lawsuits, and it is even more difficult for criminal evidence that requires stricter requirements than civil lawsuits. Sun Haoyu was just lucky. He got the evidence and the verdict of winning the civil lawsuit, and he had more confidence to file a criminal private prosecution. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But Sun Haoyu’s good luck is difficult to replicate. In order for those who make false accusations and framers to be punished, the threshold for turning false accusations and frame-ups into public prosecutions needs to be lowered. As long as the victim makes a complaint, the case should be turned into public prosecutions and the police will investigate the case and collect evidence. In this way, we can intensify the crackdown on rumors and slander, protect the interests of victims, and maintain online order. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[杭州亚运会：赛场内外，同样精彩]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257834]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As of 17:00 on September 27, 2023, the Chinese delegation It is far ahead in the medal list of the Hangzhou Asian Games, with a total of 124 medals, including 69 gold medals, 39 silver medals, and 16 bronze medals. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 24, 2023, Li Bingjie, who won the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle final, displayed her medal.&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;721&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 27/ea98f3aa2a.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252480&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 24, 2023, won the women&#39;s 1500-meter freestyle final championship Li Bingjie shows her medal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou will be held from September 23 to October 8, 2023, with a total of 15 competition days. The competition events of this Asian Games include 40 major events, 61 sub-events, and 481 minor events. It is the Asian Games with the largest number of events. It is worth noting that most of the non-Olympic events, which distinguish the Asian Games from the Olympic Games, originate from traditional folk sports activities and have profound&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[政府办马拉松，摊主开新店：淄博烧烤国庆“再拼一把”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257832]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;On September 13, 2023, the 4th China International Cultural Tourism Expo was held in Jinan , Zibo barbecue model is on display in the exhibition area. Visual China Picture&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/2a6b600519.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/27/2a6b600519.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;252360&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 13, 2023, the 4th China International Cultural Tourism Expo was held in Jinan, with a Zibo barbecue model on display in the exhibition area. (Visual China/Photo)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past &quot;May Day&quot; and the approaching &quot;National Day&quot;, Dr. Sun from the emergency department of Zibo Traditional Chinese Medicine Hospital went on two missions during two consecutive long holidays. In order to protect people from all over the country who came to Zi for barbecue, as a member of the city&#39;s medical security team, he stayed on duty at the makeshift barbecue city for several days during the May Day holiday. The constant flow of people made him, an &quot;Old Zibo&quot;, feel unreal. The outside world kept saying that it was going to be cold, but it was always crowded every time he passed by the popular barbecue spot Ba Daji when he went out. Just like that, half a year passed in a blink of an eye. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After this summer vacation, the streets have indeed regained some calm, but after a marathon, it is full of people again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There will definitely be a wave of traffic during the National Day holiday. This is what it means to hold a marathon at this time.” On September 24, the last weekend before the National Day holiday, this internet celebrity city held its first marathon Marathon. Just after the game ended that day, Dr. Sun gave his prediction for the passenger flow during the National Day holiday. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because it was held in Zibo, this marathon was nicknamed the &quot;BBQ Marathon&quot; by runners. “As soon as I heard it was the Zibo Marathon, I rushed (to sign up).” After getting off the high-speed train at noon on September 23, Feng Yanhua made an appointment with fellow runners to have a meal. They queued for an hour and a half, and many people in front of the store were carrying Marathon on their backs. The pre-game package looked like a contestant who stopped by for the tooth festival. &quot;Zibo people are very welcoming, and the barbecue is very affordable and delicious.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After several months of &quot;turbulent&quot; drama, Zibo Barbecue has experienced a fierce evolution from explosion to crazy expansion, and then to a brief period of calm. Many interviewees said that after the summer vacation, the market showed obvious signs of calming down. However, whether it will return to its original shape before the epidemic or maintain an average value of warm but not cool, people are still waiting and watching, and it is difficult to tell. Conclusion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the interviewees agreed that at least during this National Day Golden Week, Zibo will still see a peak of tourists. For this reason, businesses and citizens are eager to try to seize this possible &quot;last wave of traffic.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;Barbeque shop owner: Give it a try again on National Day&lt;/h4>;&lt;p>;The obvious &quot;turning point&quot; occurred after the summer vacation. &quot;You can see it all at a glance&quot; on Badaju Street, which is booming. The popularity of Zibo barbecue has dropped after half a year. &quot;It was still very busy in July and August, but after September, it subsided a bit quickly.&quot; Standing at the fork in the traffic flow, whether to advance or retreat, the owner of a barbecue restaurant in Zhangdian District, Zibo City was a little undecided. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Boss Shan’s shop was featured in the documentary &quot;A String of Life&quot;, coupled with the super popularity of &quot;Going to Zi for Barbecue&quot;, the business has been really booming for a long time. &quot;It was a bit broken at the time. There were too many people, and the whole store was spinning.&quot; He told Southern Weekend reporters that he had hired a lot more waiters, and his salary also increased from 2,800 to 3,000, and then from 3,000 to 3,500. &lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[病儿为何大额捐赠自家？儿慈会明星项目“冲配捐”调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257829]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 00:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/ image/23/09/24/928a05c694.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/ 24/928a05c694.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251850&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;In order to arouse the enthusiasm of the whole people to participate in public welfare, the organizers of 99 Charity Day They introduced matching donations. (Visual China/Picture)&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As a charity organization with strong fundraising capabilities, the China Children’s Charity Aid Foundation (referred to as the Children’s Charity Society) has recently fallen into disarray. In the midst of the donation turmoil. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In September 2023, Ke Mouxiao was accused of using the Children&#39;s Charity Society&#39;s &quot;9958 Children&#39;s Emergency Assistance&quot; project (hereinafter referred to as 9958) to defraud families of seriously ill children out of nearly 1,000 yuan. 10,000 life-saving money was detained by the police. The Children&#39;s Charity Association publicly stated that Ke Mouxiao was not its staff and had only served as a volunteer in the Hebei Langfang Team Cooperation Organization of the 9958 Project. But the controversy has not yet died down. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many parents of children who were deceived said that they participated in the &quot;matching donation&quot; initiated by Ke Mouxiao and transferred the funds to Ke Mouxiao. They expected that within a period of time Afterwards, a return higher than the principal amount will be obtained, and the excess will be donated by the enterprise. Because this kind of &quot;matching donation&quot; is a normal operation mode in the charity sector, and families of seriously ill children are accustomed to it, there is no doubt about the authenticity of the project initiated by Ke Mouxiao. (For details, please see Southern Weekly’s report &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infzm.com/contents/256685?source=131&quot;>;China Children’s Charity Association volunteers are involved in nearly 10 million yuan in aid, and families with serious illness are in trouble again. Matching donation scam&lt;/a>;》)&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;However, the &quot;matching donation&quot; that parents of children with children are accustomed to, is it a arbitrage donation in a gray area? According to relevant laws and policies, it is illegal for charitable organizations to induce parents of children with self-raised funds to participate in matching donations or donate for their own use. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Does the Children&#39;s Charity Association know about such &quot;matching donations&quot;? Southern Weekend reporters discovered that deficiencies in the management and operation of charitable organizations provide a breeding ground for the alienation of matching donations. The more money is raised, the more matching donations are made - with the same goal, the people who need the money most take their money out of their pockets, boosting the charity&#39;s fundraising figures. &lt;/p>;&lt;h4>;“Who dares to do it if you can’t get the money back?”&lt;/h4>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It’s the 99 Charity Day in September every year. Li Shan (pseudonym) from Guangxi I want to raise more life-saving money for my daughter who is suffering from leukemia. He decided to participate in &quot;matching donations.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;99 Charity Day is a national charity event jointly launched by Internet companies and hundreds of charity organizations, enterprises, and celebrities. September 9, 2015 is China’s first Internet Charity Day. In order to arouse the enthusiasm of the whole people to participate in public welfare, the organizers introduced a popular foreign method-matching donations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Matching donation is a matching donation. After a donor donates a sum of money to a charity organization, another donor (usually a company) will randomly or according to Donate a certain percentage of money to the same charity organization. The original intention of the matching donation model is to encourage the public to participate in donations. According to its original intention, the donation amount including corporate matching should not be used for the donor himself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Charity Law also clearly stipulates that when a donor and a charitable organization agree on the purpose and beneficiaries of donated property, the donor&#39;s interested parties shall not be designated as beneficiaries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But Li Shan has never heard of the above regulations. On the eve of the 99 Charity Day in 2023, Li Shan opened a &quot;Donate Together&quot; charity matching donation project for each of the three charity matching projects launched by the Children&#39;s Charity Society: &quot;Sunflower Protects Children in the West&quot;, &quot;Girls in Need Guarantee Plan&quot; and &quot;Aiding Children in Need to Dream of Going to School&quot;. ” fundraising link and named it after his daughter, who has leukemia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Donate Together&quot; is a charity game launched by Tencent Charity Platform. Users click the corresponding button on the public welfare project homepage and fill in the target amount and sponsor information to generate a link. Donors open the link and enter the amount to donate. Subsequently, this donation information and the corresponding matching donation will be recorded in the initiator&#39;s &quot;Donate Together&quot; and can be publicly queried. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to the public information and execution plan of the project, the recipients of &quot;Sunflower Protecting Children in the West&quot; are children in need in the western provinces under the age of 18. &quot;Girls in Distress&quot; The &quot;Guarantee Plan&quot; will provide long-term assistance to girls in need across the country, and the goal of &quot;Assisting Children in Need to Dream of Going to School&quot; is to allow children in need to go to school with peace of mind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I really don&#39;t understand this.&quot; On September 17, 2023, Li Shan listened to a reporter from Southern Weekend introduce the above three projects and said that he neither I don’t know who these projects are aiding, and I don’t know whether my behavior counts as a donation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But before that, in the three days from September 7th to 9th, Li Shan raised more than 210,000 yuan for these three projects through &quot;donate together&quot; , including several &quot;donations&quot; worth 3,000 yuan and 4,000 yuan. According to the rules, Tencent will donate more than 22,000 yuan to this end. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shan explained to Southern Weekend reporters that these &quot;donations&quot; were all his own money. &quot;The people who &#39;donated money&#39; were some relatives and friends. I gave the money to them first and then asked them to donate it to the project.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Li Shan said frankly , for the more than 200,000 yuan he &quot;donated&quot;, he had no intention of using it to aid children or girls in need in the west. &quot;We are all short of money ourselves.&quot; He believes that the money &quot;donated&quot; and matched by enterprises will eventually come back to him. &quot;Who dares to do it if he can&#39;t get (the money) back?&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Southern Weekend reporters found that during the three days from September 7th to 9th, a total of 12,000 people participated in the above-mentioned activities in the form of &quot;donate together&quot; For the three projects, they &quot;donated&quot; a total of more than 8.86 million yuan. Each &quot;donate together&quot; raised an average of 45,900 yuan, and the largest single &quot;donation&quot; was 10,000 yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9658c1749b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/24/9658c1749b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;251851&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A &quot;Donate Together&quot; link initiated by a parent of a seriously ill child for the project of &quot;Aiding Children in Distress to Dream of Going to School&quot;. (Internet screenshots/pictures)&lt;/p>;&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Self-raised, self-donated, self-used&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Through &quot;matching donations&quot;, the money &quot;donated&quot; can be returned &quot;with interest&quot;. Li Shan began to form this understanding in 2022. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;At that time, he was hospitalized in Dongguan with his daughter. In order to seek medical treatment for his daughter, who has not yet entered elementary school, he claimed to have spent at least 700,000 yuan in two years. He remembered that day, the patient next to him took out 2,000 yuan and asked him to &quot;donate&quot; the link he had opened for him, and at the same time answer questions to help.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[病儿为何大额捐赠自家？儿慈会明星项目“冲配捐”调查]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257801]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 19:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[电竞加入亚运会，意味着什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/257864]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Those spectators who were lucky enough to win tickets for the Honor of Kings Asian Games finals on September 26 are heading to the Hangzhou E-Sports Center Come. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;E-sports is the only competitive event in the Asian Games that requires ticket purchase by lottery. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;One hour before the start of the game, people waiting at the entrance of the e-sports center began to enter. Although two young cosplayers (cosplay enthusiasts) did not win the ticket, they still decided to stay at the entrance of the e-sports center and spend an unforgettable night watching the TV broadcast. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/oupRK0i3RNd0s4DHvrfOBnDXXiOnYwvQj7Qvj2sZ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height= &quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/oupRK0i3RNd0s4DHvrfOBnDXXiOnYwvQj7Qvj2sZ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252657&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On September 26, 2023, the final scene of the Honor of Kings Asian Games held at the Hangzhou E-sports Center. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Southern Weekend reporter Zhang Rui/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On September 25, 2023, the Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports event King of Glory Asian Games version half In the final, CCTV Sports and CCTV5+ channels broadcast the game. This is the first time that CCTV broadcasts the Asian Games e-sports competition. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Coser Yifeng is also a fan artist. She chose this job because of her interest in e-sports. &quot;Ever since (e-sports) entered Asia, I have been explaining (e-sports).&quot; Yifeng told Southern Weekend reporters that three days ago, she and her father watched the opening ceremony of the Asian Games together. When the e-sports players entered, She excitedly pointed it out to her father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The game of King of Glory is participated by two teams, red and blue, with 5 people in each team. The two teams start teamwork and competitive confrontation on the King&#39;s Canyon map. Cosplayer Lu Zhian said that people around her, including male friends who participated in youth training, were biased against the competitive strength of female players, which gave her the idea of ​​&quot;proving&quot; herself. By watching professional players&#39; e-sports competitions, she learned some game strategies and techniques, and thus improved her rank. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A male audience born in the 1980s began to pay attention to e-sports events in 2006 because of &quot;DOTA&quot;. &quot;DOTA2&quot; is one of the e-sports events at the Hangzhou Asian Games. He is also a football fan and talked to Southern Weekend reporters about the similar teamwork and competitiveness between the two, especially the thrill of a desperate comeback at the decisive moment of the game. Going into the game, he was confident of the outcome. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the evening of September 26, in the final of the Asian Games version of the e-sports e-sports King of Glory in Hangzhou, the Chinese team defeated the Malaysian team 2-0 and won the first e-sports gold medal in the history of the Asian Games, and was included in China’s Medal table. The 31 Chinese players participating this time have an average age of about 24 years old. They have played more than 11,000 games in total and have won more than 60 championship trophies in various competitions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is almost a game without any suspense. The cheers at the scene reached their peak when Chinese players appeared on the stage. They came from leagues and clubs that were more professional than their opponents. The sound of cheering accompanies every &quot;attack&quot; in the game. In the second game of the final, the Chinese team even changed players and flattened the opponent&#39;s &quot;base&quot; more cleanly and quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/Wn5XEdjfBQOfaV0ZIS9ZBKA5CRLQ7yBofH6lKUdb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1024&quot; height= &quot;683&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/09/28/Wn5XEdjfBQOfaV0ZIS9ZBKA5CRLQ7yBofH6lKUdb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;252655&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color : #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;On the evening of September 26, 2023, in Hangzhou, members of the Chinese team took the stage to greet the audience after winning the first e-sports gold medal in the Asian Games. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the first final night of the Asian Games e-sports. When the winner is decided, Hangzhou It seems that the enthusiasm in the e-sports center has not yet had time to be fully unleashed. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Sports in the Digital Age&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;E-sports has a history of at least forty years. In 1980, the &quot;International &#39;Space Invaders&#39;&quot; competition held in New York, USA, was considered the world&#39;s first formal e-sports competition. The champion at that time later became a video game programmer. With the launch of the WCG (World Electronic Sports Competition) after the millennium, Esports, or &quot;electronic sports&quot;, began to become an international event. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Xiaodong, dean and doctoral supervisor of the School of Leisure Sports and Management of Guangzhou Institute of Physical Education, told Southern Weekend reporters that in primitive society, people had invented sports activities such as running and swimming; in agricultural society, people had horse riding, bows and arrows, etc. Activities; In industrial society, people began to ride bicycles, race cars, etc.; &quot;The digital age will definitely use numbers as tools and new sports will appear.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On February 16, 2023, at the &quot;Asian Games TALK Guangzhou Station&quot; event held at the Guangzhou Library, Xu Deqing, director of the Propaganda Department of the Hangzhou Asian Organizing Committee and deputy director of the Propaganda Department of the Hangzhou Municipal Party Committee, responded to Southern Weekend Reporter’s question about e-sports. Xu Deqing believes that e-sports is a culture of youth, teamwork and innovation. &quot;E-sports is different from games. E-sports is defined as a contest of intelligence, just like chess and Go. It is a contest of intelligence.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Among the forty competition events at the Hangzhou Asian Games, e-sports are classified as &quot;intellectual events&quot; along with bridge, chess, go and xiangqi. The &quot;World Brain Games Federation&quot; once defined &quot;brain games&quot; as &quot;a sport or game that is related to the mental abilities of the participants rather than their physical advantages.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qi Xin, associate professor and master’s tutor at the Department of Physical Education and Research of Peking University, recalled a scene from 20 years ago. In 2003, the State Sports General Administration listed &quot;e-sports&quot; as the 99th official sports event in my country. At that time, e-sports was still a new thing, and she and her students discussed &quot;whether e-sports is a sport or not&quot; in class. Opponents accounted for the vast majority. In fact, it was not just e-sports, but also chess sports. These sports lacked physical movement and were not well accepted as &quot;sports&quot; at the time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the past ten years, Qi Xin has clearly felt that the outside world&#39;s perception of sports and e-sports has changed significantly. Peking University has a student-organized e-sports association, and more and more students are participating. According to Qi Xin&#39;s observation, the personal abilities of these students have been developed, such as thinking ability, reaction ability, overall view, willpower and team spirit. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A few years ago, she met a former professional e-sports player at an event. She listened to the player talk about competitions and training, and her impression of e-sports gradually changed. &quot;In addition to talent, you also need to undergo hard training the day after tomorrow.&quot; Qi Xin said that when the players compete, they are the same as traditional sports athletes. There is nothing else in front of them, only the competition, even if they encounter physical and mental problems. In the difficult situation, he will try his best to win at that moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“People are gradually realizing that competitiveness is also the core content of e-sports.” Qi Xin listed to Southern Weekend reporters, “In a game, what will be improved physically and mentally, and what will be negative? Appear? How to stimulate team enthusiasm and creativity in e-sports competitions, and cultivate the sports spirit of not admitting defeat, not being discouraged, and fighting tenaciously? These are important research topics.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qi Xin believes that if e-sports Athletes can gain a certain degree of social visibility and recognition like well-known athletes in other sports fields, and they can even participate in college teaching in the future. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from traditional domestic sports, e-sports events have always been promoted from the bottom up by game manufacturers, e-sports clubs, etc.: e-sports games appear, clubs enter, live broadcast platforms rise, and events gradually improve. Finally entered the Asian Games. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When the news of e-sports entering Asia came, Wang Guoji felt it was &quot;a bit sudden, but not unexpected.&quot; Wang Guoji is the chairman of the e-sports working committee of the China Cultural Management Association. He explained that although e-sports developed from online games, it is quite different from games: &quot;Online games and e-sports, hobbies and professionalism must be clearly understood. Be aware of it and make a clear distinction. It does not mean that today, when Hangzhou holds the Asian Games and 7 e-sports events have become official competition events, online games are fully endorsed.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&quot;We are doing A serious matter&quot;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;Industry insiders believe that the entry of e-sports into Asia will bring the e-sports industry into a more standardized direction. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qi Xin told Southern Weekend reporters that the difference between &quot;playing e-sports&quot; and &quot;playing games&quot; lies in &quot;sports rules.&quot; E-sports needs to comply with strict sports regulations. These norms are called &quot;edges and boundaries&quot; by Qi Xin to ensure that e-sports is orderly and controllable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jing, a staff member involved in the Asian Games e-sports project, said that e-sports projects are gradually becoming &quot;serious&quot;, and the competition format and rules are closer to traditional and formal sports projects. &quot;This is a problem for many manufacturers.&quot; It is a big challenge for the competition team.” In order to adapt to the rules of the Asian Games, some e-sports schedules have been changed. For example, the original five games that decided victory were reduced to three. At least three months in advance, e-sports players must start closed training and implement a diet plan to ensure that they pass doping tests. And these are still unimaginable in the league. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The rules are indeed more detailed. Sun Jing said that in 2006, the e-sports management rules totaled about 5,000 words; now, the latest version of the rules has about 120,000 words. &quot;The process of the game, various foul situations, and the details of each event are all broken down in detail,&quot; he told Southern Weekend reporters. &quot;It is still far from the rules of football and basketball, but it is already comparable to the rules of some traditional events. It&#39;s relatively close.&quot; For example, when confirming the start of the game, &quot;the rules state that within 5 minutes of the start of the game, if an irreparable bug is triggered, the game must be replayed.&quot; The industry discussed this for a long time before determining which moment should be counted. &quot;Game start&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with the relaxed age requirements for athletes in some traditional sports, such as the current Asian Games, where 13-year-old Cui Chenxi won the women&#39;s skateboarding street finals, the industry has stricter age requirements for e-sports athletes. high. For example, the Zhejiang Provincial E-Sports Association requires that to meet the requirements for registered e-Sports athletes, you must be over 18 years old, complete nine years of compulsory education, and obtain a full-time junior high school diploma or above. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters visited the Hangzhou LGD E-sports Club. Club manager Marseille said that they would not consider minors to become players. The professional age of e-sports players is between 18 and 25 years old, which means that the opportunity to become a professional player is fleeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Club professional testing often dissuades many young people with e-sports ideas. This test tests people&#39;s reaction, instant memory, hand-eye-brain coordination and other abilities through computer and equipment. After multiple rounds of tests, only six people passed all the tests, but after entering the youth training team, they still faced many difficulties. The elimination rate from the youth training to the second team is 67%, and the elimination rate from the second team to the first team is 50%. Some youth training players will leave the club and find another place if they cannot prove that they can participate in higher-level competitions within half a year. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Pan Jie, CEO of LGD E-Sports Club, said that there is a very detailed evaluation system for talent selection, which not only examines online practical performance, but also offline interviews to evaluate their realistic psychological conditions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sun Jing told Southern Weekend reporters that some e-sports events are exactly the same as traditional sports. For example, in FPS (first-person shooter) games, he noticed that players need to complete a certain amount of traditional physical exercise to train muscle reaction speed, and the concept of &quot;warm-up&quot; is also introduced. Some high-intensity games are played from morning to night. Without this foundation, it is easy to suffer from physical exhaustion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ying Shunjie is the deputy director of the Shanghai E-sports Education and Training Working Committee and has been engaged in e-sports education for many years. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the e-sports industry has always paid attention to the traditional sports industry, including the training system and management, and is learning from traditional sports. &quot;It pays attention to players&#39; mental health, injury management, daily work and rest, physical functions, etc., these are traditional Something that esports doesn’t have.” He mentioned that the past &quot;Internet cafe-style&quot; model was obviously unhealthy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pan Jie said that the great development of e-sports competitions is due to learning from the game rules, transfer rules, salary caps, etc. of mature sports leagues such as the NBA. However, in the process of learning, traditional sports rules are always &quot;acclimated&quot;, especially how to adapt the rules that serve offline to online. &quot;At the beginning, all the rules were purely competitive, and later they included some commercial terms.&quot; It has also gradually been incorporated into the club system.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Why do we have so many people organizing, media operation center, athlete village, media village, venue competition team, and referee team? Because we are doing a serious thing.&quot; Sun Jing said . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;High-intensity physical exercise, the future of e-sports? &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;On September 6, 2023, the International Olympic Committee announced the establishment of the International Olympic Committee E-sports Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“We believe that virtual sports can help promote the core values ​​of the Olympic Movement such as excellence, friendship and respect,” said IOC President Bach. “They can inspire young people around the world to participate in sports activities and have active health. lifestyle.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is worth mentioning that Bach divided e-sports into three categories: The first category is virtual reality sports, in which there are physical movements and the participants&#39; bodies are faced with (high-intensity) Sports and challenges; the second category involves esports competitions conducted under the rules of international sports federations; and the third category is broader esports. The International Olympic Committee’s priority is Category 1 admission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Guangzhou Institute of Physical Education is the first public undergraduate university in China to offer e-sports majors. Wang Xiaodong believes that e-sports is divided into competitions with physical sports and competitions without physical sports, and virtual sports refers to the former. He used simulated racing as an example. The intensity of exercise in a racing simulator is not much different from that in actual racing. They once held a simulation racing competition, and all the children participating in the competition were &quot;full of energy.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Xiaodong advocates what Bach calls virtual sports. He told Southern Weekend reporters that the school’s e-sports courses must first learn physical education, and the students are also traditional sports students. He also mentioned the difficulty of these projects. At present, the market competition acceptance of virtual sports is not too high, and the youth foundation is relatively weak. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Compared with virtual sports, non-physical e-sports events such as &quot;FIFA Online 4&quot;, &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; and &quot;League of Legends&quot; obviously have higher acceptance in the market. The e-sports events at the Hangzhou Asian Games actually cover two directions, including virtual sports events like the former and popular e-sports events like the latter. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Southern Weekend reporters learned that the current investment of domestic clubs is still in the latter, rather than traditional virtual sports projects. Pan Jie analyzed that a club’s investment project needs to consider the user base, market conditions, league system, event viewing, etc. At present, the development of virtual sports is relatively limited. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wang Guoji participated in the Olympic Esports Week held in Singapore in June 2023, and he had a deep feeling. Among the competitions held in Singapore, 9 are virtual sports, such as shooting, taekwondo, dance games, etc. that require physical participation. &quot;With the continuous advancement of electronic equipment, under the current human environment, e-sports, especially virtual sports, has become a new form of sports. This is very positive and healthy, and it also has broad development prospects in the future.&quot; Wang Guoji believes , when humans enter the digital age, some new forms of sports will be born, and they may far exceed traditional forms of sports. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For a long time, people have believed that there are some problems in non-physical sports competitions. For example, sitting for a long time without exercise is not in line with a healthy spirit. At the same time, the hidden dangers of addiction have also aggravated the concerns of the outside world. Unlike traditional sports, e-sports are likely to be influenced by game copyright owners, which also increases people&#39;s doubts about fairness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Qi Xin told Southern Weekend reporters that if e-sports is just a leisure and entertainment activity based on the original games in the future, the direction will be very limited: &quot;If in the future our e-sports is just an intellectual activity I think the challenge may become narrower and narrower. The future direction of e-sports is to develop towards sports, not just games.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;The end of the industry is culture&lt;/h4>; &lt;p >;In eighteen years of relevant industry experience, Pan Jie believes that the development of the e-sports industry has always been a &quot;step-by-step&quot; process. Its prosperity is inseparable from the huge user base, especially the enthusiasm of young people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Different from the past “rectification of names”, after the professionalization of e-sports, “persuading people to quit” has become an important matter. &quot;Many children use e-sports as an excuse to play games. In fact, they lack talent and do not work hard enough.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In 2018, e-sports was selected for the Jakarta Asian Games exhibition competition, and the Chinese team achieved two gold medals and one silver medal. On April 1, 2019, the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, the State Administration for Market Regulation, and the Bureau of Statistics officially released 13 new occupation information to the public. Among them, the new occupations related to the e-sports industry include e-sports operators and e-sports athletes. item. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;At that time, Ying Shunjie could feel the changes brought about by the 2018 Jakarta Asian Games and a series of international events on the e-sports industry. When recruiting employees in the first half of 2018, “most people who come here don’t know what e-sports is, and their levels vary.” Ying Shunjie asked them about their understanding of e-sports, and the answer they got was often related to games. Starting from the second half of the year, Ying Shunjie received more resumes, including some traditional sports practitioners who also started to join. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Ying Shunjie said that there is a huge gap in e-sports talents. “It requires practitioners to both understand the industry rules of e-sports and have good professional skills and literacy. This was very difficult before 2018. &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Four years after the Jakarta Asian Games, the &quot;2022 China E-sports Industry Report&quot; shows that China&#39;s e-sports industry revenue in 2022 will be 144.503 billion yuan, the e-sports population will be approximately 488 million, and e-sports events will be held throughout the year 108 items. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Executive Secretary-General of the Hangzhou Asian Games Organizing Committee and Deputy Mayor of Hangzhou City Chen Weiqiang admitted in an exclusive interview with the media that the more long-term consideration of e-sports&#39; &quot;entering Asia&quot; lies in the industry - &quot;entering Asia&quot; through e-sports, Drive the development of Hangzhou and the entire Chinese e-sports industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“From game planning and development to athlete training, event organization, live broadcast commentary and commentary, and big data statistics, the entire e-sports industry chain is very long and contains a lot of content.” Wang Guo Ji told Southern Weekend reporters that in addition to standardization, professionalization and internationalization, industrialization is also very important. Entrusted by the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, the E-Sports Committee has formulated national vocational skills standards for e-sports players, and related textbooks will be published soon. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pan Jie’s club once cooperated with French Ligue 1 football club Paris Saint-Germain. She told Southern Weekend reporters that when she came to Saint-Germain’s home stadium, she found that people did not necessarily go to watch football matches. , but she will definitely visit the surrounding areas of the club. This has almost become a kind of urban culture, which touched her a lot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In one issue of the 2004 TV program &quot;E-Sports World&quot; on CCTV Sports Channel, the column team compiled a sitcom. In the play, the host went to Portugal to cover the European Cup. Before leaving, he had a strange dream: some FIFA football and live football game players turned out to be the head coaches of the 16 national teams in the European Cup...&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;This is a &quot;prophecy&quot; from twenty years ago. At the 2023 Hangzhou Asian Games, eight e-sports events including &quot;FIFA Online 4&quot; have become official competition events of the Asian Games. From September 24 to October 2, the Hangzhou Asian Games e-sports competition will produce a total of 7 gold medals. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;(Yifeng, Lu Zhian, and Sun Jing are pseudonyms.)&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>