<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[不在职业资格目录中的“律师经纪人”，3860元拿证]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260871]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 20:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Lawyers and brokers&quot; have appeared in many lawsuits related to contract disputes. (People Visual courtesy)&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;764&quot; data -src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f3e9515ac0.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258743&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Lawyers and brokers&quot; appear in many lawsuits related to contract disputes. (Photo provided by People’s Vision)&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 14, 2023, a recommendation letter issued by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association was circulated in the legal community. The letter showed that the association recommended a &quot;lawyer broker&quot; to the Haicheng City People&#39;s Court as a litigation agent in a loan dispute case. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the letters of recommendation were made public, many lawyers posted on social media to express concerns that lawyer brokers might corrupt the industry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;Lawyer broker&quot; is not the first time that &quot;lawyer broker&quot; has appeared. With this keyword, 27 civil and enforcement cases can be retrieved on the Judgment Document Network. Among them, 24 cases in which lawyers and brokers acted as litigation agents were heard by courts at all levels in Liaoning Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It is certain that lawyer brokerage should be a job type &quot;created&quot; by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association. The association recommends others as litigation attorneys in the name of social groups. However, relevant legal persons pointed out that the operations of the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association violated relevant legal regulations, and there are no occupations related to &quot;lawyer brokerage&quot; in the national professional qualification catalog. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After this matter was fermented in the legal community, the local lawyers association issued a reminder: Lawyers discovered the problem of &quot;lawyer agents&quot; and &quot;legal agents&quot; when performing their duties. You should raise objections to the case-handling agency where you are located, and do not participate in the operations of relevant companies or institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;For each case represented, 500 yuan is required to be paid to the association&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left; &quot;>;In past cases, &quot;lawyer brokers&quot; mainly appeared in insurance disputes, contract disputes, and private lending disputes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a motor vehicle traffic accident liability dispute ruled by the Yuhong District People&#39;s Court of Shenyang City in March 2023, Xiao drove a passenger car and rode an electric bicycle and ran a red light. Yang Mou collided, causing Yang to be injured. Yang then sued Xiao and the two insurance companies that Xiao insured, demanding various compensations totaling about 250,000 yuan. Both of Yang&#39;s litigation attorneys are &quot;lawyers and agents.&quot; In the end, the Shenyang Yuhong District Court ordered the insurance company to pay compensation of about 120,000 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In a contract dispute with the case number (2022) Liao 14 Min Zhong No. 1093, Yang and Liu signed a tableware factory transfer agreement, stipulating that Yang A certain person paid the transfer fee of RMB 170,000 in installments, but after the first payment period expired, Yang did not pay as agreed. Liu then sued Yang to perform the contract and pay liquidated damages, totaling about 200,000 yuan. Yang lost the case and appealed to the Huludao Intermediate People&#39;s Court, entrusting a &quot;lawyer agent&quot; to serve as his litigation agent. The Huludao Intermediate People&#39;s Court did not support Yang&#39;s appeal, and the second instance upheld the original verdict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The similarity between these cases is that the &quot;lawyers and brokers&quot; who represent the cases come from the same social organization: the Lawyers and Brokers Special Committee of the Liaoning Brokers Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The National Social Organization Credit Information Disclosure Platform shows that the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association was registered and established in 2007. Its supervisory unit is the Liaoning Provincial Supply and Marketing Cooperative Federation, and its business scope In order to guide the work of the brokerage industry in the province, organize broker business training and provide legal, policy, information consulting services, etc. to brokers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The Special Committee for Lawyers and Brokers is a subsidiary organization of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association. The association stated in the &quot;Instructions for the Liaoning Provincial Broker Qualification Certificate&quot; that, Possessing the Liaoning Provincial Broker Qualification Certificate can solve the problem of agency litigation qualification: you only need to pay 3,860 yuan once, and you can obtain the certificate after training and examination. &quot;You can pass the test without a legal basis.&quot; After that, you can act as an agent in civil litigation in Liaoning Province. cases, and engage in related activities such as appearing in court to respond to lawsuits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In addition, those who have obtained the broker qualification certificate need to pay 500 yuan to the association to issue a recommendation letter for each case they represent. In addition, the broker&#39;s qualification certificate needs to be inspected every year, and the fee is 50 yuan. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Obviously different from citizen agents&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Lawyer broker The events have once again put citizen agency in the spotlight. However, attorney-broker representation cases initiated by the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association are significantly different from normal citizen representation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Before the amendment of the Civil Procedure Law in 2012, the law allowed three categories of citizens to represent civil litigation cases: close relatives of the parties, relevant social groups or employees of the unit where they work. persons; other citizens entrusted by the parties concerned and approved by the People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wu Zhiwei, deputy director of the Supreme People&#39;s Court Applied Law Research Base of Southwest University of Political Science and Law, said that the quality of citizen agency services is poor, fees are irregular, and it is easy to breed judicial rent-seeking, Regarding issues such as bribing judges, when the Civil Procedure Law was revised in 2012, &quot;other citizens permitted by the court&quot; were deleted, and the scope of citizens as entrusted litigation agents was limited to two categories: close relatives or staff of the parties; communities where the parties are located, Citizens recommended by units and relevant social groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Further requirements for community recommendation can be found in the interpretation of the Supreme People&#39;s Court on the application of the Civil Procedure Law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;It stipulates that if relevant social groups recommend citizens to serve as litigation agents, the groups should be non-profit legal persons registered and established in accordance with the law. The principal shall be a member of a social group, or the domicile of one of the parties shall be in the area of ​​activity of the social group. In addition, the recommended person should also be the person in charge of the society or a staff member who has a labor relationship with the society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Compared with relevant regulations, Wu Zhiwei believes that strictly speaking, the behavior of the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association violates the provisions of Article 87 of the Judicial Interpretation, &quot;These people do not Qualified to act as an agent in legal matters.&quot; The agency affairs must fall within the business scope specified in the articles of association of the social group. The business scope of the broker association is generally related to brokers. However, judging from the currently public judgment documents, the client in the case is not Brokers, &quot;If brokers have relevant civil disputes, they act as litigation agents, which is in compliance with the regulations.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another question is whether social groups can provide paid services. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;As early as 1993, the Ministry of Justice issued the &quot;Reply on Individual Citizens Not to Engage in Paid Legal Services Without Approval&quot; which explicitly required that citizen agents No remuneration can be collected. According to relevant regulations, travel expenses in citizen representation can be reimbursed by the parties. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;But lawyers and brokers obviously charge fees. On November 14, 2023, the verdict of a contract dispute in Liaoning Province was circulated in the lawyer community: a lawyer and agent was sued by the client for failing to perform his obligation to appear in court in a previous divorce lawsuit, and requested the return of 5,000 yuan in legal services. fee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The &quot;Tips for Social Organizations to Carry out Legal Service Activities&quot; issued by the Social Organization Administration Bureau of the Liaoning Provincial Department of Civil Affairs on March 22, 2023 has mentioned that individual Social organizations illegally recommend citizens to act as agents in lawsuits and seek unfair economic benefits. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This reminder sheet mentions that in accordance with relevant regulations, law-related social organizations strictly implement a management system with dual responsibilities between the registration management agency and the business supervisory unit. Social organizations shall carry out activities in accordance with the purposes and business scope stipulated in their articles of association and shall not engage in for-profit business activities. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Not in the National Vocational Qualification Catalog&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although Liaoning Province The Brokers Association has issued lawyer broker qualification certificates to many people, but the profession of &quot;lawyer broker&quot; is not included in the &quot;National Vocational Qualification Catalog&quot; announced by the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security in 2021. The professional qualifications stipulated in this catalog all specify the implementing departments or units, and require that no other institution or unit can set up professional qualifications for implementation on its own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, a reporter from Southern Weekend called Chen Wencheng, president of the Liaoning Provincial Broker Association, on related issues. He first stated that he could only undertake work in Liaoning Province. However, he later stated that he currently does not directly engage in civil litigation, nor does he engage in lawyer-broker-related business. As of press time, the association’s official website is no longer displayed properly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 16, Southern Weekend reporters called the Liaoning Provincial Department of Justice several times. The operator said they did not know anything about &quot;lawyers and brokers&quot; and that they could consult the local authorities for specific information. Lawyers Association. Southern Weekend reporters called the Liaoning Provincial Lawyers Association several times but received no reply as of press time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;According to upstream news reports, relevant staff of the Liaoning Provincial Department of Civil Affairs responded that they would investigate the situation related to the Liaoning Provincial Brokers Association. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On November 15, 2023, the Beijing Tongzhou District Lawyers Association issued a reminder that if lawyers discover problems with &quot;lawyer agents&quot; and &quot;legal agents&quot; when performing their duties, , you should raise objections to the case-handling agency where you are located, and do not participate in the operations of &quot;legal brokers&quot;, &quot;lawyer brokers&quot; and other related companies and institutions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In Liaoning Province, Fushun Civil Affairs Bureau, Tieling Civil Affairs Bureau and other agencies have issued similar reminders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 20:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[美国人的家当]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260692]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 19:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Since 2003, I have been shooting the &quot;Inheritance&quot; series 20 years, a total of 148 works. I moved a family&#39;s belongings stored in different spaces into the same space and posed for photos with their owners, most of which were taken outdoors with the home as the backdrop. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;90% of my past works were shot in China. It was a period of rapid economic development and modernization and globalization in China. I used this special Recorded by posing, the real internal space is briefly exposed in the external space, combining the changes in the current environment, urban expansion, technological development, and changes in people&#39;s lifestyles to create a dynamic social picture with static documentary . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2022, I started photographing American families. Home is the smallest unit that makes up society, and many such units make up the entire society. I continue to use the &quot;Household Possessions&quot; series to reflect the internal structure and diversity of contemporary American society. I have observed that the basic material living standards of American families, regardless of urban or rural areas, are not much different, so I pay more attention to showing their spiritual attributes. I spend a long time preparing for each photo, learning the characters’ stories in advance, visiting their rooms, thinking about the purpose of the shoot, and carefully selecting items for display. The choice of family covers both native Americans and immigrants who miss their hometown, as well as concepts about love, career, identity and gender, and the passage of time. The objects in each picture have been carefully arranged, using materials to reflect spiritual life. I moved these spiritual items in space and placed them in the same picture to visually enhance the common scenes. , highlighting the current living conditions, beliefs and emotional memories of this family or individual, and using a photo to outline a combination of reality and the spiritual world. Readers can directly think through the photos and their stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Thank you so much to the families who were willing to face my camera, show off their possessions, and share their stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Whitney Jensen August 2022&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ 16/cbb711c0c3.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/cbb711c0c3.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258478&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Whitney Jensen August 2022&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Whitney Jensen, 36 years old. She was a very cheerful and enthusiastic woman who was born and raised in Galesburg, Illinois, USA. She traveled to Iowa, fell in love and got married while traveling, and worked in the hospitality industry for many years. When the marriage ended and the coronavirus pandemic hit, she moved to Peoria, found work as a photographer, and was profiled in magazines while taking pictures in the park. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She currently works as a salesperson in a BMW store. She also enjoys interior design and creates small art installations of her own. In addition to her job at the BMW store, she has other part-time jobs, including helping out at a non-profit organization and performing poetry readings every Thursday night at the Contemporary Arts Center. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Many of Whitney&#39;s belongings come from family members, such as her grandma&#39;s antique box and her cousin&#39;s old sofa who was shot. She is full of affection for these items and is closely related to her. A friend who she grew up with gave her an owl necklace with her first month&#39;s salary, and she has been collecting all kinds of owls ever since. Her name Whitney itself means wise owl, which was the name given to her by her aunt. She was born during the era when singer Whitney Houston was most popular. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;George, the Shoeshine Man February 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/bef1b74cca.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/bef1b74cca.JPG &quot; data-key=&quot;258479&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;George, the Shoeshine Man February 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;George Manias, 92, celebrated his 76th working anniversary with friends, family and customers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He has worked for U.S. Presidents Gerald Ford, Ronald Reagan, George W. Bush, Bill Clinton, Barack Obama and Joe Biden, every Illinois governor since 1952, every Peoria mayor since 1957 and many celebrities, diplomats and businessmen have polished their shoes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 1931, George was born in Peoria, Illinois, USA. His parents were Greek immigrants. When he was four, he returned to his parents&#39; native island of Crete, which the Nazis had occupied. George was captured and forced to carry water for the Germans barefoot and starve. After World War II, George and his family returned to Peoria in 1946 penniless. At the age of 15, George began working as a shoeshine boy to earn money to help his family. Through hard work, George used the money he saved to buy a store named &quot;George&#39;s Shoe Shine and Hat Shop.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;George won many honors and medals, and his decades of hard work were praised by visitors from around the world. George treated everyone equally, and treated shoes regardless of whether they were high or low. He rubbed shoe polish on the leather with his bare hands. As for other secrets, he thought it was too early to reveal them now. Every January 1st, George would write the year on a brick for good luck. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Now he works four hours a day, five days a week, and his 86-year-old brother Manny accompanies him every day. He considers the chairs in this room to be his most important possession; it is a place where he meets people and unites the community. In addition to his shoe polishing tools, there are photos of him with six U.S. presidents and dignitaries. George never married. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Colleen Johnson June 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 5d4803a8f6.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/5d4803a8f6.JPG&quot; data- key=&quot;258480&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Colleen Johnson June 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text -align: left;&quot;>;Colleen, 58 years old, her husband passed away due to illness a few years ago and currently lives alone. She works as the director of development for a software, website design and networking company in downtown Peoria. She was often active in events commemorating historical events, particularly the abolitionist movement and the Civil War, and she spoke on behalf of racial equality. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Colleen loves old furniture and heirloom items, some of which are Asian antiques from her grandmother&#39;s collection. She loved bringing nature into the house and collected art and decorations mostly related to plants and animals. Her decorations are often paired, with lotus, leaves, and bird elements recurring, and the green plants and flowers she raises are also often paired. She likes to keep and recall beautiful things. Among these souvenirs are the dolls handmade by her grandmother, the quilts made by her mother, and the shirts of her late husband. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Colleen is a mother and grandmother in life. Her son and daughter-in-law live in another city 90 minutes away. Their daughter is 3 years old. There is also a son on the way. Colleen has an adorable Yorkshire terrier named Toto who enjoys the joy of a new life. Colleen enjoys walking and exercising by the river and participating in sailboat racing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She has just started a new relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Prasanna Jeer 2023-4&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/ 536232ce15.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;807&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/536232ce15.JPG&quot; data- key=&quot;258481&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Prasanna Jeer April 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot; text-align: left;&quot;>;Prasana Gill and his wife Lavanya are from Chennai, South India. After completing his education and working in India for several years, he came to India 13 years ago with many dreams and hopes. U.S. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Prasana is an IT employee who works for Caterpillar. He dances every day after work. Dance carries his passion and dreams. He founded two dance schools in his spare time, teaching traditional Indian dance and Bollywood dance. In the past seven years, he has had more than 100 students. Prasanna and his students have become the centerpiece of major festivals in Peoria. As a mainstay, they also perform voluntarily for charity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Some of Prasanna’s dance items were brought from India, and some were handmade by them. Their daughters, Oviya and Iniya, learned to dance at an early age, and dance was an integral part of this Indian family&#39;s life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Prasana said that he has realized his dream in the United States and is grateful to the people who gave him the opportunity. He is willing to use his own strength to repay the community and use dance to People connect, share joy, share love. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Alexander Martin May 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f7e76b5835 .JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/f7e76b5835.JPG&quot; data-key =&quot;258482&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Alexander Martin May 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align : left;&quot;>;Alexander Martin is an artist, performer, educator, and community advocate. Born and raised in the Appalachian Mountains of West Virginia, she moved to Illinois about 9 years ago to pursue a graduate degree and has lived here ever since. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She strives to exist authentically, powerfully and joyfully in this space, and her works give her such a platform. It also allows her to share personal narratives and stories of her community and celebrate their existence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;This home is the first house she has ever owned and is a very important space to her. She wanted the house to be a refuge, a safe space of existence, a space of joy, a sacred place of relaxation and happiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Fashion and clothing play an important role in her life. From performance outfits to everyday wear, she dresses and embellishes with meaning, and it&#39;s important to her to have a variety of items to create her looks. It’s her way of expressing and living authentically every day. She truly believes that being an artist is not just about the work you create, but also about how you live your life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Meng Li &amp;amp; Chunhui Pan April 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/d4a15b82ec.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/d4a15b82ec .JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258483&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Meng Li &amp;amp; Chunhui Pan April 2023 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Pan Chunhui studied abroad after graduating from Peking University, and stayed in the United States to work after graduating with a doctorate. He is a very representative student who was one of the top Chinese students to study abroad. He has been working for Caterpillar, a Fortune 500 company, and has lived in the United States for 31 years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The hostess Li Meng also had a similar experience. After getting married, she gave up her nine-to-five job, but spent a lot of time as a volunteer, and was especially keen on publicity. Chinese culture. She is a board member of Global Fest and the person in charge of the Chinese booth, and she also appeared in the Chinese Spring Festival Gala performances. Much of the furniture, household items and decorations were brought over from China and stayed with them for many years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The calligraphy work &quot;Home&quot; they held in their hands was made with their parents when they got married. Each of them wrote one or two strokes with a brush to form This &quot;home&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Burt Raabe &amp; Lisa Raabe April 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms /medias/image/23/11/16/61ddc6fa3c.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/61ddc6fa3c.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258484&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Bert and Lisa Rabe (Burt Raabe &amp;amp; Lisa Raabe) April 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Burt and Lisa Raabe have been married for 20 years and have lived in this house 10 years. Lisa grew up in northwestern Pennsylvania and graduated from the Art Institute of Chicago. She holds a master&#39;s degree in art therapy from Illinois State University and has been involved in counseling for 15 years, as well as being a yoga teacher. She is now a full-time artist and holds an MFA from Bradley University. Her work has been exhibited throughout the Midwest and she has received several awards. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Bert&#39;s great-grandfather came to the United States from Germany to farm in 1867. He grew up in Walnut City, Illinois, and graduated from Bradley University in 1968. , served in the Peace Corps in India as a welder, consultant and mentor. He now writes poetry and has published two books of poetry, several of which have also been published in magazines. Bert and Lisa enjoyed traveling and made many trips to India. In the United States, they love Chicago, Washington, D.C., and Myrtle Beach. They prefer taking trains to flying or driving. Many of the items in the photos are materials Lisa used for her artwork; there are also items from both homes and second-hand stores. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mae &amp;amp; Jonathan Wright June 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23 /11/16/4913f98a0a.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/4913f98a0a .JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258485&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Mae &amp;amp; Jonathan Wright June 2023 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;May is the executive director of the Central Illinois Arts Partnership and the public history coordinator and affiliated faculty member at Bradley University. She received her master&#39;s and doctoral degrees in theology from the University of Edinburgh in Scotland, where she studied changes in ancient Greek religious manuscripts over time. She returned to Peoria, Illinois, in 2013, and subsequently fell in love with and married Jonathan. Jonathan is a writer, editor, communications expert, vinyl DJ, and veteran of the Peoria music scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Jonathan owns more than 10,000 vinyl records; May collects art from local artists; and they both have extensive book collections. Jonathan reads mostly nonfiction. In the early years of their relationship, May was more oriented towards academic/ancient Greek books, and religious studies, but in recent years she has begun immersing herself in novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;They have three cats named Luna, Hermione and Frega, but the larger family is the community. They spend a lot of time doing volunteer work. May is a member of the Central Illinois Women&#39;s Foundation and the City of Peoria&#39;s Public Art Advisory Committee, as well as a member of the Central Illinois Animal Welfare Grants Committee. Jonathan serves on the steering committees of the Peoria Symphony, the Central Illinois Jazz Society, the Turner Center for Entrepreneurship Advisory Council at Bradley University, and the Peoria City/County Racial Justice and Equity Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Their house tells the story of their time as a couple. It was an old house built in 1913 and needed a lot of maintenance when they purchased it. Jonathan and May gradually transformed it into a beautiful space that they never wanted to leave. The tree in the front yard was planted by them as a couple and has grown with their marriage. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Erica Pamson May 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/e6cf25f6a1.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/e6cf25f6a1.JPG &quot; data-key=&quot;258486&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Erica Pamson May 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Erica, 29, just completed her BA in Art Therapy at Millikin University in Decatur, IL, and will be attending Lesley University in Cambridge, MA to study Expression Graduate programs in healing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She is also a circus juggler, visual artist, and performance artist. On stage she is known by the name Hexli. She performs throughout the United States and her work combines different types of performance arts, including butoh, juggling, fire dance, ritual bodywork, and live painting. The &quot;Hexli&quot; tapestry is her personal vaudeville flag, a hand-sewn gift from her friend and well-known actor The Enigma, who also gave her the stage name. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She has lived in this apartment for two years. Her home contains many performance costumes and props, as well as completed and in-progress paintings. This home was her first place that was truly her own, and she felt extremely grateful for the opportunity to grow and create in this space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Neng Wang &amp;amp; Lucy Feng April 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/6ba90c1112.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/6ba90c1112. JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258487&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Neng Wang &amp;amp; Lucy Feng April 2023&lt;/ p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Wang Neng and Feng Luxi are a pair of first-generation immigrants born in the 1980s from mainland China. I have been in the United States for more than ten years, and I have gone through many obstacles all the way, first studying and then working, and moving several times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The two met through church activities in different cities, fell in love and got married, and now live in the small town of Peoria, Illinois. People also accumulate some belongings of their own. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Kirk Perry &amp;amp; Barbie Perry May 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/ medias/image/23/11/16/a7a5fc9eb1.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/16/a7a5fc9eb1.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258488&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Kirk Perry and Barbie Perry Perry &amp;amp; Barbie Perry) May 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Barbie was born into a white Midwestern family. Her parents both experienced the Great Depression. Her father was a German prisoner of war for 18 months during World War II, and the war had a devastating impact on him and the entire family. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Barbie experienced domestic violence, mental illness, drug and alcohol problems, and was hospitalized multiple times for suicidal ideation. The lack of structure in her life and inability to seek help led to a difficult life throughout her childhood and into her twenties. She gave birth to her daughter Stephanie and was a single mother for 13 years. My daughter has had 15 surgeries since she was 1 year old. The birth of her daughter became a turning point in Barbie&#39;s life, and she began to save herself through various therapies. She was able to finish school and find work, working in a variety of jobs including ice cream server, retail salesperson, waitress and more. This difficult life ended when Barbie met Kirk Perry in 1997 and married him a year later. Since then, with love and a patient ear, Barbie has lived a beautiful, fulfilling, and loving life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Kirk Perry is a retired criminal intelligence analyst who worked for the Illinois State Police. He holds an associate&#39;s degree in criminal justice, a bachelor&#39;s degree in administrative justice and a juris doctorate. In his career of more than thirty years, he not only solved many criminal cases and sent many bad guys to prison. He fell in love with books at the age of six and never stopped reading. He has a collection of over 10,000 comic books. Barbie has been making art since 2015, all about feminism, while Kirk has written three novels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;For the couple, the Barbie collection is a testament to their love. During their marriage, Barbie and Kirk have had seven dogs, with Biscuit being their current favorite. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;Brandie Centi-Fislar August 2023&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias /image/23/11/16/9294743f69.JPG&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;810&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11 /16/9294743f69.JPG&quot; data-key=&quot;258489&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Brandie Sendy-Fislar Centi-Fislar) August 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Brandy Centi-Fislar, 31, from Clearfield, Pennsylvania, High School Class of 2010 After graduation, she enrolled at Lincoln College in Lincoln, Illinois, on swimming and soccer scholarships. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In 2012, she earned an associate degree in art and transferred to Illinois State University in Normal, IL to begin her art studies. She began with an art education and later switched professions to glassblowing. At the same time, she began dating her now-husband. Over the next 10 years, she and her husband completed their bachelor&#39;s degrees together and worked multiple jobs in an effort to stay financially stable. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After a lot of good times and some bad times, they now have a dream house filled with their fur babies (three dog and two cats) to enjoy life with less stress. She still blows glass full-time and enjoys being creative every day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“从深度和广度推动中新合作” | 亚太群英荟]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260859]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 18:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;According to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, on November 1, 2023, Assistant Minister of Foreign Affairs Nong Rong and the Ministry of Trade and Industry of Singapore Permanent Secretary Lin Mingliang held the China-Singapore Bilateral Cooperation Mechanism Senior Officials&#39; Meeting via video link. In March this year, Singaporean Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong visited China, and China-Singapore relations were upgraded to a comprehensive, high-quality, forward-looking partnership. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Taking the opportunity to take China-Singapore cooperation to a new level, Southern Weekend researchers interviewed Professor Liu Hong, Associate Vice President of Nanyang Technological University in Singapore. As an alumnus of Xiamen University and Fudan University, Liu Hong has studied and worked in many countries in Asia, North America, and Europe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Liu Hong said that in the past ten years or so, he has noticed from his teaching, research and management work that the relationship between China and Singapore is showing several characteristics: all-round, advancing with the times and high quality. . From the early days of China learning from Singapore, it has now become a two-way trend of learning from each other and learning from each other. As China -Singapore relations have entered a new stage of development, Nanyang University of Science and Technology has also continuously improved the level of cooperation projects, and further promotes friendliness and cooperation between Singapore and China in terms of depth and breadth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img alt = &quot;Liu Hong&quot; src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/cac4375609.png&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; width = &quot;1080&quot; height = &quot;1544&quot; data-src = &quot;// Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/cac4375609.png&quot; data- key = &quot;258735&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; Liu Hong &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; Photo of Lou Xiaoxi &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Go to China, it is better to see it &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt; Strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; You have studied and worked in universities in many countries in the world, and you feel that Chinese students and students from other countries in other countries What are the characteristics? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The general characteristics of students in mainland China are very diligent and easy to learn. There are more than 10 million college students who graduate each year, and the competition is very large. Among college students in various countries I have contacted, Chinese students can be said to be a leading degree. This is because the Chinese nation has a tradition of learning learning, but on the other hand, it is also because social competition is becoming more and more intense, so everyone has to stand out. College students&#39; employment is a big challenge. Chinese students are very concerned about the development of the world, and they also have a strong willingness to study abroad. I studied in the Netherlands and the United States, and then worked in Singapore and Britain. I spent almost two years at Kyoto University and Osaka University in Japan. I think the characteristics of Chinese students&#39; diligence and learning are very obvious. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What do you think is no more than Eastern and Western educational systems? Same? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; I have studied in the Netherlands for more than a year and studying in the United States for more than five years. Western countries have a tradition of knowledge pursuing knowledge. It does not take the test results as the main goal, but a relatively scattered, diverse goal. Students choose some subjects based on their own interests, so they will look at some problems diversified and multi -angle, but I think Western education has a greater flaw -lack of understanding of developing countries including China. Recently, some scholars have analyzed that in the textbooks and related papers of international political economics in the 2010s, the proportion of China does not account for only 11%, which is a small proportion; but China is now the second largest economy in the world Its total GDP has been close to about 20%of the world. It can be seen that the knowledge of China in university textbooks is very lacking. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; How to let the West better understand China through education to better understand China in China ? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; During my tenure in the UK, I organized hundreds of college students from different universities in the UK to do it in China for two weeks to three to three. Zhou&#39;s study and immersion, I named this project &quot;Experience a Dynamic China&quot;. Many British people have a lack of understanding of China and outdated, and most of them are seen in books. Through we organize them to different cities such as Beijing, Shanghai, Nanjing, Guangzhou, and Jinan, to different places (including rural areas), let them feel a changing and developing China. I think that in international education and exchanges, we can have more Chinese stories and more Chinese voices. One of the sources is to let foreigners feel themselves. The feedback from these participants in these immersed activities is that after many people go back, they have said that the impression of China has almost changed dramatically. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>; Scientific research results landing Greater Bay Area &lt;/h4>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, Kai style_GB2312, Stkaiti &quot;>; How does Nanyang University of Science and Technology in the Guangdong -Hong Kong -Macao Greater Bay Area cooperation? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; The Greater Bay Area is now the most potential area in China. Singapore and China have established China -Singapore Guangzhou Knowledge City. Our university has established the China -Singapore International Institute with Knowledge City and South China University of Technology. In addition to the combination of industry -university -research, Knowledge City also arranges some government officials to come here to train. I am currently hosting a research project that improved and improved the business environment entrusted by the Guangzhou Development Zone and China New Knowledge City. We hope that when it comes to China&#39;s development, it is not to talk about the soldiers on paper, but to have a understanding of China&#39;s latest development, and then connect China&#39;s development with the development of the world. In this process, what useful experience can Singapore be provided? How to make progress together? In fact, the purpose of our project is to promote friendly relations between Singapore and China, ASEAN and China. This big goal is the direction of my colleagues and my colleagues. This is also the main goal of creating &quot;Singapore-China Intellectual Hub&quot;, the new principal of Nanyang University of Technology, recently proposed to create &quot;Nanyang University of Technology Singapore-China Intellectual Hub&quot;. Whether it is the Singapore Government or Nanyang University of Technology, they are very concerned and attached great importance to the development of the Greater Bay Area. For example Big background in the rapid development of the Greater Bay Area. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What are the plans for cooperation? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Whether in Guangzhou, Hong Kong, or Shenzhen, we have many cooperation with the future. For the training of talents, we also pay special attention to the combination of production, research and research. New China relations are more about mutual learning, borrowing from each other, and advancing with the times. Our main purpose is to transform the latest scientific research results from all over the world, especially Singapore, to the fertile soil in the Greater Bay Area, and take root and promote it. This is why we set up an international joint research institute in Guangzhou, and why in the cooperation with Shenzhen, a very important point is innovation. Singapore and Shenzhen focus on the establishment of a series of new development of smart cities and digital economies. Shenzhen leads not only China, but also leading the world. We have always cooperated with universities in the Greater Bay Area. Exchange and scientific research cooperation with Hong Kong universities will further deepen. In the future, our Nanyang Public Management Graduate School may further increase talent training in Guangzhou and Shenzhen. Shenzhen is more and more concerned about ASEAN. Of course, ASEAN can also use the platforms of Shenzhen or Guangdong to further develop. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot;>; What can I learn from each other? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Our research pays special attention to Asian public governance. Some theories, experiences and models of the entire global public governance are now based on Western experience. We hope to explore the experience of these countries through in -depth analysis of the development of Singapore and China and the development models of other ASEAN countries, and analyze what they will help for global public governance theory and practice. We have a lot of research projects, including focusing on the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; as a new model of cross -border governance, and focus on mutual learning and reference between Asian countries and African countries. In the context of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, Chinese companies &quot; &quot;Going out&quot; and different modes of cooperation with other countries are several research priorities of myself and our college. We hope to continue to connect with the Chinese government, state -owned enterprises or universities in the future. As Sino -new relations have entered a new stage of development, we are constantly improving the level of the project, and further promoting friendly cooperation between Singapore and China in terms of depth and breadth. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;文明对话的精髓&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot; >; What do you think of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative? What are the focus of future development? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; This year is the 10th anniversary of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative, which is a very important development milestone. In the past few months, I have been invited to give a speech about the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; in less than 10 times. It can be seen that different countries in the world are very concerned about the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, although their starting points are different. The &quot;five -pass&quot; in the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative includes the communication between the people and the communication of the policy. These are the two aspects that our college and I am very concerned about. I regard the popularity of the people in the &quot;Five Links&quot; as a software; infrastructure construction, trade, and investment are hardware. The hardware and software must be organically combined to play the best role. In the future development, on the one hand, we must think about how to further enhance the quality and influence of the “Belt and Road” project based on the achievements that have achieved in these 10 years, including focusing on the digital economy, green development, and public health. It will become the focus of the future development of the “Belt and Road”. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Southern Weekend: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span style = &quot;font-family: regular body, regular body_gb2312, stkaiti;&quot; In terms of, what role can they play? &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Liu Hong: &lt;/strong>; &lt;span>; Chinese culture &quot;go global&quot; to perform civilized dialogue, we need to further develop. In the process, young people from China, as well as Chinese state -owned enterprises, Chinese researchers, college teachers, etc., all played an important role. I think that in the future development, it is important to grasp the essence of the development of Chinese culture, including some characteristics of Chinese cultural traditions: to keep the right and obey the old, and to be retro. First of all, you must understand your own culture, have the root of your own culture, and then talk to other cultures. Secondly, we must look at other cultures with an equality, tolerance, openness, and respect. In terms of culture, the culture of each country has its own characteristics and advantages, and it is a product in the environment of different countries. We should be in an attitude of understanding and respect. this way? Only by understanding and communication can we truly &quot;go global&quot;. Third, we must pay attention to innovation. Whether it is Chinese culture or other countries culture, it must reflect the development characteristics of the new era, including the era of the fourth industrial revolution we are now, the era of globalization and adverse globalization Global geopolitics has also changed a lot. Under such circumstances, the creative transformation of Chinese culture and world culture should be seen to achieve more effective dialogue. The &quot;global development initiative&quot; and &quot;global civilization initiative&quot; proposed by the Chinese government provided Chinese wisdom for the development of the world. Chinese wisdom has a very deep connotation, but in the way of communication and communication, we still have more room for effort to let countries around the world understand the essence of Chinese culture. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 18:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一中学发生拥挤踩踏事件：改善硬件设施与提高管理水平当双管齐下丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260863]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-18 17:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Campus accident casualties together. On November 14, 2023, the People&#39;s Government of Wudi County, Henan Province notified a casualties in the local middle school: at 10 am on November 13th, some boys in the second day of the first day of the first year of the Xinghua Middle School of Wuxian County were like a toilet in the middle exam. At the time, due to a crowded and injured on the upper and lower stairs, the students involved were sent to the hospital for examination and treatment for the first time. At present, a student has died after full rescue. One student is heavier. The students are being treated with all their strength. Four students who are suffered by minor injuries can be hospitalized and can be discharged recently. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to the &quot;Beijing News&quot;, the details of the incident revealed by the person familiar with the matter are &quot;the toilet of Xinghua Middle School is the upper and lower floors, and the men&#39;s toilet must go up the stairs. How happened to the stamp. &quot; According to the pictures of the school school, there is no toilet in the teaching building of the school. Students need to go to the teaching building first, and then go to the stairs to go upstairs to the toilet. The tragedy also happened when going upstairs. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the accident, many schools across the country demanded that duty teachers on various floors. Some media have called for &quot;class time&quot; or &quot;test time time&quot; to allow students to have more time to calmly toilet. Some netizens believe that the school should improve the hardware facilities and set up toilets on each floor of the teaching building. In addition to these bright problems, this accident is still worthy of analysis as concerned with responsibility distribution and prevention measures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; First of all, the nature of the accident. Media reports all reported the accident as &quot;stepping incident&quot;, but the words in the report were &quot;crowded and falling.&quot; So, what is the nature of the accident? This is worth investigation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If the &quot;stair railing is intact&quot; and the &quot;toilet in another building&quot; revealed by netizens, the accident may be in the ten minutes of the exam, a lot of a large number The students first went to the teaching building, and then went to the &quot;toilet building&quot; next door. The high -density flow occurred in the process of going up and down the stairs. Students who died unfortunately were one of the following possibilities. One was squeezing asphyxasting from high -density groups, and the other was the heights caused by gravity reasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Followed by the cause of the cause and responsibility of the accident. After the accident, the number of toilets is insufficient and the test interval is insufficient. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A period of mid -term exams often take about two hours, at least three times that of a class time, which will greatly increase the frequency of toilet. Candidates need to relax in the gap between the exams, and will undoubtedly further increase the frequency of toilet. If the candidate&#39;s psychological pressure is more psychological and the toilet is more rushing to the toilet, the superposition of multiple variables is enough to enlarge the risk of security: the common two -hour test time, the intense mood, which has raised the group of the same frequency resonance The probability of occurrence also increases the chance of accidents. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The hardware facilities of the school have been unchanged on the day of the incident, and the test time and test interview time has also been determined. Then, what the monitoring teacher can do that day is probably that only the students who are not allowed to go out to the toilet can they eliminate any possibility of the accident. What should be pursued is, who has set these rules? What artificial hardware facilities are there? This is the subject of responsibility for it, not the monitoring teacher who performs rules on the day of the incident. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How to prevent similar accidents happen again? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Similar accidents in China are not the first time. In the step -by -step accident of the third experimental primary school in Puyang, Henan, in March 2017, the students &quot;flooded down&quot; after the early reading of early reading; and in the stamping accident of a middle school in Xuchang, Henan in November 2000, students were studying in the evening. After class, something happened. Similar accidents in all parts of the country have also occurred many times, and the causes of these accidents are similar: short time time, or the duration of the class for a long time, the students go to the toilet or go out as soon as the bell rang, because the congestion causes the stamping to step on the stamping. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Therefore, control variables, and the right medicine can be found to prevent such accidents. Of course, the school&#39;s strictly installing toilet in accordance with the &quot;Specifications for Primary and Middle Schools&quot; is of course necessary. It is also a way to install diversion obstacles at the densely exit entrance and exit of the school. During the period of large -scale activities such as examinations, sports meetings, and school celebrations, it is also an indispensable measure to arrange special personnel to guarantee order and implement peak management. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In addition to improving hardware facilities, the school should also focus on improving software, that is, management level. Specifically, you should also question whether the school arranges the peak test on that day, and is there a person responsible for maintaining the order of people? No matter how detailed it is, the school allows candidates to go to the toilet when the exam is in progress on the day of the incident? This will also relieve the toilet pressure in the test gap. And, do the school usually do a good job in security knowledge education for preventing and squeezing stomachs, and have you done the corresponding safety exercise? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; No matter how good the hardware facilities are approved, the number of bears is approved, and its redundant also has a limit value. You cannot expect more toilet repair, broaden teaching buildings, and install diversion obstacles. A complete large -scale tourist attraction will not occur. The long -term scientific management way is the best guarantee for preventing problems before, and its importance will never be under the improvement of hardware facilities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Of course, the school cannot keep the students in the classroom because of such incidents. After the teacher&#39;s non -teaching burden, enter the misunderstanding of &quot;school responding to students&#39; unlimited safety responsibilities&quot;. The school improves management, and can also think more about decentralization, give students more freedom of classrooms, teaching buildings, and exercise venues, so that students can exercise the ability to deal with risks, and learn to protect themselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 17:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[为什么有的人睡觉打着呼噜就“嘎”了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260615]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-18 16:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Recently, Olympic gymnastics champion Yang Wei exposed the respiratory problem with problems with the respiratory tract problems. , Attracted everyone&#39;s attention. He revealed in social dynamics that he couldn&#39;t breathe in his own time when he was sleeping. This situation was once 6 minutes. According to the advice given by the doctor, &quot;the former athlete, now &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; /span>; &lt;span>; Planetic &quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; In fact, Yang Wei&#39;s symptoms are not an example. Search. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; When the US President Biden delivered a speech in June this year, he was found by the media on his face with a belt mark on the ventilator; In a program, Huo Qigang disclosed the fact that he suffered from insomnia disorders and moderate sleep injury; Chen Qiaoen had undergone surgery because of his throat collapse and could not breathe air. Artist Hu Haiquan actively worn breathing because of snoring in the show and actively wearing breathing breathing. The machine sleeps. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; We all know that snoring after falling asleep will only affect the sleep of the pillow, but I did not expect that in some cases, in some cases The snoring may be accompanied by breathing suspension, which makes people &quot;repeatedly suffocate&quot; in their dreams, or even dangerous &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; and &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; life. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/mrxb5diqlerfb732b6q8yyu84GFLNaoqbzv&quot; Border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 720 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/mrxb5diqlerfb732B6Q8yyu84GFLNaoqbzv.jpeg &quot;data-key = &quot;258641&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align : left; &quot;>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>; Does snoring cause breathing suspension? &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Yang Wei this situation is called &quot;breathing pause comprehensive &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; sign &lt;/span>; /span>; &lt;span>; &quot;, including three types: obstruction, centrality, and mixed. Snoring, accompanied by qi and hypoxia, may cause sudden death in severe cases. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Of course, not all snoring will be diagnosed as respiratory suspension synthesis &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, the two have not confirmed the inevitable relationship. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; According to the &quot;Adults Obstacles Sleep Respiration Respiratory Disposal Disasel more abuse of adult sleep and respiratory respiratory suspension in 2018 according to the Chinese Medical Association&#39;s Respiratory Disease Branch The discipline diagnosis and treatment guideline (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Guidelines&quot;), the diagnostic standards of respiratory suspension &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 征 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;, there are two main: respiratory suspension and low air ventilation incidents, and the number of times of low ventilation incidents, and The frequency of the two. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; The breathing suspension mentioned here is almost literally, refers , Refers to the reduction of breathing and blood oxygen saturation to below the basic level. During a period of 7 hours of sleep, if the breathing suspension and low ventilation have more than 30 times, or the low ventilation index (AHI) is greater than 5 times per hour, it can be diagnosed as a respiratory suspension comprehensive &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Sheng &lt;/span>; &lt;span>;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Obstacles of respiratory suspension comprehensive &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 征 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; (OSA) and centrality The difference between respiratory suspension comprehensive &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Zheng &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; (CSA) is that the former is due to the obstruction of the upper airway, which causes respiratory suspension. The nose stopped but the brain was fine, the latter was caused by the abnormality of the central nervous system, the brain stopped, and the nose and nose stopped. Mixed respiratory suspension synthesis &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; 征 &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; (MSA) belongs to both. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Surprisingly, the complexity of the breathing suspension &lt;/span>; &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; surface It only causes interference to night sleep. In fact, this kind of sleep rhythm disorders caused by irregular breathing have caused more adverse effects on daily life, such as drowsiness during the day, decreased memory, and even psychology. Abnormal intelligence and behavior. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Medical experts who published the &quot;Guide&quot; believe that OSAHS patients have risen rapidly in the short term, with certain possibilities and hypertension, and hypertension. Coronary heart disease has abnormal heart rate, stroke, type 2 diabetes, etc., and the families of patients with the above diseases can observe more attention. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/ilqwhkpfm67777777777777FLXHRJPEG&quot; border = &quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 810 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/ilqwhkpm677777777777flxhrjssusvu.jpeg &quot;data-key = &quot;258642&quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>; (visual China/picture) &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style = &quot;text-align : left; &quot;>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>; Why is this disease easily missed diagnosis &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>; &lt;span>;? &lt;/span>; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/h4>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; 2019 academic magazine &quot;Liuye Knife-Respiratory Diseases&quot; published a name &quot;Obstructiveness Investigation reports of sleep respiratory suspension and global economic burden &quot;, based on the diagnostic criteria published by the American Sleep Medicine Society (AASM) as a reference, have compiled the data of obstructive sleep apnea from 16 countries and 17 studies. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; This report believes that the prevalence of obstructive sleep apnea has increased from 2%-4%10 years ago to 24% Above, more than 85%of sleeping respiratory suspension patients were missed. Researchers have further speculated that about 936 million adults 30 to 69 are suffering from obstructive sleep respiratory suspension in the world. China has the most affected people, followed by the United States, Brazil and India. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; When it comes to why sleep breathing is particularly easy to missed the diagnosis, the author of the report believes that this may originate from everyone&#39;s health and health. Two prejudices. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; First of all, everyone is more accustomed to blaming the fatigue in daily life on age and pressure. &quot;It is normal&quot; &quot;The work KPI is too heavy, and I can&#39;t sleep when I think of it.&quot; I rarely consider the direction of sleep disease. In fact, respiratory suspension during sleep can also cause physical function to decline, which causes migraine and other diseases such as migraine and chronic fatigue. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; In some of the traditional concepts, snoring often becomes a sign of &quot;sleeping sweetly&quot;, even if the family is noticed abnormal, It is rarely interrupted and valued. Take a step back, some people&#39;s snoring sounds are irregular, and the emergence of respiratory suspension is random, and it is difficult for relatives and family members to effectively identify. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; &quot;Guide&quot; specifically mentioned that the body&#39;s obesity (referring to the weight of the body weight of 20%or more) may increase the affected affected The risk of sleep apnea; the prevalence of the prevalence grows forward, the number of patients in women after menopause increases, and the prevalence of men during the birth period is higher than that of women. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; In addition, the sedentary people, long-term drinking smokers, and people with OSAHS family history are also faced with high problems Disease risk. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; In the end, this disease is common and common, but it is not easy to find. . Many domestic medical research has confirmed that portable blood oxygen instruments and mobile phone snoring analysis APPs will help early diagnosis and screening of OSAHS patients. Perhaps in the near future, monitoring respiratory suspension comprehensive &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; Zheng &lt;/span>; &lt;span>; It is as convenient and fast as monitoring body temperature. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: left;&quot;>; &lt;span>; More importantly, if you suspect that you or your family will have similar symptoms, you should go to the hospital for diagnosis as soon as possible. According to the doctor&#39;s order, according to the doctor&#39;s order Take surgical, appliances, ventilator, etc. for treatment. In a person&#39;s life, one -third of the time spent in sleep. Sleep health is really healthy. May the monarchs sleep well and healthy every day. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 16:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[离经叛道的“禁片之王”，终于迎来大结局]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260850]]><description> &lt;div>; &lt;i>; 2023-11-18 15:00:00 &lt;/i>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; This month, the biggest matters in the animation industry &lt;/span>; The end of the giant is the end. The long -lost end of the offensive finally came to this epic series of works. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ea5a811e3e55d28ca36b54338FD4F66.png&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;opac it: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 537 &quot;height =&quot; 416 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/ea811e3e55d28ca363387fd4f66.png &quot;Data-key = &quot;258721&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; &quot;Attack on the Giant&quot; is a masterpiece of Japanese painter, a painter, a total of 139 episodes, serialized in comic magazines for 12 years from 2009 to 2021. In 2013, the TV animation version of &quot;Attack on the Giant&quot; came out. After ten years of production, a total of four seasons (except theatrical version and special articles). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; According to Douban entries, the complete watch of the entire drama is smooth. Giant &quot;Season 3 (2018) →&quot; Attack Giant &quot;Season 3 (2019) →&quot; Attack Giant &quot;final season part.1 (2020) part.2 (2022) →&quot; Attack on the Giant &quot; Final season &amp; nbsp; End &amp; nbsp; first &amp; nbsp; latter (2023). &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/2604828329483186b6089ea3.png&quot; 0 &quot;style = &quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 600 &quot;Height =&quot; 337 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/2604828329483186b6089ea3.p ng &quot;data-key =&quot; 258720 &quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Unique worldview architecture, background setting of hunting, the reverse brain reversal, bloody battle scenes, and sensitive issues have made this work come out, and they will be admitted to it. The attention of all walks of life. But while attracting countless audiences &lt;/span>;, it was banned by many countries in the world because of its excessive scale. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nevertheless, it has obtained a good score in Douban. It is 9 points+in the season. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/4c766315f871e47850543e220dc2.png&quot; 0 &quot;0&quot; 0 &quot;opac it: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 483 &quot;Height =&quot; 439 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/4c766315f87850543E220dc2.png &quot;Data- key = &quot;258723&quot;>; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Since the comic version has ended in 2021, the audience&#39;s end of this work has long been clear. It is worth noting that when the comic was over &lt;/span>;, it caused huge controversy due to the plot that violated the humanity and was criticized by fans as &quot;bad tail&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The fundamental is because of the protagonist of &quot;Attack on the Giant&quot; Allen, which is suspected of &quot;Mother&quot;. His predictive ability is likely to manipulate the giantless giant, let the giant eat his mother, leave a huge spiritual trauma for his childhood, and then enter the investigation military regiment and determine to get rid of the giant. This setting is mainly to make the entire story logic smoothly, &lt;span>; constitutes a closed loop of causality. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; But whether it is the emotion based on the character or the audience&#39;s emotions, this setting is unacceptable, and there is a sense of power that forcibly self -tell. To apply the netizens, this move is tantamount to &quot;Harry Potter manipulated the Voldemort to kill his parents in the past&quot;, &quot;Batman buying a thief back to kill his parents&quot;, &quot;Iron Man instructed the Winter soldiers back and killed &quot;My parents&quot;. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; In the animated version, this &quot;mother -in -law&quot; plot has been taken by a stroke, which is extremely vague. Because of this, it did not cause controversy like the comic version, but just made Allen a little tragedy. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/fb44a83ea8765F7FA.PNG&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 692 &quot;Height =&quot; 389 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/fb44a8765AFCBE894DA7E5F7FA. png &quot;data-key =&quot; 258722 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>;&quot; Attack on the Giant &quot;is known as &lt;/span>; God&#39;s masterpiece is because it reflects reality and depicts a conflict of imaginary world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The story begins with a giant invasion on Paradi. Human beings were unable to resist the giants, so three high walls (Hina, Rosse, Mary) were established to resist the giants in exchange for a hundred years of peace. But the terrible giant came, &quot;On that day, humans finally remembered the fear of being dominated by the giant, and the humiliation trapped in the bird cage &lt;span>;.&quot; &lt;/Span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Allen and his friends Samada and Almin, suffered a heavy blow in the invasion of the giant, and finally admitted to the investigation team to fight the giant together. At first, the growth line of Allen and others followed the traditional hot routine. However, with the continuous advancement of the plot, the audience quickly discovered its abnormalities -it was not subject to the dual confrontation of good and evil, but instead digging the complexity of human nature. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; The reversal of the plot drives the audience and the protagonist to continue thinking, breaking, rebuilding, and breaking their thinking. Ellen fought a line during the battle, but he did not expect to force his giant power. In the investigation of the Corps, many giants were also hidden, and three comrades -in -arms who were born with Allen not only had the power of giants, but also &quot;spy.&quot; I thought the giants were all non -human monsters. I did not expect giants to be humans. The giants were suffering from war and were victims of race opponents. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f946227cb4cb52357034e66a9.png&quot; 0 &quot;style&quot; style = &quot; OPACITY: 1; &quot;Width =&quot; 693 &quot;Height =&quot; 383 &quot;Data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/f9462227cb52357034e66a9. png &quot;data-key =&quot; 258724 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; All &lt;/span>; humans who can become giants are Edians. They are regarded as&quot; descendants of devil &quot;by ordinary people. Two thousand years ago, the Eldians who won the power of the giant from the ancestor Yomil were called a king in the world. One hundred years ago, the Edians were defeated by the Malays. The royal family led some people to cross the sea to Parady Island and lived a isolated life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Edians who stayed in other countries became slaves and lived a concentrated camp. For thousands of years, ordinary people have a deep hostility for the Edians, and have always wanted to remove it quickly. This hostile made Allen go to &quot;blackened&quot;. He decided to borrow the land to launch the &quot;destroyed plan&quot; -hundreds of thousands of 60 -meter -high &lt;span>; giant giants runaway on the ground, which is indiscriminately, without differences, without differences, without differences, without differences, without differences, without differences, without differences, without differences, without differences, without differences, there is no difference. Traveling on all life and massacre 80%of humans outside Paradi. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; The next part of the part is the &quot;Final War&quot; after the launch of the ground. At the end, under the cover of other members, Misaki found Allen&#39;s true body, then cut off Allen&#39;s skull, and gave him a affectionate kiss. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;img src = &quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/d6f869a729a1ad946452176faf14.jpeg&quot; border = &quot;0&quot; style = &quot; opacity: 1; &quot;width =&quot; 1080 &quot;height =&quot; 607 &quot;data-src =&quot; // images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/d6f869a729452176faf14. jpeg &quot;data-key =&quot; 258719 &quot;>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; On the surface,&quot; Attack on the Giant &quot;&lt;/span>; tells the story of&quot; Dragon Dragon Slaying Boys into the Dragon &quot;. Simple, related to sacrifice, more related to saving. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Allen&#39;s death is destined. As early as the awarding ceremony, he had predicted the future. He repeatedly tried to change his destiny, but all ended in failure. In order to break the reincarnation, let the power of the giant completely disappear, and let the Eldian people be treated equally or even admired, he can only embark on an extremely lonely path. He mobilized the ground, opened the Holocaust, and then made his companions a hero, intending to use his own sacrifice in exchange for the peace of the Edians, as he said, &quot;This is to save Paradish Island The only way to go to everyone &quot;. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;艾伦的所作所为，是另一种意义上的以战止殇。他在拯救与牺牲之间权衡，最终选择通过牺牲全世界去拯救身边人。这种决定，让他从英雄蜕变成了恶魔。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/adcd3b5f37cd9df03705d86e6529a58d.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/adcd3b5f37cd9df03705d86e6529a58d.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258725&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;除了挖掘人性复杂外，&lt;/span>;《进击的巨人》还涉及了诸多深刻命题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;比如自由。艾伦一直追求自由，自幼时起，他便对墙外的大海、以及海的另一边充满好奇，觉得那是自由的理想世界。可到头来，他却发现，“海的那边是敌人”。所谓的自由，尤其是绝对的自由，根本不存在。于是，艾伦最后沦为了自由的奴隶，直至死亡让他解脱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;再比如，有关于生存意义的探讨。完结篇后篇里，阿尔敏和吉克展开了一场富有哲思的对话。吉克是典型的悲观主义者，他认为人类的宿命，就是在进行一场无尽而痛苦的轮回&lt;span>;，生命的目的就是为了繁衍，毫无意义。而阿尔敏则认为，生命的意义就在瞬息之间，在于对活在当下的感受：在海边捡贝壳，和伙伴们一起奔跑，下雨天在家看书，看松鼠吃树果……这些看似随意的零星片段，构成了人类生命里的华彩篇章。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这些命题，都让《进击的巨人》具有了普通热血漫所不具有的深度。所以，从某种意义上来说，这十年来，观众一边观看艾伦等人的成长、分道扬镳，一边也随着个人心智的成熟，对这部作品有了更多的感知与体悟。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;人类世界因贫富、种族、意识形态等问题造成的割裂、战争，总是循环往复，层出不穷。犹如眼下的巴以冲突，它们似乎总在一次又一次地验证着谏山创在《进击的巨人》中包含的隐喻。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;故事最后，三笠将艾伦埋在了他最喜欢午睡的那颗树下。未来，即便失去了巨人之力，但人类的战争依旧从未停息。此时，一个男人发现了埋葬艾伦的那颗树。他走了进去，就像千百年前的始祖尤弥尔那样，即将获得巨人之力……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这似乎在告诉我们，只要人类的命运周而复始，那悲剧就不会被彻底终结。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/daf3712a921d7eb60a4ae64d6f372410.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;692&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/daf3712a921d7eb60a4ae64d6f372410.png&quot; data-key=&quot;258726&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;既然如此，那眼下这个冲突不断的世界，是否仍值得我们为之努力、奋斗与生活？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这就回到了吉克与阿尔敏的那番对话。他们犹如谏山创的一体两面，一面揭露世界本质，为我们指出世界的残酷性；一面予以我们温情、希望与力量，让我们立足当下，珍惜宝贵瞬间，过好自己的人生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;或许，说到底，一切都只是一个选择的问题。你会选择成为吉克还是阿尔敏？又或者，你尚有其他选择？无论如何，想要如何存活于世，一切只取决于你自己。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 15:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[当WeWork不再work]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260848]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/JGRhwuRuCpQduncfyATYDZirEwUctBOQITGqN4gD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/JGRhwuRuCpQduncfyATYDZirEwUctBOQITGqN4gD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258717&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年8月19日，北京，WeWork联合共享办公空间&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10月12日一早，上班路上的黄伟突然收到了前台群发的通知——办公区即日起将停止供水。赶到公司不久，他便被告知，这家位于上海世贸大厦的WeWork联合办公区已无法继续经营，租户需尽快搬至WeWork旗下的其他物业。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄伟的初创团队2023年9月才刚刚入驻。租金比他预期的低，单个工位的月报价是1200元。 2019年底刚回国时，他曾了解过行情，苏州河附近的一家WeWork，同等配置的工位报价在2000元左右。销售告诉他，如果不是空置率高影响了经营，这个价位是签不到这个地段的。当时这家WeWork里，5人以下的办公区域还算饱和，10人以上的办公室则是成片空置。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;前台“先到先得”的提醒容不得他犹豫。 Huang Wei quickly selected a office space for Wework to be located one kilometers away. When he saw the news of &quot;WeWork&#39;s application for bankruptcy protection&quot;, he had moved into the WeWORK office area in Shanghai Square for half a month. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当地时间11月6日，为摆脱巨额负债，WeWork在美国新泽西州申请破产保护。 However, the bankruptcy application is limited to the office of Wework in the United States and Canada.次日，WeWork中国发布声明称，WeWork中国已于2020年末与WeWork分离，作为独立品牌拥有独立的经营和管理能力，“WeWork在美国与加拿大做出的重大战略重组决定，与WeWork中国没有任何关联。”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;创立于美国纽约的WeWork被誉为“共享办公鼻祖”。 WeWork会以优惠价格长期租赁商业楼宇，经重新设计和装修后将其分割成共享办公空间，为自由职业者、初创公司及大型企业等提供弹性租赁合约，赚取租金差和附加服务费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在其最初创立的2010年，美国金融危机的负面影响仍在持续，商业楼宇因企业倒闭潮而广泛闲置，大量企业裁员，失业者变成自由职业者。彼时横空出世的WeWork不仅装修时尚、提供了灵活的租赁选择，还会供应免费的咖啡饮品，举办丰富的社区活动……WeWork联合创始人亚当·诺依曼主张“空间即服务”，宣称要打造“实体社交网络”，一个“让人们生活而不仅仅是谋生的世界”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/uDRbK6SD0u9ElpCRqVlC0VN5YV3jgatYqoXhjH1r.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;633&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/uDRbK6SD0u9ElpCRqVlC0VN5YV3jgatYqoXhjH1r.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258715&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2019年11月6日，日本东京，软银集团董事长兼总裁孙正义出席新闻发布会。软银表示，其在WeWork的投资价值减少了近46亿美元&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;金融危机后，美国基准利率长期处于较低水平，资本急于进入私募市场谋求更高收益。在那个共享经济概念备受热捧的年代，WeWork成了资本的宠儿，成立仅四年便跻身独角兽行列。 2019年，在大股东软银的一路“护航”下，WeWork的估值飙升至惊人的470亿美元。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;彼时，软银集团CEO孙正义将WeWork称为“下一个阿里巴巴”。阿里巴巴是这位“独角兽猎人”最成功的投资案例。 2000年，软银向成立仅一年的阿里巴巴注资2000万美元。 14年后阿里巴巴上市，软银持有的股份价值翻了约2900倍。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;软银一度是共享经济赛道的投资风向标。孙正义主张向初创公司注入海量资本，帮助其在规模上快速碾压竞争对手，成为市场主导品牌，以期在获得用户和市场的绝对优势后实现长期盈利。优步（Uber）和滴滴就是同时期软银在共享经济赛道的投资案例。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;然而，WeWork在登上估值巅峰半年后，便一头栽入漫长而陡峭的下坠阶段。 2019年8月，随着首次公开募股(IPO)申请书的曝光，WeWork的连年亏损引发了市场对该公司盈利能力的担忧。诺依曼的财务和领导能力等问题也被陆续曝出。同月，刚刚上市半年的优步在跌破发行价后，出现了自公布财报以来的最大亏损。一时间，有关独角兽泡沫破灭的讨论十分热烈。 WeWork的上市计划被无限期搁置。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;此后，诺伊曼辞去CEO职务，新的管理层被引入，帮助重组公司的租赁业务。直到2021年10月，WeWork才终于以90亿美元的估值成功上市。可上市不是灵药，反而成了问题持续暴露的放大镜。虽然WeWork一直自诩为科技公司，但其始终无法依靠自身盈利实现非线性增长，经营模式并未脱离重资产的商业地产租赁范畴。 WeWork的客户主体是小型及创业型机构，抗风险能力较弱，流动性较大。随着行业竞争日趋激烈，要留住这部分对成本极为敏感的客户，WeWork就不得不面对价格下调、成本上升的难题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2020年新冠疫情在全球暴发，居家办公成为普遍趋势，经济衰退导致大量客户关门歇业，办公室空置率陡升，而作为“二房东”的WeWork仍需向房东支付租金。崛起于上一轮危机的WeWork成为了新一轮危机的受害者。期限错配在经济繁荣期可能带来丰厚的利润，在经济下行期则是沉重的负累，而美联储自疫情以来的数轮加息更是加剧了WeWork的债务负担。由来已久的系统性风险迎来了集中性爆发。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/gjloiN0n5FG6LPE2jsj5YWdTUDrfDfeu0wMnJf7h.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;641&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/gjloiN0n5FG6LPE2jsj5YWdTUDrfDfeu0wMnJf7h.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258716&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2018年4月12日，WeWork联合创始人诺依曼访问上海&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2023年8月，WeWork在二季度财报中指出，考虑到亏损和预计的现金需求，再加上会员流失增加和当前的流动性水平，公司能否持续经营取决于管理层在未来12个月内能否改善流动性和盈利能力。截至6月30日，该公司仍有29亿美元的长期债务，以及133亿美元的长期租赁债务。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;WeWork首席执行官大卫·托利认为，由于缺乏“必要的财务灵活性以适应快速变化的商业房地产市场”，必须对“不可持续的租赁重新定价”。申请破产保护正是WeWork逆境求生的尝试。 WeWork正寻求法院批准其终止履行“基本上无法运营”的69份租约，并与四百多名房东协商修改既有租约。分析普遍认为，WeWork的退出将导致原本就走高的写字楼空置率进一步上扬，对写字楼的现金流和价值产生负面影响。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;仿佛一个循环。在市场热烈探讨WeWork风波引发的蝴蝶效应时，竞争者更愿意将WeWork的“大败局”视作行业变化的“插曲”，甚至是机遇。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“WeWork 破产的最大讽刺之处在于，它发生在行业表现创纪录的时刻。”总部位于纽约的共享办公运营商Industrious的CEO杰米·霍达里在接受《金融时报》采访时打了个比喻，“当万豪酒店经营不善时，它就会变成凯悦酒店。”同为共享办公运营商的IWG集团首席执行官马克·迪克森在接受BBC采访时则介绍，IWG目前已收购并重新推出了40处曾经属于WeWork的办公空间。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;有WeWork的前车之鉴，从“直租”的重资产模式转向“分润”的轻资产模式是近年来行业普遍努力的方向，如今更显得迫在眉睫。不过，业主是否愿意接受这种调整，仍然取决于他们对经济大环境和运营价值等的综合评估。 IWG近期公布的一项报告显示，其在2023年第三季度签下的204处新办公场地中有200处属于轻资产运营，但整从体上看，以传统租赁方式运营的仍占六成. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在中国市场，WeWork中国同样希望成为存量时代的流量入口。 “只靠租金差的生意模式是很苦的，但这也是我们的核心竞争力和优势,”&amp;nbsp;WeWork大中华区副总裁全斌近日在接受“观点新媒体”采访时表示，企业要活得更好、更久，必须在降本增效方面做得更快、更坚决。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/aXaJ158QLVgKsFL7LpYGSCNn5DIyBk8rsjRTmAeT.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/aXaJ158QLVgKsFL7LpYGSCNn5DIyBk8rsjRTmAeT.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258718&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;上海，WeWork联合共享办公空间&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（视觉中国/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对黄伟来说，房租成本下降固然是好事，但也反映出地产行业的不景气。黄伟的创业项目做的就是建筑设计，生意好坏和行业的起落息息相关。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2019年底，黄伟从荷兰回国，先后就职于一家欧美建筑设计公司和一家本土设计工作室。 “甲方都不太行了，下游做设计服务的就更难。能接到的项目量严重缩水，行业内卷严重，要活下去，要么下沉，要么缩体量。即便能拿到订单，性价比也非常低。我的很多同学和朋友都转行了。”2022年初，黄伟和其他两位合伙人共同创立了妙奇设计工作室。面对不确定性和30岁的槛，黄伟还是执着地想在自己热爱的行业再试试看。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;创业一年多，他一直在社交媒体分享自己的创业体悟。这次小小的办公室搬迁风波也被他剪辑成了一条短视频。视频末尾，他聊到了对这个“不确定的时代”的看法。没想到，这成了他近期关注度最高的视频之一。私信如雪花般涌入。不少留言谈及了他们对于这类突然变故的感同身受。当然，“打广告的”更多，向他推销自家的办公场地。据世邦魏理仕预测，上海2023年下半年写字楼市场新增供应预计超过95万平方米，是近十年来的最高水平。需求疲软，供应放量，写字楼市场仍处于缓慢复苏期。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;黄伟飞快地划过留言板。与持续运营的压力相比，办公室被突然关停显得不值一提。他的租约已经签到了2024年9月。 2023年即将过去，行业竞争的激烈程度远甚去年，投标会上，大师级事务所下场拼抢，两三百个提案择一的情况已十分普遍。明年如何？他依然“心怀期望”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 14:25:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[梁静茹演唱会“柱子票”案开庭：主办方是否应提前告知成焦点]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260853]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;今年5月，有多名观众反映，在梁静茹上海演唱会买到“柱子票”，视野被舞台四周的立柱遮挡，引发热议。 11月17日，买到“柱子票”的李女士告诉南都记者，事后共有9名观众向演唱会主办方上海魔方泛文化演艺有限公司提起诉讼。 On November 15, the Meilong People&#39;s Court of Minhang District, Shanghai, opened the trial of the first trial of the Meilong People&#39;s Court. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/67dacecd2e0c7f3166cf55332857d456.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;481&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/18/67dacecd2e0c7f3166cf55332857d456.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258728&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;李女士提供的“柱子票”现场图。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;9名观众起诉演唱会主办方&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;今年5月20日-21日，2023梁静茹世界巡回演唱会在上海举行，多名观众反映，到场后发现，视野被舞台四周的立柱遮挡，“看歌手成了看柱子”。有网友在社交平台发文称，“花1599全款拿下梁静茹演唱会柱子位”“我这1599是花钱买糟心”等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月17日，演唱会观众李女士告诉南都记者，包括自己在内的9名观众分别向演唱会主办方上海魔方泛文化演艺有限公司提起诉讼，要求获得合理的退款和赔偿。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;11月15日下午，上海市闵行区人民法院梅陇人民法庭一审公开开庭审理该案。李女士表示，“目前庭审结果还没宣判，我们在等待主办方的调解方案，如果他们提出的方案我们仍旧不能接受，我们会等待法院判决。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李女士介绍，本次提起诉讼的9名观众中，6人为5月20日场观众，3人为5月21日场观众，购买票面价格包括1299元、999元等。 “我们8月初向法院递交材料申请立案，8月底收到法院立案的消息。大家都是通过社交媒体认识的，因为前期和主办方协商均失败了，我们也是迫于无奈选择了起诉。我们想要搞清楚，主办是否侵犯了我们正当权益。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李女士称，其购买了5月20日两张价值1299元的二层看台门票，当天的上座率相当高。 The photo shows that Ms. Li&#39;s vision is a hollowed column in the middle, and singers can be seen vaguely. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南都记者搜索座位分布图发现，四个角形成的两条对角线基本都出现了被柱子遮挡的情况，但是页面并未标注。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，主办方上海魔方泛文化演艺有限公司曾回应，仅负责梁静茹上海演唱会的落地事宜，舞台不由该公司搭建。售票阶段，公司不知道舞台设计会有四根柱子。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李女士告诉南都记者，主办方曾表示在其认可的遮挡范围内，送一张200元的购物卡作为心意金，“无论什么价位的票，一律只补偿200元” . &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;争议焦点在主办方是否应提前告知&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;11月15日，在该案件的庭审中，双方围绕着“主办方是否应提前告知&#39;柱子票&#39;的存在及这些位置是否影响演唱会体验”等争议焦点，进行了法庭调查及辩论。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;李女士向南都记者介绍，9名原告的请求事项主要有三方面——请求判令被告返还原告演唱会门票款项；判令被告向原告支付惩罚性赔偿金；判令被告承担本案诉讼费。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原告代理人称，本案的焦点在于被告到底有没有事先告知所有的原告，他们的视线是否会被遮挡。原告看演唱会的目的就是“看”，视线被遮挡是非常严重的违约行为。原告的知情权受到侵害，导致失去了选择权。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被告代理人表示，本次演出采用承重柱，是因为场馆的吊顶承重不够，如果没有地面的承重柱，这场演出无法正常举办，根本过不了安全审批，使用地面承重柱也是业内常规的做法。 “观众席某些位置不可避免会有视线的遮挡问题，这是常识，被告从来没有在宣传中故意提及没有台柱、没有遮挡。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;原告方认为，现场的设计布置应当是更早就已完成，演唱会开始之前，主办方也应履行相应的责任，告知视线会受到遮挡的消费者，询问他们是否要退款，或是给出其他的方案。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;被告代理人则称，被告主要基于安全的考虑设置了台柱，并不是故意要欺瞒观众，并且本次演出是系列巡演的第一站，不能苛责他们事先考虑到如此多details.后续其他演出场次的应对方式，是受到这一场演出的影响后改进的，不能以后续场次的处理方案来要求第一站；更不能因为有个别场次事先告知视线有遮挡，就认为被告未告知就是有欺诈的故意。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;15日下午3时许，此案庭审结束，未当庭宣判。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;&lt;strong>;中消协曾点名批评“柱子票”现象&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;针对“柱子票”，演唱会主办方的处理方式有所不同。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;南都此前报道，今年8月14日，周杰伦2023嘉年华世界巡回演唱会呼和浩特站主办方，山西星台光影文化娱乐有限公司发布公告，称为满足广大歌迷需求，让更多歌迷可以现场感受演唱会的欢乐氛围，减少演唱会场外拥堵，主办单位经与各方协调、争取，将因音控台遮挡区域视线不良的座位，进行特价折扣销售。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，主办方在公告中声明，此区域座位观演视角受音控台影响，有不同程度的遮挡，无法完全看到舞台全部，音控台后设立大屏幕方便观众观看，特价票购买后不退不换。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8月2日，中消协曾点名批评各类“柱子票”“墙根票”现象，指出消费者在网购演出门票遭遇“盲选”座位，部分演出场所不支持消费者购票时选座，到达现场才得知购买到的是存在视野盲区的“柱子票”“墙根票”，导致演唱会全程“只闻声不见人”这一票务问题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中消协称，相关演出票务平台和主办方应该站在促进消费潜力释放的角度，思考如何更好保护消费者的权益和提高消费体验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 13:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[首位博士说 | 陈云生：宪法监督的研究任务依然任重道远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260736]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;博士档案：&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;陈云生，新中国第一位宪法学博士。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1942年，出生于北京市平谷县（今平谷区）；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1966年，北京政法学院（现中国政法大学）法律系毕业；毕业后在广西从事过司法、教育、行政工作；1978年，考入中国社会科学院研究生院法学系深造，&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;硕士毕业后在中国社会科学院法学研究所工作；1983年，师从法学家张友渔攻读宪法学专业博士；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;1987年，获得法学博士学位；&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, SimKai, STKaiti;&quot;>;先后担任中国社会科学院法学研究所宪法行政法研究室副主任、教授、博士生导师，上海交通大学法学院、北京师范大学法学院等7所大学兼职教授、博士生导师，最高人民检察院专家咨询委员会荣誉专家咨询委员，享受国务院特殊津贴。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;2023年10月，陈云生在京郊的书房里。（南方周末记者陈怡帆/图）&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/018fc437d2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;811&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/16/018fc437d2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;258522&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;2023年10月，陈云生在京郊的书房里。 （南方周末记者陈怡帆/图）&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;81岁的陈云生，很少休息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他的每天从凌晨四五点开始，在北京郊外的平谷区快走、做饭、阅读和写作，过着有规律的暮年生活。他在“认领”的一片荒地上种豆角、红薯、南瓜和玉米，时时灌溉耕耘。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;对务农的兴趣，源于他的出身。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;这个1942年生于平谷的农村子弟，是村里第一个高中生，第一个大学生，第一个法学博士。 1966年，从北京政法学院（现中国政法大学）毕业后，他被分配到广西农村，和农民同吃同住，每天都在牛排便的腾腾热气中苏醒。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;国家恢复研究生考试后，他靠着一本“幸免于难”的宪法学教程，以复试第一的成绩考上中国社会科学院法学graduate School. Later, he studied his doctorate degree and became the only student of Zhang Youyu, a famous law. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;其间，他读尽了法学所的专业书，从宪法学的“小喽啰”成为“国内宪法监督第一人”。 1980年，他参与“82宪法”修正案制定工作。他始终认为，宪法的真正意义并不在于宪法文件本身。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;在治学路上，他不爱参与行政事务，也把不少机会拒之门外。 He laughed at the &quot;lonely soul ghost of the academic world&quot;, and only asked to do the most to the extreme, and it was never moved by the trend. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;他劝学生们，要耐得寂寞。他始终遵循笛卡尔的行为守则第三项：始终只求克服自己，不求克服命运，只求改变自己的欲望，不求改变世界的秩序。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;“天助我也”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;退休后，你现在的生活日常是怎样的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我一般早上四点起床，简单吃点东西，就去河边exercise.以前是跑步或者走过去，我今年5、6月得一场大病后，体力不支，就骑车锻炼一小时。然后回来研究或写作一小时，就去做早餐、打扫卫生。吃过早饭后到地里干活，一般干两小时，再回来接着研究。前两天还在抢收地里种的菜。午休后又在书桌前工作。接着又到地里干点活，晚上再骑车锻炼。没有双休日和节假日，也不知道每天是星期几，几十年如一日。对我而言，外出讲学和参加学会，也是难得的休息方式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;像你这样年过八旬还种地的老人并不多，你为什么过这样的农民生活？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我家世代都是贫农，家里兄弟五人，我排行老二。我小时候就是孔子说的“吾少也贱，故多能鄙事”，除了上学外，要帮家里干活，种地、割野菜、砍柴火、喂猪牛，农村孩子做的活我都做Pass. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;快上中学时，邻村成立了初中，平谷东部、南部、北部地区的孩子都可以去读，结果我们报到后发现，只有一块空地。我们上学第一件事就挖地基，盖房子。过了半年多才有了间教室和食堂，还简单修了个篮球场，学生借用村民的房屋当宿舍和厨房。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;当时学校经费不够，刚好有一个做布鞋的制鞋厂，我们承包了厂里一部分工程。我的制鞋技术较好，就让我做了监督员。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;中考时，全县就收百来个高中生，我是村里第一个考上高中的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;高考时，只考数学、语文、化学3门。夏天我躺在野地上、山坡上看着朗朗晴空，流星一个接一个，银河系清晰可见，所以填报大学志愿时，第一志愿报了天文系，但只招几个人，我就落选了。北京政法学院是最后一个志愿，我的成绩达线，就被录取过去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你那个年代的大学是什么样子的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我是1962年入学，学制先是5年，后改为4年，主要学政治和法学各科目，前两年在学马克思主义、批判修正主义，其间还组织去四川峨眉县（现峨眉山市）搞“四清”运动。大学毕业后，我被分到广西去，但人家广西接收单位发来电报：“请暂缓报到。”这就暂缓了两年。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;两年之后去广西，印象最深的是什么？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我刚到广西的单位，还没落脚，行李都没打开，领导就组织员工敲锣打鼓把我送到农村接受贫下中农教育，进行劳动锤炼。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我被分配在中越边境的一个村庄，和农民同吃同住。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我分在楼房下层住，脚底对着牛棚，我床下的空间也没浪费，养了一窝小狗，贴着我耳朵的是隔壁家的鸡笼。早晨三四点，头牛开始排便，粪便味热气腾腾，马上扩散到整个楼屋，然后我床底下的狗也开始排便。这些都是小事，狗粪我每天早晨清理，牛粪气味难闻，但也不沾身。最难的就是公鸡司晨，让我没法休息。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我在起初很不适应，经半年多的刻苦磨炼，终于可以同当地农民一样光脚走碎石路、下水田扶犁插秧，像一个有模有样的地道农民了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我在广西农村最大的收获是：耐得饥苦，磨炼了坚韧的意志，为我后来的人生发展打下了深厚的基础。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;什么时候决定参加研究生考试的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;在农村待了两年后，我回到县里，后来又到农村做人文基本教育工作队的队员。虽然读了大学但没有发挥余地，感到个人前途茫茫。另一方面，我乡土观念浓厚，故土难离，还是想回到北方发展。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1977年的一天，夫人突然托人从县城给我带话，说国家要招研究生。我了解了一下，确实是一个机会。但我大学没学得很扎实，到农村又待了10年，没有报纸看、没有广播听。当时我就想，我们1962年毕业的那一批本科生是四百多人，加上再往前两三年毕业的，也就一千多人。这些人中有很多已成家立业，不少人做了领导，有稳定的收入和家庭，所以最后报考的人肯定不多，估计也就百来个人。我还是决定试一试，就找县领导汇报，他很支持，让我回县城准备考试了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;毕竟放下书本十几年了，怎么备考？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;当时只有两个月的准备时间，第一个难题是，我找不到书，尤其没有专业书可看。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;再一个难题就是英语，大学时学的英语基本都荒废了。我借了初中教材，从ABCD开始学，心里完全没底，学两三个月，自认为有所长进，可以考试了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那最终怎么应对考试的呢？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;考试前一天，我还在火车上背教材、1975年宪法和一些报纸文章。考试题目，也是天助我也。我记得当时作文题目是“跟着华主席进行新的长征”，而法理考题就五个字——“法兰西内战”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;领导新的长征，那作文就都是较为熟悉的政治话语，自然难不倒考生的，就看个人发挥如何。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;备考期间，我借阅了一些马列主义的书。对书中讲述的无产阶级革命和无产阶级专政的文章，例如《哥达纲领批判》《法兰西内战》等反复阅读，多有体会，所以对法理学考题应答起来，自然就顺畅了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;只剩下英语没底，结果一打开考卷就高兴了，那是《人民日报》一篇关于农业学大寨的英文报道，我英语不行，但对大寨人改天斗地的壮举和里面的专业名词是很熟悉的。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;比如，让你翻译“七沟八梁”，“沟”和“梁”的英语我不认识，但是我一看“七（seven）”和“八（eight）”，我马上就知道这肯定是七沟八梁，这一下英语过关了。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;82宪法通过后，“小有名气”&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;研究生生活，和想象中有不一样的地方吗？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;1978年9月1日上学，到中国社科院法学所报到后，才发现研究生也没有校舍。学校领导就到北京师范大学借地方，我们在人家楼间空地用油毛毡盖了个简陋的教室，借了楼房做宿舍，一屋8人。研究生阶段的学习和生活就这样安置下来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;一年多以后，社科院研究生院也觉得不方便，就让我们搬出来，又住到北京市十一学校go.平时，我们去社科院法学所上课，上完课再回来。我每天学习12个小时，早晚锻炼2小时，睡6个小时。就这样艰苦学习三年，我学习成绩还算优秀，学校领导也比较满意，1980年硕士毕业就留在法学所工作。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这与本科毕业后被分到广西农村工作，感受完全不一样了吧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那确实，特别是我一参加工作马上就进入到与制定82宪法相关的工作中。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;具体有哪些工作是你参与过的？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;宪法修改的牵头工作主要由时任全国人大常委会法制委员会副主任的张友渔先生负责，专设了秘书处，负责调研和起草工作。当时中国社科院法学研究所所长王叔文是秘书处成员，所以秘书处的一些学术调研和资料准备工作，便自然地由张友渔直接交与王叔文承担。王叔文每次领回任务急匆匆赶回法学所，就召集全体工作人员分工承办。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;我们5个人一般都不准离开单位，24小时坚守工作岗位，一来指示我们马上调研，不舍昼夜地写调研报告，当时都只能在办公室里简单休息一下，夜深了，我们自己买碗泡面吃。那时找资料很难，学术界一片荒芜。法学所里有过去清华北大转来的图书，二十多年没人看，灰尘都有一寸厚，我就把尘土扒开找资料。从1980年开始准备，到1982年宪法修改完成，我们这样一直坚持了两年多。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;制宪的流程很复杂。我们只是做最初步的工作，报告提交后，秘书处的专家们又汇总征求各方意见，再提到领导层面。草案通过后，一共由《人民日报》公布了三次征求意见。当时民众参与热情很高，可能希望通过宪法的制定和实施，永远结束“文革”那样的社会无序和国家混乱的状态。在全民参与讨论过程中，收集了三千多条意见，甚至连哪个字、哪个标点该用什么，都有人提出来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;参与制定82宪法相关工作给你个人带来了什么影响没有？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>; 82宪法通过后，宪法一下变成全民瞩目的大事件。首先是大量的宣传，当时连我这种“小喽啰”发表在报纸上的豆腐块文章都有上百篇。出版社也纷纷向我们约稿，从领导到专家，到我们这些小人物。我广泛地参与出版新宪法宣传的小册子，不下几十本。在这个过程中我就“小有名气”了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;说到张友渔先生，你对他有什么特别的印象？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为修改宪法，我和张友渔先生有了往来，当时他已经八十多岁，觉得我写的文章比较耐看，所以喜欢找我帮他撰写文稿，然后由他修改，我也实际上承担了他的文字秘书工作。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;1982年左右，国务院有领导提倡由几位泰斗级的老专家以传统的“师徒”形式培养学术传承人，当时张友渔先生就选了我。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;从学一年多，国家改变了传承的师徒模式，正式改为现代博士教育制度。我就参加国家规定的博士生考试，考法理、宪法、英语和政治，我是唯一的考生，就这样成了他的博士研究生。 &lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;作为学者要保持“平常心”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你跟随张先生研究宪法学，后来怎么具体关注宪法监督了？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;因为82宪法实施后，它只是一个文本上的法律规定。但政府机关执行过程中是否正义、是否符合理性、宪法的实施和监督机制是否科学，都需要继续研究。自然而然，我就进入宪法监督理论的研究中，宪法监督司法化是我十几年来的主攻方向，我先后出版了3本书，其中一本是我修改和扩容后的博士论文。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;宪法学的宿命注定要和国家最高权力打交道。当时我极力主张把全国人大常委会的法律委员会改成宪法和法律委员会。这是我提出来的，后来经宪法学界一代又一代反复论证，2018年，终于在全国人大常委会设立“宪法和法律委员会”。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你怎么看学术与政治的关系？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;学术不能脱离社会，也不可能与政治完全隔绝。有相当一部分学者，他们将自己主要的学术兴趣和注意力放在直接为现实的政治、法律服务上面。这本无可厚非，现实的问题当然需要有人去研究，这也是一门大学问，而且是更为艰难的学问。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;问题是，做这种学问的人应当调整好自己的心态，要有如下的思想准备，即并不是任何针对现实问题作出的研究报告、提出的改进意见，都应当或可能被有关的政治决策机构所接受和采纳。我们说过，理论上的结论与政治上的决策并不总是相吻合的。理论上需要细推物理、洞幽察微，而政治上则要权衡利弊、趋利避害，两者所站立场不同，追求的价值目标不同，结论和决定自然也会不同。 As a scholar, it is important to maintain a &quot;normal heart&quot;.自己的意见被采纳了，自然是一件令人高兴和鼓舞的事，即使没有被采纳，也不应当感到失望和灰心。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;就你而言，做学问的乐趣何在？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的书出版了，有人去看、去体会，你觉得好就接受，不好就拒斥。但我们做学问本身不考虑它的影响，那是时人和后人是否认同的问题。我写的书可能要三五十年以后，才有人有兴趣去深读，知道那时有一个学者做过这样的研究，他有这样思想上的超前认识。 I don&#39;t expect this generation to understand. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;做学术不只是为了博取实际利益，为学也是一种“稻粱之谋”、养家糊口的一种手段，之外我做学术还是为了增加我的学识。我按照自己的研究思路摸索前进，勇于探索，一生治学、自甘寂寞，绝不为潮流所动，不跟风。所以我在某学会上自嘲说，我是学术界的孤魂野鬼。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: normal;&quot;>;我只想把这学问做深做透，做到我自认为成熟的程度，就能从中感受到乐趣。我的学生说，30年过去了，现在还在研究我当时研究“宪法监督”的主题。因为宪法监督的研究任务任重道远。在学术生涯中，我走过一段有意义又曲折的道路，我如果能把这方面学问做到极致，也是一种能聊以自慰的幸事。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;“我为故我在”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong >;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在年轻人，不管是找工作还是考研究生，都面临激烈的竞争，同时他们也较为迷茫.你对年轻人有什么建议？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我在北师大教了七八年书，这个情况我深有体会。一个硕士或博士考进来，第一件事是考证，司法从业资格证、计算机证书、雅思等。 3年的时间你要考五六个证，哪有时间去学习看书？证考得差不多了，就该四处投简历找工作了。等到硕士论文答辩还有两周时，他才匆忙拼凑论文，其质量可想而知。我一向告诉学生做好学问，将来不愁找不到工作，是金子都要发光的。这个社会总是要由有学识、有远见的人才能支撑起来。但第二，社会竞争这么激烈，毕业即失业，现在很多人博士毕业送外卖，这是很现实的。如果你一开始把自己的起点放这么低，就找份工作养家糊口，我们的社会怎么能进步？过去我们讲“我思故我在”，现在我觉得是“我为故我在”，你之所以成为你，都是你自己做过的事造就的。个人自我实现、获得成功，总是要付出很大乃至毕生的努力。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方周末：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;您怎么看待现在的硕士、博士培养制度? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;陈云生：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我认为我们现在的培养制度是一种灌输式教育，而且严进宽out.我读博时，老师们三五星期才上一堂课，主要是靠自己跑到外面听讲座、听学术会议，千万百计地扩大知识面。我在美国访学时，学校每天邀请一个外校或本校的教授在午饭时做主题演讲，其他人边吃边听，或放下刀叉举手提问，分分钟都不浪费。现在的学生对参与学术活动也没有那么活跃了。所以现在和以前的培养模式差别主要是，一个是灌输式的，一个是启发式的；一个是开放式，一个封闭式的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 12:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[江苏205国道将收费引质疑：公共福利易涨难降，能否推进有待观察丨快评]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260825]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Recently, a toll station was built on the Huai&#39;an section of 205 National Highway in Suqian, Jiangsu, and the news that vehicle tolls will be collected soon has aroused social concern. great concern and doubt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to China Jiangsu Net, on October 20, the Jiangsu Provincial Government approved that after the Suhuai Toll Station of National Highway 205 is completed and meets the traffic conditions, it will be managed as a government loan repayment road and jointly operated by Suqian and Huaian. Charges have been set and the charging standards for various types of vehicles have been determined, ranging from 10 yuan to 50 yuan. Media reports indicate that the toll station has been built. This means that tolls may be activated on this section of the national highway at any time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;New toll stations on national highways! Many people believe that this is contrary to the country&#39;s policy of gradually canceling ordinary highway toll stations in recent years. However, the Jiangsu Provincial Transportation Department stated that the toll collection of first-class highways for which the government repays loans complies with the policy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the current &quot;Toll Road Management Regulations&quot;, roads constructed by the government using loans or paid funds raised from enterprises and individuals can collect tolls upon approval. The Suqian and Huai&#39;an sections of National Highway 205 were built with government loans. According to the Jiangsu Transportation Department, this section still has nearly 1 billion yuan in debt to be repaid. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After sorting out the historical context of the Suhuai Toll Station on National Highway 205, we can find that the toll collection on this section is not a recent decision. In the early 2010s, the Suqian and Huai&#39;an sections of National Highway 205 were successively renovated and expanded and upgraded to first-class highways. In 2014, the Jiangsu Provincial Government approved in a document the establishment of a toll station at the junction of National Highway 205 Huai&#39;an and Suqian, and the two cities will jointly charge fees. In 2018, the Jiangsu Provincial Development and Reform Commission approved the feasibility report for the construction of the toll station. Today, the toll station is built and the provincial government issues documents approving the toll. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the minds of many people, only expressways still charge tolls, and all other ordinary highway toll stations have been abolished. However, in fact, there are not only ordinary highway toll stations, but they have increased in the past two years. According to information released on the official website of the Jiangsu Provincial Department of Transportation, as of December 2022, there are still more than 10 national and provincial highway toll stations in Jiangsu Province. Also on National Highway 205, more than 90 kilometers north of Suhuai Toll Station, there is Xinyi Toll Station. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;According to the National Toll Road Statistical Bulletin of the Ministry of Transport, at the end of 2021, there were 308 first-level highway main line toll stations and 115 second-level highway main line toll stations across the country. Compared with the end of the previous year, there were 308 second-level highway main line toll stations. The number of toll stations decreased by 7, but there were 8 more toll stations on first-class highways. The total mileage of tolled first-class highways was 17,600 kilometers, an increase of more than 200 kilometers over the previous year. Media reports show that since 2022, at least 7 new national highway toll stations have been added in various provinces. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, in recent years, it has become a trend to cancel tolls on ordinary highways. The central government has repeatedly proposed reducing road transportation costs and reducing road and bridge tolls. As early as 2009, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Transport and the Ministry of Finance jointly issued a document calling for the gradual and orderly elimination of tolls on secondary roads for government loan repayment. The revised draft of the &quot;Toll Road Management Regulations&quot; released in 2018 stipulates that the construction of new first- and second-level toll roads and independent bridges and tunnels will be stopped, and only expressways can collect tolls. However, this revision has not yet been completed. In 2020, the General Office of the State Council forwarded the &quot;Implementation Opinions on Further Reducing Logistics Costs&quot; from the National Development and Reform Commission and the Ministry of Transport, once again requesting to ensure that the overall burden of truck tolls is not increased. Under these policies, a large number of toll plazas have been eliminated across the country. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Therefore, although Jiangsu’s new 205 National Highway Suhuai Toll Station collects fees, it is not impossible to rely on it. Although the project was established based on loans for road construction and toll repayment at the beginning of the reconstruction and expansion, the funds mainly came from banks. Loans, and there are still huge loans that have not been repaid, but this is now and then. In the early 2010s, the construction and reconstruction of first- and second-level toll roads was still allowed, but after a few years the policy has changed. Except for expressways, the central government has discouraged and even explicitly proposed to stop the construction of first- and second-level toll roads, and many places have also canceled them. A large number of toll stations on primary and secondary roads have been installed. Especially in the past year or two, due to the impact of the epidemic, the economy is struggling to recover. Under such circumstances, adding new toll stations and increasing public transportation costs will of course be questioned by the public. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Although there is no explicit regulation, &quot;national highways, provincial highways and other ordinary highways should be free of charge&quot; has become &quot;common sense&quot; in the public mind, just like highways are free on holidays. Once this kind of psychological expectation is formed, if you want to reverse it, you will certainly be questioned. It is easy to bring welfare from scratch, but it is difficult to bring it from existence to nothing. It is easy to go from paid to free, but difficult to go from free to paid. If the previously charged service is changed to free, the public will think they have benefited. But conversely, if it was free before and now it has to be charged, everyone will feel that their interests have been violated. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is true not only in public policy, but also in business. Since the birth of the Internet, various services have been almost free for ordinary users. Netizens are accustomed to enjoying free services. Once charges start to be charged, they will of course feel very unhappy if they have to pay to watch videos or use large-capacity, high-speed download network disks. Broadband and data traffic have been charged from the beginning, and no one thinks these should be free. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, a truly free lunch does not actually exist. If you want to watch free videos, you have to endure a lot of ads; if you want to use a free network disk, you can only endure the download speed of a small water pipe. Likewise, public benefits also need to be paid for by someone. There are no tolls on national highways, and construction and maintenance costs are indispensable. They can only come from fiscal revenue such as taxes, which means taxpayers must pay for them. If the local government&#39;s fiscal revenue is sufficient, then of course it won&#39;t be a problem. But if finances are tight, I&#39;m afraid we can only reduce spending on road construction and maintenance, or consider charging fees. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Suhuai Toll Station of National Highway 205 is preparing to collect fees at this time, which may be related to the local financial difficulties in recent years. But it remains to be seen whether it can move forward after attracting huge attention and opposition. Although Suqian and Huai&#39;an are in northern Jiangsu and are less economically developed than southern Jiangsu, they are still much more prosperous than many places in the west. There is still 1 billion in road construction loans, which may not be too big for local finances. of holes. What&#39;s more, Jiangsu, as the country&#39;s second largest economic province, should have enough financial resources to make transfer payments to local governments. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;However, if no tolls are allowed on national and provincial roads in the future, will the enthusiasm of local governments to build new roads be greatly reduced? This is also worth noting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 11:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[的里雅斯特：微型世界丨意长意短]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260814]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-18 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/17/gFlg06M7cgduE6nvUXaxWXkllUq2SXgeMB5ummeC.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;736&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/17/gFlg06M7cgduE6nvUXaxWXkllUq2SXgeMB5um meC. jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;258623&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Trieste in 1895. &lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;(Visual China/Photo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time I pass through Trieste, I have to go and sit for a while in the ancient San Marco Cafe . This city has the best coffee in Italy, and the headquarters of Illy is here. Like many cities that were once glorious and then fell into silence, this city is half reality and half exists in words. Trieste was once the most important port of the Austro-Hungarian Empire and a blend of Slavic, Latin and Germanic cultures. More than a hundred kilometers away, Venice has kept the world&#39;s attention in a flashy way. Although every stone that built it came from elsewhere, and all the beauty is artificial, the first sight of Venice will make you wonder. One feels amazed and mesmerized. In comparison, Trieste is a sleepy city. She is located in the northeastern border of Italy, more than ten kilometers away in Slovenia. It faces the sea, backed by karst rocks, and under the mountains are checkerboard-like neighborhoods. There are many deep houses and compounds on the mountain. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;James Morris, an Englishman who served as a soldier here, later changed his gender and became Jane Morris. After World War II, she wrote full-time and became a reporter for The Guardian and a famous travel writer. In her book &quot;Trieste and the Meaning of Nowhere&quot; (Trieste and the Meaning of Nowhere), Trieste is an unforgettable city, but when she tried to remember it, she found that it was like an unforgettable city. Presented face. This city has no unforgettable scenery, no unique food, and it doesn’t even have an Italian flavor. In a 1999 survey, 70% of Italians didn’t even know that this city belongs to Italy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Despite this, Trieste also has her unique charm. This former free port chose to be included in Italy during the dispute between Yugoslavia and Italy in the last century. The chaotic past can stimulate people&#39;s imagination and reflection. She is more literary than any other city. At the beginning of the last century, Joyce lived in many places in this city. He worked as an English teacher and began to write &quot;Ulysses&quot; here. For him, Trieste was a particularly draining place for his liver. Joyce interacted with the melancholy Italo Svevo, encouraged the Jewish businessman to write, and highly praised his &quot;Zeno&#39;s Consciousness&quot;. Svevo&#39;s writing has a slowness that is rare in Italian. Most of the writing is about a businessman questioning his own conscience, which complements the thoughtfulness of a stream-of-consciousness novel. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a kind of continuity in the literature of this city. The writings of contemporary Trieste writer Claudio Magris also have the melancholy of Svevo, and his works are very similar to It was translated from German into Italian, which is not surprising since Magris is a professor of German literature at the university. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If a writer wants to present a city, it is actually difficult to capture its spirit and soul. Magris has been telling stories about the land. As the most important seaport in the Austro-Hungarian Empire, Trieste&#39;s once glorious history made her current situation look bleak, and the entire city was shrouded in a twilight. Magris&#39;s writing is, in a sense, a pursuit of Trieste&#39;s literary tradition and an attempt to get closer to reality. His &quot;Micro World&quot;, which won the &quot;Strega&quot; award but is difficult to classify, has many texts related to the space of the city and the literature of the past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is difficult for a person with limited life experience to establish a deep connection with the vast world. Sociologist Xiang Biao proposed the concept of &quot;nearness&quot;. Magris is an example of practicing &quot;neighborhood&quot;. He lives in this city and uses the tenacity of a scholar to understand the place and penetrate deeply into the life here. His &quot;miniature world&quot; actually consists of cafes, parks and Sacré Coeur. After reading his &quot;Micro World&quot; and then seeing the San Marco Cafe, the park and the nearby Sacré Coeur, you will recognize everything and feel that the world is what he described. The San Marco Cafe, which opened in 1914, has a very high ceiling with leaves and coffee beans on the top. The ebony bar and the wine racks against the wall stand firmly there. You will recognize the mask behind the counter. There is a The golden coffee machine with the flying eagle logo and the lion-shaped table legs under the table are reminiscent of Saint Mark, the patron saint of Venice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The city’s ancient cafes resist the times in their own way. In the San Marco Cafe, the bar is still made of solemn dark wood, and the tables, chairs and wall decorations are still the same as a hundred years ago. One side of its &quot;L&quot;-shaped structure has been transformed into a bookstore, filled with nostalgic books. The most conspicuous place is Magris&#39;s &quot;Micro Worlds&quot;, which has dozens of pages describing the past and present of the San Marco Café. The café is the living room of the city, an open public space where some faces disappear and new ones appear. In this urban space, the history of literature here is recorded. Cafe San Marco is a place frequented by literary &quot;pilgrims&quot;. Everyone, in their own way, hopes that this cultural &quot;ark&quot; will continue to exist. In addition to drinking coffee, you can also eat exquisite pasta in this cafe. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After coming out of the cafe, you can go for a walk in the nearby park to get some fresh air. There are towering plane trees in the park, and the sun shines through the leaves, and the golden light falls on a pool in the garden, which Magris also described. There are benches everywhere in the garden, where people read newspapers, books, or just sit around. There is a children&#39;s playground and an open-air cinema at the end of the park. Statues of city celebrities are scattered around, including a bust of Joyce wearing a hat and glasses, which was erected on the centenary of his birth in 1982, and a bust of local poet Saba, a second-hand bookseller of Jewish origin. , a neurotic patient and the cultural soul of Trieste, once wrote a poem titled &quot;Trieste&quot;:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Italics , 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I walked through the whole city,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;climbed a large Slope,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It was crowded at first, but then the road became empty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;At the end of the road is a low wall:&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;I am sitting alone in this small corner. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Where the low wall ends,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style =&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It is also where the city ends. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Trieste has an inaccessible beauty. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;If you like, this city is like a rough, &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt; p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Greedy wild child, &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_ GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Having blue eyes and using a pair of overly large hands&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sent A flower;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Like a paragraph full of jealousy&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt; span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;&#39;s love. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 凯体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;On this hillside, I see the city (Trieste)&lt;/ span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Every church, every street, even the crowded beach,&lt;/span>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;And the top of the mountain is full of rocks&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font -family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The last house seems to be firmly rooted there. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Everything around me&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style= &quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;all have a strange, tortured feeling,&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti _GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;This is the smell of hometown (this is where I was born). &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: KaiTi, KaiTi_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Every part of my city is full of life&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;She reserved a corner for me, suitable for me&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti , Italics_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;A worried and lonely life. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Everyone lives in the corners of the city, including poets like Saba. The city has beaches, hills, and therefore a hint of countryside. Watching life from above, but not participating in it, while not feeling like an outsider, is exactly what this city offers Saba. Magris lives in this city in another way. He exists in a strict ritual, as cautious and solemn as the black and white marble floor of the Sacre Coeur. For him, everything was close by, a trip to the park was like traveling around the world, the clear cistern of the Sacre Coeur was like a spring in the glade, and the dim light of the church was as deep as the sea at night. Unfathomable. His life permeates the San Marco Cafe, the Park in the Street and the Sacred Heart Church two steps away. Magris even designed a reassuring ending for himself: with the comfort of his two sons, he lives in the Sacred Heart Church. In the golden sky painted by the church, jump through the ring of fire held by two angels. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Trieste described by Magris is a city of twilight. In 2019, when he was 80 years old, he published &quot;The Bent Time of Krems&quot;. This is a book about twilight. There are five short stories in the book, telling the stories of five men in their twilight years. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In &quot;The Concierge&quot;, there is an old man who is reluctant to advance but to retreat, a president who once owned several companies. He enters an unknown field to get rid of the reality of facing enemies on all sides. He is a Czech who walked from the interior to Trieste for development. When he was young, the world was beautiful and big. He played his role successfully, building himself a strong armor with checks and profits. However, one day, his desire for success and inner panic left him. He became relaxed, sold his company, and became a concierge of an apartment with a calm mood. Once the sea has returned to the waterside safely. He tries to avoid roads where he can see the sea in the morning, takes the bus, and then walks to work. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protagonist of &quot;Music Lesson&quot; is a Polish Jew who has entered his twilight years, a survivor with shame. He takes a car to go up the mountain to the home of his former student. The student, who became a musical master, showed him a piece of music he had composed as a tribute to the tragedy of the Jews, and he accepted the piece with embarrassment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The protagonist in &quot;Bent Time in Krems&quot; is the closest thing to Magris. He gives a lecture on Kafka and has dinner in a city called Krems. At the dinner party, someone mentioned Noni, the goddess of his youth, and by chance, he actually contacted her later. The &quot;now&quot; changes the &quot;before&quot;, time becomes curved, and all that is left is &quot;his&quot; longing for the god-like Noni. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Awarding&quot; is about an old writer attending a literary award ceremony, feeling melancholy and relieved as time passes. In &quot;Outing Day&quot;, an old man went to the set to see the actor who played him in his youth. Everything was different from the previous story, and the old man got a kiss that he missed when he was a teenager. The five fragments of life are all based on the theme of &quot;old age&quot;, allowing people to see the scene of the city&#39;s twilight reflecting on life: the sunset fills the sky, and everything tends to be relieved. Magris uses short words to accurately outline some life fragments. The past and present coexist at the same time, and death becomes infinitely gentle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In addition to Magris, there is also a world-class best-selling female writer Susana Tamaro among the contemporary writers in Trieste. Most Italian families have her book &quot;Where the Heart Guidance&quot; 》. It was also a woman in her twilight years who was reckoning with the past through letters. There is also a writer recently introduced to the country - Gianfranco Kaligaric, who has certain connections with Trieste. He was born in Asmara, Eritrea, Africa. His family is a &quot;cosmopolitan&quot; family from Trieste, and he carries traces of the city&#39;s ethnic mix. He lived and worked in Milan and Rome. In 1974, he wrote the highly praised &quot;Waste of Summer&quot;. There is an indelible trace of youthful debauchery in his style, which still exudes endless charm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 10:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>