<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>southern weekend</title><description> Southern Weekend full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://infzm.com <item><title><![CDATA[成都地铁被疑偷拍案开庭，涉事女子“差一个道歉”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/260000]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 17:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;He Jun described the incident on Weibo, with diagrams of each scene . On November 3, 2023, he appeared in court wearing the shoes on the day of the incident. Internet screenshot&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/14932cc6aa.jpeg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;738&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/14932cc6aa.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257123&quot; >;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #999999;&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;Shoes suspected of containing secret camera equipment. On November 3, 2023, He Jun appeared in court wearing this pair of shoes. Internet screenshots&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The incident of a man being suspected of being secretly photographed on the subway in Chengdu originated on June 1, 2023. The person involved, He Jun (pseudonym), wrote in a long post on Weibo that he was secretly photographed on the subway by a small camera hidden in his shoes. He was then carried to the platform by a subway security guard and stood with one foot off his shoes and socks. span>;&lt;span>;The crowd&lt;/span>; watches. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun believes that this process is like a shadow in life. For this reason, he went through many twists and turns and brought the two women involved and the Chengdu Metro to the court, demanding a public apology and financial compensation. The incident occurred a week after a Sichuan University girl falsely accused migrant workers of secretly filming her, and thus attracted much attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Nearly half a year after the incident, on November 3, 2023, He Jun sued two women for a general personality rights dispute in the Chengdu Railway Transportation First Court. . The trial lasted for two and a half hours that day, and no verdict was announced in court. He Jun said on Weibo that when he recalled the entire process during the trial, he still felt very uncomfortable and had to constantly restrain his emotions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Dan, He Jun’s attorney, mentioned, “Leave aside the issue of men and women, any person can defend themselves when their rights and interests are threatened. own rights.&quot; Liu Dan said that he understood the behavior of the woman involved in standing up bravely when she suspected that she was being secretly photographed; but with such rights, she should also bear corresponding obligations. After discovering that it was a misunderstanding, the woman involved&lt;span >;The child&lt;/span>; should apologize proactively. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/83324ca659.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot; 1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/83324ca659.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;257124&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;He Jun described the incident on Weibo, accompanied by diagrams of each scene. Internet screenshots&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Unacceptable apology&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun has told the story of the incident many times on different occasions. For the first time, He Jun wrote a long article on Weibo based on his own memories, and always kept this article at the top of Weibo. After the case entered the investigation and evidence collection stage, He Jun made additional corrections to some details based on the contents of surveillance videos and law enforcement recorders, and gradually updated them on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On June 11, 2023, He &lt;span>;Jun&lt;/span>; took the subway home from Xipu, Chengdu. When he arrived at the South Railway Station, there was Two girls said they saw the green light flashing on his shoes and suspected that he was filming secretly. According to the video provided by passengers in the same carriage, two girls pointed at his shoes and said, &quot;It&#39;s shining, it&#39;s not reflecting light, it&#39;s shining.&quot; &quot;When we were filming, he put it on closed&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the train safety officer of the car arrived, He Jun took off his shoes in public according to the girl&#39;s request. After the train safety officer and the two girls checked, no camera was found. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun recalled to Southern Weekend reporters before the court session that during this process, everyone on the train suddenly focused their attention on him, and some people deliberately looked out. When he looked up, he saw someone was taking pictures with a mobile phone, which already made him feel uncomfortable. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Another place that made him feel uncomfortable was when he arrived at the station. The security officer and the station attendant arranged for him to stand against the wall and take off his right shoe. He Jun said that the environment he was in at that time was a public place connected to the platform. Passengers coming and going could see him taking off his right shoe and socks and standing next to the wall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;&quot;I think this matter is not final. I was just a suspect at the time, so we should consider reducing some of the impact, such as taking me to a In a place with few people, maybe use something to block me, that’s what I thought.” He Jun believed that this was something Chengdu Metro did improperly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Dan, He Jun&#39;s attorney, told Southern Weekend reporters that they added Chengdu Metro as a defendant precisely because Chengdu Metro had problems with expanding the damage. It is true that the subway security officer did not force He Jun to take off his shoes or search him, but after a preliminary check that he was not secretly photographed, he could consider finding an office where the two parties could sit down and negotiate and wait for the police to arrive. Liu Dan said that in the case, He Jun also took the initiative to call the police. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;After the police took off He Jun&#39;s shoes for inspection, they confirmed that there was no camera. The police also showed a restored video taken at the same location on the subway, and speculated that the advertising plates on both sides were reflected on the shiny surface of the shoes, reflecting green light. After mediation by the police, the two &lt;span>;&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;girls&lt;/span>; apologized to He Jun. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun is not satisfied with this apology. He said that according to the video content of the law enforcement recorder reviewed afterwards, the older female student said &quot;I&#39;m sorry, handsome man&quot;, and the younger female student said immediately &quot;We I have wronged you.&quot; &quot;The entire sentence did not take more than two seconds,&quot; He Jun said. They were &lt;span>;wearing&lt;/span>; masks and could not hear clearly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;In the long article recorded by He Jun afterwards, the police mediation was still continuing, and the girl &lt;span>;&lt;/span>; emphasized that she was speaking for the public. , to prevent other people&#39;s privacy from being infringed, and He Jun emphasized that the two &lt;span>;girls&lt;/span>; &lt;span>;girls&lt;/span>; had a &quot;meal-eating&quot; mentality to share their experiences with their friends. &lt;p>; &quot;After they apologized, I think they may have made up their minds (to defend their rights),&quot; He Jun said. The next day, he took the initiative to post the experience online with the subject &quot;I was falsely accused of being secretly filmed by wearing a shoe-covered camera on the Chengdu subway.&quot; &quot;, hoping to record the progress of his rights protection, and also hope to find &lt;span>;eyewitnesses&lt;/span>; in the same carriage through the Internet. The post quickly attracted attention. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img alt=&quot;He Junfa&#39;s diagram on Weibo. Internet screenshot&quot; src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/d3a352aff2. jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;740&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/d3a352aff2.jpeg&quot; data-key= &quot;257125&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;A diagram posted by He Jun on Weibo. Internet screenshot&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;Do not support using violence to fight violence&lt;/h4>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;He Jun&#39;s rights protection process was not smooth. At first, He Jun could not find any evidence such as video of the scene to prove the place of occurrence, which made it impossible to file a case in court for investigation and evidence collection. After many twists and turns, a man in the same carriage provided a signed certificate stating that the incident had occurred on Chengdu Metro Line 1, and the case was officially filed on August 15. During subsequent evidence collection, Chengdu Metro informed the platform that the monitoring equipment was damaged and the video was missing. On September 27, after communicating with his lawyer, He Jun added Chengdu Metro as a defendant in the prosecution case. The main reason was that Chengdu Metro was suspected of breach of contract and infringement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Although some netizens demanded &quot;severe punishment&quot;, He Jun has not disclosed the two &lt;span>;names&lt;/span online in the six months since he posted this experience >;&lt;span>;Girls&lt;/span>; appearance, name and other private information. He does not support the method of &quot;responding to violence with violence.&quot; &quot;I have never had such an idea, and I have been calling on the media and netizens not to (defame or bully the other party online).&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ding Yaqing, a lawyer at Guangdong Zhiheng (Guangzhou) Law Firm, has represented cases involving sexual harassment liability disputes. She believes that the two women involved suspected that someone was filming secretly and found the subway security officer to intervene in the verification. There was no problem in itself. In some situations where sexual harassment is alleged, finding a third party to intervene can help resolve the dispute. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;The key is that after the facts were clarified, this man spent time and energy to cooperate with the investigation and was scrutinized in public. &quot;He felt bad.&quot; Therefore, it is necessary and reasonable to demand an apology and explanation. &quot;The core problem for the girls in this case is that the process of &lt;span>; and &lt;/span>; apologizing was not explained in the end.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;On the other hand, Ding Yaqing believes that Chengdu The train safety officers of the subway do not have the power to enforce the law, and their actions may not be appropriate in this regard. &quot;I noticed that the person involved said that the security officer carried him away,&quot; Ding Yaqing said. This &lt;span>;suggested&lt;/span>; whether the security officer exceeded his authority to conduct a search. She suggested that in places such as subways where sexual harassment accusations are prone to occur, staff should be trained, such as how to respond when such accusations occur, what are the staff&#39;s scope of authority, how to appease both parties, etc. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;She believes that the response to sexual harassment accusations in public places can be compared to passengers encountering theft on the subway or bus - find a third party, The police, who have law enforcement powers, do not need to raise the issue of differences between men and women and gender antagonism. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Ding Yaqing analyzed that in general personality rights infringement cases, the responsibilities stipulated by law include stopping the infringement, eliminating the impact, making an apology, etc. He Jun&#39;s current demands One is to publicly apologize, but whether the scope of disclosure refers to the place where the incident occurred or on social media such as Weibo, and to whom it is disclosed depends on the court hearing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;>;Liu Dan said that since the case is not open to trial, the form of a public apology cannot be disclosed. &quot;But it must be public, because the infringement is also public, and the apology It should also be made public.&quot; After the court hearing that day, Liu Dan said in an interview that there was a fierce debate in the court and the other party also provided tenable arguments. He did not have high expectations for the verdict. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 17:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[中央气象台发布寒潮、暴雪、大风、强对流四预警]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259998]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 16:00:51&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;At 06:00 on November 5, the Central Meteorological Observatory issued four major warnings: cold wave, blizzard, strong wind, and strong convection! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue a cold wave blue warning at 06:00 on November 5:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Affected by strong cold air, it is expected that at 08:00 on November 5 As of 20:00 on the 7th, the temperature in the eastern part of northwest China and most parts of central and eastern China will drop by 6 to 10 degrees Celsius. Among them, the temperature in central and eastern Inner Mongolia, the central and southern parts of Northeast China, and the central and eastern Jianghuai areas will drop by 12 to 14 degrees Celsius. ℃, the local cooling in southeastern Inner Mongolia, southwestern and eastern Jilin, central and northern Liaoning, and central and northern Jiangsu can reach more than 16℃; the lowest temperature occurred on the morning of the 7th, and the lowest temperature line of 0℃ will be located in northern Hebei and southern Beijing , southern Shanxi to the Guanzhong Plain of Shaanxi, southeastern Gansu, and most areas along the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River, the minimum temperature will drop to about 10°C. Areas north of the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River have northerly winds of magnitude 4 to 6, with gusts of magnitude 7 to 9, and locally up to magnitude 10; from the 5th to 6th, there are winds of magnitude 6 to 8 in the Bohai Sea, Yellow Sea, East China Sea and other sea areas, with the maximum gusts Level 9~10. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/88625308e4012be7a20db624fafd7401.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;703&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/88625308e4012be7a20db624fafd7401.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257118&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/abe6c2d110d5768a275edc42e989ecd7.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;821&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/abe6c2d110d5768a275edc42e989ecd7.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257115&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue an orange warning for heavy snowfall at 06:00 on November 5:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is expected that from 08:00 on November 5 to 08:00 on the 7th, the central and eastern parts of Inner Mongolia and the northeastern region will There were heavy to heavy snowfalls from west to east in the central and western regions and northern parts of the country. Some areas had heavy snowstorms, and local heavy snowstorms (30 to 38 mm). The new snow depth was 10 to 20 cm, and locally it could reach more than 25 cm. The main snowfall period is from the night of the 5th to the 6th. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From 08:00 on November 5 to 08:00 on November 6, there were heavy snowfalls in parts of central and eastern Inner Mongolia, northern Hebei, northwest Liaoning, and southeastern Heilongjiang. Among them, southeastern Inner Mongolia and southeastern Heilongjiang There were heavy local heavy snowfalls (20-22 mm) in parts of the country. The new snow depth in some of the above-mentioned areas is 5 to 10 centimeters, and it can reach more than 15 centimeters in some places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f3f35e9297889d60a2245f55010652bb.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;821&quot; height=&quot;679&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f3f35e9297889d60a2245f55010652bb.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257117&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;From 08:00 on November 6 to 08:00 on November 7, there were heavy snowfalls in parts of southeastern Inner Mongolia, central and eastern Heilongjiang, central and western Jilin, and central and northern Liaoning, including southern and eastern Heilongjiang, Jilin, and other places. Local heavy snowfall (30-38 mm) occurred in northern and other places; there was local freezing rain in central and western Jilin, southern Heilongjiang and other places. The new snow depth in the above-mentioned areas is 10 to 20 centimeters, and it can reach more than 25 centimeters in some places. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/38fdf7821954eb60b71e596258dbcc96.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;704&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/38fdf7821954eb60b71e596258dbcc96.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257120&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue a blue warning for strong winds at 06:00 on November 5:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is expected that from 08:00 on November 5 to 08:00 on the 6th, central Xinjiang Northern, central and southern Inner Mongolia and southeastern Inner Mongolia, eastern Qinghai, central Gansu, Ningxia, northern Shaanxi, Shanxi, central and western Hebei, Beijing, eastern Tianjin, northern Henan, eastern Shandong, western Liaoning, western Jilin, southern Heilongjiang, southeastern Hubei, There will be strong winds of magnitude 5 to 6 and gusts of magnitude 7 to 9 in northern Hunan and northern Jiangxi; there will be strong winds of magnitude 7 to 8 and gusts of magnitude 9 in the Bohai Sea, Bohai Strait, most of the Yellow Sea, and the northern waters of the East China Sea. Winds in parts of the Taiwan Strait and the northern and central parts of the Yellow Sea can reach level 9, with gusts of level 10 to 11. &lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f4ef68884d0e0f3ed9c77ff1ed58606b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;821&quot; height=&quot;899&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f4ef68884d0e0f3ed9c77ff1ed58606b.jpeg&quot; data-key =&quot;257116&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;From 08:00 on November 6 to 08:00 on November 7&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;, &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;Bohai Sea, Bohai Strait, and most of the Yellow Sea , the northern waters of the East China Sea, the Taiwan Strait, the Bashi Strait, the ocean east of Taiwan, and the northeastern waters of the South China Sea will have strong winds of magnitude 7 to 8 and gusts of magnitude 9 to 10. The wind force in some areas of the Bohai Strait, northern and central Yellow Sea can reach 9 Level, gust level 10~11&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;; northern and southern Xinjiang, northern Tibet, central Qinghai, western Gansu, most of Inner Mongolia, most of Heilongjiang, central and western Jilin, northwestern and southern Liaoning, and most of Hebei , central Beijing, eastern Tianjin, central and eastern Shandong&lt;/span>;&lt;span>; and other places will have strong winds of magnitude 5 to 6 and gusts of magnitude 7 to 8&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;. &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/bd34849b91a8251e27248cfe28554b7e.jpeg&quot; border =&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;821&quot; height=&quot;899&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/bd34849b91a8251e27248cfe28554b7e.jpeg &quot; data-key=&quot;257119&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Central Meteorological Observatory will continue to issue blue warnings for severe convective weather at 06:00 on November 5:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is expected to be in November From 08:00 on the 5th to 08:00 on the 6th, some areas in southern Anhui, central and northern Jiangxi, central and southern Hunan, southern Guizhou, and central and northern Guangxi will have thunderstorms or hail of magnitude 8-10; central and southern Anhui, central Jiangsu There will be short-term heavy rainfall in some areas of , western Zhejiang, central and northern Jiangxi, eastern Hubei, most of Hunan, southern Guizhou, most of Guangxi, Hainan Island and other places. The maximum hourly rainfall is 30-40 mm, and locally it can reach 50 mm or more. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It is expected that the main impact period of strong convection will be from today to night. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/7209dba773e72e2e468f88cb09cb407d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1; &quot; width=&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;703&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/7209dba773e72e2e468f88cb09cb407d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257121&quot;>;&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/cda050a7d669ad6d47ed62dd383dbe2b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width =&quot;831&quot; height=&quot;703&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/cda050a7d669ad6d47ed62dd383dbe2b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257122&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 16:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[9.4分科幻动画，每一帧都脑洞大开]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259987]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 15:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;According to &quot;The Analysis of Dreams&quot;, people Can&#39;t imagine something I haven&#39;t seen before. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;But a recent American TV series has done it - &quot;Reign of the Scavengers&quot; (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Reign&quot;). &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This science fiction drama is produced by HBO Max, and its Douban score is stable at 9.4 points. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/b57b65c9292582aa7c369266dea59443.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;770&quot; height= &quot;345&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/b57b65c9292582aa7c369266dea59443.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257046&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Other science fiction The works are all trying to explain something clearly, or making it unclear to make the audience feel mysterious, but &quot;Dominion&quot; focuses on one thing: don&#39;t talk, feel first. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;01&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&quot;Dominion&quot; is adapted from the 2016 animated short &quot;Scavengers&quot; produced by Joe Bennett and Charles Huttner. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This work has no dialogue throughout, and the storyline is almost non-existent: a spaceship breaks down and loses contact, and a pair of male and female scientists on board become the only survivors. Thus, the two people began a wonderful life on the alien planet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/8dccca93ed7fb627b2a1c40f6edc4470.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/8dccca93ed7fb627b2a1c40f6edc4470.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257045&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It&#39;s like The alien version of &quot;Pulse of the Earth&quot; leads humans to experience a gorgeous adventure of imagination in a spectacular way. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, bugs that can be used as telescopes and gas masks;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04 /44B1E5F9EA121695CB5143575CD8414e.gif &quot;Border =&quot; 0 &quot;width =&quot; 640 &quot;height =&quot; 351 &quot;data-src =&quot; // Images.infzm.com/Mes/image/23/11/000 4/44B1E5F9EA121695CB5143575CD8414e.gif &quot;Data -key=&quot;257048&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;There is also a flying fish that can be used as a bamboo dragonfly when put into a backpack. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ef766eab154b4836f62f19add198ad01.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;353&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ef766eab154b4836f62f19add198ad01.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257054&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On this planet The creatures are beautiful, weird and absurd. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The drama series &quot;Dominion&quot; is an all-round expansion and extension of the short film &quot;Scavengers&quot;, developing the line of the spacecraft malfunctioning on the alien planet into three lines. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The first line is the story of Sam and Ursula. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Of these two people, one is a classic white man and the other is an independent and strong woman. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/20d5feb2ff1476c25bd7a4129185e6c7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/20d5feb2ff1476c25bd7a4129185e6c7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257049&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Two persons The creatures on this planet already have a certain level of understanding, and they can skillfully transform bugs into gas masks, and capture creatures to use as aircraft. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the process, we see that they still have a tendency to use living things as tools, but at the same time they have to be cautious, after all, they are surrounded by unknowns. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/6d849233303ff2b4acbb53a46aa9caa3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/6d849233303ff2b4acbb53a46aa9caa3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257047&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 2 Thread is the story of a black girl, Archie, and an artificial intelligence, Levi. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a robot, Levi originally simply received orders and performed tasks. But because a certain yellow creature on the planet gradually grew with its body, Levi seemed to have a will. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/6965c165b005531d005ae4726ef3e578.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/6965c165b005531d005ae4726ef3e578.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257052&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;It will be in As you explore this planet at night, you will feel pain and begin to understand the lives of other creatures. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/f6c628593669107293700d1de472e106.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;351&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/f6c628593669107293700d1de472e106.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257051&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 3 The thread is the story of Carmen, the unshaven uncle. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Carmen can hold up the entire line by himself because he has a connection with Blackie, a strange creature on the planet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/9dc2d966dc300e71edecb4ac53cd7b3d.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/9dc2d966dc300e71edecb4ac53cd7b3d.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257050&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The card door is small Black hunts, and Black feeds Carmen by creating hallucinations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Carmen&#39;s wife died when the spacecraft landed, so he suffered from severe depression. Xiao Hei took advantage of Carmen&#39;s longing for his wife and mentally controlled Carmen, making her think that their symbiotic relationship was a normal couple&#39;s relationship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/01aaa88d5e918344d93bd783c8fd01da.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;351&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/01aaa88d5e918344d93bd783c8fd01da.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257056&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Three lines The characters have a common purpose, which is to repair the damaged spacecraft and return to Earth. But those wonderful alien creatures brought them unspeakable shock. &lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;02&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;The painting style of &quot;Dominion&quot; is weird and imaginative, and it seems to have an ethereal and lonely beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, plants that can turn corpses into landscapes. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/1686a60eb1ef7a48d7c15d40f25df8c2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/1686a60eb1ef7a48d7c15d40f25df8c2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257053&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, mayfly A villain who lives and dies every day, from birth to death in just a short moment, just to bury new seeds, and then use his body as nourishment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/c547df2d44e986f19dc27b072d96085b.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;351&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/c547df2d44e986f19dc27b072d96085b.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257060&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For example, as White creatures that are as invisible as chameleons and moths. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/67d599567acd1ca33dd38cf46e94da04.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/67d599567acd1ca33dd38cf46e94da04.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257055&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;And those The densely packed and sturdy plants can be opened by a bird feather. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/a8ba59b21e59bbffcefd44ab9b80a13d.gif&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height= &quot;351&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/a8ba59b21e59bbffcefd44ab9b80a13d.gif&quot; data-key=&quot;257059&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Flying The beasts are not running aimlessly, but have the same breathing and rhythm, so the seemingly bulky creatures instantly become extremely light and beautiful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, it is difficult to say that there is any plot in this animation. The story here is secondary and the creature itself is the main thing. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The plants and animals here have their own beauty and uniqueness. They share the ecosystem of the entire planet, are related to each other, and live in harmony. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3aae2a2baad9b976b4cce35884b4e15e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3aae2a2baad9b976b4cce35884b4e15e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257065&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;03&lt;/ h4>; &lt;p>;At the beginning of the animation, when the spacecraft lost contact, someone reported the situation to the relevant person in charge. The person in charge understands that the top management will not spend manpower and material resources to find a spaceship. Therefore, we can only pray that no one survives, &quot;otherwise they will live an even worse life.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/25e1e044b37f0cdf7867e78abcc039ff.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/25e1e044b37f0cdf7867e78abcc039ff.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257058&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src =&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/8654cdf95383461e160dfc912ad190a3.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;// images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/8654cdf95383461e160dfc912ad190a3.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257057&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This is the tone that &quot;Reign&quot; wants to deny, life is like Grass mustard. The entire three lines actually emphasize that life itself is full of meaning. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the first line, the white uncle Sam has a nakedly hostile, repulsive and exploitative attitude toward alien creatures. He cannot accept unknown creatures and always looks at other creatures from a superior perspective. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When Ursula was shocked by the beauty of the living and dying plant villain, Sam was very angry, feeling that Ursula had deviated from the mission and was irrational. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/dfee3c0c682bd74543d15335b9c3bf68.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;604&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/dfee3c0c682bd74543d15335b9c3bf68.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257062&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So in this On the planet, Sam seemed out of place. Ursula, on the other hand, seems to be gradually mastering the rhythm of the planet. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;She put aside her own prejudices and tried to let perception take precedence, getting to know the planet step by step and discovering its beauty. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The same goes for Archie in the second line. At first, she had no feelings for Levi, only command and control. But gradually, she realized the changes in Levi, and felt the pulse of the planet through Levi&#39;s guidance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, artificial intelligence has actually completed the connection with living things earlier than humans, thus guiding humans to return to a state of childlike curiosity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/c6c5af4e6002655305e8d88c27af2919.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/c6c5af4e6002655305e8d88c27af2919.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257063&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Article 3 The Carmen in this line is different from the first two lines. He reaches a connection with the alien creature Xiao Hei in a way that loses his humanity. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;On the one hand, Carmen&#39;s use of tools as a human made Xiao Hei quickly become the king of the species. On the other hand, Carmen&#39;s obsession with illusions makes Xiao Hei lose the ability to distinguish the truth in the process of using tools. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e3f3cac002d9d9fc55b4940a90d67aa0.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e3f3cac002d9d9fc55b4940a90d67aa0.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257064&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, Man has become a captive and a tool, in a lower position, while the little black who enslaved him has reached the top of the food chain. But on the other hand, perhaps in the eyes of other creatures, human beings are like that scary fat little black insect, with endless greed and desire. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d9cfcf79dc8b1b7d90b4dc9fb25431b7.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height= &quot;608&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d9cfcf79dc8b1b7d90b4dc9fb25431b7.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257061&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This drama Although it is a science fiction work, it uses the method of weakening the plot and enlarging the picture to break the anthropocentric thinking path, trying to bring the audience into an almost wild and equal environment, and use imagination to awaken human beings to The awe of life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Here, the power of technology is hidden, but a kind of primitive vitality is filled with it. Here, no creature is superior to other creatures, and there is no large-scale plundering or killing. Everything is slow and orderly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;So, don’t talk, don’t think, feel first, is the most correct way to open this animation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 15:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[周涛　宿命狷狂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259996]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 14:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/ 11/05/98756b2c861e592ad4dfd9368f93a90b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/98756b2c861e592ad4dfd9368f93a90 b. jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257100&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Zhou Tao&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Picture/Liu Xin&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Whether it is in the oral autobiography &quot;A Man and Xinjiang&quot; or the novel &quot;Journey to the West&quot;, Zhou Tao regarded himself as a specimen in that period of history. His unscrupulous self-exposure is due to his background in military life and his arrogant nature, just like his unbridled poetry and prose. At the same time, it also presents the true ecology of this special group of cadres&#39; children in the long river of history. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border -box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;The beginning of chaos&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Kashgar in early October , next to Ustang Boyi Road, a thousand-year-old street in Id Kah, musical instrument shops and carpet shops selling hot wapu and tambourines are lined up, and the craftsmen making copper pots are clanging and banging, surrounded by black The vat where the stove is brewing&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 毷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;Sheep&lt;/span>;)&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;The meat is sizzling. With the heat, the fragrance spreads far and wide. The tourists who flock here will definitely not let go of these antiques. They either raise their mobile phones to take pictures, or they want to eat two vats of meat, fresh and hot. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Forty-six years ago, Zhou Tao, a college student in Xinjiang, never imagined that a place he thought was a &quot;purgatory&quot; would now become a place of fascination and curiosity for inland tourists. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&quot;When I heard that I was assigned here, my legs were weak. It&#39;s over, I collapsed.&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;Before decentralization Although he had experienced the &quot;baptism&quot; of starving and carrying food on the Yili farm in the past 26 years, he always regarded himself as a son of cadres and his life was definitely going up. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;This earth-yellow town completely buried his blueprint with its loneliness and indifference. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 凯体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;The crowded Uighur residential areas are all built with adobe and wood... The houses are like beehives, the roads are like spider webs, and the civil buildings are all yellow. You clearly walked in, but there were very few people around, you couldn&#39;t hear anyone&#39;s voice, and the doors facing the street were all closed, as if you had walked into an empty and silent mountain forest alone. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;It&#39;s like this every day. Ji Shuteng rides a bicycle from here to work at the prefectural committee and goes out under the city wall. From the gate of Daluo Dam, ride through the narrow dirt road on the side of the dam, pass through the road next to Abdul Kerim Street, then pass through the clanking streets of Ustangbuyi Street, and come to the cement-paved main street. On the spacious road, the car went straight down and arrived at the prefectural committee compound where he worked. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Kaiti, Kaiti_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——&quot;Journey to the West&quot;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;In the spring of 2018, 72-year-old Zhou Tao finally completed the autobiographical novel &quot;Journey to the West&quot; in his attic. He originally named it &quot;The Beginning of Chaos&quot; to refer to the confusion of young people during the &quot;Cultural Revolution&quot; who could not see the way forward.在《当代》发表之前的某天，他忽地意识到，自己和同伴下放到偏远之地，正是一路向西之径：而“西方是日落的地方，雪的囤积地，向西去的路是暮云低垂如挽幛的路，人的心始终蜷缩在胸膛里，谁也不知道下一步踏在一个什么虚空上。或许，一不小心就会从地球的边缘掉下去”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/e041c1723aae44d699deeaaa33e04203.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;863&quot; height=&quot;1265&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/e041c1723aae44d699deeaaa33e04203.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257101&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他在书中写了屈铭那样一个前有理想、后带城府的“革命文人”生涯，写出了一个“完美的政治泥鳅”成志敏，以及司马义·艾合买提江那样得体的维族干部，描摹出边地喀什的权力派系渊源与丛林法则。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;而书中的主角姬书藤，长着一副帅皮囊，腹有诗书、心高气傲、内心随俗、外强中干，政治上不具备与外界抗衡的能力，眼力与生活又处处倚仗妻子，很难不让对作者略有了解的读者生出一句：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这就是周涛自己吧？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;文学评论家、《解放军文艺》主编殷实初次看到书稿，感到震撼，太直接了！ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“1980年代有很多伤痕文学暴露时代的问题，大多数是一种受害者的控诉，写一个人物或者事件的时候，似乎隐藏着不满和轻微的抗议，带着很隐晦的批判，但它不清楚，并没有针对具体的政治生活、政治任务，或者政治信念的描述。写到所谓的反面人物的时候，不往他的内心深处走，只是简单地符号化。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;殷实指出，在《西行记》里，青少年时代到延安读鲁艺，受过红色教育的屈铭，在“文革”期间变成了投机者和程墙背后的谋士，寄望于另一场“革命”的成功和新的利益分配——这正是姬书藤逐渐摆脱屈铭影响的主要原因。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛还写到了农民出身的“造反派”程墙内心的想法，他对上层政治走势的判断，以及——他壮烈的、忠于内心信仰的自杀方式。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;姬书藤不喜欢程墙，但当程墙成了囚犯，他却一点儿也高兴不起来，程墙近乎于勇的跳崖自尽，更是让他惊心。 “他见不得别人落难，就像他不能容忍任何人飞扬跋扈……热爱自由，崇尚平等，姬书藤也是逐渐看到了自己天性中的另一面。一个人或一些人欺负、凌辱另一个人或一些人，并不是什么稀松平常的事，这是那种非常恐怖的行为；这种事一旦开了头，迫害、虐待、杀戮和毁灭就会随之而来。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在喀什的8年里，屈铭和程墙在为人处世上塑造了姬书藤，最终被他超越，然而姬书藤并未因此逃脱更为可怕的精神恐怖与心灵磨难。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;因为在闲聊中讲了对领导的内心看法被人举报，姬书藤开始写检查，人立刻像个泄了气的皮球。他在检查里写，自己一定要“脱胎换骨”云云，不想竟真的如蛇一样蜕起皮来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;“不疼，一点都不疼，你就放心揭它，没事！”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;（妻子）庄延揭下来一块，放在旁边让他看。又揭下来一大块，“哎哟，好大的一块！”他偏过脸去一看，有半张小报那么大一块，白纸一张，质地坚韧，便说“别扔了，还不如在上面直接写检查呢。人皮检查，比稿纸上的更深刻！”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——《西行记》&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;为了迎接历史的畸变，人甚至可以自我非人化，迎合着自然力一样的暴行。殷实因而认为，尽管写作技法、人物塑造上有缺陷，但毫不掩饰地暴露心迹和展现干部子弟的沉浮轨迹与思想，使《西行记》具有了“人性科学调查报告”的价值。 “对于像周涛这样的准&#39;官二代&#39;，精神自传和文献价值是第一步，自省，则属于进一步的要求。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/7dc37dba640ff1da5d7f0082e3868018.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;564&quot; height=&quot;824&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/7dc37dba640ff1da5d7f0082e3868018.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257105&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;如果把《西行记》与周涛几年前出版的自传体口述实录《一个人和新疆》结合起来，便更能领会到这种“自我暴露”的程度。在后者当中，他口无遮拦，将父亲、家人的可笑可哀，自己的难堪、丑陋、人性暗面，一一剥开来。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这样的个体，与中国传统中的君子儒士无疑拉开很远。似乎，那些不得不保全的、不得不在意的面具，他决意在古稀之年来临前，一把撕掉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f37d4fae1864a9506df6526b7ff2e059.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;734&quot; height=&quot;984&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/f37d4fae1864a9506df6526b7ff2e059.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257104&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;60年代新疆的干部子弟们，前排右一为周涛&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border-box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;深入骨髓的优越感&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在古城喀什熬了8年，周涛终于有机会去乌鲁木齐军区从事文学创作——乱世结束后，老天给了文武兼修的他最合适的安排。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;以后的人生似乎也证明，他从此顺风顺水，走上了阳光坦途。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;离开喀什的周涛，如同《西行记》中的姬书藤，对这片他长居过的黄土地没有丝毫留恋。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“为什么这么寡情？答曰：这儿本来就不是我的地方。”他认为，一个人，18岁以前生长在什么地方，那地方就会成为他永远的故乡。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;9岁以前，周涛生活在北京。在伊犁接受再教育和下放到喀什前，他都跟随父母生活在乌鲁木齐——在他眼中显然“高”出南疆。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;优越感与生俱来。首先便是长相。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;从小他生得肤白眼大，放在有外国小孩儿的娃娃堆里，也是最吸睛的那个。周家全家人皮肤都白。他曾经问姨妈，爷爷什么样？姨说，“你爷爷你们都比不了，长得排场。”周涛觉得自家血统应该是混血，因为老家山西榆社就是一个人种混杂地区，“匈奴、羌、羯氐聚集。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;比他年轻近10岁的军旅作家小乔说，周涛天生一副“让人怀疑上帝偏心的面孔和身段。再加上幽默狡猾反应极快且词锋犀利，这种人很容易让人产生嫉妒之心的同时又产生交好的愿望”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;皮囊在外，家世才是根底。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛父亲周文杰早年参加山西抗日青年决死队&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当时的党外团体，其实是共产党领导的抗日团体，后来变成正规军&lt;/span>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;，从事群众工作，担任文化教员，后来成为陈赓的部下。开国大典时，正营级干部周文杰站在天安门城楼下第一排，再往后考上了军队里的外交官，分在外国语学院。 “文革”前是十四级干部。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛的小学同学里有不少高级干部的子女。优越感无形中就注入了童年周涛的头脑。他记得弟弟出生时，中午医院给他母亲做蛋炒饭，她不吃，给4岁的周涛吃。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;也是4岁那年，周涛站在海淀区的一个小山坡上，正好是早上上班时间。他觉得自己好像大将军一样，“看着脚下灰蓝黑的人流，心里忽然间生起优越感。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这个念头周涛一生都记得，越大越觉得奇怪：“那么小的时候怎么会产生这种念头呢？”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;那念头是他一生当中思想基础所发出的芽儿。芽长出来，也和他一生联系在一起。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他的同学赵南有一次看到街上要饭的，说咱们有一天沦落到这个地步怎么办？周涛答：“即便沦落到这个地步，我们站着，别人一看也不一样。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“很多革命子弟都有那种优越感，其实相对这几十年的历史来说，都是很肤浅的东西。&#39;天下&#39;这种观念，也是很腐朽的了。”殷实说。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛未尝意识不到。他在《西行记》里写过姬书藤所在阶层的自傲与顽固：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有个小家伙才小学三年级，就可以历数十大元帅、十个大将、六十几位上将的姓名、职务、军衔。人奇之，问道：“那你长大能当什么将？”答曰：“至少上将。”长到十六七岁，愈加高俊不凡，体育文艺，多有天赋，似乎父辈的革命生涯真有什么血脉遗传。但是之后到了社会上，大部分不能适应。 ……至于中国革命的精神遗产：追求社会平等，崇尚利他主义的新文化，到了他们那儿更是全然不见了踪影。毫无疑问，姬书藤自己就是这类人中的一员，他很清楚，自己是“被严格筛选过的食品喂大的”，他也确信：“正是这样，我们这一代人正是这样满怀信心地像一块石头一样地长大了，水泼不进，针扎不透，任何别的事物都很难再渗入我们的头脑。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在这样一群眼界高的顽主里，周涛的桀骜不驯更加突出。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;有父亲的回忆为证：“涛十四五岁特爱骑马，特爱骑脚踏车。一次，随党校干部到南山玩，独自骑上哈萨克的马在山路上猛跑，目睹者惊骇，经领导急喊大骂，始罢。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他身体素质好，曾经获得全疆大学生男乒单打冠军。但初中时去北京集训一年，就不愿意干了，故意把球踩烂，把拍子摔在墙上。 “主教练让我改了横板以后我特别别扭，因为我这个人的性格是进攻型不是防守型的，让我打防守就不愿意了。不愿意了就破坏，不干了。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;恃才放旷、年少轻狂里，也有异乎同龄人的审时度势。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;十四五岁，他已经明白，打乒乓球，成不了事。不在于身体条件和头脑，而是起步太晚。 “如果我要在北京，我绝对打进国家队，条件足够了。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;还有一件事，他更不在话下。中学语文老师吴国梅给周涛作文打95分，给了他巨大的鼓励。别的同学都把札记作业当成苦差事，只有他在札记里找到了乐趣。 “为什么后来我一写散文就拿下？因为老早就写过，十本札记就是散文。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;文学，是天分，也是周涛上升通道里最清晰的那条。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/73a2271d659b7a2e6a6d7fc959a3ccde.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;869&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/73a2271d659b7a2e6a6d7fc959a3ccde.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257103&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;1965年，周涛获全疆大学生乒乓球单打冠军&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border-box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;非人的一年&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《二十四片犁铧》，经常被周涛要求放在散文集里的居前位置，足见他对这篇的重视。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;那来自于他在伊犁9901农场接受再教育的一年。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;去的时候大家坐着大轿子车，一路唱歌，什么《草原牧歌》，“红岩上红梅开”，欢声笑语不断，大家都充满了好像要开始新生活的情感。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;到了那儿发现，一夜之间变成“囚”了：不许离开连队25米，出去要报告，每天实行严格的军事管理。 “拉粮食的看见说，你们哪像大学生，跟劳改犯有什么区别？男女不分，一个个破破烂烂的鬼样子。马圈里面铺了稻草，半夜老鼠在头上跑，把有的人半个耳朵咬掉了。”蛮横无情的指导员，不让生病的学生看病。周涛说那时最大的心愿就是“把指导员抓起来扔到巩乃斯河里”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我们把草原耕到什么程度？ （用手比划）这是个毡房，毡房周围全部耕了，耕地离毡房也就五米远。 “白毡房成了仅存于翻耕土地间的一个孤岛。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;毡房里的狗狂吠，出来一个老太婆，一句话没说，冷冷地看着我们的拖拉机，“那不是愤怒，是藐视。那一眼，凝聚了七十多个冬天的寒冷，一眼就把我们的灵魂看成了碎片。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在你看我肚子够大吧，那时我的肚子就像挖地机挖出的大坑，全凹下去。瘦到64公斤，脸上棱骨都出来了。八十多公斤两袋的麦子，人家两个人抓着袋角，一提，你往下一钻，搭到背上吧。我那时候怎么干的？我一个人把那两个袋子提起来以后，直接架肩上，瘦骨嶙峋，力大无穷（笑）。能够这样的人没几个。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;粮仓上面有个三角顶，要把一个钢筋从顶上打下去，两面上螺丝固定。有个胆大的在上头抡榔头，我在下头扶着，有一回榔头差点砸到脑袋。还有一回我从空中跳下去抓住那个绳子，结果抓住以后，绳子是盘着的，好长一段没绑，要是那头也没绑，那就非得死了，没死也非得残废。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;荷尔蒙爆棚的年纪，陡然间从天上掉入泥坑。他开始琢磨出身与命运之间的关系。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“人和人没有太大的差别，除非特别笨的人和特别聪明的人，大部分人都是一样的。人的差别都是社会造成的。我当时有一句话——如果平等，你们敢吗？如果在同一个起跑线上，我们怕谁？但那时你处处受压制，处处都碰壁，啥事也办不成。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这种琢磨和玩味，从此伴随一生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/a9168589bca8721555e60a9bdea74826.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;650&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/a9168589bca8721555e60a9bdea74826.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257102&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;20世纪80年代中，周涛一家三代合影，前排左一抱小孩者为周涛，前排左四为马文，除老人外为周涛三个弟弟和弟媳及孩子们&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border-box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;“坐滑梯”的父亲&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛一直慨叹，伊犁与喀什的10年，是自己人生最颓顿的岁月。近五十年后回首，他依然对父亲的“糊涂”报以嗤笑和不太理解。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;1941、1942年的时候，父亲得了病，在驻军医院里成了日本人的俘虏。被吊起来拷打，他始终没有暴露他的军人身份。有一个汉奸先进来，他当时给汉奸写了一个条子，说你也是中国人，咱们都是中国人。我父亲的意思是让他帮忙。到了“文革”他被打成叛徒。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我父亲属于小地主家庭的思维方式，还有点理想主义的东西，和现实距离太远，不太会接人待物，对啥人都热情，不适应中国文化。马文到我们家稍微一接触，她就说你爸的思维怎么像外国人？ &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;他是很厚道很正直的人，但他不是一个社会能力强的人。他这一辈子走下坡路，是坐滑梯的人。他不是不想跟，他太想跟了，但是他跟不上。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1970年，已经开除党籍的周文杰被下放到昌吉吉木萨尔县国庆公社当农民，母亲也跟随父亲去了农村。两年后，老大周涛从伊犁农场再教育结束，确定分配到喀什以后，先带着妻子到吉木萨尔探家。他的散文名篇《吉木萨尔纪事》就是写的那次经历。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/d5fb99b945f2f7fbfac26d3fa269ca63.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;335&quot; height=&quot;505&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/d5fb99b945f2f7fbfac26d3fa269ca63.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257107&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在村口，周涛抽根烟歇一会儿，打算过一会儿问问路。一个穿着黑棉袄的老汉拿着粪筐，老往他身边绕。周涛心想他看啥呢，还笑着。再仔细看看，这不是我爹吗？ &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;老爷子已经完全成农村老汉了，一个是穿着打扮农村化，一个是精神状态农村化，整个把他改造成农民了。我妈在门口站着等。她看着很可怜，头发花白，被风吹着。去的时候头发还没白，才五十多岁就已经老得很。他们觉得没有可能回来了，一辈子就成这样了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;看着眼前的这个提筐子的人，我就想起少年时在机关院里与ー群顽童舞枪弄棍鏖战正酣时，突然出现在楼前怒喝我为“疯狗”的人；想起星期天逼我帮他冲洗全家无穷无尽的衣物，水寒刺骨，手冻通红，而他不把最后一点肥皂沫冲净决不善罢甘休；还想起那个原先穿军官制服尔后穿中山装干部服最后又穿上农民黑棉袄的人；而且想起曾经风采翩翩然后神态庄重终于苍老迷惘成现在这个样子的父亲。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在散文里，他自责，自己总是由于父亲在现实中的失败而低估他，忽视了他作为一个人在本质上具有的优秀品质。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;吊诡的是，从说话的声音到走路的姿势，从身材和五官，到习性和灵魂，无论社会环境有利还是不利，他始终摆脱不了父亲注入自己体内的遗传基因。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;后来他领悟到：如果没有父亲这种结局的突兀出现，他很可能会沿着一个五陵公子的生活轨迹延续下去，直到有一天突然发现自己已经被社会的变迁远远甩在车厢后面。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;性情也就此有了收敛。 “他倒霉以后我就比较低调。心里有鬼，有软肋，老实多了，不敢再张扬了。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在那个年代，文学是兴趣，也是为自己和家庭谋求出路的门径。婚姻，异曲同工。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;妻子马文的父亲当时是南疆军区政委、少将。在《一个人和新疆》里，周涛坦承，自己的婚姻是明显的机会主义行为，为此抛弃了那时的爱人，“终生内疚”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;马文家本不同意接纳当时潦倒落魄的周涛，但马文一门心思和周涛好，跟父亲明确说，“如果你不让我跟他好也行，我听你的，但我一辈子不会结婚。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;结完婚不到十天，周涛便和马文一块去了伊犁农场。一回头，已是半个世纪。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/fcbe7b129290d54f13e3d7743edf0137.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;656&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/fcbe7b129290d54f13e3d7743edf0137.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257106&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;周涛夫妇&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;图/ 刘新&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;我面前的马文，皮肤白皙，说话清晰有力。五六年前，马文眼睛动了手术，视力几乎为零，平时在家戴着墨镜。不论跟周涛、跟外人交流，都自有气场。周涛年轻时打枪伤了耳朵，如今需要戴助听器才能和人对话。家里的主心骨，一望便知。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;坐在乌市部队小区敞亮的小院儿里，周涛对妻子的好如数家珍。 “她可能干了。家里里里外外都是她打理。你别看她眼睛不好，什么都明白。我这院儿里种的树，她全给我砍了，换了海棠、石榴、枣、杏、桃子、样样长得溜。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛虽狂，却明白自己的短处。他外向张扬，但碰到突如其来的挫折，反而容易乱了方寸。妻子却不然，永远沉得住气。 “我会看自己，不大会看别人。马文善于识人，好人坏人，她看得很明白。办事能力在女人里面是出类拔萃的。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;马文对名利也看得开。周涛说自己退休进北京是够条件的，军队可以给他安排房子。 “马老太不去，她说她自己在新疆待着。她这个人有定力，不容易为虚荣左右。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;然而自传出版后，一位部队女作家按捺不住愤怒，撰文批评周涛放弃爱情，选择“最合适”&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;最安全、不惹麻烦&lt;/span>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;的女性成为伴侣，用“中国男人传统的&#39;丑妻薄地热炕头&#39;”那一套来作说辞，最终对两位女性的总结以及功利性评判，又等于否定了自己的罪疚感。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;对此，周涛没有给予任何回应。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“自传里的描述，你有给马文老师看吗？”我问他。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“没。”周涛笑笑。笑容里既有“她就算看到，也顶多一笑置之”的了解，也有那么一丝丝的忌惮。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border-box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;40岁之后，不再写诗&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;时运在上世纪70年代末降临在“怀才不遇”的周涛身上。依靠自己的文学才能和父亲的关系，他成功地调入乌鲁木齐的军区创作室，专心以文为生。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1978年8月，作家曹禺和徐迟去新疆时，读到周涛的诗作《天山南北》之后，在座谈会上赞扬“有情有味，是真正的诗”。周涛被这大好消息弄得猝不及防，想起引发自己文学梦的昔日“神童作家”刘绍棠，“上高中老师在讲台上讲他的《大青骡子》，他&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（刘绍棠）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;和同学一起坐在课堂里听讲。那该是一种什么感觉！”自己而立之年碰上高人赏识，心中涌起欢喜。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;那之后的两三年成了周涛诗歌的爆发期。小乔记得，1981年的几乎每一两天，周涛就会有一首新诗的岩浆喷涌出地面。 “看看它们的日期，密集得如诗人每天出门时留下的足迹！”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛曾经和杨牧、章德益合计，打造“新边塞诗”，不是写征战，而是反映新疆地区的独特风貌。一时间，他们的名字接连占据了《诗刊》、《人民文学》、《上海文学》的版面，处在文学潮的风头浪尖。新疆文联主席刘肖无对此表示反对，理由是“边塞诗原来是征战西北的，现在新疆是祖国的一部分，你征战谁去？”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;待朦胧诗起来以后，周涛曾给自己定向——“郭小川的声音、闻捷的色彩”，却发现这样的结合“不太好使”。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/0e32231c9649e4b49505957342ee2a0b.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;579&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/0e32231c9649e4b49505957342ee2a0b.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257108&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;1984年，三位军队作家在昆明机场，准备乘直升机飞赴老山。从左往右依次为李斌奎、周涛、李彦清&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;1984年，他和另外两位作家一道受命去老山前线创作。一开始，他还拿上山的路险“添油加醋”说给没上山的作家听，吓唬人家；到后来，他亲眼目睹战士被越军地雷炸瞎了眼。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;习惯了，晚上战士们都睡得着。 “一个个钢盔在枕头边撂着，一个个面孔睡得像雕塑一样，一个个都是从死神手里逃出来的人。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;天天和战士们同吃同睡，混熟了，周涛从他们嘴里没听到任何豪言壮语。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;问打仗感觉咋样？战士说，“敌人炮弹覆盖的时候太可怕了，恨不得钻到地底下去，赶快爬不说，也顾不上姿势了。没法表述那个恐怖，那是人的意志绝对无法抗拒的，能躲过去就不错了。”周涛想象，我方的炮火覆盖对方的时候也是一样的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他写下了2000行的长诗《山岳山岳，丛林丛林》。诗里不光有战争的残酷，也有超越胜负与因果的书写角度：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我的可怜而固执的邻居&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我的性情忧郁爱闹纠纷的远亲呵&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;当我和你作战时&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我的心其实是愤怒而又疼痛&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;几乎是一边在打一边在哭&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;我流着泪痛击着自己的另一部分&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;东方——是我们共同祖母的名字&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;一代又一代的死者并没有使大地腐烂&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;却是活着的人们使之拥挤混乱&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;一切形式的死&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;目的都在于提醒和挖掘生的意义&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;死去的人已经不怕死了&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;活着的正怀着恐惧&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——《山岳山岳，丛林丛林》&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这首长诗只在两家不太著名的边疆刊物上发表过，单行本又因出版社方面拆版未能问世，没有进入更多读者的视野。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“有点遗憾。被莫名其妙地忽略了。如果这首诗能在《人民文学》这样的刊物全文刊出，影响会很大的。”殷实等多位评论家和好友为周涛抱不平。作者自己倒是想开了，“写得太容易，很随便。只是在本子上开始写着玩，后来越写越长，一字没改，别人都不相信。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛说过，他惟一的敌人就是自己。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;写诗写得兴高采烈，但他对自己的要求是：我的诗，达到全国&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（顶尖）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;水平，就不写了。果不其然，他40岁生日那天得了全国奖，他便觉得，自己的诗歌生涯也到了头。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;下一个要攻的山头？散文吧。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛认为自己的贡献和独到在于“解放散文”：散文的写作“重要的不是化验和肢解，而是感受和拥抱”，他不喜欢“研究”，更愿意漫无边际地遐想、悠思、品味，所以他不在乎开头的突兀，不关心上下段的过渡和照应，而是以诗的逻辑、结构和笔法去写散文。他甚至口出狂言，“散文没有章法。我就是章法。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;于是在周涛的文字里，种种记忆、思想、情感和想象奔涌交汇，如越过堤岸的河水，在无际的草地上四处蔓延。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他反感“游山玩水”的说法，认为那只是“把山和水当作精神意义上的妓女罢了”。在名作《巩乃斯的马》里，他把观赏马的气韵、筋骨当成艺术享受；在《猛禽》里，他聚焦一只与老狼搏斗、利爪分别深陷于老狼骨缝和树干最后被奔跑的狼撕裂的鹰；在《过河》里，惊叹年逾八旬的瘦弱的哈萨克族老太太竟制服了不肯过河的烈马……&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;无论是神山或者野马，或是人，在周涛激昂豪放的表达中，总会浮现出强烈的“夫子自况”色彩，自认强大并与强者引为同类的惺惺相惜。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/869c4630e5db9b2e0e06a7b6a78217b2.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;498&quot; height=&quot;828&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/869c4630e5db9b2e0e06a7b6a78217b2.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257110&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他的散文以篇幅长&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;好几篇都在两万字以上&lt;/span>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;、强烈的表达和思辨冲动著称。周涛对此也曾有过冷静的认识：“思辨是散文里的一种成分，过分了，会伤害艺术，所以我特别看重贾平凹的散文，他恰恰不重思辨而撷取生活中暗含的底蕴，他更重对生活原始形态的直接感光。对他的认可，实际上表现我对自己某些缺陷的认可。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;虽然二十多年前已有上述认识，但自那之后，他急切言说思想的习惯，至今未改。 《西行记》里依然可见一斑。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;周涛的身上聚集着天之骄子的自得与时代笼罩在头上、害怕“丧失既得”的恐惧；他迷恋文学，以为它自由、公平，不像政治那样复杂。 20年前，以散文集首获鲁迅文学奖，他却没去领奖。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;原因？ “文学各种奖项和我心目中想象的距离太大。奖要公正，不能鱼目混珠，泥沙俱下，不能撒胡椒面，要奖给那些最值得奖励的人，不管那个人是谁，也许不是我。”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他说曾经的80年代，民族目标明确，人人充满希望，整个时代是《祝酒歌》所渲染的情绪。但90年代初，他无可避免地产生了虚无的情绪，游离于社会，不再那么直接。 《博尔塔拉冬天的惶惑》，便写于那样的状态之下——然而读懂的人，终是少数。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/569f47056b7b988679b14a3928354a6f.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;984&quot; height=&quot;712&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/569f47056b7b988679b14a3928354a6f.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257109&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span>;1986年3月，周涛（右一）获全国第二届新诗（诗集）奖，左一为著名诗人艾青，颁奖者为胡乔木&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4 data-css=&quot;box-sizing: border-box;color: inherit;margin: 0px;padding: 5px 15px 0px&quot;>;&lt;span data-css=&quot;box-sizing:border-box;color:inherit;font-size:18px;margin:0px;padding:0px&quot;>;&lt;strong>;天注定？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;二十多年后完成的《西行记》里，周涛写到姬书藤等干部下乡，享受了叶尔羌河畔胡杨林下一顿烤鱼盛宴：“古老的麦盖提人变戏法似的，从河里捕捞出活蹦乱跳的大鱼！……托盘呈上，那种滋味，真是香透脑片骨！”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;值得注意的绝不是美味，而在于美食供给者与享用者的姿态：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;检查团的领导们盘腿坐在胡杨林间的空地上，地上铺着华丽的和田地毯。村民捧着托盘，俯首躬身，膝语蛇行，如侍帝王。这些伟大的礼仪是谁教给他们的？这种令人噙泪的文明是什么时候养成的？姬书藤忽然心生愧疚，觉得自己配不上这样的盛宴和虔诚的礼节，对不起这些在篝火边跳刀郎舞、在果园里画农民画的沙漠人。我们为人家做了什么值得人家这样隆重接待？ ” &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;——《西行记》&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这让我想起周涛80年代创作的长篇散文《哈拉沙尔随笔》。在那篇文章里，他从同行人干裂的嘴唇，联想到多半个世纪以前，马仲英的回族兵和霍加·尼牙孜的维吾尔人血战，而今，往事遗迹却被干渴的北方之唇&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;无水的山沟&lt;/span>;）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;吃光了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他在生活在焉耆的这支回族人身上，看到一种并非人人都能感到的“百年孤独”：&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;隐忍、沉默的后面藏着可怕的强悍；怀疑、狡黠的不信任的目光后面有着最真诚的诺言和舍命相陪的友谊；屈辱的自卑感和深藏于心的强大自尊心的矛盾造成的痛苦；不被理解却又顽强地要保存自己所形成的隔阂；边远、贫困的落后生活方式与心比天高的自信力之间的大反差所导致的悲哀和固执心理，就造成了这种百年孤独。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他提出，“中华民族的历史不仅仅是汉族的历史，历代帝王、名臣、保国有功的武将中就不知有多少是少数民族。 ”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;这样的着墨和观点，在他几十年的丰盛书写里，并不多见。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;和他有忘年之交的殷实犀利地指出他的问题：“他对新疆这片土地，对维吾尔族等少数民族表达得仍然不够。周涛在这点上也表达了一个汉人的精明。他没有从语言、从经典、从世俗文化，方方面面——他没有深入新疆。 ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在刚刚写就的《西行记》分析里，殷实直言：“如果他们每一个人&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;（主角）&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;的内在世界，也都可以像姬书藤一样展开，特别是，如果对那个维吾尔族人物司马义·艾合买提江的个人精神世界、文化性格乃至民族属性，有深入挖掘和呈示的话，那么这部作品中的众声喧哗，包括不同&#39;声音&#39;之间的对话，将会构成多么巨大的张力。 ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;为何无法展开？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“语言障碍是一，不敢再真实下去是二。只能到此为止。 ”周涛回答我。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他表达过对张承志的钦佩，却也坦言后者在信仰上走向了极致。事实上，周涛在大学的专业正是维吾尔语，但不到半年，高等教育之路便被伊犁“再教育”拦腰截断。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;而他表达懊恼叹惜的角度是：“假如学完了四年维语，到南疆哪个公社当书记，再当县一级干部，对民族关系、人事各个方面了解多一些、再进入历史的研究和民族的考察，就可能组织长篇小说。但那半年我没有多大兴趣学维语，看不到这么远。 ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他在心理上很靠近哈萨克这样的草原民族，自比为“一个习惯了毡房和羊肉、热爱着草原和纵马的半游牧者”。而对生长于斯的新疆，他自认此地为故土，却也始终是以中原文化的根脉来观察和体验。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在文学评论者韦器闳看来，周涛极少描写市井生活，也不以表现百姓的喜怒哀乐和审美趣味为己任，而是极力张扬自己个人化的人生体验。于是他的写作也呈现出一种“贵族化”的倾向。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/97d629aae0ecf1617113532ed8d97452.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;479&quot; height=&quot;663&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/05/97d629aae0ecf1617113532ed8d97452.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257111&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;0&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;0&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;回顾这大半生，周涛说自己介乎文武之间：生在军队里是武，这是打的底色；读书上学是文；当运动员从武；回来读书上学喜欢文学又从文：从文以后最终又跑到兵营里从文了。“可以说文不成武不就，也可以说文武两道都在滋养你，也都在制约你；制约也是滋养。 ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;到老，他在部队文职干部中算最高级别，享受军级待遇。反而是操持了一辈子的母亲，听到儿子涛说，“妈，我快当将军了”，回了一句，“你一天仗也没打过，当什么将军？ ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“喀什的八年教会你什么呢？ ”我问他。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他答：“不是你天生就怎么样，你那些个人的条件都必须在一个社会的大势之下才能得以施展和表现，否则一文不值。 ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;“你是宿命论者？ ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;他点头。“人各有命，运是社会给你的可能性。有胆无识是&#39;二杆子&#39;，有识无胆是书呆子。有胆识，还有运，才可能成大事。我和马文？不是运，是命。 ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在全家被政治运动分崩离析的年代里，他发出诘问：“从一个个由家庭中诞生出来的自在的少年，到成为被社会和自身条件嵌入某一职业的成人，命运啊，你将怎么打发我们？是对我们格外垂青呢还是特别冷漠？对后一种可能，我们当时是不愿意设想也不可能接受的。 ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;时光过去了50年，谜底完全揭开了。让他无限惊奇的是，今天的谜底，当初已经不断向他显示。他始终相信，那时候，一切都已注定。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #808080;&quot;>;（参考资料：《西行记》、《一个人和新疆》、《周涛自选集诗歌散文卷》、《众眼阅周涛》、《一种承认的书写》、《《西行记》的阅读方法》，实习记者施佳一、王雨曼、张淼对本文亦有贡献。感谢《当代》杂志、花城出版社）&lt;/span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 14:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[海南白沙：云端之上，蓝天之下]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259994]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 13:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 13:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[这款下饭剧，正在悄然流行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259899]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 12:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p data-mpa-powered-by=&quot;yiban.io&quot;>;新剧《田耕纪》完结了，评分不高，热度却不低。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它改编自种田文《重生小地主》：现代姑娘连蔓儿乱入古代农村，成为了农家女子。她与神秘男子沈诺一起，与极品亲戚斗智斗勇，为懦弱“爹娘”讨回公道。在有限的条件下勤劳致富、苦心经营，收获种田事业的同时也收获了爱情。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《田耕纪》的热播秘诀只有两个字——种田。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c7495f4ccca4d14862ab7149f37acf14.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/c7495f4ccca4d14862ab7149f37acf14.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256834&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在强调快节奏、强叙事的网文中，主打稳稳的幸福的种田文显得有些独树一帜。种田文的发展分为三个阶段。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;早期脱胎于SLG（策略类）游戏，主角和玩家一样在异世界招兵买马，完成任务，以“高筑墙，广积粮，缓称王”为宗旨，发展经济或农业，不断拓展自身势力。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;中期则聚焦于字面意思，让主角在封建社会发家致富，叙事风格流于温馨平和生活化。除了《田耕纪》&lt;span>;的原作《重生小地主》，《古代山居种田养娃之日常》《我在大宋卖火锅》等热门小说也隶属于这一时期的种田文范畴。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;后期种田文画风清&lt;/span>;奇，在“种田”的基础思维上融合无限流、奇幻、悬疑等因素，实现了类型的融合，如《重生成龙王后我靠海鲜发家》《我靠种田，在星际拯救人类》等等。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如果要在传统文学中给种田文找&lt;span>;个源头，那么最贴近的便是乡土文学。两者均把目光投向了乡野景观，但乡土文学的底色是厚重的，通常承载着苦难叙事，而种田文则是轻盈的、舒缓的真空式写作。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49e2fb8f4e551fbc1fb45b218c4791fe.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49e2fb8f4e551fbc1fb45b218c4791fe.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256831&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;种田文的影视化改编之路走得比较坎坷，相比别的冲突强、反转多的网文，它其&lt;/span>;实不那么适合被搬上荧幕。如今被改编为“种田剧”的，一般是细水长流的中期种田文，其拍摄难度小于早期种田文与后期种田文。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;《花间提壶方大厨》和《&lt;span>;人间烟火花小厨》就属于比较成功的范例，没有快意恩仇，没有嗔痴怨念，仅围绕搞事业的女主角展开小切口叙事。这两部剧均弱化了农耕属性，放大美食元素，借助可口菜肴勾起观众的共情体验。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/79d11908058c277cff63481c61f129db.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;718&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/79d11908058c277cff63481c61f129db.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256832&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;年度爆剧《知否知否应是绿肥红瘦》改编自关心则乱的同名种田文，讲述盛家庶女盛明兰利用聪明才智在大家族内生存并闯过人生层层考验的故事。剧版删去了原作里的穿越元素，让女主在等级森严、嫡庶有别的封建社会里依矩行事的逻辑更为自洽。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《知否》在弱化农耕元素的同时，凸显宅斗与经营元素，增强戏剧冲突，围绕大娘子、林小娘、墨兰的嫡庶讨论一度超过了女主角盛明兰。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/be81d57344a5d940a288c87483302cdc.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;719&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/be81d57344a5d940a288c87483302cdc.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256836&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;《玉面桃花总相逢》改编自《屠户家的小娘子》，以胡娇从辅助丈夫到独当一面的成长为主线，立意上彰显女性力量，呈现上却差了一口气。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/948462ff5883bf8134990b1f861c86f1.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/948462ff5883bf8134990b1f861c86f1.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256833&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;综上，《田耕纪》虽不是&lt;/span>;第一部种田剧，但它的关联度无疑是最高的，既呈现了农家生活的淳朴闲适，又刻画了宗族亲缘间的龃龉。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;女主角连蔓儿事业线（完成系统任务，赚足1000金）、爱情线（和沈诺从坚定盟友变知心爱人）、亲&lt;span>;情线（帮爹娘智斗无德亲戚）三手抓，争做每条赛道的赢家。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49d75a2346f3bfa7c78e7bbd3db59117.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/49d75a2346f3bfa7c78e7bbd3db59117.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256835&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;只不过从观众反馈来看：爱情线太腻缺乏CP感，亲情线太气人影响观众情绪，大家最爱看的还是种田的事业线。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;毕竟，爱情故事在当代网剧里泛滥成灾，点击任意一部偶像剧就能收获帅哥美女在任何时代、任何行业里谈恋爱；气死人不偿命的极品亲戚们近年来在古装剧、都市剧也看得不少，难免有雷同之感。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;因此，《田耕纪》最终火于看似平平淡淡的种田线，而非其他也不难理解了。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;它不禁让人联想到今年上半年的一档现象级综艺《种地吧》，10个年轻嘉宾，用190天时间，在142亩土地上的播种与收获。可能连他们自己也没想到，居然会有那么多观众愿意看他们种地的事情。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/97ce23d7460c454ac135cfad19543d0e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/97ce23d7460c454ac135cfad19543d0e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256837&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对种田的眷念，刻在中国人的DNA里。十年前，虚拟种菜游戏QQ农场风靡一时，有人深夜难眠开车去看海，有人早起早睡只为订闹钟偷菜。十年后，人们又转战微信农场，在状态栏里养鸡养鱼喂鸽子。打开手机，各大电商平台都推出了浇水种树、经营果园的虚拟服务，并和真实福利挂钩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对于国人而言，“种田天赋”是不需要&lt;span>;点亮就能获得的初始技能。几千年来，中国社会占主导的便是农耕文明，它凝聚了劳动人民的智慧结晶，孕育出博大精深的中华文化。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;陶渊明笔下“采菊东篱下，悠然见南山”也象征了国人对田园牧歌式生活的追求与向往，田园诗派文人的金句佳章历久弥新。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;当代年轻人读陶渊明，也追种田文、种田剧（综）。如果说前者构建的乌托邦想象遥远缥缈，隔着时代的丝罗帷幔有些看不真切，那么后者所提供的慰藉，是触手可及且平易近人的。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/1f0b0900204242054072a0cdc952588e.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/03/1f0b0900204242054072a0cdc952588e.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;256838&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;在高速发展的时代，万事万物&lt;/span>;都像上了发条一般狂飙突进，青年人裹挟在湍急潮流间飞速向前，但偶尔也会想在茶余饭后喘口气、寻找情绪出口。因此，节奏缓慢、风景优美的种田文（剧）便是缓解压力的极佳消遣了。而且相比激进的创业故事，种田还有一份笃定的安心感，一分耕耘一分收获，付出和回报总体成正比例。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;上世纪六十年代，台湾健康写实主义电影中就存在二元对立的都市or乡村叙事，在一派秀丽的乡野风光中暗含褒贬意图。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;六十年后的今天，“种田流”实则也隐藏了某种创作倾向，乡村往往是治愈系的乌托邦，而都市则是迷茫中的青年人想逃离的异托邦。隔着方寸屏幕，都市人也远程做了一回种田人。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;种田文和种田剧虽然存在叙事陈旧、角色脸谱化、节奏略平淡等弱点，但到底是精准击中了一种蔓延且流行的大众情绪。我们不妨多给它们一些成长空间，相信会有更多的爆款出来。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[贵人鸟转型卖吃的，国产运动鞋三巨头正在分岔路口]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259989]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 11:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/eaa4eb85be65a96bdaa301cfe2d17880.jpeg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;631&quot; height=&quot;841&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/eaa4eb85be65a96bdaa301cfe2d17880.jpeg&quot; data-key=&quot;257037&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作为时尚圈曾经最抢手的单品之一，球鞋的热度正在退去。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9月22日，贵人鸟发布公告称，鉴于运动鞋服业务自司法重整以来收入下降、持续亏损，市场竞争日趋激烈，公司将结束经营36年的运动鞋服业务，并以粮食业务作为公司未来主要经营发展方向。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;贵人鸟财报显示，2023年1-6月，贵人鸟运动鞋服业务实现营业收入2.32亿元，同比下降19.51%。 2018年-2022年，ST贵人年归母净利润出现4次亏损，累计亏损超20亿元。 “贵人鸟”品牌零售终端数量已从2019年的2358家下降至2023年上半年的1584家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/4e35dce86edf26ad3c2e59e5511f4fe6.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/4e35dce86edf26ad3c2e59e5511f4fe6.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257038&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;同时，安踏体育、李宁、特步国际相继发布2023年上半年财报，面对耐克和阿迪达斯中国区业绩回暖，国货依旧扛打。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;不过，和去年安踏营收超越耐克中国、李宁领先阿迪达斯中国的成绩单相比，表现还是有一定回落。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/93ba6b3e658359194e85bd53db909e2e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/93ba6b3e658359194e85bd53db909e2e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257039&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;数据显示，今年上半年，三大国货运动品牌中只有特步还在大幅扩展门店，目前门店总数8256家，排名第二。李宁主品牌门店净减少155家，是唯一没有品牌门店净增长的集团。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ea57ccb33ca4fc7db4141baa349f8f4e.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/ea57ccb33ca4fc7db4141baa349f8f4e.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257040&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;过去，在几大潮牌的品牌效应下，阿迪达斯与耐克以绝对的优势傲视国产的安踏、李宁、特步、361度。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d2cbe8eccffe6128694adefe9d34b673.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/d2cbe8eccffe6128694adefe9d34b673.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257041&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;如今，国货三巨头深耕自家核心技术——安踏“氮科技”，“李宁䨻”轻弹科技，特步“XTEP ACE缓震科技平台”，以差异化战略全面开花，安踏李宁连续两年领跑国内运动品牌市场。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/57b049e6ef9c40de403b13c20b8132ba.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/57b049e6ef9c40de403b13c20b8132ba.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257042&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;未来，运动品牌要想走得更远，不能只是“吃老本”“炒冷饭”，在鞋款设计上利用配件、涂鸦、解构主义的拼接等设计语言做加法已经被挤出了主流讨论范围，取而代之的是“如何把球鞋做得不像一双球鞋”的命题。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e009a49268a310f5faf5ecea0da8dfb1.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;opacity: 1;&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/e009a49268a310f5faf5ecea0da8dfb1.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257043&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;去球鞋化、人工智能化是值得探索的创新之路。同时，以受众思维为导向，运动品牌商要更了解年轻人的内心。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3e9648a7aab0c4e2c59e37f9a8fe3a93.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;1200&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/04/3e9648a7aab0c4e2c59e37f9a8fe3a93.png&quot; data-key=&quot;257089&quot; data-mce-width=&quot;140&quot; data-mce-height=&quot;140&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;随着DIY文化的兴起，越来越多的年轻人对运动鞋进行二次创作，通过涂鸦、爆改、自制的方式改造旧鞋。在国潮风尚的涌现下，回力国潮爆改鞋销量迅速上升，受到许多年轻人的喜爱。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;今天，“知道”跟你一起探讨国产运动鞋该如何突破瓶颈。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 11:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[男子用16.8万彩礼钱环游中国：抽身离开也是一种觉醒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259967]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 10:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;这样的“活出自我”，你赞成吗？山西一位男子因女方彩礼临时加价而退婚，拿彩礼钱辞职旅行。从今年6月1日，朱某背着行囊出发，5个月的时间，走了40多个城市，花了3万多。“交通主要是绿皮火车，就住青旅，都花不了什么钱。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;朱某介绍，他和女友是通过相亲认识的，“谈了差不多八九个月，觉得时间到了，就准备结婚了”。他称，彩礼18万8是当地的“正常行情”，“我们那叫&#39;大包&#39;，这个钱就包括了婚纱照、三金钱这些。18万8我自己有16万8的积蓄，还有2万是找朋友借的”。后来，女友索要额外3万的三金钱，“我说我给不起了，这些也是找人借下来的”，吵架后分手。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;坦率地讲，朱某还是没有放开。坐绿皮火车、住青旅，5个月旅行才花3万多，属于非常节省的那种。这大概因为这是自己存下来的血汗钱，不想大手大脚花了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;更重要的是，他体恤父母的艰辛，表示：“每次相亲我都有点难受，我跟女生一起吃海底捞，看电影啥的，可我父母从来没吃过海底捞。”父母原本打算帮他出太原买房的首付，“我也挺心疼我父母的，他们很多地方都没去过，还一心想着要给我买房子”。自己辞职的事，并没有告诉父母，“以后有机会的话会说，暂时可能不会告诉，怕他们接受不了，说我不务正业”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;可以看出，朱某与父母都是价值观上比较传统的人，脚踏实地，为人质朴，对生活有长远考虑，对婚姻家庭的态度是郑重的。表面上，3万元成了压垮骆驼的最后一根稻草；实际上，朱某恐怕是担心此例一开，以后会没完没了，女友索取3万元的理由是“她闺蜜都是还另外要了3万的三金钱”，攀比是没有尽头的，日后婚姻生活未必能舒心和谐。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从进化心理学的角度看，婚姻或专偶制的起源是：女性有9个月的孕期，婴儿出生后还有哺乳期，人类的孩子到成年时间很长，且需要习得各种生存技能，这就需要一个父亲的角色，给母子提供保护与生存资源，并对子女言传身教；男人得到的是通过婚姻降低父子不确定性（paternal uncertainty），承担家庭责任、社会意义上的父亲是文化建构的产物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;无论中西，传统婚姻价值观，底层逻辑都是这一套。只不过，进入现代社会之后，这一套价值观先是受到了个人主义的冲击，进而受到进步主义/后现代主义的解构，越来越难以为继。养育自己的孩子有持续的获得感与幸福感，然而确实辛苦，耗费金钱与心力，也需要责任感与延迟满足能力Vs立马花钱享受当下、及时行乐，潇洒的“现代人”会选择哪一种？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;一方面，当某些女性抱怨自己从婚姻中得到了什么，某些男性也会反思自己为什么要结婚。当某些女性论及生男生女与所谓冠姓权时对男方说“你家难道有皇位要继承”，某些男性也会恍然大悟，反躬自问：我家确实没有皇位要继承，那么我花大价钱结婚、含辛茹苦养育子女值得吗？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;当越来越多的男女追问“结婚组建家庭生儿育女的意义何在”，本身就意味着生育本能的衰弱与婚姻家庭价值观的式微，进而意味着生育收益端的价值减记。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;另一方面，彩礼与传统社会的聘礼不是一回事。彩礼是底层男性为了进入婚姻市场而支付的对价，但近些年不断走高且不断泛化。婚姻市场是分区域、多层次的复合结构，底层市场可能是男多女少，但顶层市场可能是女多男少，按照供求关系的逻辑，男多女少时男方支付彩礼，女多男少时是否会反过来？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;拿到彩礼结婚几天后闹离婚，彩礼全退几乎是不可能的；一方把另一方的名字加到房产证上，失去半套房子。“谈感情伤钱”，出资方面临的风险越来越大。在婚姻市场上，出资方作为甲方，面对过高的要求与成本，会考虑减少交易，这是从生育成本端对婚姻的挤压。朱某因女方彩礼临时加价而退婚，是又一个鲜活的案例。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现代社会，男女的自我意识都在不断强化，即所谓“自我觉醒”。既然有女性觉醒，就会有男性觉醒，觉醒最终一定是双向的。觉醒或有先后，但对等才是终局，才是稳定均衡（stable equilibrium）。一个随时间演化的系统中，暂态解（transient state solution）是暂时现象，长期稳定解（long-term steady solution）才是最终结果。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2015年，郑州一位女教师辞职信“世界那么大，我想去看看”走红网络，舆论盛赞她自我觉醒、勇于追求个人自由、活出自我。朱某决定退婚，然后基于同样的动机，花自己的积蓄去环游中国，也理应得到同样的评价。作为一个成年人，无论男女，不想过循规蹈矩、按部就班的生活，想要追逐自己的梦想，也能为自己的决定负责，就无可厚非。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;男女未来会觉醒到什么程度？未来能稳定下来的婚姻家庭究竟是什么形态？不好说，但有一点是肯定的：必定是基于男女对等的原则，在男女对等之上形成新的稳定均衡。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;任何一个值得的婚姻，必定建立在爱与道德的基础上。唯有如此，家才是让人身心放松的港湾，而不是精神内耗的修罗场。这就需要各种对等：爱的对等，家庭责任感的对等，付出的对等，提供情绪价值的对等……一方永远付出、另一方永远榨取的关系行之不远。故而，在发现正进入这样的关系之时，有必要及时止损；或者，在发现已进入这样的关系之后，有必要抽身离开，谁能否认这是一种觉醒呢？&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #ba1010;&quot;>;•&lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti; font-weight: bold;&quot;>;（本文仅为作者个人观点，不代表本报立场）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 10:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[索南才让：写最后一代游牧人的故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259932]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 09:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/RaZv85deQGOVAoK0hsyPdiKIWKD5XbflDNetMbJQ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/RaZv85deQGOVAoK0hsyPdiKIWKD5XbflDNetMbJQ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256518&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;褪去枣红或靛青的蒙古服，摘下礼帽，换上polo衫，就如同推开了传送门，踏入另一个世界。38岁的作家索南才让的身形本就在牧民中算不上高大威壮，离开鲜亮衣装和奔腾草场，走在拥挤都市，连略显吃力的翘舌音都透着拘谨的书生气。他习惯性地摆出一副客气、礼让、绅士的面孔，规规矩矩坐在餐桌旁，提醒自己杯里浅浅的红酒本就没多少，但还是要先抿一口。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;二十多岁刚离开家乡，外面世界默认的在酒桌上要站立敬酒、说一堆敬酒词的举动让他无所适从。慌张地效仿了一段时间，以后便谎称自己从不喝酒，等回到草原才卸下心理负担放开了喝。牧区规矩是，哪怕对方再怎么盛情款待，也没有一个人站起来端着酒杯感谢东道主，表示下次我回请；也不会仅仅因为说错话就让对方觉得被冒犯。不分先后，众人两三杯下肚后就开始划拳，“简单很多，特别直接粗暴。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“草原尤其是高寒地区生活的人们，情感不能说淡漠，总之不会那么丰富。”放牧的时候，两三天见不着人交流说话是常事，最长的一次，从索南才让的个人纪录来看，这样的缄默蔓延了四五十天。他置身苍凉、辽阔的环境里自言自语，练就了一副远观、俯瞰的目光，很难再多愁善感。“人在和环境相互依存的关系中形成了这种性格，他对生灵的态度是不一样的，更加冷酷。”亲手喂养的牲畜，对牧民来说既可以是远行的工具，也可以是下酒的食物。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在索南才让2023年出版的短篇小说集《找信号》里，这些动物还成了情节推动的真凶。8月份上海书展的对谈活动中，嘉宾韩松落特意提前统计了书里出现的死亡方式，并在现场用报账单一般的口吻诵念，“冻死一次，猝死一次，被牛撞死两次，从马背上摔死一次……”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对比爱丽丝·门罗笔下那些逃离小镇的人死去的“现代方式”，例如飞机火车失事、罹患癌症、海难溺水等，韩松落将索南才让书里殉于跟自然抗衡或与动物交互的桥段划分为“前现代”。作者解释道，这确实是高原牧民们日常要面对的环境考验，“青海经常会有洪水，还有闪电，被雷劈死、被马摔死的，各种意外都存在。”韩松落感慨，“之前以为我们离前现代社会非常远，但索南才让的文字令我们回到这个现场，人和动物、土地、死亡之间仍靠本能维系。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;对谈发生在米盖尔·德·塞万提斯图书馆，隔壁便是时髦的巨鹿路，台下有观众并不买账，抛出疑问道，在这样的环境下“完全无法联想到草原”，而且也不理解，“讲过去的故事意味着什么？”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;索南才让依然低声回应，“写作中有一种滞后性，当下感受到的不能立刻成为作品，经过沉淀和发酵，才能书写父辈传承下来的放牧经验”；至于能否传递出强烈的异域感，这其实掀起的是索南才让写作的一道重要线索。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;他于2021年出版的小说集《荒原上》一度被导演万玛才旦看上，新作《找信号》也在2023年10月入围了第七届平遥国际电影展“迁徙计划·从文学到影视”单元——故事必然多少散发出跟都市截然不同的气质，才接连引来导演们购买版权试图改编；但这类西北牧场风情并非他文字里强调的重点，作为最后一代游牧人，他肩负亲身的经历、父辈的记忆，连同成年后外出务工打拼的生活碰撞，若干年后带着混杂的目光回到家乡，因此绝不满足于记录表象的异样风光，而是站在更广阔的视角下探讨牧民的精神变化——面对城市化扩张无疑流露出越来越多趋向一致的生活及思考方式，导致读者无法感受到扑面而来的“草原”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2008年他揣着300块钱来到北京，在一家做城市雕塑的工厂打工，进厂前买了上下两册诺贝尔文学奖作品集，以及耗资一百多块、用掉几乎半副身家的福克纳传记。某次春节没回老家，独自在空荡的厂区看烟花，突然感受到一股力量，仿佛青海湖近在眼前，推开隐形的家门，前一天喝多了的父亲正扣着帽子躺在沙发上睡觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“故乡是我写作的血脉，后来产生怀疑，牵引的线越来越微弱，离开后才能写故乡，才能理解。”如今他家里已没有了羊，大约还有80头牛，平时交给弟弟打理，他则一个月回牧场一趟。为了保持创作的状态，他住在离牧场不算远的海晏县，保留着一些城市的生活习惯，每天起来先慢跑、煮咖啡、吃鸡蛋，然后磨磨蹭蹭地翻一会儿书，8点多到工作室开始一天的写作。每天写到七八百字就不想写了，便去干些别的事。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;新书编辑曾总结，“他的小说多半写的是高寒草原牧区的故事，但并不因此让读者感觉遥远。”究其原因，青海省作协副主席、评论家刘晓林有过一番剖析，“他并不刻意凸显民族性和地域风情，缺少一般的草原小说那种宁静、单纯、悠扬的牧歌情调，没有在世界与本土、传统与现代二元对立中审视本民族的过去和未来，更无意把小说变为民族的寓言，这些民族文学写作中惯常的思维似乎丝毫没有影响到他，他更愿意采用一种冷峻的不动声色的叙述，关注的是草原的俗世生活，放牧、饮酒、恋爱等日常生活，呈现在现代文明的冲击下草原日趋芜杂的生活状态和人生形式。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/l2VGmDF1AHXwd1npPJEKUFA3j1fCJQZKAIjXoWV6.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;546&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/l2VGmDF1AHXwd1npPJEKUFA3j1fCJQZKAIjXoWV6.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256523&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;索南才让自家牧场&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（受访者提供/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;故乡的最后一代游牧人&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我特别喜欢看电影，香港的警匪片、TVB古装武打片伴随了我的成长。草原上每年除了冬天，其余季节都有流动的帐篷录像厅，很火爆，一到晚上喇叭里就开始放碟招揽客人。草原和城市不一样，声音穿透力特别强，方圆十几公里都能听得见。我们听见之后心痒难耐，在家里根本坐不住，立马跑到几公里外某个人流量大的三叉路口，钻进支在路边的流动帐篷。椅子占空间，为了尽可能坐更多的人，大家都盘腿坐，连伸腿都不行。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;没去上学之前，我叔叔是草原上的电影放映员。我坐在他的马车上，跟着他去过十几个村放大的胶卷。等到12岁辍学，从学校回到牧场，我就开始在流动帐篷看，一直看到二十多岁。刚开始是VCD，后来是DVD，价格从五毛涨到一块。每天放的都不一样，不仅仅是香港片，还有内地的一些经典片子，也有《乱世佳人》这样的外国片。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;听起来是很美妙的青少年时期。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我到现在唯一还没有后悔过的事情，就是从学校出来。那个时候条件不允许（读书），家在牧区，读书的话要去县城，冬牧场隔着40公里，夏牧场七八十公里。县里没有寄宿学校，必须去亲戚家住宿，又没有人照顾。加上我自己也读不进去，一说不读了家里也很高兴，因为需要人手帮助。后来回看，我在学校之外得到的可能比学校里更多，我在学校不读书，是出来之后才读书的，进学校和读书是两回事，学校是学习，不是读书。我接触的第一本书是《天龙八部》，我拿着那本书去放羊，那是冬天，而且还是一个黄沙漫天的日子，但我一整天都没有时间去关注别的事情，我甚至不知道自己的羊群在哪里。那是我真正意义上阅读的开始。电影的话在那几年也看了有几千部吧。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;这些电影对你日后写小说会有影响吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我觉得我的写作里很大的一个成分是电影，无论是叙述，还是在观察人物的对话或神态方面，肯定潜移默化都会有影响。因为我在看电影的时候，会特别投入，好的电影我会记住它里面的台词，甚至每个人物说那些台词时的表情、语调、语气语速我都能模仿，场景环境也会在脑海里栩栩如生。我现在就特别向往还有那样的能力，要是我在看电影，你在旁边跟我说话，我根本听不到。虽然这个习惯还没有彻底丧失，但还是做不到以前那样专注，包括读书。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;在流动帐篷看电影看到了二十多岁，家里那时候有电视了吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们家通电是2008年，我23岁，那时候我已经结婚了，帐篷电影也慢慢不景气了。太阳能出现后，很多牧民就买一台小黑白电视机，买一个VCD，买两块大的太阳能充电器和一个电瓶蓄电池就可以在家里看，我家也是。我经常把那个蓄电池看到亏电，通电是冬牧场，是定居点，其他的游牧点哪有电，还是照样放，反正帐篷电影还是苟延残喘了七八年，才彻底没有了。后来大家又有了手机。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你觉得牧区现在的生活跟城市的差距还大吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;基本没有差别，有了手机之后其实就没有任何差别。城市和牧区的信息流没有滞后性，当你们得到这样一个重大信息的时候，我们的手机里立刻也弹出来了，只不过关注点不一样。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;牧民的生活也随之发生了很大变化？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是啊，尤其是对青年一代的影响，是一个彻底的转换。父辈一直处在游牧的序列当中，当他们年纪大了、由我们这一代接替上去的时候，就像断层一样改变了生活方式。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;附近的农民农闲的时候会到牧区来盖房子，做一些临时工，他们无一例外都会很羡慕我们。因为他们看到所有男人不论老少，都是很悠闲的样子，年老一点的整天喝喝酒、骑骑马，到处溜达，把羊赶回来、赶出去；年轻一点的，天天不是玩就是打台球，看电影，谈恋爱。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;现在十几岁的小孩，还有可能去放牧吗？不会吧，都去读书了，所有牧民的认知都改变了。以前不会觉得读书是唯一的出路，或是人生未来最好的一个前提，但是现在就会这么做。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;但是你也没有走那条路。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我们那一批很多都没有走，所以我们这一代是最后的游牧人了，下一代没有几个人会去真正游牧的，游牧正在萎缩。这个萎缩不单单是我们自己决定的，更多的是生态政策调整，我们青海是重要的保护区，一切都以保护生态、提供良好循环为前提，所以不鼓励放牧。有很多限制，比如说不能养太多牛羊，得取决于草场的承载力，如果有一千亩草场，就只能养两三百只羊。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yYMPeuFO6Ju7Wkz3NVTlS0taekLSKwGzQf6SdUMh.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;683&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/yYMPeuFO6Ju7Wkz3NVTlS0taekLSKwGzQf6SdUMh.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256519&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;h4>;粗犷与细腻都是草原上的真实&lt;/h4>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;现在回想起来，你会觉得不上学是一个很好的选择吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我不认为我的女儿也能够在这条路上坚持那么长时间，那是不现实的，这是个别的案例，还得有一点天赋。我现在有的时候也是不敢想象——我怎么能莫名其妙成了一个作家？我要不是作家的话，我肯定在做生意或者在干其他的一些事情，我觉得那样一直在一个环境里待着没意思，我总想改变一点自己的活法。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你现在每天去县里的工作室，活动范围似乎更小了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;自我的精神空间不就更大了吗？我也经常去牧区那边，很近嘛，经常就是纯粹去转一圈，什么也不干，有时候就去找朋友玩玩，或给亲戚帮忙。那边也有房子，羊舍牛棚都是现成的。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;类似《请一头牛吃饭》这种故事，是你听来的还是发生在你牛棚里的事改编的？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是从一个很小的点构思的虚构故事。我们家门口有一个大盆子，装着各种菜叶子和剩饭，每天晚上牦牛归圈的时候，有一两头会固定来吃。它俩霸占着那个地方，其它的牛来了，它们会用犄角发起攻击，几次之后，其它的就不来了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;那时候已经通电了，我家从老房子到新房子接的电线太长，中间立了一个根头杆子，有一天它们两个就没吃到，就在那流连不去，发泄似地从胸腔里蹦出颤动的声音，把那根杆子给顶折了。把我气得呀，电线杆子倒下，虽然没有伤到人，但是让我损失很大，电线扯掉两边，保险全部烧毁了。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;它们在闹的时候，会有意识地知道不能伤害主人，所以它们没撞门，不会闯进来。你知道我们以前最烦牛的是什么？夏天秋天的时候天快亮，凌晨四五点的时候，牛就会慢慢地吃东西，一直吃到帐篷旁边来。因为人的走动、倒一些水，那一片有盐分。赶都赶不走，顶多往外走两三步，过一会儿又回来了，又吃帐篷的帆布边，嚼得不让你睡觉。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bbhbALOhJpzgz4f89UXuCgxQvoW2yviZp3xM87IA.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;617&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; data-src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/bbhbALOhJpzgz4f89UXuCgxQvoW2yviZp3xM87IA.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256517&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;牧民的脾性会因此比较有耐心吗？因为要懂得如何适应这种跟动物的相处。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;也没有，都是暴脾气，动物并没有改变他们什么，反而变本加厉，虐待牛羊的多的是，这两年稍微好些。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;那种简单粗暴的语言环境，你觉得对你写小说是好还是不好呢？会觉得我是不是可能要更细腻一点？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;我的小说不就呈现出简单粗暴的样子吗？当然当然，我正在努力地让自己的文本在粗犷中有细腻的成分。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;什么时候开始转变的，是因为旁人的评价吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;是我自己意识到的，到了一定地步，你就会意识到这个。不可能写了两三本书，一直这样，你还津津乐道、自以为是。看多了、写多了之后，《找信号》就是有这种意识后的产物，你看里面《圣人画像与象牙麻将》那个中篇和《荒原上》就不一样，我写得细腻多了。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;新书里第一篇《哲学教授》写的是一位当教授的后妈嫁来主人公的家，我觉得对其中那位18岁少年的心理部分描写还挺细致。那个故事你是怎么想到的？跟你年少的经历有关系，还是当地有过一位这样的外来教授？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;（&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;思索很久后&lt;/span>;）我想起来了，不是教授，是猫王音响！我当时想买一个音响，挑来挑去，最后看中猫王核桃木的一款，就突发奇想，如果这个音响产生了一个故事，它会是什么？其实那个就是一个引子，后来在小说里音响都抛到九霄云外。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;有了细腻的意识后现在写起来会跟之前感觉很不一样吗？&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;有了这个意识之后，会有一点警觉，也会有一些焦虑。但如果我过分地追求某一方，就会失去另外一方，写作还是得掌握一个平衡。我不能这边丢得太多，那边放得太多。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;南方人物周刊：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: 楷体, 楷体_GB2312, STKaiti;&quot;>;你还是很珍视牧民身份带来的粗放。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;索南才让：&lt;/strong>;&lt;span>;那种风格是草原上的一个真实。它的真实性是特别重要的，但是不代表说草原上的这种真实性里就没有细腻，有细腻，但是我还没有完全学到，那么我要接着学习，学习的时候要平衡两边的关系。&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我国新增4处世界灌溉工程遗产]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259983]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05 08:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;安徽七门堰调蓄灌溉系统、江苏洪泽古灌区、山西霍泉灌溉工程、湖北崇阳县白霓古堰4日成功入选2023年（第十批）世界灌溉工程遗产名录。至此，我国的世界灌溉工程遗产达到34处。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;记者从水利部了解到，第十批世界灌溉工程遗产名录，是在印度维萨卡帕特南召开的国际灌排委员会第74届执行理事会上公布的。中国国家灌排委员会主席、水利部农村水利水电司司长陈明忠说，我国的世界灌溉工程遗产几乎涵盖了灌溉工程的所有类型，是灌溉工程遗产类型最丰富、分布最广泛、灌溉效益最突出的国家。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;七门堰调蓄灌溉系统位于安徽省舒城县境内，最早创建于西汉，利用湿地形态，“串荡成渠，连塘为蓄”，两千多年来发挥着重要的灌溉、防洪、防旱作用，目前灌溉农田达20万亩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;洪泽古灌区位于江苏省淮安市洪泽区境内，为蓄水型灌区，由蓄水、取水、输水和排水工程组成。自东汉开始，古人引水灌溉耕作，历代建设水利设施，灌区延续至今。目前，灌区控制灌溉面积48.13万亩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;霍泉灌溉工程位于山西省洪洞县，自唐贞观年间开始便有明确记载，至今仍发挥着灌溉、供水、生态、旅游等功能。目前，工程灌溉总面积为10.1万亩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;白霓古堰位于湖北省崇阳县境内，包括石枧堰和远陂堰两座古堰。文献记载，古堰最早建于五代后唐时期，至今仍发挥着灌溉、防洪、抗旱、供水等功能，灌溉面积约3.5万亩。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;世界灌溉工程遗产名录自2014年设立，旨在梳理世界灌溉文明发展脉络、促进灌溉工程遗产保护，总结传统灌溉工程治水智慧，为可持续灌溉发展提供历史经验和启示。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;据了解，与我国4项遗产同时列入第十批世界灌溉工程遗产名录的，还有来自印度、印度尼西亚、伊拉克、日本、泰国、土耳其等国的15个项目。目前，世界灌溉工程遗产总数达159项。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 08:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“海”中取粮]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://www.infzm.com/contents/259946]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04 23:00:00&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/y4O4A33lBsLB3TRC9iI9iD6PgQUk9TK3l1GPwqIJ.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;593&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/y4O4A33lBsLB3TRC9iI9iD6PgQUk9TK3l1GPwqIJ.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256515&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科研人员正在为水稻搭建防鸟网。在海水稻灌浆期，防鸟工作尤为重要，不采取措施可能会颗粒无收&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;清晨日头刚起，张树寅戴好遮阳帽，一手拿着试验记录本，一手揣着大容量水袋，钻进绿色的稻浪，一待就是一上午。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;张树寅是青岛海水稻研究发展中心科研人员，他和同事6个人扎根在三亚国家南繁科研育种基地约百亩的试验田，一待就是半年，他们在试验田里选育着近两千份水稻种质资源。对于张树寅和同事而言，“我们每天摸的是水稻，想的也是水稻。这片田里的每一个品种都像是我们的孩子，一天也离不开它们。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/hV72HFJ9duFfnIK5Or93SaqKjU5epYGrRWkGAosp.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/hV72HFJ9duFfnIK5Or93SaqKjU5epYGrRWkGAosp.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256505&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科研人员顾晓振（左）、殷会德（右）在做田间记录，包括水稻长势、株高、分蘖数等&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;何为“海水稻”？张树寅解释说，从字面意思上理解，“海水稻”是与海水有关联的水稻。不是指能够在海水里生长的水稻，而是耐盐碱水稻，可以在沿海滩涂和内陆盐碱地种植。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/CPxtRxs7AA4sFPt1oSQh8PRxf2sMpHtXFEDOE0Da.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;618&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/CPxtRxs7AA4sFPt1oSQh8PRxf2sMpHtXFEDOE0Da.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256514&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科研人员张树寅正在补充水分。三亚常年气温高，科研人员每天都要携带大容量水袋&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;“人类从未停止过向险恶的自然环境挑战。在盐碱地上种植&#39;海水稻&#39;就是其中的一种方式。”张树寅介绍，青岛海水稻研究发展中心总部设在青岛，从2016年开始，他和同事们每年秋季就奔赴三亚南繁进行水稻播种，待到次年4、5月份水稻成熟采收后，再带着培育出的优质的耐盐碱水稻品种返回总部进行下一步的研究。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/JD0I9L3swqxxfMbqJNbRTh1jBivSrAYWsNMtRcAR.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/JD0I9L3swqxxfMbqJNbRTh1jBivSrAYWsNMtRcAR.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256506&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科研人员于萌在田间做杂交试验：整理稻株稻穗，剪颖去雄&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;在南繁基地，科研人员对稻田进行巡查、选取稻株开展杂交实验、对水稻材料手工脱粒……日复一日。“海南一年四季均可开展水稻试验研究，能够加速育种进程，科研时间能缩短一半。”张树寅说，他们培育一个水稻新品种，平均需要经历8次更新换代才能获得一个稳定的品种。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/69zGhORE7gDfoStZOfXARtjxYxDd5xk88eaATqsB.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;609&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/69zGhORE7gDfoStZOfXARtjxYxDd5xk88eaATqsB.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256508&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;于萌在泥泞的稻田里行走，深一脚浅一脚（&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;青岛海水稻研究发展中心技术研发部部长万吉丽介绍，“目前，我们已经拥有种质资源近2000份。种质的耐盐能力也不断提高,从最初的3‰，提高到现在的8‰。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DvLNQNmj2dlVcSV386QDR0ZE3wjAygAQa45iCEPb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DvLNQNmj2dlVcSV386QDR0ZE3wjAygAQa45iCEPb.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256504&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;结实的杂交稻穗。这表明杂交试验成功，可以收获到杂交种&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;从2012年到2022年，耐盐碱的“海水稻”已从科研试验阶段，发展到产业化规模化推广。截至2022年年底，我国“海水稻”种植面积已突破100万亩，品种覆盖全国四大类典型盐碱地。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Ry0MumwOXN7tZRQMN0ywoRbVvhXLh5sN5iThHsMu.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/Ry0MumwOXN7tZRQMN0ywoRbVvhXLh5sN5iThHsMu.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256509&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;福寿螺几乎在水稻的整个生育期都会产生危害&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;全国有15亿亩盐碱地，其中适宜种植粮食的有5亿亩，利用潜力十分巨大。在不久的将来，那些之前看起来“用处不大”的盐碱地或将成为“再造良田”。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/tHUXMLc8ErnYEhyMG4wPGyuPM7r3TUg8IJCxPVXn.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/tHUXMLc8ErnYEhyMG4wPGyuPM7r3TUg8IJCxPVXn.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256516&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;水稻育种专家杨汉树（右）带领科研人员查看水稻长势，并指导选育工作&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/zor9FwWokvX43ONAFEcO9f2dpWiQwqz7sDgFL66d.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;518&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/zor9FwWokvX43ONAFEcO9f2dpWiQwqz7sDgFL66d.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256507&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科研人员在进行水稻制种材料调查。树起隔离膜是为了防止花粉偷偷授粉“交流”&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2aTkg7ZtQzIGh0ZMjjDMTTNUqi3h2pUzPZtdjVL4.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;546&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/2aTkg7ZtQzIGh0ZMjjDMTTNUqi3h2pUzPZtdjVL4.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256512&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科研人员彭南锡正在进行水稻脱粒。他采用比较原始的脚踩脱粒机，便于清机，以免种子混杂&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d8o2Pxve2K1vWdhNVZYHUm6gIJxmVkfozN8UTvng.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;625&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/d8o2Pxve2K1vWdhNVZYHUm6gIJxmVkfozN8UTvng.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256510&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科研人员在打开调好比例的海水给水稻灌溉&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DpftIXzh8QpHPXtENJBmdHBWuSHmR1nKKj26ZudD.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/DpftIXzh8QpHPXtENJBmdHBWuSHmR1nKKj26ZudD.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256511&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;科研人员收获的不同水稻种子。每一袋种子都可能藏着好品种&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/U0Lp7Nf0B8wssfiiGjCmLOVOQBRd00FYdYFvjuHc.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;540&quot; data-src=&quot;//images.infzm.com/cms/medias/image/23/11/01/U0Lp7Nf0B8wssfiiGjCmLOVOQBRd00FYdYFvjuHc.jpg&quot; data-key=&quot;256513&quot;>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;color: #999; text-align: center;&quot;>;海南省三亚市崖州区国家耐盐碱水稻技术创新中心海水稻试验基地&lt;span style=&quot;color: #aaa;&quot;>;（张茂/图）&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 23:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>