<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约客</title><description>纽约客全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.newyoker.com <item><title><![CDATA[Innovative Ways to Demand an N.B.A. Trade]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/innovative-ways-to-demand-an-nba-trade]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T16:06:21.597Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65367b7a13c1e561d000bf20/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Babb-Shouts-NBA-Trades.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508 V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>; &lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/ span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height= &quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12 .5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V 4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt; span >;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey -hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;在整个联盟出现多个交易请求的休赛期之后，篮球赛季即将到来。 NBA 请求交易的传统方式是球员或其代表与球队管理层进行谈判。但 2022 年就是这样了。是时候发挥创意，让您的交易请求像病毒一样传播开来了。把它当作一场舞会。向您的团队表明您是认真的。以下是球员可以用来让自己穿上新球队制服的一些交易请求想法，统计数据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;退役，然后再退役&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有人愿意打电话它退出了。但如果你想让你的球队知道你永远不会再为他们效力，那就挂上球衣吧。退出你喜爱的游戏。你的合同将无效。然后静坐一年，然后发现——天哪！——你改变了主意。当你二十二岁退役时，你只需要从比赛中休息一下。好好休息后，二十三岁回来，与你原本想交易的球队签约。这是一个大胆的举动，可能会让您损失数百万美元，但想想您将不得不一直玩电子游戏！&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在另一支球队的竞技场前扎营&lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;露营将表明您有多么致力于改变自己的处境。假设这是 iPhone 版本。准备一个帐篷和一些瓶装水，然后在所需团队的总部前面开设商店。你是一名 NBA 球员，这意味着你的身高和名气足以吸引人们的注意。你不会孤单，因为媒体和粉丝会和你一起出去玩。您甚至可能会在进入大楼的路上遇到您想要的团队的经理，并将您的简历交给他。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;纹身您的交易请求&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport- monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;将您的交易请求写在身上。每个人都会看着你想，他一定很讨厌他所在的球队；另外，我想知道纹身师是谁——他们做得很棒！把它放在你的前臂或脸上，或者两者兼而有之——这将是不可避免的，而且对于你当前的团队成员来说，每当他们看到你时，事情都会变得非常尴尬。当他们问“你好吗？”时，你只需指着你的纹身即可。一旦你被交易，请去除纹身，并为你准备好请求另一次交易腾出空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;向泰勒·斯威夫特支付费用以发布你的交易请求&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;如果您希望自己的事业得到关注，请向泰勒·斯威夫特寻求帮助。无论她发布什么内容，Swifties 都会团结起来。泰勒将你的交易请求发布到她的 Instagram 故事上二十四小时，这将改变你未来几年的生活。如果她标记团队主席，他将无法处理数以百万计的 Swifties 向他的社交媒体帐户发送垃圾邮件。他不想在 Swifties 不利的一方待太久。这种社会耻辱是难以克服的。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;获得一款签名鞋&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥有自己的运动鞋的玩家会出于各种不同的原因发布特别版本。例如，迈克尔·乔丹 (Michael Jordan) 出售“流感游戏”版的鞋子，因为他在 NBA 总决赛期间带病打球时穿着这双鞋。为您的签名鞋制作一个特殊的配色，称为“Trade Request”版或“Get Me Out of Town”版。颜色？显然它们必须是你想效力的球队的颜色。拍摄一个由斯派克·李主演的很酷的广告，这样当你最终被交易时，人们就会说，“一定是鞋子！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;举办一个派对，只邀请来自不同球队的球员&lt;/strong >;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每个人都喜欢精彩的聚会。他们不喜欢的是不被邀请。举办一场聚会，只邀请您想效力的球队中的球员。不要邀请你现在的队友。聚会结束后的第二天，在社交媒体上发布聚会的照片。当你的队友看到他们错过的所有乐趣时，比如香槟喷泉、杂技杂耍和激烈的叠叠乐游戏，他们会感到被冒犯。他们会非常生气，再也不会把球传给你，从而迫使管理层确保你尽快离开球队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;从家里得到一张便条&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;父母或监护人的便条的力量被低估了。仅仅因为你不再是孩子，并不意味着你父母形象的权威就不那么重要了。让你妈妈给球队主席写一封简短的便条，说：“我的儿子不再被允许为你的球队效力，因为我们有顾虑。”繁荣——问题解决了。什么样的球队主席不会听取球员妈妈的担忧？&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;从你的医生那里得到一张便条&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;如果那个无情的球队主席不理会家里的便条，你就必须用医生的便条提高赌注。让你的医生解释为什么你因身体原因不能再为球队效力，并且必须迅速被交易到新球队。这是一个需要解决的严峻形势。你的团队主席有义务倾听科学。从你的医生那里得到这张单子，你很快就会被派到一个新的团队开始治疗过程。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;6bo8un&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;16ccsx&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 01:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How the Yale Unions Took Over New Haven]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/dispatch/how-the-yale-unions-took-over-new-haven]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T15:04:02.068Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65315c44644ae0aa3f4c29e3/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/NewYorker_YaleUnions_R3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2. 95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/s vg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/ span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d= “M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3” H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;纽黑文绿地 (New Haven Green) 是一座 17 世纪的公园，一侧毗邻法院大楼和朴素的政府办公室，包括纽黑文市政厅独特的条纹外观。对面是耶鲁大学豪华的哥特式建筑，这是常春藤盟校，拥有四百亿美元的捐赠。平衡城镇和大学的利益在很大程度上取决于纽黑文奥尔德斯委员会，这是一个由三十名成员组成的委员会。董事会每月召开两次会议，出席的桤木成员通常比公众多得多。但在二月初，在市政厅二楼举行的一次会议上，桤木数量处于劣势。人群挤在长椅上，沿着后墙站立，聆听市长贾斯汀·埃利克 (Justin Elicker) 发表年度市情咨文。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;身着深蓝色西装、身材瘦长的耶鲁大学校友埃利克 (Justin Elicker) 宣称纽黑文在经历了大流行病低迷和六千六百万美元的预算赤字后，“表现优于整个州和所有其他主要城市”。尽管中位家庭的收入仍然约为四万九千美元，四分之一的居民生活在联邦贫困线或以下，但复苏是真实的。耶鲁大学是该市最大的土地所有者，是一家非营利组织，因此无需缴纳学校财产税。 （耶鲁大学和耶鲁纽黑文医院的总税收减免将涵盖该市的大部分教育预算。）1990年，该大学开始每年自愿付款，通常只是象征性地支付其所欠费用的一小部分。埃里克解释说，事情开始发生变化。他说，到 2022 年，“我们将耶鲁大学的年度自愿捐款几乎增加了一倍，从 1300 万美元增加到 2300 万美元”。据市长说，原因之一是？ “&lt;em>;Unite Here&lt;/em>; 进行了数十年的草根组织。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;Unite Here&lt;/em>; 是一个北美工会，植根于服装和酒店行业，即以敢于罢工而闻名。其在纽黑文的部门已发展到拥有约八千名在耶鲁工作的员工。最早的努力始于 1941 年的 Local 35，当时校园发电厂的机械师组织起来，后来努力引进了保管员和餐厅工人。 1984 年，工会罢工了十周，支持接待员、图书管理员和实验室研究人员组建 Local 34。最近，经过三十多年的几次失败尝试，研究生教师终于赢得了自己的工会 Local 34。 33.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市长称赞工会让大学负起责任，但这一姿态也是政治上的权宜之计：奥尔德斯委员会由&lt;em>;团结在这里&lt;/em>;的成员或盟友主导。在 2011 年一场名为“Alderania”的竞选活动中，工会选出了一批候选人，以赢得董事会的多数席位。这个想法是让工人阶级居民进入政府，并使委员会不仅仅是市长的橡皮图章机制。在炎热的夏季，数周的上门拜访得到了回报：工会支持的十八名候选人中有十七人赢得了选举。他们是黑人、白人和拉丁裔；其中有一名耶鲁大学看门人、一名耶鲁大学图书馆助理和一名耶鲁大学本科生。此后，多数席位一直保持不变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰莎·沃克-迈尔斯 (Tyisha Walker-Myers) 在 2011 年选举中成为桤木议员，目前已是董事会主席的第四个任期。在市情咨文演讲期间，她坐在埃里克的右边，戴着眼镜，留着长辫子。她在西河长大，这是一个以黑人为主的社区，当时该地区的工厂正在萎缩。她就读于阿尔伯特·马格努斯学院，这是纽黑文当地的一所罗马天主教大学，但她感到格格不入——“我是唯一的少数派”——所以没有拿到学位就离开了。 1998 年，她在耶鲁大学的一家餐厅找到了一份工作，这是她第一次真正体验这所大学，超越了它给她的家乡带来的金钱阴影。 “如果你来到校园而不应该在那里，你就会被保安赶出去，”她回忆道。她成为 Local 35 的一名商店代表，然后在工会找到了一份全职工作。她涉足当地政治——从技术上讲，桤木工作是兼职，而且只有很少的津贴——仍然感觉很奇怪。 “人们认为政治是扭曲的，”她说。 “我不是政客，因为我不撒谎。我很直率。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在全国各地，&lt;em>;Unite Here&lt;/em>;在选举政治上投入了大量资金。拉斯维加斯的当地人之一，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1996/02/26/how-the-maids-fought-back&quot;>;烹饪联盟&lt;/a>; ，为保持内华达蓝色发挥了重要作用。在加利福尼亚州，前&lt;em>;团结在这里&lt;/em>;组织者玛丽亚·埃琳娜·杜拉索（María Elena Durazo）是加利福尼亚州参议院的重要成员，并曾担任民主党全国委员会副主席。但正是在纽黑文，工会才最接近真正的政党运作。耶鲁当地人让成员上台的努力是弥合纽黑文城镇礼服分歧的更大使命的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;这是一个令人畏惧、雄心勃勃的计划：打破种族、阶级和精英教育的界限。有些经历永远不会被分享。埃里克在演讲中谈到了枪支暴力的话题。新年刚过一个月，拥有十三万九千人口的纽黑文市已有五名居民被杀——全是有色人种。 （纽黑文市的白人约占百分之四十；其余大部分是黑人或拉丁裔。）第一位受害者唐泰·迈尔斯 (Dontae Myers) 在元旦被枪杀时年仅 23 岁。他的兄弟 Dashown 于 2020 年在类似的情况下被杀，&lt;em>;Unite Here&lt;/em>; 发起的一个名为 New Haven Rising 的社区团体在他们两人去世后组织了守夜活动。男孩们的母亲拉奎维亚·琼斯 (LaQuvia Jones) 是沃克·迈尔斯最好的朋友，关系就像姐妹一样亲密。市长解释了琼斯说过的话：“当你扣动扳机时，你并不是把它扣在目标上。你把它拉到一个社区上。你可以对任何爱那个人的人施加压力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;一月份，Dontae 葬礼的计划与工会的庆祝活动。距离市政厅几个街区，穿着牛仔裤和破旧别致毛衣的研究生聚集在卫理公会教堂的地下室里，该教堂向工会租用了空间，观看国家劳工关系委员会的现场直播，以确认支持和反对当地工会的选票。 33. 观看派对基本上没有悬念（赞成票压倒性的），但当工会宣布正式成立时，房间里仍然欢呼雀跃。有一种决心的感觉。同时，结果将测试&lt;em>;Unite Here&lt;/em>;模型的耐用性。毕业生工人将他们的要求建立在当地人 35 和 34 的斗争之上：纽黑文的工人阶级。这些工会成员期望效忠于耶鲁的劳工和城市居民的需求。阿尔德马尼亚已经十多年了，现在它已成为一个在一个顽固不平等的地方进行的成熟的政治实验。耶鲁大学工会能否在研究生、保管人和记账员之间找到足够的共同点来让实验继续下去？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城袍的分歧几乎和大学城本身一样古老。在十四世纪中叶的一个传说中，牛津大学的学生指责 Swindlestock Tavern 酒馆的老板提供劣质酒。城镇居民前来保卫酒馆，冲突爆发为一场为期三天的骚乱，造成近百人死亡。很久以后，美国引进了物理上和社会上与世隔绝的英国大学体系的许多方面。当学院只是当地经济的一部分时，镇与镇的关系被证明是可以管理的。当曾经因制造业繁荣的城市过度依赖高等教育时，压力变得更加严重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到了七十年代和八十年代，纽黑文的工厂纷纷关闭。工人们转向医疗保健和服务业工作，耶鲁大学成为该市最好的雇主之一。 （它的姊妹公司耶鲁纽黑文医疗系统是康涅狄格州最大的私人雇主。）耶鲁大学的入学人数和实体规模不断扩大，其捐赠基金以难以理解的速度增长，自大衰退以来翻了一番。与此同时，纽黑文仍然相对贫困：非营利组织 DataHaven 发现，从 1990 年到 2017 年（近三十年），家庭收入中位数减少了约两千美元。五分之四的高薪工作由不住在城市的郊区通勤者担任。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;耶鲁大学为成为好邻居做出了一些努力：它建立了一个纽黑文事务办公室重建了市中心的商业走廊，并为大学员工设立了首次购房补贴，其中许多人来自周边社区。尽管如此，耶鲁大学工会仍然认为需要进行更雄心勃勃的重新分配。他们推行的举措与合同或其他典型的工会费用无关，引发了“机器政治”的指控以及批评者的不当影响。 Local 35 的历史学家、纽约大学毕业生工人工会前成员扎克·施瓦茨-韦恩斯坦 (Zach Schwartz-Weinstein) 告诉我：“这种工业工会主义的特殊愿景非常独特，在其他高等教育机构中并不常见。” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工会向耶鲁大学施压，要求其向市政府提供更多自愿付款，并审查耶鲁大学的建筑许可请求。他们与该大学合作开展了一项本地招聘计划，该计划于 2015 年承诺在五年内从纽黑文雇佣 1000 名居民，其中一半来自以少数族裔为主的“有需要的社区”。当耶鲁未能跟上步伐时，奥尔德斯委员会召开了一次听证会，听证会挤满了奥尔德斯会议厅。董事会主席沃克-迈尔斯指责耶鲁大学夸大了短期建筑工作的统计数据。一位大学代表承诺“考虑系统性变革”以实现其目标。 （2021 年，这一目标得以实现。）&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data- node-id=&quot;n3xru&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Unite Here&lt;/em>;战略的一部分是从耶鲁大学学生团体中招募组织者。 1969年，它聘请了曾是工人阶级转学生和民权活动家的约翰·威廉(John Wilhelm)。当时，Local 35 正在进行长期、积极的罢工，以争取高于贫困水平的工资。威廉认为，工会应该主要由普通工人来管理——他的导师是文森特·西拉贝拉（Vincent Sirabella），他曾是一名服务员和调酒师，由普罗维登斯当地人晋升——但他也看到了知识分子的一席之地。 2000 年，工会招募了在纽黑文长大的康奈尔大学毕业生格温·米尔斯 (Gwen Mills)。米尔斯帮助开展了为奥尔德斯委员会管理劳工名单的运动。和 Wilhelm 一样，她后来被晋升为 &lt;em>;Unite Here&lt;/em>; 国际总部的高管职位。他们设计了一条供数十名耶鲁大学毕业生遵循的职业道路原型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4 月，Wilhelm 和 Mills 飞往纽黑文，为 Local 33 的胜利举行了为期两天的庆祝活动。前博士来自美国、英国和巴西各地的学生（其中许多现已成为终身教授）聚集在卫理公会教堂的避难所中。米尔斯站在讲坛上，描述了她从憎恨耶鲁的城镇居民到工会组织者的转变。 “我是在离这里一英里的地方长大的，”她说。 “我在这个避难所结婚了。”她回忆起童年时流行的保险杠贴纸——“嘟嘟！嘟！耶鲁大学很便宜！”——这批评了大学对社区的吝啬态度。她说，纽黑文是一个“后工业化的制造业小镇，一家价值数十亿美元的教育公司突然出现在它的中间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我在十九世纪末作为一名大学新生来到耶鲁大学 -九十年代，天真且毫无准备。我从未在东海岸呆过。我不擅长研究和写作。我不认识任何有钱的人。当我试图闲聊并问一个女孩她来自哪里时，她说：“切尔西。”另一个预科学校的孩子回答说：“公园大道。”在哪里？与此同时，耶鲁大学发出的信息是留在校园内，远离纽黑文市中心的危险。当我了解到研究生员工和学生组织（Local 33 的前身）&lt;em>;GESO&lt;/em>; 的努力时，我感到这堵疏离之墙出现了一道小小的裂缝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回首过去，它对于 35 岁和 34 岁的当地人来说，要求餐厅厨师和图书馆助理（他们住在我被告知要避开的社区）将他们的会费捐给年轻古典学者联盟是有风险的，更不用说那些看似可以继续研究的化学家了。大型制药公司的高薪工作。芭芭拉·维琳 (Barbara Vereen) 是 Local 34 的一名工作人员，当时从事医疗账单工作，在纽黑文长大，她告诉我，她最初对毕业生竞选活动不屑一顾。然后，在 2003 年，她听到了关于终身教授制度的演讲。 “我回来后告诉我的同事，我们对这一切的看法都是错误的，”她说。 “就像，这些人是工人。他们和我们遇到了同样的问题。”耶鲁大学历史学家迈克尔·丹宁告诉我，“最初十年或十五年的斗争是将研究生的教学工作视为工作。”我写了两三篇文章来向自己证明这一点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;更多的说服力来自耶鲁大学。来自九十年代和两千名的&lt;em>;GESO&lt;/em>;成员经历了多年的激烈交易。即使在看似对工会友好的部门，学生组织者也表示他们被边缘化，甚至被列入黑名单。 “在人类学中，这是堑壕战，”博士纳齐玛·卡迪尔 (Nazima Kadir) 说。那个系的学生告诉我的。她的一位同学差点被开除。一位站出来支持他们的副教授被剥夺了终身教职。这位教授就是&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2013/05/13/paint-bombs&quot;>;David Graeber&lt;/a>;，他后来在英国任教并帮助发起了“占领墙”运动街道。 （根据耶鲁大学的说法，格雷伯团队中的绝大多数教授都被剥夺了终身教职；大学坚称它尊重组织权。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在两千名教授中，随着大学越来越依赖博士生，教授的职位也越来越多。 D .为了满足教学需求，美国各地的研究生和硕士候选人纷纷求助于工会。但是，在私立大学，这支劳动力的地位并不稳定：他们是学生学徒，还是值得组织权利的真正雇员？国家劳动关系委员会在这个问题上反复讨论。 2016 年，Local 33 在几个选定的部门成立了工会； 2017年，成员绝食抗议。然后，在特朗普时代之后，工会重新发起了全面的运动。 2022 年秋天，组织者收集了两千多张工会卡，与往年不同的是，耶鲁大学的管理人员和教职员工大多没有理睬学生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Local 33 今年的胜利是众多学术界压倒性胜利之一几个月后举行选举。在波士顿大学，工会赢得了百分之九十八的选票；芝加哥大学为 92%；明尼苏达大学于 1974 年首次尝试建立工会，这一比例为 97%；在杜克大学，百分之八十八。去年年底，加州大学近五万名研究生教师和研究人员罢工了六周，这是美国历史上最大规模的学术停工。几个月后，罗格斯大学约九千名学术人员因合同到期而辞职。只有耶鲁大学的毕业生工人融入了更大的校园工会，但罗格斯大学的竞选活动强调了与社区的联系。它的“共同利益”要求包括冻结罗格斯大学拥有的所有房产的租金以及对周边社区进行数百万美元的投资——尽管它在谈判桌上都没有获胜。 （罗格斯大学确实承诺通过非营利组织分配六十万美元。）&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;pa667p&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data- testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;自 2022 年初以来，国家劳动关系委员会已在私立学院和大学认证了 27 个谈判单位，包括超过 32000 名学生工人。在达特茅斯大学、宾夕法尼亚大学、巴纳德大学、塔夫茨大学和马萨诸塞大学阿默斯特分校，在校内工作的本科生也组织起来。加州州立大学系统 23 个校区的约 19000 名学生工人很快将在工会选举中投票。圣地亚哥州立大学的本科生科林·卡尔弗告诉我，大多数人来自城里的工薪阶层家庭。学校支付给他们的工资低于正式员工的工资。 “他们利用学生员工来降低每个人的工资，”卡尔弗说。他希望工会能够阻止这种情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年春天，我会见了苏莱玛·汉密尔顿 (Sulema Hamilton)，她是 Local 35 的管理员，她刚刚在耶鲁大学亚裔美国文化中心下班。 （我大四时在那里工作，作为我经济援助计划的一部分。）该中心坐落在一栋古老的三层砖砌建筑内，有一个带顶棚的门廊。汉密尔顿穿着耶鲁海军蓝衣服和安全鞋，戴着闪闪发光的耳环。她说，当她在纽黑文长大时，她的祖母在一家枪支工厂工作，并且是一个工会成员。汉密尔顿去上大学，然后回来结婚并抚养两个女儿和一个儿子。多年来，她一直担任银行出纳员，但一段时间后，她的职业生涯陷入停滞。她知道耶鲁大学的工作是工会性质的，所以询问了一个文员职位，设想在办公桌前做一些事情。招聘人员给她指出了另一个方向。 “她说，‘这可能是厨房，或保管服务，’”汉密尔顿告诉我。 “我说，‘好吧，我在家里做所有这些事情——这能有多困难呢？’她确实有一项非常肮脏的任务——在耶鲁大学拥有的格里芬酒吧，闻起来像啤酒和小便的味道。 “我让它看起来像一座宫殿，”她说。 “我从来没有把自己的立场视为‘我做得少了’。” ” 她的清洁工工资和福利很快就超过了她作为出纳员的收入。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汉密尔顿将自己视为普通麻烦的解决者，是那种如果你遇到麻烦时你会想在身边的人。 ：无薪加班、不适当的命令、令人讨厌的主管。她和我采访的其他校园工作人员也从更广泛的角度描述了工会成员身份。 “如果你想到一个大机构、一个大机构，你就必须涉足政界，”耶鲁大学癌症中心的医疗助理兼 Local 34 的副总裁丽莎·史蒂文斯 (Lisa Stevens) 告诉我。 “你必须找到其他的战斗方式。我们永远无法与他们相比。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年，汉密尔顿抽出时间为宾夕法尼亚州和佐治亚州的民主党参议员候选人拉票。 Locals 35 和 34 的其他成员以及 Local 33 的毕业生也加入了她的行列。工会支持民主党政客的情况并不罕见。但是，在 2020 年，&lt;em>;Unite Here&lt;/em>; 总部的纽黑文镇居民格温·米尔斯 (Gwen Mills) 设计了一项群众动员活动，其目的是增加收入。大多数&lt;em>;团结在这里&lt;/em>;成员在酒店和酒店业工作，在大流行期间失业了。工会为他们提供了每小时一次的上门工作，并帮助他们在亚利桑那州、宾夕法尼亚州和佐治亚州取得了令人紧张的胜利（尽管覆盖亚利桑那州和南加州的 Local 11 后来似乎对他们代表现在所做的努力感到遗憾）参议员 Kyrsten Sinema）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当&lt;em>;GESO&lt;/em>;在九十年代开始时，研究生会被认为是时尚，而且在经济上是不必要的：这是性别研究学者或父母是马克思主义学生的职权范围。马克思主义教授。 &lt;em>;STEM&lt;/em>;人们被认为很难组织。国际学生也是如此。现在很难想象出一个典型的形象。在教堂地下室计票时，我注意到一名南亚妇女穿着一件剪裁 T 恤，上面写着“Local 33 &lt;em >;UNITEHERE&lt;/em>;!”锁子甲风格的按钮，当她在房间里走动时发出叮当作响的声音。她的名字叫 Arita Acharya，她已经从博士学位课程中休学了。从事遗传学工作，为工会工作。 “我进入 STEM 的部分原因是我真正的渴望和好奇心，但同时我的文化也让我相信这是唯一值得做的事情，”她告诉我。在大流行期间，她曾在纽黑文游说，试图让人们接种疫苗，并发现组织是“我可能想要的另一件事”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前组织者告诉我，&lt;em>;团结在这里&lt;/em >; 的期望是“疯狂的”，而这次经历是“令人筋疲力尽的”。他们还表示，这改变了他们的生活。沙娜·雷德蒙德（Shana Redmond）现在是哥伦比亚大学的英语教授，她是 GESO 的一部分，该组织向耶鲁大学施压，要求其从私人监狱公司撤资。她告诉我，作为“曾经被监禁者的孩子”，她在那次竞选中看到了“工会的可能性”。雷德蒙德选择留在学术界，但其他组织者将他们的博士学位应用于劳工职业。在 4 月份举行的 Local 33 庆祝活动中，校友包括迈阿密和西雅图的&lt;em>;Unite Here&lt;/em>;当地人主席、马萨诸塞州的一位劳工教育家和亚利桑那州的一位劳工战略家。耶鲁到工会的管道催生了一种半滑稽的阴谋论：也许“团结在这里”故意延长了研究生组织的时间，以便招募尽可能多的聪明年轻人加入劳工运动.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;By late spring, Acharya was weighing this choice herself. “It&#39;s a scary moment right now,” she told me. Would she return to her lab in the fall or defect for a union job? She ultimately chose an option in between, extending her leave of absence—“Because I&#39;m still having a good time!” she texted me. Other leaders of Local 33 resumed their studies. Abigail Fields, a Ph.D. candidate in French who&#39;d been on leave with Acharya, went back to her dissertation on representations of agriculture and rural life in the nineteenth-century French novel. Fields would spend the coming year in France, but planned to stay involved in the union. Her immersion in organizing had changed her personality. “I like myself much more now than when I was keeping my head down,” she said. “My adviser also noticed a move in my dissertation from ecology to labor.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When campus emptied out for the summer, Acharya stayed busy with collective bargaining—Local 33 was meeting regularly with university representatives—and other &lt;em >;Unite Here&lt;/em>; business. The summer agenda was to tell neighbors about a new law that allowed renters to form tenants&#39; unions, and encourage them to file complaints with the city&#39;s Fair Rent Commission. In June, the members of New Haven&#39;s first two tenants&#39; unions rallied outside the offices of their corporate landlord. One protester held up a sign that said “A 30% Rent Increase Is a Soft Eviction!!!” Another described “a lot of mice, just killing them constantly.” In late August, after sixteen households in one of those buildings were given eviction notices, the statewide Connecticut Tenants Union (whose founders include members of Local 33) filed a lawsuit and called for a mass protest. The Yale unions showed up with hundreds of other people. Two days later, the company cancelled the evictions and agreed to negotiate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Luke Melonakos-Harrison, the vice-president of the Connecticut Tenants Union, graduated earlier this year from Yale&#39;s Divinity School. “I had some anxiety when I got into organizing as a Yale student, trying to get involved in New Haven,” he told me. “There&#39;s definitely tension there, and bad histories.” There were also commonalities. When he and his wife rented their first apartment in New Haven, the bathroom ceiling nearly crashed down on their heads—and the rent wasn&#39;t cheap. “Everyone&#39;s rent is going up and everyone hates their landlord,” Acharya said. While door-knocking three days a week, she found that housing issues got people talking, which she could use to segue into conversations about politics. A primary election was coming up, and the Yale unions had endorsed Elicker for a second term and twenty-two candidates for alder seats. Three of those alder candidates were running for the first time. A handful of others—including the fourth-term president, Walker-Myers—were incumbents dating back to Aldermania. Acharya could point to plenty of achievements: Elicker and the union-backed alders had passed the ordinance legalizing tenants&#39; unions; they had steered pandemic-relief funds toward social services; they had pushed Yale to pay more in taxes. “I didn&#39;t realize how much the union was gonna feel like a political campaign,” Acharya told me. “It &lt;em>;was&lt;/em>; a political campaign.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Daily Cartoon: Friday, October 20th]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/daily-cartoon/monday-october-23rd-devil-good-boy]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T15:44:47.062Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65368deabeefb3f70ae7b54b/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/A28352.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Buy &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; Cartoons »&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;exigx&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;nd4wp&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Reorienting “Madama Butterfly”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/30/reorienting-madama-butterfly]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6531455193870ad043cb8b94/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43253web.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;When Japanese audiences encountered Puccini&#39;s “Madama Butterfly”—a sumptuous Italianate treatment of a geisha&#39;s doomed love for an American naval officer—they found it implausible, insulting, and riotously funny. In 1925, two decades after the opera&#39;s première, the &lt;em>;Japan Times&lt;/em>; reported “screams of hearty laughter” as spectators took in the posturings of a touring foreign troupe. Puccini&#39;s habit of citing popular Japanese songs did not help matters. As Arthur Groos points out in “Madama Butterfly/Madamu Batafurai,” a new book about the opera&#39;s Japanese sources and reception, the composer ignored advice about how to use his material appropriately. When Suzuki, Butterfly&#39;s maid, prays at an alleged Buddhist shrine, she sings to the tune of “Takai Yama,” a song that extols cucumbers and eggplants. Furthermore, she garbles the names of Shinto gods, who don&#39;t belong in a Buddhist setting to begin with. It&#39;s similar, Groos writes, to “having a Catholic pray to Adam and Eve in front of a menorah.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Nevertheless, Japanese audiences and artists have continued to engage with “Butterfly,” not least because it has influenced Western perceptions of Japan for generations. In the fifties, the Fujiwara Opera, based in Tokyo, collaborated with New York City Opera on a bilingual production: Japanese singers took the Japanese roles, and white singers portrayed the callous Lieutenant Pinkerton and the more sympathetic consul Sharpless. The 1953 musical “Chōchō-san Sandaiki” (“Three-Generation Butterfly”) wove Puccini&#39;s characters and music into a tale of Japan under Allied occupation; the fact that the opera is set in Nagasaki added a shuddering layer of significance to that retelling. The scholar Mari Yoshihara, in a 2004 essay about the pioneering Japanese soprano Tamaki Miura, who won international fame as Butterfly, notes that the singer challenged restricted ideas of femininity at home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Today, as the American opera business grapples anew with the political baggage of its repertory, a fresh wave of “Butterfly” productions is arriving, with people of East Asian descent dominating the creative teams. Amon Miyamoto, Aria Umezawa, and Phil Chan have lately directed the work, at San Francisco Opera, New Orleans Opera, and Boston Lyric Opera, respectively. Earlier this month, at Detroit Opera, I saw a staging by Matthew Ozawa in which the story is framed as the increasingly disturbed fantasy of a modern American guy addicted to anime imagery and to VR technology.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Some operagoers will inevitably protest that “Butterfly” should be left alone, as an innocent artifact of its time. Yet a work that delves into late-nineteenth-century sexual colonialism and makes ironic use of “The Star-Spangled Banner” cannot be stripped of its politics. As Groos and other scholars have noted, “Butterfly,” especially in its original version, has an anti-imperialist streak; Pinkerton, who goes through the motions of marrying Butterfly and then discards her, is a devastating caricature of cultural arrogance. After the opera&#39;s unsuccessful première, at La Scala, in 1904, Puccini softened the Pinkerton character, but there remains enough of the initial idea for directors to run with. Butterfly, for her part, may be hemmed in by Orientalist stereotypes, yet she draws power from the opulence of the music that Puccini wrote for her. Grotesque in some ways, greathearted in others, “Butterfly” is the kind of piece that not only invites but requires reflection on the part of performers and spectators alike.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;At the beginning of Ozawa&#39;s “Butterfly” in Detroit, we see a bored young man alone in his apartment, which is decorated with Japanese posters and tchotchkes. He gets a beer out of the fridge—Sapporo or Kirin, no doubt. You have the sense of an emotionally shut-down business bro who studied for a semester in Tokyo. He settles into a chair and picks up his VR gear, at which point his modern world dematerializes. Ceremonially clad characters step out of the fridge; imperial sets slide forward. When Pinkerton is not in a scene, the singer who plays him often hovers to the side, gesturing and twitching in an indolent trance.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The framing is ingenious because it compensates for the opera&#39;s misbegotten notions of Japan. When Shinto names are mangled, or when Chinese folk songs come out of nowhere, we can blame the protagonist&#39;s muddled reverie. Even Puccini&#39;s most questionable choice in his revision of the score—giving Pinkerton an aria of bathetic remorse—can be justified as a spasm of performative self-pity on the part of the player&#39;s avatar. I remain convinced that the original “Butterfly,” in which the cowardly Pinkerton slinks away while “The Star-Spangled Banner” snarls dissonantly in his wake, is superior; New York City Opera&#39;s staging of it in 1993 transformed my perspective on the work. But I also recognize the practical need to give the lead tenor something a bit more gratifying to sing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Puccini, a sovereign artist terrified of commercial failure, tinkered with “Butterfly” for several years, steadily backtracking on his provocative initial conception. Ozawa drops some of the later changes, essentially adhering to a version that was presented in Brescia, several months after the première. The most crucial difference comes in the Act II aria “Che tua madre,” in which Butterfly, processing the news that Pinkerton has abandoned her, imagines her future and that of Dolore, her child. In the Brescia version, as in the original, she spins out a triumphant scenario in which Dolore is discovered by the Emperor and raised to a high station. Puccini later inserted a different, more lachrymose text, one that forecasts her suicide. The original Butterfly is a prouder, steelier character, a shade closer to the imperious Tosca.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;So she was in Detroit, in a formidable embodiment by Karah Son. Like many sopranos of East Asian background, Son has sung Butterfly over and over—in her case, more than three hundred times. She has not lapsed into routine. Her rendition of “Un bel dì” was a full-blown psychodrama, more a feverish hallucination of Pinkerton&#39;s return than a hopeful vision of it. Eric Taylor, as Pinkerton, brought to bear full-voiced lyric ardor while also communicating the character&#39;s rising unease over his entangled desires. Nmon Ford, as Sharpless, and Kristen Choi, as Suzuki, deftly navigated the show&#39;s imaginary landscape. Kensho Watanabe, in the pit, led a confidently paced, vibrantly colored performance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What I like most in this “Butterfly,” which has also played at Cincinnati Opera and will travel next to Utah Opera and Pittsburgh Opera, is its conjuring of stage pictures that are at once beautiful to look at and troubling to think about. Ozawa&#39;s collaborators—the design collective known as dots, the costume designer Maiko Matsushima, and the lighting designer Yuki Nakase Link—festoon the scene with glowing lanterns, cherry blossoms, and the like, but the images have a tacky, CGI-like glow. Sometimes figures freeze and lights flicker, signalling a breakdown in the smooth function of the fantasy. It wasn&#39;t clear to what extent the audience grasped the deconstructive agenda; I heard confused mutterings at intermission. The message of the closing tableau, though, should have been unmistakable. After Butterfly stabs herself, Pinkerton rushes onstage and clutches her, only to be left holding her bloody garment as she strides away. At the final, shocking triple-forte chord, she fixes the audience with an icy stare.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There are days, many days, when I miss the old City Opera. It rejuvenated audience favorites, like “Butterfly,” which remained piles of bric-a-brac at the Met. It took chances on American singers instead of flying in jet-lagged European stars. And it featured new works that the bigger company discovered only decades later. The Met opened its current season with Jake Heggie&#39;s “Dead Man Walking”; City Opera presented the work in 2002, with the young Joyce DiDonato leading the cast. Coming in November is Anthony Davis&#39;s “X: The Life and Times of Malcolm X,” which had its world première at City Opera in 1986. If the Met is looking for more inspiration in past City Opera seasons, it might consider Bernd Alois Zimmermann&#39;s “Die Soldaten” (1991), Erich Wolfgang Korngold&#39;s “Die Tote Stadt” (1975), and Alberto Ginastera&#39;s “Don Rodrigo” (1966). Or it could come up with new ideas.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“X,” which Detroit Opera revived last year, is a major work whose impact has deepened with time. “Dead Man Walking,” based on Sister Helen Prejean&#39;s account of her friendship with a death-row inmate, made a feebler impression on its return to New York. It&#39;s an uncommonly popular piece, having been staged by more than seventy companies around the world. But the score is derivative and discursive, reacting to the story instead of driving it. At the Met, the opera felt like a movie of the week blown up to CinemaScope dimensions. Frantically loud orchestral playing, under the overeager baton of Yannick Nézet-Séguin, only amplified the music&#39;s limitations. DiDonato, again playing Sister Helen, and Ryan McKinny, as the inmate, were vocally secure and theatrically incisive; the production, by Ivo van Hove, undercut them with video trickery and a relentlessly chilly mise en scène. The execution scene had a clinical vividness, yet the barbaric politics of the death penalty remained an abstraction. Curiously, “Butterfly” in Detroit seemed more of the moment: it suggested how the virtual realm can infect and degrade the real one, turning us into prisoners of other people&#39;s fantasies. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;8k5n75&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;d328wk&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Slide Show: New Yorker Cartoons October 30, 2023]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/issue-cartoons/cartoons-from-the-october-30-2023-issue]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532f8f9ea2ca67cf0b30aac/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/231030_a27167.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;hr />;&lt;span style=&quot;touch-action:none&quot;>;&lt;ul style=&quot;transform:translate(0px, 0)&quot; >;&lt;li >;&lt;div data-event-boundary=&quot;click&quot; data-in-view=&quot;{&amp;quot;pattern&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;variation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide.ItemCenterNoCaption&amp;quot;}&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;pattern&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;variation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide.ItemCenterNoCaption&amp;quot;}&quot; orientation=&quot;landscape&quot; data-testid=&quot;GallerySlideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div orientation=&quot;landscape&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;responsive-cartoon&quot;>;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a27167&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a27167&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“I dont mind wandering the hallways for all eternity but all this candy is making me sick.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6532f8f9ea2ca67cf0b30aac/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_a27167.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6532f8f9ea2ca67cf0b30aac/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_a27167.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6532f8f9ea2ca67cf0b30aac/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_a27167.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6532f8f9ea2ca67cf0b30aac/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_a27167.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6532f8f9ea2ca67cf0b30aac/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_a27167.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6532f8f9ea2ca67cf0b30aac/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_a27167.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6532f8f9ea2ca67cf0b30aac/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_a27167.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6532f8f9ea2ca67cf0b30aac/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_a27167.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“I don&#39;t mind wandering the hallways for all eternity, but all this candy is making me sick.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;ul data-testid=&quot;socialIconslist&quot; >;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/dialog/feed?&amp;amp;display=popup&amp;amp;caption=&amp;amp;app_id=1147169538698836&amp;amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa27167%3Futm_source%3Dfacebook%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dialog/feed?&amp;amp;display=popup&amp;amp;caption=&amp;amp;app_id=1147169538698836&amp;amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa27167%3Futm_source%3Dfacebook%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;7.2&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 7.2 16&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Facebook&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M1.548 3.099v2.203H0v2.693h1.548V16h3.179V7.995H6.86s.2-1.291.297-2.703H4.739V3.45c0-.275.346-.646.689-.646H7.16V0H4.805C1.47 0 1.548 2.696 1.548 3.099z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Share on X&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa27167%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&amp;amp;text=&amp;amp;via=NewYorker&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa27167%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&amp;amp;text=&amp;amp;via=NewYorker&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 1200 1227&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; style=&quot;width:45%;height:45%&quot;>;&lt;title>;X&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M714.163 519.284L1160.89 0H1055.03L667.137 450.887L357.328 0H0L468.492 681.821L0 1226.37H105.866L515.491 750.218L842.672 1226.37H1200L714.137 519.284H714.163ZM569.165 687.828L521.697 619.934L144.011 79.6944H306.615L611.412 515.685L658.88 583.579L1055.08 1150.3H892.476L569.165 687.854V687.828Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Share via Email&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:?subject=&amp;amp;body=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa27167%3Futm_source%3Donsite-share%26utm_medium%3Demail%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;mailto:?subject=&amp;amp;body=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa27167%3Futm_source%3Donsite-share%26utm_medium%3Demail%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;17.3&quot; height=&quot;13&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 17.3 13&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Email&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M0 .776V13h17.333V.776L8.67 8.931 0 .776z M.756 0L8.67 7.443 16.578 0H.756z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Get in store&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://condenaststore.com/conde-nast-brand/cartoons&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://condenaststore.com/conde-nast-brand/cartoons&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;18&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 18&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shopping&lt;/title>;&lt;g fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;>;&lt;path fill=&quot;#D4D4D4&quot; d=&quot;M20 16a2 2 0 1 1-3.999.001A2 2 0 0 1 20 16&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path stroke=&quot;#D4D4D4&quot; stroke-width=&quot;2&quot; d=&quot;M0 1h4.36L8 12l12.952-3.364L22 4.273H5.238&quot; style=&quot;fill:none !important&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path fill=&quot;#D4D4D4&quot; d=&quot;M12 16a2 2 0 1 1-3.999.001A2 2 0 0 1 12 16M21 8l-4.714 2L8 12 6 4h16z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;/ul>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by PC Vey&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;div data-event-boundary=&quot;click&quot; data-in-view=&quot;{&amp;quot;pattern&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;variation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide.ItemCenterNoCaption&amp;quot;}&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;pattern&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;variation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide.ItemCenterNoCaption&amp;quot;}&quot; orientation=&quot;landscape&quot; data-testid=&quot;GallerySlideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div orientation=&quot;landscape&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;responsive-cartoon&quot;>;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a28107&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a28107&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“Is this height better”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_a28107.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Is this height better?”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;ul data-testid=&quot;socialIconslist&quot; >;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/dialog/feed?&amp;amp;display=popup&amp;amp;caption=&amp;amp;app_id=1147169538698836&amp;amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28107%3Futm_source%3Dfacebook%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dialog/feed?&amp;amp;display=popup&amp;amp;caption=&amp;amp;app_id=1147169538698836&amp;amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28107%3Futm_source%3Dfacebook%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;7.2&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 7.2 16&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Facebook&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M1.548 3.099v2.203H0v2.693h1.548V16h3.179V7.995H6.86s.2-1.291.297-2.703H4.739V3.45c0-.275.346-.646.689-.646H7.16V0H4.805C1.47 0 1.548 2.696 1.548 3.099z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Share on X&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28107%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&amp;amp;text=&amp;amp;via=NewYorker&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28107%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&amp;amp;text=&amp;amp;via=NewYorker&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 1200 1227&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; style=&quot;width:45%;height:45%&quot;>;&lt;title>;X&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M714.163 519.284L1160.89 0H1055.03L667.137 450.887L357.328 0H0L468.492 681.821L0 1226.37H105.866L515.491 750.218L842.672 1226.37H1200L714.137 519.284H714.163ZM569.165 687.828L521.697 619.934L144.011 79.6944H306.615L611.412 515.685L658.88 583.579L1055.08 1150.3H892.476L569.165 687.854V687.828Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Share via Email&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:?subject=&amp;amp;body=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28107%3Futm_source%3Donsite-share%26utm_medium%3Demail%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;mailto:?subject=&amp;amp;body=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28107%3Futm_source%3Donsite-share%26utm_medium%3Demail%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;17.3&quot; height=&quot;13&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 17.3 13&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Email&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M0 .776V13h17.333V.776L8.67 8.931 0 .776z M.756 0L8.67 7.443 16.578 0H.756z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Get in store&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://condenaststore.com/conde-nast-brand/cartoons&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://condenaststore.com/conde-nast-brand/cartoons&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;18&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 18&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shopping&lt;/title>;&lt;g fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;>;&lt;path fill=&quot;#D4D4D4&quot; d=&quot;M20 16a2 2 0 1 1-3.999.001A2 2 0 0 1 20 16&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path stroke=&quot;#D4D4D4&quot; stroke-width=&quot;2&quot; d=&quot;M0 1h4.36L8 12l12.952-3.364L22 4.273H5.238&quot; style=&quot;fill:none !important&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path fill=&quot;#D4D4D4&quot; d=&quot;M12 16a2 2 0 1 1-3.999.001A2 2 0 0 1 12 16M21 8l-4.714 2L8 12 6 4h16z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;/ul>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Lynn Hsu&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;div data-event-boundary=&quot;click&quot; data-in-view=&quot;{&amp;quot;pattern&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;variation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide.ItemCenterNoCaption&amp;quot;}&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;pattern&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;variation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;GallerySlide.ItemCenterNoCaption&amp;quot;}&quot; orientation=&quot;portrait&quot; data-testid=&quot;GallerySlideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div orientation=&quot;portrait&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;responsive-cartoon&quot;>;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a28241&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a28241&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“Quit hogging the covers”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_a28241.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Quit hogging the covers!”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;ul data-testid=&quot;socialIconslist&quot; >;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Share on Facebook&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.facebook.com/dialog/feed?&amp;amp;display=popup&amp;amp;caption=&amp;amp;app_id=1147169538698836&amp;amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28241%3Futm_source%3Dfacebook%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dialog/feed?&amp;amp;display=popup&amp;amp;caption=&amp;amp;app_id=1147169538698836&amp;amp;link=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28241%3Futm_source%3Dfacebook%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;7.2&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 7.2 16&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Facebook&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M1.548 3.099v2.203H0v2.693h1.548V16h3.179V7.995H6.86s.2-1.291.297-2.703H4.739V3.45c0-.275.346-.646.689-.646H7.16V0H4.805C1.47 0 1.548 2.696 1.548 3.099z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Share on X&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28241%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&amp;amp;text=&amp;amp;via=NewYorker&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28241%3Futm_source%3Dtwitter%26utm_medium%3Dsocial%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker%26utm_social-type%3Dearned&amp;amp;text=&amp;amp;via=NewYorker&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 1200 1227&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; style=&quot;width:45%;height:45%&quot;>;&lt;title>;X&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M714.163 519.284L1160.89 0H1055.03L667.137 450.887L357.328 0H0L468.492 681.821L0 1226.37H105.866L515.491 750.218L842.672 1226.37H1200L714.137 519.284H714.163ZM569.165 687.828L521.697 619.934L144.011 79.6944H306.615L611.412 515.685L658.88 583.579L1055.08 1150.3H892.476L569.165 687.854V687.828Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Share via Email&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;mailto:?subject=&amp;amp;body=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28241%3Futm_source%3Donsite-share%26utm_medium%3Demail%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;mailto:?subject=&amp;amp;body=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fcartoon%2Fa28241%3Futm_source%3Donsite-share%26utm_medium%3Demail%26utm_campaign%3Donsite-share%26utm_brand%3Dthe-new-yorker&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;17.3&quot; height=&quot;13&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 17.3 13&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Email&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M0 .776V13h17.333V.776L8.67 8.931 0 .776z M.756 0L8.67 7.443 16.578 0H.756z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;Get in store&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://condenaststore.com/conde-nast-brand/cartoons&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://condenaststore.com/conde-nast-brand/cartoons&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;18&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 18&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shopping&lt;/title>;&lt;g fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;>;&lt;path fill=&quot;#D4D4D4&quot; d=&quot;M20 16a2 2 0 1 1-3.999.001A2 2 0 0 1 20 16&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path stroke=&quot;#D4D4D4&quot; stroke-width=&quot;2&quot; d=&quot;M0 1h4.36L8 12l12.952-3.364L22 4.273H5.238&quot; style=&quot;fill:none !important&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path fill=&quot;#D4D4D4&quot; d=&quot;M12 16a2 2 0 1 1-3.999.001A2 2 0 0 1 12 16M21 8l-4.714 2L8 12 6 4h16z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;/ul>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Ollie Wootton&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/li>;&lt;/ul>;&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;span >;1 &lt;/span>;&lt;span >;/ 9&lt;/span>;&lt;/span>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; >;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;gallery-back&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 32 32&quot; width=&quot;32&quot; height=&quot;32&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Chevron&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M19.071 16L12 8.929l1.414-1.414L21.9 16l-8.485 8.485L12 23.071z&quot; fill-rule=&quot;nonzero&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;gallery-forward&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg focusable=&quot;false&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 32 32&quot; width=&quot;32&quot; height=&quot;32&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Chevron&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M19.071 16L12 8.929l1.414-1.414L21.9 16l-8.485 8.485L12 23.071z&quot; fill-rule=&quot;nonzero&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;figcaption >;&lt;/figcaption>;&lt;hr />;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;qmbjzm&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;rbekxd&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What Gardening Offered After a Son’s Death, by Yiyun Li]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/30/onward-and-upward-in-the-department-of-not-moping]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6531561d35f07f19b4c86ba1/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43240.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;“It&#39;s rather vexing, isn&#39;t it, not to know what flowers will come up next year?” I said to my friend Brigid, in a voice that sounded more like a character&#39;s in a novel than my own. It was November, 2017, and my family had just moved into our house in Princeton. The trees were shedding their leaves, in a theatrical manner that was new to us—we had relocated from California to the East Coast four months earlier.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“There are some roses,” Brigid said. “Those look like lilies.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“And those are hostas.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There were six or seven rose bushes, with residual flowers, fuchsia-colored, shivering on top of the near-leafless branches. Lilies and hostas, their leaves already paled and half rotted by the cold autumn rain, remained recognizable. The rest of the garden was a wilted mystery, buried under fallen leaves.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I was not a character, but I was speaking like one for a reason: I was pondering a set of characters. I went on and told Brigid about a moment in “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Saga-Century-Trilogy-Fountain-Overflows-ebook/dp/B0090WRZYS/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1D21Z2MNESIPN&amp;amp;keywords=The%20Saga%20of%20the%20Century%20rebecca%20west&amp;amp;qid=1697748370&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=the%20saga%20of%20the%20century%20rebecca%20wes,stripbooks,96&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Saga-Century-Trilogy-Fountain-Overflows-ebook/dp/B0090WRZYS/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1D21Z2MNESIPN&amp;amp;keywords=The%20Saga%20of%20the%20Century%20rebecca%20west&amp;amp;qid=1697748370&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=the%20saga%20of%20the%20century%20rebecca%20wes,stripbooks,96&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Saga-Century-Trilogy-Fountain-Overflows-ebook/dp/B0090WRZYS/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1D21Z2MNESIPN&amp;amp;keywords=The%20Saga%20of%20the%20Century%20rebecca%20west&amp;amp;qid=1697748370&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=the%20saga%20of%20the%20century%20rebecca%20wes,stripbooks,96&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The Saga of the Century Trilogy&lt;/a>;,” by Rebecca West, about a British family living in London in the first half of the twentieth century. The eldest daughter in the family, Cordelia, newly wed, has moved into a pretty house in Kensington; when she has her two younger sisters over for a visit, she frets, with the leisure of a young woman married into respectability and stability, about not knowing whether the hawthorn tree in her garden will bear white, pink, or red flowers in the spring.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A few chapters later, the hawthorn tree blooms. By then, the little brother of the family, Richard Quin, still a teen-ager, has been killed in the Great War, ten days after arriving in France. “Killed, not missing?” Cordelia cries out in agony when she&#39;s told the news. The hawthorn tree outside reveals the answer to the riddle from the winter before: the flowers are red.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;It is a quick stroke in a trilogy. The first time I read it, I did not fully register the weight of the detail. But, moving into a house in the fall, studying a garden that would remain unknowable for the moment, I went back and reread the few paragraphs about the tree.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Richard Quin, in West&#39;s trilogy, is killed in the same manner that one imagines Andrew Ramsay is killed in “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lighthouse-Virginia-Woolf/dp/0156907399/ref=sr_1_4?crid=MDH1WY2VP4MR&amp;amp;keywords=to%20the%20lighthouse&amp;amp;qid=1697748496&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=to%20the%20lighthouse,stripbooks,129&amp;amp;sr=1-4&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lighthouse-Virginia-Woolf/dp/0156907399/ref=sr_1_4?crid=MDH1WY2VP4MR&amp;amp;keywords=to%20the%20lighthouse&amp;amp;qid=1697748496&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=to%20the%20lighthouse,stripbooks,129&amp;amp;sr=1-4&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lighthouse-Virginia-Woolf/dp/0156907399/ref=sr_1_4?crid=MDH1WY2VP4MR&amp;amp;keywords=to%20the%20lighthouse&amp;amp;qid=1697748496&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=to%20the%20lighthouse,stripbooks,129&amp;amp;sr=1-4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;To the Lighthouse&lt;/a>;”: “[A shell exploded. Twenty or thirty young men were blown up in France, among them Andrew Ramsay, whose death, mercifully, was instantaneous.]”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;For all we know, Richard Quin might have died next to Andrew Ramsay, in a pair of Virginia Woolf brackets.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Some days, that pair of brackets of Woolf&#39;s continue to baffle me. Other days, they feel just right. The predicament when writing about a sudden, untimely death: the more you remember, the more elusive that death becomes. A sudden, untimely death is a black hole, absorbing all that you can give, not really clamoring for more. Though is a black hole ever to be fully filled so that it can cease to be one? Has anyone been able to define, capture, or even get close to a black hole?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;[In September, 2017, our older son, Vincent, died by suicide, at sixteen.]&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;[On that day, we put down the deposit for the house. Deposit, death, in that order, four hours apart.]&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In a novel, I would never have put the two happenings on the same day. In writing fiction, one avoids coincidences like that, which offer unearned drama, shoddy poignancy, convenient metaphor, predictable spectacle. Life, however, does not follow a novelist&#39;s discipline. Fiction, one suspects, is often tamer than life.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Some fiction is tamer than some life, I should amend. And I confess that this is only a variation of a statement made by another character in “The Saga of the Century Trilogy,” who, upon discovering her husband&#39;s extramarital affair, reads “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Madame-Bovary-Penguin-Classics-Deluxe/dp/014310649X/ref=sr_1_4?crid=1GS2TAQUI4J9F&amp;amp;keywords=madame%20bovary&amp;amp;qid=1697748590&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=madame%20bovar,stripbooks,82&amp;amp;sr=1-4&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Madame-Bovary-Penguin-Classics-Deluxe/dp/014310649X/ref=sr_1_4?crid=1GS2TAQUI4J9F&amp;amp;keywords=madame%20bovary&amp;amp;qid=1697748590&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=madame%20bovar,stripbooks,82&amp;amp;sr=1-4&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Madame-Bovary-Penguin-Classics-Deluxe/dp/014310649X/ref=sr_1_4?crid=1GS2TAQUI4J9F&amp;amp;keywords=madame%20bovary&amp;amp;qid=1697748590&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=madame%20bovar,stripbooks,82&amp;amp;sr=1-4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Madame Bovary&lt;/a>;” and exclaims, “But art is so much more real than life. Some art is much more real than some life, I mean.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A couple of months after Vincent died, a colleague asked me where I was “in the process of grieving,” assuming, I supposed, that there would be, and should be, a conclusion of mourning at some point. That phrase struck me as inaccurate; she might as well have asked me where I was “in the process of living.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There is, alas, not a normal course of life, against which deviations can be measured and, hopefully, corrected. Only changed courses, altered lives. One can look longingly at the alternatives: Vincent graduating from high school (as our younger son did this summer) or graduating from college (as Vincent&#39;s old school friends will next year), but alternatives belong to the realm of fiction. To paraphrase Elizabeth Bowen, the great Anglo-Irish writer, good fiction is good because it offers “the palpable presence of the alternatives.” In life, that presence can be palpably felt, but too much preoccupation with the alternatives may lead to a dilemma of either/or; even, neither here nor there. “Dilemma,” from its Greek etymology, means two lemmas: double assumptions, double propositions. But death is definitive; death does not lead to a dilemma.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I think about the alternative lives of my characters all the time. But, as I did not live in fiction, I decided, soon after Vincent&#39;s death, to stop pondering the alternatives. &lt;em>;What if&lt;/em>; belongs to fiction; &lt;em>;what now&lt;/em>;, to this real life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What now, in the last months of 2017: I could not read fiction. It was not a problem of mental focus. I spent hours every day reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/william-shakespeare&quot;>;Shakespeare&lt;/a>;&#39;s plays and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/05/02/the-thrilling-mind-of-wallace-stevens&quot;>;Wallace Stevens&lt;/a>;&#39;s poems—all of a sudden, those words were the only ones that made sense to me. But if I stopped reading fiction would I ever be able to write fiction again? I was in the middle of a long novel. Forging ahead or scrapping the project felt equally impossible. Anguished, I looked up “anguish” in the OED, to make sure that I was using the right word to describe my situation, and, indeed, it was an apt word choice. Etymologically, “anguish” comes to us from the Latin &lt;em>;angustia&lt;/em>;—narrowness, lack of space, narrow space, narrow passage, strait, limitations, restrictions, confinement, imprisonment, restrictedness, shortage, scantiness, critical situation, narrow-mindedness, pettiness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A black hole takes all and gives back naught. The anguish from a sudden, untimely death has a narrowing effect: alternatives are lost; space in the mind, too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;On her next visit, Brigid brought me two books. The first was “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Onward-Upward-Garden-Review-Classics/dp/1590178505/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2HSD3E1J99O1A&amp;amp;keywords=Onward%20and%20Upward%20in%20the%20Garden&amp;amp;qid=1697748739&amp;amp;sprefix=onward%20and%20upward%20in%20the%20garden,aps,188&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Onward-Upward-Garden-Review-Classics/dp/1590178505/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2HSD3E1J99O1A&amp;amp;keywords=Onward%20and%20Upward%20in%20the%20Garden&amp;amp;qid=1697748739&amp;amp;sprefix=onward%20and%20upward%20in%20the%20garden,aps,188&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Onward-Upward-Garden-Review-Classics/dp/1590178505/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2HSD3E1J99O1A&amp;amp;keywords=Onward%20and%20Upward%20in%20the%20Garden&amp;amp;qid=1697748739&amp;amp;sprefix=onward%20and%20upward%20in%20the%20garden,aps,188&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Onward and Upward in the Garden&lt;/a>;,” a collection of fourteen essays by the former &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; fiction editor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1996/02/26/lady-with-a-pencil&quot;>;Katharine S. White&lt;/a>;. The essays were originally published, in a span of twelve years, in the magazine, ostensibly as reviews of nursery catalogues. The other book was “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Two-Gardeners-Katharine-Lawrence-Friendship/dp/0807085588/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2YION9QR196CG&amp;amp;keywords=Two%20Gardeners:%20A%20Friendship%20in%20Letters&amp;amp;qid=1697748815&amp;amp;sprefix=two%20gardeners%20a%20friendship%20in%20letters,aps,84&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Two-Gardeners-Katharine-Lawrence-Friendship/dp/0807085588/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2YION9QR196CG&amp;amp;keywords=Two%20Gardeners:%20A%20Friendship%20in%20Letters&amp;amp;qid=1697748815&amp;amp;sprefix=two%20gardeners%20a%20friendship%20in%20letters,aps,84&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Two-Gardeners-Katharine-Lawrence-Friendship/dp/0807085588/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2YION9QR196CG&amp;amp;keywords=Two%20Gardeners:%20A%20Friendship%20in%20Letters&amp;amp;qid=1697748815&amp;amp;sprefix=two%20gardeners%20a%20friendship%20in%20letters,aps,84&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Two Gardeners: A Friendship in Letters&lt;/a>;,” a collection of correspondence between White and Elizabeth Lawrence. Lawrence was a gardener and a gardening writer in North Carolina, and the friendship began when Lawrence wrote a fan letter to White after reading her first essay, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1958/03/01/book-review-onward-upward-in-the-garden-t&quot;>;A Romp in the Catalogues&lt;/a>;,” in the March 1, 1958, issue of &lt;em>;The New Yorker&lt;/em>;. For a year, they were “Mrs. White” and “Miss Lawrence” to each other, and then they became “Katharine” and “Elizabeth.” They would write to each other for the next nineteen years, until White&#39;s death, in 1977.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Through the winter, I read the two books, very slowly. There was no reason to hurry, as that first winter was a long one; cold, snowy—cold and snowy for recent transplants from California, in any case. Day after day, I looked at the bare limbs of the trees, brownish gray, and the stale snow covering the garden, grayish white. I thought one afternoon, What if spring never returns? Right away I recognized the illogic and the melodrama of that thought. I had at my hand the words of two gardeners of yesteryear, books that had taken years to be written. Were these words not enough evidence that spring always comes, if not now, later?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;[That winter, I often returned to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/marianne-moore&quot;>;Marianne Moore&lt;/a>;&#39;s words: “If nothing charms or sustains us (and we are getting food and fresh air) it is for us to say, &#39;If not now, later,&#39; and not mope.” Incidentally, it was Moore who may have first suggested that White should collect her reviews of garden catalogues into a book.]&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Not to mope, I thought, was a proper goal: it would take all my energy and all my vigilance, and it was attainable. White&#39;s essays and the letters between White and Lawrence were just right for that aspiration. The two women (and likely some of the gardens and many of the plants that they had written about) were no more, and yet their words remained and sustained, offering facts and opinions, gardening tales and personal woes, seasons and years, illnesses and deaths—all there, ready to distract me.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;For instance, there were the names of plants to learn. In both books, I encountered many names, some familiar, others unfamiliar, and every one of them—even the most common, like “peony” or “lotus” or “fuchsia”—required investigation. Unlike Lawrence, I&#39;m not a purist when it comes to botany, and I don&#39;t always look up the Latin names for the plants. But I do like to know the etymology of their English names. And what one can learn just by going to the dictionary! “Peony” goes all the way back to ancient Greek: Paieon, or Paeon, was the physician of the gods. (What afflicts the gods? Possibly what afflicts us mortals.) “Lotus” comes from the Greek &lt;em>;lōtos&lt;/em>;, a mythical plant bringing forgetfulness to those who eat its fruits. (I have eaten my share of lotus seeds, a delicacy in Chinese cuisine, without achieving oblivion.) “Fuchsia,” a word I often misspelled as “fuschia”—what mythical story accompanies thee? It turns out that fuchsia was named for the sixteenth-century German physician and botanist Leonhard Fuchs, whose name gave birth not only to that of the flower and that of the color but also to the nickname, Fuchsienstadt, for his home town of Wemding, where there is a pyramid made of as many as seven hundred fuchsia plants. And yet Fuchs never saw the flower fuchsia in his lifetime: it was discovered in the Caribbean and named by the French botanist and monk Charles Plumier, who was born a hundred and forty-five years after Fuchs. What led Plumier to name the flower for Fuchs? One can ask the question, but any speculation would be closer to fiction, just as peony was once the physician of the gods and lotus would bring forgetfulness.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;o0tki7&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Nearer our time—nearer than Fuchs and Plumier—were the horticulturists, seedsmen, growers, some older than White, others her contemporaries, behind those nursery catalogues which were once scrutinized by her. “They are as individualistic . 。 。 as any Faulkner or Hemingway, and they can be just as frustrating or rewarding,” White wrote. And what a great joy to get to know the Faulkners and Hemingways of the nursery world through her words. Signing off for the catalogue of White Flower Farm was one Amos Pettingill. “I have no idea whether Amos Pettingill is a real person—the name sounds like an ill-advised fabrication,” White observed. Real or not, the name alone, I thought, was enough to send one&#39;s imagination on a detour to Dickens-land. In the catalogue of White Flower Farm, Mr. Pettingill claimed that its French Pussy Willow was “not the unreliable wild Pussy Willow,” which led White to protest, “What is unreliable, pray, about the native wild pussies? I have found them trustworthy in every respect.” David Burpee, the president of the W. Atlee Burpee &amp;amp; Company, campaigned to have the marigold recognized as the national flower of the United States. White, describing “David Burpee&#39;s one-man lobby,” noted, “I was also pleased as well as entertained, a couple of years back, when Mr. Burpee in person went to Washington, bearing marigold boutonnières for the legislators, and, at a Congressional hearing on naming a national flower, faced down the Senatorial proponents of grass, the corn tassel, the rose, and the carnation.” (Mr. Burpee did not succeed; the rose prevailed to become the national flower.)&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;To catch a glimpse, in White&#39;s essays, of these men and women who once lived in their gardens, cultivating, hybridizing, dreaming of colors and shapes and scents that would catch their fancy, and then turning their obsessions into words, hoping that their catalogues would catch the fancy of many gardeners&#39; hearts: there is nothing narrowing in the world of roses, dahlias, marigolds, tulips, daylilies, and chrysanthemums. They were not black holes but rabbit holes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And, of course, there were White and Lawrence, knowledgeable, opinionated, delighting in miscellanies. In her first letter, Lawrence recommended that White write about Cecil Houdyshel&#39;s catalogues (which always opened with “Dear Floral Friends”): “I think he is in his nineties now, so you had better hurry.” In reply, White confessed, “I am always nervous when I write about old people.” Both women saw a garden writer in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/lewis-carroll&quot;>;Lewis Carroll&lt;/a>;. In her first &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; review of nursery catalogues, referring to the card gardeners painting roses in “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Alice-Wonderland-Original-Complete-Illustrations/dp/B0948LPG76/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3RZ8PHCVV4363&amp;amp;keywords=alice%20adventures%20in%20wonderland%20book&amp;amp;qid=1697749109&amp;amp;rnid=2941120011&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=alice%20ad,aps,91&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Alice-Wonderland-Original-Complete-Illustrations/dp/B0948LPG76/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3RZ8PHCVV4363&amp;amp;keywords=alice%20adventures%20in%20wonderland%20book&amp;amp;qid=1697749109&amp;amp;rnid=2941120011&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=alice%20ad,aps,91&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Alice-Wonderland-Original-Complete-Illustrations/dp/B0948LPG76/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3RZ8PHCVV4363&amp;amp;keywords=alice%20adventures%20in%20wonderland%20book&amp;amp;qid=1697749109&amp;amp;rnid=2941120011&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=alice%20ad,aps,91&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Alice&#39;s Adventures in Wonderland&lt;/a>;,” White wrote, “Lewis Carroll was prophetic; today the garden men are quite as busy changing the colors of flowers as they are changing their size and shape.” A year later, Lawrence wrote in a letter, “If I have to hear flowers talk, I would rather read &lt;em>;Through the Looking-Glass&lt;/em>;, which &lt;em>;is&lt;/em>; my favorite garden book.”&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a28107&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a28107&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“Is this height better”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_a28107.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65315622cc1213fa97a82233/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_a28107.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Is this height better?”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Lynn Hsu&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Copy link to cartoon&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178637)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M16.3488 10.5017C16.2107 10.7357 16.2926 11.035 16.5318 11.17C16.7709 11.3052 17.0767 11.225 17.2148 10.991L18.4648 8.87225C19.5694 7.00002 18.9139 4.60601 17.0007 3.52508C15.0875 2.44415 12.6412 3.08562 11.5366 4.95785L9.53657 8.34782C8.432 10.22 9.08751 12.6141 11.0007 13.6949C11.1888 13.8012 11.382 13.8908 11.5785 13.9642C11.7819 14.0403 12.0058 13.9485 12.1147 13.764C12.2794 13.4849 12.1103 13.1276 11.8083 12.9992C11.7041 12.9549 11.6014 12.9044 11.5007 12.8475C10.0658 12.0368 9.57417 10.2413 10.4026 8.83712L12.4026 5.44715C13.2311 4.04298 15.0658 3.56187 16.5007 4.37257C17.9356 5.18327 18.4272 6.97878 17.5988 8.38295L16.3488 10.5017ZM7.6526 13.4983C7.79067 13.2643 7.70873 12.965 7.46959 12.8299C7.23044 12.6948 6.92464 12.775 6.78657 13.009L5.53657 15.1278C4.432 17 5.0875 19.394 7.00068 20.475C8.91385 21.5558 11.3602 20.9144 12.4648 19.0422L14.4648 15.6521C15.5694 13.78 14.9139 11.3859 13.0007 10.305C12.8127 10.1988 12.6195 10.1091 12.4229 10.0357C12.2195 9.95975 11.9956 10.0515 11.8867 10.236C11.7221 10.5151 11.8911 10.8724 12.1932 11.0008C12.2973 11.0451 12.4 11.0956 12.5007 11.1525C13.9356 11.9632 14.4272 13.7587 13.5988 15.1628L11.5988 18.5529C10.7704 19.957 8.93555 20.4382 7.50068 19.6274C6.0658 18.8167 5.57417 17.0212 6.4026 15.6171L7.6526 13.4983Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;div role=&quot;dialog&quot;>;&lt;div aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;p aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;Link copied&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Shop&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Shop&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shop&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178638)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 3H2V4H4.23828L6.99617 15.2631C7.11483 15.6982 7.50998 16 7.96094 16H18.0365C18.4875 16 18.8826 15.6982 19.0013 15.2631L20.9648 7.26312C21.1383 6.62698 20.6594 6 20 6H10V7H20L18.0365 15H7.96094L5.03652 3H4.58055H4ZM10.0365 19C10.0365 19.5523 9.58881 20 9.03652 20C8.48424 20 8.03652 19.5523 8.03652 19C8.03652 18.4477 8.48424 18 9.03652 18C9.58881 18 10.0365 18.4477 10.0365 19ZM11.0365 19C11.0365 20.1046 10.1411 21 9.03652 21C7.93195 21 7.03652 20.1046 7.03652 19C7.03652 17.8954 7.93195 17 9.03652 17C10.1411 17 11.0365 17.8954 11.0365 19ZM18.0365 19C18.0365 19.5523 17.5888 20 17.0365 20C16.4842 20 16.0365 19.5523 16.0365 19C16.0365 18.4477 16.4842 18 17.0365 18C17.5888 18 18.0365 18.4477 18.0365 19ZM19.0365 19C19.0365 20.1046 18.1411 21 17.0365 21C15.932 21 15.0365 20.1046 15.0365 19C15.0365 17.8954 15.932 17 17.0365 17C18.1411 17 19.0365 17.8954 19.0365 19Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;[Their conversation led me to reread “Alice&#39;s Adventures in Wonderland” and “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Through-Looking-Glass-Illustrated-Classics/dp/1949460894/ref=sr_1_2?crid=34UWZQRGNKDV1&amp;amp;keywords=through%20the%20looking%20glass%20lewis%20carroll&amp;amp;qid=1697749240&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=through%20the%20look,stripbooks,85&amp;amp;sr=1-2&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Through-Looking-Glass-Illustrated-Classics/dp/1949460894/ref=sr_1_2?crid=34UWZQRGNKDV1&amp;amp;keywords=through%20the%20looking%20glass%20lewis%20carroll&amp;amp;qid=1697749240&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=through%20the%20look,stripbooks,85&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Through-Looking-Glass-Illustrated-Classics/dp/1949460894/ref=sr_1_2?crid=34UWZQRGNKDV1&amp;amp;keywords=through%20the%20looking%20glass%20lewis%20carroll&amp;amp;qid=1697749240&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=through%20the%20look,stripbooks,85&amp;amp;sr=1-2&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Through the Looking-Glass&lt;/a>;,” the first fiction I read after Vincent&#39;s death. The books, of course, have less to do with the missed or lost alternatives; instead, they make perfect nonsense out of the alternatives.]&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;After we moved into the house, I ordered twenty-five hyacinth bulbs (Delft Blue) and buried them haphazardly in the corners where I was certain that they would not interfere with any existing plants. Twenty-five, in retrospect, was a touchingly small number—a gesture rather than a plan, a prelude to a dream rather than a dream realized. But a gardener, like a writer, must start somewhere. (Last fall, I planted eight hundred bulbs; the fall before, seven hundred.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Because of those twenty-five bulbs, garden catalogues began to arrive. One could be realistic: it had taken little time for one&#39;s address to be shared among the nurseries. One could also be romantic: imagine that tentative order of bulbs as a small bugle, announcing a budding gardener. The catalogues, though radically improved graphically from the ones reviewed by White, still bore the same names: White Flower Farm, Wayside Gardens, Park Seed Company, W. Atlee Burpee &amp;amp; Company, and several more. I perused the catalogues as I imagined White and Lawrence had done; although new to this literature, I had yet to cultivate my tastes and form my opinions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It occurred to me one day that no one had made a catalogue of gardeners: professional gardeners, who might be like important cultivars, bearing poetic or eccentric names; amateurs, akin to common carnations and cornflowers; and those, like me, who were gardeners only in their fantasies. Such a catalogue, abundant with human stories, would be amusing to read, no? I then realized that I was, true to my profession, fictioneering again.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When I was growing up, in Beijing, my family lived on the ground floor of an apartment block, so we were lucky to have a tiny lot, about two metres by 1.5 metres. My father, who had come from poor peasant stock, gardened judiciously: a grapevine that produced very sweet grapes (often pillaged by the wasps), our favorite green beans (which bore the name “pig ears”), loofahs (good for soup when the gourds were young and tender; when they were old and fibrous, they made the best kitchen scrubs), a honeysuckle plant (dried honeysuckle flowers can be used as medicinal tea). One year, when I was four or five, he planted some potatoes and described to me the unforgettable flavor of new potatoes. The only other time I have heard such a rapturous description of new potatoes was from an Irish poet in Cork.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;My father did not garden for beauty. Some years, he would plant a cluster of impatiens, which he called “fingernail flowers” because, in the old days, the pink and red petals had been used when painting girls&#39; fingernails. The only constant floral decorations in our garden were the morning glories, self-seeding and wildly vivacious. Once, two women laughed at our garden to my face, dismissing my father as a lazy gardener who grew flowers that were no more than weeds. I was too young and too intimidated to defend him: he was a nuclear physicist, but he also did all the grocery shopping and most of the housework, cooked three meals a day for the family, and gardened in his spare time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;People who cultivated peonies and roses and orchids were not necessarily kind, which was not a surprise. I had learned from Chinese history that cold-blooded dictators—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/mao-zedong&quot;>;Chairman Mao&lt;/a>;, for instance—had also written heartrending poetry, and that capricious dynastic tyrants had often been supreme calligraphers and painters. On the other hand, people who were cruel to garden plants could easily extend that cruelty to human beings. One day, my mother uprooted the honeysuckle for no other reason than that she could—so she would—inflict pain. My father mourned, and I seethed, though we both did so quietly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When the spring of 2018 arrived, I, the daughter of my pragmatic father, started by growing vegetables in containers—I was still waiting for the flowers in the garden to emerge and show themselves to me. In the next two years, I grew Chinese celtuce, baby bok choy, green beans, eggplants, tomatoes, sweet peppers, okra, and a variety of herbs, and ended up having plenty of opportunities to observe at close hand birds and squirrels, snails and slugs, aphids and spider mites, and all the other archenemies of a garden. Various campaigns were carried out: I ordered live ladybugs, hundreds at a time, and released them in the evenings after it rained, hoping that they would not fly away; I hung up birdhouses, waiting for wrens to move in and feed their chicks with my garden&#39;s offering of bugs; fake snakes were strategically placed to ward off rodents, and they did little but frighten me every time I stepped on their rubbery bodies.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;And then there is the problem without any solution: the bigger animals. Deer graze undiscriminatingly (but luckily, in my case, only in the front yard, for the back yard is fenced). The fence, of course, does nothing to deter rabbits. (On a visit I paid to the Irish writer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/william-trevor&quot;>;William Trevor&lt;/a>;, at his house in Devon, he pointed out rolls of metal mesh, to be buried at a certain depth—inches? feet? I forgot how much—into the ground as a rabbit fence. I have yet to be so enterprising.) The rabbits show up in late May or early June, fist-size fluffs, and a month later they can stand on their hind feet and stretch more than a foot tall. They chomp down everything and turn me into a maddened Mrs. McGregor. (I will never believe any catalogue if it dares label a plant rabbit-resistant.) Next comes our resident groundhog. Perhaps there is more than one, but they all look the same to me: giant and comical. The groundhogs are the most effective destroyers of a garden. I named ours for an infamous politician, although a friend, quite sensibly, pointed out that calling the groundhog by the politician&#39;s name was an insult to the animal: the groundhog is doing only what he&#39;s supposed to do, tramping and feasting in what he considers his garden.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One early summer morning, I looked out the window and saw two deer and a rabbit in my front garden, eating up some hydrangea bushes I had planted a few weeks earlier. It occurred to me that, had I been able to go back to my childhood self and tell her that one day I would live in a place where rabbits and deer eat side by side peacefully, the child would be incredulous: certainly no real people could live in a fairy tale like that?&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;i11q09&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;“I am sure that if you had been told when you were a child about all the things that you were going to have to do, you would have thought you had better die at once, you would not have believed you could ever have the strength to do them.” In West&#39;s trilogy, Richard Quin says this to his mother before he leaves to be killed in France. Had I been able to go back to my childhood self and tell her that one day I would live as a mother who has lost a son, the child would be equally incredulous: surely such things happen only in fiction, to characters who are much more interesting and tragic?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;My garden this spring looks a little different from the garden that came back to life in the spring of 2018. For two years in a row, it was razed by an endless army of rabbits, and, by late summer, it looked like a sad head suffering irregular hair loss, with large bald patches and some surviving stalks of flowers. But this, I had learned from White and Lawrence, is only part of a garden&#39;s fate. In a letter from the spring of 1960, Lawrence reported to White about her magnolia, “We had a real frost last night (almost unheard of for mid-April) and &lt;em>;Magnolia Lennei&lt;/em>; is covered with brown rags. I am going to chop it down, for this happens too often.” In her reply, White wrote, “I called home and learned that mice had eaten and destroyed nine of my old-fashioned rose bushes, so I am extra sympathetic about the magnolia.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Anything can happen in a garden, nothing lasts, and yet something can always be made out of the soil, even with the most destructive weather, even when rabbits and groundhogs and Japanese beetles join forces, greedy and ruthless. All things in the garden, just as in life, are provisional and impermanent. One gardens with the same unblinded hope and the same willingness to concede as one lives, always ready to say, If not now, later; if not this year, next year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But these sentiments would have sounded preachy had I said them to Vincent when he was alive. (The truth is, I would not have been able to, since I had not yet learned them myself.) A few weeks before his death, when we were touring the house with real-estate agents, he said to me, “This garden needs improvement. I can&#39;t wait to garden with you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One can linger in that memory, but there is no reason to attach too much meaning to it. A garden is not a shrine. Living is not metaphorizing. I don&#39;t always think about Vincent&#39;s plan to work alongside me when I potter in the garden. A garden is trustworthy only at this moment, in this now: the past is irrevocable, the future unpredictable.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;[Though I did plant a special patch of tulips for Vincent last fall: Tulipa Vincent van Gogh, dark and mysterious, and Tulipa Ballerina, golden and elegant.]&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Five years later, I still consider myself a beginning gardener. I&#39;m avid, but always ready to surrender to disappointments, to setbacks, to failures and deaths. Unlike White and Lawrence, I garden without a design. (From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2005/02/14/andy&quot;>;E. B. White&lt;/a>;&#39;s introduction to the essay collection, one gathers that Katharine&#39;s garden provided the right colors, shapes, and scents throughout the year.) Much of the planting and growing delights me because of the connections I can make.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The blooming of the Vanessa Bell, one of my favorite roses from the David Austin catalogue, reminds me of one of the last public readings that William Trevor gave, in 2008; I had flown from California to England to attend the event, which took place in Charleston, Vanessa Bell and Duncan Grant&#39;s house in East Sussex. Emily Brontë, another of my favorite David Austin roses, blooms with what I call “a wuthering tenderness,” and when the Emily Brontës are blooming I always think of my first reading of “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wuthering-Heights-Penguin-Classics-Bront%C3%AB/dp/0141439556/ref=sr_1_3?crid=1HL1KLVP7V91Q&amp;amp;keywords=wuthering%20heights&amp;amp;qid=1697749633&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=wuthering%20heigh,stripbooks,100&amp;amp;sr=1-3&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wuthering-Heights-Penguin-Classics-Bront%C3%AB/dp/0141439556/ref=sr_1_3?crid=1HL1KLVP7V91Q&amp;amp;keywords=wuthering%20heights&amp;amp;qid=1697749633&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=wuthering%20heigh,stripbooks,100&amp;amp;sr=1-3&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wuthering-Heights-Penguin-Classics-Bront%C3%AB/dp/0141439556/ref=sr_1_3?crid=1HL1KLVP7V91Q&amp;amp;keywords=wuthering%20heights&amp;amp;qid=1697749633&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=wuthering%20heigh,stripbooks,100&amp;amp;sr=1-3&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Wuthering Heights&lt;/a>;,” as a teen-ager in Beijing. Mystified and electrified, I held on to the book as though it offered a refuge for my mind, but I now suspect that I was only pretending to understand the passion and the drama in the story. A few Roald Dahls from David Austin were planted because Dahl was among my children&#39;s favorite authors when they were young. The Lady of Shalott and Tess of the d&#39;Urbervilles for poetry and fiction. The Lady Gardener as a self-mocking gesture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Over the past few years, I&#39;ve added a dozen hydrangea bushes to the garden, because one of my characters, Lilia—who, like me, lost a child at the age of forty-four—has grown hydrangeas all her life with a passion. [It was the novel I was working on when Vincent died. I had already written about the death of Lilia&#39;s child when I encountered the same loss.]&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Daylilies are not really my favorite, but I grow them because in my father&#39;s village in southern China the soil is the meagrest type, and the only crops my father&#39;s family could grow were yams and daylilies; the flowers were harvested for culinary use—a delicacy for other people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Some flowers in my garden have been inherited from the previous owners: astilbes, baptisias, azaleas, and buddleias. When the astilbes bloom, their white flowers make a shimmering mass in the sun, countering the meaning of their name, in Greek, as something that does not shimmer. The baptisias have indigo flowers, and the name comes from the Greek: to dip, to immerse, to dye (which shares the root with “baptism”). Azaleas&#39; name, too, comes from the Greek, meaning “dry,” but there is nothing dry about these flowers. Buddleias, however, were simply named for an English botanist, Adam Buddle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Primroses bloom early, before the roses. Anemones (ancient Greek&#39;s daughters of the wind) wave their strikingly colorful and delicate flowers in the spring breeze. Geraniums (from the Greek: cranes) expand long-leggedly. Campanulas (from the Latin: little bells) produce bell-shaped flowers without making a cacophony. These and other varieties I have added to the garden. Some have stayed and prospered. Others have proved to be a trustworthy food supply for rabbits. Delphiniums, I have learned, can never stay in the garden for more than a few days. Dianthus and phlox are a game of statistics, which is possibly just like fate; if they survive the raids of the rabbits, they have neither themselves nor me to credit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When Vincent was in the eighth grade, I drove him and a friend, a girl, back from a birthday party, and, like all mothers, I eavesdropped on their conversation. They were discussing the girl&#39;s decision not to participate in a poetry contest. She had read the previous winners, she said, and they were composed of words such as “injustice,” “inequality,” “empowerment,” “action.” “What I don&#39;t understand,” the girl said, “is why can&#39;t we write about flowers anymore.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“Of course we can,” Vincent said. “But . 。 .”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;He did not finish the sentence. I wondered if he was asking: Is there still a place for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/emily-dickinson&quot;>;Emily Dickinson&lt;/a>; these days?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Every spring, when the first flush of David Austin roses bloom, there is always a moment when I turn, in my mind, to Vincent. “Here&#39;s something you haven&#39;t seen: these roses.” The line is offered as a fact, not as an argument, for a rose is never an argument. There is no such thing as an angry rose or a moping rose or an empowered rose; only a realistic rose, a matter-of-fact rose, a transient rose.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;A garden is a place full of random, diverting, and irrelevant happenings, and a garden, as good as a rabbit hole, serves also as an antidote to a black hole. These days, I often get up early. Every flower seems to require an individual greeting from me. In the Buddhist tradition, one encounters sayings like “A flower is a world, a grass leaf is a paradise.” But I, not quite a believer in any kind of religion or metaphor, would rather think that each flower in my garden holds some concrete space, a physical one as well as a temporal one. A flower, like a thought, a sentence, a book, is but a placeholder. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Revenge of the Luddites!]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/30/revenge-of-the-luddites]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532ea970b537a206b5acdbc/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43257illuweb-site.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;“I&#39;m absolutely a Luddite,” the author and columnist Brian Merchant said the other day at an outdoor café in Brooklyn. He has long, brown hair and a goatee, and was wearing a plaid shirt over a T-shirt that read “The Luddites Were Right.” On the chair next to him sat an HP printer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Merchant feels that the original Luddites, early-nineteenth-century cloth-makers who raided British factories and destroyed the new machines that were replacing them, have been getting a bad rap lately. Modern people tend to see them as fools who didn&#39;t appreciate the benefits of technology. In Merchant&#39;s view, the Luddites saw the future all too clearly: new machinery meant that the work they had previously done in their own homes would now be done in factories, as mass production, destroying the workers&#39; way of life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“It wasn&#39;t so much resisting any kind of change—it was resisting getting steamrolled, getting crushed and thrown into poverty,” Merchant said. “They were more anti-poverty than they were anti-technology.” He thinks their rebellion, which came after more peaceful attempts to save their jobs failed, was “morally justified.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;He sees parallels in the present, including people throwing rocks at Google&#39;s employee buses, actors striking over streaming pay, writers protesting the use of artificial intelligence, and activists placing construction cones on driverless cars to scramble their computers. “That&#39;s a Luddite tactic right there,” Merchant said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;He was about to host what he called a Luddite Tribunal at Starr Bar, around the corner, to celebrate his new book, “Blood in the Machine,” about the history of the movement. Merchant and other tech critics—the artist Molly Crabapple; the podcast host Edward Ongweso, Jr. (“This Machine Kills”); the labor reporter Alex Press; and Paris Marx, the host of “Tech Won&#39;t Save Us”—planned to hold up pieces of technology, debate whether they caused more harm than good, and then smash the condemned objects to bits. Merchant had brought an eight-pound sledgehammer purchased from a local hardware store. (He shuns Amazon.)&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;At the bar, he explained that the panel would “try” the printer and a Ring camera he&#39;d brought, and accept submissions from the audience. “You have to have something that&#39;s, like, satisfying to smash,” he said. “I think we&#39;re gonna have to have a blast radius.” He supplied the front row with safety goggles.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;One of the bar&#39;s events managers, Quinton Counts, wasn&#39;t fazed by the potential for glass projectiles and flying motherboard shards. “We get it all,” he said. “It&#39;s Bushwick.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Two guys were sitting in the front row with cans of beer. One of them, Christian Cmehil-Warn, an MIT grad student with long hair and a red T-shirt, said that he worried about AI being used to oppress workers and make unjust decisions about loans and housing. His friend, a former professional gamer who has a graduate degree in quantitative finance (and who didn&#39;t want to be identified), said he&#39;d become skeptical of technology after realizing that the industry he works in—mobile gaming—had created the equivalent of online slot machines, primed to drive addiction. “It&#39;s, like, sixty to ninety per cent of the revenues come from one per cent of the people,” he said. “They&#39;re essentially degenerate gamblers being exploited by sophisticated algorithms.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;As the room filled up with other tech skeptics, Cmehil-Warn said that, at MIT, scientists were developing robots and apps without considering how they would be used. “It&#39;s like Frankenstein&#39;s monster,” he said. “The guy just makes it and lets it go.” The former gamer was interested in the psychology of cults and scams and said that he was opposed to cryptocurrency, which he called a “multilevel-marketing scheme for tech bros.” Which technological development were they most worried about? “AI girlfriends,” the former gamer said without hesitating.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;David Gray Widder, fresh from Carnegie Mellon with a Ph.D. in computer science, sat down. He said that, as a student, he&#39;d protested the use of facial-recognition software by the Pittsburgh police. He wore a Garmin, rather than an Apple, watch. He had helped cause a kerfuffle at Carnegie Mellon (named after “two anti-labor philanthropy capitalists,” he said) in 2020, when he took a screwdriver and removed a “smart sensor,” which included a microphone, that had been preinstalled in his campus office. He put the sensor in a plexiglass box on a shelf and notified the department leadership of his concerns. (After a backlash, he reinstalled it.) Caleb Malchik, another computer scientist, took a seat next to him. He&#39;d been radicalized against tech in part by Edward Snowden and said that copyright posed a threat to free speech.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“Look!” the former gamer said, holding up his phone screen. “I just got a recruiting e-mail from Meta. How&#39;s that for irony?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Onstage, Merchant leaned forward on the handle of his hammer. “You know, it&#39;s important to point out that the Luddites were not just in a blind rage, smashing everything,” he said. “They were very tactical and very focussed on what was actually causing exploitation.” After significant effort, the panelists managed to break the Ring camera (“expanding the surveillance state”), and then tore up a hideous clown poster created using generative AI (“made basically from plagiarized work”). Then Merchant brought out the printer (a symbol of the indignities of office life which only works with Hewlett-Packard&#39;s own overpriced ink) and placed it on a chair.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“ &#39;Office Space&#39; that shit!” someone yelled. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;rgjk0i&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;83ep3y&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Real Cost of Plundering the Planet’s Resources]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/30/the-real-cost-of-plundering-the-planets-resources]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6530266723b1c7056b8e042f/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43242.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The town of Spruce Pine, North Carolina, doesn&#39;t have a lot to say for itself. Its Web site, which features a photo of a flowering tree next to a rusty bridge, notes that the town is “conveniently located between Asheville and Boone.” According to the latest census data, it has 2,332 residents and a population density of 498.1 per square mile. A recent story in the local newspaper concerned the closing of the Hardee&#39;s on Highway 19E; this followed an incident, back in May, when a fourteen-year-old boy who&#39;d eaten a biscuit at the restaurant began to hallucinate and had to be taken to the hospital. Without Spruce Pine, though, the global economy might well unravel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Spruce Pine&#39;s planetary importance follows from an accident of geology. Some three hundred and eighty million years ago, during the late Devonian period, the continent of Africa was drifting toward what would eventually become eastern North America. The force of its movement pressed the floor of a Paleozoic sea deep into the earth&#39;s mantle, where, in effect, it melted. Over the course of tens of millions of years, the molten rock cooled to form deposits of exceptionally pure mica and quartz, which were then pushed back up toward the surface. In the twentieth century, Spruce Pine&#39;s mica was mined to make windows for coal-burning stoves and insulation for vacuum tubes. In the computer age, it&#39;s the town&#39;s quartz that&#39;s critical.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Silicon chips are essentially made of quartz, although this is a bit like saying that the “Mona Lisa” is essentially made of linseed oil. Manufacturing microchips is phenomenally complex and supremely exacting. The process generally begins with quartz&#39;s cousin, quartzite, which consists in large measure of silicon dioxide. Under very high heat, and in the presence of carbon, the quartzite gives up most of its oxygen. Then acid and a great deal more heat are applied, until the silicon reaches a purity level of 99.9999999 per cent, or, as it&#39;s known in the business, “nine nines.” At this point, the silicon is ready to be fashioned into a “boule,” or ingot, that weighs upward of two hundred pounds and consists of a single perfectly aligned crystal. It is here that Spruce Pine&#39;s quartz comes into play.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;To form a boule, pure silicon has to be heated in a special crucible to twenty-seven hundred degrees Fahrenheit. The crucible must be tough enough to withstand this temperature, and, at the same time, it must have the right chemical composition, so it won&#39;t introduce contaminants. The only substance that meets both these criteria is high-purity quartz, and one of the only spots where the right sort of quartz can be found is Spruce Pine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Spruce Pine&#39;s quartz is so valuable that, as the Vancouver-based journalist Vince Beiser observes in his book “The World in a Grain,” almost everything about it, outside of its purity, is a closely guarded secret. The company that owns the town&#39;s largest mine—Sibelco, a Belgian conglomerate—doesn&#39;t publish production figures. When contractors arrive to make repairs at the mine, they are reportedly led to the equipment in blindfolds. According to documents filed in a case that the company once brought against a former employee, it tries to divvy up its contracting jobs, so that no individual can learn too much, and for the same reason it purchases its supplies from multiple venders.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;All this stealth, Ed Conway suggests in his new book, “Material World: The Six Raw Materials That Shape Modern Civilization” (Knopf), is justified. “There are few such cases where we are so utterly reliant on a single place,” he writes. He quotes an unnamed industry veteran who notes that someone flying a crop duster over Spruce Pine and releasing “a very particular powder” could “end the world&#39;s production of semiconductors” within six months. No production of semiconductors would mean no production of computers, cell phones, automobiles, microwaves, game consoles, fitness trackers, digital watches, digital cameras, televisions—the list goes on and on.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;“Even in devices that don&#39;t have &#39;smart&#39; in their name, mechanical linkages have long since given way to a network of semiconductors,” Conway, a London-based journalist, observes. “Nearly every economic activity, nearly every dollar of global GDP, relies in one way or another on the microscopic switches of semiconductors.” Prudently, he does not reveal what that very particular powder is.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Of the ten largest corporations in the world, six are tech companies. In 2021, fifty per cent of Americans said they spend more than half the day in front of a screen, and a recent survey found that kids in the United States devote almost seven hours a day to staring at pixels. Statistics like these can produce the sense that matter doesn&#39;t matter all that much anymore. Conway thinks that this is an illusion, and a dangerous one. Contemporary society continues to rely on raw materials, like Spruce Pine&#39;s quartz, taken from the earth. Indeed, extraction rates, far from slowing, keep accelerating. These days, Conway reckons, humanity mines, drains, and blasts more stuff out of the ground each year than it did in total during the roughly three hundred millennia between the birth of the species and the start of the Korean War. This comes with immense consequences, both ecological and social, even if we don&#39;t attend to them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Consider sand, the first of Conway&#39;s not so dark materials. According to a 2022 report from the United Nations Environment Programme, global demand for “sand resources” has tripled in the past two decades, to something like a hundred trillion pounds a year; this amounts to almost thirty-five pounds a day for every person on the planet. A lot of sand (though no one seems to know exactly how much) goes into land building. Among the world&#39;s biggest sand importers is Singapore, which has grown by more than fifty square miles since the nineteen-sixties. Among the major exporters is Vietnam, where sand dredging along the Mekong Delta has caused so much erosion that whole villages&#39; worth of homes have been swept downstream.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;“Where once there were riverbanks, today there are sheer drops into the water,” Conway writes. Such is the hunger for sand that, in many parts of the globe, an illicit trade has sprung up. In India, so-called sand mafias are rumored to pay off cops and politicians. According to the South Asia Network on Dams, Rivers and People, a Delhi-based advocacy group, at least a dozen civilians and two government officials were killed by sand mafias between December, 2020, and March, 2022. (This was down from twenty-three civilians, five journalists and activists, and eleven government officials killed during the two years prior.)&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;A lot of sand also goes into building buildings, not to mention dams, bridges, overpasses, and roadways. Sand and gravel are the major ingredients in concrete, some seven hundred billion tons of which now slather the earth. Often, concrete is reinforced with rebar, which is made with iron, the third of Conway&#39;s six materials. (The material I&#39;ve skipped here is salt, which, Conway says, is essential to just about every chemical process that&#39;s ever been invented.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Worldwide, nearly three billion tons of iron ore are extracted each year. Australia is currently the leading source, and its biggest mines are in the Pilbara, a region in the country&#39;s dry, dusty northwest. Iron from the Pilbara is mined by blasting the landscape apart and then carting away the pieces, using, as Conway puts it, “church-sized diggers.” Just the other day, several people died in the Pilbara when a truck carrying ammonium nitrate, an explosive used in the blasts, collided with another vehicle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Conway devotes a hefty chunk of his discussion of iron to the story of the rock shelters in Juukan Gorge. These were sacred to two of the Pilbara&#39;s Aboriginal peoples, the Puutu Kunti Kurrama and the Pinikura, and contained artifacts that were some forty thousand years old. After assuring the communities that “all reasonable endeavors” would be made to minimize the impact of its operations in the area, the mining company Rio Tinto blew the rock shelters up. (The company has since apologized for what happened.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“Perhaps what makes the destruction of the Juukan caves most disturbing is that we are all, one way or another, complicit,” Conway writes. Most of Australia&#39;s iron ore is shipped off to China, where it&#39;s converted into steel and used to construct the factories and machinery that churn out the phones, consoles, chargers, T-shirts, running shoes, housewares, and assorted tchotchkes the rest of the world buys.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Like many books in its genre—about how &lt;em>;x&lt;/em>; number of &lt;em>;y&lt;/em>; items explain &lt;em>;z&lt;/em>;—“Material World” has trouble sticking to its chosen integer. One of Conway&#39;s six raw materials is oil, but into this category he also squishes natural gas. Both are obviously fossil fuels, but, as Conway himself notes, they have distinctive properties that make them essential in different ways. Oil powers the transportation sector—cars, trucks, airplanes, and supertankers—and its by-products go into plastics, which show up in just about every consumer product you can name, from air mattresses to zippers. Natural gas, meanwhile, is primarily used to generate heat and electricity. It&#39;s also a key ingredient for synthesizing nitrogen fertilizer, without which, it is estimated, half the world&#39;s eight billion people would starve.&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a28241&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a28241&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“Quit hogging the covers”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_a28241.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65302676ed0f4ae933f034f9/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_a28241.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Quit hogging the covers!”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Ollie Wootton&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Copy link to cartoon&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178637)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M16.3488 10.5017C16.2107 10.7357 16.2926 11.035 16.5318 11.17C16.7709 11.3052 17.0767 11.225 17.2148 10.991L18.4648 8.87225C19.5694 7.00002 18.9139 4.60601 17.0007 3.52508C15.0875 2.44415 12.6412 3.08562 11.5366 4.95785L9.53657 8.34782C8.432 10.22 9.08751 12.6141 11.0007 13.6949C11.1888 13.8012 11.382 13.8908 11.5785 13.9642C11.7819 14.0403 12.0058 13.9485 12.1147 13.764C12.2794 13.4849 12.1103 13.1276 11.8083 12.9992C11.7041 12.9549 11.6014 12.9044 11.5007 12.8475C10.0658 12.0368 9.57417 10.2413 10.4026 8.83712L12.4026 5.44715C13.2311 4.04298 15.0658 3.56187 16.5007 4.37257C17.9356 5.18327 18.4272 6.97878 17.5988 8.38295L16.3488 10.5017ZM7.6526 13.4983C7.79067 13.2643 7.70873 12.965 7.46959 12.8299C7.23044 12.6948 6.92464 12.775 6.78657 13.009L5.53657 15.1278C4.432 17 5.0875 19.394 7.00068 20.475C8.91385 21.5558 11.3602 20.9144 12.4648 19.0422L14.4648 15.6521C15.5694 13.78 14.9139 11.3859 13.0007 10.305C12.8127 10.1988 12.6195 10.1091 12.4229 10.0357C12.2195 9.95975 11.9956 10.0515 11.8867 10.236C11.7221 10.5151 11.8911 10.8724 12.1932 11.0008C12.2973 11.0451 12.4 11.0956 12.5007 11.1525C13.9356 11.9632 14.4272 13.7587 13.5988 15.1628L11.5988 18.5529C10.7704 19.957 8.93555 20.4382 7.50068 19.6274C6.0658 18.8167 5.57417 17.0212 6.4026 15.6171L7.6526 13.4983Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;div role=&quot;dialog&quot;>;&lt;div aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;p aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;Link copied&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Shop&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Shop&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shop&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178638)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 3H2V4H4.23828L6.99617 15.2631C7.11483 15.6982 7.50998 16 7.96094 16H18.0365C18.4875 16 18.8826 15.6982 19.0013 15.2631L20.9648 7.26312C21.1383 6.62698 20.6594 6 20 6H10V7H20L18.0365 15H7.96094L5.03652 3H4.58055H4ZM10.0365 19C10.0365 19.5523 9.58881 20 9.03652 20C8.48424 20 8.03652 19.5523 8.03652 19C8.03652 18.4477 8.48424 18 9.03652 18C9.58881 18 10.0365 18.4477 10.0365 19ZM11.0365 19C11.0365 20.1046 10.1411 21 9.03652 21C7.93195 21 7.03652 20.1046 7.03652 19C7.03652 17.8954 7.93195 17 9.03652 17C10.1411 17 11.0365 17.8954 11.0365 19ZM18.0365 19C18.0365 19.5523 17.5888 20 17.0365 20C16.4842 20 16.0365 19.5523 16.0365 19C16.0365 18.4477 16.4842 18 17.0365 18C17.5888 18 18.0365 18.4477 18.0365 19ZM19.0365 19C19.0365 20.1046 18.1411 21 17.0365 21C15.932 21 15.0365 20.1046 15.0365 19C15.0365 17.8954 15.932 17 17.0365 17C18.1411 17 19.0365 17.8954 19.0365 19Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;“Much of what we eat today is, one way or another, a fossil fuel product,” Conway observes. Despite a lot of talk about cutting back on fossil fuels, the world, he points out, is consuming just as much oil and gas as ever before (and very nearly as much coal). But, if Conway is concerned about our continuing reliance on fossil fuels, he&#39;s also concerned about what it will take to replace them. Two of the alternatives are solar and wind. Conway calculates that building enough wind turbines to shutter a hundred-megawatt natural-gas plant would take fifty thousand tons of concrete and thirty thousand tons of iron. Meanwhile, a transportation sector that runs on electricity will require a whole lot more of his fourth material, copper. A recent report from S. &amp;amp; P. Global predicted that, worldwide, copper consumption will double over the next twelve years and that “there is a looming mismatch” between the available supply and the growing “copper demand resulting from the energy transition.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Conway visits the Chuquicamata copper mine, in northern Chile—Chuqui, for short—which is believed to be the largest open-pit mine on the globe. When a blast goes off at the bottom of the pit, more than half a mile down, the noise, he says, is “shattering.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Industrial mining operations began at the site a century ago. In the intervening decades, most of the best-quality ore there, and indeed around the globe, has been churned through. “Even as people demanded more copper the earth became considerably less willing to give it up,” Conway writes. In 1900, fifty tons of rock yielded a ton of copper; to obtain that ton today, some eight hundred tons of rock must be processed.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Next to the Chuquicamata mine sits a town of the same name, which was abandoned in the early two-thousands, as waste rock began tumbling into people&#39;s gardens and residents fell ill. (The citizens of the town took to calling it &lt;em>;Chuqui qui mata&lt;/em>;, or “Chuqui which kills.”) By now, the waste has piled up high enough to consume a quarter of the vacant houses and a seven-story hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Lithium—the last of Conway&#39;s materials—is equally essential to electrification. A typical electric-car battery contains nearly twenty pounds of the metal, which, in the era of climate change, has been dubbed “white gold.” Like many strategic resources—see, for example, high-purity quartz—lithium is unevenly distributed. More than three-quarters of the known resources lie in just four countries: Chile, Argentina, Bolivia, and Australia. Competition over lithium supplies is one of the many sources of tension between the US and China. Conway fears a replay of the nineteenth century, “when European countries colonised their way through much of the world, seeking rubber here, copper there.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The best option he sees for the future lies in what he calls “unmanufacturing.” Iron, copper, and lithium, in contrast to oil, can be recycled. Faced with climate change on the one hand and the material demands of new energy infrastructure on the other, perhaps humanity will finally figure out how to reuse the gazillions of tons of resources it&#39;s already dug up. Conway doesn&#39;t believe this will happen anytime soon—“We are still a long, long way from that promised land,” he cautions—but it is at least theoretically possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Chip Colwell, too, argues that it&#39;s time to rethink our ties to the material world. But Colwell is an archeologist, and, as such, he takes a longer view. In “So Much Stuff: How Humans Discovered Tools, Invented Meaning, and Made More of Everything” (Chicago), he seeks to explain how &lt;em>;Homo sapiens&lt;/em>; went from knapping chert to ordering granite countertops. What happened, he asks, “that led our species from having nothing to needing everything?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Colwell, a former curator at the Denver Museum of Nature &amp;amp; Science, divides humanity&#39;s association with “stuff” into three periods. At the start of the first (and by far the longest), our hominin ancestors realized that some of the objects that were lying around—rocks, primarily—could be fashioned into implements. By two and a half million years ago, hominins—it&#39;s uncertain which species they belonged to—had mastered what&#39;s known as “secondary tool use”; they could take a stone and bash it against a different kind of stone to produce a blade with one sharp edge. This method of tool production continued, pretty much unchanged, for a million years or so, until some other group of hominins—probably &lt;em>;Homo erectus&lt;/em>;—made a breakthrough: they figured out how to make stone tools with &lt;em>;two&lt;/em>; sharp edges. Meanwhile, the story goes, humans began to evolve in concert with their technologies. Their hand axes allowed them to chop up other animals (and also, presumably, plants); this, in turn, allowed them to devote less effort to digestion and put more toward cogitation. The result was a feedback loop.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;kni319&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;“Bigger and smarter brains led to the ability to create better tools, which in turn provided more energy for bigger and smarter brains,” Colwell writes. Eventually, early humans became so dependent on their tools that they couldn&#39;t do without them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The next period, in Colwell&#39;s telling, begins with the invention of what might, broadly speaking, be called art. This happened perhaps as early as half a million years ago, when a &lt;em>;Homo erectus&lt;/em>; living in what&#39;s now Indonesia made some scratches on a mussel shell. By thirty thousand years ago, &lt;em>;Homo sapiens&lt;/em>; living in what&#39;s now Italy were grinding ochre to paint figures on stone. The advent of art marks the point, Conway writes, at which things were no longer valued only for their utility—“when objects began to do more than just serve our biological needs.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;During periods one and two, accumulating stuff was tough. In the days before agriculture, humans were constantly on the move and could possess only as much as they could carry. Once they began farming and settling down, around ten thousand years ago, whole new classes of objects were created—wheels, plows, sickles. The new objects, along with the food surpluses they helped produce, gave rise to new forms of human relations. Societies became stratified, and their most powerful members began to express their status by accumulating objects of value. Still, everything had to be made by hand, and the vast majority of people remained, by today&#39;s standards, dirt poor.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Then came the Industrial Revolution, which ushered in period three. People figured out how to reliably turn iron into steel and sand into concrete. They invented steam engines, followed by steam turbines. Each innovation begat more innovation, and the feedback loop was, in a manner of speaking, electrified. To manufacture demand, marketers capitalized on the equation of stuff with status. In the Global North, at least, scarcity gave way to superabundance. Colwell quotes an estimate—perhaps reliable, perhaps not—that the average US household possesses three hundred thousand things. (Some of these things, admittedly, are paper clips.) Americans now have so many belongings, he notes, that they routinely pay to keep piles of them in storage.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;While writing his book, Colwell decides to try to step off the consumerist treadmill. Together with his wife and nine-year-old daughter, he embarks on what he calls a “slow-buy year.” Each member of the family agrees to purchase no more than five items over the course of twelve months, besides “necessities”—a category that includes food and school supplies. Before the halfway mark, Colwell and his family are already starting to chafe against their self-imposed limits. Then they purchase a new house. The idea of slow buying gets tossed out with the moving boxes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“So Much Stuff” and “Material World” each make strong points; taken together, the books are even more compelling—and alarming. Consumption patterns in the Global North—and South, increasingly—simply cannot be sustained. Everyone who&#39;s read the news lately, or just ventured outside into this summer&#39;s smoke-filled, record-breaking heat, knows this. But that knowledge doesn&#39;t seem to change much. Conway explains this failure as a function of modernity. The industrialized world was built out of mountains of sand, iron, and copper, and it cannot operate without vast quantities of these or other materials. Colwell traces the problem back even further. Our special talent as a species is our ability to refashion raw materials—first rocks into tools, then, eventually, quartz into integrated circuits. We are, he suggests, &lt;em>;Homo stuffensis&lt;/em>;, a creature “defined and made by our things.” We should change our ways—we &lt;em>;must&lt;/em>; change our ways—but this long history is against us. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“My Name Is Barbra,” Excerpted]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/30/my-name-is-barbra-excerpted]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653011c4e129bd34403a2f44/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43241.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;With her long-awaited memoir, Barbra Streisand offers a funny and frank look at her career, six decades in. At a whopping 992 pages, it appears that the Hollywood and Broadway legend . 。 。 isn&#39;t skimping on the details of her rarefied life.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;align-right&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:align-right&quot;>;&lt;p>;—&lt;em>;Time.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 1 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra chalks up her cardiovascular wellness to screaming daily at C-&lt;em >;SPAN&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 5 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra recounts girls&#39; weekend with Donna Karan full of laughter, nail care.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 14 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra says that Track II diplomacy is the “Hello, gorgeous” of statecraft.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 20 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra recounts anecdote featuring Shimon Peres, throw pillows.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 112 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra says Thomas Jefferson&#39;s Monticello is “an autobiographical masterpiece but the drawer pulls are all wrong.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 261 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra says that too much guitar noodling on a song can sound like jazzturbation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 290 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra says that being the only artist to have No. 1 albums in each of the past six decades always makes people ask her if she wants to lie down after lunch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 292 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra interlards her praise for Sojourner Truth&#39;s “Ain&#39;t I a woman?” speech with a digression on period-appropriate sconcing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 293 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra says calling up Apple&#39;s Tim Cook to have Siri&#39;s pronunciation of “Streisand” corrected was her “Norma Rae” moment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 384 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra says of her collection of Cartier and Cheuret antique clocks, “They are &lt;em>;all&lt;/em>; my children.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 477 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra says she included on her archival album the forty-nine seconds of applause for her at the 1969 Oscars for “context.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 578 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra writes that starring in “Nuts” resulted in speaking requests from Planters and Blue Diamond.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 649 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra writes that she cloned her dog Sammie because her other dogs pooped on her antique-doll collection.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 702 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra says that many Republicans attend her concerts “because they&#39;re who can afford the tickets.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 803 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra writes that a carefully selected array of Jordan almonds on a Lalique platter is as close as man gets to God. “Have I ever suffered for my commitment to perfectionism?当然。 But shouldn&#39;t we be willing to suffer for the things we love? It&#39;s like the time at a fund-raiser in the nineteen-eighties—oh, my God, I&#39;m losing my breath control even &lt;em>;thinking&lt;/em>; about this—I got seated next to the real-estate magnate Donald Trump. &lt;em>;Talk&lt;/em>; about suffering. The eleventh plague. Even then, I knew. I knew. But I kept my mouth shut until dessert. Because we all have to practice empathy. Life is not always easy. You want a walk along the ocean at sunset? Order the mussels. If you&#39;re not a listener, then you can&#39;t get informed, and Jefferson said that &#39;a well-informed electorate is a prerequisite to democracy.&#39; Or look at the Hebrew word &lt;em>;dayenu&lt;/em>;, which means &#39;enough.&#39; No one mandates what is and isn&#39;t &lt;em>;dayenu;&lt;/em>; there&#39;s no Dayenu Committee (though if you&#39;re looking for people to serve: hello). You&#39;ve got to determine this stuff on your own—when to speak out, when to rejoice in song. You know, some of my friends tease me for color-coördinating the wrappers on the candy in my living rooms; other people thought I was crazy when I built a &#39;shopping mall&#39; of antique stores and my used costumes, based on the one at the Winterthur estate, in the basement of my barn in Malibu. But at the end of the day? These are precisely the things that these same people love about me. Bill and Hillary adored it when I gave them a tour of the barn and I made Hillary try on my sequinny black see-through Scaasi pants suit from the &#39;69 Oscars: NSFW Hillary. Hillary &lt;em>;beyond&lt;/em>; e-mails. I mean, if you don&#39;t assert your will and your consummate design sense, who are you really? Sure, people have called me &#39;mouthy&#39; or &#39;pushy&#39; or a million things that they&#39;d never say about a man, but you know what? The world needs to know what the rest of the world is thinking. People who need people, etc. And in my experience people &lt;em>;want&lt;/em>; to be told if their jeans make their ass look fat. Sure, they&#39;ll smart at first, but later that night, as they&#39;re falling asleep? They&#39;re smiling.为什么？ Because they&#39;re thinking, Barbra cares about my silhouette. So, sometimes you need to speak out. Sometimes you need to look at the person next to you at the dinner party of life and—on realizing that he is a liar and a bully and a misogynist and a tax cheat who supports capital punishment—whisper in his ear, &#39;Donald, honey. Less is more.&#39; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 945 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra recounts vacation with Madeleine Albright rife with handbag repair, disappointment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 963 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra concludes lengthy section on global disarmament with “Yentl” &#39;s tagline, “Nothing&#39;s impossible.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 970 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra designs own headstone, which reads “Dayenu already.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PAGE 992 —&lt;/strong>; Barbra says the two greatest threats to civilization are encroachments on the truth and the stickers on fruit. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;g49we&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;lpu1bob&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Better Things to Do than Training for a Marathon]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/30/better-things-to-do-than-training-for-a-marathon]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653406f21193686b1a832498/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/r43260_web-social.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Better Things to Do than Training for a Marathon&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186101/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43260_a.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186101/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43260_a.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186101/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43260_a.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186101/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43260_a.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186101/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43260_a.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186101/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43260_a.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186101/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43260_a.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186101/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43260_a.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Better Things to Do than Training for a Marathon&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681978f936e3d41e31/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43260_b.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681978f936e3d41e31/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43260_b.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681978f936e3d41e31/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43260_b.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681978f936e3d41e31/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43260_b.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681978f936e3d41e31/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43260_b.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681978f936e3d41e31/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43260_b.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681978f936e3d41e31/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43260_b.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681978f936e3d41e31/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43260_b.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Better Things to Do than Training for a Marathon&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc6813c1e561d000bb68/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43260_c.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc6813c1e561d000bb68/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43260_c.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc6813c1e561d000bb68/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43260_c.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc6813c1e561d000bb68/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43260_c.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc6813c1e561d000bb68/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43260_c.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc6813c1e561d000bb68/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43260_c.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc6813c1e561d000bb68/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43260_c.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc6813c1e561d000bb68/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43260_c.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Better Things to Do than Training for a Marathon&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681193686b1a83230a/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43260_d.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681193686b1a83230a/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43260_d.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681193686b1a83230a/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43260_d.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681193686b1a83230a/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43260_d.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681193686b1a83230a/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43260_d.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681193686b1a83230a/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43260_d.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681193686b1a83230a/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43260_d.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc681193686b1a83230a/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43260_d.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Better Things to Do than Training for a Marathon&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68266fac5bf871b048/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43260_e.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68266fac5bf871b048/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43260_e.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68266fac5bf871b048/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43260_e.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68266fac5bf871b048/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43260_e.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68266fac5bf871b048/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43260_e.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68266fac5bf871b048/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43260_e.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68266fac5bf871b048/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43260_e.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68266fac5bf871b048/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43260_e.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Better Things to Do than Training for a Marathon&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186103/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43260_f.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186103/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43260_f.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186103/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43260_f.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186103/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43260_f.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186103/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43260_f.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186103/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43260_f.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186103/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43260_f.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6532dc68221dafa188186103/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43260_f.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Better Things to Do than Training for a Marathon&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653300f1ed704f89d6f93fdb/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/r43260_g.png&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653300f1ed704f89d6f93fdb/master/w_120,c_limit/r43260_g.png 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653300f1ed704f89d6f93fdb/master/w_240,c_limit/r43260_g.png 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653300f1ed704f89d6f93fdb/master/w_320,c_limit/r43260_g.png 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653300f1ed704f89d6f93fdb/master/w_640,c_limit/r43260_g.png 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653300f1ed704f89d6f93fdb/master/w_960,c_limit/r43260_g.png 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653300f1ed704f89d6f93fdb/master/w_1280,c_limit/r43260_g.png 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/653300f1ed704f89d6f93fdb/master/w_1600,c_limit/r43260_g.png 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Briefly Noted Book Reviews]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/30/the-upstairs-delicatessen-revolutionary-spring-pet-and-fire-in-the-canyon]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed10d12854ff6621607bd/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43247web-tout.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Briefly Noted Book Reviews&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0ba12854ff6621607b9/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43247web.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0ba12854ff6621607b9/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43247web.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0ba12854ff6621607b9/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43247web.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0ba12854ff6621607b9/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43247web.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0ba12854ff6621607b9/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43247web.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0ba12854ff6621607b9/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43247web.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0ba12854ff6621607b9/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43247web.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0ba12854ff6621607b9/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43247web.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Upstairs Delicatessen&lt;/strong>;&lt;em>;, by Dwight Garner (Farrar, Straus &amp;amp; Giroux)&lt;/em>;. Garner, whose book reviews are a highlight of the &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>; culture pages, serves up a commonplace book composed of literary quotations, advice for living, recipes, and a heaping side order of memoir. The assortment makes it clear that, in his reading and at the table, Garner, like A. J. Liebling before him, is a man of immense appetites. He likes his dishes unpretentious––his yearning for chili dogs is at least as powerful as his love of oysters––and his tastes as a reader range from thrillers centered on hardboiled boozers to “Ulysses,” in which grilled mutton kidneys thrill Leopold Bloom, with their “tang of faintly scented urine.” Garner&#39;s mind––his “upstairs delicatessen”––is generous, excellent company.&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Revolutionary Spring by Christopher Clark.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c112854ff6621607bb/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43248web.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c112854ff6621607bb/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43248web.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c112854ff6621607bb/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43248web.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c112854ff6621607bb/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43248web.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c112854ff6621607bb/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43248web.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c112854ff6621607bb/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43248web.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c112854ff6621607bb/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43248web.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c112854ff6621607bb/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43248web.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Revolutionary Spring&lt;/strong>;&lt;em>;, by Christopher Clark (Crown)&lt;/em>;. This Cambridge historian&#39;s scrupulous survey takes up the interconnected uprisings that engulfed almost all of Europe in 1848. Arguing that they represent “the only truly European revolution that there has ever been,” Clark follows these revolts&#39; trajectories, from heady beginnings, when parliaments were convened and new constitutions proliferated, to counter-revolutionary backlashes. Resisting the “stigma of failure” that has tended to lurk over this period, he insists that it was consequential, calling it “the particle collision chamber at the centre of the European nineteenth century. People, groups and ideas flew into it, crashed together, fused or fragmented, and emerged in showers of new entities whose trails can be traced through the decades that followed.”&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;h2 >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/best-books-2023&quot;>;The Best Books of 2023&lt;/a>;&lt;/h2>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Briefly Noted Book Reviews&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63d16763c44837936a5fb854/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/bestbooks-header-2023-desktop.png&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63d16763c44837936a5fb854/master/w_120,c_limit/bestbooks-header-2023-desktop.png 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63d16763c44837936a5fb854/master/w_240,c_limit/bestbooks-header-2023-desktop.png 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63d16763c44837936a5fb854/master/w_320,c_limit/bestbooks-header-2023-desktop.png 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63d16763c44837936a5fb854/master/w_640,c_limit/bestbooks-header-2023-desktop.png 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63d16763c44837936a5fb854/master/w_960,c_limit/bestbooks-header-2023-desktop.png 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63d16763c44837936a5fb854/master/w_1280,c_limit/bestbooks-header-2023-desktop.png 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63d16763c44837936a5fb854/master/w_1600,c_limit/bestbooks-header-2023-desktop.png 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Read our reviews of the year&#39;s notable new fiction and nonfiction.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pet by Catherine Chidgey.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0bd2decf96c1efd95d0/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43249web.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0bd2decf96c1efd95d0/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43249web.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0bd2decf96c1efd95d0/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43249web.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0bd2decf96c1efd95d0/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43249web.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0bd2decf96c1efd95d0/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43249web.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0bd2decf96c1efd95d0/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43249web.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0bd2decf96c1efd95d0/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43249web.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0bd2decf96c1efd95d0/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43249web.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;6wmryj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;d6n86r&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Pet&lt;/strong>;&lt;em>;, by Catherine Chidgey (Europa)&lt;/em>;. In this suspenseful bildungsroman, Justine, a Catholic schoolgirl living in New Zealand in the nineteen-eighties, searches for a classroom thief, as the school&#39;s suspicions shift from her to her best friend to a glamorous new teacher. Justine&#39;s adolescence is colored by concerns both workaday and personal: a close female friendship, petty teen-age infighting, seizures that disrupt her recall, grief for her recently deceased mother. The novel occasionally jumps forward to 2014, when Justine, now an adult with a daughter of her own, tends to her dementia-stricken father. In these moments, Justine&#39;s girlhood collapses into her present, and she appraises “shimmers in my memory” and revisits the mysteries of her youth.&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fire in the Canyon by Daniel Gumbiner.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c3f45a3e98c312b24c/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231030_r43250web.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c3f45a3e98c312b24c/master/w_120,c_limit/231030_r43250web.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c3f45a3e98c312b24c/master/w_240,c_limit/231030_r43250web.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c3f45a3e98c312b24c/master/w_320,c_limit/231030_r43250web.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c3f45a3e98c312b24c/master/w_640,c_limit/231030_r43250web.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c3f45a3e98c312b24c/master/w_960,c_limit/231030_r43250web.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c3f45a3e98c312b24c/master/w_1280,c_limit/231030_r43250web.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ed0c3f45a3e98c312b24c/master/w_1600,c_limit/231030_r43250web.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Fire in the Canyon&lt;/strong>;&lt;em>;, by Daniel Gumbiner (Astra)&lt;/em>;. Set in the foothills of California&#39;s gold country, this dread-laden novel follows a family who make their living cultivating grapes for winemaking as they attempt to resume their lives in the wake of a wildfire. After an evacuation, they return to the same land, but their environment—increasingly marred by drought, fire, and high temperatures—presents a cascade of fears: not just death and injury from fire but power outages, dangerous air quality, and smoke that might taint their grapes and thus take away their livelihood. The father&#39;s detailed awareness of the region&#39;s weather produces a sense of looming crisis; he notes how often once unusual events now occur—a set of circumstances that make it “hard not to wonder where the bottom was.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;yjhlil&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 20:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>