<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约客</title><description>纽约客全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.newyoker.com<item><title><![CDATA[Martin Scorsese on Making “Killers of the Flower Moon”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/martin-scorsese-on-making-killers-of-the-flower-moon]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6529d837a6c0cad6e89e9c99/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/brody-martin%20scorsese.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width =&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>; &lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M 23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt; /svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;马丁·斯科塞斯拥有业内最好的曲线球。他 2013 年的电影《华尔街之狼》 &lt;/a>;》根据一个大规模金融诈骗犯的真实故事改编，也是他最疯狂、最古怪的喜剧，其灵感更接近杰里·刘易斯而不是奥利弗·斯通。他于 2010 年拍摄的现代哥特式恐怖惊悚片《禁闭岛》是主要是一篇折射个人的文章，讲述了他在核战争阴影下观看偏执的黑色经典电影的童年时光。现在，他即将上映的电影《花月杀手》是他作为八十多岁的老人首次尝试西部片，本质上是一部类似于斯坦利·库布里克最后一部电影《大开眼戒》的婚姻剧。它更多地借鉴了《魅影缝匠》、《深闺疑云》和《煤气灯下》等亲密心理剧，而不是约翰·福特的任何西方经典作品。换句话说，斯科塞斯的新电影所带来的第一个谜团并不在于情节，而是它本身的起源之谜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几周前我见到斯科塞斯时，我告诉他，在我们之前一开始，我很少接受采访，因为，好吧，我有导演的电影，如果观看它们不能给我足够的思考和写作，那么我就从事了错误的职业。也就是说，关于斯科塞斯，我想了解的东西有很多，尤其是因为他的艺术地位的矛盾：他以数亿美元的预算执导了非凡的电影，但又使它们非常个性化，并充满了艺术的华丽——壮观的摄影机动作、亲密的观察、戏剧性的震撼和表演时刻——这些都既大胆又独特。我想问一下他的方法，因为我一直觉得导演艺术的很大一部分是&lt;em>;制作&lt;/em>;——一部完成的电影的原创性通常源于其导演方法的独特性制作它的系统和方法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我在 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the- front-row/review-jonas-mekass-illustration-documentary-of-martin-scosese-on-the-set-of-the-departed&quot;>;乔纳斯·梅卡斯的纪录片&lt;/a>;，讲述斯科塞斯 2006 年的黑帮剧情片《The 《离去》——在之前的五次提名均以失望告终之后，斯科塞斯最终凭借这部电影获得了奥斯卡最佳导演奖——这也预示着他在过去十五年作品的巨大爆发。我还在《华尔街之狼》中看到了这一点，斯科塞斯采用了日益普遍的 CGI 技术，并像画家一样使用它。但我最好奇的是他在《花月杀手》的创作过程中涉及到了题材。 《花月杀手》以十九世纪二十年代的俄克拉荷马州为背景，基于 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Killers-Flower-Moon-Osage-Murders-ebook /dp/B01CWZFBZ4&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Killers-Flower-Moon-Osage-Murders- ebook/dp/B01CWZFBZ4&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Killers-Flower-Moon-Osage-Murders-ebook/dp/B01CWZFBZ4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;非小说类本书&lt;/a>;的同名作者是&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/david-grann&quot;>;David Grann&lt;/a>;，他是我在《纽约客》的同事&lt;/em>;。在电影中，莱昂纳多·迪卡普里奥饰演白人欧内斯特·伯克哈特，他在黑帮般的叔叔（罗伯特·德尼罗饰）的指导下与一位名叫莫莉（莉莉·格拉德斯通饰）的奥色治妇女结婚，这是一个范围广泛的谋杀计划的一部分窃取奥塞奇族的财富，该族的领土上发现了石油。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;观看改编自原著的电影时常见的挫败感之一是不可避免地删减源材料。阅读一本几百页长的书比观看一部较长的故事片要花更多的时间，而且通常，人们在不读这本书的情况下就能感受到改编的压缩和间隙。斯科塞斯的新电影非常庞大——三小时二十六分钟——但即使是这个长度也无法涵盖格兰在他那本引人入胜、恐怖的书中所讲述的大量事件。斯科塞斯以一种近乎胡迪尼般的独创性摆脱了这一困境，将注意力集中在一些即使格兰的大量研究也无法阐明的问题上：那对夫妇的关系是什么样的？由于重点的改变，剧本的写作任务不再是浓缩，而是扩展——通过想象来填补历史空白。正如斯科塞斯向我明确表示的那样，这对夫妇的关系被重新构想的方式体现了他自己对格兰故事中潜在道德的挣扎——他有责任将奥塞奇人置于故事的中心，结果却改变了故事的中心。电影的美学。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几乎所有导演同时也是演员；他们只是碰巧为演员和工作人员保留了表演。有些人还在自己或其他导演的电影中表演；斯科塞斯这两部作品都出演过，尽管只是一些配角。在《花月杀手》中，他扮演了一个虽小但至关重要的戏剧角色，这种表演远比希区柯克式的眨眼或取悦鉴赏家的客串更有力量。斯科塞斯赢得奥斯卡奖之际，电影制片厂已经不再接受他那种规模宏大、艺术雄心勃勃的电影制作，而随之而来的超级英雄电影和其他主要以年轻人为中心的知识产权系列电影的崛起让情况变得更糟。斯科塞斯利用自己的声望，在倡导电影公司投资于经典电影的保存和发行以及由雄心勃勃的导演发行新的实质性电影方面发挥了主导作用。事实上，他已经成为过去、现在和未来电影艺术事业的代言人和代言人。没有剧透，但是，当他在《杀手》中表演时，他仍然为自己说话，也为整个电影说话。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;斯科塞斯本人有很多话要说，而他的说话方式也增强了他所说的话的魅力它。正如电影中的一个场景可能由几十个不同时长、以不同方式组合而成的镜头组成，而且往往在时间、空间和语气上相差甚远，斯科塞斯以一种自由联想、快速剪辑、蒙太奇式的方式说话。他以完全属于他自己的方式，通过细节的积累和与语言对应物的剪切、溶解、叠加和其他类型的电影标点符号的联系来构建戏剧。他的谈话是一个运动中的心灵的形象，在记忆和感知之间、在实际细节和想法之间、在第一手经验和从观看电影中收集到的概念之间自由游移——所有这些都像他的电影一样充满了目的和激情。正如《花月杀手》是我看电影生涯中最快的三个半小时一样，我与斯科塞斯的谈话也是我经历过的最快的一个小时。为了篇幅和清晰度，我们的讨论已经过编辑。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;《花月杀手》有一些特别之处”。你总是讲美好、感人、充满激情的故事，但在这里我觉得你不仅仅是在讲故事。我感觉你在见证。您在拍这部电影的时候有这样的感觉吗？这是项目的一部分吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当然。我想这可以追溯到 74 年，当时我有机会和南达科他州的奥格拉拉拉科塔（苏族）部落一起度过了一段时间，只有一两天，也许两天，我参与其中一个没有成功的项目。这是一次痛苦的经历，我还太小，无法理解。我不理解破坏和贫困。我是在另一种贫困中长大的，那就是伊丽莎白街、莫特街和马尔伯里的工人阶级男女，但我们也有包厘街。所以我是在贫困中长大的。&lt;em>;&lt;/em>;但我从来没有见过像这样的东西，我无法描述为什么——这是绝望的。当时我在洛杉矶再次见到了一些美洲原住民，我们讨论了另一个项目，我也看到了我们小时候成长的这种令人难以置信的幻想——尽管我们在纠正好莱坞的错误方面做出了精彩的尝试。 《断箭》、《鼓声》、《阿帕奇》、《魔鬼之门》等都是亲美国原住民的电影，仍然有美国白人演员扮演美国原住民。但这些故事不仅平衡了谁站在自己一边，而且还尊重文化，尤其是在《断箭》中，我想。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，无论如何，不​​，我是我总是意识到贫穷，而且我总觉得我只在那里见证了几天。但随着山姆·佩金帕的西部片结局，出现了一个新的领域：我们如何思考，我们如何根据美洲原住民的经历来看待这一切？他们真的走了吗？在某种程度上，作为孩子，我们想，好吧，他们和我们在一起，但他们现在就像我们一样。我想，我们还是孩子，就想以这种方式思考在某种程度上强迫同化原住民的问题。但我不知道。当我走出去看到它是什么时，它是不同的。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:自动&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;hbfp1k&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden= &quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;k6n2u&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;但是从 1974 年到现在，已经四十九年了。您一直在考虑一个涉及美洲原住民的项目吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;我没有考虑它。我远离它，因为震动太强烈了。不知何故，它必须是正确的故事，这花了很长时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你是如何找到大卫·格兰的书的？你是怎么找到它的？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哦，Rick Yorn 给我的。里克是我的经纪人，也是里奥·迪卡普里奥的经纪人。是的，花月的想法——花月是女性化的，我们刚刚制作了《沉默》，月亮的图像和耶稣作为耶稣女性化的一面而不是男性化的一面的感觉非常重要。所以，对我来说，花月，女性，却是“花月杀手”，它的冲突，和这幅风景，只存在于我的想象中——我从来没有去过草原。当我到达那里时，我们在一条路上行驶了很长时间，我想知道为什么我们开得这么慢，我看了看——大约是四十五分钟——我看了看这个车速表，我们’正在做七十五，我意识到这个地方永无止境。而且两边都没有树。你真的无法判断自己的速度有多快。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你对这本书所做的事情，我的意思是，不是我想教的，而是如果我正在教一门关于适应的课程，我会给人们看你的电影，我会让他们读大卫的书，因为对我来说，你对书的改造是你众多伟大成就之一，因为你拥有书中的一切，几乎书中的一切，几乎所有恐怖的突出细节都在电影中。但你颠倒了视角。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;是的。利奥和我想一起拍一部关于西方的整体观念和诸如此类的事情的电影。他将扮演联邦调查局特工汤姆·怀特。所以我说，我在想，我们要怎么做呢？因为我只是，不是油嘴滑舌，但汤姆·怀特实际上是一个意志非常坚强的人。非常非常非常有纪律、有道德、直率。而且简洁。几乎没说什么。不需要多说。现在，利奥喜欢——我告诉过他很多次，我说，你的脸是一张电影脸。我说，你可以拍无声电影。你不需要说这个或这个，只要你的眼睛就能做到，移动，无论你做什么，他就拥有了——但我确实知道他喜欢在电影中说话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后我也意识到这些人是谁？我说，这些人从华盛顿进来，当他们下了火车的那一刻，当他们进入那个城镇的那一刻，你环顾四周，你会看到鲍勃·德尼罗，你会看到某某——“我知道是谁干的”。观众远远领先于我们。我说，就像我们要观看两个半小时这些人试图找到东西一样。这是警方的程序。在书中，它有效；在书中，它有效。在书中，它有效。但对于我来说，警察程序，我会看，但我做不到。我不知道该怎么做。我不知道剧情该怎么做。我不知道把笔放在哪里。所以我说，我们到底要在这里做什么？所以我们不断尝试。我们的剧本有两百多页，有一天晚上我们读了很多书：我自己、利奥、[合著者]埃里克[罗斯]和我的女儿，还有很多人。最初的两个小时，我们一直在前进。接下来的两个小时，孩子，正如他们所说，这已经有点长了。事情就是这样——我们真的在故事中耗尽了精力，我想讲述越来越多的故事，我想做更多的题外话，偏离主题，可以这么说，看起来像切线，但事实并非如此。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但与此同时，幸运的是，我去过俄克拉荷马州几次，我做的第一件事是，我非常关心与奥色治族会面，看看我们如何可以一起合作。我发现，是的，他们担心信任。我让他们明白，我想尽我所能地对待他们和这个故事，并且我希望他们能够信任我。他们开始这样做，但我也理解为什么他们不这样做。我完全明白了。这就是故事。现在，真正的故事是你对婚姻的信任，对吧？好吧，它有不同的层次，有一些方面、错误和事情，但有信任。嗯，我从奥塞奇人那里学到的是，所有的家庭都还在那里。伯克哈特一家和罗恩一家，亨利·罗恩。他们的后代告诉我们，不要忘记这一点，欧内斯特和莫莉相爱了。她到底为什么留下来？不是&lt;em>;为什么&lt;/em>;她要和他在一起？ &lt;em>;&lt;/em>;她是如何和他在一起的？为什么一个人会和另一个人在一起，我们不知道。 “如何”是另一个问题，是故事的另一种方式。 “如何”是欺骗、自欺； “如何”是爱比她敢于想象的他所做的更强烈。所以这是一种掩盖，但她相信。所以这个爱情故事，这个爱情故事。我们通过 Zoom 与莉莉 [格莱斯顿] 会面，因为 [选角导演] 艾伦·刘易斯向我展示了凯利·雷查特的《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/goings-on-about-town/movies/ certain-women&quot;>;某些女性&lt;/a>;。”莉莉在这方面表现得非常出色。然后 Leo 和她在 Zoom 上见面，因为他非常关心我们要让谁来扮演这个角色？显然，她必须是美洲原住民，我们希望获得奥塞奇的批准。他们批准了她，在批准她之前，Leo 在 Zoom 上与她进行了对话，Zoom 通话一结束，他就说：“她太棒了。”我说：“是的，有很多不同的原因。”我想你可以在电影中看到很多内容；她正直、有幽默感。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ci4o99&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;她的脸庞深邃，有时也有甜蜜。我们相信她比我们懂得更多。她只是知道这一点，这意味着她了解人们，她了解情况，她了解混乱的微妙性，我认为，可以这么说，她了解侵犯。但无论如何，读完之后，一周后，利奥来找我——我们脑子里仍然有这样的想法：他们相爱了。而事实是，她直到审判结束后才离开。我们在那里有场景，联邦调查局的人——或者局里的人——说，“她怎么还和他在一起？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们实际上是这么说的。我们有法庭笔录。她还在法庭上。她在法庭上。她不明白吗？但他和她有一些共同点，然后她就离开了他。我们说，好吧，那是关于什么的？我说，如果这就是故事怎么办？利奥来找我说——所以我们试图在其他人扮演欧内斯特、汤姆·怀特再次处理警察程序的背景下构建它，但它压倒了它。程序性的内容压倒了个人的故事。一周后的一个晚上，利奥再次来找我，他来到我家，他说：“电影的核心在哪里？”我说：“好吧，我的心与她和欧内斯特同在。”他说：“因为无论如何，如果我扮演汤姆·怀特，我们就会处理德克萨斯游骑兵的标志性本质。”我们已经看到了；很好。他需要这样做吗？我会如何做不同的事情？我试过。我找不到办法。于是他看着我，坐下来说道：“现在，别难过。”他说，“但是如果我扮演欧内斯特呢？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;所以这是他的主意。哇。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说，“如果你扮演欧内斯特，我们处理爱情故事，那么我们就处于故事的核心。我们正处于日复一日的生活中。”我说，“你当然知道，这意味着我们要进入剧本的中心，把它撕开并改变一切，然后告诉工作室你想扮演另一个人，我们要走这条路，而莉莉的太棒了，我们将重写整个事情，”这就是我们所做的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是“重写”这个词是错误的。我们建造了这一切。埃里克[罗斯]、我和几个朋友帮忙了。这也是我们在《赌场》中所做的，尼克·皮勒吉和我，我们根据文字记录进行工作。所以我会说，“这里很棒。”然后另一个人会说，“嘿，我们为什么不把&lt;em>;这个&lt;/em>;放进去呢？”所以，我的意思是，在我们进入排练之前，我们一直在不断地努力，不断地努力，我们和奥色治乐队本身有很多接触，他们会说一些事情，还有一个人，威尔逊·派普斯特姆（Wilson Pipestem），他是一名律师，一个非常棒的人，奥塞奇（Osage），他一开始非常担心。他看着我说：“你不明白，我们有特定的生活方式。”他是一位非常强大的律师，一位活动家，他指出并说，“我们是这样长大的，我们是这样长大的”——他给我的是一些事情的例子，而不是教训，不是争论反对我，但却是为他自己和他的人民辩护，他说：“这就是我们，你不明白这一点。例如，当我年轻的时候，我的祖母会在家里，突然暴风雨来了，我会到处跑，她会说，‘不，坐下，坐下，让暴风雨来吧。风暴的力量从我们身上流过。这是上帝的礼物。这是 Wah&#39;Kon-Tah 的礼物。让风暴——不要移动，吸收风暴。” ” 他说，“这就是我们的生活方式。”所以我把它写下来。从这里抓，从那里抓。场景的结尾，与莫莉和利奥共进晚餐的场景，我们写到她说：“你想喝点威士忌吗？”他们喝酒，她比他喝得更多，但她没有喝醉，而他却喝醉了。我说：“我们可以拍出很棒的场景。”我说：“但是有件事——如果下雨怎么办？如果风暴发生了怎么办，不要让它变得太不祥，风暴，但这就是风暴的力量，Wah&#39;Kon-Tah 的美丽，风暴的礼物。而且，为了做到这一点，你必须保持安静。你不能成为你的小土狼。”她就这样控制了他，而他只是等待。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;这就是它的构建方式。我们对此很感兴趣，因为我们总是在寻找新事物，因为有人会经过并说些什么，或者[制片人]玛丽安·鲍尔会发现很多东西。她是我们与所有人的联系。她会与不同的部门、不同部门的不同奥塞奇技术顾问一起工作，而且，嗯，“某某这么说，某某这么说。” “那很有意思。那是什么？” “嗯，你知道他们通常会做什么：家里最小的成员走过死去的长辈的棺材。”嗯，一定是这样，一定是这样。我们必须这样做。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;05b5&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;84sohh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;然后葬礼场景变得更大。所以，在某种程度上，我所说的“变得更大”是指我们甚至拥有更多，但我们必须缩小范围，缩小范围。然后我来自西西里岛，最重要的事情之一是，我是在很多老人去世的背景下长大的。所以我在很多殡仪馆长大，那些意大利老妇人、穿黑衣的老西西里人，就像“萨尔瓦托·朱利亚诺”，还记得吗？ “图里杜！”她对着她的儿子尖叫——那是我们一起长大的。儿子拉住了母亲，而她则投进了棺材。我说：“他们正在谈论哭泣者和哀悼者。”我说：“他们有哀悼者。”他们有会哭的人。所以我们必须这样做。当我们这样做时，我发现——他们说，“我们在房子前面做。”我说：“太好了。”我说：“好吧，让我们从上方远距离拍摄它。”那是房子，后面什么也没有，还有这三个人影，他们在哭泣，听起来，嗯，那太棒了。 “你不想拍得更近一点吗”？我说不。他说，“我有一个更近的镜头，可能是来自——”我说，“不，镜头在这里。我想它在这里是因为他们在呼喊 Wah&#39;Kon-Tah。我们看到了这一切。还有这座小房子，可怜的人类。我们都像我们一样，只是在哭泣，而你几乎听不到。”事情就是这样的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你对俯视镜头的发现的描述让我想起了大型电影制作杰作中的奇迹之一，那就是它就像你一样正在用起重机末端的画笔画一幅画，但你没有驾驶。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不，我没有驾驶它。我想，我想开起重机，但那样我就会遇到各种各样的麻烦。但不，我不想让技术限制我，也就是说太沉迷于技术。多年来我一直在与这个斗争。这就是为什么我与许多不同的摄影导演保持着良好的关系，迈克·查普曼（Mike Chapman），当然还有迈克尔·鲍尔豪斯（Michael Ballhaus），其他与我合作过的人都很棒，但我们只一起拍了一两部电影。但我经常会发现很多DP都喜欢这些设备，而这些设备却很碍事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;当我看到发布后不久就在网上发布的东西时，我感到了一生的震惊。 《华尔街之狼》是&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/83523133&quot;>;由 Brainstorm Digital 制作的视频&lt;/a>;，该公司为这部电影做了一些后期制作工作。他们展示的是电影中出现的镜头，然后是摄像机的原始镜头，以及如何通过数字技术，通过 CGI，将婚礼场景从一个地点物理地移走并放置在另一个完全不同的背景。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哦，是的，我们做了一些事情。是的，是的，是的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;您是否发现自己在制作《花月杀手》时需要使用大量 CGI？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不，不是真的。除了整理一些景观。例如，据推测，某些树木不太正确。我们被告知这些树不一定属于地面的这一部分，无论如何。不，我们发现（制作设计师）杰克·菲斯克（Jack Fisk）对我们拍摄的波胡斯卡（Pawhuska）所做的事情，使它看起来像费尔法克斯（费尔法克斯距离大约四十五分钟路程），就像一个工作室。就好像我们真的要去这些地方一样。我们重建了店面。真的就像回到了过去。我们在 1921 年和 22 年度过了很多时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;关于这部电影的其中一件事，对我来说，你最近的一系列电影，包括《爱尔兰人》，都具有强烈的政治色彩。我对《爱尔兰人》的真实感受是，让我向你展示这个受人尊敬的社会背后隐藏着什么，而《花月杀手》就像揭开盖子说，这就是你的美国历史。这是你在学校里没有学到的。这就是我们现在的社会所建立的，不敢正视的。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正是如此。确切地。我想，也许是因为我来自哪里，我在街上看到过它。这很大程度上与相信自己是对的、相信自己应得的有关。这就是我在过去二十五年、三十年里根据制定这个国家的人、白人新教徒——英国人、法国人、荷兰人和德国人逐渐意识到的。所以这个国家就是以这种思维方式形成的。这是欧洲的，但不是天主教，不是犹太教，而是新教徒的职业道德，这是好的。只是那是阵法。然后政治和权力结构就随之而来并保持不变。它只是留在它身边。我也看到和经历过一些身边的人，他们基本上都还不错，但做了一些坏事，被执法人员利用。所以我从小就认为没有可以信任的执法者。有一些好警察，有一些在巡逻的好警察，好人。有些则不然。但是，对于我父亲的世界，对于他这一代人来说，这是一次非常不同的经历。但这期——我真的很佩服那些真正为了公共服务而从政、真正成为公务员的人的想法。这真的很有趣。如果他们真的为公众服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;oys79g&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;你能拍一部关于其中的电影吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;我不知道。一个可以尝试的人，一个可以尝试成为一名优秀公务员的人。这让我想起《黑水仙》里的台词。院长嬷嬷在黛博拉·蔻儿去印度之前告诉她：记住，他们所有人的领导者都是他们所有人的仆人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;我有一种感觉，在《无间行者》之后，你的工作发生了一些变化。 ，”在你赢得奥斯卡奖后。并不是说奖项真的很重要，而是说，在那一刻，无论有意识还是无意识，就像你没有其他东西可以证明一样。然后你拍了一部我认为是你最好的电影之一，从最积极的意义上来说，也是最疯狂的电影之一，《禁闭岛》。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是的，人们在这个问题上存在分歧。那个。但我喜欢它，因为每一行对话都可能意味着无数的事情。这对我来说真的很有趣，我真的很想这么做。赢得这个奖项是——别忘了，距离奥斯卡最佳导演奖已经有三十七年了，更不用说最佳影片了，这对我来说完全是一个惊喜。但这是一个与我刚开始时不同的学院。但对于我来说，这个奖项是无意的。我制作了《无间行者》作为结束语。我要离开，只是去拍一些小电影，我不知道。恰巧“无间行者”点击了。由于许多不同的原因，这是一件非常困难的事情。那是另外一个故事了。但我们努力摆脱了困境——我应该说是通过它。穿过它，走出它。而且，当我最终把它扔到屏幕上时，人们喜欢它。我并不是说我不认为这是好或坏。我只是觉得我们已经完成了一些事情。我不知道事情会是这样。我不知道。我的下一部电影是《沉默》。这就是我的想法。但介于两者之间的是“禁闭岛”。那里有问题。我确实感觉到了一些东西——让我们制作吧，好吧，现在我可以了——让我们尝试制作另一部&lt;em>;电影&lt;/em>;。我拿到了剧本，我就爱上了这个剧本。然后我没有意识到，直到我们开始与演员合作，不同的层次，我知道层次在那里，但如何感知——如何拍摄它，如何感知图像，以及如何指导演员.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But the thing about it was that in a way, after “Departed,” it was like I knew I could not make films for the studios anymore, because at that time—there&#39;s no ill will between us and the people who were at the studio at the time—but, even to this day, they wanted a franchise film, and I killed off the two guys. They wanted one to live. I didn&#39;t want to make films that way. And I realized there was no way I could continue making films. And so everything since then has been independent to a certain extent since “Shutter.” The guy who took care of me was [the Paramount Pictures CEO] Brad Grey. He came in, Brad gave me “Departed,” and he agreed on “Shutter.” And so then he passed away. And, since then, it&#39;s really been independent. There&#39;s no room for me to make films through the studios that way anymore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Well, that&#39;s been my hypothesis: that an entire generation of younger filmmakers found their second wind with independent producers, whether it&#39;s Wes Anderson or Sofia Coppola or Spike Lee.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Yeah.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;But, from your generation, you are the person who—the studio was holding you back in a certain sense. Not that you made bad films, you made wonderful films. But I kind of always felt there&#39;s more. There&#39;s a—not compromise—but there&#39;s a wall that a filmmaker hits, any filmmaker hits when they&#39;re working for the big studios.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There&#39;s no doubt. And my thing was to explore that. And in some cases—in the case of “Last Temptation of Christ,” I had a deal at Universal. I owed them some movies; that became “Cape Fear” and “Casino,” and that was it. But by the time we did “Kundun” and “Bringing Out the Dead,” it was over. It was over. We were declared gone, “Bringing Out the Dead” only played for a few weeks. And it was a Paramount film. And that was the end. And again, [my agent, Michael] Ovitz came and kind of helped me and put together “Gangs of New York” with Leo, with [Harvey] Weinstein, and all of them. That became a whole other period of my life. I was glad when it was over, but I was obsessed with “Gangs.” I never really even finished it in my head. And I just said, OK, this obsession is over with. I still haven&#39;t, at that point, hadn&#39;t cracked the script for “Silence.” So I was ready to do a &lt;em>;movie&lt;/em>;. I wanted to work and make a film, and they had this thing called “The Aviator.” They didn&#39;t tell me what it was about. And so I started reading it, don&#39;t tell me it&#39;s Howard Hughes, because Spielberg, Warren Beatty want to do—but then I kept reading it. It&#39;s the different Howard Hughes, it&#39;s the early Howard Hughes. He flies and he&#39;s—but right here, in the meantime, he can&#39;t touch a doorknob.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;8q76ti&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;llltjm&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;That&#39;s interesting. So we did that. And, even that, that was fine. That was a terrific shoot. The editing was good, but the elements involved in the distribution caused some serious problems toward the end. I had some very, very ugly—and I decided at that point, you can&#39;t make films anymore. If this is the way I&#39;m going to have to make them, it&#39;s over. And so I said, I wanted to make this. I found the script of “The Departed” and I liked the idea and I said, “Let&#39;s just make this in the streets and let&#39;s do something.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But that became—it turns out it was Warner Bros., which was one of the distributors of “Aviator” that we had some arguments with. And they said, “Don&#39;t worry, we&#39;ll take care of you.” But, in the meantime, it was difficult. And so, after that I said, “No more.” And so we went into “Shutter Island,” but I was able to make “Departed” pretty much the way I wanted to. But it was a knockdown, drag-out fight all the way from Day One to the end. So by that point I realized, if that&#39;s the way you&#39;re going to make a film, there&#39;s no sense anymore. So it was going to be independent films and it was going to be going into “Silence” and that sort of thing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;So did you think you were going to scale back and work on very low budgets with seven people in the street?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes. Yes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Are you still tempted?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I think, let me put it this way, it&#39;s into my head. Seven people could be seventy, but it&#39;s got to &lt;em>;feel&lt;/em>; like seven, because, quite honestly, I&#39;m short. I&#39;m old now. Try to get in the room with the lighting and all the cable. I have to have an assistant in front of me, taking me. I would love to be able to have the freedom of the smaller crews again, a sense of freedom. But in the case of “The Irishman,” for example, out of the question, because of the trucks, because of the CGI, and Bob [De Niro] and me, I was seventy-five. Bob was seventy-five, Al [Pacino] was seventy-seven, Joe [Pesci], I don&#39;t know what age he is. I mean, at a certain point, by the time we all get on set, they&#39;re good for a certain amount of hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And if you want to say, “Hey, we&#39;re going to go down the block and shoot another scene, we&#39;re going to move all the trucks,” they need sleep. So we were kind of locked in there. But with “Killers of the Flower Moon,” by having Pawhuska to ourselves, that was quite something. Adam Sumner&#39;s a brilliant assistant director. He works with Steven Spielberg and Ridley Scott. His staging is wonderful, and the background stuff—I would say, “OK, they&#39;re going to be coming down the block here, we&#39;re going to track this way,” and, of course, it&#39;s 1921. So the background, costumes, horses, you need people doing things. It&#39;s not like shooting in New York, but we had the control. It was like a studio. We had the control. And that, in a funny way, made it feel like we were making a smaller picture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And we had such devotion from the Osage, from all the people working behind the camera to get the costumes right. I chose them. You could see it with [the costume designer] Jackie West. I sent black-and-white pictures everywhere, and drawings. I would circle a tie or a collar or a shoe. They would bring me stuff from the Osage and I&#39;d circle certain things. They&#39;d tell me what&#39;s right and what&#39;s wrong for certain. But, primarily, I mean buttons. I would go on—every place in the film, all the men&#39;s and women&#39;s costumes had gone through me, through to Jackie, from historical photographs and from films like “The Winning of Barbara Worth,” which I saw one night. My wife was in the hospital, it was on TV on TCM. And I think Gary Cooper&#39;s wearing the goggles in the car. It&#39;s a silent film. And so we had the goggles. Or “Blood on the Moon,” which I looked at again last night because I want to do something on TCM with it. “Blood on the Moon,” the costuming there and the brooding nature of the way they move. And Robert Mitchum, Charles McGraw, Robert Preston. Very, very important influence for this picture. So it felt free, and maybe in a way, too, because we weren&#39;t in LA, we weren&#39;t in New York. There wasn&#39;t anywhere to go. You&#39;re in a big house that I had rented and you go and make the movie, you&#39;re not going to Tulsa; you have night life in Tulsa. I was in Bartlesville, where Terry Malick grew up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;So you&#39;re all focussed together and there&#39;s essentially nothing to think about but the movie.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The picture. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;58t3h&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 18:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A Journalist Exposes the Philippines’ Extralegal Killings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/a-journalist-exposes-the-philippines-extralegal-killings]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65297bbd0a152c346bc003ab/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/remnick-patricia%20evangelista.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Over the years, I&#39;ve had the honor of reading and publishing reporters who are as resilient as they are intelligent: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/katherine-boo&quot;>;Katherine Boo&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/jon-lee-anderson&quot;>;Jon Lee Anderson&lt;/a>;—I won&#39;t go on because the list is as long as it is distinguished. It is a cliché to compare such writers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2009/04/13/a-fine-rage&quot;>;George Orwell&lt;/a>; or, more lately, with justice, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/letter-from-the-uk/a-memorial-for-the-remarkable-martha-gellhorn&quot;>;Martha Gellhorn&lt;/a>;. But, if the shoe fits . 。 。 Recently, a Filipina reporter named Patricia Evangelista came by the office, for an interview for &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://link.chtbl.com/qOucM248&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://link.chtbl.com/qOucM248&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://link.chtbl.com/qOucM248&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The New Yorker Radio Hour&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Our topic was her new book, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Some-People-Need-Killing-Country/dp/0593133137/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1BEU0AZ5JNE3C&amp;amp;keywords=some+people+need+killing+patricia+evangelista&amp;amp;qid=1697206966&amp;amp;sprefix=some+people+need+k%2Caps%2C122&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Some-People-Need-Killing-Country/dp/0593133137/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1BEU0AZ5JNE3C&amp;amp;keywords=some+people+need+killing+patricia+evangelista&amp;amp;qid=1697206966&amp;amp;sprefix=some+people+need+k%2Caps%2C122&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Some-People-Need-Killing-Country/dp/0593133137/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1BEU0AZ5JNE3C&amp;amp;keywords=some+people+need+killing+patricia+evangelista&amp;amp;qid=1697206966&amp;amp;sprefix=some+people+need+k%2Caps%2C122&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Some People Need Killing&lt;/a>;,” about the reign of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/11/21/when-a-populist-demagogue-takes-power&quot;>;Rodrigo Duterte&lt;/a>;. It is hardly written with Orwellian cool, but it stands next to “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Homage-Catalonia-George-Orwell/dp/0156421178&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Homage-Catalonia-George-Orwell/dp/0156421178&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Homage-Catalonia-George-Orwell/dp/0156421178&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Homage to Catalonia&lt;/a>;.” Evangelista&#39;s title comes from a vigilante, whose offhand comment to her exemplified the bloodiness of the Duterte Presidency and its extralegal drug wars. Evangelista covered the killings, which left thousands dead, for the independent news platform &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/dispatch/the-triumph-of-marcos-dynasty-disinformation-is-a-warning-to-the-us&quot;>;Rappler&lt;/a>;. The site was co-founded by the journalist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/the-new-yorker-radio-hour/the-nobel-prize-winner-maria-ressa-on-the-turmoil-at-facebook&quot;>;Maria Ressa&lt;/a>;, who, along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/how-russias-nobel-winning-newspaper-is-covering-ukraine&quot;>;Dmitry Muratov&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/the-nobel-peace-prize-acknowledges-a-dangerous-era-for-journalists&quot;>;won the Nobel Peace Prize&lt;/a>; two years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ressa would surely be the first to say that there would have been no Nobel, and very little truth in the Duterte era, were it not for the meticulous reporting of Evangelista and others like her. Evangelista was on the street every night, surveying the horror, examining the corpses, talking to the grieving families, and prodding the police. She wrote news pieces, and she wrote longer investigations. Now, in “Some People Need Killing,” she has written a journalistic masterpiece. She is a very rare talent; our conversation below was blunt—“Can I curse?”—and open. It has been edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Your book is one of the most remarkable pieces of narrative nonfiction I have read in a long, long time. But let&#39;s start with you: you were a staff writer at a newspaper in the Philippines that has a reputation for intense independence, and rare independence. Tell me how your career started.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, I&#39;ve been a trauma journalist for more than a decade. That means I go to places where people die. I pack my bags, I interview the survivors, I file my stories. And then I go home, to wait for the next catastrophe. I don&#39;t wait very long.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;For most of the time I spent as an investigative reporter for Rappler, I covered disasters, I covered massacres. I covered the aftermath of internal conflict. And, in 2016, a man named Rodrigo Duterte ran for the Presidency of the Philippines.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;He ran on a platform of death, and that&#39;s not an exaggeration. He promised that the fish would feed fat on the corpses of criminals. He said morticians would grow rich with a deluge of dead. He said that if your neighbor&#39;s child is an addict, to kill them yourselves. It would be a kindness to their parents.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Duterte won.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;There&#39;s not a country I can think of without a drug-addiction problem, without a drug-trafficking problem. What was Duterte running against, and why?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, when he ran, things were generally stable, so to speak. So it was necessary to create a spectre that he could run against. The Philippines has a drug problem, as most countries do, but comparative studies will demonstrate that we have less than half the global average when it comes to drug use.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But that wasn&#39;t the picture Duterte painted. He painted a picture of drug dealers leaving the country in shambles. He said that every drug addict was schizophrenic, hallucinatory. That he will rape your mother and butcher your father, and, if he can&#39;t find a child to rape, he&#39;ll rape a goat. And he said, if you don&#39;t believe it, if you don&#39;t believe how terrible they are, that he would give you drugs himself. Feed them to your children, and watch them become monsters.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;He was elected in 2016.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Not a good year for democracy.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Not quite.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;How would you compare Duterte to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/donald-trump&quot;>;Donald Trump&lt;/a>;? Or would you?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, certainly they make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/trumps-bloody-campaign-promises&quot;>;promises&lt;/a>;. But there are charismatic men all over the world who will make promises, who will say outrageous things, and people will laugh, and they will draw crowds. And sometimes it&#39;s funny.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Then they say more terrible things. Kill the drug addicts. And people will find that maybe a little acceptable, because they make life terrible. And then later they&#39;ll say, Kill the activists, and then kill the journalists, and then kill whoever it is. So are they similar men? Certainly in that they like the outrageous, and they like the applause, and they know how to entertain a crowd.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Perhaps one of the differences is that Duterte keeps his promises. Not all of them—he didn&#39;t end drugs in the Philippines, or criminality, or corruption; but he said, “Kill them all,” and people died.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;This is a quote, “Kill them all,” and it resounds through your book like a ghostly chorus. You used the phrase “drug pusher” in the book, but this phrase includes a number of people, including drug users.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes. In Filipino, Duterte calls them “&lt;em>;durugistas&lt;/em>;,” meaning drug dealers, drug users, junkies. Sometimes, he even refers to people who want to protect individuals who are castigated for using drugs that way. So, it can be any sort of association.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Now tell me about Rappler, the publication you were writing for. Maria Ressa is the famous editor of it, co-winner of the Nobel Prize. Tell me about how you started working on the Duterte regime&#39;s brutality, what your daily life was like, and what kind of danger you were in day to day.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What was good about working for Rappler was that there was no editor who said, “Step back, it&#39;s dangerous.” Maria was something like a lightning rod. When the government was angry, they directed the anger at her. Those of us in the field had the freedom to cover what we needed to cover. We were small-staffed. We had very few resources. We had two cars.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Two cars.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Two cars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;How many people on the staff?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Reporters? Fewer than twenty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Tiny.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Tiny. And, to answer your question, about why I started covering the drug war: we saw it coming. Early on, I was doing analysis for Rappler, looking at the narratives that the Presidential candidates were using to sell themselves. The final story I wrote before the election was called “The Rapture of Rodrigo Duterte.”And I thought I went terribly purple on that piece. The final line was: “The streets will run red if Rodrigo Duterte is elected.” And I regretted that line, because I thought it was too dramatic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And then I was standing by the side of a road, and there was a body on the ground, and I stepped over the gutter, and the blood ran red over my boots. And then I understood. And the only way I could survive that on a daily basis was that, at the height of the drug war, when there were corpses every night, was to—&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;rnno1&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;e4om6h&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;On the streets of Manila.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;On the streets of Manila. The night shift, a group of very talented photographers and writers from everywhere, would go body to body, crime scene to crime scene. And, at the height of the killings, when there were so many, I would ask the same questions every night: Was it a body dump? Was it a salvaging? Was it by a bus? Was it a drive-by? Was the killer—&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Police reporting.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Police reporting, essentially. Was the killer a cop, or a vigilante? Were the hands bound? Was the head wrapped in tape? Was the body stuffed in a bag? Was there a gun on the ground? That sort of thing. And then you learn to develop a better checklist, so you don&#39;t miss anything.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And then—and this is the new thing—and then you learn to stand still and listen for the screaming. That&#39;s how you find out who the family is. And then you go up to them, you apologize, you console, you keep your voice low. You ask simple questions. What was his name? When did you last see him? How did you know he was gone?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Mostly what I asked was, Tell me a story. Tell me your story. And then tell me what happened next. And the methodology was important to me, because it kept me on the scene in my mind, and I would test it every time. If I could close my eyes and see the room or the highway, or the alley, in three hundred and sixty degrees—know where the bullet came in, how the light pitched through the window if there was a window, know that the bikini briefs were red-and-white polka dots—then it meant I could go home, and it could live in my head, and I could tell the story again.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What&#39;s the effect on you, to do this night after night after night?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;[&lt;em>;Long pause.&lt;/em>;] I knew this question was coming; I still don&#39;t have an answer. Usually the question people ask is, How do you survive it? And I have a pretty good answer for that. It&#39;s caffeine, nicotine, and alcohol. But that&#39;s the throwaway line.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Yeah, that&#39;s the glib version.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;That&#39;s the glib version. The not-so-glib version is that it is very hard to keep my universe in place, in that I appear to be a functioning member of society. When I was filing stories, I was delivering the word count. But you pay for it. You pay for what you do.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And I think the best explanation was something some war correspondent said before: you&#39;re not a camera, in that you take all of this in. I take all of this in, and I live with it every day; every story, every interview I never publish, lives in my head. They play back at three in the morning. And then every phone call from an unknown number, I think, Someone&#39;s going to tell me someone&#39;s dead, and it&#39;s because of something I wrote. And you can&#39;t explain why the nightmares play out the way they do. And you can&#39;t explain why sometimes you just sit there, and then your brain goes in a loop, and the loop doesn&#39;t stop. So to get that book out—I&#39;m hoping the loop may stop for a little bit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You think the writing of it may in some way end your nightmares, and purge them.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No. I made a mistake. I thought if I took a break from the night reporting and wrote a book, that maybe that was a safer place for my head.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Or it may have just clarified the stories.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It clarifies the stories. And maybe it was good, because I didn&#39;t intend to write this book in the first person. This was meant to be a reportorial book, third person—here are the dead, here is what happened, here is who&#39;s responsible. But I came to understand, through the writing process, that I had to take accountability. This whole dramatic “I am an objective reporter, I write in the third person”—that&#39;s not a moral high ground. That&#39;s a failure of nerve.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Because I can tell you the worst of all of this: It&#39;s that I go to cover a story, and there&#39;s your blood on the ground, and there&#39;s all of that. And I&#39;m used to that. It&#39;s the aftermath, of going to Starbucks and getting a cappuccino. It&#39;s that I can &lt;em>;go&lt;/em>; to Starbucks and get a cappuccino. And I know, two blocks down, some family can&#39;t even afford the coffin to bury the kid in. But you have to divide your brain, because if you help one family it means you bought the story. And I feel like I&#39;m making moral judgments every step of the way. And, if I stray out of the way just one bit, I won&#39;t have control.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And this is why I&#39;m terribly inarticulate about all of this. I try not to think about it, and I hang on by my fingertips.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You wrote these stories again, and again, and again, as did your colleagues. And yet the drug war, to use Duterte&#39;s phrase for it—this kind of murderous, extralegal, ongoing assault—was popular.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Describe the popularity of it and why.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What Rodrigo Duterte did was he told a story. And he started with language—and I know that I promised not to deploy profanity during your interview. But I find it very odd to sit in a polite setting, expected to be polite—&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;w2s977&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Don&#39;t be.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Speaking about the man who decided to break language. A large part of the fact-checking of the book was about discovering the nuances—of when he said “&lt;em>;putang ina&lt;/em>;,” in Filipino, did he mean “motherfucker” or “son of a bitch”? So he liked—&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;This was on national broadcast?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;This is a national broadcast. And, generally, regardless of which culture you&#39;re from, a public figure, a politician, a head of state, is not expected to deploy profanity in public speeches. And he said, Fuck that. He said Barack Obama was a son of a bitch. He said the Pope was a son of a bitch. Many people, many institutions, were sons of bitches. The European Union, the United States, journalists, the United Nations, activists, drug dealers, everyone.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;And he, like Donald Trump, discovered that that had enormous connective appeal.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Precisely. And he said many things that other Presidents never said before. He said he would kill a hundred thousand criminals when he was elected. He said he wanted to rape an Australian missionary, except he couldn&#39;t, because she was dead by the time he showed up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;He said—I believe he wanted to be the first one there.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes. He said journalists are legitimate targets of assassination. He said he killed cops. He killed kidnappers. He killed—&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;He himself, he personally—?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;He himself. He used that language. And then he would say, Sometimes, I only killed three. Or three hundred. Or a thousand. It doesn&#39;t matter. Because listen to the language: I killed, I shot, I saved, I ordered. I. I, Rodrigo Duterte. So it&#39;s that sort of mythology that exploded. Rodrigo Duterte, the one who will save us all.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What did you learn about your fellow Philippine citizens? What did you learn in reporting about your country?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I learned that, inasmuch as Duterte made himself the everyman, it meant every man could be Duterte if they wanted. Duterte may have provided the language. He provided the vernacular, he provided the narrative—but we wanted it, too. We decided that some people didn&#39;t deserve to live.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You write these stories. What effect did this have on the populace, on the country as a whole?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I hesitate to use the word “trauma,” because I&#39;m told that this is a word that is overused in general. But we&#39;re a traumatized nation, and the trouble is, in the aftermath, after six years of Duterte, we elected the son of another dictator. And we elected Duterte&#39;s daughter. So it&#39;s the dictator&#39;s son with the punisher&#39;s daughter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Bongbong.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Bongbong Marcos. And there&#39;s no accountability there. There&#39;s no reckoning. If you don&#39;t know there are wounds, you can&#39;t fix things. So there are many children and many generations of people who will continue to believe that some people—because of some failure of virtue or some sickness or some whatever any politician says—some people do not deserve to live.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;How many people were killed? What do we know about the numbers?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I can&#39;t give you any numbers because we don&#39;t know for sure. The highest estimate is up to maybe thirty thousand. What I can tell you is that the police admit to having killed at least six thousand. And it&#39;s not like the police wandered around executing people and saying, OK, you&#39;re next on the kill list. There is a narrative, a performance of regularity behind it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What do you mean?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In that, when Duterte said, I will kill you all, I will destroy you, he never said murder them. He said, you can kill legally because they might fight back. They will fight back. And that was the loop of the narrative. They are drug addicts; therefore, they are armed. Because they are drug addicts, they will fight back. And, if they fight back, they must die.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Now, how long has it been since you left the Philippines?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A few months, give or take. It was recommended that it was in my best interests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What does that mean?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It means we don&#39;t know the risk of my having released this book. There was a security assessment, and the assessment was, Get the fuck out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;And do you think you&#39;ll go back?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes, absolutely. When I&#39;ll go back is not certain, but I have to go back. It&#39;s not moral patriotism or anything—that&#39;s my home. And the story is ongoing. It&#39;s not over. People are still dying on the streets. Journalists have been shot in Manila. And there are many other stories that have to be told about my country. I am a field reporter; that&#39;s where I belong. And I&#39;m also formerly Catholic—I own the guilt. How can I sit in New York when the people whose stories I told—who took the risk to tell me their stories—are sitting in shanties across the country, and might be at risk because of things they told me?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;In the book, you describe yourself as “a citizen of a nation I cannot recognize as my own.” Do you still feel that way?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes, but in a more nuanced fashion. I am Filipino; I take accountability for the choices we made. We voted for Duterte. I may not have, but that&#39;s under my watch as well. But I refuse to believe that this is the only possibility for my country. I don&#39;t think this is the only future possible for us.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Do I believe that journalism is the way forward?我不知道。 Because I have learned after many years to negotiate my expectations as a journalist. If I believed my stories saved lives, or changed things, I would&#39;ve stopped working. I wouldn&#39;t have been able to get up in the morning. Now all I believe is that my job is to keep a record, and that&#39;s it. And if someday that record is necessary, then it&#39;s out there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You don&#39;t think your stories change anything?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No. No. Maybe—I don&#39;t know. But I can&#39;t believe they do, because, if I expect that, I will be like the rest of my country: expecting, and hopeful, and not getting anything, and breaking down in the aftermath.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;If journalism doesn&#39;t save the world—and it doesn&#39;t; we both know that—I would like to have honored the people who risked their lives to tell their stories. They didn&#39;t have to talk to me, and they did. They are living examples of what happens when autocrats and dictators rise, and we let them. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ouhee2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 18:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Monthly Baby-Milestone Pics That Aren’t Total B.S.]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/monthly-baby-milestone-pics-that-arent-total-bs]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/baby2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two parents looking hesitantly at their crying newborn.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby1.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_120,c_limit/baby1.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_240,c_limit/baby1.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_320,c_limit/baby1.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_640,c_limit/baby1.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_960,c_limit/baby1.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby1.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby1.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Birth/Zero Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Hello, world! Your first breath took ours away . 。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Toddler crying and baby swaddled and sleeping.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby2.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_120,c_limit/baby2.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_240,c_limit/baby2.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_320,c_limit/baby2.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_640,c_limit/baby2.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_960,c_limit/baby2.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby2.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby2.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;One Month&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;We&#39;re all in love!&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mother lying on couch with baby after breastfeeding.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby3.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_120,c_limit/baby3.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_240,c_limit/baby3.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_320,c_limit/baby3.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_640,c_limit/baby3.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_960,c_limit/baby3.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby3.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby3.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Two Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Breast-feeding is bliss—plus, it&#39;s free!&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mother sleeping on floor and baby in seat watching Sex and the City on TV.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby4.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_120,c_limit/baby4.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_240,c_limit/baby4.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_320,c_limit/baby4.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_640,c_limit/baby4.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_960,c_limit/baby4.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby4.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby4.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Three Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Cute AND curious?!?&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Toddler sister holding baby by her head.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby5.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_120,c_limit/baby5.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_240,c_limit/baby5.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_320,c_limit/baby5.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_640,c_limit/baby5.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_960,c_limit/baby5.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby5.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby5.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Four Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Proud big sis.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baby sitting in soiled diaper.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby6.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_120,c_limit/baby6.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_240,c_limit/baby6.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_320,c_limit/baby6.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_640,c_limit/baby6.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_960,c_limit/baby6.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby6.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby6.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Five Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Such a huge miracle in such a small person!&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mother breastfeeding and on a Zoom call.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby7.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_120,c_limit/baby7.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_240,c_limit/baby7.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_320,c_limit/baby7.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_640,c_limit/baby7.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_960,c_limit/baby7.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby7.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby7.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Six Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;#momboss #leanin #haveitall&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baby opening up Christmas presents.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby8.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_120,c_limit/baby8.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_240,c_limit/baby8.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_320,c_limit/baby8.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_640,c_limit/baby8.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_960,c_limit/baby8.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby8.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby8.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Seven Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;A child&#39;s smile is worth more than all the money in the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman dressed up as Cruella de Vil and baby dressed as a dalmatian.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby9.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_120,c_limit/baby9.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_240,c_limit/baby9.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_320,c_limit/baby9.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_640,c_limit/baby9.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_960,c_limit/baby9.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby9.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby9.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Eight Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Happiness is the laughter of children.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baby crying in carseat.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby10.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_120,c_limit/baby10.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_240,c_limit/baby10.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_320,c_limit/baby10.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_640,c_limit/baby10.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_960,c_limit/baby10.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby10.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby10.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Nine Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Twinkle, twinkle, little star, do you know how loved you are?&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baby crying in stroller.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby11.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_120,c_limit/baby11.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_240,c_limit/baby11.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_320,c_limit/baby11.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_640,c_limit/baby11.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_960,c_limit/baby11.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby11.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby11.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Ten Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;If you&#39;re happy and you know it, clap your hands!&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Closeup of baby&amp;#x27;s dirty face.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby12.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_120,c_limit/baby12.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_240,c_limit/baby12.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_320,c_limit/baby12.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_640,c_limit/baby12.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_960,c_limit/baby12.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby12.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby12.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Eleven Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;All of God&#39;s grace in one tiny face.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A party hat birthday card teddy bear and ball.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby13.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_120,c_limit/baby13.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_240,c_limit/baby13.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_320,c_limit/baby13.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_640,c_limit/baby13.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_960,c_limit/baby13.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby13.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby13.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;ONE YEAR!&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Mommy went on a work trip and Daddy forgot about the picture thing.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 18:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Louise Glück, Remembered by Writers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/louise-gluck-remembered-by-writers]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T00:45:15.242Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652d944836878a543204e2e3/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Glu%CC%88ck-Final-Photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;Louise Glück, who contributed poems to The New Yorker for half a century, died on Friday. We&#39;ve gathered reflections on her life and work from writers and poets who knew, read, and studied with Glück.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In the fall of 2005, I signed up to take Louise Glück&#39;s writing workshop. At our small liberal-arts college, Professor Glück cut an intimidating figure. My classmates and I knew it was a privilege to be in her company. The Nobel was still more than a decade off, but she had won awards, big ones, we were vaguely aware. More important, she was a practicing poet. Was it tedious for her to be in our company? The class was called Introduction to Poetry, and there were no prerequisites for entry. Most of us did not know what poetry was and mistook curlicues, flourishes, and acrobatic metaphors for the apex of the form. Which is to say, we were children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And yet, Professor Glück refused to treat us like children. The fact was made manifest during the first weeks of class, when she said that a few lines of what I believed to be stylish verse were “inert.” I had thought I knew what the word meant, but I had never heard it used with such visceral aversion. It wasn&#39;t until years later, when I read her essay “Education of a Poet,” in which she describes “the fundamental experience of the writer” as “helplessness,” that I realized her reaction to inertness on the page arose out of her own helplessness to respond otherwise.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Write anything you want, she told us. Just make sure it&#39;s not dead. Every class, Glück chose a poem from our submissions to read and analyze aloud. A few weeks in, a poem of mine was chosen. I don&#39;t remember much of the poem, except that it was about a mother and a daughter and the swollen feelings that could not be expressed between them. A few things about the poem stood out to Glück. One, the line “peeling porch swing, creaking weakly” was a mistake; it was too much, and creaking with too much desperation to “sound like poetry.” That line aside, though, she had found the “sparse” quality of the poem&#39;s language appealing. It was the first thing of mine she&#39;d ever read.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Glück gave us assignments on a weekly basis. Always, I kept my poems simple because the simplicity of my “poetic form” seemed to keep them in Glück&#39;s favor. One of the poems she even called “accomplished,” seemingly unaware that its sparseness was not a stylistic choice as much as the consequence of a lack of experience.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;For our last student-teacher conference, Professor Glück called me into her office. The last poem I turned in didn&#39;t work, she told me frankly. For this final assignment, I had been determined to demonstrate that I could write something that was emphatically un-sparse. And so I had spent a considerable amount of time imitating the style of a famous twentieth-century poet whose baroque lines I did not understand and therefore found worthy of imitation. In front of Professor Glück, I now looked at the page I had submitted. She hadn&#39;t even bothered marking it up because, as she put it, “There&#39;s not much there.” As she said those words, a liquid shame poured over me. It was over. I had been found out, not only for my mediocrity but for my perverse deception.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;She must have said other things, but I didn&#39;t hear them. My ears perked up only at what I understood to be consolation. Some of my earlier poems were good, she said. They were “not quite there but came very close.” Close to what? I dared not ask. Then the most perplexing thing in my short writing life happened. “When you write more, you can send them to me over the holiday break,” she said. On a notepad, she wrote down her address and tore it off for me. She couldn&#39;t possibly be paid to read student poems after she had handed in all the grades, was my first thought. The second thing that struck me was her certainty that I would write more poems despite the disastrous effort of the most recent one.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I never sent her any poems. But, for a long time, that scrap of paper on which she wrote her address was the most precious thing I owned. Years passed, and gradually I did begin to write, not poems but small reflections that spun into longer essays about my mother, childhood, and feelings that could not be easily expressed, as it turned out, in any form.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;My time in Glück&#39;s class did not mark the beginning of my life as a writer. It hardly marked the start of my conception of what it meant to be one. But it initiated my belief that the aspiration to be one was a struggle in which I could claim agency. It would be my choice whether to continue to write, and embracing that choice was what made a writer, as much as the quality of the writing itself. “Not quite there” is still how I feel when I read back my own words on the page. It is a struggle every time, with words that start slow and leaden, and, if I am assiduous and patient, acquire something approximating life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The ambition to create is indistinguishable from the fear, verging sometimes on conviction, that you can never do so. Glück&#39;s genius as a poet was reflected in her keen understanding that the craft returns us all to childhood, helpless and desperate for mastery. Her equally remarkable generosity as a teacher meant that she could never be less than honest with students about the reality of this process. A writer&#39;s life is dignified “by yearning,” she believed, “not made serene by sensations of achievement.” Write anything you want, just make sure it&#39;s not dead, she told us, knowing that we would most certainly write things that were dead—but that it was up to us where we went from there. —&lt;em>;Jiayang Fan&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Though I&#39;m not entirely sure where I first read Louise Glück—I believe it was her poem “Mock Orange,” in the “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Morrow-Anthology-Younger-American-Poets/dp/0688034500&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Morrow-Anthology-Younger-American-Poets/dp/0688034500&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Morrow-Anthology-Younger-American-Poets/dp/0688034500&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Morrow Anthology of Younger American Poets&lt;/a>;,” in which she&#39;s pictured, defiant, wearing a headband—I know for certain where I first came to love her work, which was when I found a copy of her début book, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Firstborn-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/0912946938&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Firstborn-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/0912946938&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Firstborn-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/0912946938&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Firstborn&lt;/a>;.” Though she eventually came to be less appreciative of this early poetry, for me it was a window into what only deepens in her later work—that is, family, loss, and myth. Later still, artistic-but-not-poet friends of mine sang the praises of the stark language in Glück&#39;s books “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ararat-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/088001248X&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ararat-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/088001248X&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ararat-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/088001248X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Ararat&lt;/a>;” and “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wild-Iris-Louise-Gluck/dp/0880013346&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wild-Iris-Louise-Gluck/dp/0880013346&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wild-Iris-Louise-Gluck/dp/0880013346&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The Wild Iris&lt;/a>;”; I came to that work newly hearing the rich emotion they had heard in its ornate plainness. I still had my father then, not for long enough, and Glück&#39;s books were waiting for me once I lost him, nineteen years ago—her poem “Vespers” I especially saw as a useful field guide to grief. “You permit me / use of earth,” Glück writes, ending, “I am responsible / for these vines.” I would include it in “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Art-Losing-Poems-Grief-Healing/dp/1608194663&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Art-Losing-Poems-Grief-Healing/dp/1608194663&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Art-Losing-Poems-Grief-Healing/dp/1608194663&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The Art of Losing&lt;/a>;,” a book of elegies that I edited.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I didn&#39;t know then that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://archives.newyorker.com/newyorker/1991-11-04/flipbook/068/&quot;>;Vespers&lt;/a>;” had first appeared in &lt;em>;The New Yorker&lt;/em>;, nor could I have guessed that I would get the chance to edit, which is to say, include, her poems in the magazine. The poems she sent arrived typed up and via snail mail; she didn&#39;t care for e-mail, or any number of modern things, but that was only part of the charm. Her poems were indeed missives from another world, and we were always eager to have them in hand. The day she won the Nobel Prize, nonplussed about the honor—“I was unprepared,” she said—we had recently taken her poem “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/10/19/song&quot;>;Song&lt;/a>;,” which ran in the magazine a few days later. It was the culmination of more than fifty years of appearing in &lt;em>;The New Yorker&#39;s&lt;/em>; pages. While we mourn her dying, and seemingly so suddenly, her work, like the vines in “Vespers,” remains renewed and renewing. As she says in “Song”: “And I say then I&#39;m glad I dream / the fire is still alive.” —&lt;em>;Kevin Young&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;During my freshman year, Louise taught me to revise. It was perhaps the hardest lesson to learn in a year of hard lessons in and out of the classroom. After my first submission, I wept upon reading, in her distinctive half-print, half-cursive scrawl, “hopelessly conventional” on my poem. At last, I thought, I have reached my limits as a writer; I am mediocre and must learn to bear it. Later, Louise and I laughed about this whirlpool of teen-age feeling. We shared a tendency toward melodrama, and an awareness of this tendency, and thus a suspicion of it, and a weary amusement when confronted yet again with the inability to excise it. (It was also from her that I learned how to laugh at habitual faults without tolerating them.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Sometimes she would circle a line and name it the only “alive” thing in a whole poem. Sometimes she would say, “There&#39;s something here, but it&#39;s not on the page yet.” I think her excitement about the possibility of a poem that was alive in every particular helped me keep trying. I remember the trying, which was excruciating and slow, because writing and revising are often excruciating and slow, as alchemical transformation. I remember sitting on my extra-long twin bed in my dorm room, typing and—this is how I remember it—all at once understanding how to reimagine, not simply reword.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In her approach to my work, and to her own—in book after book, an effort at reinvention within the boundaries that must be resisted even as they are laid out, unavoidably, by the self—she showed me the kind of dedication that writing requires: a fidelity to the making of the best thing that one can make.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I realized as I was writing this that, in teaching me to revise, Louise also taught me to suffer the loss of language. Though it&#39;s frightening because words are so hard-won (from the world, from the self), much must be discarded to truly create. Writing demands a ruthless love. I am a less fearful rewriter because of her, but I don&#39;t know how I will bear the loss of &lt;em>;her&lt;/em>;, even with all the language she&#39;s left behind. —&lt;em>;Elisa Gonzalez&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Of course she would die on Friday the 13th in October. It rivals being the daughter of one of the men who created the X-Acto knife. We fear profaning the absence she left behind, and so we are all dumbly quoting her, intuiting that only her poetry can rise to the occasion of her death. The truth is that any kind of writing is hard—something is so rarely preferable to nothing. Professor Glück, instead of pretending to forget this, distilled it down, and to read her work is to stand unprotected against the difficulty not just of writing but of bearing the knowledge that is worth being written. The words in her poems are like divining rods wiggling above an icy stream. You can only hold them for so long. When I was in school and she was briefly my professor, her office sat at the very top of the English building. You had to climb four flights of stairs, and then her door was unmarked at the end of a long hall. Most of us were terrified to meet with her, even though she was unfailingly kind. What I remember is a small round table; you&#39;d sit across from her and she&#39;d pore over your fanned-out pages with a stubby pencil in hand. My poems rarely got her going, but there&#39;s one, now, that still feels charged with the dark quality of her attention. When I read it, I can feel her eyes staring back at me. —&lt;em>;Katy Waldman&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Louise Glück once said to me that she thought American poets were extremely cautious in their opinions of one another socially, but promiscuous privately. She thought this was a formula that should be reversed. We were on the telephone, discussing her essay “American Narcissism,” which had recently appeared in &lt;em>;The Threepenny Review&lt;/em>;. Louise had just begun to write again, after a two-and-a-half-year hiatus, so she was understandably happy. This meant that she would be able to make poems in the new life she was constructing for herself in Cambridge, Massachusetts, after living for many years in Vermont. I had already known that long silences were a painful, inexplicable part of her writing life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A few weeks later, when I drove up the dead-end street where Louise lived, she was waiting at the foot of her front steps, wearing all black and carrying a small purse over her shoulder. Her hair was freshly washed. We were going out to dinner, but she wanted first to show me her apartment and garden, which I had never seen, and I took this as a sign that the seeds of friendship were being planted. Louise lived on the second floor of a triple-decker, and her little book-lined study was in an alcove at the front, in the treetops. The apartment was freshly painted white and scarcely furnished. On the mantle, a collection of Japanese netsuke was displayed. Her bedroom was at the back, overlooking the garden, and the linens on the bed were white, like much of the apartment. At the foot of the bed were two stuffed animals, anteaters or armadillos, which Louise told me were especially beloved because they could be microwaved and used as heating pads.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In the back yard, she had planted a large horseshoe-shaped garden, and many of its contents had come from her old garden in Vermont. There were pale-pink tea roses, dark-maroon peonies, and a small, mesh-covered lettuce plot. She told me there would soon be Casablanca lilies blooming, remembering I had written a poem about them. Then we drove to Inman Square, where Louise had reserved her usual table at a neighborhood restaurant. To start, we each drank a glass of California chardonnay, and Louise intermittently splashed seltzer in hers. For dinner, she ordered a bowl of mussels, with extra broth, garlic, and parsley, then an arugula salad, without pears, walnuts, or blue cheese; I ordered a sirloin steak with dandelion salad, and when our meals arrived we shared between us a second glass of chardonnay.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Louise told me that writing her most recent book, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Seven-Ages-Louise-Gluck/dp/0060933496&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Seven-Ages-Louise-Gluck/dp/0060933496&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Seven-Ages-Louise-Gluck/dp/0060933496&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The Seven Ages&lt;/a>;,” had been like “flying,” and she recounted the story of a friend, a classicist from Williamstown, who&#39;d had a dream in which Louise appeared. Louise, her friend, and her friend&#39;s husband were on the rooftop of a high building, and Louise told them they must all jump, because if they did they would not be hurt. So they jumped, and all of them experienced nirvana. The last poem in Louise&#39;s book, entitled “Fable,” reconfigures this dream as Louise and a lover:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;Then I looked down and saw&lt;br/>;the world I was entering, that would be my home.&lt;br/>;And I turned to my companion, and I said &lt;em>;Where are we?&lt;/em>;&lt;br/>;And he replied &lt;em>;Nirvana.&lt;/em>;&lt;br/>;And I said again &lt;em>;But the light will give us no peace.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;We talked about solitude, and Louise admitted that three days alone were too much. As our conversation grew intimate, she sat sideways in her chair, folding her slender leg up on it like a bird or a teen-ager. A sensualist, she wiped the salad dressing and juices from her plates with her index finger and unself-consciously licked it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I told Louise I thought her new long poem “October,” which had recently appeared in &lt;em>;The New Yorker&lt;/em>;, was magnificent, and she was pleased. It is a lyric sequence in six parts, and she explained how the first two were written first but the third, whose final lines I love, was written last:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;Come to me,&lt;/em>; said the world. I was standing&lt;br/>;in my wool coat at a kind of bright portal—&lt;br/>;I can finally say&lt;br/>;&lt;em>;long ago:&lt;/em>; it gives me considerable pleasure. Beauty&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;the healer, the teacher—&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;death cannot harm me&lt;br/>;more than you have harmed me,&lt;br/>;my beloved life.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;“The rest was stitched together like scraps from a quilt,” she told me, adding that it was conceived, in part, as a response to her recovery from whiplash. I said I believed the body&#39;s impulse was toward healing and that I&#39;d learned this watching my own body recover from a bicycling accident in which I was thrown a great distance and lay unconscious in a hospital bed for many hours. But Louise argued instead that the body&#39;s impulse was toward collapse and decay.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;We talked about the need to transcend Eros in one&#39;s work and discussed when this occurs in a career. We talked about contemporary tastes in American poetry and agreed that the Zeitgeist was shifting but what the future held was unknown. When I showed her two different jacket designs for my new collection “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Middle-Earth-Poems-Henri-Cole/dp/0374529280&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Middle-Earth-Poems-Henri-Cole/dp/0374529280&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Middle-Earth-Poems-Henri-Cole/dp/0374529280&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Middle Earth&lt;/a>;,” after holding each close to her face in the dim light, she said she favored the more austere version. Then she excused herself and went to wash her hands.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Awaiting her return, I thought about the pristine whiteness of Louise&#39;s apartment. In her bathroom, the white tub, white toilet, white pedestal sink, white tiles, white floor, white cabinets, and white trash bin were brightly lit and offset by a large bevel-edged oval mirror with shiny chrome brackets. I imagined Louise lying in that white tub, like a figure in a Bonnard painting, surveying her body, floating in dream or thought or both. No truth would escape her there. Her home reminded me of Japanese teahouses I&#39;d visited in the foothills around Kyoto, where there is a high value placed on austerity and rustic simplicity. Her poems could be said to be influenced by this aesthetic, in which beauty is always imperfect, impermanent, or incomplete, and in which only three simple realities are acknowledged: nothing lasts, nothing is finished, and nothing is perfect. This Japanese aesthetic brings about within us a serene melancholy or spiritual longing, as Louise&#39;s poems sometimes do for me—with their simple vocabulary, dramatic juxtapositions, subtle pacing, and sentiments of desolation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When Louise returned to the table, she asked about my love life, and I answered truthfully. Louise always listened carefully and reflected a moment before replying. She said she thought a writer had to be tough to survive. She said she tried to teach her students to be ambitious. She said she is always listening for the solitary voice in lament.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Louise called her mother every day to “check in.” Her mother was ninety-five, and that morning, when Louise had reported she&#39;d been to the orthodontist, her mother had replied, “That&#39;s marvellous, darling.” The television was loud in the background, and her mother had plainly misunderstood. She thought Louise had said she&#39;d been to the “orchid-eater.” Louise was delighted and wanted to tell me because I was from the “lush South, where you might really have such things as orchid-eaters.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Once, at a public reading, I heard Louise say that in her Pulitzer Prize-winning collection, “The Wild Iris,” the figure of God, when he speaks, sounds remarkably like her mother, though she&#39;d never told her mother this. When I told Louise how my mother had French expressions she frequently used when I was a boy—like “&lt;em>;mon&lt;/em>; &lt;em>;derrière&lt;/em>;” (“my ass”) and “&lt;em>;minute, papillon&lt;/em>;” (“slow down, hold your horses”)—Louise said her parents had little phrases, too, in Japanese and French, that they used to call the family to meals, etc. She hated them.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;89kke&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;41b2r&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;After dinner, in the car driving home, Louise and I talked about writing during periods of happiness and love—which she believed was possible. Louise described a time long before, when she lived in Vermont and felt profound happiness in her marriage and was also able to write. I told her I believed love was our highest vocation and that I hoped I wouldn&#39;t die without experiencing it. At her front door, we embraced. The next morning, she was flying to Washington, where there would be a gathering of young poets whom Louise would introduce.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“They&#39;ll be like young eaglets watching one another,” she said, slamming the car door shut. —&lt;em>;Henri Cole&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A few years ago, I was chatting with an actress friend—an acquaintance, really—and, toward the end of our conversation, I asked the usual question: Was she working? Any scripts out there that were worth her time? Actually, the woman said, she had been cast in a small ensemble piece, one in which she was meant to play with and against the fabled K; it was a TV flick written by Z, an author whose work we both admired. But, I countered, could she, an intuitive, internal performer, really perform with K? Although K had been fascinating in a number of projects, I said, I had never been able to locate her wound—a feeling my actress friend understood at once. Being a consummate artist, she knew that a wound was essential to a creative inner life, that the hurt she&#39;d experienced had contributed to her understanding of how other people lived and suffered and survived. While K&#39;s relative healthiness might serve her well in life, I said, it wasn&#39;t the best thing for art, or, at least, for the kind of art that I was interested in, which conveyed something of what it felt like to stand in the rain outside the house of the family of man.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When I first heard of Louise Glück&#39;s death, I thought of that conversation, which sounded, in memory, like a poem that only Louise Glück could write—she who knew how to write about that kind of creative alchemy, how to experience it. Alchemy was one of her great subjects, as was getting at the truth of character, of the soul, through the wounded self. In her 2009 poem “Bats,” Glück writes, “There are two kinds of vision: / the seeing of things, which belongs / to the science of optics, versus / the seeing beyond things, which / results from deprivation.” If we are fat with life, the writer suggests, how can we see beyond our satiation? In her electric and spartan work, Glück concentrates, too, on the white space surrounding a poem, how the light of that whiteness makes her words incandescent, beyond our reach even as we try to read them, dream them, sing them. A Glück poem can sound like the most intimate, constructive conversation you&#39;ve ever had with a friend who is smarter than you, her intelligence a gift, her words a form of charity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I came to Glück rather late in her career, and, when I did, I didn&#39;t “like” her writing. It didn&#39;t feel like “poetry” to me—romantic, “wild”—but, rather, like lines that one would find stitched into “apocalyptic wallpaper” by the visual artist Elaine Reichek. Indeed, I thought some of the poems would resonate more—for me, at least—as visual objects. Something to hang on a wall and study from a distance—the distance I felt in Glück&#39;s verse. But when I read her final volume, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Winter-Recipes-Collective-Louise-Gl%C3%BCck/dp/037460410X&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Winter-Recipes-Collective-Louise-Gl%C3%BCck/dp/037460410X&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Winter-Recipes-Collective-Louise-Gl%C3%BCck/dp/037460410X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Winter Recipes from the Collective&lt;/a>;” (2021), I started to understand why Glück used relatively simple language to get at the heart of things: to earn her poems&#39; endings. She didn&#39;t seem to be interested in finishing a poem in order to let it go; rather, she wanted to work her way toward the &lt;em>;sound&lt;/em>; of a conclusion, that village church bell announcing the end of one day and the beginning of another. Glück&#39;s poem “Night Thoughts,” in “Winter Recipes,” for instance, takes us on a journey of inquiry about the self:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;Long ago I was born.&lt;br/>;There is no one alive anymore&lt;br/>;who remembers me as a baby.&lt;br/>;Was I a good baby? A&lt;br/>;bad? Except in my head&lt;br/>;that debate is now&lt;br/>;silenced forever.&lt;br/>;What constitutes&lt;br/>;a bad baby, I wondered. Colic&lt;br/>;my mother said, which meant&lt;br/>;it cried a lot.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;Of course, the “it” is and isn&#39;t Glück: she may have had colic, but there are many other colicky babies, too, a world of babies. At the close of the poem, though, Glück becomes an “I,” a baby unto herself:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;What a shame I became&lt;br/>;verbal, with no connection&lt;br/>;to that memory. My mother&#39;s love!&lt;br/>;All too soon I emerged&lt;br/>;my true self,&lt;br/>;robust but sour,&lt;br/>;like an alarm clock.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;To be robust but sour, like an alarm clock, is to make a fretful noise. And, when I first read this poem, I not only heard the clock; I felt the humor in Glück&#39;s description of a body and mind that grew and grew past being “mothered.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I knew little about Glück&#39;s life when I started reading her work seriously. In any case, I never gravitate to poets&#39; biographies at first: the sound and meter of who they are—what makes up their soul—is there in the work, along with their wounds. As it happens, Glück, who benefitted from psychoanalysis, doesn&#39;t hide from straight-up autobiography, particularly in her philosophical prose. And even though she was considered a confessional poet, along the lines of Robert Lowell and Sylvia Plath, early in her career, I have to say that part of what I grew to love about her writing was how much she was hiding in plain sight within it. It is very difficult to find the metaphors that ring true about a life, but Glück achieved that again and again. Before Glück&#39;s birth, there was an older sister, but she died, leaving Glück bereft before she even knew what that meant; for her whole life she lived with a ghost that her poet self could not let go. And it is that haunting that we see and feel in Glück&#39;s extraordinary 1975 work “Gretel in Darkness,” which goes, in part:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;This is the world we wanted.&lt;br/>;All who would have seen us dead&lt;br/>;are dead. I hear the witch&#39;s cry&lt;br/>;break in the moonlight through a sheet&lt;br/>;of sugar: God rewards.&lt;br/>;Her tongue shrivels into gas. 。 。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;No one remembers. Even you, my brother,&lt;br/>;summer afternoons you look at me though&lt;br/>;you meant to leave,&lt;br/>;as though it never happened.&lt;br/>;But I killed for you. I see armed firs,&lt;br/>;the spires of that gleaming kiln come back, come back&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;Nights I turn to you to hold me&lt;br/>;but you are not there.&lt;br/>;Am I alone? Spies&lt;br/>;hiss in the stillness, Hansel,&lt;br/>;we are there still and it is real, real,&lt;br/>;that black forest and the fire in earnest.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;To turn to someone who is not there is to know something about both deprivation and hope. When Glück wishes for something that is not there, how can she will it to be present? Through words and their failures. From her 1989 lecture “The Education of the Poet”:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;The fundamental experience of the writer is helplessness. This does not mean to distinguish writing from being alive: it means to correct the fantasy that creative work is an ongoing record of the triumph of volition, that the writer is someone who has the good luck to be able to do what he or she wishes to do: to confidently and regularly imprint his being on a sheet of paper. But writing is not decanting of personality. And most writers spend much of their time in various kinds of torment: wanting to write, being unable to write; wanting to write differently, being unable to write differently. 。 。 。 [The writer&#39;s life] is dignified, I think by yearning, not made serene by sensations of achievement.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ik095q&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;In other words, writing heals nothing: it only reopens a wound as you try—in vain—to dress it. Writers are not nature; we do not regenerate and grow again. But we can rise, crooked and beautiful, as we try to describe what nature does to us, which is one of the themes of Glück&#39;s 1992 collection “The Wild Iris.” In that book, Glück gives the wounded and wounding earth—and all that grows in it—a voice. From “Daisies”:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;. 。 。 It is&lt;br/>;not modern enough, the sound the wind makes&lt;br/>;stirring a meadow of daisies: the mind&lt;br/>;cannot shine following it. And the mind&lt;br/>;wants to shine, plainly, as&lt;br/>;machines shine, and not&lt;br/>;grow deep, as, for example, roots. It is very touching,&lt;br/>;all the same, to see you cautiously&lt;br/>;approaching the meadow&#39;s border in early morning&lt;br/>;when no one could possibly&lt;br/>;be watching you.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;Sometimes, while reading Glück, I am reminded of this comment by Diane Arbus, to whose photographs of the real and imagined self Glück&#39;s poems—or, more precisely, her ethos as an artist—can sometimes bear an uncanny resemblance. Describing the experience of taking photographs at a nudist camp in New Jersey, Arbus recalled:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;I mean there&#39;d be an empty pop bottle or a rust bobby pin—the lake bottom oozes mud in a particularly nasty way and the outhouse smells, the woods look mangy. It gets to seem as if way back in the Garden of Eden after the Fall, Adam and Eve had begged the Lord to forgive them and He, in His boundless exasperation, had said, “All right, then. Stay. Stay in the Garden. Get civilized. Procreate. Muck it up.” And they did.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;In her poems, Glück describes how the landscape we&#39;ve mucked up is just another manifestation of our loneliness, and how we try to fill that loneliness with some spiritual value beyond ourselves. Can that spirit hear us? Or is it too late? The earth in “The Wild Iris” also helps the poet reckon with death, with how the life we&#39;re given is the life that must be taken away, in order for the world to blossom (if it can). In “Heaven and Earth,” Glück writes:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;Where one finishes, the other begins. 。 。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;The extremes are easy. Only&lt;br/>;the middle is a puzzle. Midsummer—&lt;br/>;everything is possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;Meaning: never again will life end.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;Never will imagery like Glück&#39;s end. It will last as long as death still grows in the moist and not holy earth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;—&lt;em>;Hilton Als&lt;/em>; ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;dm652f&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 09:06:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New High-Stakes Dating Shows You Won’t Want to Miss]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/new-high-stakes-dating-shows-you-wont-want-to-miss]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T21:11:54.376Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6529cd6fea7c98fc2f5ea20f/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Shouts-Dating-Shows-1016-23.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;If you never skip an episode of “Love Island” but feel like the contestants don&#39;t have enough to lose, or if you wish the cash prize on “Too Hot to Handle” required a little more risk-taking to win, then you&#39;ll love our new lineup of high-stakes dating shows! Coming soon to a streaming service near you.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Heart to Heart”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Hot young singles looking for love and a heart transplant arrive on an island, ready to party. But there&#39;s a catch! The winner gets a new heart only if they find their soulmate. Everyone else goes home empty-handed. Good luck, young paramours!&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Billionaire Beach”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Ten bachelors and ten bachelorettes live on a beach together.收获是什么？ One of the bachelors is a billionaire, and &lt;em>;everyone&#39;s&lt;/em>; trying to end up with him. The other catch? The billionaire decides to retreat to his own separate, private beach. They never see him again. Also, they all have to pay for this “vacation.” The billionaire does not.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Love Is BlA.I.nd”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Single men and women go on virtual dates and look for love online with the goal of getting engaged before ever meeting in person. The twist: all but one of them is an artificial-intelligence chatbot. Get ready for one lonely human to meet their soulmate . 。 。 and then grapple with the fact that they&#39;re not even real.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Pension Peninsula”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Two dozen auto workers spend a month living together at a beautiful resort. The only rule? No touching! If one of them even pecks another one on the cheek, they all lose their pensions. (They are not told about the one rule.)&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Tropical Treason”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Fit, fun hotties from all over the world get dropped off in the tropics. Each of them is given a sealed envelope they can open and read aloud only once—to the person they believe to be their one true love! Unfortunately, each card contains one of their nation&#39;s most highly guarded secrets. In the finale, they are all tried for treason.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Archenemy Archipelago”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;People who have hated one another for their entire lives are stranded on a group of unclaimed islands. There are no laws. Whoever makes it to the end of the season can leave the show and try to find a love that&#39;s as powerful as the connection they felt with the one person they despise most in this world.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“A Date with Debt-stiny”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;A group of thirtysomethings are paired with people they believe to be their scientifically proven soulmates. But they&#39;re in for a surprise—those soulmates are also their debt collectors.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“You and Who?”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;You&#39;re on this show now. Yes, you. The one reading this. You&#39;re being filmed and your life is being broadcast all around the world. You have two weeks to fall in love. We won&#39;t stop watching you until you&#39;ve done so. Have fun! ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;This is drawn from“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/This-Wont-Help-Proposals-Apocalypse/dp/1615199993&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/This-Wont-Help-Proposals-Apocalypse/dp/1615199993&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/This-Wont-Help-Proposals-Apocalypse/dp/1615199993&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;This Won&#39;t Help: Modest Proposals for a More Enjoyable Apocalypse&lt;/a>;.”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;1pq3m5&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;phvgbr&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 07:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nanci Griffith’s Lone Star State of Mind]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/listening-booth/nanci-griffiths-lone-star-state-of-mind]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T20:47:58.509Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652996db55cb8e4a802ed65e/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/syme-nanci%20griffith.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The Texas-born singer-songwriter Nanci Griffith&#39;s voice is an “acquired taste,” as one critic put it after Griffith&#39;s death two years ago, at the age of sixty-eight. To me, Griffith&#39;s idiosyncratic sound—coquettishly girlish, aggressively dulcet, almost lamblike in its high, warbly register—is as comforting as a home-cooked meal, but that is likely because I acquired a taste for Griffith&#39;s singing before I knew that it was a niche pleasure. My mother played me Nanci Griffith records from the time I was born; Griffith was and still is her favorite singer, and so by inheritance she became one of mine. Some of my earliest auditory memories are of listening to Griffith&#39;s records on road trips—an experience I have since come to find is quite common among older millennials who grew up in the South or in the West. Griffith&#39;s songs—mostly tender, romantic ditties about drive-in movies and dime-store novels—were broadly appealing but seemed to have a special hold on a certain kind of suburban Boomer mom in the nineteen-eighties and nineties who took solace in Griffith&#39;s high-femme cooing about loneliness, long drives, and lost love. When I spoke recently to Sarah Jarosz, a thirty-two-year-old singer-songwriter who appears on a new tribute record, “More Than a Whisper: Celebrating The Music of Nanci Griffith,” which was released on vinyl by Rounder Records, on October 13th, she told me that she, too, had come to Griffith&#39;s music during car trips with her parents. “It was before I could even really comprehend what the lyrics meant,” Jarosz said. “But the music was still coming through to me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The tribute album was originally conceived before Griffith&#39;s death, by the former Rounder Records president John P. Strohm. It now serves as a kind of musical memorial. Jarosz sings the first song on “More Than a Whisper”: a gentle folk cover of “You Can&#39;t Go Home Again,” a ballad off Griffith&#39;s second album, from 1982, “Poet in My Window.” Jarosz grew up in Wimberley, Texas, not far from Griffith&#39;s home town of Austin, and told me that, when selecting what song to cover from Griffith&#39;s deep catalogue of more than twenty records, she chose the track because of her parents&#39; affinity for it. Griffith named the song after a posthumous 1940 novel by Thomas Wolfe, one of her favorite writers, whom she regularly thanked in her liner notes. Knowing this, Jarosz&#39;s parents once brought a copy of the novel with them to a Nanci Griffith concert at the Cactus Cafe in Austin and implored the singer to sign it. Griffith inscribed it, “To Home Again, Nanci.” The book became a kind of family heirloom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One irony of this inscription—and of the nostalgic sense of place that Griffith&#39;s records capture—is that Griffith very rarely felt at home, either in Texas or in the music industry. Her longtime producer and collaborator, Jim Rooney, told me, on a recent phone call, “I think she felt chronically underappreciated.” When Griffith died on August 13, 2021, she was leading a reclusive life in Nashville, Tennessee. She had not recorded an album in more than nine years, and had not played a show in more than seven. Her management explained only that she had died of “natural causes,” and that Griffith herself had requested that no formal statement be issued until a week after her death. A week came and went, and no further statement ever appeared. Fans were left speculating. She had battled cancer twice, and had, by her own admission, struggled for years with a crippling depression that had sometimes led to, as she once told a reporter, “drinking, popping every kind of pill, doing anything that would bring me down off that wall.” She&#39;d spent her later life cultivating a fiercely guarded privacy and nursing a sense of alienation. “She had a very lonely streak in her,” Rooney said. “And it was not because other people didn&#39;t love her work.” He added, “That was the hardest thing for me to deal with in her later years–how that message didn&#39;t seem to come through to her.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Rooney produced three of the tracks that appear on “More Than a Whisper,” but he also found himself taking on a much larger-scale Griffith project shortly after her death. To his surprise, Griffith left him the masters for her first three records, along with the manuscript for an unpublished novel, “Two of a Kind Heart,” about a girl from Texas who leaves the state in search of adventure. In August, he self-published the book and, through Craft Records, released a beautiful new box-set reissue of Griffith&#39;s first four albums: “There&#39;s a Light Beyond These Woods” (1978), “Poet in My Window” (1982), “Once in a Very Blue Moon” (1985), and “The Last of the True Believers” (1986). In addition to overseeing a faithful remaster of the audio, Rooney, who originally produced “Blue Moon” and “True Believers,” put together a wide-ranging oral history of Griffith&#39;s early years to go along with the collection. Through a series of interviews, a young, optimistic, ambitious, collaborative, and gregarious Griffith emerges—though her dogged solitariness is also apparent from the beginning. Joy Lewallen, a woman who befriended Griffith shortly after the singer relocated from Austin to Houston in the late nineteen-seventies, with her husband at the time, the singer-songwriter Eric Taylor, remembered that Griffith would often sit for hours at a time at a table at Anderson Fair, a restaurant that became a central hub of the Houston folk scene, frequented by the likes of Townes Van Zandt and Lucinda Williams. “Nanci would be over in a corner, eating a plate of spaghetti and drinking a Shiner or a Lone Star, working on a song,” Lewallen recalled.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Rooney called the reissued box set “Working in Corners,” which is also the title of a song off Griffith&#39;s second album, released when Griffith was twenty-eight years old. He told me that he meant the title to be hopeful, a nod to the work ethic of a burgeoning artist. But he also said that, like Griffith&#39;s tune of the same name, it was tinged with melancholy. The song, perhaps my favorite she ever recorded, is a beautifully pared-down acoustic lament—just Griffith, and her guitar, and a voice that wobbles between ethereal sweetness and guttural strength. Griffith sings about being a working musician travelling alone, with glasses of whiskey and strangers as her only companions. It is the kind of misty-eyed number a musician plays at the very end of the night when the stragglers left at the bar are calling out for one more song. For me, it almost always elicits a good cry. My favorite verse is the last, in which Griffith sings, “These city streets at five in the mornin&#39; / I would&#39;ve stopped to phone you / But I&#39;m almost home.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;On paper, Griffith accomplished things that would have seemed hopelessly far-fetched when she first started singing in Austin coffeehouses at the age of twelve. She recorded her first album, on the indie label BF Deal, at the age of twenty-four, and signed with the major Nashville label MCA less than a decade later. She went on to win the Grammy for Best Contemporary Folk Album in 1994 for her covers record, “Other Voices, Other Rooms.” She recorded or performed songs with Emmylou Harris, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/postscript/john-prines-perfect-songs&quot;>;John Prine&lt;/a>;, Don McLean, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/03/28/retirement-the-margaritaville-way&quot;>;Jimmy Buffett&lt;/a>;, Arlo Guthrie, and even one of her childhood idols, the folksinger &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/how-odetta-revolutionized-folk-music&quot;>;Odetta&lt;/a>;. Still, Griffith often felt ill at ease with her position within the music industry. She said to one reporter that an MCA executive told her that “I would never be on radio because my voice hurt people&#39;s ears.” Though she was a bona-fide star in Ireland, where her 1987 version of Julie Gold&#39;s anthem “From a Distance” was a Top Ten hit, she sometimes expressed feeling overshadowed by other artists in the American music scene. Bette Midler ultimately made “From a Distance” a smash hit in the US Griffith allowed the up-and-coming country star Kathy Mattea to cover her song “Love at the Five and Dime.” The two versions came out in the same year; Griffith&#39;s original did not chart, whereas Mattea&#39;s went to No. 3. Griffith could be prickly with journalists. In 1998, she wrote a fuming open letter to several Texan newspapers, lambasting their critics for the general disdain she felt the Texas press had for her work. “I carry with me always the pride and the knowledge that great things have come from my native soil—very few ever return there,” she wrote in the letter, which was printed in both the Houston &lt;em>;Chronicle&lt;/em>; and the Austin &lt;em>;Chronicle&lt;/em>;. “Texas is, after all, the only place on earth that actually eats its young.” Griffith compared herself in the letter to the writer Katherine Anne Porter, who was born in Indian Creek, Texas, but spent most of her life bouncing among bohemian enclaves in places like Greenwich Village and Mexico and Europe. “She too,” Griffith wrote of Porter, “had the wisdom to get the hell out.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Part of what Griffith experienced was a problem of timing. Her offbeat, self-consciously artsy aesthetic—more Stevie Nicks than Tammy Wynette—could perhaps have made Griffith a viable pop star, but she moved to Nashville during a time that the musician Steve Earle has dubbed the “great credibility scare.” The era of the “urban cowboy” that had brought Willie Nelson and Merle Haggard to fame was over, and many of country&#39;s major stars—Kenny Rogers, Linda Ronstadt, and Alabama—were crossing over into the mainstream. Nashville executives, loathe to lose more artists to pop radio, rushed to sign a new class of grittier, harder-edged artists such as Earle, Lyle Lovett, kd lang, and Ricky Skaggs. Griffith was a gregarious member of the country-folk scene that forged many of these artists—she invited a young Lyle Lovett to perform onstage at Anderson Fair, after he interviewed her for his college newspaper—but her tenderhearted songs made her seem out of step with her harder-edged peers. She often posed for her album covers wearing floral sack dresses and bobby socks, either cradling or sitting next to one of her favorite books (Larry McMurtry&#39;s “Lonesome Dove,” Eudora Welty&#39;s “Delta Wedding”). She dedicated her albums to authors and artists with the zeal of a college freshman, thanking Carson McCullers and Truman Capote in her liner notes. On more than one of her albums, she tilts her giant doe eyes upward, as if she were trying not to cry. At MCA, she started out recording with the country department, but ultimately switched over to the pop division before exiting after five years. Both her record label and the critical establishment seemed unsure where to place her music. In a long piece for &lt;em>;Texas Monthly&lt;/em>;, Michael Hall wrote that some country music gatekeepers considered her a “greeting-card folkie” and a “faux naïf.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Griffith&#39;s sense of estrangement proved a generative subject for her art. After she and Taylor divorced in 1982, she never married again, did not have children, and, in her later years, for the most part, chose to live alone. In one of her most famous songs, “Late Night Grande Hotel,” off her 1991 album of the same title, Griffith sang about her purposeful loneliness with an almost swooning sense of attachment:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;And maybe you were thinkin&#39;&lt;br/>;That you thought you knew me well&lt;br/>;But no one ever knows the heart of anyone else&lt;br/>;I feel like Garbo in this late-night grande hotel&lt;br/>;Cause living alone is all I&#39;ve ever done well.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;Despite her air of cutesy innocence, Griffith wrote lyrics that suggest a depth of self-awareness. In one song, she sings, “You would never hold me / I don&amp;#x27;t like to be held.” Another goes, “The telephone is ringin&#39; in the middle of the night / And I pull the bed clothes higher / Will it stop calling out if I turn on the light? / I&#39;m afraid of these shadows here / &#39;Cuz my past is truly frightening.” Her breezy, gushy style could give the sadness of her lyrics a sneaky potency. Her catchiest song, “Listen to the Radio,” is all about a woman who drives away from her domestic life without looking back, set to a rollicking honky-tonk bass line. “When you can&#39;t find a friend,” she sings in the cheerful chorus, “you&#39;ve still got the radio.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In his 1999 article, Michael Hall suggested that her critics, citing her diaristic writing style, “see a phony in a genre beholden to authenticity.” What I see is an artist who was attempting to chronicle the inner lives of imaginative girls. The fact that she sang about burgeoning friendships and the magic of blue moons and getting lost in dime-store novels does not strike me not as phony but as bracingly ahead of its time. Griffith&#39;s lyrics might be understood as a precursor for Taylor Swift&#39;s diaristic songwriting. Swift&#39;s “I&#39;m Only Me When I&#39;m With You,” from her début 2009 album, in which she sings about lying underneath the stars with a close friend, has an antecedent in “There&#39;s a Light Beyond These Woods (Mary Margaret),” a haunting, autobiographical song off of Griffith&#39;s début record. On it, Griffith sings about her childhood best friend, with whom she grew up in Austin, fantasizing about becoming musicians and getting out of town. “Let&#39;s go to New York City, Margaret!” she sings. “We&#39;ll hide out in the subways / And drink the poets&#39; wine.” Then Margaret settles down with a husband and a family and Griffith must leave her behind:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;And what about the light that glowed beyond&lt;br/>;Our woods when we were ten?&lt;br/>;You were the rambler then.&lt;br/>;The fantasies we planned, well, Maggie,&lt;br/>;I&#39;m living them now.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;Sarah Jarosz told me that she almost considered picking “There&#39;s a Light Beyond These Woods (Mary Margaret)” for her contribution to the tribute album. “That song just rips my heart out,” she said. What tipped her toward “You Can&#39;t Go Home Again,” in addition to her prized book inscription, is that its chorus—“This ole town never did really care that much for me / I don&#39;t know why I always come here in my dreams”—echoed Jarosz&#39;s own conflicted feelings about moving from Texas to Nashville, and about being a woman trying to chart her own course through the industry. “Nanci is a great example of an artist who just couldn&#39;t be described, and couldn&#39;t be pigeonholed, and could be multiple things at once,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Between the reissued box set and the tribute album—which features both Griffith&#39;s peers, such as Lyle Lovett, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/iris-dements-new-album-is-a-sustained-political-statement&quot;>;Iris DeMent&lt;/a>;, and Emmylou Harris along with younger artists in the folk space, including Aaron Lee Tasjan and Molly Tuttle—we are in the midst of a Griffith renaissance. She did not live to see it, but she did get to hear one of the tribute songs before she died. In December, 2019, Jim Rooney went over to her house to play her a cover of “Love at the Five and Dime” that he had produced as a duet between John Prine and the rising Kentucky singer Kelsey Waldon. He visited Prine the same day, to play him the recording. It was the last time Rooney saw either artist. But he was heartened by the fact that Griffith, who could be a tough audience, seemed to like the new take on her old song. He told me that, as Prine and Waldon crooned the chorus, “Dance a little closer to me, dance a little closer now / Dance a little closer tonight,” a smile appeared across Griffith&#39;s face. “It seemed to me that Kelsey reminded her of herself,” Rooney said, “when she was young.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;n4rihe&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;xqckdb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 05:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A Russian Journalist’s Pained Love for Her Country]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/persons-of-interest/a-russian-journalists-pained-love-for-her-country]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T20:01:27.238Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652983c110114da26d9e58ae/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Yaffa_Elena.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;When Elena Kostyuchenko was five years old, in Yaroslavl, a provincial city a hundred and seventy miles from Moscow, the corner of the room that she shared with her mother was taken up by a television with a bulging screen and a fuzzy picture. Kostyuchenko was captivated. She brushed the dust off the picture with her fingers. “It felt like touching a moth&#39;s wings, ever-so-gently,” she writes in “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Love-Russia-Reporting-Lost-Country/dp/0593655265&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Love-Russia-Reporting-Lost-Country/dp/0593655265&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Love-Russia-Reporting-Lost-Country/dp/0593655265&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;I Love Russia&lt;/a>;,” a memoir and collection of reportage translated by Bela Shayevich and Ilona Yazhbin Chavasse and published this month. Later, as a teen-ager, Kostyuchenko discovered newspapers at the school library. “I got obsessed with them—the pictures didn&#39;t change, you could think while you read,” she writes. “I decided to go work at one.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The paper for which Kostyuchenko most dreamed of working was &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&lt;/em>;, where &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2009/03/23/the-accused&quot;>;Anna Politkovskaya&lt;/a>;, a fearless and revered reporter, filed dispatches telling the grim truth of the Russian war in Chechnya. Kostyuchenko describes the sensation of encountering Politkovskaya&#39;s articles. “I&#39;d feel like I was getting a fever,” she writes. “It turned out I didn&#39;t know anything about my country.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In 2005, Kostyuchenko started as an intern at &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&lt;/em>;, tiptoeing into Politkovskaya&#39;s office to leave apples on her desk. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/vladimir-putin&quot;>;Vladimir Putin&lt;/a>; was relatively new to the Presidency, and high oil prices were fuelling a consumer boom. But Kostyuchenko was less interested in the Russia hurtling forward than the one left behind, a place—or, rather, a people—defined by trauma and disorientation, but also hardiness and resolve.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;For one early piece, Kostyuchenko spent a night hanging out at a roadside brothel, “the Market,” observing how the sex workers and their customers squabbled, connived, ingratiated, treated—and mistreated—one another. For another, she wandered among the ruins of an unfinished hospital in Moscow&#39;s northern outskirts, which had become a mecca for misfit teen-agers and others who found themselves lost or cast aside. She describes one such itinerant, who arrives in search of a mystic encounter and instead gets his head shat on in an empty elevator shaft; he leaves in a huff, declaring, “The spirits have rejected me.” For Kostyuchenko, it was a familiar Russia, not sophisticated, moneyed, or powerful, but one that, as her book&#39;s title suggests, she loved—and still does.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“You know the kind of love you have for your hand, or for your leg,” Kostyuchenko told me recently in Berlin, where she moved last year. “Or for your home, or your family. It&#39;s a love that, above all, is connected to a sense of attachment, of belonging.” One should be both conscious and mature about this fact, she said. “You take responsibility for what belongs to you.” She went on, “I am connected to the people who live on this land by a common fate. Yes, this fate is not always happy, but yet it is ours, all of ours.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In Putin&#39;s Russia, muckraking journalism has become a difficult, underpaid, thankless, and oftentimes outright dangerous profession. In 2006, a little more than a year into Kostyuchenko&#39;s tenure at &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&lt;/em>;, Politkovskaya was shot dead in the elevator of her apartment building in Moscow. She is one of seven &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&lt;/em>; journalists who have been killed during the past two decades. Kostyuchenko describes her memorial picture being hung in the paper&#39;s conference room, alongside those of her murdered colleagues. “Every time a new portrait goes up, we try to hang it so that there is no more room on the wall,” she writes. “When you can&#39;t protect yourself or your people, you get superstitious.” But, she knows, “There is always room for one more.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Kostyuchenko is now thirty-six, and one of Russia&#39;s premier journalists; she carries herself with a subdued, almost ethereal bearing that belies a stubborn, even fierce, reportorial energy. She can feel anger, shame, disgust, but she doesn&#39;t feel as if she and the Russia she writes about are something apart. “I&#39;m Russian. I was born in Russia,” she writes. “My mother is Russian and so is my biological father. 。 。 。 My last name is Ukrainian, it was my mother&#39;s from her first marriage. Our family name is Malyshev. I have blue eyes and white skin, Slavic features. I braid my long hair. My native language is Russian, which I speak without any accent. I&#39;ve never felt like a foreigner in my country. I belong here.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The book, Kostyuchenko told me, is a personal reckoning, an attempt to work through how she missed—or, rather, failed to adequately react to—Russia&#39;s descent into fascism. That trajectory led to the invasion of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/ukraine&quot;>;Ukraine&lt;/a>; and a war that has dragged on for nearly two years, but in truth began much earlier. For Kostyuchenko, the clock started as she reached civic consciousness: that is, in the years when Putin was cementing his power and constructing an autocratic system that would eventually launch a war against its neighbor.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Kostyuchenko, who is gay, became involved in LGBT activism in her twenties. At the time, she writes, she thought that if she and her then girlfriend attended Pride parades in Moscow—which were officially banned—they would, over time, be able to calmly and convincingly argue for their rights. Instead, she was punched in the temple and her girlfriend was arrested. In 2013, when the Russian Duma passed a law banning the distribution of so-called “propaganda of nontraditional sexual relationships,” she stood in front of the Duma and, in an act of protest, kissed her girlfriend. Orthodox activists pelted them with eggs and feces. “The law was clear,” Kostyuchenko told me. “We are not socially equal. This is clearly a fascist formulation.” But, she said, “This was an unpleasant thought, and I didn&#39;t want to fully look in that direction.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In 2021, Kostyuchenko spent two weeks living inside a state-run residential facility for people with psychiatric and neurological disorders. The article that emerged from that experience is the masterwork at the heart of “I Love Russia,” a wrenching and visceral text that almost seems to waft off the page: industrial cleaning supplies; stale, watery soup; soiled bedsheets. Nurses roam the wards ready to inject anyone who causes any problems with a syringe full of tranquillizers. Walks outside, even just to the walled-in courtyard, are granted or withheld with similar caprice. Kostyuchenko has a searing encounter with two women, Alina and Vera, who had their pregnancies forcibly terminated and were then sterilized without consent. “How do I get out of this hell?” Vera asks.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Behind a metal door in Ward 3-A, which held the most difficult cases, Kostyuchenko encounters Tyoma, a thin, naked man with drool hanging from his lips, and buttocks bruised from repeated injections. When Kostyuchenko and a volunteer named Katya suggest taking him for brief strolls in the yard, the doctor in charge of Tyoma&#39;s case reacts with bemused skepticism. But, after a few days, the nurses in Ward 3-A are amazed that Tyoma has stopped ripping up and chewing pieces of the windowsill. “It turns out that, in Russia, we have concentration camps maintained at state expense,” she told me. “Our taxes go to keep people locked up like animals, deprived of their rights.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The care home, Kostyuchenko also realizes, is a particularly ghoulish manifestation of the larger Russia beyond its walls. “You are alone, face-to-face with the state,” she said, “and here it is, that is what it looks like, this is the state&#39;s true nature.” A paternalistic state presumes to know what&#39;s best for its charges, but its real concern is for its own authority and convenience. If that means delivering a shot of tranquillizer to the butt, so be it. Your best chance is only to avoid an even worse fate. “If you want to stay safe, you must put a smile on your face, or at the very least be neutral,” Kostyuchenko writes. “Indifferent, docile, to what they do to you and those around you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In hindsight, Kostyuchenko told me, “I knew there was fascism in my country and at the same time believed that if I did my job, if I described this fascism, that would somehow be enough. But it could never be enough.” Even as the life of an independent Russian journalist wasn&#39;t easy or glamorous, it had its own comforts and rituals and satisfactions. There were reporting trips and nights at the theatre and even later nights drinking with colleagues in someone&#39;s kitchen. “I liked my life, and didn&#39;t want to change it,” she said. For Kostyuchenko and others in her circle—nonprofit founders, experimental-theatre directors, bookshop or café owners—it could feel as if these “small crystalline worlds,” as she put it, would keep steadily expanding. And then one day these many small worlds would merge into one, and there would be no place left for Putin; this Russia wouldn&#39;t belong to him. But, she told me, “On February 24th”—the day of Russia&#39;s invasion—“these worlds shattered, they vanished.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Late the next evening, Kostyuchenko crossed into Ukraine, becoming one of an exceedingly small number of Russian journalists who managed to report from the war zone. (That is, from the perspective of those under attack—plenty of correspondents from state media were embedded with those Russian units doing the attacking.) She reported from Odesa and Kherson, then under Russian occupation. She sneaked in and out across the front lines; inside Kherson, she located the building where Russian troops brought local residents to be tortured. Her articles were published by &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&lt;/em>;, whose editor, Dmitry Muratov, was awarded the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/the-nobel-peace-prize-acknowledges-a-dangerous-era-for-journalists&quot;>;Nobel Prize in 2021&lt;/a>; on behalf of the paper; but, given Russia&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/how-putin-criminalized-journalism-in-russia&quot;>;wartime censorship&lt;/a>; laws, she and her editors excised certain words and passages, stating in brackets or italics that text had been removed. “We didn&#39;t want to hide this act of forced censorship but make it plain,” she told me. “Plus, in Russian, you can tell well enough what is missing.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Her dispatch from the southern city of Mykolaiv, which Russian forces shelled relentlessly in the early days of the war, appears in its original form as the book&#39;s last chapter. The writing is bracing, painful in its clinical documentation, laced with a sense of guilt and the utter futility of that guilt. Kostyuchenko visits the Mykolaiv morgue. “The bodies in the cold storage are stacked up in layers,” she writes. “Two girls lie one on top of the other. They are sisters. The older one is seventeen. All I can see in the heap of bodies is her hand, her slim, long fingers with neat pink nail polish. The younger girl is three years old and lies on top of her sister. She is blond. Her jaw has been tied shut with gauze, her hands tied together to rest on her stomach. Little red wounds from the shrapnel cover her body. The girl looks alive.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In late March, Kostyuchenko was on her way to Mariupol, then the site of the most prolonged and brutal siege of the war, when she got a call from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/how-russias-nobel-winning-newspaper-is-covering-ukraine&quot;>;Muratov&lt;/a>;, &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&#39;s&lt;/em>; editor in Moscow. He had information that pro-Kremlin Chechen militants had orders to intercept Kostyuchenko at a checkpoint and kill her. Muratov said she had to leave Ukraine immediately; at first, Kostyuchenko resisted. “An entire city was destroyed along with tens of thousands of its inhabitants,” Kostyuchenko said of Mariupol. “This is a war crime at an incredible scale, and must be documented and recorded.” But she relented, and made plans to flee Ukraine. The sudden inability to fulfill this task weighed on her more acutely than the threat against her life. “I couldn&#39;t come to terms with my own helplessness,” she wrote in an essay for Meduza, an independent Russian news site based in Riga.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Kostyuchenko never returned to Moscow. She began an enervating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/03/13/how-russian-journalists-in-exile-are-covering-the-war-in-ukraine&quot;>;exile&lt;/a>;—Venice, Prague, a village in Switzerland, a spell in the States—along with her girlfriend, Iana, a journalist and disability-rights activist. (They met when Iana showed up at &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&#39;s&lt;/em>; offices after Kostyuchenko published her article on care homes.) By then, &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&lt;/em>; was effectively shuttered. After multiple warnings from state regulators, and fearing criminal prosecution, its employees had voted to indefinitely suspend operations. Kostyuchenko disagreed with the decision but chose not to cast a vote—she was abroad, facing her own difficulties, but not those confronted by her colleagues who were still in Russia. “I didn&#39;t bear the risks of making a different decision,” she told me. “They did. And so I&#39;m not sure my opinion mattered much.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Kostyuchenko and Iana ultimately rented an apartment in Berlin. Kostyuchenko wanted to get back to work; in particular, she hoped to return to Ukraine, but that was no easy task, given that, after the invasion, Russian citizens needed approval, rarely granted, in order to enter the country. She travelled to the Ukrainian consulate in Munich to apply for a visa. On her way back to Berlin, she fell ill. The symptoms came in waves: stomach pain, nausea, swelling of her face, fingers, and toes. For two months, doctors had little clue what might be wrong with her. Finally, one of them suggested that she may have been poisoned. “It seemed too wild an idea,” she told a police detective. “I was in Europe. I felt that I was safe.” The detective answered harshly. “You come here and think you&#39;re on vacation,” he said. “We have political murders here. Russia&#39;s secret services are active in this country.” He chastised Kostyuchenko for what he said was a reckless and lackadaisical attitude to her own safety.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;eb4rhl&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;1at8de&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;She was admitted at Charité hospital in Berlin, where &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/alexey-navalny&quot;>;Alexey Navalny&lt;/a>; was treated after his poisoning in 2020. The prosecutor&#39;s office closed the investigation, then reopened it, but she hasn&#39;t heard anything further. When the Insider, an independent Russian site that often covers the security services, briefed a number of doctors and chemists on Kostyuchenko&#39;s case, all said her symptoms “cannot be explained by anything other than exogenous poisoning.” They named an organochlorine compound as the likely poison, and suggested it was ingested or absorbed through the skin.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;German police told Kostyuchenko to keep an unpredictable schedule, to move regularly, and to avoid repeating her routes or destinations. She and Iana moved out of their Berlin apartment and headed to a residency program in a remote, bucolic stretch of northern Scandinavia. From there, they began shuttling between friends&#39; houses and apartments in Europe. This fall, they plan to visit the US for Kostyuchenko&#39;s book launch. She recalled one of her early scares at &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&lt;/em>;, when she was investigating a ring of Moscow gangsters and corrupt police officers that killed people so as to steal and then sell their expensive cars. Kostyuchenko was followed, and someone tried to break into her apartment; some of the officers showed up at the paper&#39;s offices and made threats. She told me what a sympathetic police investigator had relayed to her: “If they are set on killing you, they will kill you. You can make this process longer and more costly for them. But it is impossible to guarantee your safety.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The alleged poisoning is an awkward subject for Kostyuchenko. She tries not to dwell on the inherent danger of her work. “There are various professions that carry a potential risk to your life,” she told me. “Police, rescue services, excuse me for the example, military.” That&#39;s just the nature of the job, she said. “It turns out that, in Russia, journalism is one of them. It doesn&#39;t make it more or less important. Of course, it&#39;s unfortunate to work in these conditions, but I&#39;ve been doing it for a very long time.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The more difficult thing, Kostyuchenko told me, is being separated from Russia. As the war drags on, and Russia continues to inflict suffering on Ukrainians and repress its own citizens, she has found it harder to maintain or profess her love for her country. Kostyuchenko doesn&#39;t subscribe to the illusion that her country is somehow trapped by Putin alone. “He is a symptom, let&#39;s say, the personification of all our shit,” she told me. “But he&#39;s not the root of all troubles.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Not long ago, in one of their regular phone calls, Muratov—who remains based in Moscow—offered a metaphor that Kostyuchenko found compelling. Putin and other top Kremlin officials, he told her, present themselves like priests who purport to mediate a believer&#39;s relationship to God. That is, they act as intermediaries in how Russians feel love, or anything at all, toward their country. “The state stands between us and our love for our country,” she told me, explaining the idea, “and tells us what is right, how we should feel, what we are obligated to do.” In her work, Kostyuchenko has tried, perhaps futilely, to challenge this idea. “Love does not require silence,” she told me. “It doesn&#39;t require lying. It doesn&#39;t require murder.” Rather, she said, love is an “active feeling.” She explained, “You see Russia&#39;s many shortcomings and name them. You try to stop the evil it commits, correct what you can, mourn what you can&#39;t, and find some purpose in this sorrow.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;dvgxfc&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“Taylor Swift: The Eras Tour” is Intimate, Colossal, and Slightly Disappointing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/taylor-swift-the-eras-tour-is-intimate-colossal-and-slightly-disappointing]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T20:02:30.418Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652d4cfca2dd76a04bfbc885/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Brody-Eras-Tour.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Like most people, I know some of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/taylor-swift&quot;>;Taylor Swift&lt;/a>;&#39;s songs by the mere fact of being alive, but it&#39;s one thing to hear music and another to listen to it. The prime virtue of her concert film, “Taylor Swift: The Eras Tour”—shot last August, during three performances at SoFi Stadium, in Inglewood, California—is to concentrate one&#39;s attention on her music, for two and three-quarter hours, as if in a listening booth. What it reveals about her artistry only heightens my appreciation for the substance and the imagination that goes into the making—indeed, the being—of this pop superstar. The concerts are megaspectacles, simultaneously intimate and colossal; Swift commands the stadium throughout, amid large-scale stage business. She&#39;s often alone, sometimes joined by a handful of dancers, occasionally backed by a brigade of them, as huge video screens and stage sets serve as elaborate backdrops adorned by light shows and smoke effects. (As for the band, it&#39;s kept far away, in a paddock of its own.) The film of this show puts her songwriting in the foreground, as if her music were a movie script, brought to dramatic life by her performance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There are film directors who manage to turn big-budget studio movies into personal works, and, as I watched, I felt that Swift commandeers the mighty mechanism of celebrity in a similar way. The concept of the concert is autobiographical: Swift looks back at her career, album by album, each of which she ascribes to a different “era” in her life and each of which constitutes a segment of the show. She writes in the first person, with telling detail and candor, but also locks into a mythology of modern American young womanhood in a manner that lends narrative richness to her self-portraiture: young romance and boyfriends, friends and frenemies, school and neighborhood and family. The songs reflect a headlong desire to live the passions of the moment fully and deeply, an awareness of the barriers to this posed by the conventions of daily life, and a sense of pushing past these by sheer force of emotion toward hard-won self-knowledge. Swift is a melodramatist in the best sense, finding heroic grandeur in ordinary lives and circumstances, conceiving her experiences as a form of naturalistic legend in which her audience, of girls and young women, find their own experiences taken seriously, as they deserve to be. The “Eras” concept notwithstanding, Swift&#39;s songs are curiously detached from their times: in expanding the specifics of her life to a quasi-universality, she filters out cultural specifics, as if inviting listeners to fill in the blanks with their personal set of references.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I found myself thinking of the romantic melodramas of Douglas Sirk, such as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/movie-of-the-week-written-on-the-wind&quot;>;Written on the Wind&lt;/a>;,” and this notion was reinforced by Swift&#39;s performance of “the last great american dynasty,” a song from her album “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/taylor-swifts-new-album-folklore&quot;>;folklore&lt;/a>;,” in which she tells the story of the late socialite and arts patron Rebekah Harkness (whose Rhode Island mansion Swift bought in 2013). While she sings the song—about a “middle-class divorcée” who marries the heir to an industrial fortune and becomes the focus of scandal—she&#39;s accompanied not just by dancers but also by an actress who portrays Harkness clad in a glamorous fifties-style gown and elbow-length gloves. This number, a sort of impressionistic refraction of a glossy classic-era Hollywood romance, is the high point of the movie&#39;s staging, though not its most inventive sequence. (There is more immediately eye-catching allure to the staging of some songs early on, in front of a huge, abstractly geometrical cutaway diorama-like house, reminiscent of Jerry Lewis&#39;s “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/dvd-of-the-week-the-ladies-man&quot;>;The Ladies Man&lt;/a>;”—and of the &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://images.app.goo.gl/xcLCZNqR4a8Lq5zr8&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://images.app.goo.gl/xcLCZNqR4a8Lq5zr8&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://images.app.goo.gl/xcLCZNqR4a8Lq5zr8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Hollywood Squares&lt;/a>;.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The tour&#39;s concept—the “eras” of Swift&#39;s career—could easily seem self-aggrandizing, but it doesn&#39;t come off this way because of a core of authentic experience that it delivers. Swift has grown up in public, and her fans&#39; fervent response to each new facet of her work corresponds to the major life changes (inner and outer) that accompany her artistic development. (Let no one who contemplates John Coltrane&#39;s or Franz Schubert&#39;s year-by-year musical self-transformations cast the first stone.) The movie shows Swift&#39;s performance to be both artful and modest; she displays prodigious talent but not intimidating virtuosity. Though her dancing is adroit, she conveys far more with her theatrical repertoire of striding, gesturing, and glancing. Her singing is strong but not operatic, expressive but not flamboyant, perched at the border of a conversational or confessional tone. In effect, it&#39;s a voice made to fit the lyrics—neither overwhelming nor underwhelming, an intensification and distillation of what&#39;s extraordinary in ordinary life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In short, the fascination of Swift&#39;s performance is personal. That&#39;s why the movie ultimately falls short of her aesthetic. Concert movies are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/13/movies/taylor-swift-eras-tour-concert-film.html&quot;>;rarely straightforward documentaries&lt;/a>;; rather, they generally build an image track to go along with a music track, somewhat like a music video, with the celebratory and promotional aspects to the fore. But this movie (directed by Sam Wrench) hardly adds another level of experience to the performances, because its visual composition, moment to moment, is burdened by convention and complacency. This doesn&#39;t get in the way of the music, but it disregards the authenticity of Swift&#39;s presence, the physical side of her performance.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;What&#39;s missing from the film is both a sense of proximity and a sense of time. “The Eras Tour” offers very few screen-filling closeups of Swift, and they go by in a flash. Indeed, the movie is almost entirely made up of very short shots, whether Swift is singing in motion while striding across the stage or in place when accompanying herself on guitar or piano, introducing songs with spoken commentary. The decision to film and edit the movie that way comes off as no mere concession to short attention spans and impatience with stasis. Short shots, chez Wrench or Sergei Eisenstein or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/ridley-scott&quot;>;Ridley Scott&lt;/a>;, serve one purpose: to insure that each image says exactly one thing, to reduce complexity to an instantly graspable unity. To turn such images into a complex whole requires virtuosic editing, but the editing of “The Eras Tour” doesn&#39;t rise to the challenge, providing little variety or contrast from image to image.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The impersonality of the filming is diametrically antithetical to Swift&#39;s artistry. The movie&#39;s visual monotony—its uninspired angles, its sameness of tempo, its obstinate cutting away from action—renders the cinematic experience wearying, even as one can see that the live performances were invigorating. Among the fascinations of Swift&#39;s stage presence is its apparent lack of spontaneity—the way the band is relegated to the sidelines, except in a few theatricalized moments in which guitarists briefly jam alongside her. But I say “apparent” because I don&#39;t believe it: for all the careful rehearsal that makes the numbers come off like clockwork, Swift is very much in the moment. The movie, however, catches this fervor only in glints and flashes, as if in still frames, never in motion. A freer and more creative directorial approach—longer and more urgent closeups, say, or more patient and more curious wide shots—would reveal the spontaneity and the immediacy and humanity of Swift&#39;s performances. Such a film would mirror her combination of concentration and abandon, thought and feeling, converging in the inner life of the artist at the center of the spectacle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Instead, the movie is shot and edited like a commercial—and it&#39;s obviously an effective one, because it provides an opportunity for a cohort of middle-aged film critics, myself included, to fawn over her work in a way that risks doing it an injustice. Like so many parents, grandparents, aunts, and uncles, movie writers may coo, “She&#39;s such a nice girl,” as if implicitly differentiating her from edgier rockers and rappers, or from more reckless celebrities. And she may well be a nice person, but her art involves much more than that, and she gives much more than that to her art. To get to the passion and the power of Taylor Swift would require a much better movie; the one she deserves would show not just how she shakes it off but how she shakes it up. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ud33zh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;mrdq87&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Bearing Witness with My Daughter at the Church of Taylor Swift]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/bearing-witness-with-my-daughter-at-the-church-of-taylor-swift]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T18:23:48.562Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652d39ad1bcbeea303da6cfb/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Winter-Taylor-Swift-Eras-Movie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot; 24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508 L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H1 6V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>; &lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z”>; &lt; /path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot; ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;当它出现时，我正在努力对事实、虚构和谣言进行分类泰勒·斯威夫特和特拉维斯·凯尔斯的关系。但随后，周五晚上，我开车带着一群四年级的女孩去康涅狄格州的一家购物中心看电影《泰勒·斯威夫特：时代之旅》，该片在北美周末票房收入近亿美元，成为北美周末票房收入近亿美元的电影。有史以来票房最高的音乐会电影。通过偷听我女儿和她的 Swifties 同伴在后座的闲聊，然后问我的孩子一些后续问题，我了解到 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/sports/sporting-scene /kelce-swift-is-a-dream-pairing-for-the-nfl&quot;>;泰勒和“国家橄榄球运动员”特拉维斯&lt;/a>;“暂时只是朋友——&lt;em>;暂时&lt; /em>;”，尽管泰勒确实“让所有人都在谈论”一段所谓的浪漫史，为《时代》电影宣传，但她和凯尔斯确实很快就会开始“真正”约会。果然，就在第二天晚上，斯威夫特和凯尔斯在《周六夜现场》中分别客串后，狗仔队发现他们手拉手离开派对结束。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女孩们对斯威夫特的分析——凯尔斯提炼了初级 Swiftie 心态的关键方面，无论是在其纯洁的愿望铸造中（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VuNIsY6JdUw&quot;>;闪回&lt;/a>;大约在 2009 年，泰勒坐在看台上等待与这位足球明星的射门），正如我的一位乘客所说，斯威夫特是“最伟大的女商人”：是的，她是一个精明、甚至狡猾的品牌设计师，但本质上是一个诚实的经纪人。即使是最新手的 Swifties，在某种直觉层面上也知道他们正在被玩，并且他们很乐意一起玩 - 尤其是因为他们有很多朋友可以一起玩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在夏末，我我和家人搬到了一个新城镇，在那里我们谁也不认识，开学几周后，我的女儿就成了《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker. com/culture/listening-booth/in-taylor-swifts-midnights-the-easter-eggs-arent-the-point&quot;>;午夜&lt;/a>;”被招募为激进的斯威夫特。很容易看出原因。我错过了为孩子们报名参加足球比赛的最后期限。我们不去教堂。斯威夫特之家以歌词的形式提供经文，以音乐会商品和友谊手镯的形式提供法衣；它提供了共同奉献的社会粘合剂。我只能给孩子一个新家；我需要泰勒·斯威夫特帮助她找到她的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在电影院大厅内，我为每个女孩购买了一个 10 美元的“泰勒·斯威夫特：时代之旅”水杯和 13 个女孩-一桶价值一美元的“泰勒·斯威夫特：时代之旅”爆米花供他们分享——我们加入了母亲和女儿、一群二十多岁的女性、年轻的同性恋夫妇和一对老年异性恋夫妇，他们希望我们的小队知道“泰勒·斯威夫特：时代之旅”所有的音乐都是她自己写的。”这个场景是 Swiftian Ren Faire 的场景：我们看到了《Shake It Off》视频中的啦啦队服装、《You Belong with Me》中的魔术标记 T 恤、《Reputation》巡演中的黑色亮片连帽紧身连衣裤以及大量闪闪发光的及地长礼服，体现了斯威夫特的罗达特与追逐萤火虫的美学。电影观众在眼睛周围画了粉色闪光的心形，以纪念《情人》的宣传艺术，并将友谊手镯叠到肘部，以致敬《孩子，你靠自己》中的一句歌词。一位女士将她的雨燕鞋混合搭配，将她的褶边苔绿色“民俗”连衣裙与“Lavender Haze”视频中的毛茸茸夹克搭配，并搭配一双“Fearless”复古女牛仔靴，强调“合身”。服装就像音乐会和电影一样，在泰勒时代巧妙地来回移动，本着一丝不苟的崇敬精神。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;我的同事阿曼达·彼得鲁西奇 (Amanda Petrusich) 写道&lt;a href =&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/06/19/taylor-swift-eras-tour-review&quot;>;斯威夫特的粉丝如此热情地与她联系&lt;/a>;，部分原因是这位明星的“ ”你们充满活力，一种健谈的、虚假的亲密关系。” 《Eras》电影恰恰体现了这种氛围，把斯威夫特表现得就像一个单身女孩出去庆祝生日，她邀请了七万名她最亲密的朋友，而这恰好轮到她在卡拉 OK 麦克风前。她做了很多“哎呀谁-我”的事情？！她一直在演戏，这在她十几岁的时候很迷人，几年后就变得刺耳和虚伪，现在看起来像是对这一点无可挑剔的承诺。在《残酷的夏天》之后，斯威夫特假装难以置信，所有这些&lt;em>;人&lt;/em>;都来这里看&lt;em>;她&lt;/em>;，就像，&lt;em>;什么&lt;/em>;？！？ - 告诉她观众认为他们让她感觉“如此强大”；音乐会快结束时，她声称对观众不得不忍受最后一首歌曲感到有点内疚（天哪，抱歉！）。在“永远”期间，斯威夫特——在&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/coronavirus&quot;>;&lt;em>;COVID&lt;/em>;-19&lt;/a的头几个月里>; 封锁，建立了一个家庭录音室，创作并录制了整张专辑，并主演并导演了一部精心制作的音乐视频，所有这些都在严格的安全限制下进行——将她在大流行时代的状态描述为“一个孤独的千禧一代，全身覆盖着猫毛，花了七年的时间每天看一百小时电视。”这些假装谦虚的行为是荒谬的，而且在斯威夫特职业生涯的这个阶段，它们是&lt;em>;极其&lt;/em>;可笑的——宏伟而古怪，也就是说，适合一个超级巨星。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯威夫特二十多岁的时候，她的事业经历了一段尴尬的青春期，当时她似乎陷入了思想的中学阶段。她的失败者形象开始变得坚强，成为烈士情结。 （这段时期我最喜欢的一集是金球奖主持人蒂娜·菲对斯威夫特的连续约会倾向开了一个极其温和的玩笑，斯威夫特对此回应道：“地狱里有一个特殊的地方，专门为那些不帮助其他女性的女性准备的。” ”）《时代》电影几乎没有否认斯威夫特的后页中任何她可能会后悔的章节——或者她只是已经长大了——但有时它会用最微弱的精心校准的羞怯来缓和其深情的怀旧之情，就像当斯威夫特转世为 BPD 恶棍时那样《空白》和《看看你让我做了什么》，或者《魔法奇缘》中的奶油糖霜公主。 Whether she&#39;s striding down the catwalk in a cadence of confrontational glam or swirling her arms in faux-balletic glissandos, she&#39;s doing it in air quotes, and the person she is quoting is the younger Swift, whom she has not quite left behind.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;This measure of remove, I think, also helps to illustrate Swift&#39;s extraordinary command over tweens and teens.孩子们正在为成人的世界进行排练，他们正在尝试着外表、姿势和信仰，看看自己是否适合自己，而斯威夫特，在三十三岁的成年期，正在以一种讽刺的事后诸葛亮的态度重新审视她过去的自己；艺术家和她的粉丝在稍微接近材料时，最终在中间相遇并紧紧地抱在一起。至少从周五晚上来看，柏拉图式的中间部分可能是“红色”的：在诸如“22”和“We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together”之类的歌曲中，一个疲惫不堪的陪伴者可以看到她比她年轻的人经历着一种欣喜若狂的溶解自我融入歌曲——一种纯粹的、令人兴奋的快乐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这种情况下反对任何被认为过度的热情可能会让人觉得无礼。但观众中有一个人的斯威夫特式的欣快感，在歌词的记忆中完美无瑕，在音量上几乎是暴力的、煽动性的、令人震惊的。她恰好坐在我女儿和她朋友的正后方，随着电影的进行，她的叫声分贝和频率都增加了。这个女孩是不真实的——就好像《全金属外壳》中的教官是一个斯威夫特，或者是一个绞痛的新生儿，或者是一个有知觉的手提钻，或者是流浪者队的球迷。我试图通过思考尖叫电影来分散自己的注意力。 （当她在“看看你让我做了什么”期间尖叫“我不喜欢你！”时，我在笔记本上写道，“《闪灵》中的雪莱·杜瓦尔。”当她尖叫时，“香槟！问题！”在“香槟问题”期间，我写道，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O7lVAuXGEOo&quot;>;“我是一个&lt;em>;staaarrrrrrr&lt;/em>;。”&lt;/a>; ”）我负责的女孩们在猛烈的攻击下退缩了，然后萎靡不振；他们停止跳舞，倒在座位上。有人低声说，她一直希望泰勒·斯威夫特能在这次放映中惊喜亮相，但现在她不抱希望了，因为他们背后的女孩可能会病得很重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最终，我的女儿和她的朋友们他们逃到剧院前面，第一排和银幕之间，在那里他们又开始跟着每句话跳舞和唱歌。几个女孩跟着他们，然后还有几十个。当我注意到那位肠绞痛的教官也来到前线时，我的心沉了下去。但没有什么可担心的。显然，她已经了解了社区的信号和社会规范，并相应地调整了电压；她现在被拨入人群，她在唱歌，而不是尖叫，她知道她的人民可以听到她的声音。在“午夜”场景中，女孩们在闲聊中闲逛，交换名字和友谊手镯。一名高中生带来了一整袋手镯来分发。一群孩子和另一群孩子手拉着手围成一圈跳舞，而其他孩子则围着他们翻滚。音乐流淌在他们身上，也为他们而流淌；他们比屏幕上的任何东西都更全神贯注地看着彼此，泰勒从高处向他们微笑，一时半被遗忘，只是另一位陪伴者。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;rwqi1j&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;e2pet8&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 03:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Jim Jordan’s Speaker Bid in Jeopardy After He Accidentally Locks Himself in Bathroom]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report/jim-jordans-speaker-bid-in-jeopardy-after-he-accidentally-locks-himself-in-bathroom]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T16:55:23.586Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652d67db58a4e8bc4ae07464/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Boro-Jim-Jordan-Sad-Social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V 0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span >;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data -journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;华盛顿 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report&quot;>;The Borowitz报告&lt;/a>;）——代表。吉姆·乔丹 (Jim Jordan) 不小心把自己锁在国会浴室里的消息传开后，他竞选众议院议长的努力遇到了新的障碍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位俄亥俄州国会议员本来预计会遇到反对他竞选的人，失踪了几个小时后，助手们才注意到他办公室的厕所里传出绝望的吼叫声。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;乔丹无法设计出自己卫生间的出口，这引发了关于他是否适合继续工作的新问题。议长，有人质疑是否应该信任他拿着一把巨大的、有潜在危险的木锤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，众议员马乔里·泰勒·格林等支持者表示，乔丹在浴室里的自我监禁无关紧要。 “我每周都会不小心把自己锁在浴室里三四次，但这并没有阻止我成为一名优秀的领导者，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div 数据-node-id=&quot;blg0rd&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;rxvpoj&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 01:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Daily Cartoon: Monday, October 16th]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/daily-cartoon/monday-october-16th-pumpkin-intelligence]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T15:41:17.226Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652d4bfb97b08b2a82692155/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/A28347.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22。 1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot; 0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2 .95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/ svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span >;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-内容&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content =daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-银行?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp; ;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;购买《纽约客》漫画 »&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;7oyfeu&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div 数据-node-id=&quot;63ivlo&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>